<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41862856</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of concurrent training on fat mass and its distribution in individuals with overweight or obesity: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and exploratory regression analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-026-26869-5</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Xuewan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports Science, South China Normal University, Guangzhou, 510006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Gen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports Science, South China Normal University, Guangzhou, 510006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Jinli</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports Science, South China Normal University, Guangzhou, 510006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Songtao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports Science, South China Normal University, Guangzhou, 510006, China. wangsongtao@m.scnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>25TKGA17</GrantID><Agency>the Students Scientific Research Project of South China Normal University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fat distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fat mass</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41862856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-026-26869-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-026-26869-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hruby A, Hu FB. The Epidemiology of Obesity: A Big Picture. PharmacoEconomics. 2015;33(7):673&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Obesity and Overweight. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/obesity-and-overweight. Accessed 1 Jun 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haslam DW, James WP. Obes Lancet. 2005;366(9492):1197&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caballero B. Humans against obesity: who will win? Adv Nutr. 2019;10(suppl1):S4&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway B, Rene A. Obesity as a disease: no lightweight matter. Obes Rev. 2004;5(3):145&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macklin M, Thompson C, Kawano-Dourado L, Bauer Ventura I, Weschenfelder C, Trostchansky A, et al. Linking adiposity to interstitial lung disease: the role of the dysfunctional adipocyte and inflammation. Cells. 2023;12(18):2206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank AP, de Souza Santos R, Palmer BF, Clegg DJ. Determinants of body fat distribution in humans may provide insight about obesity-related health risks. J Lipid Res. 2019;60(10):1710&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsushio K, Baden MY, Kagisaki T, Kato S, Niki A, Takayama R, et al. Interrelationships among accumulations of intra- and periorgan fats, visceral fat, and subcutaneous fat. Diabetes. 2024;73(7):1122&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tchernof A, Despr&#xe9;s JP. Pathophysiology of human visceral obesity: an update. Physiol Rev. 2013;93(1):359&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed B, Sultana R, Greene MW. Adipose tissue and insulin resistance in obese. Biomed Pharmacother. 2021;137:111315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Bradshaw AJ. The future of obesity reduction: beyond weight loss. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2009;5(6):319&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estruch R, Ros E, Salas-Salvad&#xf3; J, Covas MI, Corella D, Ar&#xf3;s F, et al. Primary prevention of cardiovascular disease with a mediterranean diet supplemented with extra-virgin olive oil or nuts. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(25):e34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge L, Sadeghirad B, Ball GDC, da Costa BR, Hitchcock CL, Svendrovski A, et al. Comparison of dietary macronutrient patterns of 14 popular named dietary programmes for weight and cardiovascular risk factor reduction in adults: systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomised trials. BMJ. 2020;369:m696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khera R, Murad MH, Chandar AK, Dulai PS, Wang Z, Prokop LJ, et al. Association of pharmacological treatments for obesity with weight loss and adverse events: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA. 2016;315(22):2424&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m L, Lindroos AK, Peltonen M, Torgerson J, Bouchard C, Carlsson B, et al. Lifestyle, diabetes, and cardiovascular risk factors 10 years after bariatric surgery. N Engl J Med. 2004;351(26):2683&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, Manore MM, Rankin JW, Smith BK. American College of sports medicine position stand. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(2):459&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verheggen RJ, Maessen MF, Green DJ, Hermus AR, Hopman MT, Thijssen DH. A systematic review and meta-analysis on the effects of exercise training versus hypocaloric diet: distinct effects on body weight and visceral adipose tissue. Obes Rev. 2016;17(8):664&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissers D, Hens W, Hansen D, Taeymans J. The effect of diet or exercise on visceral adipose tissue in overweight youth. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(7):1415&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao S, Pandey A, Garg S, Park B, Mayo H, Despr&#xe9;s JP, et al. Effect of exercise and pharmacological interventions on visceral adiposity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of long-term randomized controlled trials. Mayo Clin Proc. 2019;94(2):211&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan GE, Perri MG, Theriaque DW, Hutson AD, Eckel RH, Stacpoole PW. Exercise training, without weight loss, increases insulin sensitivity and postheparin plasma lipase activity in previously sedentary adults. Diabetes Care. 2003;26(3):557&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkahtani S, Aljuhani O, Alkhalidi N, Almasuod N, Hezam O, Aljaloud I et al. Impact of acute eccentric versus concentric running on exercise-induced fat oxidation and postexercise physical activity in untrained men. Biomed Res Int. 2020, 2020:2608730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pahk K, Kim EJ, Joung C, Seo HS, Kim S. Exercise training reduces inflammatory metabolic activity of visceral fat assessed by (18) F-FDG PET/CT in obese women. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2020;93(2):127&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claussnitzer M, Dankel SN, Kim KH, Quon G, Meuleman W, Haugen C, et al. FTO obesity variant circuitry and adipocyte browning in humans. N Engl J Med. 2015;373(10):895&#x2013;907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn C, Zhang T, Yang G, Rode T, Varshney P, Ghayur SJ, et al. Years of endurance exercise training remodel abdominal subcutaneous adipose tissue in adults with overweight or obesity. Nat Metab. 2024;6(9):1819&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann M, Feuerbacher JF, S&#xfc;nkeler M, Freitag N, R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Doma K, et al. Compatibility of concurrent aerobic and strength training for skeletal muscle size and function: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2022;52(3):601&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eddens L, van Someren K, Howatson G. The role of intra-session exercise sequence in the interference effect: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):177&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murlasits Z, Kneffel Z, Thalib L. The physiological effects of concurrent strength and endurance training sequence: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(11):1212&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markov A, Hauser L, Chaabene H. Effects of concurrent strength and endurance training on measures of physical fitness in healthy middle-aged and older adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(2):437&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canli U, Aldhahi MI. The physiological and physical benefits of two types of concurrent training: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024;16(1):8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins R, Loureiro N. The effects of low-volume combined training on health-related physical fitness outcomes in active young adults: a controlled clinical trial. Sports Med Health Sci. 2023;5(1):74&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung HC, Jeon S, Lee NH, Kim K, Kang M, Lee S. Effects of exercise intervention on visceral fat in obese children and adolescents. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2019;59(6):1045&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, He H, Xie K, Zhang L, Cao C. Effects of various exercise types on visceral adipose tissue in individuals with overweight and obesity: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of 84 randomized controlled trials. Obes Rev. 2024;25(3):e13666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarizadeh H, Eftekhar R, Anjom-Shoae J, Speakman JR, Djafarian K. The Effect of aerobic and resistance training and combined exercise modalities on subcutaneous abdominal fat: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Adv Nutr. 2021;12(1):179&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail I, Keating SE, Baker MK, Johnson NA. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of aerobic vs. resistance exercise training on visceral fat. Obes Rev. 2012;13(1):68&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang YH, Yang HY, Shun SC. Effect of exercise intervention dosage on reducing visceral adipose tissue: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Obes (Lond). 2021;45(5):982&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Zhang X, Ren H, Zhou H, Yuan Y, Chai Y. Effects of different exercise types on visceral fat in young individuals with obesity aged 6&#x2013;24 years old: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2022;13:987804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Chandler J, Welch VA, Higgins JP, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;10(10):Ed000142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(11):777&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drevon D, Fursa SR, Malcolm AL. Intercoder reliability and validity of webplotdigitizer in extracting graphed data. Behav Modif. 2017;41(2):323&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The cochrane collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshem H, Helfand M, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Oxman AD, Kunz R, Brozek J, et al. GRADE guidelines: 3. Rating the quality of evidence. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(4):401&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, You Q, Hou X, Zhang S, Du L, Lv Y, et al. The effect of exercise on cognitive function in people with multiple sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Neurol. 2023;270(6):2908&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton K, Norton L, Sadgrove D. Position statement on physical activity and exercise intensity terminology. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(5):496&#x2013;502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N. ACSM&#x2019;s foundations of strength training and conditioning. Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaston TB, Dixon JB. Factors associated with percent change in visceral versus subcutaneous abdominal fat during weight loss: findings from a systematic review. Int J Obes (Lond). 2008;32(4):619&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuit M, Rance M, Morel C, Bouillon P, Boscaro A, Martin V, et al. Effect of concurrent training on body composition and gut microbiota in postmenopausal women with overweight or obesity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54(3):517&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hens W, Vissers D, Verhaeghe N, Gielen J, Van Gaal L, Taeymans J. Unsupervised exercise training was not found to improve the metabolic health or phenotype over a 6-month dietary intervention: a randomised controlled trial with an embedded economic analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(15):8004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nono Nankam PA, Mendham AE, De Smidt MF, Keswell D, Olsson T, Bl&#xfc;her M, et al. Changes in systemic and subcutaneous adipose tissue inflammation and oxidative stress in response to exercise training in obese black African women. J Physiol. 2020;598(3):503&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendham AE, Larsen S, George C, Adams K, Hauksson J, Olsson T, et al. Exercise training results in depot-specific adaptations to adipose tissue mitochondrial function. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):3785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortuin-de Smidt MC, Mendham AE, Hauksson J, Hakim O, Stefanovski D, Clamp L, et al. Effect of exercise training on insulin sensitivity, hyperinsulinemia and ectopic fat in black South African women: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Endocrinol. 2020;183(1):51&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashti BA, Mehrabani J, Damirchi A, Babaei P. The influence of concurrent training intensity on serum irisin and abdominal fat in postmenopausal women. Prz Menopauzalny. 2019;18(3):166&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houghton D, Thoma C, Hallsworth K, Cassidy S, Hardy T, Burt AD, et al. Exercise reduces liver lipids and visceral adiposity in patients with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis in a randomized controlled trial. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;15(1):96&#x2013;e102103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houghton D, Hallsworth K, Thoma C, Cassidy S, Hardy T, Heaps S, et al. Effects of exercise on liver fat and metabolism in alcohol drinkers. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;15(10):1596&#x2013;e16031593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SM, Kwak YS, Ji JG. The effects of combined exercise on health-related fitness, endotoxin, and immune function of postmenopausal women with abdominal obesity. J Immunol Res. 2015;2015:830567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro PA, Chen KY, Lira FS, Saraiva BT, Antunes BM, Campos EZ, et al. Concurrent and aerobic exercise training promote similar benefits in body composition and metabolic profiles in obese adolescents. Lipids Health Dis. 2015;14:153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberga AS, Prud&#x2019;homme D, Kenny GP, Goldfield GS, Hadjiyannakis S, Gougeon R, et al. Effects of aerobic and resistance training on abdominal fat, apolipoproteins and high-sensitivity C-reactive protein in adolescents with obesity: the HEARTY randomized clinical trial. Int J Obes (Lond). 2015;39(10):1494&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchonville M, Armamento-Villareal R, Shah K, Napoli N, Sinacore DR, Qualls C, Villareal DT. Weight loss, exercise or both and cardiometabolic risk factors in obese older adults: results of a randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes (Lond). 2014;38(3):423&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donges CE, Duffield R, Guelfi KJ, Smith GC, Adams DR, Edge JA. Comparative effects of single-mode vs. duration-matched concurrent exercise training on body composition, low-grade inflammation, and glucose regulation in sedentary, overweight, middle-aged men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2013;38(7):779&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrosielski DA, Gibbs BB, Ouyang P, Bonekamp S, Clark JM, Wang NY, et al. Effect of exercise on blood pressure in type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. J Gen Intern Med. 2012;27(11):1453&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JN, Gyllenhammer LE, Vanni AA, Meija M, Tung A, Schroeder ET, et al. Startup circuit training program reduces metabolic risk in Latino adolescents. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(11):2195&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barone BB, Wang NY, Bacher AC, Stewart KJ. Decreased exercise blood pressure in older adults after exercise training: contributions of increased fitness and decreased fatness. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(1):52&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Park JH, Kwon YC, Kim HS, Yoon MS, Park HT. The effect of combined aerobic and resistance exercise training on abdominal fat in obese middle-aged women. J Physiol Anthropol Appl Hum Sci. 2003;22(3):129&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuff DJ, Meneilly GS, Martin A, Ignaszewski A, Tildesley HD, Frohlich JJ. Effective exercise modality to reduce insulin resistance in women with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2003;26(11):2977&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC, Rosenkoetter MA, Brown MM. Strength training effects on aerobic power and short-term endurance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1980;12(5):336&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe4;bler M, Prieske O, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U. The effects of concurrent strength and endurance training on physical fitness and athletic performance in youth: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, Wilson SM, Loenneke JP, Anderson JC. Concurrent training: a meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(8):2293&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Hansen EA, Raastad T. High volume of endurance training impairs adaptations to 12 weeks of strength training in well-trained endurance athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(4):1457&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petr&#xe9; H, Hemmingsson E, Rosdahl H, Psilander N. Development of maximal dynamic strength during concurrent resistance and endurance training in untrained, moderately trained, and trained individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51(5):991&#x2013;1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouamra M, Zouhal H, Ratel S, Makhlouf I, Bezrati I, Chtara M, et al. Concurrent training promotes greater gains on body composition and components of physical fitness than single-mode training (endurance or resistance) in youth with obesity. Front Physiol. 2022;13:869063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, Peterson MD, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. Concurrent aerobic plus resistance exercise versus aerobic exercise alone to improve health outcomes in paediatric obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(3):161&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros Nda S, de Abreu FG, Colato AS, de Lemos LS, Ramis TR, Dorneles GP et al. Effects of concurrent training on oxidative stress and insulin resistance in obese individuals. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2015;2015:697181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meister BM, Hong SG, Shin J, Rath M, Sayoc J, Park JY. Healthy versus unhealthy adipose tissue expansion: the role of exercise. J Obes Metab Syndr. 2022;31(1):37&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You T, Arsenis NC, Disanzo BL, Lamonte MJ. Effects of exercise training on chronic inflammation in obesity: current evidence and potential mechanisms. Sports Med. 2013;43(4):243&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsiloulis T, Watt MJ. Exercise and the regulation of adipose tissue metabolism. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci. 2015;135:175&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabag A, Chang D, Johnson NA. Growth hormone as a potential mediator of aerobic exercise-induced reductions in visceral adipose tissue. Front Physiol. 2021;12:623570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nouri Y, RNF, Mirzaie B, Arazi H. The effect of resistance and endurance training on resting metabolic rate and body composition in sedentary males. Zanjan Univ Med. 2013;21:51&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmons JF, Minnock D, Hone M, Cogan KE, Murphy JC, Egan B. Comparison of time-matched aerobic, resistance, or concurrent exercise training in older adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(11):2272&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva MAR, Baptista LC, Neves RS, De Fran&#xe7;a E, Loureiro H, Lira FS, et al. The effects of concurrent training combining both resistance exercise and high-intensity interval training or moderate-intensity continuous training on metabolic syndrome. Front Physiol. 2020;11:572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu F, He R, Wei Y, Gong J, Mu D, Shi L et al. The accuracy of visceral adipose tissue for the screening of metabolic syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2025:e70064. Published online 16 December 2025. https://doi.org/10.1111/obr.70064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Ten Hoevel C, Besora-Moreno M, Queral J, Llaurad&#xf3; E, Valls RM, Sol&#xe0; R, et al. Ultrasound and MRI abdominal fat distribution and its associations with metabolic conditions in adults with abdominal obesity. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2026;28(3):2061&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty S, Suvarna R, Bhattacharya S, Seetharaman K. Visceral adiposity and cardiometabolic risk: clinical insights and assessment. Cardiol Rev. Published online 7 July 2025. https://doi.org/10.1097/CRD.0000000000000984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim MM. Subcutaneous and visceral adipose tissue: structural and functional differences. Obes Rev. 2010;11(1):11&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arner P, Kriegholm E, Engfeldt P, Bolinder J. Adrenergic regulation of lipolysis in situ at rest and during exercise. J Clin Invest. 1990;85(3):893&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goossens GH. The metabolic phenotype in obesity: fat mass, body fat distribution, and adipose tissue function. Obes Facts. 2017;10(3):207&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K, Kusminski CM, Scherer PE. Adipose tissue remodeling and obesity. J Clin Invest. 2011;121(6):2094&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landecho MF, Tuero C, Valent&#xed; V, Bilbao I, de la Higuera M, Fr&#xfc;hbeck G. Relevance of leptin and other adipokines in obesity-associated cardiovascular risk. Nutrients. 2019;11(11):2664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji SJ, Qian ZH, Hu PY, Chen FY. Age-dependent changes in skeletal muscle mass and visceral fat area in a chinese population. Curr Med Sci. 2023;43(4):838&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wajchenberg BL. Subcutaneous and visceral adipose tissue: their relation to the metabolic syndrome. Endocr Rev. 2000;21(6):697&#x2013;738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valente GV, Machado LG, Figueiredo CP, Caparbo VF, Takayama L, Franco AS, et al. Visceral adipose tissue measured by DXA predicts metabolic syndrome in low-income community-dwelling elderly: insights from the S&#xe3;o Paulo Aging &amp; Health (SPAH) study. Bone. 2025;190:117308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colleluori G, Villareal DT. Aging, obesity, sarcopenia and the effect of diet and exercise intervention. Exp Gerontol. 2021;155:111561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy JC, McDaniel JL, Mora K, Villareal DT, Fontana L, Weiss EP. Preferential reductions in intermuscular and visceral adipose tissue with exercise-induced weight loss compared with calorie restriction. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2012;112(1):79&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rost&#xe1;s I, P&#xf3;t&#xf3; L, M&#xe1;trai P, Hegyi P, Tenk J, Garami A, et al. In middle-aged and old obese patients, training intervention reduces leptin level: a meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(8):e0182801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters DL, Aguirre L, Gurney B, Sinacore DR, Fowler K, Gregori G, et al. Effect of aerobic or resistance exercise, or both, on intermuscular and visceral fat and physical and metabolic function in older adults with obesity while dieting. J Gerontol Biol Sci Med Sci. 2022;77(1):131&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams R, Periasamy M. Genetic and Environmental Factors Contributing to Visceral Adiposity in Asian Populations. Endocrinol Metab (Seoul). 2020;35(4):681&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nn PF, Andersen GS, Lauritzen T, Christensen DL, Aadahl M, Carstensen B, et al. Ethnic differences in anthropometric measures and abdominal fat distribution: a cross-sectional pooled study in Inuit, Africans and Europeans. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2017;71(6):536&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai H, Alsalhe TA, Chalghaf N, Ricc&#xf2; M, Bragazzi NL, Wu J. The global burden of disease attributable to high body mass index in 195 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2017: an analysis of the global burden of disease study. PLoS Med. 2020;17(7):e1003198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HS, Lee J. Effects of exercise interventions on weight, body mass index, lean body mass and accumulated visceral fat in overweight and obese individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ruiz K, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Correa-Bautista JE, Peterson MD, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A. The effects of exercise on abdominal fat and liver enzymes in pediatric obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Child Obes. 2017;13(4):272&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho SS, Dhaliwal SS, Hills AP, Pal S. The effect of 12 weeks of aerobic, resistance or combination exercise training on cardiovascular risk factors in the overweight and obese in a randomized trial. BMC Public Health. 2012;12:704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poirier P, Despr&#xe9;s JP. Exercise in weight management of obesity. Cardiol Clin. 2001;19(3):459&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Li G, Zhang S, Zhou Y, Lv Y, Feng L, et al. Effects of exercise on depression and anxiety in breast cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cancer Med. 2025;14(5):e70671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargreaves M, Spriet LL. Skeletal muscle energy metabolism during exercise. Nat Metab. 2020;2(9):817&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romijn JA, Coyle EF, Sidossis LS, Gastaldelli A, Horowitz JF, Endert E, et al. Regulation of endogenous fat and carbohydrate metabolism in relation to exercise intensity and duration. Am J Physiol. 1993;265(3 Pt 1):E380&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Scotto A, Guerra E, Orlandi C, Bazzucchi I, Sacchetti M. Effect of combined resistance and endurance exercise training on regional fat loss. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2017;57(6):794&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World health organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayedi A, Soltani S, Emadi A, Zargar MS, Najafi A. Aerobic exercise and weight loss in adults: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(12):e2452185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM, Neilson HK, O&#x2019;Reilly R, Duha A, Yasui Y, Morielli AR, et al. Effects of a high vs moderate volume of aerobic exercise on adiposity outcomes in postmenopausal women: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Oncol. 2015;1(6):766&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maillard F, Rousset S, Pereira B, Traore A, de Pradel Del Amaze P, Boirie Y, et al. High-intensity interval training reduces abdominal fat mass in postmenopausal women with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Metab. 2016;42(6):433&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wewege M, van den Berg R, Ward RE, Keech A. The effects of high-intensity interval training vs. moderate-intensity continuous training on body composition in overweight and obese adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2017;18(6):635&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritzlaff CJ, Wideman L, Blumer J, Jensen M, Abbott RD, Gaesser GA, et al. Catecholamine release, growth hormone secretion, and energy expenditure during exercise vs. recovery in men. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2000;89(3):937&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Jiao J, Liu Y, Li H, Zhang H. The release of lipolytic hormones during various high-intensity interval and moderate-intensity continuous training regimens and their effects on fat loss. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23(1):559&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore CJ, Withers RT. The effect of exercise intensity and duration on the oxygen deficit and excess post-exercise oxygen consumption. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1990;60(3):169&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG, Chatzinikolaou A, Tournis S, Nikolaidis MG, Jamurtas AZ, Douroudos II, et al. Intensity of resistance exercise determines adipokine and resting energy expenditure responses in overweight elderly individuals. Diabetes Care. 2009;32(12):2161&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko SH, Jung Y. Energy metabolism changes and dysregulated lipid metabolism in postmenopausal women. Nutrients. 2021;13(12):4556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambikairajah A, Walsh E, Tabatabaei-Jafari H, Cherbuin N. Fat mass changes during menopause: a metaanalysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2019;221(5):393&#x2013;e409350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambacciani M, Ciaponi M, Cappagli B, Benussi C, De Simone L, Genazzani AR. Climacteric modifications in body weight and fat tissue distribution. Climacteric. 1999;2(1):37&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira-Potter VJ, Mishra G, Townsend KL. Health of adipose tissue: oestrogen matters. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2026;22(2):76&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klisic A, Ahmad R, Daka B, Sindhu S. Editorial: Cardiometabolic diseases in postmenopausal women. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2024;15:1514913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalo-Encabo P, Valad&#xe9;s D, Garc&#xed;a-Honduvilla N, de Cos Blanco A, Friedenreich CM, P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez A. Exercise type and fat mass loss regulate breast cancer-related sex hormones in obese and overweight postmenopausal women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120(6):1277&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsatti FL, Nahas EA, Maesta N, Nahas-Neto J, Burini RC. Plasma hormones, muscle mass and strength in resistance-trained postmenopausal women. Maturitas. 2008;59(4):394&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Habibi Maleki A, Sakhaei MH, Rosenkranz SK, Pourvaghar MJ, Ehsanifar M, et al. The effects of exercise training on body composition in postmenopausal women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2023;14:1183765.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>