<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33665034</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2167-8359</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PeerJ</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pushing up or pushing out-an initial investigation into horizontal- versus vertical-force training on swimming start performance: a pilot study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e10937</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e10937</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e10937</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.10937</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The block phase in the swimming start requires a quick reaction to the starting signal and a large take-off velocity that is primarily horizontal in direction. Due to the principle of specificity of training, there is a potential benefit of performing a greater proportion of horizontal force production exercises in a swimmers' dry-land resistance training sessions. Therefore, the purpose of this pilot study was to provide an insight into the effects of a horizontal- (HF) vs vertical-force (VF) training intervention on swim start performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eleven competitive swimmers (six males (age 20.9 &#xb1; 1.8 years, body mass 77.3 &#xb1; 9.7 kg, height 1.78 &#xb1; 0.05 m) and five females (age 21.4 &#xb1; 2.0 years, body mass 67.5 &#xb1; 7.4 kg, height 1.69 &#xb1; 0.05 m)) completed 2 weekly sessions of either a horizontal- or vertical-force focused resistance training programme for 8 weeks. Squat jump force-time characteristics and swim start kinetic and kinematic parameters were collected pre- and post-intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Across the study duration, the swimmers completed an average of nine swimming sessions per week with an average weekly swim volume of 45.5 &#xb1; 17.7 km (HF group) and 53 &#xb1; 20.0 km (VF group), but little practice of the swim start per week (<i>n</i> = 9). Within-group analyses indicated a significant increase in predicted one repetition maximum (1RM) hip thrust strength in the HF group, as well as significant increases in grab resultant peak force but reductions in resultant peak force of the block phase for the VF group. No significant between-group differences in predicted 1RM hip thrust and back squat strength, squat jump force-time and swim start performance measures were observed after 8 weeks of training. Significant correlations in the change scores of five block kinetic variables to time to 5 m were observed, whereby increased block kinetic outputs were associated with a reduced time to 5 m. This may be indicative of individual responses to the different training programmes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results of this current study have been unable to determine whether a horizontal- or vertical-force training programme enhances swim start performance after an 8-week training intervention. Some reasons for the lack of within and between group effects may reflect the large volume of concurrent training and the relative lack of any deliberate practice of the swim start. Larger samples and longer training duration may be required to determine whether significant differences occur between these training approaches. Such research should also look to investigate how a reduction in the concurrent training loads and/or an increase in the deliberate practice of the swim start may influence the potential changes in swim start performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Thng et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thng</LastName><ForeName>Shiqi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Medicine, Bond University, Gold Coast, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Academy of Sport, Nathan, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pearson</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queensland Academy of Sport, Nathan, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keogh</LastName><ForeName>Justin W L</ForeName><Initials>JWL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9851-1068</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Medicine, Bond University, Gold Coast, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance Research Centre New Zealand, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cluster for Health Improvement, Faculty of Science, Health, Education and Engineering, University of the Sunshine Coast, Sippy Downs, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kasturba Medical College, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Force-vector theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Specificity of training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Swim start</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Swimming</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Justin W.L. Keogh is an Academic Editor for PeerJ.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33665034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.10937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aspenes S, Kjendlie PL, Hoff J, Helgerud J. Combined strength and endurance training in competitive swimmers. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine. 2009;8:357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3763280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow H, Halaki M, Stuelcken M, Greene A, Sinclair PJ. The effect of different kick start positions on OMEGA OSB11 blocks on free swimming time to 15m in developmental level swimmers. Human Movement Science. 2014;34:178&#x2013;186. doi: 10.1016/j.humov.2014.02.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2014.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24636696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie K, Kenny IC, Lyons M, Carson BP. The effect of strength training on performance in endurance athletes. Sports Medicine. 2014;44(6):845&#x2013;865. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0157-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0157-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24532151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness. Sports Medicine. 2005;35(10):841&#x2013;851. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200535100-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535100-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16180944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D, Smith R, Smith M, Rigby H. Effect of plyometric training on swimming block start performance in adolescents. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2009;23(7):2137&#x2013;2143. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b866d0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b866d0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop DJ, Bartlett J, Fyfe J, Lee M. Methodological considerations for concurrent training. In: Schumann M, R&#xf8;nnestad B, editors. Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Training. Cham: Springer; 2019. pp. 183&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Born D-P, St&#xf6;ggl T, Petrov A, Burkhardt D, L&#xfc;thy F, Romann M. Analysis of freestyle swimming sprint start performance after maximal strength or vertical jump training in competitive female and male junior swimmers. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2020;34(2):323&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31985714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branscheidt M, Kassavetis P, Anaya M, Rogers D, Huang HD, Lindquist MA, Celnik P. Fatigue induces long-lasting detrimental changes in motor-skill learning. Elife. 2019;8:131. doi: 10.7554/eLife.40578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.40578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6443347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breed RV, Young WB. The effect of a resistance training programme on the grab, track and swing starts in swimming. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2003;21(3):213&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1080/0264041031000071047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0264041031000071047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12703850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength testing&#x2014;predicting a one-rep max from reps-to-fatigue. Journal of Physical Education, Recreation &amp; Dance. 1993;64(1):88&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1080/07303084.1993.10606684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07303084.1993.10606684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x10c;oh M, Peharec S, Ba&#x10d;i&#x107; P, Mackala K. Biomechanical differences in the sprint start between faster and slower high-level sprinters. Journal of Human Kinetics. 2017;56(1):29&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1515/hukin-2017-0020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hukin-2017-0020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5384050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras B, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Beardsley C, McMaster DT, Reyneke JH, Cronin JB. Effects of a six-week hip thrust vs. front squat resistance training program on performance in adolescent males: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2017;31(4):999&#x2013;1008. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27253835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley E, Harrison A, Lyons M. The impact of resistance training on swimming peformance: a systematic review. Sports Medicine. 2017;47(11):2285&#x2013;2307. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0730-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0730-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28497283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Fernandez F, Lopez-Contreras G, Arellano R. Effect on swimming start performance of two types of activation protocols: lunge and yoyo squat. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2015;29(3):647&#x2013;655. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25226318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Fern&#xe1;ndez F, Ruiz-Teba A, L&#xf3;pez-Contreras G, Arellano R. Effects of 2 types of activation protocols based on postactivation potentiation on 50-m freestyle performance. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2018;34(11):3284&#x2013;3292. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33105381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick DA, Cimadoro G, Cleather DJ. The magical horizontal force muscle? A preliminary study examining the force-vector theory. Sports. 2019;7(2):30. doi: 10.3390/sports7020030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7020030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6409580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30678251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Pallares J, Sanchez-Medina L, Carrasco L, Diaz A, Izquierdo M. Endurance and neuromuscular changes in world-class level kayakers during a periodized training cycle. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2009;106(4):629&#x2013;638. doi: 10.1007/s00421-009-1061-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1061-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19396614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Ramos A, Stirn I, Padial P, Arguelles-Cienfuegos J, De la Fuente B, Calderon C, Bonitch-Gongora J, Tomazin K, Strumbelj B, Strojnik V, Feriche B. The effect of an altitude training camp on swimming start time and loaded squat jump performance. PLOS ONE. 2016;11(7):e0160401. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0160401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0160401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4965075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27467760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harland MJ, Steele JR. Biomechanics of the sprint start. Sports Medicine. 1997;23(1):11&#x2013;20. doi: 10.2165/00007256-199723010-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199723010-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9017856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haycraft J, Robertson S. The effects of concurrent aerobic training and maximal strength, power and swim-specific dry-land training methods on swim performance: a review. Journal of Australian Strength and Conditioning. 2015;23:91&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda KE, Sinclair PJ, Mason BR, Pease DL. A biomechanical comparison of elite swimmers start performance using the traditional track start and the new kick start. In: Kjendlie P-L, Stallman RK, Cabri J, editors. International Symposium for Biomechanics and Medicine in Swimming. Oslo: BMS; 2010. pp. 94&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W. A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics. A new view of statistics. 2002. http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/effectmag.html http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/effectmag.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones JV, Pyne DB, Haff GG, Newton RU. Comparison of ballistic and strength training on swimming turn and dry-land leg extensor characteristics in elite swimmers. International Journal of Sports Science &amp; Coaching. 2018;13(2):262&#x2013;269. doi: 10.1177/1747954117726017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747954117726017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenhard W, Lenhard A. Calculation of effect sizes. Dettelbach, Germany. 2016. https://www.psychometrica.de/effect_size.html https://www.psychometrica.de/effect_size.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthorne NP. Analysis of standing vertical jumps using a force platform. American Journal of Physics. 2001;69(11):1198&#x2013;1204. doi: 10.1119/1.1397460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1119/1.1397460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell LJ, Argus CK, Taylor KL, Sheppard JM, Chapman DW. The effect of initial knee angle on concentric-only squat jump performance. Research Quarterly for Exercise and Sport. 2017;88(2):184&#x2013;192. doi: 10.1080/02701367.2017.1293777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2017.1293777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28339350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin JB, Petrakos G, Jimenez-Reyes P, Brown SR, Samozino P, Cross MR. Very-heavy sled training for improving horizontal-force output in soccer players. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. 2017;12(6):840&#x2013;844. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2016-0444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27834560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morou&#xe7;o PG, Marinho DA, Izquierdo M, Henrique N, M&#xe1;rio CM. Relative contribution of arms and legs in 30s fully tethered front crawl swimming. BioMed Research International. 2015;2015(s2):1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1155/2015/563206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/563206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4619838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26539511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randell AD, Cronin JB, Keogh JWL, Gill ND. Transference of strength and power adaptation to sports performance&#x2014;horizontal and vertical force production. Strength and Conditioning Journal. 2010;32(4):100&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181e91eec.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181e91eec</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebutini VZ, Pereira G, Bohrer R, Ugrinowitsch C, Rodacki AL. Plyometric long jump training with progressive loading improves kinetic and kinematic swimming start parameters. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2014;30(9):2392&#x2013;2398. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24531431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejman M, Bilewski M, Szczepan S, Klarowicz A, Rudnik D, Mackala K. Assessing the impact of a targeted plyometric training on changes in selected kinematic parameters of the swimming start. Acta of Bioengineering and Biomechanics. 2017;19:149&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28869635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie D, Keogh JW, Reaburn P, Bartlett JD. Utilising one minute and four minute recovery when employing the resistance training contrast method does not negatively affect subsequent jump performance in the presence of concurrent training. PeerJ. 2020;8(1):e10031. doi: 10.7717/peerj.10031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.10031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7566756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33083124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Doyle TL. Increasing compliance to instructions in the squat jump. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2008;22(2):648&#x2013;651. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816602d4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816602d4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tano G, Bishop A, Climstein M, DeBeliso M. The reliability of the prowler in high school male football players. Journal of Sports Science. 2016;4:183&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thng S, Pearson S, Keogh JW. Relationships between dry-land resistance training and swim start performance and effects of such training on the swim start: a systematic review. Sports Medicine. 2019;49(12):1&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1007/s40279-019-01174-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01174-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31493205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thng S, Pearson S, Rathbone E, Keogh JWL. The prediction of swim start performance based on squat jump force-time characteristics. PeerJ. 2020;8:e9208. doi: 10.7717/peerj.9208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.9208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32547864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tor E, Pease D, Ball K. Key parameters of the swimming start and their relationship to start performance. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2015a;33(13):1313&#x2013;1321. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2014.990486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2014.990486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25555171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tor E, Pease D, Ball K. The reliability of an instrumented start block analysis system. Journal of Applied Biomechanics. 2015b;31(1):62&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1123/JAB.2014-0155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/JAB.2014-0155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25268512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AP. The science and practice of periodization: a brief review. Strength and Conditioning Journal. 2011;33(1):34&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0b013e3182079cdf.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e3182079cdf</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vantorre J, Chollet D, Seifert L. Biomechanical analysis of the swim-start: a review. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine. 2014;13:223&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3990873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24790473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winwood PW, Cronin JB, Posthumus LR, Finlayson SJ, Gill ND, Keogh JW. Strongman vs. traditional resistance training effects on muscular function and performance. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2015;29(2):429&#x2013;439. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25627449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>