<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33405189</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interference Phenomenon with Concurrent Strength and High-Intensity Interval Training-Based Aerobic Training: An Updated Model.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>599</StartPage><EndPage>605</EndPage><MedlinePgn>599-605</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-020-01421-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Previous research has suggested that concurrent training (CT) may attenuate resistance training (RT)-induced gains in muscle strength and mass, i.e.' the interference effect. In 2000, a seminal theoretical model indicated that the interference effect should occur when high-intensity interval training (HIIT) (repeated bouts at 95-100% of the aerobic power) and RT (multiple sets at&#x2009;~&#x2009;10 repetition maximum;10 RM) were performed in the same training routine. However, there was a paucity of data regarding the likelihood of other HIIT-based CT protocols to induce the interference effect at the time. Thus, based on current HIIT-based CT literature and HIIT nomenclature and framework, the present manuscript updates the theoretical model of the interference phenomenon previously proposed. We suggest that very intense HIIT protocols [i.e., resisted sprint training (RST), and sprint interval training (SIT)] can greatly minimize the odds of occurring the interference effect on muscle strength and mass. Thus, very intensive HIIT protocols should be implemented when performing CT to avoid the interference effect. Long and short HIIT-based CT protocols may induce the interference effect on muscle strength when HIIT bout is performed before RT with no rest interval between them.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vechin</LastName><ForeName>Felipe C</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0975-8654</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Av. Prof. Mello Moraes, 65, Cidade Universit&#xe1;ria, Sao Paulo, SP, 05508-030, Brazil. felipevechin@usp.br.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations To Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Sao Carlos, Sao Carlos, Brazil. felipevechin@usp.br.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Miguel S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Av. Prof. Mello Moraes, 65, Cidade Universit&#xe1;ria, Sao Paulo, SP, 05508-030, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Telles</LastName><ForeName>Guilherme D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Av. Prof. Mello Moraes, 65, Cidade Universit&#xe1;ria, Sao Paulo, SP, 05508-030, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations To Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Sao Carlos, Sao Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugrinowitsch</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Av. Prof. Mello Moraes, 65, Cidade Universit&#xe1;ria, Sao Paulo, SP, 05508-030, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="Y">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="N">Rest</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33405189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01421-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-020-01421-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Hawley JA. Concurrent exercise training: do opposites distract? J Physiol. 2017;595(9):2883&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27506998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, Gorostiaga E, Izquierdo M, Rusko H, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations during concurrent strength and endurance training versus strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89(1):42&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12627304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balabinis CP, Psarakis CH, Moukas M, Vassiliou MP, Behrakis PK. Early phase changes by concurrent endurance and strength training. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(2):393&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JP, Pozniak MA, Agre JC. Neuromuscular adaptations to concurrent strength and endurance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(3):511&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty D, Sporer B. A proposed model for examining the interference phenomenon between concurrent aerobic and strength training. Sports Med. 2000;30(6):385&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11132121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveritt M, Abernethy PJ, Barry BK, Logan PA. Concurrent strength and endurance training. A Rev Sports Med. 1999;28(6):413&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG, MacDougall JD, Jacobs I, Garner S. Interaction between concurrent strength and endurance training. J Appl Physiol. 1990;68(1):260&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2312468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG, Jacobs I, MacDougall JD, Garner S. Comparison of two regimens of concurrent strength and endurance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1990;22(3):348&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2381303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa AC, Neiva HP, Izquierdo M, Cadore EL, Alves AR, Marinho DA. Concurrent training and detraining: brief review on the effect of exercise intensities. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40(12):747&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-0975-9471 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0975-9471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31476783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryman N, Mujika I, Bosquet L. Concurrent training for sports performance: the 2 sides of the medal. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(3):279&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29809072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabag A, Najafi A, Michael S, Esgin T, Halaki M, Hackett D. The compatibility of concurrent high intensity interval training and resistance training for muscular strength and hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(21):2472&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Pinto RS, Teodoro JL, da Silva LXN, Menger E, Alberton CL, et al. Cardiorespiratory adaptations in elderly men following different concurrent training regimes. J Nutr Health Aging. 2018;22(4):483&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29582887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca V, Minganti C, Borrione P, Grazioli E, Cerulli C, Guerra E, et al. Effects of concurrent aerobic and strength training on breast cancer survivors: a pilot study. Public health. 2016;136:126&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27161493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botonis PG, Toubekis AG, Platanou TI. Concurrent strength and interval endurance training in elite water polo players. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(1):126&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26492103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, Chacon-Mikahil MP, Cavaglieri CR, Tricoli V, Roschel H, Vechin FC, et al. Effect of concurrent training with blood flow restriction in the elderly. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36(5):395&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijwel S, Backman M, Bolam KA, Olofsson E, Norrbom J, Bergh J, et al. Highly favorable physiological responses to concurrent resistance and high-intensity interval training during chemotherapy: the OptiTrain breast cancer trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2018;169(1):93&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29349712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5882634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach KA, Bagley JR. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy with concurrent exercise training: contrary evidence for an interference effect. Sports Med. 2016;46(8):1029&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26932769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC. Interference of strength development by simultaneously training for strength and endurance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1980;45(2&#x2013;3):255&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7193134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bartlett JD, Hanson ED, Stepto NK, Bishop DJ. Endurance training intensity does not mediate interference to maximal lower-body strength gain during short-term concurrent training. Front Physiol. 2016;7:487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27857692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5093324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bishop DJ, Stepto NK. Interference between concurrent resistance and endurance exercise: molecular bases and the role of individual training variables. Sports Med. 2014;44(6):743&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24728927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza EO, Tricoli V, Aoki MS, Roschel H, Brum PC, Bacurau AV, et al. Effects of concurrent strength and endurance training on genes related to myostatin signaling pathway and muscle fiber responses. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(11):3215&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza EO, Tricoli V, Roschel H, Brum PC, Bacurau AV, Ferreira JC, et al. Molecular adaptations to concurrent training. Int J Sports Med. 2013;34(3):207&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23044732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, Wilson SM, Loenneke JP, Anderson JC. Concurrent training: a meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(8):2293&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader GA. Concurrent strength and endurance training: from molecules to man. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(11):1965&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Laursen PB. High-intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle: part I: cardiopulmonary emphasis. Sports Med. 2013;43(5):313&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23539308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Laursen PB. High-intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle. Part II: anaerobic energy, neuromuscular load and practical applications. Sports Med. 2013;43(10):927&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23832851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Mendez-Villanueva A, Bishop D. Repeated-sprint ability&#x2014;part I: factors contributing to fatigue. Sports Med. 2011;41(8):673&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21780851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D, Girard O, Mendez-Villanueva A. Repeated-sprint ability&#x2014;part II: recommendations for training. Sports Med. 2011;41(9):741&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21846163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">21846163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Solheim JAB, Bencke J. Comparison of hamstring muscle activation during high-speed running and various hamstring strengthening exercises. Int J Sports Phys Therapy. 2017;12(5):718&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara A, Ono T, Kubota J, Okuwaki T, Fukubayashi T. Functional differences in the activity of the hamstring muscles with increasing running speed. J Sports Sci. 2010;28(10):1085&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20672221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller SM, Aguayo D, Zuercher M, Fleischmann O, Boutellier U, Auer M, et al. High-intensity interval training with vibration as rest intervals attenuates fiber atrophy and prevents decreases in anaerobic performance. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(2):e0116764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25679998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4332652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Smet S, Van Thienen R, Deldicque L, James R, Sale C, Bishop DJ, et al. Nitrate intake promotes shift in muscle fiber type composition during sprint interval training in hypoxia. Front Physiol. 2016;7:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27378942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4906611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn TA, Essen-Gustavsson B, Myburgh KH. Specific muscle adaptations in type II fibers after high-intensity interval training of well-trained runners. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21(6):765&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20492589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linossier MT, Denis C, Dormois D, Geyssant A, Lacour JR. Ergometric and metabolic adaptation to a 5-s sprint training programme. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1993;67(5):408&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8299612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linossier MT, Dormois D, Geyssant A, Denis C. Performance and fibre characteristics of human skeletal muscle during short sprint training and detraining on a cycle ergometer. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1997;75(6):491&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9202944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osawa Y, Azuma K, Tabata S, Katsukawa F, Ishida H, Oguma Y, et al. Effects of 16-week high-intensity interval training using upper and lower body ergometers on aerobic fitness and morphological changes in healthy men: a preliminary study. Open Access J Sports Med. 2014;5:257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25395872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4226445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, Gillen JB, Bellamy LM, McKay BR, Tarnopolsky MA, Gibala MJ, et al. Evidence for the contribution of muscle stem cells to nonhypertrophic skeletal muscle remodeling in humans. FASEB J. 2013;27(11):4596&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23928822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3804745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, McKay BR, Nederveen JP, Scribbans TD, Gurd BJ, Gillen JB, et al. Satellite cell activity, without expansion, after nonhypertrophic stimuli. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2015;309(9):R1101&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26333785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4666950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsitkanou S, Spengos K, Stasinaki AN, Zaras N, Bogdanis G, Papadimas G, et al. Effects of high-intensity interval cycling performed after resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(11):1317&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27659479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laird RHT, Elmer DJ, Barberio MD, Salom LP, Lee KA, Pascoe DD. Evaluation of performance improvements after either resistance training or sprint interval-based concurrent training. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(11):3057&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26950345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuchi N, Yoshida S, Okuyama M, Nakazato K. The effect of high-intensity interval cycling sprints subsequent to arm-curl exercise on upper-body muscle strength and hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(8):2318&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantrell GS, Schilling BK, Paquette MR, Murlasits Z. Maximal strength, power, and aerobic endurance adaptations to concurrent strength and sprint interval training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(4):763&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24390691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robineau J, Lacome M, Piscione J, Bigard X, Babault N. Concurrent training in rugby sevens: effects of high-intensity interval exercises. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(3):336&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27294374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robineau J, Babault N, Piscione J, Lacome M, Bigard AX. Specific training effects of concurrent aerobic and strength exercises depend on recovery duration. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(3):672&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25546450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross RE, Ratamess NA, Hoffman JR, Faigenbaum AD, Kang J, Chilakos A. The effects of treadmill sprint training and resistance training on maximal running velocity and power. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(2):385&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva RF, Cadore EL, Kothe G, Guedes M, Alberton CL, Pinto SS, et al. Concurrent training with different aerobic exercises. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33(8):627&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22562730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MJ, Ballantyne JK, Chagolla J, Hopkins WG, Fyfe JJ, Phillips SM, et al. Order of same-day concurrent training influences some indices of power development, but not strength, lean mass, or aerobic fitness in healthy, moderately-active men after 9 weeks of training. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(5):e0233134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32407361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7224562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Looney DP, Kraemer WJ, Joseph MF, Comstock BA, Denegar CR, Flanagan SD, et al. Electromyographical and perceptual responses to different resistance intensities in a squat protocol: does performing sets to failure with light loads produce the same activity? J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(3):792&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26270694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Ghigiarelli JJ, Sell KM, Shone EW, Kelly CF, Mangine GT. Muscle activation during resistance exercise at 70% and 90% 1-repetition maximum in resistance-trained men. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(3):505&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27935085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaulley GO, McBride JM, Cormie P, Hudson MB, Nuzzo JL, Quindry JC, et al. Acute hormonal and neuromuscular responses to hypertrophy, strength and power type resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;105(5):695&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19066934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Hoffman JR, Townsend JR, Jajtner AR, Boone CH, Beyer KS, et al. Intramuscular anabolic signaling and endocrine response following high volume and high intensity resistance exercise protocols in trained men. Physiol Rep. 2015;3(7):e12466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26197935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4552541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smilios I, Pilianidis T, Karamouzis M, Tokmakidis SP. Hormonal responses after various resistance exercise protocols. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(4):644&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12673149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(1&#x2013;2):50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptations to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20(5(Supplement)):S135&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3057313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtara M, Chaouachi A, Levin GT, Chaouachi M, Chamari K, Amri M, et al. Effect of concurrent endurance and circuit resistance training sequence on muscular strength and power development. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(4):1037&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobrega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs. Volitional interruption at high- and low-intensities on muscle mass and strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(1):162&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- versus high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estes RR, Malinowski A, Piacentini M, Thrush D, Salley E, Losey C, et al. The effect of high intensity interval run training on cross-sectional area of the vastus lateralis in untrained college students. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10(1):137&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28479954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5214170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>