<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41289064</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Efficacy of Various Exercise Types on Psychophysiological Outcomes in Colorectal Cancer Survivors: A Network Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>670</StartPage><EndPage>682</EndPage><MedlinePgn>670-682</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003900</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This network meta-analysis aimed to evaluate and rank the comparative efficacy of aerobic training (AT), resistance training (RT), combined AT and RT (CT), and high-intensity interval training (HIIT) primarily on body weight and secondarily on body mass index (BMI), fat-free mass, fasting glucose, fasting insulin, handgrip strength, physical activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, fatigue, quality of life, anxiety, depression, and exercise adherence in colorectal cancer (CRC) survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">MEDLINE/PubMed, Scopus, Web of Science, CENTRAL, and MedRxiv were searched for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) from inception up to July 1, 2025. RCTs published in English comparing exercise to controls (CON) or to another exercise type in CRC patients after colon resection surgery were qualified.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirty-two studies involving 2001 CRC survivors (51.3/48.7 male-female ratio; mean &#xb1; standard deviation: age, 58.0&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10.2 years; BMI, 27.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.9 kg&#xb7;m -2 ) were included. HIIT and CT were more effective than CON in improving cardiorespiratory fitness and fasting insulin, respectively. No exercise type was identified as being more efficacious than CON in improving any other outcome measures. Nevertheless, HIIT had the highest probability of being the best exercise intervention for improving body weight, physical activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, and quality of life. AT had the highest likelihood of reducing BMI, fasting glucose, and anxiety. CT had the highest probability of improving fasting insulin, fatigue, depression, and exercise adherence, while RT showed the highest probability of being the most effective exercise type in increasing handgrip strength and fat-free mass.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The current evidence indicates few confirmed benefits of exercise in CRC survivors, suggesting which types of exercise are most promising for a given psychophysiological outcome and may inform further large-scale RCTs of high methodological quality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Batrakoulis</LastName><ForeName>Alexios</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Science, University of Thessaly, Trikala, GREECE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Science, Democritus University of Thrace, Komotini, GREECE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perivoliotis</LastName><ForeName>Konstantinos</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, General Hospital of Volos, Volos, GREECE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Courneya</LastName><ForeName>Kerry S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, Sport, and Recreation, College of Health Sciences, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta, CANADA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmitz</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn H</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwartz</LastName><ForeName>Anna L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Coleman Health, LLC., Parks, AZ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Mhanna</LastName><ForeName>Sameer Badri</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Global Health Research, Saveetha Medical College and Hospitals, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Chennai, INDIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan, MALAYSIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Higher Studies, Al-Qasim Green University, Babylon, IRAQ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liapis</LastName><ForeName>Nikolaos</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Thessaly, Larissa, GREECE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tzovaras</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University Hospital of Larissa, Larissa, GREECE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baloyiannis</LastName><ForeName>Ioannis</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University Hospital of Larissa, Larissa, GREECE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015179" MajorTopicYN="Y">Colorectal Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073116" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cancer Survivors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072599" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiorespiratory Fitness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="N">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071076" MajorTopicYN="N">Network Meta-Analysis as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001835" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Weight</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010349" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Compliance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AEROBIC EXERCISE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CONCURRENT TRAINING</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIGH-INTENSITY INTERVAL TRAINING</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NEOPLASM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RESISTANCE TRAINING</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41289064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-00950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fitzmaurice C, Abate D, Abbasi N, et al.; Global Burden of Disease Cancer Collaboration. Global, regional, and national cancer incidence, mortality, years of life lost, years lived with disability, and disability-adjusted life-years for 29 cancer groups, 1990 to 2017: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study. JAMA Oncol. 2019;5(12):1749&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71(3):209&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oruc Z, Kaplan MA. Effect of exercise on colorectal cancer prevention and treatment. World J Gastrointest Oncol. 2019;11(5):348&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puetz TW, Herring MP. Differential effects of exercise on cancer-related fatigue during and following treatment: a meta-analysis. Am J Prev Med. 2012;43(2):e1&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthaiah CA, Devaru NC, Shivakumar NH, R R, Madhunapantula SV. Vitamin D mitigates hyperglycemia-induced cognition decline in Danio rerio (zebrafish) through the activation of antioxidant mechanisms. Antioxidants (Basel). 2022;11(11):2114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone KM, Wiskemann J, et al. Exercise guidelines for cancer survivors: consensus statement from International Multidisciplinary Roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(11):2375&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toohey K, Hunter M, Paterson C, Murray T, Singh B. Clinical updates on the effects of high intensity interval training (HIIT) exercise in people diagnosed with cancer. A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2023;26(12):667&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Hayes SC, Spence RR, Steele ML, Millet GY, Gergele L. Exercise and colorectal cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise safety, feasibility and effectiveness. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2020;17(1):122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung Y, Chung J, Son H. Physical activity interventions for colorectal cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cancer Nurs. 2021;44(6):E414&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelosi AC, Rostirola GC, Pereira JS, et al. Remote and unsupervised exercise strategies for improving the physical activity of colorectal cancer patients: a meta-analysis. Healthcare (Basel). 2023;11(5):723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Vizcaino V, Cavero-Redondo I, Reina-Gutierrez S, et al. Comparative effects of different types of exercise on health-related quality of life during and after active cancer treatment: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2023;12(6):726&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(11):777&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. 2nd ed. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safizadeh F, Mandic M, Pulte D, Niedermaier T, Hoffmeister M, Brenner H. The underestimated impact of excess body weight on colorectal cancer risk: evidence from the UK Biobank cohort. Br J Cancer. 2023;129(5):829&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A, Jamurtas AZ, Metsios GS, et al. Comparative efficacy of 5 exercise types on cardiometabolic health in overweight and obese adults: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of 81 randomized controlled trials. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2022;15(6):e008243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovic J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hozo SP, Djulbegovic B, Hozo I. Estimating the mean and variance from the median, range, and the size of a sample. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2005;5:13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G. Indirect and mixed-treatment comparison, network, or multiple-treatments meta-analysis: many names, many benefits, many concerns for the next generation evidence synthesis tool. Res Synth Methods. 2012;3(2):80&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salanti G, Del Giovane C, Chaimani A, Caldwell DM, Higgins JP. Evaluating the quality of evidence from a network meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2014;9(7):e99682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S, Welton NJ, Caldwell DM, Ades AE. Checking consistency in mixed treatment comparison meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2010;29(7-8):932&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuya-Kanamori L, Barendregt JJ, Doi SAR. A new improved graphical and quantitative method for detecting bias in meta-analysis. Int J Evid Based Healthc. 2018;16(4):195&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn K-Y, Hur H, Kim D-H, et al. The effects of inpatient exercise therapy on the length of hospital stay in stages I&#x2013;III colon cancer patients: randomized controlled trial. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2013;28(5):643&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allgayer H, Nicolaus S, Schreiber S. Decreased interleukin-1 receptor antagonist response following moderate exercise in patients with colorectal carcinoma after primary treatment. Cancer Detect Prev. 2004;28(3):208&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allgayer H, Owen RW, Nair J, et al. Short-term moderate exercise programs reduce oxidative DNA damage as determined by high-performance liquid chromatography-electrospray ionization-mass spectrometry in patients with colorectal carcinoma following primary treatment. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2008;43(8):971&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Damjanov N, Courneya KS, et al. A randomized dose&#x2010;response trial of aerobic exercise and health&#x2010;related quality of life in colon cancer survivors. Psychooncology. 2018;27(4):1221&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Rhim AD, Manning SL, et al. Effects of exercise on circulating tumor cells among patients with resected stage I-III colon cancer. PLoS One. 2018;13(10):e0204875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Rickels MR, Troxel AB, et al. Dose&#x2013;response effects of exercise on insulin among colon cancer survivors. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2018;25(1):11&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Troxel AB, Ky B, et al. Dose-response effects of aerobic exercise among colon cancer survivors: a randomized phase II trial. Clin Colorectal Cancer. 2018;17(1):32&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Zemel BS, Troxel AB, et al. Dose&#x2013;response effects of aerobic exercise on body composition among colon cancer survivors: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Cancer. 2017;117(11):1614&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantarero-Villanueva I, Cuesta-Vargas AI, Lozano-Lozano M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Lao C, Fern&#xe1;ndez-P&#xe9;rez A, Galiano-Castillo N. Changes in pain and muscle architecture in colon cancer survivors after a lumbopelvic exercise program: a secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial. Pain Med. 2017;18(7):1366&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantarero-Villanueva I, Sanchez-Jimenez A, Galiano-Castillo N, Diaz-Rodriguez L, Martin-Martin L, Arroyo-Morales M. Effectiveness of lumbopelvic exercise in colon cancer survivors: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(8):1438&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen JF, Sundberg A, Osterkamp J, et al. Interval walking improves glycemic control and body composition after cancer treatment: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2019;104(9):3701&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courneya K, Friedenreich C, Quinney H, Fields A, Jones L, Fairey A. A randomized trial of exercise and quality of life in colorectal cancer survivors. Eur J Cancer Care. 2003;12(4):347&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courneya KS, Vardy JL, O&#x2019;Callaghan CJ, et al. Effects of a structured exercise program on physical activity and fitness in colon cancer survivors: one year feasibility results from the CHALLENGE trial. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2016;25(6):969&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devin JL, Jenkins DG, Sax AT, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness and body composition responses to different intensities and frequencies of exercise training in colorectal cancer survivors. Clin Colorectal Cancer. 2018;17(2):e269&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devin JL, Sax AT, Hughes GI, et al. The influence of high-intensity compared with moderate-intensity exercise training on cardiorespiratory fitness and body composition in colorectal cancer survivors: a randomised controlled trial. J Cancer Surviv. 2016;10(3):467&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang SH, Kang DW, Lee MK, et al. Changes in DNA methylation after 6&#x2010;week exercise training in colorectal cancer survivors: a preliminary study. Asia&#x2010;Pacific J Clin Oncol. 2022;18(1):52&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Lee MK, Lee DH, et al. Effects of a 12-week home-based exercise program on quality of life, psychological health, and the level of physical activity in colorectal cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Support Care Cancer. 2019;27(8):2933&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindred MM, Pinto BM, Dunsiger SI. Predictors of sedentary behavior among colorectal survivors. Support Care Cancer. 2019;27(6):2049&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindred MM, Pinto BM, Dunsiger SI. Association of body esteem with fitness and body fat among colorectal cancer survivors: secondary analyses from a randomized trial. Int J Behav Med. 2019;26(6):619&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DH, Kim JY, Lee MK, et al. Effects of a 12-week home-based exercise program on the level of physical activity, insulin, and cytokines in colorectal cancer survivors: a pilot study. Support Care Cancer. 2013;21(9):2537&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MK, Kim J-Y, Kim D-I, et al. Effect of home-based exercise intervention on fasting insulin and adipocytokines in colorectal cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Metabolism. 2017;76:23&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MK, Kim NK, Jeon JY. Effect of the 6-week home-based exercise program on physical activity level and physical fitness in colorectal cancer survivors: a randomized controlled pilot study. PLoS One. 2018;13(4):e0196220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Liu X. Incremental patient care program decreases anxiety, reduces depression and improves the quality of life in patients with colorectal cancer receiving adjuvant chemotherapy. Exp Ther Med. 2019;18(4):2789&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascherini G, Ringressi MN, Castizo-Olier J, et al. Preliminary results of an exercise program after laparoscopic resective colorectal cancer surgery in non-metastatic adenocarcinoma: a pilot study of a randomized control trial. Medicina (Kaunas). 2020;56(2):78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min J, An K-Y, Park H, et al. Postoperative inpatient exercise facilitates recovery after laparoscopic surgery in colorectal cancer patients: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Gastroenterol. 2023;23(1):127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraitis AM, Rose NB, Johnson AF, et al. Feasibility and acceptability of an mHealth, home-based exercise intervention in colorectal cancer survivors: a pilot randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2023;18(6):e0287152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen AP, Vinther A, Ragle A-M, et al. Physical exercise program to older frail patients receiving chemotherapy for colorectal cancer-feasibility and experiences from the GERICO study. J Geriatric Oncol. 2023;14(1):101382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Vulpen JK, Velthuis MJ, Steins Bisschop CN, et al. Effects of an exercise program in colon cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(5):767&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Waart H, Stuiver MM, van Harten WH, et al. Recruitment to and pilot results of the PACES randomized trial of physical exercise during adjuvant chemotherapy for colon cancer. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2018;33(1):29&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer CG, Tusscher MRT, de Roos BM, et al.; AMICO Consortium. Experiences of patients with metastatic colorectal cancer participating in a supervised exercise intervention during chemotherapy. Support Care Cancer. 2025;33(2):82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Yang S, Compton SLE, et al. Effect of resistance training on physical function during chemotherapy in colon cancer. JNCI Cancer Spectr. 2024;8(4):pkae058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caan BJ, Brown JC, Lee C, et al. Effect of home-based resistance training on chemotherapy relative dose intensity and tolerability in colon cancer: the FORCE randomized control trial. Cancer. 2024;130(10):1858&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Batrakoulis A, Norhayati MN, et al. Combined aerobic and resistance training improves body composition, alters cardiometabolic risk, and ameliorates cancer-related indicators in breast cancer patients and survivors with overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Sports Sci Med. 2024;23(2):366&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovannucci E, Michaud D. The role of obesity and related metabolic disturbances in cancers of the colon, prostate, and pancreas. Gastroenterology. 2007;132(6):2208&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirillo F, Catellani C, Sartori C, Lazzeroni P, Amarri S, Street ME. Obesity, insulin resistance, and colorectal cancer: could miRNA dysregulation play a role? Int J Mol Sci . 2019;20(12):2922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Batrakoulis A, Wan Ghazali WS, et al. Effects of combined aerobic and resistance training on glycemic control, blood pressure, inflammation, cardiorespiratory fitness and quality of life in patients with type 2 diabetes and overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2024;12:e17525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mhanna SB, Rocha-Rodriguesc S, Mohamed M, et al. Effects of combined aerobic exercise and diet on cardiometabolic health in patients with obesity and type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15(1):165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herranz-Gomez A, Cuenca-Martinez F, Suso-Marti L, et al. Effectiveness of HIIT in patients with cancer or cancer survivors: an umbrella and mapping review with meta-meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(11):1522&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A, Jamurtas AZ, Fatouros IG. High-intensity interval training in metabolic diseases: physiological adaptations. ACSM&#x2019;S Health Fit J. 2021;25(5):54&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu ZJ, Wang ZY, Gao HE, Zhou XF, Li FH. Impact of high-intensity interval training on cardiorespiratory fitness, body composition, physical fitness, and metabolic parameters in older adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Exp Gerontol. 2021;150:111345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassidy S, Thoma C, Houghton D, Trenell MI. High-intensity interval training: a review of its impact on glucose control and cardiometabolic health. Diabetologia. 2017;60(1):7&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirsasan R, Akbarzadeh M, Akbarzadeh S. Exercise and colorectal cancer: prevention and molecular mechanisms. Cancer Cell Int. 2022;22(1):247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misiag W, Piszczyk A, Szymanska-Chabowska A, Chabowski M. Physical activity and cancer care&#x2014;a review. Cancers (Basel). 2022;14(17):4154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A, Fatouros IG. Psychological adaptations to high-intensity interval training in overweight and obese adults: a topical review. Sports (Basel). 2022;10(5):64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Madaan V, Petty FD. Exercise for mental health. Prim Care Companion J Clin Psychiatry. 2006;8(2):106.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>