<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">18823166</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0735-7044</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>122</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Behavioral neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Behav Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hippocampal response patterns during discriminative eyeblink/jaw movement conditioning in the rabbit.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1087</StartPage><EndPage>1099</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1087-99</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1037/a0012892</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rabbits were given concurrent training in eyeblink (EB) and jaw movement (JM) conditioning in which 1 tone predicted an airpuff and another tone predicted water. After 10 days of discrimination training, the animals were given 10 days of reversal training. In the discrimination phase, acquisition of the 2 conditioned responses was not significantly different; however JM discrimination errors were much more frequent than were EB errors. In the reversal phase, correct performance on EB trials increased gradually, as was expected, whereas there was immediate behavioral reversal on JM trials. Differences in size and topography of dorsal CA1 multiple-unit responses reflected the ability of the hippocampus to discriminate between stimuli in trained animals, corresponding to the performance of the behavioral discrimination. During JM trials, the rhythmicity of the neural response was further modulated by the type of the prior trial, suggesting the coding of sequential events by the hippocampus. Thus, hippocampal conditioned activity can rapidly change its magnitude and pattern depending on the specific trial type during a concurrent EB/JM discrimination task and its reversal. (PsycINFO Database Record (c) 2008 APA, all rights reserved).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mauldin</LastName><ForeName>Kristin N</ForeName><Initials>KN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Miami University, Oxford, OH 45056, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griffin</LastName><ForeName>Amy L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliver</LastName><ForeName>Celia G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berry</LastName><ForeName>Stephen D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R15 DE012248</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DE012248</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Behav Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8302411</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0735-7044</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001522" MajorTopicYN="N">Behavior, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001767" MajorTopicYN="N">Blinking</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003214" MajorTopicYN="N">Conditioning, Classical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004193" MajorTopicYN="N">Discrimination Learning</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006624" MajorTopicYN="N">Hippocampus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007568" MajorTopicYN="N">Jaw</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="Y">innervation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009068" MajorTopicYN="N">Movement</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010812" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Stimulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011817" MajorTopicYN="N">Rabbits</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18823166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS59363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2559961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0012892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2008-13280-009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asaka Y, Seager MA, Griffin AL, Berry SD. Medial septal microinfusion of scopolamine disrupts hippocampal activity and trace jaw movement conditioning. Behavioral neuroscience. 2000;114(6):1068&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11142639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger TW, Alger B, Thompson RF. Neuronal substrate of classical conditioning in the hippocampus. Science. 1976;192(4238):483&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1257783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger TW, Orr WB. Hippocampectomy selectively disrupts discrimination reversal conditioning of the rabbit nictitating membrane response. Behavioural brain research. 1983;8(1):49&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6849679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger TW, Rinaldi PC, Weisz DJ, Thompson RF. Single-unit analysis of different hippocampal cell types during classical conditioning of the rabbit nictitating membrane response. Journal of Neurophysiology. 1983;50:1197&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6644367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger TW, Thompson RF. Neuronal plasticity in the limbic system during classical conditioning of the rabbit nictitating membrane response. I. The hippocampus. Brain research. 1978;145(2):323&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">638791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry SD, Swain RA. Water deprivation optimizes hippocampal activity and facilitates nictitating membrane conditioning. Behavioral neuroscience. 1989;103(1):71&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2923678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgnis RL, Seager MA, Berry SD. Differential learning-related activity of hippocampal single units during classical conditioning in the rabbit. Society for Neuroscience Abstracts. 1995;21:1931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgnis RL, Seager MA, Berry SD. Hippocampal units change phase relation to local slow wave during rabbit classical conditioning. Society for Neuroscience Abstracts. 1996;22(1):431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colman SR, Patterson MM, Gormezano I. Conditioned jaw movement in the rabbit: Deprivation procedure and saccharin concentration. Psychonomic Science. 1966;6:39&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deadwyler SA, West MO, Christian EP, Hampson RE, Foster TC. Sequence-related changes in sensory-evoked potentials in the dentate gyrus: a mechanism for item-specific short-term information storage in the hippocampus. Behavioral and neural biology. 1985;44(2):201&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4062774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disterhoft JF, Segal M. Neuron activity in rat hippocampus and motor cortex during discrimination reversal. Brain research bulletin. 1978;3(6):583&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">318180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichenbaum H, Dudchenko P, Wood E, Shapiro M, Tanila H. The hippocampus, memory, and place cells: is it spatial memory or a memory space? Neuron. 1999;23(2):209&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10399928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fishbein HD, LeBlanc M. Human eyelid conditioning as a function of interstimulus interval. Journal of Experimental Psychology. 1967;75(1):130&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6065828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman JH, Jr, Cuppernell C, Flannery K, Gabriel M. Context-specific multisite cingulate cortical, limbic thalamic, and hippocampal neuronal activity during concurrent discriminative approach and avoidance training in rabbits. Journal of Neuroscience. 1996;16(4):1538&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6578549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8778303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gormezano I, Prokasy WF, Thompson RF. Classical Conditioning. Hillsdale, N.J.: L. Erlbaum Associates; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gormezano I, Schneiderman N, Deaux E, Fuentes I. Nictitating membrane: classical conditioning and extinction in the albino rabbit. Science. 1962;138:33&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13900561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin AL, Berry SD. Inactivation of the anterior cingulate cortex impairs extinction of rabbit jaw movement conditioning and prevents extinction-related inhibition of hippocampal activity. Learning &amp; memory. 2004;11(5):604&#x2013;610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC523079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15466315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossberg S. A neural model of attention, reinforcement and discrimination learning. International review of neurobiology. 1975;18:263&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1107246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huff KD, Asaka Y, Griffin AL, Berg WP, Seager MA, Berry SD. Differential mastication kinematics of the rabbit in response to food and water: implications for conditioned movement. Integrative physiological and behavioral science: the official journal of the Pavlovian Society. 2004;39(1):16&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15379379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllister WR. Eyelid conditioning as a function of the CS-US interval. Journal of Experimental Psychology. 1953;45(6):417&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13052882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEchron MD, Disterhoft JF. Hippocampal encoding of non-spatial trace conditioning. Hippocampus. 1999;9(4):385&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10495020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DP, Steinmetz JE. Hippocampal activity during classical discrimination--reversal eyeblink conditioning in rabbits. Behavioral neuroscience. 1997;111(1):70&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9109625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell DS, Gormezano I. Effects of water deprivation on classical appetitive conditioning of the rabbit's jaw movement response. Learning and Motivation. 1970;1:199&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olds J. Unit recordings during Pavlovian conditioning. UCLA forum in medical sciences. 1975;18:343&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1198715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver CG, Swain RA, Berry SD. Hippocampal plasticity during jaw movement conditioning in the rabbit. Brain research. 1993;608(1):150&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8495339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr WB, Berger TW. Hippocampectomy disrupts the topography of conditioned nictitating membrane responses during reversal learning. Behavioral neuroscience. 1985;99(1):35&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4041232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scavio MJ., Jr Classical-classical transfer: effects of prior aversive conditioning upon appetitive conditioning in rabbits (Oryctolagus cuniculus) Journal of comparative and physiological psychology. 1974;86(1):107&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4809966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scavio MJ, Gormezano I. Classical-classical transfer: effects of prior appetitive conditioning upon aversive conditioning in rabbits. Animal Learning and Behavior. 1980;8(2):218&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmajuk NA, DiCarlo JJ. A neural network approach to hippocampal function in classical conditioning. Behavioral neuroscience. 1991;105(1):82&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2025396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneiderman N, Gormezano I. Conditioning of the nictitating membrane of the rabbit as a function of CS-US interval. Journal of Comparative Physiological Psychology. 1964;57:188&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14168641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seager MA, Borgnis RL, Berry SD. Delayed acquisition of behavioral and hippocampal responses during jaw movement conditioning in aging rabbits. Neurobiology of aging. 1997;18(6):631&#x2013;639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9461061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal M, Olds J. Activity of units in the hippocampal circuit of the rat during differential classical conditioning. Journal of comparative and physiological psychology. 1973;82(2):195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4571893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheafor PJ, Gormezano I. Conditioning the rabbit's (Oryctolagus cuniculus) jaw-movement response: US magnitude effects on URs, CRs, and pseudo-CRs. Journal of comparative and physiological psychology. 1972;81(3):449&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4649185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Frank LM, Wirth S, Yanike M, Hu D, Kubota Y, Graybiel AM, Suzuki WA, Brown EN. Dynamic analysis of learning in behavioral experiments. Journal of Neuroscience. 2004;24(2):447&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14724243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spooner A, Kellogg WN. The Backward Conditioning Curve. The American Journal of Psychology. 1947;60(3):321&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20254693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmetz JE, Logue SF, Miller DP. Using signaled barpressing tasks to study the neural substrates of appetitive and aversive learning in rats: behavioral manipulations and cerebellar lesions. Behavioral neuroscience. 1993;107(6):941&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8136069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmetz JE. Brain substrates of classical eyeblink conditioning: a highly localized but also distributed system. Behavioural brain research. 2000;110(12):13&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10802300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RF. The neurobiology of learning and memory. Science. 1986;233(4767):941&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3738519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timofeeva NO, Kotlyar BI, Popovich LD. Analysis of the neuronal mechanism of conditioned-reflex switching. Neuroscience of Behavioral Physiology. 1984;14(2):146&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6328356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolman EC. A Psychological Model. In: Parsons Talcott, Shils Edward A., editors. Toward A General Theory of Reasoned Action. Cambridge: Harvard University Press; 1951. pp. 148&#x2013;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weible AP, O'Reilly JA, Weiss C, Disterhoft JF. Comparisons of dorsal and ventral hippocampus cornu ammonis region 1 pyramidal neuron activity during trace eyeblink conditioning in the rabbit. Neuroscience. 2006;141(3):1123&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16753261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weikart CL, Berger TW. Hippocampal lesions disrupt classical conditioning of cross-modality reversal learning of the rabbit nictitating membrane response. Behavioural brain research. 1986;22(1):85&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3790239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodruff-Pak DS, Steinmetz JE, editors. Eyeblink classical conditioning: Volume II: Animal models. Boston: Kluwer Academic Publishers; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyble BP, Hyman MH, Rossi CA, Hasselmo ME. Anaylsis of theta power in hippocampal EEG during bar pressing and running behavior in rats during distinct behavioral contexts. Hippocampus. 2004;14:662&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15301442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>