<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32091466</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of Periodization Models of Concurrent Training in Recreationally Active Postmenopausal Women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>977</StartPage><EndPage>983</EndPage><MedlinePgn>977-983</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003559</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Medeiros, LHL, Sandbakk, SB, Bertazone, TMA, and Bueno J&#xfa;nior, CR. Comparison of periodization models of concurrent training in recreationally active postmenopausal women. J Strength Cond Res 36(4): 977-983, 2022-Although concurrent training is the most effective way to improve both neuromuscular and cardiorespiratory functions in older populations, there are no studies in the literature comparing different periodization models on cardiorespiratory and muscle strength adaptations. Thus, the main objective of this study was to investigate the effects of different periodization models of concurrent aerobic and strength training using equalized training volume programs on muscle strength and cardiorespiratory fitness in recreationally active postmenopausal women. After 3 weeks of adaptation, 58 women aged 50-75 years were randomly assigned to (a) nonperiodization (NP), (b) daily nonlinear periodization (NLP), or (c) flexible daily NLP (FNLP). At baseline and after 12 weeks, aerobic fitness (peak oxygen uptake [V&#x307;o2peak] and the 6-minute walk test) and maximal muscle strength (1 repetition maximum of bench press and leg press) were measured. It was shown that maximal strength increased in the bench press (effect size [ES] 1.18 in NLP and 1.22 in FNLP) and leg press (ES 0.92 in NLP and 0.89 in FNLP) in the periodized groups-in the NP group, these values were 0.49 and 0.46, respectively. In the 6-minute walk test, aerobic fitness statistically improved in all groups-with an ES of 1.02 in the NP, 1.33 in the NLP, and 0.54 in the FNLP. This study showed that only periodization models (NLP and FNLP) induced a moderate ES in maximal strength, and all groups (NP, NLP, and FNLP) demonstrated improved aerobic fitness evaluated by V&#x307;o2peak and the 6-minute walk test in recreationally active postmenopausal women.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Medeiros</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo H L</ForeName><Initials>LHL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine (Ribeirao Preto Medical School), University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeirao Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sandbakk</LastName><ForeName>Silvana B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Circulation and Medical Imaging (Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences), Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bertazone</LastName><ForeName>Tha&#xed;s M A</ForeName><Initials>TMA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ribeirao Preto College of Nursing, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeirao Preto, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bueno J&#xfa;nior</LastName><ForeName>Carlos R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine (Ribeirao Preto Medical School), University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeirao Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ribeirao Preto College of Nursing, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeirao Preto, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport of Ribeirao Preto, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeirao Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Biological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postmenopause</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32091466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202204000-00014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ambrose AF, Paul G, Hausdorff JM. Risk factors for falls among older adults: A review of the literature. Maturitas 75: 51&#x2013;61, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine, Chodzko-Zajko WJ, Proctor DN, Fiatarone Singh MA, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 1510&#x2013;1530, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aral S, Nicolaides C. Exercise contagion in a global social network. Nat Commun 8: 14753, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazilian Association of Research Companies. Score system. In: Brazilian Criterion of Economic Classification. S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil: Brazilian Association of Research Companies S&#xe3;o Paulo, 2010. pp. 11-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Young JD, Whitten JHD, et al. Effectiveness of traditional strength vs. power training on muscle strength, power and speed with youth: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol 8: 423, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazil Ministry of Health. Food Surveillance System Protocols and Nutritional in Health Care. Bras&#xed;lia, Brazil: Brazil Ministry of Health, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito ADF, Oliveira CVC, Santos MDSB, Santos ADC. High-intensity exercise promotes postexercise hypotension greater than moderate intensity in elderly hypertensive individuals. Clin Physiol Funct Imag 34: 126&#x2013;132, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Pinto RS, Bottaro M, Izquierdo M. Strength and endurance training prescription in healthy and frail elderly. Aging Dis 5: 183&#x2013;195, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciconelli RM, Ferraz MB, Santos W, Mein&#xe3;o I, Quaresma MR. Tradu&#xe7;&#xe3;o para a l&#xed;ngua portuguesa e valida&#xe7;&#xe3;o do Question&#xe1;rio Gen&#xe9;rico de Avalia&#xe7;&#xe3;o da Qualidade de Vida SF-36 (BRASIL, SF-36). Rev Bras Reumatol 39: 143&#x2013;150, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Some issues in power analysis. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, MI: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 531&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun RJ, Gai CM, Walters J, et al. Comparison of powerlifting performance in trained men using traditional and flexible daily undulating periodization. J Strength Cond Res 31: 283&#x2013;291, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlon JA, Newton RU, Tufano JJ, et al. Periodization strategies in older adults: Impact on physical function and health. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 2426&#x2013;2436, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csapo R, Alegre L. Effects of resistance training with moderate vs heavy loads on muscle mass and strength in the elderly: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 26: 995&#x2013;1006, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBeliso M, Harris C, Spitzer-Gibson T, Adams K. A comparison of periodized and fixed repetition training protocol on strength in older adults. J Sci Med Sport 8: 190&#x2013;199, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunbar CC, Kalinski MI. Using RPE to regulate exercise intensity during a 20-week training program for postmenopausal women: A pilot study. Percept Mot Skills 99: 688&#x2013;690, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C. Monitoring training in athletes with reference to overtraining syndrome. Med Sci Sports Exerc 30: 1164&#x2013;1168, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas MC, Pereira CGS, Batista VC, et al. Effects of linear versus nonperiodized resistance training on isometric force and skeletal muscle mass adaptations in sarcopenic older adults. J Exerc Rehabil 15: 148&#x2013;154, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallal PC, Andersen LB, Bull FC, et al. Global physical activity levels: Surveillance progress, pitfalls, and prospects. Lancet 380: 247&#x2013;257, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallal PC, Victoria CG. Reliability and validity of the International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ). Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 556, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris C, Debeliso MA, Spitzer-Gibson TA, Adams KJ. The effect of resistance-training intensity on strength-gain response in the older adult. J Strength Cond Res 18: 833&#x2013;838, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CM, Griffiths PC, Mellalieu SD. Training load and fatigue marker associations with injury and illness: A systematic review of longitudinal studies. Sports Med 47: 1&#x2013;32, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knutzen KM, Brilla LR, Caine D. Validity of 1RM prediction equations for older adults. J Strength Cond Res 13: 242&#x2013;246, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: A practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol 4: 863, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makino T, Umegaki H, Cheng XW, et al. Effects of aerobic, resistance, or combined training on cognitive function in older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Alzheimers Dement 12: 819, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Dankel SJ, Buckner SL, et al. Periodization: What is it good for? J Trainol 5: 6&#x2013;12, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara JM, Stearne DJ. Flexible nonlinear periodization in a beginner college weight training class. J Strength Cond Res 24: 17&#x2013;22, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol 113: 71&#x2013;77, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietta-Dias C, Bello MD, Silva R, et al. Differential impact of endurance, strength, or combined training on quality of life and plasma serotonin in healthy older women. Aging Clin Exp Res 31: 1573&#x2013;1581, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, Cunha Nascimento D, Tibana RA, et al. Understanding the individual responsiveness to resistance training periodization. Age 37: 55, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauch JT, Ugrinowitsch C, Barakat CI, et al. Auto-regulated exercise selection training regimen produces small increases in lean body mass and maximal strength adaptations in strength-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1133&#x2013;1140, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymond MJ, Bramley-Tzerefos RE, Jeffs KJ, Winter A, Holland AE. Systematic review of high-intensity progressive resistance strength training of the lower limb compared with other intensities of strength training in older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 94: 1458&#x2013;1472, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alderman BL. A meta-analysis of periodized versus nonperiodized strength and power training programs. Res Q Exerc Sport 75: 413&#x2013;422, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res 18: 918&#x2013;920, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rikli RE, Jones CJ. Development and validation of a functional fitness test for community-residing older adults. J Aging Phys Act 7: 129&#x2013;161, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues SL, Baldo MP, Mill JG. Associa&#xe7;&#xe3;o entre a raz&#xe3;o cintura estatura e hipertens&#xe3;o e s&#xed;ndrome metab&#xf3;lica: Estudo de base populacional. Arq Bras Cardiol 95: 186&#x2013;191, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rognmo &#xd8;, Hetland E, Helgerud J, Hoff J, Sl&#xf8;rdahl SA. High intensity aerobic interval exercise is superior to moderate intensity exercise for increasing aerobic capacity in patients with coronary artery disease. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil 11: 216&#x2013;222, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Blair SN, Arena R, et al. Importance of assessing cardiorespiratory fitness in clinical practice: A case for fitness as a clinical vital sign: A scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation 135: 1851&#x2013;1867, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2857&#x2013;2872, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Holviala J, H&#xe4;kkinen A. Combined strength and endurance training improves health-related quality of life in healthy middle-aged and older adults. Int J Sports Med 33: 981&#x2013;986, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza EO, Tricoli V, Rauch J, et al. Different patterns in muscular strength and hypertrophy adaptations in untrained individuals undergoing nonperiodized and periodized strength regimens. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1238&#x2013;1244, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strohacker K, Fazzino D, Breslin WL, Xu X. The use of periodization in exercise prescriptions for inactive adults: A systematic review. Prev Med Rep 2: 385&#x2013;396, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarazona-Santabalbina FJ, G&#xf3;mez-Cabrera MC, P&#xe9;rez-Ros P, et al. A multicomponent exercise intervention that reverses frailty and improves cognition, emotion, and social networking in the community-dwelling frail elderly: A randomized clinical trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc 17: 426&#x2013;433, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volaklis KA, Halle M, Meisinger C. Muscular strength as a strong predictor of mortality: A narrative review. Eur J Intern Med 26: 303&#x2013;310, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JJE, Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36): I. Conceptual framework and item selection. Med Care 30: 473&#x2013;483, 1992.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>