<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">22389524</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-3711</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>97</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the experimental analysis of behavior</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exp Anal Behav</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a meaningful, a discriminative, and a meaningless stimulus on equivalence class formation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>163</StartPage><EndPage>181</EndPage><MedlinePgn>163-81</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1901/jeab.2012.97-163</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Thirty college students attempted to form three 3-node 5-member equivalence classes under the simultaneous protocol. After concurrent training of AB, BC, CD, and DE relations, all probes used to assess the emergence of symmetrical, transitive, and equivalence relations were presented for two test blocks. When the A-E stimuli were all abstract shapes, none of 10 participants formed classes. When the A, B, D, and E stimuli were abstract shapes and the C stimuli were meaningful pictures, 8 of 10 participants formed classes. This high yield may reflect the expansion of existing classes that consist of the associates of the meaningful stimuli, rather than the formation of the ABCDE classes, per se. When the A-E stimuli were abstract shapes and the C stimuli became S(D)s prior to class formation, 5 out of 10 participants formed classes. Thus, the discriminative functions served by the meaningful stimuli can account for some of the enhancement of class formation produced by the inclusion of a meaningful stimulus as a class member. A sorting task, which provided a secondary measure of class formation, indicated the formation of all three classes when the emergent relations probes indicated the same outcome. In contrast, the sorting test indicated "partial" class formation when the emergent relations test indicated no class formation. Finally, the effects of nodal distance on the relatedness of stimuli in the equivalence classes were not influenced by the functions served by the C stimuli in the equivalence classes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fields</LastName><ForeName>Lanny</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Queens College and the Graduate School of The City University of New York, Flushing, NY 11367, USA. lanny.fields@qc.cuny.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arntzen</LastName><ForeName>Erik</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nartey</LastName><ForeName>Richard K</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eilifsen</LastName><ForeName>Christoffer</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Exp Anal Behav</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0203727</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-5002</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032882" MajorTopicYN="N">Comprehension</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003210" MajorTopicYN="Y">Concept Formation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004192" MajorTopicYN="Y">Discrimination, Psychological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010775" MajorTopicYN="N">Photic Stimulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stimulus Equivalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acquired discriminative function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">college students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">comparison selection in matching to sample trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enhanced equivalence class formation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meaningfulness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nodal distance effects</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22389524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3292228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1901/jeab.2012.97-163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arntzen E. Probability of equivalence formation: familiar stimuli and training sequence. The Psychological Record. 2004;54:275&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arntzen E, Holth P. Differential probabilities of equivalence outcome in individual subjects as a function of training structure. The Psychological Record. 2000;50:603&#x2013;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arntzen E, Lian T. Trained and derived relations with pictures as nodes. The Psychological Record. 2010;60:659&#x2013;677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustson E.M, Dougher M.J. The transfer of avoidance functions through stimulus equivalence classes. The Journal of Behavior Therapy and Experimental Psychiatry. 1997;28:181&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9327297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes D, Browne M, Smeets P, Roche B. A transfer of functions and conditional transfer of functions through equivalence relations in three- to six-year-old children. The Psychological Record. 1995;45:405&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes D, Keenan M. A transfer of functions through derived arbitrary and nonarbitrary stimulus relations. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1993;59:61&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1322076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16812685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes-Holmes D, Barnes-Holmes Y, Stewart I, Boles S. A sketch of the implicit relational assessment procedure (IRAP) and the relational elaboration and coherence (REC) model. The Psychological Record. 2010;60:527&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belanich J, Fields L. Generalized equivalence classes as response transfer networks. The Psychological Record. 2003;53:373&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortoloti R, de Rose J.C. Assessment of the relatedness of equivalent stimuli through a semantic differential. The Psychological Record. 2009;59:563&#x2013;590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousfield W.A, Sedgewick C.H.W. An analysis of sequences of restricted associative responses. Journal of General Psychology. 1944;30:149&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buffington D.M, Fields L, Adams B.J. Enhancing the formation of equivalence classes by pretraining of other equivalence classes. The Psychological Record. 1997;47:120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Rose J.C, McIlvane W.J, Dube W.V, Galpin V.C, Stoddard L.T. Emergent simple discrimination established by indirect relation to differential consequences. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1988;50:1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1338837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3171472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickins D.W, Bentall R.P, Smith A.B. The role of individual stimulus names in the emergence of equivalence relations: The effects of interpolated paired-associates training of discordant associations between names. The Psychological Record. 1993;43:713&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L. The synthesis of complex categories from perceptual and equivalence classes: Effects of training and testing parameters. The European Journal of Behavior Analysis. 2009;10:205&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Adams B, Buffington D, Yang W, Verhave T. Response transfer between stimuli in generalized equivalence classes: A model for the establishment of natural kind and fuzzy superordinate categories. Psychological Record. 1996;46:665&#x2013;684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Hobbie-Reeve S.A, Adams B.J, Reeve K.F. Effects of training directionality and class size on equivalence class formation by adults. The Psychological Record. 1999;49:703&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Landon-Jimenez D.V, Buffington D.M, Adams B.J. Maintained nodal-distance effects in equivalence classes. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1995;64:129&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1350106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16812764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Moss P. Effects of contingency and nodal structure on stimulus relatedness in equivalence classes: History and Integration. European Journal of Behavior Analysis. 2007;8:141&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Reeve K.F. A methodological integration of generalized equivalence classes, natural categories, and cross modal perception. The Psychological Record. 2001;51:67&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Reeve K.F, Rosen D, Varelas A, Adams B.J, Belanich J, Hobbie S.A. Using the simultaneous protocol to study equivalence class formation: The facilitating effects of nodal number and size of previously established equivalence classes. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1997;67:367&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16812847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Varelas A, Reeve K.F, Belanich J, Wadhwa P, DeRosse P, Rosen D. Effects of prior conditional discrimination training, symmetry, transitivity, and equivalence testing on the emergence of new equivalence classes. The Psychological Record. 2000;50:443&#x2013;466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Verhave T. The structure of equivalence classes. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1987;48:317&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1338734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16812494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields L, Watanabe-Rose M. Nodal structure and the partitioning of equivalence classes. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2008;89:359&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2373765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18540220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaze J.A. The association values of nonsense syllables. Journal of Genetic Psychology. 1928;35:255&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galizio M, Stewart K.L, Pilgrim C. Typicality effects in contingency-shaped generalized equivalence classes. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2004;82:253&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1285010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15693522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grehan P.M. Depressed subjects' formation of mood congruent and incongruent equivalence relations. 1998. (Unpublished doctoral dissertation.) Hofstra University, Hempstead, New York.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall G. Exposure learning in animals. Psychological Bulletin. 1980;88:535&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holth P, Arntzen E. Stimulus familiarity and the delayed emergence of stimulus equivalence or consistent nonequivalence. The Psychological Record. 1998;48:81&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent H.G, Rosanoff A.J. A study of association in insanity. Part I. American Journal of Insanity. 1910;67:317&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane S.D, Clow J.K, Innis A, Critchfield T.S. Generalization of cross-modal stimulus equivalence classes: Operant processes as components in human category formation. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1998;70:267&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9821680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie J.C, Tierney K.J, Robinson C.P, Keenan M, Watt A, Barnes D. Differences between clinically anxious and non-anxious subjects in a stimulus equivalence training task involving threat words. The Psychological Record. 1993;43:153&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss-Lourenco P, Fields L. Nodal structure and stimulus relatedness in equivalence classes: post class formation preference tests. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2011;95:323&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3088076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21547071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moxon P.D, Keenan M, Hine L. Gender-role stereotyping and stimulus equivalence. The Psychological Record. 1993;43:381&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osgood C.E, Succi G.J, Tannenbaum P.H. The measurement of meaning. University of Illinois; Urbana: 1957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peoples M, Tierny K.J, Bracken M, Mackay C. Prior learning and equivalence class formation. The Psychological Record. 1998;48:111&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plaud J.J. The formation of stimulus equivalences: Fear-relevant versus fear-irrelevant stimulus classes. The Psychological Record. 1995;45:207&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randell T, Remington B. Equivalence relations between visual stimuli: The functional role of naming. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1999;71:395&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16812902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehfeldt R.A, Hayes L.J. Untrained temporal differentiation and equivalence class formation. The Psychological Record. 1998;48:481&#x2013;510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehfeldt R.A, Root S. The generalization and long-term retention of equivalence relations in adults with mental retardation. The Psychological Record. 2004;54:173&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche B, Barnes-Holmes D, Smeets P.M, Barnes-Holmes Y, McGeady S. Contextual control over derived transformation of discriminative and sexual arousal functions. The Psychological Record. 2000;50:267&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche B, Barnes D, Smeets P.M. Incongruous stimulus pairing and conditional discrimination training: Effects on relational responding. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1997;68:143&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16812852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell B. The analysis of mind, by Bertrand Russell. Lecture X. Words and Meaning. George Allen &amp; Unwin; London: 1921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryle G. The Concept of Mind. Hutchinson; London: 1949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders R.L, Green G. The nonequivalence of behavioral and mathematical equivalence. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1992;57:227&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1323125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1573374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders R.R, Saunders K.J, Kirby K.C, Spradlin J.E. The merger and development of equivalence classes by unreinforced conditional selection of comparison stimuli. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1988;50:145&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1338864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3193052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders R.R, Wachter J.A, Spradlin J.E. Establishing auditory stimulus control over an eight-member equivalence class via conditional discrimination procedure. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1988;49:95&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1338829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3346622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidman M. Reading and auditory-visual equivalences. Journal of Speech and Hearing Research. 1971;14:5&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5550631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidman M. Equivalence relations and behavior: A research story. Author's Cooperative; Boston, MA: 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidman M, Kirk B, Willson-Morris M. Six member stimulus classes generated by conditional-discrimination procedures. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1985;43:21&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1348093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3156941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidman M, Tailby W. Conditional discrimination vs. matching to sample: An expansion of the testing paradigm. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1982;37:5&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1333115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7057129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner B.F. Verbal behavior. Appleton-Century-Crofts; New York: 1957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer T.J, Chase P.N. Speed analyses of stimulus equivalence. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1996;65:643&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1349957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8636663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomanari G.Y, Sidman M, Rubio A.R, Dube W.V. Equivalence classes with requirements for short latencies. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2006;85:349&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1459849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16776056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyndall I.T, Roche B, James J.E. The relation between stimulus function and equivalence class formation. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2004;81:257&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15357509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyndall I.T, Roche B, James J.E. The interfering effect of emotional stimulus functions on stimulus equivalence class formation: Implications for the understanding and treatment of anxiety. European Journal of Behavior Analysis. 2009;10:121&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt A, Keenan M, Barnes D, Cairns E. Social categorization and stimulus equivalence. The Psychological Record. 1991;41:33&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth O, Chase P.N. Stability of functional equivalence and stimulus equivalence: Effects of baseline reversals. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2002;77:29&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11831781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>