<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27990224</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Relationship Between Aerobic and Anaerobic Performance in Recreational Runners.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>625</StartPage><EndPage>634</EndPage><MedlinePgn>625-634</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Research has indicated that combined aerobic and anaerobic training (concurrent training) may improve aerobic performance greater than aerobic training alone. The purpose of this investigation was to establish any associations between aerobic and anaerobic performance. Eleven participants (n = 11, age = 34.1 &#xb1; 13 years, VO<sub>2max</sub> = 58.4 &#xb1; 7.8) volunteered for this study. Participants were asked for endurance training experience (4.7 &#xb1; 3.7 years) and resistance training experience (4.1 &#xb1; 4.6 years). To meet training status, participants were to have a VO<sub>2max</sub> in the 80<sup>th</sup> percentile as per ACSM guidelines. The Bruce treadmill test was used to measure aerobic performance. In order to measure anaerobic performance, several tests were completed utilizing a force platform. A Pearson Product R Correlation Coefficient was calculated to determine correlations between variables. The results show significant correlation between VO<sub>2max</sub> and RFD (r = 0.68). Further analyses utilizing Cohen's effect size indicated a strong association between VO<sub>2max</sub> and peak force, as well as running efficiency and peak power, relative peak power, and power endurance. These results indicate an existing possibility that anaerobic performance measures such as RFD may have a positive relationship with aerobic performance measures such as VO<sub>2max</sub>. Therefore, it may be beneficial to integrate specific training components which focus on improving RFD as a method of improving running performance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillen</LastName><ForeName>Zachary M</ForeName><Initials>ZM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletic Training &amp; Exercise Physiology, Midwestern State University, Wichita Falls, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wyatt</LastName><ForeName>Frank B</ForeName><Initials>FB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletic Training &amp; Exercise Physiology, Midwestern State University, Wichita Falls, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Winchester</LastName><ForeName>Jason B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Therapy, University of the Incarnate Word, San Antonio, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Dalton A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletic Training &amp; Exercise Physiology, Midwestern State University, Wichita Falls, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghetia</LastName><ForeName>Vidhi</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletic Training &amp; Exercise Physiology, Midwestern State University, Wichita Falls, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">explosive-strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27990224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5154721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/KFOP9214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beaver WL, Wasserman K, Whipp BJ. A new method for detecting anaerobic threshold by gas exchange. J Appl Physiol. 1986;60(6):2020&#x2013;2027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3087938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckham G, Mizuguchi S, Carter C, Sato K, Ramsey M, Lamont H, Hornsby G, Haff G, Stone M. Relationships of isometric mid-thigh pull variables to weightlifting performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2013;53:573&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23903539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Luhtanen P, Komi PV. A Simple Method for Measurement of Mechanical Power in Jumping. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1983;50:273&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6681758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce RA. Exercise Testing of Patients with Coronary Heart Disease. Ann Clin Res. 1971;3:323&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5156892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlock JM, Sarah SL, Hartmann MJ, Morris RT, Ciroslan DA, Pierce KC, Newton RU, Harman EA, Sands WA, Stone MH. The Relationship Between Vertical Jump Power Estimates and Weightlifting Ability: A Field-Test Approach. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(3):534&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben W, Flanagan E, Jensen R. Gender Similarities in Rate of Force Development and Time to Takeoff During the Countermovement Jump. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2007;10(6):10&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaskill SE, Ruby BC, Walker AJ, Sanchez OA, Serfass RC, Leon AS. Validity and reliability of combining three methods to determine ventilatory threshold. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(11):1841&#x2013;1848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11689733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlin MJ, Draper N, Blackwell G, Shearman JP, Kimber NE. Determination of Maximal Oxygen Uptake Using the Bruce or a Novel Athlete-Led Protocol in a Mixed Population. J Hum Kinet. 2012;31:97&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23486694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazir T, Kosar NS. Assessment of gender differences in maximal anaerobic power by ratio scaling and allometric scaling. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2007;15:253&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennessy LC, Watson AWS. The Interference Effects of Training for Strength and Endurance Simultaneously. J Strength Cond Res. 1994;8(1):12&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff J, Gran A, Helgerud J. Maximal strength training improves aerobic endurance performance. Scan J Med Sci Sports. 2002;12:288&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12383074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopker J, Jobson S, Carter H, Passfield L. Cycling efficiency in trained male and female competitive cyclists. J Sports Sci Med. 2010;9:332&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. A New View of Statistics. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RE, Quinn TJ, Kertzer R, Vroman NB. Strength Training in Female Distance Runners: Impact on Running Economy. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(4):224&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung AP. The Impact of Resistance Training on Distance Running Performance. Sports Med. 2003;33(7):539&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12762828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamori N, Haff GG. The Optimal Training Load for the Development of Muscular Power. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(3):675&#x2013;684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamori N, Rossi SJ, Justice BD, Haff EE, Pistilli EE, O&#x2019;Bryant HS, Stone MH, Haff GG. Peak Force and Rate of Force Development During Isometric and Dynamic Mid-Thigh Clean Pulls Performed at Various Intensities. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):483&#x2013;491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keir DA, Zory R, Boudreau-Lariviere C, Serresse O. Mechanical Efficiency of Treadmill Running Exercise: Effect of Anaerobic-Energy Contribution at Various Speeds. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2012;7:382&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22868489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibele A. Possible errors in the comparative evaluation of drop jumps from different heights. Ergonomics. 1999;42(7):1011&#x2013;1014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10424188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthorne NP. Analysis of standing vertical jumps using a force platform. Am J Phys. 2001;69(11):1198&#x2013;1204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd BB, Zacks RM. The Mechanical Efficiency of Treadmill Running Against a Horizontal Impeding Force. J Physiol. 1972;223:355&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1331451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5039278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midgley AW, McNaughton LR, Jones AM. Training to Enhance the Physiological Determinants of Long-Distance Running Performance. Sports Med. 2007;37(10):857&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17887811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkola J, Vesterinen V, Taipale R, Capostagno B, Hakkinen K, Nummela A. Effect of resistance training regimens on treadmill running and neuromuscular performance in recreational endurance runners. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(13):1359&#x2013;1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21854344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakao M, Inoue Y, Murakami H. Longitudinal study of the effect of high intensity weight training on aerobic capacity. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1995;70:20&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7729434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paavolainen L, Hakkinen K, Hamalainen I, Nummela A, Rusko H. Explosive-strength training improves 5-km running time by improving running economy and muscle power. J Appl Physiol. 1999;86(5):1527&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10233114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng HT. Changes in Biomechanical Properties during Drop Jumps of Incremental Height. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(9):2510&#x2013;2518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21869631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Gomez J, Rodriguez GV, Ara I, Olmedillas H, Chavarren J, Gonzales-Henriquez JJ, Dorado C, Calbet JAL. Role of muscle mass on sprint performance: gender differences? Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102:685&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18084774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers SK, Howley ET. Exercise Physiology: Theory and Application to Fitness and Performance. Seventh Edition ed. New York, NY: McGraw-Hill Publishing Company; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands WA, McNeal JR, Ochi MT, Urbanek TL, Jemni M, Stone MH. Comparison of the Wingate and Bosco Anaerobic Tests. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(4):810&#x2013;815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders PU, Pyne DB, Telford RD, Hawley JA. Factors Affecting Running Economy in Trained Distance Runners. Sports Med. 2004;34(7):465&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15233599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Sands WA, Pierce KC, Carlock J, Cardinale M, Newton RU. Relationship of Maximum Strength to Weightlifting Performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(6):1037&#x2013;1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Swensen T. Impact of Resistance Training on Endurance Performace: A New Form of Cross-Training? Sports Med. 1998;25(3):191&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9554029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theurel J, Crepin M, Foissac M, Temprado JJ. Effects of different pedalling techniques on muscle fatigue and mechanical efficiency during prolonged cycling. Scan J Med Sci Sports. 2012;22:714&#x2013;721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21507064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR, Gordon NF, Pescatello LS. ACSM&#x2019;s Guildelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Williams; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto LM, Lopez RM, Klau JF, Casa DJ, Kraemer WJ, Maresh CM. The Effects of Resistance Training on Endurance Distance Running Performance Among Highly Trained Runners: A Systematic Review. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(6):2036&#x2013;2044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>