<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39281245</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1682-024X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pakistan journal of medical sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pak J Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of concurrent training on glycemic and vascular parameters among patients with T2DM-associated Peripheral Artery Disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1613</StartPage><EndPage>1618</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1613-1618</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12669/pjms.40.8.9045</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate the effects of CT to improve HbA1C and ABI among the T2DM-associated PAD population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A randomized, single-blinded, two-arm trial was conducted at the Department of Rehabilitation Sciences of Dr. Ziauddin Hospital in Karachi between July to September 2023. A total of 80 T2DM-associated PAD patients were included and randomly divided into Experimental Group (n=40) and Control Group (n=40), using the sealed envelope method. Experimental group patients received Concurrent Training (CT), whereas Control Group patients underwent Aerobic Training (AT) for 12 weeks. Both groups received thirty-minute sessions three times a week that was progressed to 60 minutes over 12 weeks. HbA1C and ABI were measured at baseline and after 12 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Analysis revealed an average age of 46.75&#xb1;3.59 and the duration of T2DM for developing PAD is 14.82&#xb1;2.23 on average. Findings revealed that both training groups were significantly effective (p&lt;0.000) at 95% CI in improving glycemic and vascular parameters after 12 weeks. Subsequently, findings showed that the CT group showed more significant improvement than AT group in improving HbA1C for glycemic control (p=0.002, CT: pre: 9.53&#xb1;1.406, post: 7.81&#xb1;0.81, AT: pre: 8.74&#xb1;0.908, post: 8.15&#xb1;0.83) and ABI for systemic blood flow (p=0.0001, CT: pre: 0.84&#xb1;0.03, post: 0.94&#xb1;0.03, AT: pre: 0.82&#xb1;0.02, post: 0.86&#xb1;0.02).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">CT showed a two-fold improvement in glycemic control and arterial blood flow than AT group, which represents that CT is an effective therapeutic approach for T2DM-associated Fontain's stage IIa PAD rehabilitation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Pakistan Journal of Medical Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amin</LastName><ForeName>Uroosa</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Uroosa Amin, Ziauddin College of Rehabilitation Sciences, Ziauddin University, Khayaban-e-Saadi Road, Boat Basin, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adnan</LastName><ForeName>Qurat-Ul-Ain</ForeName><Initials>QU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qurat-ul-Ain Adnan, PhD (Scholar) Vice Principal, Assistant Professor, Ziauddin College of Rehabilitation Sciences, Ziauddin University, Khayaban-e-Saadi Road, Boat Basin, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Tauseef</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Tauseef Ahmad, FCPS Ziauddin Hospital, Clifton, Block-5, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Pakistan</Country><MedlineTA>Pak J Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100913117</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1681-715X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ankle-brachial Indices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetic vascular Complication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glycated Hemoglobin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Peripheral Artery Disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39281245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11395383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12669/pjms.40.8.9045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PJMS-40-1613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Home, Resources, diabetes L with, Acknowledgement, FAQs, Contact etal. IDF Diabetes Atlas 2021 |IDF Diabetes Atlas [Internet. IDF Diabetes Atlas. 2021.  Available from: https://diabetesatlas.org/atlas/tenth-edition/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding JL, Pavkov ME, Magliano DJ, Shaw JE, Gregg EW. Global trends in diabetes complications:a review of current evidence. Diabetologia. 2019;62:3&#x2013;16. doi:10.1007/s00125-018-4711-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30171279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghighatpanah M, Nejad AS, Haghighatpanah M, Thunga G, Mallayasamy S. Factors that correlate with poor glycemic control in Type-2 diabetes mellitus patients with complications. Osong PHRP. 2018;9(4):167. doi:10.24171%2Fj.phrp.2018.9.4.05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6110332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30159222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makizako H, Shimada H, Doi T, Tsutsumimoto K, Hotta R, Nakakubo S, et al. Social frailty leads to the development of physical frailty among physically non-frail adults:a four-year follow-up longitudinal cohort study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15(3):490. doi:10.3390/ijerph15030490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5877035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29534470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant PJ, Cosentino F. The 2019 ESC Guidelines on diabetes, pre-diabetes, and cardiovascular diseases developed in collaboration with the EASD:New features and the 'Ten Commandments'of the 2019 Guidelines are discussed by Professor Peter J. Grant and Professor Francesco Cosentino, the Task Force chairmen. 2019;40(39):3215&#x2013;3217. doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehz687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31608951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uddin F, Ali B, Junaid N. Prevalence of diabetic complications in newly diagnosed Type-2 diabetes patients in Pakistan:findings from national registry. J Ayub Med Coll Abbottabad. 2019;30(4-Sup):S652&#x2013;S658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30838825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu J, Santulli G. Update on peripheral artery disease:Epidemiology and evidence-based facts. Atherosclerosis. 2018;275:379&#x2013;381. doi:10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2018.05.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6113064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29843915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transcript Webinar 3. (n.d.). [online]  [[Accessed 29 Oct. 2022]].  Available at: https://www.heart.org/-/media/Files/Health-Topics/Peripheral-Artery-Disease/PAD-Webinars/Webinar-3-Exercise-Therapy-for-PAD-transcript.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shou Z, Zhao Y, Zhang Y, Li S. Risk factors for peripheral arterial disease in elderly patients with Type-2 diabetes mellitus:A clinical study. Pak J Med Sci. 2020;36(6):1344&#x2013;1348. doi:10.12669/pjms.36.6.2906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criqui MH, Matsushita K, Aboyans V, Hess CN, Hicks CW, Kwan TW, et al. Lower extremity peripheral artery disease:contemporary epidemiology, management gaps, and future directions:a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2021;144(9):e171&#x2013;191. doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9847212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naveed S, Ali Z, Nageen A, Ahmed SM, Fatima M, Zehra F. Relationship between ankle brachial index (ABI) and cardiovascular risk factors in diabetes Type-II. Pak Heart J. 2020;53(4) doi:10.47144/phj.v53i4.1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treat-Jacobson D, McDermott MM, Beckman JA, Burt MA, Creager MA, Ehrman JK, et al. Implementation of supervised exercise therapy for patients with symptomatic peripheral artery disease:a science advisory from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2019;140(13):e700&#x2013;e710. doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000000727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31446770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alni MA, Nikookheslat SD. The effect of 12 weeks aerobic, resistance and combined trainings on peripheral vascular disease in type 2 diabetes with peripheral neuropathy in men. Obes Med. 2022;34:100439. doi:10.1016/j.obmed.2022.100439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro DP, Ribeiro-Samora GA, Britto RR, Pereira DA. Effects of modified aerobic training on muscle metabolism in individuals with peripheral arterial disease:a randomized clinical trial. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):15966. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-52428-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6828812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31685913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelis N, Buys R, Dewit T, Benoit D, Claes J, Fourneau I, et al. Satisfaction and acceptability of telemonitored home-based exercise in patients with intermittent claudication:Pragmatic observational pilot study. JMIR rehab. Assist Technol. 2021;8(1):e18739. doi:10.2196/18739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33749616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motahari Rad M, Bijeh N, Attarzadeh Hosseini SR, Raouf Saeb A. The effect of two concurrent exercise modalities on serum concentrations of FGF21, irisin, follistatin, and myostatin in men with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Arch Physiol Biochem. 2023;129(2):424&#x2013;433. doi:10.1080/13813455.2020.1829649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazir A. Physiological Effects and Prescription of Exercise in Patients with Peripheral Artery Disease. Indo J Phys Med Rehab. 2021;10(01):11&#x2013;21. doi:10.36803/ijpmr.v10i1.279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogando PH, Silveira-Rodrigues JG, Melo BP, Campos BT, Silva AD, Barbosa EG, et al. Effects of high-and moderate-intensity resistance training sessions on glycemia of insulin-treated and non-insulin-treated type 2 diabetes mellitus individuals. Sport Sci. Health. 2023;19(2):625&#x2013;636. doi:10.1007/s11332-022-00931-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott MM, Dayanidhi S, Kosmac K, Saini S, Slysz J, Leeuwenburgh C, et al. Walking exercise therapy effects on lower extremity skeletal muscle in peripheral artery disease. Circ. Res. 2021 Jun 11;128(12):1851&#x2013;1867. doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.121.318242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ampuero DV, Lorca ME, Cantillana CC, P&#xe9;rez DV, Queiroz AC, dos Santos DA, et al. The effect of aerobic and concurrent training on cardiovascular and metabolic control in middle-aged type II diabetics. J Phys Educ. 2023;23(3):631&#x2013;636. doi:10.7752/jpes.2023.03078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabiei V, Nasiri S, Banitalebi E. The Effects of Sprint Interval and Concurrent Trainings on eGDR Factor in Overweight Females with Type 2 Diabetes. J Exer Physiol Health J. 2019;2(1):18&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coll-Risco I, Borges-Cosic M, Acosta-Manzano P, Camiletti-Moir&#xf3;n D, Aranda P, Aparicio VA. Effects of concurrent exercise on cardiometabolic status during perimenopause:the FLAMENCO Project. Climacteric. 2018;21(6):559&#x2013;565. doi:10.1080/13697137.2018.1526892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30392388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondash ME, Ananthakumar A, Khodabukus A, Bursac N, Truskey GA. Glucose uptake and insulin response in tissue-engineered human skeletal muscle. J Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2020;17:801&#x2013;813. doi:10.1007/s13770-020-00242-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7710786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merz KE, Thurmond DC. Role of skeletal muscle in insulin resistance and glucose uptake. Compr. Physiol. 2011;10(3):785&#x2013;809. doi:10.1002/cphy.c190029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8074531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agner VF, Garcia MC, Taffarel AA, Mour&#xe3;o CB, da Silva IP, da Silva SP, et al. Effects of concurrent training on muscle strength in older adults with metabolic syndrome:A randomized controlled clinical trial. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2018;75:158&#x2013;164. doi:10.1016/j.archger.2017.12.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29306767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>