<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23487247</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>29A</Volume><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Energy expenditure combining strength and aerobic training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>21</StartPage><EndPage>25</EndPage><MedlinePgn>21-5</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/v10078-011-0054-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The combination of Strength Training (ST) with Aerobic Training (AT) exercises in the same training session, which commonly appears in literature as the concurrent training, is widely used in fitness and physical condition programs, especially when the aim is to increase the energy expenditure during and after training session. The aim of this study was to identify, through literature, whether the combination of exercises of the ST with exercises of the AT allows changes in body composition and energy expenditure during and after the training session. Chronic studies have showed a positive effect on body composition (decreased in relative body fat) when the ST are combined with AT. Similarly, the acute effects of the order of combining these two types of exercise does not seem to affect energy expenditure, measured by oxygen consumption (VO2), during the training session and only change this expenditure in the first 15 minutes after the training session. In conclusion, we can say that the studies indicate that the combination of exercises of the ST with exercises of the AT has a positive effect on changes in body composition, and energy expenditure during and after training sessions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vila&#xe7;a</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Exercise and Health, University of Tr&#xe1;s-os-Montes and Alto Douro (UTAD), Vila Real, Portugal ; Research Centre for Sport Sciences, Health and Human Development (CIDESD), Vila Real, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bottaro</LastName><ForeName>Martim</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santos</LastName><ForeName>Catarina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy expenditure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxygen consumption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/v10078-011-0054-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jhk-29a-21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Balabinis C, Psarakis C, Moukas M, Vassiliou M, Behrakis P. Early phase changes by concurrent endurance and strength training. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2003;17(2):393&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnley M, Jones A, Carter H, Doust J. Effects of prior exercise and recovery duration on oxygen uptake kinetics during heavy exercise. J Sports Sci. 2001;19:628&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11429659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis J, Tung A, Chak S, Ventura E, Byrd-Williams C, Alexander K, Lane C, Weigensberg M, Spruijt-Metz D, Goran M. Aerobic and Strength Training Reduces Adiposity in Overweight Latina Adolescents. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(7):1494&#x2013;1503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2836768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19516150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolezal B, Potteiger J. Concurrent resistance and endurance training influence basal metabolic rate in nondieting individuals. J. Appl. Physiol. 1998;85(2):695&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond M, Vehrs P, Schaalje G, Parcell A. Aerobic and resistance exercise sequence affects excess postexercise oxygen consumption. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2005;19(2):332&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuba Y, Hayashi N, Koga S, Yoshida T. VO2 kinetics in heavy exercise is not altered by prior exercise with a different muscle group. J. Appl. Physiol. 2002;92:2467&#x2013;2474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12015361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerbino A, Ward S, Whipp B. Effects of prior exercise on pulmonary gas-exchange kinetics during high-intensity exercise in humans. J. Appl. Physiol. 1996;80:99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8847338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson J, Wilmore J, Buono M, Constable S. Energy cost of weight training exercise. National Strength and conditioning Journal. 1994. Nov 22&#x2013;23,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Rashti S, Tranchina C, Ratamess N, Faigenbaum A, Hoffman J. Effect of preceding resistance exercise on metabolism during subsequent aerobic session. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19504118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppo K, Bouckaert J. In humans the oxygen uptake slow component is reduced by prior exercise of high as well as low intensity. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2000;83:559&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11192065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemos A, Sim&#xe3;o R, Polito M, Salles B, Rhea MR, Alexander J. The acute influence of two intensities of aerobic exercise on strength training performance in elderly women. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:1252&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lira F, Oliveira R, Julio V, Franchini E. Consumo de oxig&#xe9;nio p&#xf3;s-exerc&#xed;cio de for&#xe7;a e aer&#xf3;bio: efeito da ordem de execu&#xe7;&#xe3;o. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2007;13(6):402&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray R, Harrell J, Bangdiwala S, Deng S, Baggett C. Factors contributing to the energy expenditure of youth during cycling and running. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2003;15:67&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melanson E, Sharp T, Seagle H, Horton T, Donahoo W, Grunwald G, Hamilton J, Hill J. Effect of exercise intensity on 24 h energy expenditure and nutrient oxidation. J. Appl. Physiol. 2002;92:1045&#x2013;1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11842038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro A, Alveno D, Prado M, Monteiro G, Ugrinowitsch C, Aoki M, Pi&#xe7;arro I. Acute physiological responses to different circuit training protocols. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2008;48:438&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheuermann B, Hoelting B, Noble M, Barstow T. The slow component of O2 uptake is not accompanied by changes in muscle EMG during repeated bouts of heavy exercise in humans. Journal Physiology. 2001;531:245&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11179407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedlock D. Post-exercise energy expenditure after cycle ergometer and treadmill exercise. J. Appl. Sport Sci. Res. 1992;6(1):19&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E, Laaksonen D, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Karavirta, Jensen B, Kraemer W, Nyman K, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Body composition, fitness, and metabolic health during strength and endurance training and their combination in middle-aged and older women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:285&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19266214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahrlich V, Anjos L. Aspectos hist&#xf3;ricos e metodol&#xf3;gicos da medi&#xe7;&#xe3;o e estimativa da taxa metab&#xf3;lica basal: uma revis&#xe3;o da literatura. Cadernos de Sa&#xfa;de P&#xfa;blica, Rio de Janeiro. 2001;17(4):801&#x2013;817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11514862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Kamyia J, Hishimoto K. Are oxygen uptake kinetics at the onset of exercise speeded up by local metabolic status in active muscles? Eur J Appl Physiol. 1995;70:482&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7556119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>