<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40718012</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1643-8876</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Przeglad menopauzalny = Menopause review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Prz Menopauzalny</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Is concurrent training effective in the symptomatology of menopause, depression, sexual function, and the aging perspective of women during menopause? A randomised clinical trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>33</StartPage><EndPage>44</EndPage><MedlinePgn>33-44</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/pm.2025.150142</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To analyse the effect of concurrent training after 4 months of intervention compared to the control group on the symptomatology of menopause, symptoms of depression, sexual function, and aging perspective of women during menopause.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This is a randomized 2-arm clinical trial. A total of 42 menopausal women (53.21 &#xb1;3.65 years of age) were included. Questionnaires related to symptoms of menopause (menopause rating scale - MRS), depression (hospital anxiety and depression scale), sexual function (female sexual function index), and aging perspective (Sheppard inventory) were applied. Intention-to-treat and protocol adherence analysis were performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In the analysis by protocol, there was an improvement in menopausal symptoms in all domains of the MRS, specifically somatic symptoms (<i>p</i> = 0.001), psychological symptoms (<i>p</i> = 0.001), urogenital symptoms (<i>p</i> = 0.001), and total score (<i>p</i> = 0.001), as well as a reduction in depressive symptoms (<i>p</i> = 0.016). Additionally, improvements were observed in sexual function across 4 domains, including desire (<i>p</i> = 0.007), lubrication (<i>p</i> = 0.024), satisfaction (<i>p</i> = 0.030), and the overall sexual function score (<i>p</i> = 0.022). Furthermore, concerning the aspect of 'finitude', there was a significant improvement between groups in the domain of happiness (<i>p</i> = 0.046).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Concurrent training was shown to be effective for improving the symptomatology of menopause, depression, sexual function and happiness in menopause.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Termedia.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scarpel</LastName><ForeName>Cibele Medeiros</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity Leisure Research Laboratory, College of Health and Sport Science, Santa Catarina State University, Florianopolis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fausto</LastName><ForeName>Danielly Yani</ForeName><Initials>DY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity Leisure Research Laboratory, College of Health and Sport Science, Santa Catarina State University, Florianopolis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bocchi Martins</LastName><ForeName>Julia Beatriz</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity Leisure Research Laboratory, College of Health and Sport Science, Santa Catarina State University, Florianopolis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Azevedo Guimar&#xe3;es</LastName><ForeName>Adriana Coutinho</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity Leisure Research Laboratory, College of Health and Sport Science, Santa Catarina State University, Florianopolis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Prz Menopauzalny</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263235</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1643-8876</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depressive symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">female life changes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">senescence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sexual function</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40718012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12288491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/pm.2025.150142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Morardpour F, Koushkie Jahromi M, Fooladchang M, Rezaei R, Sayar Khorasani MR. Association between physical activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, and body composition with menopausal symptoms in early postmenopausal women. Menopause 2020; 27: 230-237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31999652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalo-Encabo P, McNeil J, Boyne DJ, Courneya KS, Friedenreich CM. Dose-response effects of exercise on bone mineral density and content in post-menopausal women. Scand J Med Sci Sport 2019; 29: 1121-1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaMonte MJ, Manson JAE, Chomistek AK, et al. Physical activity and incidence of heart failure in postmenopausal women. JACC Hear Fail 2018; 6: 983-995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6275092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Probo A, Soares N, Silva V, Cabral P. N&#xed;veis dos sintomas climat&#xe9;ricos em mulheres fisicamente ativas e insuficientemente ativas. Rev Bras Atividade F&#xed;sica Sa&#xfa;de 2016; 21: 246-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes IC, Oliveira Neto L de, Tavares VD de O, Duarte YA de O. Association between low level of physical activity and mobility limitation in older adults: evidence from the SABE study. Cien Saude Colet 2022; 27: 1171-1180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35293453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berin E, Hammar M, Lindblom H, Lindh-&#xc5;strand L, Rub&#xe9;r M, Spetz Holm AC. Resistance training for hot flushes in postmenopausal women: a randomised controlled trial. Maturitas 2019; 126: 55-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutcher YN, Boutcher SH, Yoo HY, Meerkin JD. The effect of sprint interval training on body composition of postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2019; 51: 1413-1419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31210647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonani C, Rossi FE, Diniz TA, et al. Concurrent training and taurine improve lipid profile in postmenopausal women. Rev Bras Med Do Esporte 2019; 25: 121-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coll-Risco I, Borges-Cosic M, Acosta-Manzano P, Camiletti-Moir&#xf3;n D, Aranda P, Aparicio VA. Effects of concurrent exercise on cardiometabolic status during perimenopause: the FLAMENCO Project. Climacteric 2018; 21: 559-565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30392388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes PRP, Martins FM, Souza AP, et al. Comparative effects of high-intensity interval training with combined training on physical function markers in obese postmenopausal women: a randomized controlled trial. Menopause 2019; 26: 1242-1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31479035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambrinoudaki I. Lipid and glucose metabolism during the menopausal transition &amp;amp; beyond. Maturitas 2019; 124: 113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Diniz TA, Neves LM, et al. The beneficial effects of aerobic and concurrent training on metabolic profile and body composition after detraining: a 1-year follow-up in postmenopausal women. Eur J Clin Nutr 2017; 71: 638-645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28120855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashti BA, Mehrabani J, Damirchi A, Babaei P. The influence of concurrent training intensity on serum irisin and abdominal fat in postmenopausal women. Prz Menopauz 2019; 18: 166-173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6970417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31975984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fausto DY, Leit&#xe3;o AE, Silveira J, Martins JBB, Dominski FH, Guimar&#xe3;es ACA. An umbrella systematic review of the effect of physical exercise on mental health of women in menopause. Menopause 2023; 30: 225-234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36696648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carcel&#xe9;n-Fraile M del C, Aibar-Almaz&#xe1;n A, Mart&#xed;nez-Amat A, et al. Effects of physical exercise on sexual function and quality of sexual life related to menopausal symptoms in peri-and postmenopausal women: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2020; 17: 2680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32295114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TM, Do TTT, Tran TN, Kim JH. Exercise and quality of life in women with menopausal symptoms: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2020; 17: 7049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7579592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fausto DY, Martins JBB, Dominski FH, de Azevedo Guimar&#xe3;es AC. Effects of jazz dance and concurrent training on psychological variables in menopausal women: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Womens Ment Health 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39190115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sociedade Portuguesa de ginecologia . Consenso Nacional sobre MENOPAUSA 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemann LAJ, Potthoff P, Schneider HPG. International versions of the menopause rating scale (MRS). Health Qual Life Outcomes 2003; 1: 1-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC183844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12914663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fausto DY, Klen JA, Pogere A, et al. Concurrent training for women in menopause: protocol of a randomized controlled clinical trial. Curr Women Heal Rev 2022; 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco MM, Pena CC, de Freitas LM, Ant&#xf4;nio FI, Lara LAS, Ferreira CHJ. Pelvic floor muscle training effect in sexual function in postmenopausal women: a randomized controlled trial. J Sex Med 2021; 18: 1236-1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34187758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Instituto Brasileiro de Geografia e Estat&#xed;stica . Indicadores Sociodemogr&#xe1;ficos e de Sa&#xfa;de no Brasil. Rio de Janeiro 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider HPG, Heinemann LAJ, Rosemeier HP, Potthoff P, Behre HM. The menopause rating scale (MRS): reliability of scores of menopausal complaints. Climacteric 2000; 3: 59-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11910611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand 1983; 67: 361-370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6880820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botega NJ, Bio MR, Zomignani MA, Garcia Jr C, Pereira WAB. Transtornos do humor em enfermaria de cl&#xed;nica m&#xe9;dica e valida&#xe7;&#xe3;o de escala de medida (HAD) de ansiedade e depress&#xe3;o. Rev Saude Publica 1995; 29: 359-363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8731275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen R, Brown C, Heiman J, et al. The female sexual function index (FSFI): a multidimensional self-report instrument for the assessment of fema. J Sex Marital Ther 2000; 26: 191-208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10782451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiel R, Dambros M, Palma P, Thiel M, Riccetto C, Ramos F. Tradu&#xe7;&#xe3;o para portugu&#xea;s , adapta&#xe7;&#xe3;o cultural e valida&#xe7;&#xe3;o do female sexual function index. Rev Bras Ginecol Obs 2008; 30: 504-510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19082387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neri AL. Envelhecer num pa&#xed;s de jovens: significados de velho e velhice segundo brasileiros n&#xe3;o idosos. S&#xe3;o Paulo 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa A, Park SY, Seo DY, Sanchez-Gonzalez MA, Baek YH. Combined resistance and endurance exercise training improves arterial stiffness, blood pressure, and muscle strength in postmenopausal women. Menopause 2011; 18: 980-984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabani A, Shabani R, Dalili S, Hassanzadeh Rad A. The effect of concurrent endurance and resistance training on cardio-respiratory capacity and cardiovascular risk markers among sedentary overweight or obese post-menopausal women. J Nurs Midwifery Sci 2018; 5: 123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan AW, Tetzlaff JM, Altman DG, et al. SPIRIT 2013 Statement: defining Standard Protocol Items for Clinical Trials. Ann Intern Med 2013; 158: 200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5114123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23295957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine . ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. 10<sup>th</sup> ed. 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Borg&#x2019;s perceived exertion and pain scales. 1st ed. Human Kinetics 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craike M, Gaskin CJ, Courneya KS, et al. Predictors of adherence to a 12-week exercise program among men treated for prostate cancer: ENGAGE study. Cancer Med 2016; 5: 787-794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4864808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26872005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berin E, Spetz Holm AC, Hammar M, Lindh-&#xc5;strand L, Berter&#xf6; C. Postmenopausal women&#x2019;s experiences of a resistance training intervention against vasomotor symptoms: a qualitative study. BMC Womens Health 2022; 22: 320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9338607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35907840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park KM, Park SC, Kang S. Effects of resistance exercise on adipokine factors and body composition in pre-and postmenopausal women. J Exerc Rehabil 2019; 15: 676-682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31723556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Niu H, Liu S. Effects of aerobics training on anxiety, depression and sleep quality in perimenopausal women. Front Psychiatry 2022; 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9730414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36506429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai ZY, Wen-Chyuan Chen K, Wen HJ. Effects of a group-based step aerobics training on sleep quality and melatonin levels in sleep-impaired postmenopausal women. J Strength Cond Res 2014; 28: 2597-2603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24552792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh ML, Oliveira MN, Vieira-Potter VJ. Adipocyte metabolism and health after the menopause: the role of exercise. Nutrients 2023; 15: 444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9862030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36678314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondarev D, Sipil&#xe4; S, Finni T, et al. The role of physical activity in the link between menopausal status and mental well-being. Menopause 2020; 27: 398-409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32049927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herson M, Kulkarni J. Hormonal agents for the treatment of depression associated with the menopause. Drugs Aging 2022; 39: 607-618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9355926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maseroli E, Rastrelli G, Di Stasi V, et al. Physical activity and female sexual dysfunction: a lot helps, but not too much. J Sex Med 2021; 18: 1217-1229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34099414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabral PUL, Can&#xe1;rio ACGM, Spyrides MHC, et al. Physical activity and sexual function in middle-aged women. Rev Assoc Med Bras 2014; 60: 47-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24918852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scavello I, Maseroli E, Di Stasi V, Vignozzi L. Sexual health in menopause. Medicina (B Aires) 2019; 55: 559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6780739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31480774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navvabi-Rigi SD, Mohammadi-Shahboulaghi F, Foroughan M, Momtaz YA. Weaving a cocoon on the way to aging transcendence: grounded theory study on aging perception during menopause transition. PLoS One 2022; 17: e0276797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9624393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36318522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elavsky S. Physical activity, menopause, and quality of life: the role of affect and self-worth across time. Menopause 2009; 16: 265-271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19169167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoga L, Rodolpho J, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Quirino B. Women's experience of menopause: a systematic review of qualitative evidence. JBI Database Syst Rev Implement Reports 2015; 13: 250-337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26455946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>