<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">23691497</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2314-6141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2013</Volume><PubDate><Year>2013</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BioMed research international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A systematic review of effects of concurrent strength and endurance training on the health-related quality of life and cardiopulmonary status in patients with HIV/AIDS.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>319524</StartPage><MedlinePgn>319524</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">319524</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2013/319524</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the effects of concurrent strength and endurance training (concurrent training) on the Health-Related Quality of Life (HRQOL) and cardiopulmonary status among HIV-infected patients, using a systematic search strategy of randomized, controlled trials (RCTs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic review was performed by two independent reviewers using Cochrane Collaboration protocol. The sources used in this review were Cochrane Library, EMBASE, LILACS, MEDLINE, PEDro and Web of Science from 1950 to August 2012. The PEDro score was used to evaluate methodological quality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Individual studies suggested that concurrent training contributed to improved HRQOL and cardiovascular status. Concurrent training appears to be safe and may be beneficial for medically stable adults living with HIV. The rates of nonadherence were of 16%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Concurrent training improves the HRQOL and cardiopulmonary status. It may be an important intervention in the care and treatment of adults living with HIV. Further research is needed to determine the minimal and optimal duration, frequency, and intensity of exercise needed to produce beneficial changes in the HIV-infected population subgroups.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gomes Neto</LastName><ForeName>Mansueto</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Biofun&#xe7;&#xe3;o, Curso de Fisioterapia, Universidade Federal da Bahia (UFBA), Salvador, BA, Brazil. netofisio@gmail.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ogalha</LastName><ForeName>Cec&#xed;lia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andrade</LastName><ForeName>Ant&#xf4;nio Marcos</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brites</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biomed Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101600173</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000163" MajorTopicYN="N">Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006321" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010349" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Compliance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23691497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/319524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lohse N, Hansen ABE, Pedersen G, et al. Survival of persons with and without HIV infection in Denmark, 1995&#x2013;2005. Annals of Internal Medicine. 2007;146(2):87&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17227932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cade WT, Peralta L, Keyser RE. Aerobic exercise dysfunction in human immunodeficiency virus: a potential link to physical disability. Physical Therapy. 2004;84(7):655&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15225084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK, Brandt C. The role of exercise-induced myokines in muscle homeostasis and the defense against chronic diseases. Journal of Biomedicine and Biotechnology. 2010;2010:6 pages.520258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2836182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20224659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;S Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. 7th edition. Baltimore, Md, USA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stringer WW. HIV and aerobic exercise. Current recommendations. Sports Medicine. 1999;28(6):389&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10623982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR, et al. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2007;116(9):1081&#x2013;1093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R, McDermott A, Weiss L, et al. Short-term progressive resistance training increases strength and lean body mass in adults infected with human immunodeficiency virus. AIDS. 1999;13(2):231&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10202829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grinspoon S, Corcoran C, Parlman K, et al. Effects of testosterone and progressive resistance training in eugonadal men with AIDS wasting: a randomized, controlled trial. Annals of Internal Medicine. 2000;133(5):348&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10979879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BA, Neidig JL, Nickel JT, Mitchell GL, Para MF, Fass RJ. Aerobic exercise: effects on parameters related to fatigue, dyspnea, weight and body composition in HIV-infected adults. AIDS. 2001;15(6):693&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11371683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xf6;ni GJ, Fedou C, Brun JF, et al. Reduction of fat accumulation and lipid disorders by individualized light aerobic training in human immunodeficiency virus infected patients with lipodystrophy and/or dyslipidemia. Diabetes and Metabolism. 2002;28(5):397&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12461477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2011;43(7):1334&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR, et al. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2007;39(8):1423&#x2013;1434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveritt M, Abernethy PJ, Barry BK, Logan PA. Concurrent strength and endurance training. A review. Sports Medicine. 1999;28(6):413&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10623984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations during strength and endurance training versus strength training. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2003;89(1):42&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12627304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lox LC, McAulley E, Tucker RS. Aerobic and resistance exercise training effects on body composition, muscular strength, and cardiovascular fitness in an HIV. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine. 1996;3(1):55&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16250767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson FP, Quinn LT, Rimmer JH. Effects of high-intensity endurance and resistance exercise on HIV metabolic abnormalities: a pilot study. Biological Research for Nursing. 2007;8(3):177&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17172316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciccolo JT, Jowers EM, Bartholomew JB. The benefits of exercise training for quality of life in HIV/AIDS in the post-HAART era. Sports Medicine. 2004;34(8):487&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15248786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien K, Nixon S, Glazier RH, Tynan AM. Progressive resistive exercise interventions for adults living with HIV/AIDS. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2004;(4)CD004248</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15495092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fillipas S, Cherry CL, Cicuttini F, Smirneos L, Holland AE. The effects of exercise training on metabolic and morphological outcomes for people living with HIV: a systematic review of randomised controlled trials. HIV Clinical Trials. 2010;11(5):270&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21126957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions 4.2.6. Chichester, UK: The Cochrane Library, John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivo SA, Macedo LG, Gadotti IC, Fuentes J, Stanton T, Magee DJ. Scales to assess the quality of randomized controlled trials: a systematic review. Physical Therapy. 2008;88(2):156&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18073267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Physical Therapy. 2003;83(8):713&#x2013;721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhagen AP, De Vet HCW, De Bie RA, et al. The Delphi list: a criteria list for quality assessment of randomized clinical trials for conducting systematic reviews developed by Delphi consensus. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology. 1998;51(12):1235&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10086815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutimura E, Stewart A, Crowther NJ, Yarasheski KE, Cade WT. The effects of exercise training on quality of life in HAART-treated HIV-positive Rwandan subjects with body fat redistribution. Quality of Life Research. 2008;17(3):377&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3167195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18320351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hand GA, Phillips KD, Dudgeon WD, William Lyerly G, Larry Durstine J, Burgess SE. Moderate intensity exercise training reverses functional aerobic impairment in HIV-infected individuals. AIDS Care. 2008;20(9):1066&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18608063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Moreno F, C&#xe1;mara-S&#xe1;nchez M, Tremblay JF. Benefits of exercise training in Spanish prison inmates. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2007;28:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17549659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan SE, Frontera W, Librizzi J, et al. Effects of a supervised home-based aerobic and progressive resistance training regimen in women infected with human immunodeficiency virus: a randomized trial. Archives of Internal Medicine. 2006;166(11):1225&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3205443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fillipas S, Oldmeadow LB, Bailey MJ, Cherry CL. A six-month, supervised, aerobic and resistance exercise program improves self-efficacy in people with human immunodeficiency virus: a randomised controlled trial. Australian Journal of Physiotherapy. 2006;52(3):185&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16942453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driscoll SD, Meininger GE, Lareau MT, et al. Effects of exercise training and metformin on body composition and cardiovascular indices in HIV-infected patients. AIDS. 2004;18(3):465&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15090799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas R, Schlicht W, Hautzinger M. Effects of exercise training on quality of life, psychological well-being, immune status, and cardiopulmonary fitness in an HIV-1 positive population. Journal of Sport and Exercise Psychology. 2003;25(4):440&#x2013;455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigsby LW, Dishman RK, Jackson AW, Maclean GS, Raven PB. Effects of exercise training on men seropositive for the human immunodeficiency virus-1. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 1992;24(1):6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1548998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien K, Tynan AM, Nixon S, Glazier RH. Effects of progressive resistive exercise in adults living with HIV/AIDS: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. AIDS Care. 2008;20(6):631&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18576165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scevola D, Di Matteo A, Lanzarini P, et al. Effect of exercise and strength training on cardiovascular status in HIV-infected patients receiving highly active antiretroviral therapy. AIDS. 2003;17(1, supplement):S123&#x2013;S129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12870538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima ALLM, Zumiotti AV, Camanho GL, et al. Osteoarticular complications related to HIV infection and highly active antiretroviral therapy. Brazilian Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2007;11(4):426&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17873999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bopp CM, Phillips KD, Fulk LJ, Hand GA. Clinical implications of therapeutic exercise in HIV/AIDS. Journal of the Association of Nurses in AIDS Care. 2003;14(1):73&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12585224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cahn P, Leite O, Rosales A, et al. Metabolic profile and cardiovascular risk factors among Latin American HIV-infected patients receiving HAART. Brazilian Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2010;14(2):158&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20563442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stringer WW, Berezovskaya M, O&#x2019;Brien WA, Beck CK, Casaburi R. The effect of exercise training on aerobic fitness, immune indices, and quality of life in HIV+ patients. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 1998;30(1):11&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spierer DK, DeMeersman RE, Kleinfeld J, et al. Exercise training improves cardiovascular and autonomic profiles in HIV. Clinical Autonomic Research. 2007;17(6):341&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18049834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x2019;Brien K O, Nixon S, Tynan AM, Glazier RH. Aerobic exercise interventions for people living with HIV/AIDS: implications for practice, education, and research. Physiotherapy Canada. 2006;58:114&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavone RM, Burnett KF, LaPerriere A, Perna FM. Social cognitive and physical health determinants of exercise adherence for HIV-1 seropositive, early symptomatic men and women. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine. 1998;5(3):245&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16250705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forkan R, Pumper B, Smyth N, Wirkkala H, Ciol MA, Shumway-Cook A. Exercise adherence following physical therapy intervention in older adults with impaired balance. Physical Therapy. 2006;86(3):401&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16506876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petr&#xf3;czi A, Hawkins K, Jones G, Naughton DP. HIV patient characteristics that affect adherence to exercise programmes: an observational study. Open AIDS Journal. 2010;4:148&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2944991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20871752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>