<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">33239940</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1303-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sports science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>CrossFit&#xae; Training Strategies from the Perspective of Concurrent Training: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>670</StartPage><EndPage>680</EndPage><MedlinePgn>670-680</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>In the basic principles of CrossFit<sup>&#xae;</sup>, the goal is to improve fitness, related to the simultaneous development of strength and endurance. This is also the main idea of concurrent training, which has been researched since the 1980s. This article aimed to analyze the acute and chronic effects of CrossFit<sup>&#xae;</sup> and to assess the relevance of using the concurrent training methodology. The findings show that CrossFit<sup>&#xae;</sup> is an intense form of exercise that affects the function of the endocrine, immune, and central nervous systems. It also has potential in the development of strength and endurance parameters. These conclusions were compared with relevant concurrent training studies. Although the CrossFit<sup>&#xae;</sup> interventions (workouts of the day) have much in common with concurrent training, methodological recommendations can only be partially transferred. The approach for training and athlete development must be based on the originality of this sport.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Journal of Sports Science and Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlegel</LastName><ForeName>Petr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Education, University of Hradec Kr&#xe1;lov&#xe9;, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1303-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high intensity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training load</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jssm-19-670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aucher H. (2014) 209,585: Rise of the Open. Retrieved 26th of June&#x2019;. 2020, from https://games.crossfit.com/article/209585-rise-open.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey B., Benson A. J., Bruner M. W. (2019) Investigating the organisational culture of CrossFit, International Journal of Sport and Exercise Psychology 17(3), 197&#x2013;211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barfield J., Anderson A. (2014) Effect of CrossFit on health related physical fitness: A pilot study. Journal of Sport and Human Performance, 2(1), 23&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellar D., Hatchett A., Judge L., Breaux M., Marcus L. (2015) The relationship of aerobic capacity, anaerobic peak power and experience to performance in CrossFit exercise, Biology of Sport 32(4), 315&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4672163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26681834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryman N., Mujika I., Bosquet L. (2019) Concurrent Training for Sports Performance: The 2 Sides of the Medal. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance 14(3), 279&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29809072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D., Bartlett J., Fyfe J., Lee M. (2019) Methodological Considerations for Concurrent Training: Scientific Basics and Practical Applications. Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Training. Cham: Springer; 183&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisebois M. F., Rigby B. R., Nichols D. L. (2018) Physiological and Fitness Adaptations after Eight Weeks of High-Intensity Functional Training in Physically Inactive Adults. Sports 6(4), 1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6316712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30428527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner S. L., Mouser J. G., Jessee M. B., Dankel S. J., Mattocks K. T., Loenneke J. P. (2017) What does individual strength say about resistance training status? Muscle &amp; Nerve 55(4), 455&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28066901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butcher S. J., Neyedly T. J., Horvey K. J., Benko C. R. (2015) Do physiological measures predict selected CrossFit(&#xae;) benchmark performance? Open Access Journal of Sports Medicine 6, 241&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4527742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26261428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore E. L., Izquierdo M., dos Santos M. G., Martins J. B., Rodrigues Lhullier F. L., Pinto R. S., Silva R. F., Kruel L. F. M. (2012) Hormonal responses to concurrent strength and endurance training with different exercise orders. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 26(12), 3281&#x2013;3288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22222319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove S. J., Crawford D. A., Heinrich K. M. (2019) Multiple Fitness Improvements Found after 6-Months of High Intensity Functional Training. Sports 7(9), 1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6784068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31480686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford D. A., Drake N. B., Carper M. J., DeBlauw J., Heinrich K. M. (2018a) Are Changes in Physical Work Capacity Induced by High-Intensity Functional Training Related to Changes in Associated Physiologic Measures? Sports 6(2), 1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford D. A., Drake N. B., Carper M. J., DeBlauw J., Heinrich K. M. (2018b) Validity, Reliability, and Application of the Session-RPE Method for Quantifying Training Loads during High Intensity Functional Training. Sports 6(3), 1-9..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6162783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30134535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Official CrossFit Affiliate Map. (2020) Retrieved 25<sup>th</sup> of June&#x2019;. 2020, from https://map.crossfit.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dexheimer J. D., Schroeder E. T., Sawyer B. J., Pettitt R. W., Aguinaldo A. L., Torrence W. A. (2019) Physiological Performance Measures as Indicators of CrossFit&#xae; Performance. Sports (Basel, Switzerland), 7(4), 1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31013585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty D., Hodgson M. J. (2007) The application of postactivation potentiation to elite sport. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance 2(4), 439&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19171961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K., Deakin G. B. (2013) The effects of strength training and endurance training order on running economy and performance. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism 38(6), 651&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23724883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K., Deakin G. B., Bentley D. J. (2017) Implications of Impaired Endurance Performance following Single Bouts of Resistance Training: An Alternate Concurrent Training Perspective. Sports Medicine 47(11), 2187&#x2013;2200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doncaster G., Twist C. (2012) Exercise-induced muscle damage from bench press exercise impairs arm cranking endurance performance. European Journal of Applied Physiology 112, 4135-4142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22526252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake N., Smeed J., Carper M., Crawford D. (2017) Effects of Short-Term CrossFit Training: A Magnitude-Based Approach. Journal of Exercise Physiology Online 20, 111&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drum S., Bellovary B., Jensen R., Moore M., Donath L. (2016) Perceived demands and postexercise physical dysfunction in CrossFit&#xae; compared to an ACSM based training session. The Journal of Sports Medicine and Physical Fitness 57, 604-609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26954573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K., Nowaczyk P. M., Siedzik K. (2019) Effect of a four-week ketogenic diet on exercise metabolism in CrossFit-trained athletes. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition 16(1), 16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6451242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30953522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falk Neto J. H., Kennedy M. D. (2019) The Multimodal Nature of High-Intensity Functional Training: Potential Applications to Improve Sport Performance. Sports (Basel, Switzerland), 7(2), 1-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6409553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30699906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feito Y., Giardina M. J., Butcher S., Mangine G. T. (2019) Repeated anaerobic tests predict performance among a group of advanced CrossFit-trained athletes. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism 44(7), 727&#x2013;735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30500263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feito Y., Heinrich K. M., Butcher S. J., Poston W. S. C. (2018a) High-Intensity Functional Training (HIFT): Definition and Research Implications for Improved Fitness. Sports (Basel, Switzerland) 6(3), 1-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6162410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30087252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feito Y., Hoffstetter W., Serafini P., Mangine G. (2018b) Changes in body composition, bone metabolism, strength, and skill-specific performance resulting from 16-weeks of HIFT. PloS One 13(6), e0198324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6003684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29906290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Fernandez J., Sabido R., Moya D., Sarabia Mar&#xed;n J. M., Moya M. (2015) Acute physiological responses during Crossfit&#xae; workouts. European Journal of Human Movement 35, 114&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe J. J., Loenneke J. P. (2018) Interpreting Adaptation to Concurrent Compared with Single-Mode Exercise Training: Some Methodological Considerations. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.) 48(2), 289&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29127601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe4;bler M., Prieske O., Hortob&#xe1;gyi T., Granacher U. (2018) The Effects of Concurrent Strength and Endurance Training on Physical Fitness and Athletic Performance in Youth: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Frontiers in Physiology 9, 1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30131714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher D., DiPietro L., Visek A. J., Bancheri J. M., Miller T. A. (2010) The effects of concurrent endurance and resistance training on 2,000-m rowing ergometer times in collegiate male rowers. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 24(5), 1208&#x2013;1214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heavens K. R., Szivak T. K., Hooper D. R., Dunn-Lewis C., Comstock B. A., Flanagan S. D., Looney D. P., Kupchak B. R., Maresh C. M., Volek J. S., Kraemer W. J. (2014) The effects of high intensity short rest resistance exercise on muscle damage markers in men and women. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 28(4), 1041&#x2013;1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen J., Rustad P. I., Kolnes A. J., Lai Y.-C. (2011) The Role of Skeletal Muscle Glycogen Breakdown for Regulation of Insulin Sensitivity by Exercise. Frontiers in Physiology 2, 1-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3248697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22232606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones T. W., Howatson G., Russell M., French D. N. (2017) Effects of strength and endurance exercise order on endocrine responses to concurrent training. European Journal of Sport Science 17(3), 326&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27817246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karavirta L., H&#xe4;kkinen K., Kauhanen A., Arija-Bl&#xe1;zquez A., Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E., Rinkinen N., H&#xe4;kkinen A. (2011) Individual responses to combined endurance and strength training in older adults. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 43(3), 484&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20689460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kephart W. C., Pledge C. D., Roberson P. A., Mumford P. W., Romero M. A., Mobley C. B., Martin J. S., Young K. C., Lowery R. P., Wilson J. M., Huggins K. W., Roberts M. D. (2018) The Three-Month Effects of a Ketogenic Diet on Body Composition, Blood Parameters, and Performance Metrics in CrossFit Trainees: A Pilot Study. Sports 6(1), 1-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5969192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindermann W., Schnabel A., Schmitt W. M., Biro G., Cassens J., Weber F. (1982) Catecholamines, growth hormone, cortisol, insulin, and sex hormones in anaerobic and aerobic exercise. European Journal of Applied Physiology and Occupational Physiology 49(3), 389&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6754371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kliszczewicz B., Quindry C. J., Blessing L. D., Oliver D. G., Esco R. M., Taylor J. K. (2015) Acute Exercise and Oxidative Stress: CrossFit(<sup>TM</sup>) vs. Treadmill Bout. Journal of Human Kinetics
47, 81&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26557192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kliszczewicz B., Williamson C., Bechke E., McKenzie M., Hoffstetter W. (2018) Autonomic response to a short and long bout of high-intensity functional training. Journal of Sports Sciences 36(16), 1872&#x2013;1879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29308709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen P., Buchheit M. (2019) Science and Application of High-Intensity Interval Training: Solutions to the Programming Puzzle. Human Kinetics.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23832851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine G., Stratton M., Almeda C., Roberts M., Esmat T., VanDusseldorp T., Feito Y. (2020) Physiological Differences Between Advanced Crossfit Athletes, Recreational Crossfit Participants, and Physically-Active Adults. PLoS One 15(4), 1-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32255792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine G. T., Cebulla B., Feito Y. (2018a) Normative Values for Self-Reported Benchmark Workout Scores in CrossFit&#xae; Practitioners. Sports Medicine - Open 4(1), 1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6102159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30128825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine G. T., Van Dusseldorp T. A., Feito Y., Holmes A. J., Serafini P. R., Box A. G., Gonzalez A. M. (2018b) Testosterone and Cortisol Responses to Five High-Intensity Functional Training Competition Workouts in Recreationally Active Adults. Sports (Basel, Switzerland), 6(3), 1-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6162535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30011910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-G&#xf3;mez R., Valenzuela P. L., Barranco-Gil D., Moral-Gonz&#xe1;lez S., Garc&#xed;a-Gonz&#xe1;lez A., Lucia A. (2019) Full-Squat as a Determinant of Performance in CrossFit. International Journal of Sports Medicine 40(09), 592&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mat&#xe9;-Mu&#xf1;oz J. L., Lougedo J. H., Barba M., Ca&#xf1;uelo-M&#xe1;rquez A. M., Guodemar-P&#xe9;rez J., Garc&#xed;a-Fern&#xe1;ndez P., Lozano-Estevan M. D. C., Alonso-Melero R., S&#xe1;nchez-Calabuig M. A., Ru&#xed;z-L&#xf3;pez M., de Jes&#xfa;s F., Garnacho-Casta&#xf1;o M. V. (2018) Cardiometabolic and Muscular Fatigue Responses to Different CrossFit&#xae; Workouts. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 17(4), 668&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6243628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30479537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mat&#xe9;-Mu&#xf1;oz J. L., Lougedo J. H., Barba M., Garc&#xed;a-Fern&#xe1;ndez P., Garnacho-Casta&#xf1;o M. V., Dom&#xed;nguez R. (2017) Muscular fatigue in response to different modalities of CrossFit sessions. PloS One, 12(7), 1-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5533437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28753624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methenitis S. (2018) A Brief Review on Concurrent Training: From Laboratory to the Field. Sports (Basel, Switzerland), 6(4), 1-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murawska-Cialowicz E., Wojna J., Zuwala-Jagiello J. (2015) Crossfit training changes brain-derived neurotrophic factor and irisin levels at rest, after wingate and progressive tests, and improves aerobic capacity and body composition of young physically active men and women. Journal of Physiology and Pharmacology: An Official Journal of the Polish Physiological Society 66(6), 811&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26769830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murlasits Z., Kneffel Z., Thalib L. (2018) The physiological effects of concurrent strength and endurance training sequence: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Sports Sciences 36(11), 1212&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28783467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perciavalle Valentina, Marchetta N. S., Giustiniani S., Borbone C., Perciavalle Vincenzo, Petralia M. C., Buscemi A., Coco M. (2016) Attentive processes, blood lactate and CrossFit&#xae;. The Physician and Sportsmedicine 44(4), 403&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27556548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petr&#xe9; H., L&#xf6;fving P., Psilander N. (2018) The Effect of Two Different Concurrent Training Programs on Strength and Power Gains in Highly-Trained Individuals. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine,17(2), 167&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5950732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29769816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poderoso R., Cirilo-Sousa M., J&#xfa;nior A., Novaes J., Vianna J., Dias M., Leit&#xe3;o L., Reis V., Neto N., Vila&#xe7;a-Alves J. (2019) Gender Differences in Chronic Hormonal and Immunological Responses to CrossFit&#xae;. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 16(14), 1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31330935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Prampero P. E. (1986) The energy cost of human locomotion on land and in water. International Journal of Sports Medicine 7(2), 55&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3519480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabag A., Najafi A., Michael S., Esgin T., Halaki M., Hackett D. (2018) The compatibility of concurrent high intensity interval training and resistance training for muscular strength and hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Sports Sciences 36(21), 2472&#x2013;2483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlegel P., Re&#x17e;n&#xfd; L., Fialov&#xe1; D. (2020) Pilot study: Performance-ranking relationship analysis in Czech crossfiters. Journal of Human Sport and Exercise, 16, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann M., Eklund D., Taipale R. S., Nyman K., Kraemer W. J., H&#xe4;kkinen A., Izquierdo M., H&#xe4;kkinen K. (2013) Acute neuromuscular and endocrine responses and recovery to single-session combined endurance and strength loadings: &#x201c;order effect&#x201d; in untrained young men. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 27(2), 421&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23222087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serafini P. R., Feito Y., Mangine G. T. (2018) Self-reported Measures of Strength and Sport-Specific Skills Distinguish Ranking in an International Online Fitness Competition. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 32(12), 3474&#x2013;3484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28195976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skattebo &#xd8;., Hall&#xe9;n J., R&#xf8;nnestad B. R., Losnegard T. (2016) Upper body heavy strength training does not affect performance in junior female cross-country skiers. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports 26(9), 1007&#x2013;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26146761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szivak T. K., Hooper D. R., Dunn-Lewis C., Comstock B. A., Kupchak B. R., Apicella J. M., Saenz C., Maresh C. M., Denegar C. R., Kraemer W. J. (2013) Adrenal cortical responses to high-intensity, short rest, resistance exercise in men and women. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 27(3), 748&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22561973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale R. S., H&#xe4;kkinen K. (2013) Acute hormonal and force responses to combined strength and endurance loadings in men and women: the &#x201c;order effect&#x201d;. PloS One 8(2), 1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3567118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale R. S., Mikkola J., Nummela A., Vesterinen V., Capostagno B., Walker S., Gitonga D., Kraemer W. J., H&#xe4;kkinen K. (2010) Strength training in endurance runners. International Journal of Sports Medicine 31(7), 468&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20432192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale R. S., Schumann M., Mikkola J., Nyman K., Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H., Nummela A., H&#xe4;kkinen K. (2014) Acute neuromuscular and metabolic responses to combined strength and endurance loadings: the &#x201c;order effect&#x201d; in recreationally endurance trained runners. Journal of Sports Sciences 32(12), 1155&#x2013;1164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24576212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibana R. A., de Almeida L. M., Frade de Sousa N. M., Nascimento D., da C., Neto I. V., de S., de Almeida J. A., de Souza V. C., Lopes M., de F. T. P. L., Nobrega O., de T., Vieira D. C. L., Navalta J. W., Prestes J. (2016) Two Consecutive Days of Crossfit Training Affects Pro and Anti-inflammatory Cytokines and Osteoprotegerin without Impairments in Muscle Power. Frontiers in Physiology 7, 260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4924482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibana R. A., Prestes J., de Souza N. M. F., de Souza V. C., de Toledo Nobrega O., Baffi M., Ferreira C. E. S., Cunha G. V., Navalta J. W., Trombeta J. C. D. S., Cavaglieri C. R., Voltarelli F. A. (2019a) Time-Course of Changes in Physiological, Psychological, and Performance Markers following a Functional-Fitness Competition. International Journal of Exercise Science 12(3), 904&#x2013;918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6719819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibana R. A., de Sousa N. M. F., Cunha G. V., Prestes J., Fett C., Gabbett T. J., Voltarelli F. A. (2018) Validity of Session Rating Perceived Exertion Method for Quantifying Internal Training Load during High-Intensity Functional Training. Sports (Basel, Switzerland) 6(3), 1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6162408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30041435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibana R. A., de Sousa N. M. F., Prestes J., Feito Y., Ernesto C., Voltarelli F. A. (2019b) Monitoring Training Load, Well-Being, Heart Rate Variability, and Competitive Performance of a Functional-Fitness Female Athlete: A Case Study. Sports 7(2), 1-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6409702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30744103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tim&#xf3;n R., Olcina G., Camacho-Carde&#xf1;osa M., Camacho-Cardenosa A., Martinez-Guardado I., Marcos-Serrano M. (2019) 48-hour recovery of biochemical parameters and physical performance after two modalities of CrossFit workouts. Biology of Sport 36(3), 283&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6786329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31624423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay M. S., Copeland J. L., Van Helder W. (2004) Effect of training status and exercise mode on endogenous steroid hormones in men. Journal of Applied Physiology 96(2), 531&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14514704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J. M., Marin P. J., Rhea M. R., Wilson S. M. C., Loenneke J. P., Anderson J. C. (2012) Concurrent training: a meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 26(8), 2293&#x2013;2307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>