<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40381170</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Activity to Counter Age-Related Cognitive Decline: Benefits of Aerobic, Resistance, and Combined Training-A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>56</StartPage><MedlinePgn>56</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">56</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-025-00857-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">With the increase in life expectancy, age-related cognitive decline has become a prevalent concern. Physical activity (PA) is increasingly being recognized as a vital non-pharmacological strategy to counteract this decline. This review aimed to (i) critically evaluate and synthesize the impact of different PA and exercise modalities (aerobic, resistance, and concurrent training) on cognitive health and overall well-being in older adults, (ii) discuss the influence of exercise intensity on cognitive functions, and (iii) elucidate the potential mechanisms through which PA and exercise may enhance or mitigate cognitive performance among older adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN BODY" NlmCategory="METHODS">An exhaustive analysis of peer-reviewed studies pertaining to PA/exercise and cognitive health in older adults from January 1970 to February 2025 was conducted using PubMed, Scopus, Web of Science, PsycINFO, and MEDLINE. There is compelling evidence that aerobic and resistance training (RT) improve cognitive function and mental health in older adults, with benefits influenced by the type and intensity of exercise. Specifically, moderate-intensity aerobic exercise appears to bolster memory, executive functions, and mood regulation, potentially through increased cerebral blood flow, neurogenesis, and production of brain-derived neurotrophic factors in the hippocampus. Moderate-to-high-intensity RT acutely enhances visuospatial processing and executive functions, with chronic training promoting neurogenesis, possibly by stimulating insulin-like growth factor-1 and augmenting blood flow to the prefrontal cortex. Findings related to the effects of concurrent training on cognitive function and mental health are heterogeneous, with some studies reporting no significant impact and others revealing substantial improvements. However, emerging evidence indicates that the combination of concurrent training and cognitive tasks (i.e., dual tasks) is particularly effective, often outperforming aerobic exercise alone.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Regular aerobic and RT performance is beneficial for older adults to mitigate cognitive decline and enhance their overall well-being. Specifically, engaging in moderate-intensity aerobic exercises and moderate-to-high-intensity RT is safe and effective in improving cognitive function and mental health in this demographic. These exercises, which can be conveniently incorporated into daily routines, effectively enhance mental agility, memory, executive function, and mood. The findings related to concurrent training are mixed, with emerging evidence indicating the effectiveness of combined concurrent and cognitive tasks on cognitive health and well-being in older adults. Key Points - Moderate-intensity aerobic exercise is associated with significant improvements in cognitive function, mood regulation, and overall well-being in older adults. These benefits are linked to structural and functional changes in the brain such as increased hippocampal volume and elevated levels of brain-derived neurotrophic factor. - Moderate-to-high-intensity resistance training, both in acute and chronic forms, enhances cognitive performance in older adults, particularly in executive functions and visuospatial processing. Cognitive benefits, including improvements in information-processing speed, attention, and memory, can be sustained through regular training. - The effects of concurrent resistance and aerobic training on cognitive function in older adults are mixed. However, combining concurrent training with cognitive tasks (i.e., dual-task training) is particularly effective and often outperforms aerobic exercise alone. - Cognitive and well-being improvements from aerobic and resistance training are mediated by mechanisms such as increased cerebral blood flow and oxygen delivery, enhanced neurogenesis, reduced oxidative stress and inflammation, and positive hormonal changes. - While the optimal exercise dosage for promoting cognitive health in older adults remains undetermined, empirical evidence indicates a positive correlation between increased exercise dosage and cognitive health improvements.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhahbi</LastName><ForeName>Wissem</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6221-546X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit "Sport Sciences, Health and Movement", High Institute of Sports and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qatar Police Academy, Police College, Training Department, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Briki</LastName><ForeName>Walid</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6298-811X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hospitalier de Grasse, Grasse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heissel</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9270-7027</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Social and Preventive Medicine, Department of Sports and Health Sciences, Intra Faculty Unit "Cognitive Sciences", Faculty of Human Science and Faculty of Health Sciences Brandenburg, Research Area Services Research and e-Health, Potsdam, Brandenburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schega</LastName><ForeName>Lutz</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, Chair for Health and Physical Activity, Otto-von-Guericke University Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dergaa</LastName><ForeName>Ismail</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, Manouba 2010, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guelmami</LastName><ForeName>Noomen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit Physical Activity, Sport, and Health, UR18JS01, National Observatory of Sport, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate School of Public Health, Department of Health Sciences (DISSAL), University of Genoa, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human and Social Sciences, High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, 7100, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Omri</LastName><ForeName>Abdelfatteh El</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4112-7924</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgical Research Section, Department of Surgery, Hamad Medical Corporation, 3050, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chaabene</LastName><ForeName>Helmi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7812-7931</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, Chair for Health and Physical Activity, Otto-von-Guericke University Magdeburg, Magdeburg, Germany. helmi.chaabane@ovgu.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Jendouba, Institut Sup&#xe9;rieur de Sport et de l'Education Physique du Kef, 7100, Le Kef, Tunisia. helmi.chaabane@ovgu.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Executive function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training modality</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: Wissem Dhahbi, Walid Briki, Andreas Heissel, Lutz Schega, Ismail Dergaa, Abdelfatteh El Omri, Noomen Guelmami, and Helmi Chaabene declare that they have no conflicts of interest relevant to the content of this review. In accordance with the editorial policy on competing interests ( https://www.springer.com/gp/editorial-policies/competing-interests ), the authors have carefully considered all potential competing interests, including financial, professional, personal relationships, and beliefs, that could be perceived as influencing the work reported in this manuscript. The authors confirm that there are no such competing interests to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40381170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12085549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00857-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-025-00857-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Idowu MI, Szameitat AJ. Executive function abilities in cognitively healthy young and older adults&#x2014;a cross-sectional study. Front Aging Neurosci. 2023;15: 976915. 10.3389/fnagi.2023.976915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2023.976915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9945216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36845657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salthouse TA. When does age-related cognitive decline begin? Neurobiol Aging. 2009;30(4):507&#x2013;14. 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2008.09.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2008.09.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2683339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19231028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reparaz-Escudero I, Izquierdo M, Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Mart&#xed;nez-Lage P, de Asteasu MLS. Effect of long-term physical exercise and multidomain interventions on cognitive function and the risk of mild cognitive impairment and dementia in older adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev. 2024;100:102463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2024.102463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39179115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Asteasu MLS, Mart&#xed;nez-Velilla N, Zambom-Ferraresi F, Galbete A, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Cadore EL, et al. Dose-response relationship between exercise duration and enhanced function and cognition in acutely hospitalized older adults: a secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial. Innovation Aging. 2024;8(6):igae053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geroni/igae053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11208931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38939651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hase Y, Horsburgh K, Ihara M, Kalaria RN. White matter degeneration in vascular and other ageing-related dementias. J Neurochem. 2017;140(5):703&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29210074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan J, Zhang Z, Wen H, Hong X, Hong Z, Qu Q, et al. Incidence of dementia and subtypes: a cohort study in four regions in China. Alzheimers Dement. 2016;12(3):262&#x2013;71. 10.1016/j.jalz.2015.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2015.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26086181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Arrigo JS. Nanotherapy for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and vascular dementia: targeting senile endothelium. Adv Colloid Interface Sci. 2017;251:44&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2017.12.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29274774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idowu M, Iyabode M. Executive function abilities, cognitive ageing, and cognitive decline. London: Brunel University London; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glisky EL. Changes in cognitive function in human aging. In: Riddle DR, editor. Brain aging: models, methods, and mechanisms. Boca Raton: CRC Press; 2007. p. 3&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, de Souto BP, Arai H, Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Cadore EL, Cesari M, et al. Global consensus on optimal exercise recommendations for enhancing healthy longevity in older adults (ICFSR). J Nutr Health Aging. 2025;29(1): 100401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnha.2024.100401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39743381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chughtai M, Gwam C, Mohamed N, Khlopas A, Sodhi N, Sultan A, et al. Impact of physical activity and body mass index in cardiovascular and musculoskeletal health: a review. Surg Technol Int. 2017;31:333&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29327778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mena C, Sep&#xfa;lveda C, Ormaz&#xe1;bal Y, Fuentes E, Palomo I. Impact of walkability with regard to physical activity in the prevention of diabetes. Geospat Health. 2017;12(2):557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/gh.2017.595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29239549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stessman J, Jacobs JM. Diabetes mellitus, physical activity, and longevity between the ages of 70 and 90. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2014;62(7):1329&#x2013;34. 10.1111/jgs.12923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.12923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25040133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk-Sanchez NJ, McGough EL. Physical exercise and cognitive performance in the elderly: current perspectives. Clin Interv Aging. 2014;9:51&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3872007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24379659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzdine LB, Dhahbi W, Dergaa I, Ceylan HI, Guelmami N, Ben Saad H, et al. Physical activity and neuroplasticity in neurodegenerative disorders: a comprehensive review of exercise interventions, cognitive training, and AI applications. Front Neurosci. 2025;19:1502417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2025.1502417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11906675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40092068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plassman BL, Langa KM, Fisher GG, Heeringa SG, Weir DR, Ofstedal MB, et al. Prevalence of dementia in the United States: the aging, demographics, and memory study. Neuroepidemiology. 2007;29(1&#x2013;2):125&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000109998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2705925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17975326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PJ, Merwin RM. The role of exercise in management of mental health disorders: an integrative review. Annu Rev Med. 2021;72:45&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-med-060619-022943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33256493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare N, Bishop DJ, Levinger I, Febbraio MA, Broatch JR. Exercise intensity matters: a review on evaluating the effects of aerobic exercise intensity on muscle-derived neuroprotective myokines. Alzheimers Dement. 2025;11(1): e70056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11837734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39975467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casta&#xf1;o LAA, de Lima VC, Barbieri JF, de Lucena EGP, G&#xe1;spari AF, Arai H, et al. Resistance training combined with cognitive training increases brain-derived neurotrophic factor and improves cognitive function in healthy older adults. Front Psychol. 2022;13:870561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.870561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9613948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36312128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman SB, Aslan S, Spence JS, Keebler MW, De Fina LF, Didehbani N, et al. Distinct brain and behavioral benefits from cognitive vs. physical training: a randomized trial in aging adults. Front Hum Neurosci. 2016;10:338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2016.00338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4939293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27462210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Prakash RS, Voss MW, Chaddock L, Hu L, Morris KS, et al. Aerobic fitness is associated with hippocampal volume in elderly humans. Hippocampus. 2009;19(10):1030&#x2013;9. 10.1002/hipo.20547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hipo.20547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19123237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieker JA, Reales JM, Mui&#xf1;os M, Ballesteros S. The effects of combined cognitive-physical interventions on cognitive functioning in healthy older adults: a systematic review and multilevel meta-analysis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2022;16: 838968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2022.838968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8987130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35399365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang YK, Tsai CL, Huang CC, Wang CC, Chu IH. Effects of acute resistance exercise on cognition in late middle-aged adults: general or specific cognitive improvement? J Sci Med Sport. 2014;17(1):51&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2013.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23491140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markov A, Hauser L, Chaabene H. Effects of concurrent strength and endurance training on measures of physical fitness in healthy middle-aged and older adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(2):437&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01764-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9876872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36222981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Gu H, Cai X, Zhang Y, Hou X, Yu J, et al. The effects of exercise for cognitive function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(2):1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20021088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9858649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36673844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szalewska D, Radkowski M, Demkow U, Winklewski PJ. Exercise strategies to counteract brain aging effects. In: Pokorski M, editor. Clinical research and practice. Cham: Springer; 2017. p. 69&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28382606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, Franklin BA, Lamonte MJ, Lee IM, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1334&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213fefb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillman CH, Erickson KI, Kramer AF. Be smart, exercise your heart: exercise effects on brain and cognition. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2008;9(1):58&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn2298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18094706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rovio S, K&#xe5;reholt I, Helkala EL, Viitanen M, Winblad B, Tuomilehto J, et al. Leisure-time physical activity at midlife and the risk of dementia and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol. 2005;4(11):705&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(05)70198-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lautenschlager NT, Cox KL, Flicker L, Foster JK, van Bockxmeer FM, Xiao J, et al. Effect of physical activity on cognitive function in older adults at risk for Alzheimer disease: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2008;300(9):1027&#x2013;37. 10.1001/jama.300.9.1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.300.9.1027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18768414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson EB, Wang L, Bowen JD, McCormick WC, Teri L, Crane P, et al. Exercise is associated with reduced risk for incident dementia among persons 65 years of age and older. Ann Intern Med. 2006;144(2):73&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-144-2-200601170-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16418406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melov S, Tarnopolsky MA, Beckman K, Felkey K, Hubbard AJ. Resistance exercise reverses aging in human skeletal muscle. PLoS ONE. 2007;2(5): e465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0000465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1866181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17520024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Brinke LF, Bolandzadeh N, Nagamatsu LS, Hsu CL, Davis JC, Miran-Khan K, et al. Aerobic exercise increases hippocampal volume in older women with probable mild cognitive impairment: a 6-month randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(4):248&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4508129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24711660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldrini M, Fulmore CA, Tartt AN, Simeon LR, Pavlova I, Poposka V, et al. Human hippocampal neurogenesis persists throughout aging. Cell Stem Cell. 2018;22(4):589-99.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.stem.2018.03.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5957089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29625071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadagni V, Drogos LL, Tyndall AV, Davenport MH, Anderson TJ, Eskes GA, et al. Aerobic exercise improves cognition and cerebrovascular regulation in older adults. Neurology. 2020;94(21):e2245&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000009478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7357295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvid LG, Harwood DL, Eskildsen SF, Dalgas U. A critical systematic review of current evidence on the effects of physical exercise on whole/regional grey matter brain volume in populations at risk of neurodegeneration. Sports Med. 2021;51:1651&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01453-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33861414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colcombe S, Kramer AF. Fitness effects on the cognitive function of older adults: a meta-analytic study. Psychol Sci. 2003;14(2):125&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-9280.t01-1-01430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12661673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss MW, Heo S, Prakash RS, Erickson KI, Alves H, Chaddock L, et al. The influence of aerobic fitness on cerebral white matter integrity and cognitive function in older adults: results of a one-year exercise intervention. Hum Brain Mapp. 2013;34(11):2972&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.22119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4096122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22674729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young J, Angevaren M, Rusted J, Tabet N. Aerobic exercise to improve cognitive function in older people without known cognitive impairment. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;4:CD005381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10554155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens JA, Berryhill ME. Older adults improve on everyday tasks after working memory training and neurostimulation. Brain Stimul. 2016;9(4):553&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brs.2016.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4957521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27178247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carral JMC, Curras DM, P&#xe9;rez CA, Su&#xe1;rez MHV. Effects of two programmes of combined land-based and water-based exercise on the cognitive function and fitness levels of healthy older adults. Motriz. 2017;23: e101641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PJ, Blumenthal JA, Hoffman BM, Cooper H, Strauman TA, Welsh-Bohmer K, et al. Aerobic exercise and neurocognitive performance: a meta-analytic review of randomized controlled trials. Psychosom Med. 2010;72(3):239&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PSY.0b013e3181d14633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2897704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20223924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Zhen K, Su Q, Chen Y, Lv Y, Yu L. The effect of aerobic exercise on cognitive function in people with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(23):15481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192315700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9736612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36497772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper KH. Aerobics program for total well-being: exercise, diet, and emotional balance. New York: Bantam; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millstein R. Aerobic exercise. In: Gellman MD, Turner JR, editors. Encyclopedia of behavioral medicine. New York: Springer; 2020. p. 61&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang JY, Lee JS, Kang H, Lee HW, Kim YK, Jeon HJ, et al. Regional cerebral blood flow abnormalities associated with apathy and depression in Alzheimer disease. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord. 2012;26(3):217&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WAD.0b013e318231e5fc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21959363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vito A, Calamia M, Greening S, Roye S. The association of anxiety, depression, and worry symptoms on cognitive performance in older adults. Aging Neuropsychol Cogn. 2019;26(2):161&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13825585.2017.1416057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29261012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penninx BW, Rejeski WJ, Pandya J, Miller ME, Di Bari M, Applegate WB, et al. Exercise and depressive symptoms: a comparison of aerobic and resistance exercise effects on emotional and physical function in older persons with high and low depressive symptomatology. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2002;57(2):P124&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geronb/57.2.P124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11867660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenthal JA, Babyak MA, Moore KA, Craighead WE, Herman S, Khatri P, et al. Effects of exercise training on older patients with major depression. Arch Intern Med. 1999;159(19):2349&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.159.19.2349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10547175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliss ES, Wong RH, Howe PR, Mills DE. The effects of aerobic exercise training on cerebrovascular and cognitive function in sedentary, obese, older adults. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14: 892343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2022.892343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9158462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35663579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McSween MP, Coombes JS, MacKay CP, Rodriguez AD, Erickson KI, Copland DA, et al. The immediate effects of acute aerobic exercise on cognition in healthy older adults: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2019;49:67&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-01039-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30560422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malin SK, Stewart NR, Ude AA, Alderman BL. Brain insulin resistance and cognitive function: influence of exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2022;133(3):748&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9744647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36269295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Alvarado CJ. Aerobic exercise as a protective factor in older adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Mex J Med Res ICSA. 2023;11(22):54&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29057/mjmr.v11i22.10631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afradi M. The effect of aerobics in the elderly. Int J Psychol Brain Sci. 2023;8(2):19&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wang L, Yan J, Yuan X, Lou QQ. Aerobic training increases hippocampal volume and protects cognitive function for type 2 diabetes patients with normal cognition. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes. 2023;131(11):605&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2105-0799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37268011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Xiao H. Exercise intervention for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: unraveling neurobiological mechanisms and assessing effects. Life. 2023;13(12):2285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life13122285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10744739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38137886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varma VR, Chuang YF, Harris GC, Tan EJ, Carlson MC. Low-intensity daily walking activity is associated with hippocampal volume in older adults. Hippocampus. 2015;25(5):605&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hipo.22397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4425252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25483019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams A, Nobari H, Afonso J, Abbasi H, Mainer-Pardos E, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, et al. Effect of aerobic-based exercise on psychological well-being and quality of life among older people: a Middle East study. Front Public Health. 2021;9: 764044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.764044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8685315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34938705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venturelli M, Scarsini R, Schena F. Six-month walking program changes cognitive and ADL performance in patients with Alzheimer. Am J Alzheimers Dis Other Demen. 2011;26(5):381&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1533317511418956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10845333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21852281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester J, Dick M, Gillen D, Reed B, Miller B, Tinklenberg J, et al. Walking stabilizes cognitive functioning in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease (AD) across one year. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2013;56(1):96&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2012.06.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3766353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22959822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Voss MW, Prakash RS, Basak C, Szabo A, Chaddock L, et al. Exercise training increases size of hippocampus and improves memory. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108(7):3017&#x2013;22. 10.1073/pnas.1015950108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1015950108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3041121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira L, Tanaka K, Santos-Galdur&#xf3;z RF, Galdur&#xf3;z JCF. Respiratory training as strategy to prevent cognitive decline in aging: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Interv Aging. 2015;10:593&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4374650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25848235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lautenschlager NT, Cox KL. Can participation in mental and physical activity protect cognition in old age? JAMA Intern Med. 2013;173(9):805&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2013.206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23545757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Miller DL, Weinstein AM, Akl SL, Banducci S. Physical activity and brain plasticity in late adulthood: a conceptual and comprehensive review. Ageing Res. 2012;3(1):6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ar.2012.e6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babyak M, Blumenthal JA, Herman S, Khatri P, Doraiswamy M, Moore K, et al. Exercise treatment for major depression: maintenance of therapeutic benefit at 10 months. Psychosom Med. 2000;62(5):633&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006842-200009000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11020092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng A, Zhao Z, Liu H, Yang J, Luo J. The physiological mechanism and effect of resistance exercise on cognitive function in the elderly people. Front Public Health. 2022;10:1013734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2022.1013734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9723356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36483263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Gamboa R, Moncada-Jim&#xe9;nez J. Acute effect of resistance training on cognitive function of Costa Rican older adults. Int J Phys Educ Fitness Sports. 2022;11(2):13&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero-Odasso M, Zou G, Speechley M, Almeida QJ, Liu-Ambrose T, Middleton LE, et al. Effects of exercise alone or combined with cognitive training and vitamin D supplementation to improve cognition in adults with mild cognitive impairment: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6(7): e2324465. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.24465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.24465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10359965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37471089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinchman CA, Cabral DF, Ciesla M, Flothmann M, Nunez C, Rice J, et al. Exercise engagement drives changes in cognition and cardiorespiratory fitness after 8 weeks of aerobic training in sedentary aging adults at risk of cognitive decline. Front Rehabil Sci. 2022;3: 923141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fresc.2022.923141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greeley B, Larssen B, Ferris J, Yeganeh N, Andrushko J, Chau B, et al. Improved cognition after high-intensity exercise paired with motor practice in individuals with stroke and older adults: a randomized controlled trial. medRxiv. 2023. 10.1101/2023.03.15.23287321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2023.03.15.23287321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonsson E, Levik Sandstr&#xf6;m S, Hedlund M, Holmberg H, Johansson B, Lindel&#xf6;f N, et al. Effects of controlled supramaximal high-intensity interval training on cardiorespiratory fitness and global cognitive function in older adults: the Ume&#xe5; HIT study&#x2014;a randomized controlled trial. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2023;78(9):1581&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glad070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10460559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36972981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowllah IM, Lopez-Alvarenga J, Maestre GE, Karabulut U, Lehker M, Karabulut M. Relationship between cognitive performance, physical activity, and socio-demographic/individual characteristics among aging Americans. J Alzheimers Dis. 2023;95(2):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10693475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36847008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bixby WR, Spalding TW, Haufler AJ, Deeny SP, Mahlow PT, Zimmerman JB, et al. The unique relation of physical activity to executive function in older men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1408&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e31806ad708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders LM, Hortobagyi T, la Bastide-van GS, van der Zee EA, van Heuvelen MJ. Dose-response relationship between exercise and cognitive function in older adults with and without cognitive impairment: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(1): e0210036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0210036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6328108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30629631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhidong C, Wang X, Yin J, Song D, Chen Z. Effects of physical exercise on working memory in older adults: a systematic and meta-analytic review. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2021;18:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11556-021-00272-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscari A, Giannoni C, Pierpaoli L, Berzigotti A, Maietta P, Foschi E, et al. Chronic endurance exercise training prevents aging-related cognitive decline in healthy older adults: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2010;25(10):1055&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gps.2462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20033904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes S. Supporting physical activity behaviour change in adults with obstructive sleep apnoea [dissertation]. Dunedin: University of Otago; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker LD, Frank LL, Foster-Schubert K, Green PS, Wilkinson CW, McTiernan A, et al. Effects of aerobic exercise on mild cognitive impairment: a controlled trial. Arch Neurol. 2010;67(1):71&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2009.307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20065132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronese N, Soysal P, Demurtas J, Solmi M, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Christodoulou N, et al. Physical activity and exercise for the prevention and management of mild cognitive impairment and dementia: a collaborative international guideline. Eur Geriatr Med. 2023;14(5):925&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41999-023-00858-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37768499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matura S, Fleckenstein J, Deichmann R, Engeroff T, F&#xfc;z&#xe9;ki E, Hattingen E, et al. Effects of aerobic exercise on brain metabolism and grey matter volume in older adults: results of the randomised controlled SMART trial. Transl Psychiatry. 2017;7(7): e1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/tp.2017.135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5538117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28934191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang P, Fang R, Li B-Y, Chen S-D. Exercise-related changes of networks in aging and mild cognitive impairment brain. Front Aging Neurosci. 2016;8:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2016.00047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4779936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27014055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SM, Choi M, Chun B-O, Sun K, Kim KS, Kang SW, et al. Effects of a high-intensity interval physical exercise program on cognition, physical performance, and electroencephalogram patterns in Korean elderly people: a pilot study. Dement Neurocognitive Disord. 2022;21(3):93&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12779/dnd.2022.21.3.93</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35949421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mundada PH, Dadgal RM, Dadgal R. Comparison of dual task training versus aerobics training in improving cognition in healthy elderly population. Cureus. 2022;14(9): e29231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekari S, Neyedli HF, Fraser S, O&#x2019;Brien MW, Martins R, Evans K, et al. High-intensity interval training improves cognitive flexibility in older adults. Brain Sci. 2020;10(11):796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci10110796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7693870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33137993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker LD, Frank LL, Foster-Schubert K, Green PS, Wilkinson CW, McTiernan A, et al. Aerobic exercise improves cognition for older adults with glucose intolerance, a risk factor for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Alzheimers Dis. 2010;22(2):569&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-2010-100768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3049111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durante R, Ainsworth BE. The recall of physical activity: using a cognitive model of the question-answering process. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28(10):1282&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199610000-00012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8897386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky VM, Kraemer WJ, Fry AC. Science and practice of strength training. 3rd ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y-K, Labban J, Gapin J, Etnier JL. The effects of acute exercise on cognitive performance: a meta-analysis. Brain Res. 2012;1453:87&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2012.02.068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22480735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colzato LS, Szapora Ozturk A, Pannekoek JN, Hommel B. The impact of physical exercise on convergent and divergent thinking. Front Hum Neurosci. 2013;7:824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3845014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24348370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, Roschel H, Tavares LD, De Souza EO, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(6):772&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1450898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29564973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C-L, Wang C-H, Pan C-Y, Chen F-C. The effects of long-term resistance exercise on the relationship between neurocognitive performance and GH, IGF-1, and homocysteine levels in the elderly. Front Behav Neurosci. 2015;9:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2015.00023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4322723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif J, Pagaduan J, James C, Dergaa I, Beaven C. Artificial intelligence in sport: exploring the potential of using ChatGPT in resistance training prescription. Biol Sport. 2024;41(2):209&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.132987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10955742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh S-S, Chang Y-K, Hung T-M, Fang C-L. The effects of acute resistance exercise on young and older males&#x2019; working memory. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2016;22:286&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychsport.2015.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh S-S, Chang Y-K, Fang C-L, Hung T-M. Acute resistance exercise facilitates attention control in adult males without an age-moderating effect. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2016;38(3):247&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsep.2015-0282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27382926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh S, Chueh T, Hung T. A literature review on the effects of acute resistance exercise on cognitive function. Bull Sport Exerc Psychol Taiwan. 2017;17:111&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudo M, Costello JT, McMorris T, Ando S. The effects of acute high-intensity aerobic exercise on cognitive performance: a structured narrative review. Front Behav Neurosci. 2022;16: 957677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2022.957677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36212191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow Z-S, Moreland AT, Macpherson H, Teo W-P. The central mechanisms of resistance training and its effects on cognitive function. Sports Med. 2021;51(12):2483&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01535-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonk M, Wikkerink S, Regan K, Middleton LE. Similar changes in executive function after moderate resistance training and loadless movement. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(2): e0212122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0212122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6386275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30794593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho F, Pereira D, Lustosa L, Silva J, Dias J, Dias R, et al. Physical therapy intervention (PTI) increases plasma brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) levels in non-frail and pre-frail elderly women. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2012;54(3):415&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2011.05.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21684022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forti LN, Van Roie E, Njemini R, Coudyzer W, Beyer I, Delecluse C, et al. Dose- and gender-specific effects of resistance training on circulating levels of brain derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) in community-dwelling older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2015;70:144&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2015.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26297701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y-K, Pan C-Y, Chen F-T, Tsai C-L, Huang C-C. Effect of resistance-exercise training on cognitive function in healthy older adults: a review. J Aging Phys Act. 2012;20(4):497&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/japa.20.4.497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22186664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagamatsu LS, Handy TC, Hsu CL, Voss M, Liu-Ambrose T. Resistance training promotes cognitive and functional brain plasticity in seniors with probable mild cognitive impairment. Arch Intern Med. 2012;172(8):666&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2012.379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22529236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Ambrose T, Nagamatsu LS, Graf P, Beattie BL, Ashe MC, Handy TC. Resistance training and executive functions: a 12-month randomized controlled trial. Arch Intern Med. 2010;170(2):170&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2009.494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh MAF, Gates N, Saigal N, Wilson GC, Meiklejohn J, Brodaty H, et al. The Study of Mental and Resistance Training (SMART) study&#x2014;resistance training and/or cognitive training in mild cognitive impairment: a randomized, double-blind, double-sham controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2014;15(12):873&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2014.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25444575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallah N, Hsu CL, Bolandzadeh N, Davis J, Beattie BL, Graf P, et al. A multistate model of cognitive dynamics in relation to resistance training: the contribution of baseline function. Ann Epidemiol. 2013;23(8):463&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annepidem.2013.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4476840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23830936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F-T, Hopman RJ, Huang C-J, Chu C-H, Hillman CH, Hung T-M, et al. The effect of exercise training on brain structure and function in older adults: a systematic review based on evidence from randomized control trials. J Clin Med. 2020;9(4):914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9040914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7230405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32230708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossers WJ, van der Woude LH, Boersma F, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Scherder EJ, van Heuvelen MJ. A 9-week aerobic and strength training program improves cognitive and motor function in patients with dementia: a randomized, controlled trial. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2015;23(11):1106&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jagp.2014.12.191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25648055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makizako H, Doi T, Shimada H, Yoshida D, Tsutsumimoto K, Uemura K, et al. Does a multicomponent exercise program improve dual-task performance in amnestic mild cognitive impairment? A randomized controlled trial. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2012;24(6):640&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03654853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23211228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo Quezada H, Mart&#xed;nez-Salazar C, Fuentealba-Urra S, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Mosqueira C, Araneda Garc&#xe9;s N, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rodr&#xed;guez F, et al. Effects of two physical training programs on the cognitive status of a group of older adults in Chile. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(8):4186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18084186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su-Ju E. The effects of combined exercise on cognitive and fitness factors in elderly women with mild cognitive impairment. Korean J Fusion Ayurveda. 2022;13:115&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52251/kja.2022.13.115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mravec B. Possible involvement of the vagus nerve in monitoring plasma catecholamine levels. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2006;86(3):353&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nlm.2006.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16860579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moor T, Mundorff L, Bohringer A, Philippsen C, Langewitz W, Reino ST, et al. Evidence that baroreflex feedback influences long-term incidental visual memory in men. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2005;84(3):168&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nlm.2005.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16111901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthoud H-R, Neuhuber WL. Functional and chemical anatomy of the afferent vagal system. Auton Neurosci. 2000;85(1):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1566-0702(00)00215-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11189015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atzori M, Cuevas-Olguin R, Esquivel-Rendon E, Garcia-Oscos F, Salgado-Delgado RC, Saderi N, et al. Locus ceruleus norepinephrine release: a central regulator of CNS spatio-temporal activation? Front Synaptic Neurosci. 2016;8:25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnsyn.2016.00025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27616990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler DJ. Evidence for a specialized role of the locus coeruleus noradrenergic system in cortical circuitries and behavioral operations. Brain Res. 2016;1641(Pt B):197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2015.11.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26607255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell J, Zeppenfeld D, McConnell E, Pena S, Nedergaard M. Norepinephrine: a neuromodulator that boosts the function of multiple cell types to optimize CNS performance. Neurochem Res. 2012;37(11):2496&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11064-012-0818-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3548657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22717696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozendaal B, McEwen BS, Chattarji S. Stress, memory and the amygdala. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2009;10(6):423&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn2651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19469026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandi C, Pinelo-Nava MT. Stress and memory: behavioral effects and neurobiological mechanisms. Neural Plast. 2007;2007:78970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2007/78970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1950232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18060012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colcombe SJ, Erickson KI, Scalf PE, Kim JS, Prakash R, McAuley E, et al. Aerobic exercise training increases brain volume in aging humans. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61(11):1166&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/61.11.1166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss MW, Prakash RS, Erickson KI, Basak C, Chaddock L, Kim JS, et al. Plasticity of brain networks in a randomized intervention trial of exercise training in older adults. Front Aging Neurosci. 2010;2:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2947936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20890449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Asteasu MLS, Cuevas-Lara C, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Mart&#xed;nez-Velilla N, Zambom-Ferraresi F, et al. Effects of physical exercise on the incidence of delirium and cognitive function in acutely hospitalized older adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Alzheimers Dis. 2022;87(2):503&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-220103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35275553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marco EM, Garc&#xed;a-Guti&#xe9;rrez MS, Berm&#xfa;dez-Silva F-J, Moreira F, Guimar&#xe3;es F, Manzanares J, et al. Endocannabinoid system and psychiatry: in search of a neurobiological basis for detrimental and potential therapeutic effects. Front Behav Neurosci. 2011;5:63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2011.00063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3186912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22007164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash RS, Voss MW, Erickson KI, Lewis JM, Chaddock L, Malkowski E, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness and attentional control in the aging brain. Front Hum Neurosci. 2011;4:229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2010.00229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21267428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelcker-Rehage C, Niemann C. Structural and functional brain changes related to different types of physical activity across the life span. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2013;37(9 Pt B):2268&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2013.01.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23399048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein AM, Voss MW, Prakash RS, Chaddock L, Szabo A, White SM, et al. The association between aerobic fitness and executive function is mediated by prefrontal cortex volume. Brain Behav Immun. 2012;26(5):811&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2011.11.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3321393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22172477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier CJ, Lefort M, Mekary S, Desjardins-Cr&#xe9;peau L, Skimminge A, Iversen P, et al. Hearts and minds: linking vascular rigidity and aerobic fitness with cognitive aging. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36(1):304&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.08.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25308963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper C. Anatomical and physiological mechanisms of arousal, with special reference to the effects of exercise. Ergonomics. 1973;16(5):601&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140137308924551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4772986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schley D, Carare-Nnadi R, Please CP, Perry VH, Weller RO. Mechanisms to explain the reverse perivascular transport of solutes out of the brain. J Theor Biol. 2006;238(4):962&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtbi.2005.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16112683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C-L, Ukropec J, Ukropcov&#xe1; B, Pai M-C. An acute bout of aerobic or strength exercise specifically modifies circulating exerkine levels and neurocognitive functions in elderly individuals with mild cognitive impairment. Neuroimage Clin. 2018;17:272&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2017.10.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5842646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29527475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C-L, Pai M-C, Ukropec J, Ukropcov&#xe1; B. Distinctive effects of aerobic and resistance exercise modes on neurocognitive and biochemical changes in individuals with mild cognitive impairment. Curr Alzheimer Res. 2019;16(4):316&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1567205016666190228125429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30819077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu-Ambrose T, Nagamatsu LS, Voss MW, Khan KM, Handy TC. Resistance training and functional plasticity of the aging brain: a 12-month randomized controlled trial. Neurobiol Aging. 2012;33(8):1690&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.05.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21741129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coetsee C, Terblanche E. Cerebral oxygenation during cortical activation: the differential influence of three exercise training modalities. A randomized controlled trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:1617&#x2013;27. 10.1007/s00421-017-3646-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3646-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28567669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujach S, Olek RA, Byun K, Suwabe K, Sitek EJ, Ziemann E, et al. Acute sprint interval exercise increases both cognitive functions and peripheral neurotrophic factors in humans: the possible involvement of lactate. Front Neurosci. 2020;14: 490460. 10.3389/fnins.2020.490460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2020.490460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6989590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32038149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riske L, Thomas RK, Baker GB, Dursun SM. Lactate in the brain: an update on its relevance to brain energy, neurons, glia, and panic disorder. Ther Adv Psychopharmacol. 2017;7(2):85&#x2013;9. 10.1177/2045125316675579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2045125316675579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5315230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28255438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks GA. The science and translation of lactate shuttle theory. Cell Metab. 2018;27(4):757&#x2013;85. 10.1016/j.cmet.2018.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2018.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29617642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marston KJ, Newton MJ, Brown BM, Rainey-Smith SR, Bird S, Martins RN, et al. Intense resistance exercise increases peripheral brain-derived neurotrophic factor. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(10):899&#x2013;903. 10.1016/j.jsams.2017.03.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2017.03.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lira FS, de Freitas MC, Gerosa-Neto J, Cholewa JM, Rossi FE. Comparison between full-body vs. split-body resistance exercise on the brain-derived neurotrophic factor and immunometabolic response. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(11):3094&#x2013;102. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33105359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B, Sewell-Loftin MK. Mechanoregulation of vascular endothelial growth factor receptor 2 in angiogenesis. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8: 804934. 10.3389/fcvm.2021.804934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2021.804934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8787114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35087885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer M, Chida Y. Physical activity and risk of neurodegenerative disease: a systematic review of prospective evidence. Psychol Med. 2009;39(1):3&#x2013;11. 10.1017/S0033291708003681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291708003681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18570697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Asteasu MLS, Mart&#xed;nez-Velilla N, Zambom-Ferraresi F, Casas-Herrero &#xc1;, Izquierdo M. Role of physical exercise on cognitive function in healthy older adults: a systematic review of randomized clinical trials. Ageing Res Rev. 2017;37:117&#x2013;34. 10.1016/j.arr.2017.05.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2017.05.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28587957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman SB, Aslan S, Spence JS, DeFina LF, Keebler MW, Didehbani N, et al. Shorter term aerobic exercise improves brain, cognition, and cardiovascular fitness in aging. Front Aging Neurosci. 2013;5:75. 10.3389/fnagi.2013.00075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2013.00075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3825180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24282403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenze EJ, Voegtle M, Miller JP, Ances BM, Balota DA, Barch D, et al. Effects of mindfulness training and exercise on cognitive function in older adults: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2022;328(22):2218&#x2013;29. 10.1001/jama.2022.21680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.21680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9856438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36511926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Ben SH. Artificial intelligence and promoting open access in academic publishing. Tunis Med. 2023;101(6):533&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11261472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38372545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>