<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">23008521</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-3711</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>98</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the experimental analysis of behavior</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exp Anal Behav</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance to extinction and relapse in combined stimulus contexts.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>169</StartPage><EndPage>189</EndPage><MedlinePgn>169-89</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Reinforcing an alternative response in the same context as a target response reduces the rate of occurrence but increases the persistence of that target response. Applied researchers who use such techniques to decrease the rate of a target problem behavior risk inadvertently increasing the persistence of the same problem behavior. Behavioral momentum theory asserts that the increased persistence is a function of the alternative reinforcement enhancing the Pavlovian relation between the target stimulus context and reinforcement. A method showing promise for reducing the persistence-enhancing effects of alternative reinforcement is to train the alternative response in a separate stimulus context before combining with the target stimulus in extinction. The present study replicated previous findings using pigeons by showing that combining an "alternative" richer VI schedule (96 reinforcers/hr) with a "target" leaner VI schedule (24 reinforcers/hr) reduced resistance to extinction of target responding compared with concurrent training of the alternative and target responses (totaling 120 reinforcers/hr). We also found less relapse with a reinstatement procedure following extinction with separate-context training, supporting previous findings that training conditions similarly influence both resistance to extinction and relapse. Finally, combining the alternative stimulus context was less disruptive to target responding previously trained in the concurrent schedule, relative to combining with the target response trained alone. Overall, the present findings suggest the technique of combining stimulus contexts associated with alternative responses with those associated with target responses disrupts target responding. Furthermore, the effectiveness of this disruption is a function of training context of reinforcement for target responding, consistent with assertions of behavioral momentum theory.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Podlesnik</LastName><ForeName>Christopher A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, The University of Auckland, Private Bag 92019, Victoria Street West, Auckland 1142, New Zealand. c.podlesnik@auckland.ac.nz</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>John Y H</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elliffe</LastName><ForeName>Douglas</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Exp Anal Behav</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0203727</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-5002</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010856" MajorTopicYN="N">Columbidae</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003216" MajorTopicYN="N">Conditioning, Operant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005108" MajorTopicYN="N">Extinction, Psychological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012055" MajorTopicYN="N">Reinforcement Schedule</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012054" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reinforcement, Psychology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behavioral momentum theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compound stimuli</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent schedules</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extinction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">key peck</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pigeon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance to change</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23008521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3449854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1901/jeab.2012.98-169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="sici">jeab-98-02-03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andrew B. J, Harris J. A. Summation of reinforcement rates when conditioned stimuli are presented in compound. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Animal Behavior Processes. 2011;37:385&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21787099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin A, Pearce J. M. Some determinants of response summation. Animal Learning and Behavior. 1997;25:108&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belke T. W. Stimulus preference and the transitivity of preference. Animal Learning &amp; Behavior. 1992;20:401&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell M. C, Williams B. A. Preference and resistance to change in concurrent variable-interval schedules. Animal Learning &amp; Behavior. 2002;30:34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12017966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown P. L, Jenkins H. M. Auto-shaping of the pigeon's key-peck. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1968;11:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1338436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5636851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr E. G, Durand V. M. Reducing behavior problems with functional communication training. Journal of Applied Behavior Analysis. 1985;18:111&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1307999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2410400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edmon E. L, Lucki I, Grisham M. G. Choice responding following multiple schedule training. Animal Learning &amp; Behavior. 1980;8:287&#x2013;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flesher M, Hoffman H. S. A progression for generating variable-interval schedules. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1962;5:529&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1404199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13945507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbon J. Dynamics of time matching: Arousal makes better seem worse. Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review. 1995;2:208&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24203655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrnstein R. J. Relative and absolute strength of response as a function of frequency of reinforcement. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1961;4:267&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1404074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13713775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honig W. K. Prediction of preference, transposition, transposition-reversal from the generalization gradient. Journal of Experimental Psychology. 1962;64:239&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13908710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehoe E. J. Summation and configuration in conditioning of the rabbit's nictitating membrane response to compound stimuli. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Animal Behavior Processes. 1986;12:186&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3819649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehoe E. J, Horne A. J, Horne P. S, Macrae M. Summation and configuration between and within sensory modalities in classical conditioning of the rabbit. Animal Learning &amp; Behavior. 1994;22:19&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lionello-DeNolf K. M, Dube W. V. Contextual influences on resistance to disruption in children with intellectual disabilities. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2011;96:317&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3212999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22084493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long C. K, Allen J. D. Stimulus compounding in pigeons. Bulletin of the Psychonomic Society. 1974;4:95&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mace C. F, McComas J. J, Mauro B. C, Progar P. R, Taylor B, Ervin R, Zangrillo A. N. Differential reinforcement of alternative behavior increases resistance to extinction: Clinical demonstration, animal modeling, and clinical test of one solution. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2010;93:349&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2861874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21119850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller L. Compounding of discriminative stimuli from the same and different sensory modalities. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1971;16:337&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1333934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5150044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misak P, Cleaveland J. M. Preference as a function of active interresponse times: A test of the active time model. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2011;96:215&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3168888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21909165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDevitt M. A, Williams B. A. Arousal, changeover responses, and preference in concurrent schedules. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 2003;80:261&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14964707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean A. P, Campbell-Tie P, Nevin J. A. Resistance to change as a function of stimulus&#x2013;reinforcer and location&#x2013;reinforcer contingencies. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1996;66:169&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1284567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16812822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A. Stimuli, reinforcers, and the persistence of behavior. The Behavior Analyst. 2009;32:285&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2941144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20852739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A, Mandell C, Yarensky P. Response rate and resistance to change in chained schedules. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Animal Behavior Processes. 1981;7:278&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A, Grace R. C. Behavioral momentum and the law of effect. Behavioral and Brain Sciences. 2000;23:73&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11303339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A, McLean A. P, Grace R., C. Resistance to extinction: Contingency termination and generalization decrement. Animal Learning and Behavior. 2001;29:176&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A, Shahan T. A. Behavioral momentum: Equations and applications. Journal of Applied Behavior Analysis. 2011;44:877&#x2013;895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3251288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A, Tota M. E, Torquato R. D, Shull R. L. Alternative reinforcement increases resistance to change: Pavlovian or operant contingencies. Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior. 1990;53:359&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1322963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2341820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevin J. A, Wacker D. P. . Response strength and persistence. In: Madden G. J, editor. Handbook of behavior analysis: Volume 2. Washington D.C: American Psychological Association; in press. In. (Ed.)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce J. M, George D. N, Aydin A. Summation: Further assessment of a configural theory. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology. 2002;55:61&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11900307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petscher E. S, Rey C, Bailey J. A. A review of empirical support for differential reinforcement of alternative behavior. Research in Developmental Disabilities. 2009;30:409&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlesnik C. A, Shahan T. A. Response-reinforcer relations and resistance to change. Behavioural Processes. 2008;77:109&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17706897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlesnik C. A, Shahan T. A. Behavioral momentum and relapse of extinguished operant responding. Learning &amp; Behavior. 2009;37:357&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2829303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19815932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlesnik C.A, Shahan T. A. Extinction, relapse, and behavioral momentum. Behavioural Processes. 2010;84:400&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20152889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rescorla R. A, Wagner A. R. A theory of Pavlovian conditioning: Variations in the effectiveness of reinforcement and nonreinforcement. In: Black A. H, Prokasy W. K, editors. Classical conditioning II: Current research and theory. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts; 1972. pp. 64&#x2013;99). In. (Eds.) (pp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner A. R. Evolution of an elemental theory of Pavlovian conditioning. Learning &amp; Behavior. 2008;36:253&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18683469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>