<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39172814</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Accelerating automatic model finding with layer replications case study of MobileNetV2.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0308852</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0308852</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0308852</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0308852</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this paper, we propose a method to reduce the model architecture searching time. We consider MobileNetV2 for 3D face recognition tasks as a case study and introducing the layer replication to enhance accuracy. For a given network, various layers can be replicated, and effective replication can yield better accuracy. Our proposed algorithm identifies the optimal layer replication configuration for the model. We considered two acceleration methods: distributed data-parallel training and concurrent model training. Our experiments demonstrate the effectiveness of the automatic model finding process for layer replication, using both distributed data-parallel and concurrent training under different conditions. The accuracy of our model improved by up to 6% compared to the previous work on 3D MobileNetV2, and by 8% compared to the vanilla MobileNetV2. Training models with distributed data-parallel across four GPUs reduced model training time by up to 75% compared to traditional training on a single GPU. Additionally, the automatic model finding process with concurrent training was 1,932 minutes faster than the distributed training approach in finding an optimal solution.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2024 Soongswang, Chantrapornchai. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soongswang</LastName><ForeName>Kritpawit</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Kasetsart University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chantrapornchai</LastName><ForeName>Chantana</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8699-5736</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Kasetsart University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>PLoS One. 2025 Aug 4;20(8):e0329645. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0329645.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">40758636</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086762" MajorTopicYN="N">Automated Facial Recognition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D021621" MajorTopicYN="N">Imaging, Three-Dimensional</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39172814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11340936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0308852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-24-06262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Romphet P, Kajkamhaeng S, Chantrapornchai C. Optimizing MobileNetV2 Architecture Using Split Input and Layer Replications for 3D Face Recognition Task. In: Advanced Data Mining and Applications: (ADMA), Proceedings, Part II. Springer; 2022. p. 103&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soongswang K, Romphet P, Chantrapornchai C. Enhancing MobileNetV2 Performance with Layer Replication and Splitting for 3D Face Recognition Task Using Distributed Training. In: 2023 International Technical Conference on Circuits/Systems, Computers, and Communications (ITC-CSCC); 2023. p. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Zhao Y, Varma R, Salpekar O, Noordhuis P, Li T, et al. PyTorch distributed: experiences on accelerating data parallel training. Proc VLDB Endow. 2020;13(12):3005&#x2013;3018. doi: 10.14778/3415478.3415530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14778/3415478.3415530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt J. Advanced guide to Python 3 programming. Springer; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandler M, Howard A, et al. MobilenetV2: Inverted residuals and linear bottlenecks. In: Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition; 2018. p. 4510&#x2013;4520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Wu F, Shao X, Wang Y, Zhou X. Joint 3d face reconstruction and dense alignment with position map regression network. In: Proceedings of the European conference on computer vision (ECCV); 2018. p. 534&#x2013;551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang B, Ren Q, Dai F, Xiong J, Yang J, Gui G. Multi-task cascaded convolutional neural networks for real-time dynamic face recognition method. In: Communications, Signal Processing, and Systems: Proceedings of the 2018 CSPS Volume III: Systems 7th. Springer; 2020. p. 59&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abadi M, Agarwal A, Barham P, Brevdo E, Chen Z, Citro C, et al. Tensorflow: Large-scale machine learning on heterogeneous distributed systems. arXiv preprint arXiv:160304467. 2016;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paszke A, Gross S, Massa F, Lerer A, Bradbury J, Chanan G, et al. Pytorch: An imperative style, high-performance deep learning library. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems. 2019;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal P, Doll&#xe1;r P, Girshick R, Noordhuis P, Wesolowski L, Kyrola A, et al. Accurate, large minibatch sgd: Training imagenet in 1 hour. arXiv preprint arXiv:170602677. 2017;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehin I, Islam MS, Saha P, Noman SM, Tuni A, Hasan MM, et al. AutoML: A systematic review on automated machine learning with neural architecture search. Journal of Information and Intelligence. 2024;2(1):52&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.jiixd.2023.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiixd.2023.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Ge C, Chen H, Sun X. PreNAS: preferred one-shot learning towards efficient neural architecture search. In: Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning. ICML&#x2019;23. JMLR.org; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsken T, Metzen JH, Hutter F. Neural Architecture Search: A survey. Journal of Machine Learning Research. 2019;20(55):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Simonyan K, Yang Y. DARTS: Differentiable Architecture Search. In: International Conference on Learning Representations; 2019.Available from: https://openreview.net/forum?id=S1eYHoC5FX.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Hernandez M, Choi J, Medioni G. Deep 3D face identification. In: 2017 IEEE International Joint Conference on Biometrics (IJCB); 2017. p. 133&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y, Lei Y, Yang M, You Z, Shan S. A fast and robust 3D face recognition approach based on deeply learned face representation. Neurocomputing. 2019;363:375&#x2013;397. doi: 10.1016/j.neucom.2019.07.047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2019.07.047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BenchCouncil International AI System and Algorithm Challenge. Challenges 2019; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskar NS, Mudigere D, Nocedal J, Smelyanskiy M, Tang PTP. On Large-Batch Training for Deep Learning: Generalization Gap and Sharp Minima. In: Proceedings of 5th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR). Toulon, France; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Zhang W, Wang F. Model Accuracy and Runtime Tradeoff in Distributed Deep Learning: A Systematic Study. In: 2016 IEEE 16th International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM); 2016. p. 171&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>