<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">33730398</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Concurrent endurance and resistance training enhances muscular adaptations in individuals with metabolic syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1440</StartPage><EndPage>1449</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1440-1449</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.13950</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of the study was to determine if concurrent training (endurance and resistance in a single session) elicits leg muscular adaptations beyond the ones obtained by endurance training alone in sedentary individuals with metabolic syndrome (MetS). Sixty-six MetS individuals (37% women, age 56&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;7&#xa0;years, BMI 32&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;5&#xa0;kg&#xa0;m<sup>-2</sup> and 3.8&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.8 MetS factors) were randomized to undergo one of the following 16-week isocaloric exercise programs: (i) 4&#xa0;+&#xa0;1 bouts of 4&#xa0;min at 90% of HR<sub>MAX</sub> of intense aerobic cycling (IAC&#xa0;+&#xa0;IAC group; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;33), (ii) 4 IAC bouts followed by 3 sets of 12 repetitions of 3 lower-limb free-weight exercises (IAC&#xa0;+&#xa0;RT group; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;33). We measured the effects of training on maximal cycling power, leg press maximum strength (1RM), countermovement jump height (CMJ), and mean propulsive velocity (MPV) at workloads ranging from 10% to 100% of baseline 1RM leg press. After intervention, MetS components (Z-score) improved similarly in both groups (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.002). Likewise, maximal cycling power during a ramp test improved similarly in both groups (time effect p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). However, leg press 1RM improved more in IAC&#xa0;+&#xa0;RT than in IAC&#xa0;+&#xa0;IAC (47&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;5 vs 13&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;5&#xa0;kg, respectively, interaction p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). CMJ only improved with IAC&#xa0;+&#xa0;RT (0.8&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.2&#xa0;cm, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.001). Leg press MPV at heavy loads (ie, 80%-100% 1RM) improved more with concurrent training (0.12&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.01 vs 0.06&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.02&#xa0;m&#xa0;s<sup>-1</sup> , interaction p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.013). In conclusion, in unconditioned MetS individuals, intense aerobic cycling alone improves leg muscle performance. However, substituting 20% of intense aerobic cycling by resistance training further improves 1RM leg press, MPV at high loads, and jumping ability while providing similar improvement in MetS components.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moreno-Caba&#xf1;as</LastName><ForeName>Alfonso</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Lab at Toledo, University of Castilla-La Mancha, Toledo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortega</LastName><ForeName>Juan Fernando</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Lab at Toledo, University of Castilla-La Mancha, Toledo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morales-Palomo</LastName><ForeName>Felix</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Lab at Toledo, University of Castilla-La Mancha, Toledo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramirez-Jimenez</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Lab at Toledo, University of Castilla-La Mancha, Toledo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alvarez-Jimenez</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Lab at Toledo, University of Castilla-La Mancha, Toledo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mora-Rodriguez</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9252-4933</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Lab at Toledo, University of Castilla-La Mancha, Toledo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>DEP-2017-83244-R</GrantID><Agency>Spanish Ministry of Economy, Industry and Competivity</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001642" MajorTopicYN="N">Bicycling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007866" MajorTopicYN="N">Leg</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057185" MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055105" MajorTopicYN="N">Waist Circumference</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016526" MajorTopicYN="N">Workload</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concurrent training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intense aerobic cycling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscular adaptations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training.</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33730398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, Vellas B, Evans WJ, et al. Sarcopenia: an undiagnosed condition in older adults. Current consensus definition: prevalence, etiology, and consequences. International working group on sarcopenia. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2011;12(4):249-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straight CR, Lindheimer JB, Brady AO, Dishman RK, Evans EM. Effects of resistance training on lower-extremity muscle power in middle-aged and older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Med. 2016;46(3):353-364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson ME, Rejeski WJ, Blair SN, et al. Physical activity and public health in older adults: recommendation from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1435-1445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1334-1359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr ZY, Collins CL, Comstock RD. Epidemiology of weight training-related injuries presenting to United States emergency departments, 1990 to 2007. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38(4):765-771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostman C, Smart NA, Morcos D, Duller A, Ridley W, Jewiss D. The effect of exercise training on clinical outcomes in patients with the metabolic syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2017;16(1):110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman LA, Slentz CA, Willis LH, et al. Comparison of aerobic versus resistance exercise training effects on metabolic syndrome (from the Studies of a Targeted Risk Reduction Intervention Through Defined Exercise - STRRIDE-AT/RT). Am J Cardiol. 2011;108(6):838-844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Palomo F, Ramirez-Jimenez M, Ortega JF, Lopez-Galindo PL, Fernandez-Martin J, Mora-Rodriguez R. Effects of repeated yearly exposure to exercise-training on blood pressure and metabolic syndrome evolution. J Hypertens. 2017;35(10):1992-1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mottillo S, Filion KB, Genest J, et al. The metabolic syndrome and cardiovascular risk a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010;56(14):1113-1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Rodriguez R, Ortega JF, Hamouti N, et al. Time-course effects of aerobic interval training and detraining in patients with metabolic syndrome. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2014;24(7):792-798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Palomo F, Ramirez-Jimenez M, Ortega JF, Mora-Rodriguez R. Effectiveness of aerobic exercise programs for health promotion in metabolic syndrome. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(9):1876-1883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>South MA, Layne AS, Stuart CA, et al. Effects of short-term free-weight and semiblock periodization resistance training on metabolic syndrome. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(10):2682-2696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11(4):209-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, McGee JE, Earnest CP, Carlisle E, Nygard M, Johannsen NM. The effects of exercise and physical activity on weight loss and maintenance. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2018;61(2):206-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Caba&#xf1;as A, Ortega JF, Morales-Palomo F, Ramirez-Jimenez M, Alvarez-Jimenez L, Mora-Rodriguez R. Substitution of parts of aerobic training by resistance training lowers fasting hyperglycemia in individuals with metabolic syndrome. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2020;46(1):69-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurca R, Lamonte MJ, Church TS, et al. Associations of muscle strength and fitness with metabolic syndrome in men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(8):1301-1307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harber MP, Konopka AR, Douglass MD, et al. Aerobic exercise training improves whole muscle and single myofiber size and function in older women. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2009;297(5):R1452-R1459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Kraemer WJ, Gorostiaga EM. Effects of combined resistance and cardiovascular training on strength, power, muscle cross-sectional area, and endurance markers in middle-aged men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;94(1-2):70-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell DI, Cuneo R, Gass GC. Can aerobic training improve muscle strength and power in older men? J Aging Phys Act. 2010;18(1):14-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffield-Moore M, Yeckel CW, Volpi E, et al. Postexercise protein metabolism in older and younger men following moderate-intensity aerobic exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;287(3):E513-E522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short KR, Vittone JL, Bigelow ML, Proctor DN, Nair KS. Age and aerobic exercise training effects on whole body and muscle protein metabolism. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;286(1):E92-E101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stensvold D, Tjonna AE, Skaug EA, et al. Strength training versus aerobic interval training to modify risk factors of metabolic syndrome. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108(4):804-810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tjonna AE, Lee SJ, Rognmo O, et al. Aerobic interval training versus continuous moderate exercise as a treatment for the metabolic syndrome: a pilot study. Circulation. 2008;118(4):346-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett JA, Winters-Stone K, Nail LM, Scherer J. Definitions of sedentary in physical-activity-intervention trials: a summary of the literature. J Aging Phys Act. 2006;14(4):456-477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig CL, Marshall AL, Sjostrom M, et al. International physical activity questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(8):1381-1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti KG, Eckel RH, Grundy SM, et al. Harmonizing the metabolic syndrome: a joint interim statement of the International Diabetes Federation Task Force on Epidemiology and Prevention; National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; American Heart Association; World Heart Federation; International Atherosclerosis Society; and International Association for the Study of Obesity. Circulation. 2009;120(16):1640-1645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook RF, Billings DW, Hersch RK, Back AS, Hendrickson A. A field test of a web-based workplace health promotion program to improve dietary practices, reduce stress, and increase physical activity: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2007;9(2):e17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ. Designing Resistance Training Programs, 4th edn. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backholer K, Wong E, Freak-Poli R, Walls HL, Peeters A. Increasing body weight and risk of limitations in activities of daily living: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2012;13(5):456-468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer E. On simple formulae for calculating the heat expenditure and the quantities of carbohydrate and fat oxidized in metabolism of men and animals, from gaseous exchange (Oxygen intake and carbonic acid output) and urine-N. Acta Physiol Pharmacol Neerl. 1957;6:795-802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Rodriguez R, Ortega JF, Guio de Prada V, et al. Effects of Simultaneous or Sequential Weight Loss Diet and Aerobic Interval Training on Metabolic Syndrome. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37(4):274-281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Cabanas A, Ortega JF, Morales-Palomo F, Ramirez-Jimenez M, Mora-Rodriguez R. Importance of a verification test to accurately assess VO2 max in unfit individuals with obesity. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(3):583-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobbert MF, Gerritsen KG, Litjens MC, Van Soest AJ. Why is countermovement jump height greater than squat jump height? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28(11):1402-1412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritti-Dias RM, Avelar A, Salvador EP, Cyrino ES. Influence of previous experience on resistance training on reliability of one-repetition maximum test. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(5):1418-1422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L. Movement velocity as a measure of loading intensity in resistance training. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31(5):347-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o F, Fernandes J, Lewis M, Gonzal&#xe9;z-Badillo JJ, Jimen&#xe9;z-Reyes P. Movement velocity as a measure of exercise intensity in three lower limb exercises. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(12):1099-1106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(9):1725-1734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaric S. Force-velocity relationship of muscles performing multi-joint maximum performance tasks. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36(9):699-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences, 2nd edn. Hillsdale, NJ: Taylor &amp; Francis; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalapotharakos VI, Tokmakidis SP, Smilios I, Michalopoulos M, Gliatis J, Godolias G. Resistance training in older women: effect on vertical jump and functional performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2005;45(4):570-575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Runge M, Rittweger J, Russo CR, Schiessl H, Felsenberg D. Is muscle power output a key factor in the age-related decline in physical performance? A comparison of muscle cross section, chair-rising test and jumping power. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2004;24(6):335-340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Iba&#xf1;ez J, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Kraemer WJ, Larri&#xf3;n JL, Gorostiaga EM. Once weekly combined resistance and cardiovascular training in healthy older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(3):435-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuoco A, Callahan DM, Sayers S, Frontera WR, Bean J, Fielding RA. Impact of muscle power and force on gait speed in disabled older men and women. J Gerontol Series A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2004;59(11):1200-1206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Sui X, Lobelo F, et al. Association between muscular strength and mortality in men: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2008;337(7661):a439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes J, Powell-Griner E, Lethbridge-Cejku M, Heyman K. Aging differently: Physical limitations among adults aged 50 years and over: United States, 2001-2007. NCHS Data Brief. 2009;20:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straight CR, Brady AO, Evans EM. Muscle quality in older adults: what are the health implications? Am J Lifestyle Med. 2015;9(2):130-136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smilios I, Sotiropoulos K, Christou M, Douda H, Spaias A, Tokmakidis SP. Maximum power training load determination and its effects on load-power relationship, maximum strength, and vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(5):1223-1233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh H, Kim D, Kim E, et al. Jump test performance and sarcopenia status in men and women, 55 to 75 years of age. J Geriatr Phys Ther (2001). 2014;37(2):76-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassey EJ, Fiatarone MA, O'Neill EF, Kelly M, Evans WJ, Lipsitz LA. Leg extensor power and functional performance in very old men and women. Clin Sci (London, England: 1979). 1992;82(3):321-327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Iba&#xf1;ez J, Gorostiaga E, et al. Maximal strength and power characteristics in isometric and dynamic actions of the upper and lower extremities in middle-aged and older men. Acta Physiol Scand. 1999;167(1):57-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargeant AJ, Jones DA. The significance of motor unit variability in sustaining mechanical output of muscle. Adv Exp Med Biol. 1995;384:323-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harber MP, Konopka AR, Undem MK, et al. Aerobic exercise training induces skeletal muscle hypertrophy and age-dependent adaptations in myofiber function in young and older men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113(9):1495-1504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson SB, Phillips SM, Atherton PJ, et al. Differential effects of resistance and endurance exercise in the fed state on signalling molecule phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human muscle. J Physiol. 2008;586(15):3701-3717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Samozino P. Interpreting power-force-velocity profiles for individualized and specific training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(2):267-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackland TR, Lohman TG, Sundgot-Borgen J, et al. Current status of body composition assessment in sport: review and position statement on behalf of the ad hoc research working group on body composition health and performance, under the auspices of the I.O.C. Medical Commission. Sports Med. 2012;42(3):227-249.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>