<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21526071</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1735-7136</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of research in medical sciences : the official journal of Isfahan University of Medical Sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Res Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effectiveness of two energy drinks on selected indices of maximal cardiorespiratory fitness and blood lactate levels in male athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>127</StartPage><EndPage>132</EndPage><MedlinePgn>127-32</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Consumption of energy drinks has become widespread among athletes. The effectiveness of Red Bull and Hype energy drinks on selected indices of maximal cardiorespiratory fitness and blood lactate levels in male athletes was examined in this study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">TEN MALE STUDENT ATHLETES (AGE: 22.4 &#xb1; 2.1 years, height: 180.8 &#xb1; 7.7 cm, weight: 74.2 &#xb1; 8.5 kg) performed three randomized maximal oxygen consumption tests on a treadmill. Each test was separated by four days and participants were asked to ingest Red Bull, Hype or placebo drinks 40 minutes before the exercise bout. The VO (2max), time to exhaustion, heart rate and lactate were measured to determine if the caffeine-based beverages influence performance. ANOVA test was used for analyzing data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A greater value was observed in VO (2max)and time to exhaustion for the Red Bull and Hype trial compared to the placebo trial (p &lt; 0.05). No significant difference was found in pre-and post-test heart rate for two drinks (p &gt; 0.05). For blood lactate levels no significant changes were observed before and two minute after the test (p &gt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Ingestion of Red Bull and Hype prior to exercise testing is effective on some indices of cardiorespiratory fitness but not on the blood lactate levels.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahnama</LastName><ForeName>Nader</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Associate Professor, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaeini</LastName><ForeName>Abbas Ali</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kazemi</LastName><ForeName>Fahimeh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Res Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101235599</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1735-1995</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Lactate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Drink</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Male Athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Taurine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VO2max</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interests</b> Authors have no conflict of interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21526071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mueller E, Rado L, Weise M, Cass T. Effects of red bull on wingate testing of college aged students. J Undergrad Kin Res. 2007;2(2):12&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvajal-Sancho A, Moncada-Jimenez J. The acute effect of an energy drink on physical and cognitive performance of male athletes. Kinesiologia Slovenica. 2005;11(2):5&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gei&#xdf; KR, Jester I, Falke W, Hamm M, Waag KL. The effect of a taurine-containing drink on performance in 10 endurance-athletes. Amino Acids. 1994;7(1):45&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24185972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alford C, Cox H, Wescott R. The effects of red bull energy drink on human performance and mood. Amino Acids. 2001;21(2):139&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum M, Wei&#xdf; M. The influence of a taurine containing drink on cardiac parameters before and after exercise measured by echocardiography. Amino Acids. 2001;20(1):75&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11310932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umana-Alvarado M, Moncada-Jim&#xe9;nez J. The effect of an energy drink on aerobic performance in male athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(5):S174&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byars A, Greenwood M, Greenwood L, Simpson WK. The effectiveness of a pre-exercise performance drink (PRX) on indices of maximal cardiorespiratory fitness. ;3(1):56-9. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2006;3(1):56&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2129156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18500964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahnama N, Younesian A, Mohammadion M, Bambaeichi E. A 90 minute soccer match decreases triglyceride and low density lipoprotein but not high-density lipoprotein and cholesterol levels. J Res Med Sci. 2009;14(6):335&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3129076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21772906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahnama N, Nouri R, Rahmaninia F, Damirchi A, Emami H. The effects of exercise training on maximum aerobic capacity, rest heart beat, blood pressure and anthropometric variables of postmenopausal women with breast cancer. J Res Med Sci. 2010;15(2):78&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21526063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaillzadeh A, Azadbakht L. Major dietary patterns in relation to general obesity and central adiposity among Iranian women. J Nutr. 2008;138(2):358&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18203904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azali Alamdari K, Kordi MR, Choobineh S, Abbasi A. Acute effects of two energy drinks on anaerobic power and blood lactate levels in male athletes. Physic Educ Sport. 2007;5(2):153&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC. 2 nd ed. Boulder: Bull Pub Co; 1990. Fitness and sports medicine: an introduction; p. 583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niles ES, Lachowetz T, Garfi J, Sullivan W, Smith JC, Leyh BP, et al. Carbohydrate-protein drink improves time to exhaustion after recovery from endurance exercise. J Exerc Physiol. 2001;4(1):45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barthel T, Mechau D, Wehr T, Schnittker R, Liesen H, Wei&#xdf; M. Readiness potential in different states of physical activation and after ingestion of taurine and/or caffeine containing drinks. Amino Acids. 2001;20(1):63&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11310931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Mazic S. Effects of a carbohydrate-electrolyte drink on specific soccer tests and performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2002;1(2):47&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24688270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanna GL, Manna I. Supplementary effect of carbohydrate-electrolyte drink on sports performance, lactate removal &amp; cardiovascular response of athletes. Indian J Med Res. 2005;121(5):665&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15937370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielson A, Morris L, Neiderhauser L, Stanek K, Wolter J. The physiological effects of water vs.Gatorade during prolonged exercise. J Undergrad Kin Res. 2006;1(2):15&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardo JA. Supplements and athletes. South Med J. 2004;97(9):877&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15455977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim W. Debunking the effects of taurine in red bull energy drink. Nutr Bytes. 2003;9(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArdle WD. Philadelphia: Lea and Febiger; 1994. Essentials of exercise physiology. .Abridged ed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers S, Howley ET. 5th ed. Boston: McGraw Hill Higher Education; 2003. Exercise physiology: theory and application to fitness and performance.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurer J. Tucson: Desert Southwest Fitness Inc; 2005. Sports beverages.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ. Nutritional ergogenic aids and exercise performance. Nutr Res Rev. 1999;12(2):255&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sungpil R, Choi SK, Joung SS, Heajung S, Cha YS, Soochun L, et al. Caffeine as a lipolytic food component increases endurance performance in rats and athletes. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol. 2001;47(2):139&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11508705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Izumi I, Kagamimori S, Sokejima S, Yamagami T, Liu Z, et al. Role of taurine supplementation to prevent exercise-induced oxidative stress in healthy young men. Amino Acids. 2004;26(2):203&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15042451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bichler A, Swenson A, Harris MA. A combination of caffeine and taurine has no effect on short term memory but induces changes in heart rate and mean arterial blood pressure. Amino Acids. 2006;31(4):471&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16699827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>