<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27990227</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a Pre-workout Energy Drink Supplement on Upper Body Muscular Endurance Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>667</StartPage><EndPage>676</EndPage><MedlinePgn>667-676</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The use of pre-workout beverages is becoming an increasingly common method of improving performance during exercise in athletic and recreationally active populations. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of a commercially available energy drink on exercise performance. Thirty-one healthy males (n=23) and females (n=8) participated in this study and were separated into two groups: supplement (SU; n=16) or placebo (PL; n=15). Subjects visited the laboratory on 2 occasions separated by no more than 7 days. The first visit consisted of completing a push up to fatigue protocol (PUFP) without ingesting the pre-workout energy drink supplement (PWEDS). The second visit consisted of ingesting either a placebo or the PWEDS 30 minutes prior to completing the PUFP. Rate of perceived exertion (RPE) was recorded following each set of pushups on both testing days. Also, participant's height, weight, and body composition were collected. There was no significant differences at baseline in any variable between groups (p = &gt;.05). After the second testing session, both groups significantly improved total push-ups (PL Pre: 133.3 &#xb1;39.4, PL Post: 155.3 &#xb1; 54.1; SU Pre: 139.3 &#xb1; 58.5, SU Post: 161.3 &#xb1; 79.4; p=&lt;.001), and push-ups completed in each of the 3 sets (p=&lt;.001), when compared to baseline. Post-testing revealed no significant difference between groups in total push-ups completed or RPE at any time point, when compared to baseline. In conclusion, the commercially available PWEDS offered no additional ergogenic effects when compared to the placebo.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Magrini</LastName><ForeName>Mitchel A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Human Performance, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colquhoun</LastName><ForeName>Ryan J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Human Performance, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dawes</LastName><ForeName>J Jay</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, University of Colorado Colorado Springs, Colorado Springs, CO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Doug B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Human Performance, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy drink</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27990227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5154715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/JJZR6040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beck TW, Housh TJ, Schmidt RJ, Johnson GO, Housh DJ, Coburn JW, Malek MH. The acute effects of a caffeine-containing supplement on strength, muscular endurance, and anaerobic capabilities. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):506&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloms LP, Fitzgerald JS, Short MW, Whitehead JR. The Effects of Caffeine on Vertical Jump Height and Execution in Collegiate Athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;30(7):1855&#x2013;1861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26626028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM. Caffeine and Sports Performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33:1319&#x2013;1334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell B, Wilborn C, La Bounty P, Taylor L, Nelson MT, Greenwood M, Ziegenfuss TN, Lopez HL, Hoffman JR, Stout JR, Schmitz S, Collins R, Kalman DS, Antonio J, Kreider RB. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: energy drinks. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3538552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier NB, Hardy MA, Millard-Stafford M, Warren GL. Small Beneficial Effect of Caffeinated Energy Drink Ingestion on Strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;30(7):1862&#x2013;1870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26670991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowe MJ, Leicht AS, Spinks WL. Physiological and cognitive responses to caffeine during repeated, high-intensity exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2006;16(5):528&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17240784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Zhao Z, Stock HS, Mehl KA, Buggy J, Hand GA. Central nervous system effects of caffeine and adenosine on fatigue. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2003;284(2):R399&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12399249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawes JJ, Campbell BI, Ocker LB, Carter JG, Temple DR, Brooks KA. The Effects of a Pre-Workout Energy Drink on Measures of Physical Performance. Int J Phys Educ Fitness Sports. 2014;3(4):122&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawes JJ, Richmond J, Melrose D, Ocker L, Edwards SW, Brooks KA, Willis D. The effects of a commercial liquid energy supplement on physical performance, reaction time, and mood state in college-aged males and females. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10(1):1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Little JP, Magnus C, Chilibeck PD. Effect of Red Bull energy drink on repeated Wingate cycle performance and bench-press muscle endurance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(5):433&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18046053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm BB, B&#xe4;ttig K, Holm&#xe9;n J, Nehlig A, Zvartau EE. Actions of caffeine in the brain with special reference to factors that contribute to its widespread use. Pharmacol Rev. 1999;51(1):83&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10049999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froiland K, Koszewski W, Hingst J, Kopecky L. Nutritional supplement use among college athletes and their sources of information. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2004;14:104&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15129934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein ER, Ziegenfuss T, Kalman D, Kreider R, Campbell B, Wilborn C, Taylor L, Willoughby D, Stout J, Graves BS, Wildman R, Ivy JL, Spano M, Smith AE, Antonio J. International society of sports nutrition position stand: caffeine and performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7(1):5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Walsh AL, Ratamess NA, Kang J, Hoffman JR. Effect of a pre-workout energy supplement on acute multi-joint resistance exercise. J Sports Sci Med. 2011;10(2):261&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Spriet LL. Performance and metabolic responses to a high caffeine dose during prolonged exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1991;71(6):2292&#x2013;2298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1778925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer F, McLean C, Graham TE. Caffeine, performance, and metabolism during repeated Wingate exercise tests. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85(4):1502&#x2013;1508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9760347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris R, Edwards R, Hultman E, Nordesj&#xf6; L, Nylind B, Sahlin K. The time course of phosphorylcreatine resynthesis during recovery of the quadriceps muscle in man. Pfl&#xfc;gers Archiv. 1976;367(2):137&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1034909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Faigenbaum AD, Ratamess NA, Ross R, Kang J, Tenenbaum G. Nutritional supplementation and anabolic steroid use in adolescents. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(1):15&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18091024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Kang J, Ratamess NA, Hoffman MW, Tranchina CP, Faigenbaum AD. Examination of a pre-exercise, high energy supplement on exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2621122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Ross R, Shanklin M, Kang J, Faigenbaum AD. Effect of a pre-exercise energy supplement on the acute hormonal response to resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(3):874&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy JL, Kammer L, Ding Z, Wang B, Bernard JR, Liao YH, Hwang J. Improved cycling time-trial performance after ingestion of a caffeine energy drink. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19(1):61&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman Jay R, ADF, Ratamess Nicholas A, Ross Ryan, Kang Jie, Tenenbaum Gershon. Nutritional Supplementation and anabolic steroid use in adolescents. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(1):15&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18091024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar JM. The influence of caffeine on voluntary muscle activation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(12):2113&#x2013;2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16331138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddalozzo GF, Cardinal BJ, Snow CA. Concurrent validity of the BOD POD and dual energy x-ray absorptiometry techniques for assessing body composition in young women. J Am Dietetic Assoc. 2002;102(11):1677&#x2013;1679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12449296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallares JG, Fernandez-Elias VE, Ortega JF, Munoz G, Munoz-Guerra J, Mora-Rodriguez R. Neuromuscular Responses to Incremental Caffeine Doses: Performance and Side Effects. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(11):2184&#x2013;2192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23669879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petr&#xf3;czi A, Naughton DP, Pearce G, Bailey R, Bloodworth A, McNamee M. Nutritional supplement use by elite young UK athletes: fallacies of advice regarding efficacy. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2008;5(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19077317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson RJ, Goss FL, Rutkowski J, Lenz B, Dixon C, Timmer J, Frazee K, Dube J, Andreacci J. Concurrent validation of the OMNI perceived exertion scale for resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(2):333&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12569225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet LL. Caffeine and performance. Int J Sport Nutr. 1995;5(Suppl):S84&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7550260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vescovi JD, Zimmerman SL, Miller WC, Hildebrandt L, Hammer RL, Fernhall B. Evaluation of the BOD POD for estimating percentage body fat in a heterogeneous group of adult humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;85(3&#x2013;4):326&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11560087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh AL, Gonzalez AM, Ratamess NA, Kang J, Hoffman JR. Improved time to exhaustion following ingestion of the energy drink Amino Impact. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2861014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20398312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>