<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39907147</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6519</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in clinical nutrition and metabolic care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of lifestyle factors across the life course on sarcopenia and physical frailty.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>208</StartPage><EndPage>223</EndPage><MedlinePgn>208-223</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCO.0000000000001111</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Muscle health helps maintain locomotor capacity, a key component of intrinsic capacity, which is required for healthy ageing. Sarcopenia is characterized by the age-related decline in muscle mass and strength leading to impaired physical performance, and has been described as a biological substrate of physical frailty. Both sarcopenia and physical frailty share phenotypic features of weakness and slowness, lead to common adverse outcomes, and have potential for reversal through early identification and intervention. The purpose of this review is to present recent evidence for the impact of lifestyle interventions across the life course on sarcopenia and physical frailty.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Resistance exercise alone or combined with balance and aerobic training as part of a multicomponent exercise program and high-quality diets incorporating adequate protein remain the mainstay of treatment for sarcopenia and physical frailty. Reducing sedentary time and increasing physical activity, adherence to Mediterranean diet, increasing vegetable and caffeinated beverage intake, cardiovascular risk factor modification, improving sleep hygiene and depressive symptoms may also contribute to slowing down age-related decline in muscle health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Lifestyle interventions such as physical activity, diet, sleep and mental health are effective against sarcopenia and physical frailty. Targeting lifestyle modifications in early to midlife may retard further decline in locomotor capacity and optimize intrinsic capacity of older persons, reducing the risk of sarcopenia, physical frailty and their attendant negative health outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Daphne Zihui</ForeName><Initials>DZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Geriatrics and Active Aging, Tan Tock Seng Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kua</LastName><ForeName>Joanne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Geriatrics and Active Aging, Tan Tock Seng Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Wee Shiong</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Medicine.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Geriatrics and Active Aging, Tan Tock Seng Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lee Kong Chian School of Medicine, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804399</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1363-1950</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073496" MajorTopicYN="Y">Frailty</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008019" MajorTopicYN="Y">Life Style</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000375" MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016330" MajorTopicYN="N">Frail Elderly</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical frailty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39907147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000001111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00075197-990000000-00201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Veronese N, Honvo G, Amuthavalli Thiyagarajan J, et al. Attributes and definitions of locomotor capacity in older people: a World Health Organisation (WHO) locomotor capacity working group meeting report. Aging Clin Exp Res 2022; 34:481&#x2013;483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk B, Cawthon PM, Arai H, et al. The conceptual definition of sarcopenia: Delphi Consensus from the Global Leadership Initiative in Sarcopenia (GLIS). Age Ageing 2024; 53:afae052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landi F, Calvani R, Cesari M, et al. Sarcopenia as the biological substrate of physical frailty. Clin Geriatr Med 2015; 31:367&#x2013;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji S, Jung HW, Baek JY, et al. Sarcopenia as the mobility phenotype of aging: clinical implications. J Bone Metab 2024; 31:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu LK, Guo CY, Lee WJ, et al. Subtypes of physical frailty: latent class analysis and associations with clinical characteristics and outcomes. Sci Rep 2017; 7:46417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried LP, Tangen CM, Walston J, et al. Frailty in older adults: evidence for a phenotype. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2001; 56:M146&#x2013;M156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis [published correction appears in Age Ageing. Age Ageing 2019; 48:601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzolino D, Spolidoro GCI, Saporiti E, et al. Musculoskeletal changes across the lifespan: nutrition and the life-course approach to prevention. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021; 8:697954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen X, Wang C, Zhou X, et al. Nonlinear dynamics of multi-omics profiles during human aging. Nat Aging 2024; 4:1619&#x2013;1634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Lepe MA, Ortiz-Ortiz M, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Ontiveros DA, Mej&#xed;a-Rangel MJ. Inflammatory profile of older adults in response to physical activity and diet supplementation: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health . 2023; 20f:4111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo YX, Zhou XH, Heng T, et al. Bidirectional transitions of sarcopenia states in older adults: the longitudinal evidence from CHARLS. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2024; 15:1915&#x2013;1929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro LW, Berndt S, Mielke GI, et al. Factors associated with handgrip strength across the life course: a systematic review. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haapanen MJ, Mikkola TM, Jylh&#xe4;v&#xe4; J, et al. Lifestyle-related factors in late midlife as predictors of frailty from late midlife into old age: a longitudinal birth cohort study. Age Ageing 2024; 53:afae066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Merchant RA, Morley JE, et al. International Exercise Recommendations in Older Adults (ICFSR): expert consensus guidelines. J Nutr Health Aging 2021; 25:824&#x2013;853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med 2020; 54:1451&#x2013;1462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, Atkinson EJ, Aversa Z, et al. Biomarkers of cellular senescence predict the onset of mobility disability and are reduced by physical activity in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2024; 79:glad257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst C, Robinson SM, Witham MD, et al. Resistance exercise as a treatment for sarcopenia: prescription and delivery. Age Ageing 2022; 51:afac003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma N, Chahal A, Balasubramanian K, et al. Effects of resistance training on muscular strength, endurance, body composition and functional performance among sarcopenic patients: a systematic review. J Diabetes Metab Disord 2023; 22:1053&#x2013;1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YC, Chen WC, Liu CW, et al. Is moderate resistance training adequate for older adults with sarcopenia? A systematic review and network meta-analysis of RCTs. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act 2023; 20:22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha JNS, Pereira-Monteiro MR, Vasconcelos ABS, et al. Different resistance training volumes on strength, functional fitness, and body composition of older people: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Arch Gerontol Geriatr 2024; 119:105303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Rosa Orssatto LB, de la Rocha Freitas C, Shield AJ, et al. Effects of resistance training concentric velocity on older adults&#x2019; functional capacity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised trials. Exp Gerontol 2019; 127:110731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Martin KI, Doros G, et al. Comparative effects of light or heavy resistance power training for improving lower extremity power and physical performance in mobility-limited older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2015; 70:374&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x10c;retnik K, Ple&#x161;a J, Kozinc Z, et al. The effect of eccentric vs. traditional resistance exercise on muscle strength, body composition, and functional performance in older adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Sports Act Living 2022; 4:873718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cve&#x10d;ka J, Vajda M, Novotn&#xe1; A, et al. Benefits of eccentric training with emphasis on demands of daily living activities and feasibility in older adults: a literature review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2023; 20:3172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Shi Q, Nong K, et al. Exercise for sarcopenia in older people: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2023; 14:1199&#x2013;1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues IB, Ching P, Kalra M, et al. Exploring the perspectives of older adults who are prefrail and frail to identify interventions to reduce sedentary behaviour and improve mobility: a thematic content analysis. BMC Public Health 2024; 24:1582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez JL, He L, Morales JS, et al. Association of physical behaviours with sarcopenia in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Lancet Healthy Longev 2024; 5:e108&#x2013;e119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Liu D, Zhang H, et al. Associations of physical activity intensity, frequency, duration, and volume with the incidence of sarcopenia in middle-aged and older adults: a 4-year longitudinal study in China. BMC Geriatr 2024; 24:258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo Y, Zhou Y, Chan H, et al. The association between sedentary behaviour and sarcopenia in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr 2023; 23:877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seino S, Abe T, Nofuji Y, et al. Dose-response associations between physical activity and sedentary time with functional disability in older adults with or without frailty: a prospective cohort study. Front Public Health 2024; 12:1357618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim GY, Jang HC, Kim KW, Lim JY. Differences in sarcopenia status and mortality according to physical activity: results from the Korean Longitudinal Study on Health and Aging (KLoSHA). Eur Geriatr Med 2024; 15:667&#x2013;676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson S, Granic A, Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Sayer AA. The role of nutrition in the prevention of sarcopenia. Am J Clin Nutr 2023; 118:852&#x2013;864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim MY, Nam YD. Gut microbiome in healthy aging versus those associated with frailty. Gut Microbes 2023; 15:2278225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Deutz NEP, Volpi E, Apovian CM. Nutritional interventions: dietary protein needs and influences on skeletal muscle of older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2023; 78: (Suppl 1): 67&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ML, Zhang F, Luo HY, et al. Improving sarcopenia in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials of whey protein supplementation with or without resistance training. J Nutr Health Aging 2024; 28:100184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao CD, Huang SW, Chen HC, et al. Comparative efficacy of different protein supplements on muscle mass, strength, and physical indices of sarcopenia among community-dwelling, hospitalized or institutionalized older adults undergoing resistance training: a network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Nutrients 2024; 16:941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hettiarachchi J, Reijnierse EM, Kew N, et al. The effect of dose, frequency, and timing of protein supplementation on muscle mass in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev 2024; 99:102325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez LJ, Donat-Vargas C, Sayon-Orea C, et al. Rationale of the association between Mediterranean diet and the risk of frailty in older adults and systematic review and meta-analysis. Exp Gerontol 2023; 177:112180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton-Chubb D, Vaughan NV, George ES, et al. Mediterranean diet and ultra-processed food intake in older Australian adults-associations with frailty and cardiometabolic conditions. Nutrients 2024; 16:2978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulou SK, Detopoulou P, Voulgaridou G, et al. Mediterranean diet and sarcopenia features in apparently healthy adults over 65 years: a systematic review. Nutrients 2023; 15:1104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosti V, Bertozzi B, Fontana L. Health benefits of the Mediterranean diet: metabolic and molecular mechanisms. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2018; 73:318&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan Y, Qi Q, Gao T, et al. Plant-based diet and risk of frailty in older Chinese adults. J Nutr Health Aging 2023; 27:371&#x2013;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Rodriguez J, Ortol&#xe1; R, Garc&#xed;a-Esquinas E, et al. Quality of plant-based diets and frailty incidence: a prospective analysis of UK biobank participants. Age Ageing 2024; 53:afae092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diao H, Yan F, He Q, et al. Association between dietary inflammatory index and sarcopenia: a meta-analysis. Nutrients 2023; 15:219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SH, Bae YJ. Association of dietary vegetable and fruit consumption with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 2024; 16:1707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua KY, Li H, Sheng LT, et al. Intake of vegetables and fruits at midlife and the risk of physical frailty in later life. J Nutr Health Aging 2024; 28:100374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konglevoll DM, Andersen LF, Hopstock LA, et al. Fish intake and prefrailty in Norwegian older adults - a prospective cohort study: the Troms&#xf8; Study. BMC Geriatr 2023; 23:411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng PT, Zeng BY, Zeng BS, et al. Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids in sarcopenia management: a network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Ageing Res Rev 2023; 90:102014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida Y, Tsuji K, Ochi E. Effects of Omega-3 fatty acids supplementation and resistance training on skeletal muscle. Clin Nutr ESPEN 2024; 61:189&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali S, Corbi G, Medoro A, et al. Relationship between monounsaturated fatty acids and sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Aging Clin Exp Res 2023; 35:1823&#x2013;1834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua KY, Li H, Lim WS, Koh WP. Consumption of coffee, tea, and caffeine at midlife, and the risk of physical frailty in late life. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2023; 24:1655&#x2013;1662. e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Chen H, Liang M. The association between habitual tea consumption and frailty transition in community-dwelling older adults: a prospective cohort study. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2024; 25:259&#x2013;265. e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Suzuki K. The effects of flavonoids on skeletal muscle mass, muscle function, and physical performance in individuals with sarcopenia: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Nutrients 2023; 15:3897.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struijk EA, Fung TT, Bischoff-Ferrari HA, et al. Total magnesium intake and risk of frailty in older women. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2024; 15:1275&#x2013;1282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera FB, Escolano BT, Nifas FM, et al. Interrelationship of sarcopenia and cardiovascular diseases: a review of potential mechanisms and management. J ASEAN Fed Endocr Soc 2024; 39:69&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan Y, Wang C, Wang L, Li G. Geriatric sarcopenia is associated with hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2023; 25:808&#x2013;816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzai S, Persits I, Kazibwe R, et al. Relationship between sarcopenia and intensive blood pressure control efficacy and safety: a secondary analysis of SPRINT. Hypertension 2024; 81:e77&#x2013;e87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Gu Y, Wang X, et al. Association between handgrip strength and Type 2 diabetes: a prospective cohort study and systematic review with meta-analysis. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2023; 78:1383&#x2013;1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boccardi V. Sarcopenia a dive into metabolism to promote a multimodal, preventive, and regenerative approach. Mech Ageing Dev 2024; 219:111941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Li Z, Dang A, et al. Obesity, birth weight, and lifestyle factors for frailty: a Mendelian randomization study. Aging (Albany NY) 2023; 15:14066&#x2013;14085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu YL, Wang C, Zhao C, et al. The association of alcohol consumption with the risk of sarcopenia: a dose-response meta-analysis. Am J Drug Alcohol Abuse 2024; 50:305&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, He J, Sun Q. Sleep duration and sarcopenia: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2023; 24:1193&#x2013;1206. e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Cui J, Cao L, et al. Association of depression with incident sarcopenia and modified effect from healthy lifestyle: the first longitudinal evidence from the CHARLS. J Affect Disord 2024; 344:373&#x2013;379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Yang M, Li M. Causality between sarcopenia-related traits and major depressive disorder: a bi-directional, two-sample Mendelian randomized study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2023; 102:e35071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billot M, Calvani R, Urtamo A, et al. Preserving mobility in older adults with physical frailty and sarcopenia: opportunities, challenges, and recommendations for physical activity interventions. Clin Interv Aging 2020; 15:1675&#x2013;1690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Hermoso A, L&#xf3;pez-Gil JF, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, et al. Adherence to aerobic and muscle-strengthening activities guidelines: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 3.3 million participants across 32 countries. Br J Sports Med 2023; 57:225&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues IB, Ching P, Kalra M, et al. Exploring the perspectives of older adults who are prefrail and frail to identify interventions to reduce sedentary behaviour and improve mobility: a thematic content analysis. BMC Public Health 2024; 24:1582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Huang H, Jiang S, et al. Facilitators and barriers to the implementation of dietary nutrition interventions for community-dwelling older adults with physical frailty and sarcopenia: a qualitative meta-synthesis. Int J Nurs Sci 2023; 11:18&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahony LO, Shea EO, O&#x2019;Connor EM, et al. &#x2019;Good, honest food&#x2019;: older adults&#x2019; and healthcare professionals&#x2019; perspectives of dietary influences and food preferences in older age in Ireland. J Hum Nutr Diet 2023; 36:1833&#x2013;1844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, H&#xf8;jfeldt G, Breen L, et al. Dietary protein requirements and recommendations for healthy older adults: a critical narrative review of the scientific evidence [published correction appears in Nutr Res Rev]. Nutr Res Rev 2023; 36:175.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>