<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33370007</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Perceived Consumption of a High-Dose Caffeine Drink Delays Neuromuscular Fatigue.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1185</StartPage><EndPage>1190</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1185-1190</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003932</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Elhaj, HM, Imam, O, Page, BW, Vitale, JM, and Malek, MH. Perceived consumption of a high-dose caffeine drink delays neuromuscular fatigue. J Strength Cond Res 36(5): 1185-1190, 2022-The placebo effect is a concept in which a desired outcome arises, mainly from the belief that the treatment (i.e., supplement or drug) was beneficial although no active ingredient was given. The results of studies related to the placebo effect primarily examine functional performance. What remains unanswered, however, is whether these changes in performance are associated with neuromuscular alterations in the exercised muscles. The purpose of the study, therefore, was to determine the influence of the placebo effect on the physical working capacity fatigue threshold (PWCFT) for a continuous exercise paradigm. To achieve this aim, subjects were told that they were participating in a study to determine the dosage response (low or high) of caffeine on neuromuscular fatigue when in fact no caffeine was given during the experiment. We hypothesized that the perceived consumption of the high-dose caffeine drink would result in a higher PWCFT than the perceived consumption of the low-dose caffeine drink and placebo. Secondarily, we hypothesized that the perceived consumption of the high-dose caffeine drink would result in a higher power output than the perceived consumption of the placebo. Nine healthy college-aged men (mean &#xb1; SEM: age, 25.7 &#xb1; 1.3 years; body mass, 84.4 &#xb1; 3.1 kg; and height: 1.82 &#xb1; 0.02 m) volunteered to be in the study. For each of the visits, subjects were given an 8 oz. bottle of water with dissolved crystal light. After the drink was consumed, subjects rested in the laboratory for 1 hour before performing the incremental single-leg knee-extensor ergometry. Immediately after the termination of the incremental single-leg knee-extensor ergometry, the subject was asked which caffeine dose (placebo, low, or high) they believed they consumed for that visit. There were no significant mean differences for maximal power output for the 3 perceived conditions (placebo: 62 &#xb1; 3, low-dose caffeine: 62 &#xb1; 4, and high-dose caffeine: 65 &#xb1; 3 W). When the subjects perceived consuming the high-dose caffeine drink, there were significant mean differences (all p-values &lt; 0.01), for PWCFT, between the other conditions (mean &#xb1; SEM: placebo: 23 &#xb1; 3 W, low-dose caffeine: 26 &#xb1; 2 W, and high-dose caffeine: 42 &#xb1; 3 W). This corresponded to a significant mean difference (all p-values &lt; 0.01) when the PWCFT was presented as a percentage of the maximal power output (mean &#xb1; SEM: placebo: 37 &#xb1; 5%, low-dose caffeine: 42 &#xb1; 3%, and high-dose caffeine: 64 &#xb1; 3%). The application of our results may indicate that the subject's expectancy, to caffeine consumption, plays a critical role in delaying the onset of neuromuscular fatigue despite not receiving any caffeine in their drinks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elhaj</LastName><ForeName>Hussein M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Program; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Care Sciences, Integrative Physiology of Exercise Laboratory, Wayne State University, College of Pharmacy and Health Sciences, Detroit, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imam</LastName><ForeName>Osama</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Program; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Care Sciences, Integrative Physiology of Exercise Laboratory, Wayne State University, College of Pharmacy and Health Sciences, Detroit, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Page</LastName><ForeName>Brad W</ForeName><Initials>BW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Program; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Care Sciences, Integrative Physiology of Exercise Laboratory, Wayne State University, College of Pharmacy and Health Sciences, Detroit, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vitale</LastName><ForeName>Joseph M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Program; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Care Sciences, Integrative Physiology of Exercise Laboratory, Wayne State University, College of Pharmacy and Health Sciences, Detroit, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malek</LastName><ForeName>Moh H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Program; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Care Sciences, Integrative Physiology of Exercise Laboratory, Wayne State University, College of Pharmacy and Health Sciences, Detroit, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caffeine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016552" MajorTopicYN="N">Ergometry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33370007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202205000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aoki F, Nagasaki H, Nakamura R. The relation of integrated EMG of the triceps brachii to force in rapid elbow extension. Tohoku J Exp Med 149: 287&#x2013;291, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basmajian JV, De Luca CJ. Muscles Alive, Their Functions Revealed by Electromyography . Baltimore, MD: Williams &amp; Wilkins, 1985. p. 100&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW, Housh TJ, Johnson GO, et al. Effects of a drink containing creatine, amino acids, and protein combined with ten weeks of resistance training on body composition, strength, and anaerobic performance. J Strength Cond Res 21: 100&#x2013;104, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW, Housh TJ, Malek MH, Mielke M, Hendrix R. The acute effects of a caffeine-containing supplement on bench press strength and time to running exhaustion. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1654&#x2013;1658, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW, Housh TJ, Schmidt RJ, et al. The acute effects of a caffeine-containing supplement on strength, muscular endurance, and anaerobic capabilities. J Strength Cond Res 20: 506&#x2013;510, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie CJ. All in the mind? Pain, placebo effect, and ergogenic effect of caffeine in sports performance. Open Access J Sports Med 1: 87&#x2013;94, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie CJ, Foad AJ. The placebo effect in sports performance: A brief review. Sports Med 39: 313&#x2013;329, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie CJ, Stuart EM, Coleman DA, Foad AJ. Placebo effects of caffeine on cycling performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 38: 2159&#x2013;2164, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berdi M, Koteles F, Hevesi K, Bardos G, Szabo A. Elite athletes' attitudes towards the use of placebo-induced performance enhancement in sports. Eur J Sport Sci 15: 315&#x2013;321, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bremer N, Peoples G, Hasler B, et al. Repeated incremental workbouts separated by 1 hour increase the electromyographic fatigue threshold. J Strength Cond Res 35: 1397&#x2013;1402, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briscoe MJ, Forgach MS, Trifan E, Malek MH. Validating the EMG FT from a single incremental cycling testing. Int J Sports Med 35: 566&#x2013;570, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooling J, Pyne D, Fallon K, Fricker P. Characterizing the perception of the placebo effect in sports medicine. Clin J Sport Med 18: 432&#x2013;437, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke MJ, Kaptchuk TJ, Pascual-Leone A. Challenges of differential placebo effects in contemporary medicine: The example of brain stimulation. Ann Neurol 85: 12&#x2013;20, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centala J, Pogorel C, Pummill SW, Malek MH. Listening to fast-temp music delays the onset of neuromuscular fatigue. J Strength Cond Res 34: 617&#x2013;622, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark VR, Hopkins WG, Hawley JA, Burke LM. Placebo effect of carbohydrate feedings during a 40-km cycling time trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 1642&#x2013;1647, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa GCT, Galvao L, Bottaro M, et al. Effects of placebo on bench throw performance of paralympic weightlifting athletes: A pilot study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 16: 9, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derry CJ, Derry S, Moore RA. Caffeine as an analgesic adjuvant for acute pain in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 12: CD009281, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>deVries HA, Moritani T, Nagata A, Magnussen K. The relation between critical power and neuromuscular fatigue as estimated from electromyographic data. Ergonomics 25: 783&#x2013;791, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>deVries HA, Tichy MW, Housh TJ, et al. A method for estimating physical working capacity at the fatigue threshold (PWCFT). Ergonomics 30: 1195&#x2013;1204, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 15: 69&#x2013;78, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Lyons M, Hankey J. Placebo effects of caffeine on short-term resistance exercise to failure. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 4: 244&#x2013;253, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eason T, Gavel CR, Hawley KA, Galen SS, Malek MH. Reliability of the log-transformed EMG amplitude-power output relationship for incremental knee-extensor ergometry. Muscle Nerve 52: 428&#x2013;434, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferris JR, Tomlinson MA, Ward TN, Pepin ME, Malek MH. Reduced electromyographic fatigue threshold after performing a cognitive fatiguing task. J Strength Cond Res 35: 267&#x2013;274, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galen SS, Guffey DR, Coburn JW, Malek MH. Determining the electromyographic fatigue threshold following a single visit exercise test. J Vis Exp, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galen SS, Malek MH. A single electromyographic testing point is valid to monitor neuromuscular fatigue during continuous exercise. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2754&#x2013;2759, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlan KG, Merucci RB, Weaver JJ, Windle TC, Malek MH. Preexhaustion exercise differentially influences neuromuscular fatigue based on habitual physical activity history. J Strength Cond Res 35: 267&#x2013;274, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 10: 361&#x2013;374, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalasountas V, Reed J, Fitzpatrick J. The effect of placebo-induced changes in expectancies on maximal force production in college students. J Appl Sport Psychol 19: 116&#x2013;124, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaptchuk TJ, Miller FG. Placebo effects in medicine. N Engl J Med 373: 8&#x2013;9, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan FL, Lawal JM, Kapture DO, Swingle JD, Malek MH. Revisiting the single visit protocol for determining the electromyographic fatigue threshold. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3503&#x2013;3507, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike T, Yamada N. Anticipation of elbow joint perturbation shortens the onset time of the reflex EMG response in biceps brachii and triceps brachii. Neurosci Lett 412: 56&#x2013;61, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek MH, Coburn JW, Tedjasaputra V. Comparison of electromyographic responses for the superficial quadriceps muscles: Cycle versus knee-extensor ergometry. Muscle Nerve 39: 810&#x2013;818, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek MH, Coburn JW, Tedjasaputra V. Comparison of mechanomyographic amplitude and mean power frequency for the rectus femoris muscle: Cycle versus knee-extensor ergometry. J Neurosci Methods 181: 89&#x2013;94, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse JJ, Pallaska G, Pierce PR, et al. Acute low-dose caffeine supplementation increases electromyographic fatigue threshold in healthy men. J Strength Cond Res 30: 3236&#x2013;3241, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble EB, Pilarski JM, Vora HK, Zuniga JM, Malek MH. Log-transformed electromyography amplitude-power output relationship: Single-leg knee-extensor versus single-leg cycle ergometry. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1311&#x2013;1319, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oikawa SY, Kamal MJ, Webb EK, et al. Whey protein but not collagen peptides stimulate acute and longer-term muscle protein synthesis with and without resistance exercise in healthy older women: A randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr 111: 708&#x2013;718, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering C, Grgic J. Caffeine and exercise: What next? Sports Med 49: 1007&#x2013;1030, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin L, Wang QR, Fang ZL, et al. Effects of three commercially available sports drinks on substrate metabolism and subsequent endurance performance in a postprandial state. Nutrients 9: 377, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson RS, Frank LR, Haseler LJ. Dynamic knee-extensor and cycle exercise: Functional MRI of muscular activity. Int J Sports Med 19: 182&#x2013;187, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaibani A, Frisaldi E, Benedetti F. Placebo response in pain, fatigue, and performance: Possible implications for neuromuscular disorders. Muscle Nerve 56: 358&#x2013;367, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheldon R, Opie-Moran M. The placebo effect in cardiology: Understanding and using it. Can J Cardiol 33: 1535&#x2013;1542, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart-Williams S. The placebo puzzle: Putting together the pieces. Health Psychol 23: 198&#x2013;206, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart-Williams S, Podd J. The placebo effect: Dissolving the expectancy versus conditioning debate. Psychol Bull 130: 324&#x2013;340, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis LA, Arthmire SJ, Baig AM, Goldberg A, Malek MH. Intersession reliability of the EMG signal during incremental cycle ergometry: Quadriceps femoris. Muscle Nerve 44: 937&#x2013;946, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner JA, Deyo RA, Loeser JD, Von Korff M, Fordyce WE. The importance of placebo effects in pain treatment and research. JAMA 271: 1609&#x2013;1614, 1994.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>