<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34611902</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interventions for preventing weight gain after smoking cessation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>CD006219</StartPage><MedlinePgn>CD006219</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD006219</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD006219.pub4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Most people who stop smoking gain weight. This can discourage some people from making a quit attempt and risks offsetting some, but not all, of the health advantages of quitting. Interventions to prevent weight gain could improve health outcomes, but there is a concern that they may undermine quitting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To systematically review the effects of: (1) interventions targeting post-cessation weight gain on weight change and smoking cessation (referred to as 'Part 1') and (2) interventions designed to aid smoking cessation that plausibly affect post-cessation weight gain (referred to as 'Part 2').</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">Part 1 - We searched the Cochrane Tobacco Addiction Group's Specialized Register and CENTRAL; latest search 16 October 2020. Part 2 - We searched included studies in the following 'parent' Cochrane reviews: nicotine replacement therapy (NRT), antidepressants, nicotine receptor partial agonists, e-cigarettes, and exercise interventions for smoking cessation published in Issue 10, 2020 of the Cochrane Library. We updated register searches for the review of nicotine receptor partial agonists.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">Part 1 - trials of interventions that targeted post-cessation weight gain and had measured weight at any follow-up point or smoking cessation, or both, six or more months after quit day. Part 2 - trials included in the selected parent Cochrane reviews reporting weight change at any time point.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">Screening and data extraction followed standard Cochrane methods. Change in weight was expressed as difference in weight change from baseline to follow-up between trial arms and was reported only in people abstinent from smoking. Abstinence from smoking was expressed as a risk ratio (RR). Where appropriate, we performed meta-analysis using the inverse variance method for weight, and Mantel-Haenszel method for smoking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">Part 1: We include 37 completed studies; 21 are new to this update. We judged five studies to be at low risk of bias, 17 to be at unclear risk and the remainder at high risk.&#xa0; An intermittent very low calorie diet (VLCD) comprising full meal replacement provided free of charge and accompanied by intensive dietitian support significantly reduced weight gain at end of treatment compared with education on how to avoid weight gain (mean difference (MD) -3.70&#x2005;kg, 95% confidence interval (CI)&#x2005;-4.82&#xa0;to&#x2005;-2.58; 1 study, 121 participants), but there was no evidence of benefit at 12 months (MD -1.30&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-3.49&#xa0;to 0.89; 1 study, 62 participants). The VLCD increased the chances of abstinence at 12 months (RR 1.73, 95% CI 1.10 to 2.73; 1 study, 287 participants). However, a second study &#xa0;found that no-one completed the VLCD intervention or achieved abstinence. Interventions aimed at increasing acceptance of weight gain reported mixed effects at end of treatment, 6 months and 12 months with confidence intervals including both increases and decreases in weight gain compared with no advice or health education. Due to high heterogeneity, we did not combine the data. These interventions increased quit rates at 6 months (RR 1.42, 95% CI 1.03 to 1.96; 4 studies, 619 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 21%), but there was no evidence at 12 months (RR 1.25, 95% CI 0.76 to 2.06; 2 studies, 496 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 26%). Some pharmacological interventions tested for limiting post-cessation weight gain (PCWG) reduced weight gain at the end of treatment (dexfenfluramine, phenylpropanolamine, naltrexone). The effects of ephedrine and caffeine combined, lorcaserin, and chromium were too imprecise to give useful estimates of treatment effects. There was very low-certainty evidence that personalized weight management support reduced weight gain at end of treatment (MD -1.11 kg, 95% CI -1.93 to -0.29; 3 studies, 121 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%), but no evidence in the longer-term 12 months (MD -0.44&#x2005;kg, 95% CI -2.34 to 1.46; 4 studies, 530 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 41%). There was low to very low-certainty evidence that detailed weight management education without personalized assessment, planning and feedback did not reduce weight gain and may have reduced smoking cessation rates (12 months: MD -0.21 kg, 95% CI -2.28 to 1.86; 2 studies, 61 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%; RR for smoking cessation 0.66, 95% CI 0.48 to 0.90; 2 studies, 522 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%). Part 2: We include 83 completed studies, 27 of which are new to this update. There was low certainty that exercise interventions led to minimal or no weight reduction compared with standard care at end of treatment (MD -0.25&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-0.78&#xa0;to 0.29; 4 studies, 404 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%). However, weight was reduced at 12 months (MD -2.07&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-3.78&#xa0;to&#x2005;-0.36; 3 studies, 182 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%). Both bupropion and fluoxetine limited weight gain at end of treatment (bupropion MD -1.01&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-1.35&#xa0;to&#x2005;-0.67; 10 studies, 1098 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 3%); (fluoxetine MD -1.01&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-1.49&#xa0;to&#x2005;-0.53; 2 studies, 144 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 38%; low- and very low-certainty evidence, respectively). There was no evidence of benefit at 12 months for bupropion, but estimates were imprecise (bupropion MD -0.26&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-1.31&#xa0;to 0.78; 7 studies, 471 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%). No studies of fluoxetine provided data at 12 months. There was moderate-certainty that NRT reduced weight at end of treatment (MD -0.52&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-0.99 to&#xa0;-0.05; 21 studies, 2784 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 81%) and moderate-certainty that the effect may be similar at 12 months (MD -0.37&#x2005;kg, 95% CI&#x2005;-0.86&#xa0;to 0.11; 17 studies, 1463 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%), although the estimates are too imprecise to assess long-term benefit. There was mixed evidence of the effect of varenicline on weight, with high-certainty evidence that weight change was very modestly lower at the end of treatment (MD -0.23 kg, 95% CI -0.53 to 0.06; 14 studies, 2566 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 32%); a low-certainty estimate gave an imprecise estimate of higher weight at 12 months (MD 1.05 kg, 95% CI -0.58 to 2.69; 3 studies, 237 participants; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">Overall, there is no intervention for which there is moderate certainty of a clinically useful effect on long-term weight gain. There is also no moderate- or high-certainty evidence that interventions designed to limit weight gain reduce the chances of people achieving abstinence from smoking.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartmann-Boyce</LastName><ForeName>Jamie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Theodoulou</LastName><ForeName>Annika</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farley</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health, Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hajek</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wolfson Institute of Preventive Medicine, Barts &amp; The London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lycett</LastName><ForeName>Deborah</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, Coventry University, Coventry, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Laura L</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health, Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kudlek</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heath</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hajizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Anisa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schenkels</LastName><ForeName>Marika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of St. Andrews, St. Andrews, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aveyard</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuffield Department of Primary Care Health Sciences, University of Oxford, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02453659</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01867983</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01199185</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT03528304</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00755716</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00921388</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01305447</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02906644</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02044874</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01401569</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01010204</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00666978</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00935818</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01370356</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00689611</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00794573</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01509547</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT03553173</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00918307</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02859142</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01860924</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01303861</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01517022</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02521662</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00985985</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT01694732</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT03156660</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT00943618</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02417467</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02162849</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT03722966</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT04088942</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>6M3C89ZY6R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009538">Nicotine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012 Jan 18;1:CD006219. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD006219.pub3.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">22258966</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electronic Nicotine Delivery Systems</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009538" MajorTopicYN="N">Nicotine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016540" MajorTopicYN="Y">Smoking Cessation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061485" MajorTopicYN="N">Tobacco Use Cessation Devices</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015430" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Gain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>JHB: co&#x2010;applicant on an award from the Cochrane Review Support Programme. JHB also writes and publishes frequently on the evidence for smoking cessation interventions, and to a lesser extent about evidence on weight management. None of these represent a conflict with what is covered in this review. AT: None. AF: co&#x2010;applicant on a researcher&#x2010;led grant from Ethicon (Johnson and Johnson). PH: research grants, last held in 2015 from Pfizer (funds were received by the institution); Recieved payment for assessing grant applications (GRAND initiative) and attending global advisory board meeting (last attended in 2017); provides invited commentaries, usually concerning an article on e&#x2010;cigarettes for journals (The Lancet, Tobacco Control, Lancet Respiratory and Addiction); was involved in the conduct of a study that was eligible for inclusion in this work which was funded by NIHR. DL: published a press release following publication of a research report; was involved in the conduct studies that were eligible for inclusion in this work: The DeMist Trial: UKCTCS, VLCD provided by Lipotrim (2010) and The SWISSS Trial: NIHR&#x2010;SPCR, Slimming Word vouchers for intervention provide by Slimming World (2013). LLJ: None. LK: None. LH: None. AH: None. MS: None. PA: was involved in the conduct of a study that was eligible for inclusion in this work funded by the School for Primary Care Research. PA and AF (nee Parsons)&#xa0;are also authors of a study included in this review testing the effect of St John's wort and chromium supplements on smoking cessation and post&#x2010;cessation weight gain. The trial was funded by Cancer Research UK and the supplements were bought from the manufacturer. Paul Aveyard has done consultancy work for pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies that has led to payments to him and his institution.&#xa0;This includes work for companies providing smoking cessation medication, including McNeil, Xenova and Pfizer.&#xa0;</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34611902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006219.pub4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies included in this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>1 Baker 2018 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Baker AL, Richmond R, Kay-Lambkin FJ, Filia SL, Castle D, Williams JM, et al. Randomised controlled trial of a healthy lifestyle intervention among smokers with psychotic disorders: Outcomes to 36&#x2009;months. Australian and New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry 2018;52(3):239-52. [DOI: 10.1177/0004867417714336]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004867417714336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28610482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Bloom 2020 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bloom EL, Ramsey SE, Abrantes AM, Hunt L, Wing RR, Kahler CW, et al. A pilot randomized controlled trial of distress tolerance treatment for weight concern in smoking cessation among women. Nicotine and Tobacco Research 2020;22(9):1578-86. [DOI: 10.1093/ntr/ntaa026]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntaa026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7443582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31993658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Bush 2012 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bush T, Levine MD, Beebe LA, Cerutti B, Deprey M, McAfee T, et al. Addressing weight gain in smoking cessation treatment: a randomized controlled trial. American Journal of Health Promotion 2012;27(2):94-102. [CENTRAL: 920998] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23113779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Bush 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bush T, Lovejoy J, Javitz H, Magnusson B, Torres AJ, Mahuna S, et al. Comparative effectiveness of adding weight control simultaneously or sequentially to smoking cessation quitlines: study protocol of a randomized controlled trial. BMC Public Health 2016;16:615. [DOI: 10.1186/s12889-016-3231-6]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3231-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4957297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27443485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bush T, Lovejoy J, Javitz H, Torres AJ, Wassum K, Tan MM, et al. Simultaneous vs. sequential treatment for smoking and weight management in tobacco quitlines: 6 and 12 month outcomes from a randomized trial. BMC Public Health 2018;18(1):678. [DOI: 10.1186/s12889-018-5574-7]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-018-5574-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5984316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29855294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Cooper 2005 (also Part 2) {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Cooper TV, Klesges RC, Debon MW, Zbikowski SM, Johnson KC, Clemens LH. A placebo controlled randomized trial of the effects of phenylpropanolamine and nicotine gum on cessation rates and postcessation weight gain in women. Addictive Behaviors 2005;30(1):61-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15561449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper TV, Montgomery GV, Debon MW, Zbikowski SM, Klesges RC, Johnson KC. The effects of PPA and nicotine gum on cessation rates and post cessation weight gain in women [POS3-46]. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 9th Annual Meeting, New Orleans, LA. 2003.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Copeland 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Copeland AL, Martin P, Geiselman PJ, Rash CJ, Kendzor DE. Smoking cessation for weight-concerned women: Group vs individually tailored, dietary and weight-control follow up session. Addictive Behaviors 2006;31(1):115-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15925449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Copeland 2015 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Copeland AL, McVay MA, Martin PD, Rash CJ, Kendzor DE, Baillie LE, et al. Smoking relapse and weight gain prevention program for postmenopausal weight-concerned women: a pilot study. Eating Behaviors 2015;18:107-14. [DOI: 10.1016/j.eatbeh.2015.05.006]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eatbeh.2015.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4506692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26026615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Danielsson 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Danielsson T, Rossner S, Westin A. Open randomised trial of intermittent very low energy diet together with nicotine gum for stopping smoking in women who gained weight in previous attemps to quit. BMJ 1999;319(7208):490-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC28202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10454403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielsson T, Rossner S. Smoking cessation rates improved by an intensive weight control program (Conference summary). Addiction 1998;93:913.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Hall 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Tunstall CD, Vila KL, Duffy J. Weight gain prevention and smoking cessation: cautionary findings. American Journal of Public Health 1992;82(6):799-803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1694191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1585959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Hankey 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hankey CR, Leslie WS, Koshy PR, Mackenzie M, Murray H, Boyle S, et al. Food choice and changes in body weight and shape in those attempting smoking cessation. FSA report: University of Glasgow 2009;Food Standards Agency Project NO 902025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koshy P, Mackenzie M, Leslie W, Lean M, Hankey C. Eating the elephant whole or in slices: views of participants in a smoking cessation intervention trial on multiple behaviour changes as sequential or concurrent tasks. BMC Public Health 2012;12:500. [CENTRAL: 842083] [EMBASE: 22759785] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3416689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22759785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie WS, Koshy PR, Mackenzie M, Murray HM, Boyle S, Lean ME, et al. Changes in body weight and food choice in those attempting smoking cessation: a cluster randomised controlled trial. BMC Public Health 2012;12:389. [CENTRAL: 842220] [EMBASE: 22642755] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22642755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Heggen 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Heggen E, Svendsen M, Klemsdal TO, Tonstad S. Low carbohydrate and moderately fat-reduced diets similarly affected early weight gain in varenicline-treated overweight or obese smokers. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2016;18(6):1440-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26242289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Johnson 2017 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Coday M, Richey P, Thomas F, Tran QT, Terrell SB, Tylavsky F, et al. The recruitment experience of a randomized clinical trial to aid young adult smokers to stop smoking without weight gain with interactive technology. Contemporary Clinical Trials Communications 2016;2:61-8. [DOI: 10.1016/j.conctc.2015.12.010]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conctc.2015.12.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26949747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson KC, Thomas F, Richey P, Tran QT, Tylavsky F, Miro D, et al. The primary results of the treating adult smokers at risk for weight gain with interactive technology (TARGIT) study. Obesity (Silver Spring, Md.) 2017;25(10):1691-8. [DOI: 10.1002/oby.21968]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.21968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28948720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 King 2012 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>King AC, Cao D, O'Malley SS, Kranzler HR, Cai X, deWit H, et al. Effects of naltrexone on smoking cessation outcomes and weight gain in nicotine-dependent men and women. Journal of Clinical Psychopharmacology 2012;32(5):630-6. [CENTRAL: 834609] [EMBASE: 2012525974] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4640209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King AC, Cao D, Zhang L, O'Malley SS. Naltrexone reduces women's weight gain in smoking cessation at six month follow-up. Neuropsychopharmacology 2011;36:S427. [CENTRAL: 814652] [6971]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King AC, Cao D, Zhang L, O'Malley SS. Naltrexone reduction of long-term smoking cessation weight gain in women but not men: a randomized controlled trial. Biological Psychiatry 2013;73(9):924-30. [CENTRAL: 878188] [EMBASE: 2013242231] [PEER: Reviewed Journal: 2013-13839-019] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3629005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23177384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Klesges 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Klesges RC, Klesges LM, Meyers AW, Klem ML, Isbell T. The effects of phenylpropanolamine on dietary intake, physical activity, and body weight after smoking cessation. Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics 1990;47(6):747-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2357868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Klesges 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Klesges RC, Klesges LM, DeBon M, Shelton ML, Isbell TR, Klem ML. Effects of phenylpropanolamine on withdrawal symptoms. Psychopharmacology 1995;119(1):85-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7675954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Levine 2010 (also Part 2) {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Levine MD, Cheng Y, Kalarchian MA, Perkins KA, Marcus MD. Dietary intake after smoking cessation among weight-concerned women smokers. Psychology of Addictive Behaviors 2012;26(4):969-73. [CENTRAL: 879590] [EMBASE: 2013467195] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3475794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22799893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine MD, Perkins KA, Kalarchian MA, Cheng Y, Houck PR, Slane JD, et al. Bupropion and cognitive behavioural therapy for weight-concerned women smokers. Archives of Internal Medicine 2010;170(6):543-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3113531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20308641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Lycett 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lycett 2010. Weight Gain Association with Smoking Cessation: a Cohort Analysis and Feasibility Trial for Dietary Management [doctoral thesis]. Birmingham, UK: University of Birmingham, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lycett D, Hajek P, Aveyard P. Trial protocol: randomised controlled trial of the effects of very low calorie diet, modest dietary restriction, and sequential behavioural programme on hunger, urges to smoke, abstinence and weight gain in overweight smokers stopping smoking. Trials 2010;11:94. [CENTRAL: 772342] [EMBASE: 20929584] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2959046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20929584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Lycett 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lycett D, Aveyard P, Farmer A, Lewis A, Munaf&#xf2; M. Referral to Slimming World in UK Stop Smoking Services (SWISSS) versus stop smoking support alone on body weight in quitters: results of a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open 2020;10(1):e032271. [DOI: 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-032271]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-032271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7045045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31988226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lycett D, Aveyard P, Farmer A, Lewis A, Munaf&#xf2; M. Slimming World in Stop Smoking Services (SWISSS): study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials 2013;14:182. [DOI: 10.1186/1745-6215-14-182]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1745-6215-14-182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3698185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23782870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Lyu 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lyu X, Du J, Zhan G, Wu Y, Su H, Zhu Y, et al. Naltrexone and bupropion combination treatment for smoking cessation and weight loss in patients with schizophrenia. Frontiers in Pharmacology 2018;9:181. [DOI: 10.3389/fphar.2018.00181]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2018.00181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5850123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29563871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT03528304 2016 {unpublished data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT03528304. Native women's wellness: contingency management for tobacco cessation and weight loss (NWW). clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03528304 (first received 17 May 2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Norregaard 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Norregaard J, Jorgensen S, Mikkelsen KL, Tonnesen P, Iversen E, Sorensen T, et al. The effects of ephedrine plus caffeine on smoking cessation and postcessation weight gain. Clinical Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 1996;60(6):679-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8988071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 O'Malley 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Epperson CN, Toll B, Wu R, Amin Z, Czarkowski KA, Jatlow P, et al. Exploring the impact of gender and reproductive status on outcomes in a randomized clinical trial of naltrexone augmentation of nicotine patch. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2010;112(1-2):1-8. [CENTRAL: 779368] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2946976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20561758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Malley S, Cooney J, Krishnan-Sarin S, Mckee S, Meandzija B, Dubin J. A dose ranging study of naltrexone augmentation of transdermal nicotine patch: smoking, weight and alcohol outcomes (POS1-064). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 10th Annual Meeting. Phoenix, Arizona, February 18-21, 2004:50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Malley SS, Cooney JL, Krishnan-Sarin S, Dubin JA, McKee SA, Cooney NL et al. A controlled trial of naltrexone augmentation of nicotine replacement therapy for smoking cessation. Archives of Internal Medicine 2006;166:667-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Oncken 2014 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Oncken C, Arias AJ, Feinn R, Litt M, Covault J, Sofuoglu M, et al. Topiramate for smoking cessation: a randomized, placebo-controlled pilot study. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2014;16(3):288-96. [CENTRAL: 977673]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3920334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24057996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Oncken 2019 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Oncken C, Allen S, Litt M, Kenny A, Lando H, Allen A, et al. Exercise for smoking cessation in postmenopausal women: a randomized, controlled trial. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2020;22(9):1587-95. [DOI: 10.1093/ntr/ntz176]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntz176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31536112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Parsons 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Parsons AC, Ingram J, Inglis J, Aveyard P, Johnstone E, Brown K, et al. A proof of concept randomised placebo controlled factorial trial to examine the efficacy of St John's Wort for smoking cessation and chromium to prevent weight gain on smoking cessation. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2009;102(1-3):116-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19328636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Perkins 2001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Perkins KA, Marcus MD, Levine MD, D'Amico D, Miller A, Broge M, et al. Cognitive-behavioral therapy to reduce weight concerns improves smoking cessation outcome in weight-concerned women. Journal of Consulting &amp; Clinical Psychology 2001;69(4):604-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11550727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Pirie 1992 (also Part 2) {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Pirie PL, McBride CM, Hellerstedt WL, Jeffery RW, Hatsukami DK, Allen S, et al. Smoking cessation in women concerned about weight. American Journal of Public Health 1992;82:1238-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1694323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1503165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Prapavessis 2018 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jung ME, Fitzgeorge L, Prapavessis H, Faulkner G, Maddison R. The getting physical on cigarettes trial: Rationale and methods. Mental Health and Physical Activity 2010;3(1):35-44. [DOI: 10.1016/j.mhpa.2010.02.002]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mhpa.2010.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prapavessis H, De Jesus S, Fitzgeorge L, Faulkner G, Maddison R, Batten S. Exercise to enhance smoking cessation: the getting physical on cigarette randomized control trial. Annals of Behavioral Medicine 2016;50(3):358-69. [DOI: 10.1007/s12160-015-9761-9]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12160-015-9761-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prapavessis H, De Jesus S, Fitzgeorge L, Rollo S. Anthropometric and body composition changes in smokers vs abstainers following an exercise-aided pharmacotherapy smoking cessation trial for women. Addictive Behaviors 2018;85:125-30. [DOI: 10.1016/j.addbeh.2018.06.003]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2018.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29902683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Rose 2019 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Davis JM. Combination lorcaserin and nicotine patch for smoking cessation without weight gain. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2020;22(9):1627-31. [DOI: 10.1093/ntr/ntz149]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntz149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7443600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31589323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Shanahan 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Shanahan W, Rose J, Glicklich A, Stubbe S, Halliday D, Zhang J, et al. Lorcaserin for smoking cessation treatment in cigarette smokers: a randomized phase 2 trial. In: American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine. Vol. 191. 2015:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanahan WR, Rose JE, Glicklich A, Stubbe S, Sanchez-Kam M. Lorcaserin for smoking cessation and associated weight gain: a randomized 12-week clinical trial. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2017;19(8):944-51. [DOI: 10.1093/ntr/ntw301]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntw301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27815511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Sobell 2017 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Sobell MB, Peterson AL, Sobell LC, Brundige A, Hunter CM, Hunter CM. Reducing alcohol consumption to minimize weight gain and facilitate smoking cessation among military beneficiaries. Addictive Behaviors 2017;75:145-51. [DOI: 10.1016/j.addbeh.2017.06.018]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2017.06.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28734154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Spring 1995 (also Part 2) {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Spring B, Wurtman J, Wurtman R, El-Khoury A, Goldberg H, McDermott J, et al. Efficacies of dexfenfluramine and fluoxetine in preventing weight gain after smoking cessation. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 1995;62(6):1181-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7491877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Spring 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Spring B, Doran N, Pagoto S, Schneider K, Pingitore R, Hedeker D. Randomised controlled trial of behavioural smoking and weight control treatment: effect of concurrent versus sequential intervention. Journal of Counselling and Clinical Psychology 2004;72(5):785-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15482037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Toll 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rojewski AM, Toll BA, O'Malley SS. Menthol cigarette use predicts treatment outcomes of weight-concerned smokers. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2014;16(1):115-9. [CENTRAL: 1000325] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3864493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24113927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toll BA, White M, Wu R, Meandzija B, Jatlow P, Makuch R, et al. Low-dose naltrexone augmentation of nicotine replacement for smoking cessation with reduced weight gain: a randomised trial. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2010;111(3):200-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3771701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20542391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Vander Weg 2016 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Vander Weg MW, Cozad AJ, Howren MB, Cretzmeyer M, Scherubel M, Turvey C, et al. An individually-tailored smoking cessation intervention for rural Veterans: a pilot randomized trial. BMC Public Health 2016;16(1):811. [DOI: 10.1186/s12889-016-3493-z]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3493-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4989380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 White 2019 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>White MA, Ivezaj V, Grilo CM. Evaluation of a web-based cognitive behavioral smoking cessation treatment for overweight/obese smokers. Journal of Health Psychology 2019;24(13):1796-806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28810442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Wilcox 2016 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Wilcox C, Tong M-L, Oskooilar N, Morrissey J, De Francisco D, Henry M, et al. A 12-week, multi-center, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, phase-2, dose selection study of lorcaserin hydrochloride for smoking cessation: preliminary report. In: Neuropsychopharmacology. 2016:S626-7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Abelin 1989 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Abelin T, Buehler A, M&#xfc;ller P, Vesanen K, Imhof PR. Controlled trial of transdermal nicotine patch in tobacco withdrawal. Lancet 1989;1(8628):7-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2563045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abelin T, Ehrsam R, Buhler-Reichert A, Imhof PR, M&#xfc;ller P, Thommen A. Effectiveness of a transdermal nicotine system in smoking cessation studies. Methods and Findings in Experimental and Clinical Pharmacology 1989;11(3):205-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2657276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller P, Abelin T, Ehrsam R, Imhof P, Howald H, Mauli D. The use of transdermal nicotine in smoking cessation. Lung 1990;168(Suppl):445-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2117147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Aubin 2008 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Aubin HJ, Bobak A, Britton JR, Oncken C, Billing CB, Gong J, et al. Varenicline versus transdermal nicotine patch for smoking cessation: results from a randomised, open-label trial. Thorax 2008;63(8):717-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2569194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18263663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Benowitz 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Anthenelli RM, Benowitz NL, West R, St Aubin L, McRae T, Lawrence D, et al. Neuropsychiatric safety and efficacy of varenicline, bupropion, and nicotine patch in smokers with and without psychiatric disorders (EAGLES): a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Lancet 2016;387(10037):2507-20. [DOI: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30272-0]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30272-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27116918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthenelli RM, Gaffney M, Benowitz NL, West R, McRae T, Russ C, et al. Predictors of neuropsychiatric adverse events with smoking cessation medications in the randomized controlled EAGLES trial. Journal of General Internal Medicine 2019;34(6):862-70. [DOI: 10.1007/s11606-019-04858-2]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-019-04858-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30847828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers CR, Heffner JL, Russ C, Lawrence D, McRae T, Evins AE, et al. Efficacy and safety of pharmacotherapies for smoking cessation in anxiety disorders: subgroup analysis of the randomized, active- and placebo-controlled EAGLES trial. Depression and Anxiety 2020;37(3):247-60. [DOI: 10.1002/da.22982]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7064930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31850603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker CL, Pietri G. A cost-effectiveness analysis of varenicline for smoking cessation using data from the EAGLES trial. ClinicoEconomics and Outcomes Research 2018;10:67-74. [DOI: 10.2147/CEOR.S153897]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CEOR.S153897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5783141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer AM, Hosie Quinn M, Lubitz SF, Flitter A, Ashare RL, Leone FT, et al. Medication adherence and rate of nicotine metabolism are associated with response to treatment with varenicline among smokers with HIV. Addictive Behaviors 2021;112:106638. [DOI: 10.1016/j.addbeh.2020.106638]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2020.106638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32911350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benowitz NL, Pipe A, West R, Hays JT, Tonstad S, McRae T, et al. Cardiovascular safety of varenicline, bupropion, and nicotine patch in smokers: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Internal Medicine 2018;178(5):622-31. [DOI: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.0397]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.0397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6145797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Bernard 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bernard P, Ninot G, Cyprien F, Courtet P, Guillaume S, Georgescu V, et al. Exercise and counseling for smoking cessation in smokers with depressive symptoms: a randomized controlled pilot trial. Journal of Dual Diagnosis 2015;11(3-4):205-16. [DOI: 10.1080/15504263.2015.1113842]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15504263.2015.1113842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26683252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Bize 2010 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bize R, Willi C, Chiolero A, Stoianov R, Payot S, Locatelli I, et al. Participation in a population-based physical activity programme as an aid for smoking cessation: a randomised trial. Tobacco Control 2010;19(6):488-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornuz J, Willi C, Chiolero A, Payot S, Stolanov R, Bize R. Physical activity as an aid to smoking cessation: a randomised controlled trial of sedentary adult smokers. Journal of General Internal Medicine 2007;22(S1):107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonseth S, Locatelli I, Bize R, Nussle S, Clair C, Pralong F, et al. Leptin and smoking cessation: secondary analyses of a randomized controlled trial assessing physical activity as an aid for smoking cessation. BMC Public Health 2014;14:911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4165916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25187423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locatelli I, Collet T-H, Clair C, Rodondi N, Cornuz J. The joint influence of gender and amount of smoking on weight gain one year after smoking cessation. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 2014;11(8):8443-55. [CENTRAL: 1066606] [EMBASE: 2014568698]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4143870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25153470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prod'hom S, Locatelli I, Giraudon K, Marques-Vidal P, Clair C, Bize R, et al. Predictors of weight change in sedentary smokers receiving a standard smoking cessation intervention. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2013;15(5):910-6. [CENTRAL: 967344] [EMBASE: 2013284959] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23048177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Blondal 1999 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Blondal T, Gudmundsson LJ, Olafsdottir I, Gustavsson G, Westin A. Nicotine nasal spray with nicotine patch for smoking cessation: randomised trial with six year follow up. BMJ 1999;318:285-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC27708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9924052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blondal T, Ludviksdottir D, Gudmundsson L, Olafsdottir I, Gustavsson G, Westin A. Efficacy of nicotine nasal spray added to transdermal nicotine patches in smoking cessation [Abstract]. In: 10th World Conference on Tobacco or Health; Aug 24-28; Beijing, China. 1997:48.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Bloom 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Abrantes AM, Bloom EL, Strong DR, Riebe D, Marcus BH, Desaulniers J, et al. A preliminary randomized controlled trial of a behavioral exercise intervention for smoking cessation. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2014;16(8):1094-103. [DOI: 10.1093/ntr/ntu036]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntu036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4155424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24812023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloom EL, Minami H, Brown RA, Strong DR, Riebe D, Abrantes AM. Quality of life after quitting smoking and initiating aerobic exercise. Psychology, Health &amp; Medicine 2017;22(9):1127-35. [DOI: 10.1080/13548506.2017.1282159]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13548506.2017.1282159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5624525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28103704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Bohadana 2000 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bohadana A, Nilsson F, Rasmussen T, Martinet Y. Gender differences in quit rates following smoking cessation with combination nicotine therapy: influence of baseline smoking behavior. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2003;5(1):111-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12745512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohadana A, Nilsson F, Rasmussen T, Martinet Y. Nicotine inhaler and nicotine patch as a combination therapy for smoking cessation - a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Archives of Internal Medicine 2000;160(20):3128-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11074742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohadana AB, Nilsson F, Martinet Y. Nicotine inhaler and nicotine patch: a combination therapy for smoking cessation [abstract]. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 1999;1(2):189.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Bolliger 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bolliger CT, Issa Jaqueline S, Posadas-Valay R, Safwat T, Abreu P, Correia EA, et al. Effects of varenicline in adult smokers: a multinational, 24-week, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Clinical Therapeutics 2011;33(4):465-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21635992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 CEASE 1999 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, Paoletti P, Gustavsson G, Russell MA, Saracci R, Gulsvik A et al. Higher dosage nicotine patches increase one-year smoking cessation rates: results from the European CEASE trial. European Respiratory Journal 1999;13(2):238-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10065662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Chengappa 2014 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Chengappa KN, Perkins KA, Brar JS, Schlicht PJ, Turkin SR, Hetrick ML, et al. Varenicline for smoking cessation in bipolar disorder: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry 2014;75(7):765-72. [DOI: 10.4088/JCP.13m08756]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.13m08756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25006684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chengappa KN. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial of varenicline in persons with bipolar disorder motivated to quit smoking. Bipolar Disorders 2015;17(Suppl 1):38.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Ciccolo 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ciccolo JT, Dunsiger SI, Williams DM, Bartholomew JB, Jennings EG, Ussher MH, et al. Resistance training as an aid to standard smoking cessation treatment: a pilot study. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2011;13(8):756-60. [CENTRAL: 784125]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3150692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21504883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Cox 2012 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Cox LS, Faseru B, Mayo MS, Krebill R, Snow TS, Bronars CA, et al. Design, baseline characteristics, and retention of African American light smokers into a randomized trial involving biological data. Trials 2011;12:22. [CENTRAL: 778725] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3038942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox LS, Nollen NL, Mayo MS, Choi WS, Faseru B, Benowitz NL, et al. Bupropion for smoking cessation in African American light smokers: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of the National Cancer Institute 2012;104(4):290-8. [CENTRAL: 814627] [EMBASE: 2012121196] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3283533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22282543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faseru B, Nollen NL, Mayo MS, Krebill R, Choi WS, Benowitz NL, et al. Predictors of cessation in African American light smokers enrolled in a bupropion clinical trial. Addictive Behaviors 2013;38(3):1796-803. [CENTRAL: 865750] [PEER: Reviewed Journal: 2013-02944-034] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3558614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23254230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Dale 1995 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Dale LC, Hurt RD, Offord KP, Lawson GM, Croghan IT, Schroeder DR. High-dose nicotine patch therapy - percentage of replacement and smoking cessation. JAMA 1995;274(17):1353-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7563559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale LC, Schroeder DR, Wolter TD, Croghan IT, Hurt RD, Offord KP. Weight change after smoking cessation using variable doses of transdermal nicotine replacement. Journal of General Internal Medicine 1998;13(1):9-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1496892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9462489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Dogar 2018 {published data only}ISRCTN43811467</Title><Reference><Citation>Dogar O, Barua D, Boeckmann M, Elsey H, Fatima R, Gabe R, et al. The safety, effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of cytisine in achieving six-month continuous smoking abstinence in tuberculosis patients - protocol for a double-blind, placebo-controlled randomized trial. Addiction (Abingdon, England) 2018;113(9):1716-26. [DOI: 10.1111/add.14242]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.14242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6099220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29676824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogar O, Keding A, Gabe R, Marshall AM, Huque R, Barua D, et al. Cytisine for smoking cessation in patients with tuberculosis: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet Global Health 2020;8(11):e1408-17. [DOI: 10.1016/S2214-109X(20)30312-0]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(20)30312-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Ebbert 2014 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ebbert JO, Hatsukami DK, Croghan IT, Schroeder DR, Allen SS, Hays JT, et al. Combination varenicline and bupropion SR for tobacco-dependence treatment in cigarette smokers: a randomized trial. JAMA 2014;311(2):155-63. [CENTRAL: 921055] [EMBASE: 2014041620] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3959999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24399554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong AS, Elrashidi MY, Schroeder DR, Ebbert JO. Depressive symptoms among patients receiving varenicline and bupropion for smoking cessation. Journal of Substance Abuse Treatment 2015;52:78-81. [CENTRAL: 1068331] [EMBASE: 2014617308] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4382391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25530426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Ebbert 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ebbert JO, Hughes JR, West RJ, Rennard SI, Russ C, McRae TD, et al. Effect of varenicline on smoking cessation through smoking reduction: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2015;313(7):687-94. [DOI: 10.1001/jama.2015.280]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2015.280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4883651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25688780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Ehrsam 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Abelin T, Ehrsam R, Buhler-Reichert A, Imhof PR, M&#xfc;ller P, Thommen A. Effectiveness of a transdermal nicotine system in smoking cessation studies. Methods and Findings in Experimental and Clinical Pharmacology 1989;11(3):205-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2657276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abelin T, Ehrsam R, Imhof P M&#xfc;ller P, Howald H. Clinical experience with a transdermal nicotine system in healthy nicotine-dependent smokers. In: Wilhemsen L, editors(s). Smoking as a Cardiovascular Risk Factor - New Strategies for Smoking Cessation. Hogrefe &amp; Huber, 1991:35-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrsam RE, B&#xfc;hler A, M&#xfc;ller P, Mauli D, Schumacher PM, Howald H, et al. Weaning of young smokers using a transdermal nicotine patch [Entwohnung junger Raucher mit Hilfe eines transdermalen Nikotinpflasters]. Schweizerische Rundschau fur Medizin Praxis 1991;80(7):145-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2008547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller P, Abelin T, Ehrsam R, Imhof P, Howald H, Mauli D. The use of transdermal nicotine in smoking cessation. Lung 1990;168(Suppl):445-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2117147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Eisenberg 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg MJ, Grandi SM, Gervais A, Joseph L, O'Loughlin J, Paradis G, et al. Bupropion for smoking cessation in patients hospitalized with acute myocardial infarction: a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Canadian Journal of Cardiology 2011;27(5 SUPPL 1):S344. [CENTRAL: 814579] [6968]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23369417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg MJ, Grandi SM, Gervais A, O'Loughlin J, Paradis G, Rinfret S, et al. Bupropion for smoking cessation in patients hospitalized with acute myocardial infarction: a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Journal of the American College of Cardiology 2013;61(5):524-32. [CENTRAL: 848271] [EMBASE: 2013073386] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23369417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandi SM, Filion KB, Gervais A, Joseph L, O'Loughlin J, Paradis G, et al. The effect of smoking cessation on weight at 12 months in patients post-myocardial infarction. Circulation 2012;125:AP323. [EMBASE: 70951199]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandi SM, Filion KB, Gervais A, Joseph L, O'Loughlin J, Paradis G, et al. Weight change in patients attempting to quit smoking post-myocardial infarction. American Journal of Medicine 2014;127(7):641-9. [CENTRAL: 1050332] [EMBASE: 2014427952] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24608017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandi SM, Filion KB, Joseph L, O'Loughlin J, Pilote L, Eisenberg MJ. Baseline predictors of relapse to smoking at 12 months in patients post-myocardial infarction. Canadian Journal of Cardiology 2013;29(10 Suppl 1):S257. [CENTRAL: 1024794] [EMBASE: 71204225]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi Zhang DD, Eisenberg MJ, Grandi SM, Joseph L, O'Loughlin J, Paradis G, et al. Bupropion, smoking cessation, and health-related quality of life following an acute myocardial infarction. Journal of Population Therapeutics and Clinical Pharmacology [Journal de la Therapeutique des Populations et de la Pharamcologie Clinique] 2014;21(3):e346-56. [CENTRAL: 1022527] [EMBASE: 2014847496] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25326910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Eisenberg 2016 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Dehghani P, Habib B, Windle SB, Roy N, Old W, Grondin FR, et al. Smokers and postcessation weight gain after acute coronary syndrome. Journal of the American Heart Association 2017;6(4):e004785. [DOI: 10.1161/JAHA.116.004785]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.116.004785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5532997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28420644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg MJ, Windle SB, Roy N, Old W, Grondin FR, Bata I, et al. Varenicline for smoking cessation in hospitalized patients with acute coronary syndrome. Circulation 2016;133(1):21-30. [DOI: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.115.019634]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.115.019634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windle SB, Bata I, Madan M, Abramson BL, Eisenberg MJ. A randomized controlled trial of the efficacy and safety of varenicline for smoking cessation after acute coronary syndrome: design and methods of the Evaluation of Varenicline in Smoking Cessation for Patients Post-Acute Coronary Syndrome trial. American Heart Journal 205;170(4):635-40. [DOI: 10.1016/j.ahj.2015.07.010]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2015.07.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26386786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windle SB, Dehghani P, Roy N, Old W, Grondin FR, Bata I, et al. Smoking abstinence 1 year after acute coronary syndrome: follow-up from a randomized controlled trial of varenicline in patients admitted to hospital. CMAJ 2018;190(12):E347-54. [DOI: 10.1503/cmaj.170377]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.170377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29581161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windle SB, Dehghani P, Roy N, Old W, Grondin FR, Bata I, et al. Sustained smoking abstinence 12 months after acute coronary syndrome: follow-up from a randomized controlled trial of varenicline in hospitalized patients. Canadian Journal of Cardiology 2016;32:S109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29581161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Fiore 1994A {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Elan Pharmaceutical Research Corp. NDA 19-983 for Approval of PROSTEP. Study 90-03 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiore MC, Kenford SL, Jorenby DE, Wetter DW, Smith SS, Baker TB. Two studies of the clinical effectiveness of the nicotine patch with different counseling treatments. Chest 1994;105:524-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8306757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenford SL, Fiore MC, Jorenby DE, Smith SS, Wetter D, Baker TB. Predicting smoking cessation. Who will quit with and without the nicotine patch. JAMA 1994;271:589-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8301790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Fiore 1994B {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fiore MC, Kenford SL, Jorenby DE, Wetter DW, Smith SS, Baker TB. Two studies of the clinical effectiveness of the nicotine patch with different counseling treatments. Chest 1994;105(2):524-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8306757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Gallagher 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gallagher SM, Penn PE, Schindler E, Layne W. A comparison of smoking cessation treatments for persons with schizophrenia and other serious mental illnesses. Journal of Psychoactive Drugs 2007;39(4):487-97. [DOI: 10.1080/02791072.2007.10399888]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02791072.2007.10399888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18303706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Garvey 2000 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Doherty K, Militello FS, Kinnunen T, Garvey AJ. Nicotine gum dose and weight gain after smoking cessation. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1996;64(4):799-807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8803371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson SG, Shiffman S, Rohay JM, Gitchell JG, Garvey AJ. Effect of compliance with nicotine gum dosing on weight gained during a quit attempt. Addiction 2011;106(3):651-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21182551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey AJ, Kinnunen T, Nordstrom BL, Utman CH, Doherty K, Rosner B, et al. Effects of nicotine gum dose by level of nicotine dependence. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2000;2(1):53-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordstrom BL, Kinnunen T, Utman CH, Garvey AJ. Long-term effects of nicotine gum on weight gain after smoking cessation. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 1999;1(3):259-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Gonzales 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gonzales D, Rennard SI, Nides M, Oncken C, Azoulay S, Billing CB, et al. Varenicline, an alpha4beta2 nicotinic acetylcholine receptor partial agonist, vs sustained-release bupropion and placebo for smoking cessation: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA 2006;296(1):47-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16820546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Gourlay 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gourlay SG, Forbes A, Marriner T, Pethica D, McNeil JJ. Double blind trial of repeated treatment with transdermal nicotine for relapsed smokers. BMJ 1995;311(7001):363-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2550432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7640544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Gray 2019 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gray KM, Baker NL, McClure EA, Tomko RL, Squeglia LM, Saladin ME, et al. Efficacy and safety of varenicline for adolescent smoking cessation: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Pediatrics 2019;173(12):1146-53. [DOI: 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2019.3553]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2019.3553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6802269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31609433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClure EA, Baker NL, Hood CO, Tomko RL, Squeglia LM, Flanagan JC, et al. Cannabis and alcohol co-use in a smoking cessation pharmacotherapy trial for adolescents and emerging adults. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2020;22(8):1374-82. [DOI: 10.1093/ntr/ntz170]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntz170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7364825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31612956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Gross 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gross J, Johnson J, Sigler L, Stitzer ML. Dose effects of nicotine gum. Addictive Behaviors 1995;20(3):371-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7653318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Hjalmarson 1984 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hjalmarson AI. Effect of nicotine chewing gum in smoking cessation. A randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind study. JAMA 1984;252(20):2835-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6387207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Hjalmarson 1994 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hjalmarson AI, Franzon M, Westin A, Wiklund O. Effect of nicotine nasal spray on smoking cessation. A randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind study. Archives of Internal Medicine 1994;154:2567-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7979853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Hjalmarson 1997 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hjalmarson A, Nilsson F, Sj&#xf6;strom L, Wiklund O. The nicotine inhaler in smoking cessation. Archives of Internal Medicine 1997;157(15):1721-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9250233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Hurt 1997 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hurt RD, Glover ED, Sachs DP, et al. Bupropion for smoking cessation: a double-blind, placebo-controlled dose response trial [Abstract]. Journal of Addictive Diseases 1996;15:137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale LC, Glover ED, Sachs DP, Schroeder DR, Offord KP, Croghan IT, et al. Bupropion for smoking cessation: predictors of successful outcome. Chest 2001;119(5):1357-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11348939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaxo Wellcome. Presentation for FDA approval of bupropion sustained release for smoking cessation. Dr J. Andrew Johnston December 10 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayford KE, Patten CA, Rummans TA, Schroeder DR, Offord KP, Croghan IT, et al. Efficacy of bupropion for smoking cessation in smokers with a former history of major depression or alcoholism. British Journal of Psychiatry 1999;174:173-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10211174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurt RD, Sachs DP, Glover ED, Offord KP, Johnston JA, Dale LC, et al. A comparison of sustained-release bupropion and placebo for smoking cessation. New England Journal of Medicine 1997;337(17):1195-202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9337378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston JA, Fiedler-Kelly J, Glover ED, Sachs DP, Grasela TH, DeVeaugh-Geiss J. Relationship between drug exposure and the efficacy and safety of bupropion sustained release for smoking cessation. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2001;3(2):131-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11403727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Ioakeimidis 2018 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ioakeimidis N, Vlachopoulos C, Georgakopoulos C, Abdelrasoul M, Skliros N, Katsi V, et al. P1234 Smoking cessation rates with varenicline and electronic cigarettes in relapsed smokers with a history of acute coronary syndrome. European Heart Journal 2018;39(Suppl 1):S242. [DOI: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehy565.P1234]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehy565.P1234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Jodar&#x2010;Sanchez 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Carrasco-Hernandez L, J&#xf3;dar-S&#xe1;nchez F, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Benjumea F, Moreno Conde J, Mesa Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Civit-Balcells A, et al. A mobile health solution complementing psychopharmacology-supported smoking cessation: randomized controlled trial. JMIR mHealth and uHealth 2020;8(4):e17530. [DOI: 10.2196/17530]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/17530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32338624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf3;dar-S&#xe1;nchez F, Carrasco Hern&#xe1;ndez L, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Benjumea FJ, Mesa Gonz&#xe1;lez MA, Moreno Conde J, Parra Calder&#xf3;n CL, et al. Using the social-local-mobile app for smoking cessation in the smokefreebrain project: protocol for a randomized controlled trial. JMIR Research Protocols 2018;7(12):e12464. [DOI: 10.2196/12464]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6302230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez FG, Hernandez LC, Benjumea FN, Rodriguez BG, Gonzalez MM, J&#xf3;dar Sanchez F, et al. Use of a mobile app to give up smoking. Results from a clinical trial. European Respiratory Journal 2019;54(63):PA2237. [DOI: 10.1183/13993003.congress-2019.PA2237]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.congress-2019.PA2237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Jorenby 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jorenby DE, Hays JT, Rigotti NA, Azoulay S, Watsky EJ, Williams KE, et al. Efficacy of varenicline, an alpha4beta2 nicotinic acetylcholine partial agonist vs placebo or sustained-release bupropion for smoking cessation: a randomised controlled trial. JAMA 2006;296(1):56-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16820547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Koegelenberg 2014 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Koegelenberg CF, Noor F, Bateman ED, Van Zyl-Smit RN, Bruning A, O'Brien JA, et al. Efficacy of varenicline combined with nicotine replacement therapy vs varenicline alone for smoking cessation: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2014;312(2):155-61. [CENTRAL: 994156]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25005652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Lerman 2004 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Jepson C, Wileyto EP, Epstein LH, Rukstalis M, Patterson F, et al. Role of functional genetic variation in the dopamine D2 receptor (DRD2) in response to bupropion and nicotine replacement therapy for tobacco dependence: results of two randomized clinical trials. Neuropsychopharmacology 2006;31(1):231-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16123753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Kaufmann V, Rukstalis M, Patterson F, Perkins K, Audrain McGovern J, et al. Individualizing nicotine replacement therapy for the treatment of tobacco dependence: a randomized trial. Annals of Internal Medicine 2004;140(6):426-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15023708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Tyndale R, Patterson F, Wileyto EP, Shields PG, Pinto A, et al. Nicotine metabolite ratio predicts efficacy of transdermal nicotine for smoking cessation. Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics 2006;79(6):600-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16765148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Wileyto EP, Patterson F, Rukstalis M, Audrain-McGovern J, Restine S et al. The functional mu opioid receptor (OPRM1) Asn40Asp variant predicts short-term response to nicotine replacement therapy in a clinical trial. Pharmacogenomics Journal 2004;4(3):184-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15007373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaiyandi V, Lerman C, Benowitz NL, Jepson C, Patterson F, Tyndale RF. Impact of CYP2A6 genotype on pretreatment smoking behaviour and nicotine levels from and usage of nicotine replacement therapy. Molecular Psychiatry 2006;11(4):400-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16402128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson F, Jepson C, Kaufmann V, Rukstalis M, Audrain-McGovern J, Kucharski S, et al. Predictors of attendance in a randomized clinical trial of nicotine replacement therapy with behavioral counseling. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2003;72(2):123-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Lycett 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lycett D, Munaf&#xf2; M, Johnstone E, Murphy M, Aveyard P. Associations between weight change over 8 years and baseline body mass index in a cohort of continuing and quitting smokers. Addiction 2011;106:1188-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20925685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Marcus 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Marcus B, Albrecht A, King T, Parisi A, Pinto B, Roberts M, et al. The efficacy of exercise as an aid for smoking cessation in women. Archives of Internal Medicine 1999;159(11):1229-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10371231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Marcus 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Marcus BH, Lewis BA, Hogan J, King TK, Albrecht AE, Bock B, et al. The efficacy of moderate-intensity exercise as an aid for smoking cessation in women: a randomized controlled trial. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2005;7(6):871-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16298722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Merci&#xe9; 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Merci&#xe9; P, Arsandaux J, Katlama C, Ferret S, Beuscart A, Spadone C, et al. Efficacy and safety of varenicline for smoking cessation in people living with HIV in France (ANRS 144 Inter-ACTIV): a randomised controlled phase 3 clinical trial. Lancet. HIV 2018;5(3):e126&#x2013;35. [DOI: 10.1016/S2352-3018(18)30002-X]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3018(18)30002-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29329763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merci&#xe9; P, Roussillon C, Katlama C, Beuscart A, Ferret S, Wirth N, et al. Varenicline vs placebo for smoking cessation: ANRS 144 Inter-ACTIV randomized trial. In: Cardiovascular, Bone, and Kidney Health. Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections. 2015 Feb 23-26; Seattle, Washington. 2015. [139]</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Nakamura 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Oshima A, Fujimoto Y, Maruyama N, Ishibashi T, Reeves KR. Efficacy and tolerability of nicotinic varenicline, an alpha4beta2 acetylcholine receptor partial agonist, in a 12-week, randomized, placebo-controlled, dose-response study with 40-week follow-up for smoking cessation in Japanese smokers. Clinical Therapeutics 2007;29(6):1040-56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17692720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Oshima A, Ohkura M, Arteaga C, Suwa K. Predictors of lapse and relapse to smoking in successful quitters in a varenicline post hoc analysis in japanese smokers. Clinical Therapeutics 2014;36(6):918-27. [CENTRAL: 995377] [EMBASE: 2014542011]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24811751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NCT02859142 2016 {unpublished data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT02859142. Varenicline augmentation of patch outcomes in heavy drinkers' smoking cessation. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02859142 (first received 8 August 2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Niaura 2002 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Borrelli B, Niaura R, Keuthen NJ, Goldstein MG, Depue JD, Murphy C, et al. Development of major depressive disorder during smoking-cessation treatment. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry 1996;57(11):534-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8968303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrelli B, Papandonatos G, Spring B, Hitsman B, Niaura R. Experimenter-defined quit dates for smoking cessation: adherence improves outcomes for women but not for men. Addiction 2004;99(3):378-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14982551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrelli B, Spring B, Niaura R, Hitsman B, Papandonatos G. Influences of gender and weight gain on short-term relapse to smoking in a cessation trial. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 2001;69(3):511-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11495180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrelli B, Spring B, Niaura R, Kristeller J, Ockene JK, Keuthen NJ. Weight suppression and weight rebound in ex-smokers treated with fluoxetine. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1999;67(1):124-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10028216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook JW, Spring B, McChargue DE, Borrelli B, Hitsman B, Niaura R, et al. Influence of fluoxetine on positive and negative affect in a clinic-based smoking cessation trial. Psychopharmacology 2004;173(1-2):153-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1847574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14727000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doran N, Spring B, Borrelli B, McChargue D, Hitsman B, Niaura R, Hedeker D. Elevated positive mood: a mixed blessing for abstinence. Psychology of Addictive Behaviors 2006;20(1):36-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16536663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hitsman B, Spring B, Borrelli B, Niaura R, Papandonatos GD. Influence of antidepressant pharmacotherapy on behavioral treatment adherence and smoking cessation outcome in a combined treatment involving fluoxetine. Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology 2001;9(4):355-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11764011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizes JS, Sloan DM, Segraves K, Spring B, Pingatore R, Kristeller J. Fluoxetine and weight-gain in smoking cessation - examination of actual weight-gain and fear of weight-gain [abstract]. Psychopharmacology Bulletin 1996;32:491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niaura R, Goldstein M, Spring B, Keuthen N, Kristeller J, DePue J, et al. Fluoxetine for smoking cessation: a multicenter randomized double blind dose response study. In: Society for Behavioral Medicine Annual Meeting; April 18 1997; San Francisco, CA. 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niaura R, Spring B, Borrelli B, Hedeker D, Goldstein MG, Keuthen N, et al. Multicenter trial of fluoxetine as an adjunct to behavioral smoking cessation treatment. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 2002;70(4):887-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12182272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan GE, Jack LM, Niaura R, Borrelli B, Spring B. Subgroups of smokers with different success rates after treatment with fluoxetine for smoking cessation [abstract]. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 1999;1:281.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Niaura 2008 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Niaura R, Hays JT, Jorenby DE, Leone FT, Pappas JE, Reeves KR, et al. The efficacy and safety of varenicline for smoking cessation using a flexible dosing strategy in adult smokers: a randomized controlled trial. Current Medical Research and Opinion 2008;24(7):1931-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18513462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Nides 2006 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Nides M, Oncken C, Gonzales D, Rennard S, Watsky EJ, Anziano R, et al. Smoking cessation with varenicline, a selective alpha4beta2 nicotinic receptor partial agonist: Results from a 7-week, randomized, placebo- and bupropion-controlled trial with 1-year follow-up. Archives of Internal Medicine 2006;166(15):1561-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16908788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oncken C, Watsky E, Reeves K, Anziano R. Varenicline is efficacious and well tolerated in promoting smoking cessation: results from a 7-week, randomized, placebo- and bupropion-controlled trial. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 11th Annual Meeting, 20-23 March 2005, Prague, Czech Republic. 2005.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Oncken 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Oncken C, Gonzales D, Nides M, Rennard S, Watsky E, Billing CB, et al. Efficacy and safety of the novel selective nicotinic acetylcholine receptor partial agonist, varenicline, for smoking cessation. Archives of Internal Medicine 2008;166(15):1571-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16908789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Oncken 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Oncken C, Cooney J, Feinn R, Lando H, Kranzler HR. Transdermal nicotine for smoking cessation in postmenopausal women. Addictive Behaviors 2007;32(2):296-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16765526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Pack 2008 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Pack QR, Jorenby DE, Fiore MC, Jackson T, Weston P, Piper M, et al. A comparison of the nicotine lozenge and nicotine gum: an effectiveness randomized controlled trial. Wisconsin Medical Journal 2008;107(5):237-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18777992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Patten 2016 {published data only (unpublished sought but not used)}</Title><Reference><Citation>Patten CA, Bronars CA, Vickers Douglas KS, Ussher MH, Levine JA, Tye SJ, et al. Supervised, vigorous intensity exercise intervention for depressed female smokers: a pilot study. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2017;19(1):77-86. [DOI: 10.1093/ntr/ntw208]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntw208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5157716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27613946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Piper 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federman EB, McCarthy DE, Bolt DM, Smith SS, Fiore MC, et al. Efficacy of bupropion alone and in combination with nicotine gum. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2007;9(9):947-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3030120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17763111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federman EB, Smith SS, Fiore MC, Baker TB. Efficacy of bupropion SR alone and combined with 4-mg nicotine gum (PA2-2). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 10th Annual Meeting February 18-21, Phoenix, Arizona. Vol. 18. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federmen EB, McCarthy DE, Bolt DM, Smith SS, Fiore ME, et al. Using mediational models to explore the nature of tobacco motivation and tobacco treatment effects. Journal of Abnormal Psychology 2008;117(1):94-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18266488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper ME. Bupropion alone and in combination with nicotine gum: efficacy, medication and moderation. Dissertation Abstracts International: Section B: The Sciences and Engineering 2007;9:947-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3030120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17763111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Piper 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Smith SS, Schlam TR, Fiore MC, Jorenby DE, Fraser D, et al. A randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial of 5 smoking cessation pharmacotherapies. Archives of General Psychiatry 2009;66(11):1253-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19884613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Puska 1995 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Puska P, Korhonen HJ, Vartiainen E, Urjanheimo EL, Gustavsson G, Westin A. Combined use of nicotine patch and gum compared with gum alone in smoking cessation: a clinical trial in North Karelia. Tobacco Control 1995;4:231-5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Richmond 1994 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Richmond RL, Harris K, De Almeida Neto A. The transdermal nicotine patch: results of a randomised placebo-controlled trial. Medical Journal of Australia 1994;161(2):130-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8028537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond RL, Kehoe L, De Almeida Neto AC. Effectiveness of a 24-hour transdermal nicotine patch in conjunction with a cognitive behavioural programme: one year outcome. Addiction 1997;92(1):27-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9060195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Rigotti 2006 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rigotti N, Thorndike A, Regan S, Pasternak R, Chang Y, McKool K, et al. Safety and efficacy of bupropion for smokers hospitalized with acute cardiovascular disease [abstract]. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2005;7:682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigotti NA, Thorndike AN, Regan S, McKool K, Pasternak RC, Chang Y, et al. Bupropion for smokers hospitalized with acute cardiovascular disease. American Journal of Medicine 2006;119(12):1080-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorndike A, Rigotti N, Regan S, Pasternak R, McKool K, Emmons K, et al. Depression and relapse to smoking in patients hospitalized with acute cardiovascular disease [POS3-094]. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 11th Annual Meeting, 20-23 March, Prague, Czech Republic. 2005.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Rigotti 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ockene I, Salmoirago-Blotcher E. Varenicline for smoking cessation in patients with coronary heart disease [editorial]. Circulation 2010;121(2):188-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigotti NA, Pipe AL, Benowitz NL, Arteaga C, Garza D, Tonstad S. Efficacy and safety of varenicline for smoking cessation in patients with cardiovascular disease. Circulation 2010;121(2):221-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4096941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Rose 2014 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Behm FM. Combination treatment with varenicline and bupropion in an adaptive smoking cessation paradigm. American Journal of Psychiatry 2014;171(11):1199-205. [DOI: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2014.13050595]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2014.13050595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4557205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24934962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Sachs 1993 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Sachs DP, Sawe U, Leischow SJ. Effectiveness of a 16-hour transdermal nicotine patch in a medical practice setting, without intensive group counseling. Archives of Internal Medicine 1993;153(16):1881-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8110249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Saules 2004 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Saules KK, Schuh LM, Arfken CL, Reed K, Kilbey MM, Schuster CR. Double-blind placebo-controlled trial of fluoxetine in smoking cessation treatment including nicotine patch and cognitive-behavioral group therapy. American Journal on Addictions 2004;13(5):438-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15764422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuh LM, Downey KK, Hopper JA, Tancer M, Schuster CR. Fluoxetine in smoking cessation treatment. College on Problems of Drug Dependence Annual Meeting, San Juan, Puerto Rico 2000.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Sharma 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Sharma SK, Mohan A, Singh AD, Mishra H, Jhanjee S, Pandey RM, et al. Impact of nicotine replacement therapy as an adjunct to antituberculosis treatment and behaviour change counselling in newly diagnosed pulmonary tuberculosis patients: an open-label, randomised controlled trial. Scientific Reports 2018;8(1):8828. [DOI: 10.1038/s41598-018-26990-5]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-26990-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5995820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29891957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Shiffman 2002A {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Dresler CM, Shiffman S, Strahs KR. Safety profile of the new nicotine polacrilex lozenge (PO1 36). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 8th Annual Meeting: Savannah, Georgia. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiffman S, Dresler CM, Hajek P, Gilburt SJ, Targett DA, Strahs KR. Efficacy of a nicotine lozenge for smoking cessation. Archives of Internal Medicine 2002;162(11):1267-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12038945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiffman S, Dresler CM, Rohay JM. Successful treatment with a nicotine lozenge of smokers with prior failure in pharmacological therapy. Addiction 2004;99(1):83-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14678066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiffman S. Nicotine lozenge efficacy in light smokers. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2005;77(3):311-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15734231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiffman S. Use of more nicotine lozenges leads to better success in quitting smoking. Addiction 2007;102(5):809-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17493108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Shiffman 2002B {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Shiffman S, Dresler CM, Hajek P, Gilburt SJ, Targett DA, Strahs KR. Efficacy of a nicotine lozenge for smoking cessation. Archives of Internal Medicine 2002;162(11):1267-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12038945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Simon 2004 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Caplan BJ. The "bupropion for smoking cessation" trial from a family practice perspective. Archives of Internal Medicine 2005;165(4):470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15738382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon JA, Duncan C, Carmody TP, Hudes ES. Bupropion for smoking cessation: a randomized trial. Archives of Internal Medicine 2004;164(16):1797-803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15364675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon JA, Duncan C, Carmody TP, Hudes ES. Bupropion for smoking cessation: a randomized trial. In: National Conference on Tobacco or Health, November 19-22. San Francisco, California. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon JA, Duncan C, Carmody TP, Hudes ES. Bupropion plus nicotine replacement no better than replacement alone. Journal of Family Practice 2004;53:953-4.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Simon 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Simon JA, Duncan C, Huggins J, Solkowitz S, Carmody TP. Sustained-release bupropion for hospital-based smoking cessation: a randomized trial. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2009;11(6):663-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19395688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Stapleton 1995 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Russell MA, Stapleton JA, Feyerabend C, Wiseman SM, Gustavsson G, Sawe U, et al. Targeting heavy smokers in general practice: randomised controlled trial of transdermal nicotine patches. BMJ 1993;306(6888):1308-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1677738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8518572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stapleton JA, Russell MA, Feyerabend C, Wiseman SM, Gustavsson G, Sawe U, et al. Dose effects and predictors of outcome in a randomized trial of transdermal nicotine patches in general practice. Addiction 1995;90(1):31-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7888977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Sutherland 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Stapleton JA, Sutherland G, Russell MA. How much does relapse after one year erode effectiveness of smoking cessation treatments? Long term follow up of randomised trial of nicotine nasal spray. BMJ 1998;316(7134):830-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC28486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9565457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutherland G, Stapleton JA, Russell MA, Jarvis MJ, Hajek P, Belcher M, et al. Randomised controlled trial of nasal nicotine spray in smoking cessation. Lancet 1992;340(8815):324-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1353803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Tashkin 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Tashkin DP, Rennard S, Hays JT, Ma W, Lawrence D, Lee TC. Effects of varenicline on smoking cessation in mild-to-moderate COPD: a randomised controlled trial. Chest 2011;139(3):591-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20864613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 TNSG 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Daughton DM, Fortmann SP, Glover ED, Hatsukami DK, Heatley SA, Lichtenstein E, et al. The smoking cessation efficacy of varying doses of nicotine patch delivery systems 4 to 5 years post-quit day. Preventive Medicine 1999;28(2):113-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10048102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross J, Stitzer ML, Maldonado J. Nicotine replacement: effects of postcessation weight gain. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1989;57(1):87-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2925978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan GE, Jack LM, Ward MM. Subgroups of smokers with different success rates after use of transdermal nicotine. Addiction 1997;92(2):207-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9158232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transdermal Nicotine Study Group. Transdermal nicotine for smoking cessation. Six-month results from two multicenter controlled clinical trials. Transdermal Nicotine Study Group. JAMA 1991;266(22):3133-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1956099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Tonstad 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Tonstad S, Tonnesen P, Hajek P, Williams KE, Billing CB, Reeves KR. Effect of maintenance therapy with varenicline on smoking cessation. JAMA 2006;296(1):64-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16820548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Tsai 2008 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Tsai ST, Cho HJ, Cheng HS, Kim CH, Hsueh KC, Billing CB Jr et al. A randomised, placebo-controlled trial of varenicline, a selective alpha4beta2 nicotinic acetylcholine receptor partial agonist, as a new therapy for smoking cessation in Asian smokers. Clinical Therapeutics 2008;29(6):1027-39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17692719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 T&#xf8;nnesen 1991 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen KL, T&#xf8;nnesen P, N&#xf8;rregaard J. Three-year outcome of two- and three-year sustained abstainers from a smoking cessation study with nicotine patches. Journal of Smoking-Related Disorders 1994;5:95-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf8;rregaard J, T&#xf8;nnesen P, Petersen L. Predictors and reasons for relapse in smoking cessation with nicotine and placebo patches. Preventive Medicine 1993;22(2):261-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8483863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, N&#xf8;rregaard J, S&#xe4;we U. Two-year outcome in a smoking cessation trial with a nicotine patch. Journal of Smoking-Related Disorders 1992;3:241-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, N&#xf8;rregaard J, Simonsen K, S&#xe4;we U. A double-blind trial of a 16-hour transdermal nicotine patch in smoking cessation. New England Journal of Medicine 1991;325(5):311-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2057036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, N&#xf8;rregaard J, Simonsen K, S&#xe4;we U. A double-blind trial of nicotine patches in smoking cessation [En dobbeltblind undersogelse af nikotinplaster ved rygeafvaenning]. Ugeskrift for Laeger 1992;154(5):251-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1736456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 T&#xf8;nnesen 1993 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, N&#xf8;rregaard J, Mikkelsen K, Jorgensen S, Nilsson F. A double-blind trial of a nicotine inhaler for smoking cessation. JAMA 1993;269(10):1268-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8437304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Ussher 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ussher M, West R, McEwan A, Taylor A, Steptoe A. Efficacy of exercise counselling as an aid for smoking cessation: a randomised controlled trial. Addiction 2003;98(4):523-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12653822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ussher M, West R, McEwan A, Taylor A, Steptoe A. Efficacy of exercise counselling as an aid to smoking cessation: a randomised controlled trial. In: European Conference of the Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco. 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ussher M, West W, McEwen A, Taylor AH, Steptoe A. Randomised controlled trial of physical activity counselling as an aid to smoking cessation: 12 month follow-up. Addictive Behaviors 2007;32(12):3060-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17499444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Uyar 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Uyar M, Bayram N, Filiz A, Elbek O, Topcu A, Dikensoy O, et al. Comparison of nicotine patch and bupropion in treating tobacco dependence. European Respiratory Journal 2005;26(Suppl 49):388s.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uyar M, Filiz A, Bayram N, Elbek O, Herken H, Topcu A, et al. A randomized trial of smoking cessation. Medication versus motivation. Saudi Medical Journal 2007;28(6):922-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Walker 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Walker N, Parag V, Verbiest M, Laking G, Laugesen M, Bullen C. Nicotine patches used in combination with e-cigarettes (with and without nicotine) for smoking cessation:a pragmatic, randomised trial. Lancet. Respiratory Medicine 2020;8(1):54-64. [DOI: 10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30269-3]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30269-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Wallstrom 2000 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Pharmacia and Upjohn. Nicorette Nicotine Microtab Monograph. 1998 edition. Chester: Adis International, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallstrom M, Nilsson F, Hirsch JM. A double-blind placebo controlled clinical evaluation of a nicotine sublingual tablet in smoking cessation [abstract]. European Respiratory Journal 1997;10(Suppl 25):440S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11092064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallstrom M, Nilsson F, Hirsch JM. A randomized double-blind placebo-controlled clinical evaluation of a nicotine sublingual tablet in smoking cessation. Addiction 2000;95(8):1161-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11092064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Wang 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fagerstr&#xf6;m K, Nakamura M, Cho H, Tsa S, Wang C, Davis S, et al. Varenicline treatment for smoking cessation in Asian populations: a pooled analysis of placebo-controlled trials conducted in six Asian countries. Current Medical Research and Opinion 2010;26(9):2165-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20666691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Xiao D, Chan KP, Pothirat C, Garza D, Davis S. Varenicline for smoking cessation: a placebo-controlled randomised study. Respirology 2009;14(3):384-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19192221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Xiao 2019 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Xiao D, Kotler M, Kang J, Wang C. A multicenter, randomized, double-blind, parallel, placebo-controlled clinical study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a nicotine mint lozenge (2 and 4 mg) in smoking cessation. Journal of Addiction Medicine 2020;14(1):69-77. [DOI: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000547]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7012347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31658113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Zellweger 2005 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Puska P, Brath H, Astbury C, Hider AE. Zyban is an effective and well tolerated aid to smoking cessation in a healthcare professionals population - a multi-country study. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 3rd European Conference, September 2001, Paris, France. 2001:45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zellweger JP, Blaziene A, Astbury C, Hider A, Hogue S. Bupropion hydrochloride sustained release is an effective and well tolerated aid to smoking cessation in a healthcare professionals population - a multicountry study. Abstract and presentation at 11th Annual meeting of European Respiratory Society, Berlin, September 22-26 2001. European Respiratory Journal 2001;18(Suppl 33):166s.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zellweger JP, Boelcskei PL, Carrozzi L, Sepper R, Sweet R, Hider AZ. Bupropion SR vs placebo for smoking cessation in health care professionals. American Journal of Health Behavior 2005;29(3):240-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15899687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>1 Ames 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ames SC, Ames GE, Stevens SR, Patten C, Werch C, Schroeder DR. Expressive writing as a treatment adjunct to reduce weight gain in young adult smokers undergoing smoking cessation (PA3-6). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 13th Annual Meeting. Austin, Texas, Feb 21-24, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Chaney 2008 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Chaney SE, Sheriff S. Weight gain among women during smoking cessation: testing the effects of a multifaceted program. American Association of Occupational Health Nurse Journal 2008;56(3):99-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18389822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Hughes 1997 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Hatsukami DK. Effects of three doses of transdermal nicotine on post-cessation eating, hunger and weight. Journal of Substance Abuse 1997;9:151-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9494946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 ISRCTN47776579 {unpublished data only}ISRCTN47776579</Title><Reference><Citation>ISRCTN47776579. A trial of physical activity assisted reduction of smoking. www.isrctn.com/ISRCTN47776579 (first received 23 October 2017). [DOI: 10.1186/ISRCTN47776579]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/ISRCTN47776579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor A, Thompson TP, Ussher M, Aveyard P, Murray RL, Harris T, et al. Randomised controlled trial of tailored support to increase physical activity and reduce smoking in smokers not immediately ready to quit: protocol for the Trial of physical Activity-assisted Reduction of Smoking (TARS) Study. BMJ Open 2020;10(12):e043331. [DOI: 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-043331]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-043331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7709511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33262194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Jeffery 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jeffery RW, Hellerstedt WL, Schmid TL. Correspondence programs for smoking cessation and weight control: a comparison of two strategies in the Minnesota Heart Health Program. Health Psychology 1990;9(5):585-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2226387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Killen 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Newman B. Weight change among participants in a large sample minimal contact smoking relapse prevention trial. Addictive Behaviors 1990;15(4):323-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2248106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Kim 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kim S. Effect of complex training on carbon monoxide, cardiorespiratory function, and body mass among college students at the initial stage of stopping smoking. Journal of Physical Therapy Science 2017;29(8):1297-300. [DOI: 10.1589/jpts.29.1297]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.29.1297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5574360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28878451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 King 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>King A, Wit H, Riley RC, Cao D, Niaura R, Hatsukami D. Efficacy of naltrexone in smoking cessation: a preliminary study and an examination of sex difference. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2006;8(5):671-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17008194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Lagrue 1994 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lagrue G, Auclair J, Cormier S, Grimaldi B, Demaria C, Banzet MN. A study of the effects of dexfenfluramine on weight and eating behavior after smoking cessation by overweight patients. Semaine des Hopitaux 1994;70:23-24.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Leischow 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Leischow SJ, Sachs DP, Bostrom AG, Hansen MD, Sachs DP. Effects of differing nicotine-replacement doses on weight gain after smoking cessation. Archives of Family Medicine 1992;1(2):233-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1341599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Love 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Love SJ, Sheffer CE, Bursac Z, Prewitt TE, Krukowski RA, West DS. Offer of a weight management program to overweight and obese weight-concerned smokers improves tobacco dependence treatment outcomes. American Journal on Addictions 2011;20(1):1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21175914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT02412631 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT02412631. Addressing post cessation weight gain. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02412631 (first received 9 April 2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT03362372 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Luj&#xe1;n F, Catalin RE, Salamanca-Gonz&#xe1;lez P, Sorl&#xed;-Aguilar M, Santigosa-Ayala A, Valls-Zamora RM, et al. A clinical trial to evaluate the effect of the Mediterranean diet on smokers lung function. NPJ Primary Care Respiratory Medicine 2019;29(1):40. [DOI: 10.1038/s41533-019-0153-7]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41533-019-0153-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6881294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31776344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCT03362372. Effect of the Mediterranean diet on lung function in smokers without previous respiratory disease (MEDISTAR). clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03362372 (first received 5 December 2017).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Patterson 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Patterson F, Wileyto EP, Ray R, Lerman C. Examiniation of post cessation weight gain (POS2-85). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 12th Annual Meeting. Orlando, Florida, Feb 15-18 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Pomerleau 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Pomerleau OF, Pomerleau CS, Morrell EM, Lowenbergh JM. Effects of fluoxetine on weight gain and food intake in smokers who reduce nicotine intake. Psychoneuroendocrinology 1991;16(5):433-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1805294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Rohsenow 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rohsenow DJ, Monti PM, Hutchinson KE, Swift RM, Mackinnon SV, Sirota AD, et al. High dose transdermal nicotine and naltrexone: effects on nicotine withdrawal, urges, smoking and effects of smoking. Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology 2007;15(1):81-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17295587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Russo 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Russo C, Cibella F, Caponnetto P, Campagna D, Maglia M, Frazzetto E, et al. Evaluation of post cessation weight gain in a 1-year randomized smoking cessation trial of electronic cigarettes. Scientific Reports 2016;6:18763. [DOI: 10.1038/srep18763]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep18763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4700433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26729619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Spring 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Spring B, Wurtman J, Gleason R, Wurtman R, Kessler K. Weight gain and withdrawal symptoms after smoking cessation: a preventive intervention using d-Fenfluramine. Health Psychology 1991;10(3):216-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1879394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Thompson 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jennings C, Kotseva K, De Bacquer D, Hoes A, De Velasco J, Brusaferro S, et al. Effectiveness of a preventive cardiology programme for high CVD risk persistent smokers: the EUROACTION PLUS varenicline trial. European Heart Journal 35;21:1411-20. [DOI: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehu051]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehu051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24616337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson E, Jennings C, Kotseva K, De Bacquer D, Hoes A, De Velasco J, et al. Effectiveness of the EUROACTION PLUS (EA+) preventive cardiology programme for high CVD risk smokers in modifying dietary habits and anthropometric indices. In: ESC Congress 2015; 2015 Aug 30. 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Toll 2008 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Toll BA, Leary V, Wu R, Salovey P, Meandzija B, O'Malley SS. A preliminary investigation of naltrexone augmentation of bupropion to stop smoking with less weight gain. Addictive Behaviors 2008;33(1):173-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2488403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17587504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Wilcox 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Wilcox CS, Oskooilar N, Erickson JS, Billes SK, Katz BB, Tollefson G, et al. An open label study of naltrexone and bupropion combination therapy for smoking cessation in overweight and obese subjects. Addictive Behaviors 2010;35(3):229-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19926400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Ahluwalia 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahluwalia JS, Harris KJ, Catley D, Okuyemi KS, Mayo MS. Sustained-release bupropion for smoking cessation in African Americans: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA 2002;288:468-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12132977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boardman T, Catley D, Mayo MS, Ahluwalia JS. Self-efficacy and motivation to quit during participation in a smoking cessation program. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine 2005;12:266-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16262545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catley D, Harris KJ, Okuyemi KS, Mayo MS, Pankey E, Ahluwalia JS. The influence of depressive symptoms on smoking cessation among African Americans in a randomized trial of bupropion. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2005;7:859-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16298721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris KJ, Ahluwalia JS, Catley D, Okuyemi KS, Mayo MS, Resnicow K. Successful recruitment of minorities into clinical trials: the Kick It at Swope project. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2003;5:575-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12959796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris KJ, Okuyemi KS, Catley D, Mayo MS, Ge B, Ahluwalia JS. Predictors of smoking cessation among African-Americans enrolled in a randomized controlled trial of bupropion. Preventive Medicine 2004;38:498-502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15020185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuyemi KS, Ahluwalia JS, Ebersole Robinson M, Catley D, Mayo MS, Resnicow K. Does menthol attenuate the effect of bupropion among African American smokers? Addiction 2003;98:1387-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14519175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Aubin 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Aubin HJ, Lebargy F, Berlin I, Bidaut-Mazel C, Chemali-Hudry J, Lagrue G. Efficacy of bupropion and predictors of successful outcome in a sample of French smokers: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Addiction 2004;99:1206-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15317642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebargy F, Aubin HJ, Lagrue G, Bidaut-Mazel C, Chemali-Hudry J, Poulain L. A placebo-controlled, double-blind study of Zyban LP: an effective and well-tolerated aid to smoking cessation - preliminary results (POS4-69). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 9th Annual Meeting February 19-22 New Orleans, Louisiana. 2003.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Berlin 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Berlin I, Said S, Spreux Varoquaux O, Launay JM, Olivares R, Millet V, et al. A reversible monoamine oxidase A inhibitor (moclobemide) facilitates smoking cessation and abstinence in heavy, dependent smokers. Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics 1995;58:444-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7586937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlin I, Spreux Varoquaux O, Said S, Launay JM. Effects of past history of major depression on smoking characteristics, monoamine oxidase-A and -B activities and withdrawal symptoms in dependent smokers. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 1997;45:31-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9179504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Blondal 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Blondal T, Gudmundsson LJ, Tomasson K, Jonsdottir D, Hilmarsdottir H, Kristjansson F et al. The effects of fluoxetine combined with nicotine inhalers in smoking cessation - a randomized trial. Addiction 1999;94:1007-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10707439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Brown 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>David SP, Brown RA, Papandonatos GD, Kahler CW, Lloyd-Richardson EE, Munaf&#xf2; MR, et al. Bupropion interacts with DRD2-TAQ1A genotype and craving to influence smoking cessation (RPOS 3-34). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 12th Annual Meeting February 15-18, Orlando, Florida. 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David SP, Niaura R, Papandonatos GD, Shadel WG, Burkholder GJ, Britt DM, et al. Does the DRD2-Taq1 A polymorphism influence treatment response to bupropion hydrochloride for reduction of the nicotine withdrawal syndrome? Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2003;5:935-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14668077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David SP, Papandonatos GD, Munaf&#xf2; MR, McCaffery JM, Lerman C, Lloyd-Richardson EE, et al. DRD2-TAQ1A genotypic moderation of bupropion treatment efficacy for smoking cessation at 6-month follow-up [abstract]. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2005;7:704.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Cinciripini 05 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Cinciripini PM, Wetter D, Minna J, et al. The effects of brief counseling, transdermal nicotine replacement and antidepressant therapy on smoking cessation among smokers carrying the DRD2 A1 allele (PA3A). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco Annual Meeting; Mar 5-7 1999; San Diego, California. 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinciripini PM, Tsoh JY, Friedman K, Wetter D, Cinciripini LG, Skaar KL. A placebo controlled evaluation of venlafaxine for smoking cessation: preliminary findings [Abstract A18]. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco Annual Meeting; Mar 27-29 1998;,New Orleans, Louisiana. 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinciripini PM, Tsoh JY, Wetter DW, Lam C, Moor C, Cinciripini L, et al. Combined effects of venlafaxine, nicotine replacement, and brief counseling on smoking cessation. Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology 2005;13:282-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16366758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinciripini PM, Wetter DW, Tomlinson GE, Tsoh JY, Moor CA, Cinciripini LG, et al. The effects of the DRD2 polymorphism on smoking cessation and negative affect: Evidence for a pharmacogenetic effect on mood. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2004;6:229-39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15203796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Collins 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Collins B, Wileyto P, Patterson F, Rukstalis M, Audrain-McGovern J, Kaufmann V, et al. Gender differences in smoking cessation in a placebo-controlled trial of bupropion with behavioral counseling. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2004;6:27-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14982685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins BN, Niaura R, Wileyto EP, Patterson F, Brown RA, Audrain J. Gender differences in smoking relapse in a behavioral counseling + placebo-controlled bupropion trial (PA2-5). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 8th Annual Meeting; February 20-23; Savannah, Georgia. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Jepson C, Wileyto EP, Epstein LH, Rukstalis M, Patterson F, et al. Role of functional genetic variation in the dopamine D2 receptor (DRD2) in response to bupropion and nicotine replacement therapy for tobacco dependence: results of two randomized clinical trials. Neuropsychopharmacology 2006;31:231-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16123753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Niaura R, Collins BN, Wileyto P, Audrain MJ, Pinto A, et al. Effect of bupropion on depression symptoms in a smoking cessation clinical trial. Psychology of Addictive Behaviors 2004;18:362-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15631608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Roth D, Kaufmann V, Audrain J, Hawk L, Liu AY, et al. Mediating mechanisms for the impact of bupropion in smoking cessation treatment. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2002;67:219-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12095672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Shields PG, Wileyto EP, Audrain J, Hawk LH Jr, Pinto A, et al. Effects of dopamine transporter and receptor polymorphisms on smoking cessation in a bupropion clinical trial. Health Psychology 2003;22:541-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14570538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerman C, Shields PG, Wileyto EP, Audrain J, Pinto A, Hawk L, et al. Pharmacogenetic investigation of smoking cessation treatment. Pharmacogenetics 2002;12:627-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12439223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wileyto EP, Patterson F, Niaura R, Epstein LH, Brown RA, Audrain-McGovern J, et al. Recurrent event analysis of lapse and recovery in a smoking cessation clinical trial using bupropion. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2005;7:257-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16036283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wileyto P, Patterson F, Niaura R, Epstein L, Brown R, Audrain-McGovern J, et al. Do small lapses predict relapse to smoking behavior under bupropion treatment? Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2004;6:357-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15203809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Covey 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Covey LS, Glassman AH, Stetner F, Rivelli S, Stage K. A randomized trial of sertraline as a cessation aid for smokers with a history of major depression. American Journal of Psychiatry 2002;159:1731-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12359680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covey LS, Glassman AH, Stetner F, Rivelli S. A trial of sertraline for smokers with past major depression. Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco Meeting. Arlington, VA (www.srnt.org/events/abstracts99/index.htm) 2000.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Covey 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Covey LS, Glassman AH, Jiang H, Fried J, Masmela J, LoDuca C, et al. A randomized trial of bupropion and/or nicotine gum as maintenance treatment for preventing smoking relapse. Addiction 2007;102:1292-302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17624979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Da Costa 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Da Costa C, Younes R, Lourenco M. Smoking cessation: a randomized double-blind study comparing nortriptyline to placebo [abstract]. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine 2001;163(5 Suppl):A354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Costa CL, Younes RN, Lourenco MT-C. Stopping smoking: a prospective, randomized, double-blind study comparing nortriptyline to placebo. Chest 2002;122:403-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12171809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Dalsgareth 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Dalsgar&#xf0; OJ, Vestbo J. A multicenter, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled 6 month trial to evaluate efficacy and tolerability of bupropion hydrochloride sustained release (SR) tablets as treatment for nicotine dependency in healthcare workers and as an aid to smoking cessation (ZYB30009). Poster and oral presentation. In: European Congress on Tobacco or Health, Warsaw, Poland, 20-22 June 2002. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalsgareth OJ, Hansen NC, S&#xf8;es-Petersen U, Evald T, H&#xf8;egholm A, Barber J, et al. A multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, 6-month trial of bupropion hydrochloride sustained-release tablets as an aid to smoking cessation in hospital employees. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2004;6:55-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14982688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Evins 2001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Evins AE, Cather C, Rigotti NA, Freudenreich O, Henderson DC, Olm Shipman CM, et al. Two-year follow-up of a smoking cessation trial in patients with schizophrenia: increased rates of smoking cessation and reduction. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry 2004;65:307-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15096068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evins AE, Mays VK, Rigotti NA, Tisdale T, Cather C, Goff DC. A pilot trial of bupropion added to cognitive behavioral therapy for smoking cessation in schizophrenia. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2001;3:397-403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11694208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Evins 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Evins AE, Cather C, Culhane M, Freudenreich O, Rigotti NA, Goff DC. Smoking cessation in schizophrenia: a double blind placebo controlled trial of bupropion SR added to cognitive behavioral therapy. Biological Psychiatry 2004;55:806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evins AE, Cather C, Deckersbach T, Freudenreich O, Culhane MA, Olm-Shipman CM, et al. A double-blind placebo-controlled trial of bupropion sustained-release for smoking cessation in schizophrenia. Journal of Clinical Psychopharmacology 2005;25:218-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15876899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evins AE, Deckersbach T, Cather C, Freudenreich O, Culhane MA, Henderson DC, et al. Independent effects of tobacco abstinence and bupropion on cognitive function in schizophrenia. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry 2005;66:1184-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16187778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Evins 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Evins AE, Cather C, Culhane M, Birnbaum AS, Horowitz J, Hsieh E, et al. A placebo-controlled study of bupropion SR added to high dose nicotine replacement therapy for smoking cessation or reduction in schizophrenia (POS2-104). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 12th Annual Meeting; February 15-18, Orlando, Florida. 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Evins 2008 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Evins AE, Culhane MA, Alpert JE, Pava J, Liese BS, Farabaugh A, et al. A controlled trial of bupropion added to nicotine patch and behavioral therapy for smoking cessation in adults with unipolar depressive disorders. Journal of Clinical Psychopharmacology 2008;28:660-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3505846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19011435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Ferry 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ferry LH, Robbins AS, Scariati PD, et al. Enhancement of smoking cessation using the antidepressant bupropion hydrochloride [abstract 2670]. Circulation 1992;86(4 Suppl 1):I-671.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Ferry 1994 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ferry LH, Burchette RJ. Efficacy of bupropion for smoking cessation in non depressed smokers [Abstract]. Journal of Addictive Diseases 1994;13(4):249.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD George 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>George TP, Vessicchio JC, Termine A, Bregartner TA, Feingold A, Rounsaville BJ, et al. A placebo controlled trial of bupropion for smoking cessation in schizophrenia. Biological Psychiatry 2002;52:53-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12079730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD GlaxoSmithK SMK20001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>GlaxoSmithKline Clinical Trials Register. Study No: SMK 20001. A multi-center, double-blind, double-dummy, placebo-controlled, randomized, parallel group, dose response evaluation of a new chemical entity (NCE) and ZYBAN (bupropion hydrochloride) sustained release (300mg/day) versus placebo as aids to smoking cessation. ctr.glaxowellcome.co.uk-Summary-bupropion-II_SMK20001.pdf (accessed 23rd August 2006).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Gonzales 2001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gonzales D, Nides M, Ferry LH, Segall N, Herrero L, Modell J, et al. Retreatment with bupropion SR: results from 12-month follow-up (RP-83). In: Rapid Communication Poster Abstracts. Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 8th Annual Meeting, February 20-23 Savannah, Georgia. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzales DH, Nides MA, Ferry LH, Kustra RP, Jamerson BD, Segall N, et al. Bupropion SR as an aid to smoking cessation in smokers treated previously with bupropion: a randomized placebo-controlled study. Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics 2001;69:438-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11406741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Haggstr&#xe4;m 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Haggstr&#xe4;m FM, Chatkin JM, Sussenbach-Vaz E, Cesari DH, Fam CF, Fritscher CC. A controlled trial of nortriptyline, sustained-release bupropion and placebo for smoking cessation: preliminary results. Pulmonary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 2006;19:205-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16517193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Hall 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Haas AL, Munoz RF, Humfleet GL, Reus VI, Hall SM. Influences of mood, depression history, and treatment modality on outcomes in smoking cessation. Journal of Consulting &amp; Clinical Psychology 2004;72:563-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15301640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Reus VI, Munoz RF, Sees KL, Humfleet G, Hartz DT, et al. Nortriptyline and cognitive-behavioral therapy in the treatment of cigarette smoking. Archives of General Psychiatry 1998;55:683-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9707377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Hall 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Humfleet G, Maude-Griffin R, Reus VI, Mu&#xf1;oz R, Hartz DT. Nortriptyline versus bupropion and medical management versus psychological intervention in smoking treatment (PA 5A). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 7th Annual Meeting March 23-23 Seattle, Washington. 2001:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Humfleet GL, Reus VI, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, Hartz DT, Maude-Griffin R. Psychological intervention and antidepressant treatment in smoking cessation. Archives of General Psychiatry 2002;59:930-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12365880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Lightwood JM, Humfleet GL, Bostrom A, Reus VI, Mu&#xf1;oz R. Cost-effectiveness of bupropion, nortriptyline, and psychological intervention in smoking cessation. Journal of Behavioral Health Services &amp; Research 2005;32:381-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16215448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Hall 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Humfleet GL, Reus VI, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, Cullen J. Extended nortriptyline and psychological treatment for cigarette smoking. American Journal of Psychiatry 2004;161:2100-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15514412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Hatsukami 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hatsukami DK, Rennard S, Patel MK, Kotlyar M, Malcolm R, Nides MA, et al. Effects of sustained-release bupropion among persons interested in reducing but not quitting smoking. American Journal of Medicine 2004;116:151-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14749158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennard S, Hatsukami D, Malcolm RE, Patel MK, Jamerson BD, Dozier G. Zyban (bupropion HCL SR) vs placebo as an aid to smoking reduction among smokers unwilling and unable to quit smoking (PO4 77). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 7th Annual Meeting March 23-23 Seattle, Washington. 2001:117.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Hays 2001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Abel GA, Hays JT, Decker PA, Croghan GA, Kuter DJ, Rigotti NA. Effects of biochemically confirmed smoking cessation on white blood cell count. Mayo Clinic Proceedings 2005;80:1022-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16092581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox LS, Patten CA, Niaura RS, Decker PA, Rigotti N, Sachs DP, et al. Efficacy of bupropion for relapse prevention in smokers with and without a past history of major depression. Journal of General Internal Medicine 2004;19:828-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1492503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15242467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durcan MJ, Deener G, White J, Johnston JA, Gonzales D, Niaura R, et al. The effect of bupropion sustained-release on cigarette craving after smoking cessation. Clinical Therapeutics 2002;24:540-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12017399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durcan MJ, Johnston JA, White J, Gonzales D, Sachs DP, Rigotti N, et al. Bupropion SR for relapse prevention: a "slips-allowed" analysis. American Journal of Health Behavior 2004;28(5):456-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15482975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzales D, Bjornson W, Durcan MJ, White JD, Johnston JA, Buist AS, et al. Effects of gender on relapse prevention in smokers treated with bupropion SR. American Journal of Preventive Medicine 2002;22:234-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11988379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hays JT, Hurt RD, Rigotti NA, Niaura R, Gonzales D, Durcan MJ, et al. Sustained-release bupropion for pharmacologic relapse prevention after smoking cessation. A randomized, controlled trial. Annals of Internal Medicine 2001;135:423-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11560455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurt RD, Wolter TD, Rigotti N, Hays JT, Niaura R, Durcan MJ, et al. Bupropion for pharmacologic relapse prevention to smoking - Predictors of outcome. Addictive Behaviors 2002;27(4):493-507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12188588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigotti N, Thorndike AN, Durcan MJ, White JD, Johnston AJ, Niaura R, et al. Attenuation of post-cessation weight gain in smokers taking bupropion: the effect of gender. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 6th Annual Meeting; Feb 18-20 2000; Arlington VA. 2000.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Hertzberg 2001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hertzberg MA, Moore SD, Feldman ME, Beckham JC. A preliminary study of bupropion sustained-release for smoking cessation in patients with chronic posttraumatic stress disorder. Journal of Clinical Psychopharmacology 2001;21:94-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11199956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Holt 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Holt S, Timu-Parata C, Ryder-Lewis S, Weatherall M, Beasley R. Efficacy of bupropion in the indigenous Maori population in New Zealand. Thorax 2005;60:120-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1747282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15681499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Hurt 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hurt RD, Croghan GA, Sloan JA, Krook JE, Silberstein PT. Bupropion for relapse prevention after nicotine patch therapy [PA 5B abstract ]. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 7th Annual Meeting, March 23-23 2001, Seattle, Washington. 2001:32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurt RD, Krook JE, Croghan IT, Loprinzi CL, Sloan JA, Novotny PJ, et al. Nicotine patch therapy based on smoking rate followed by bupropion for prevention of relapse to smoking. Journal of Clinical Oncology 2003;21:914-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12610193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Killen 2000 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Schatzberg A, Hayward C, Varady A. Onset of major depression during treatment for nicotine dependence. Addictive Behaviors 2003;28:461-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12628619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Schatzberg AF, Hayward C, Sussman L, Rothman M, et al. Nicotine patch and paroxetine for smoking cessation. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 2000;68:883-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11068974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Killen 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Robinson TN, Ammerman S, Hayward C, Rogers J, Samuels D. Major depression among adolescent smokers undergoing treatment for nicotine dependence. Addictive Behaviors 2004;29:1517-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15451121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Robinson TN, Ammerman S, Hayward C, Rogers J, Stone C, et al. Randomized clinical trial of the efficacy of bupropion combined with nicotine patch in the treatment of adolescent smokers. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 2004;72:729-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15301658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Killen 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Murphy GM Jr, Hayward C, Arredondo C, Cromp D, et al. Extended treatment with bupropion SR for cigarette smoking cessation. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 2006;74(2):286-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16649873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Myles 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Myles PS, Leslie K, Angliss M, Mezzavia P, Lee L. Effectiveness of bupropion as an aid to stopping smoking before elective surgery: a randomised controlled trial. Anaesthesia 2004;59:1053-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15479310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Piper 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federman EB, Bolt DM, Smith SS, Fiore MC, Baker TB. Mediators of bupropion treatment effects (PA5-6). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 12th Annual Meeting February 15-18, Orlando, Florida. 2006:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federman EB, Smith SS, Fiore MC, Baker TB. Efficacy of bupropion SR alone and combined with 4-mg gum (PA2-2). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 10th Annual Meeting February 18-21, Phoenix, Arizona. 2004:18.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Piper 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gennuso KP, Thraen-Borowski KM, Schlam TR, LaRowe TL, Fiore MC, Baker TB, et al. Smokers' physical activity and weight gain one year after a successful versus unsuccessful quit attempt. Preventive Medicine 2014;67:189-92. [CENTRAL: 1014125] [EMBASE: 2014546589] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4457287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25091879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Smith SS, Schlam TR, Fiore MC, Jorenby DE, Fraser D, et al. A randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial of 5 smoking cessation pharmacotherapies. Archives of General Psychiatry 2009;66:1253-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19884613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SS, McCarthy DE, Japuntich SJ, Christiansen B, Piper ME, Jorenby DE, et al. Comparative effectiveness of 5 smoking cessation pharmacotherapies in primary care clinics. Archives of Internal Medicine 2009;169:2148-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2891174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein JH, Asthana A, Smith SS, Piper ME, Loh WY, Fiore MC, et al. Smoking cessation and the risk of diabetes mellitus and impaired fasting glucose: three-year outcomes after a quit attempt. PLOS One 2014;9(6):e98278. [CENTRAL: 995881]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4043674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24893290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Prochazka 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Prochazka AV, Weaver MJ, Keller RT, Fryer GE, Licari PA, Lofaso D. A randomized trial of nortriptyline for smoking cessation. Archives of Internal Medicine 1998;158:2035-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9778204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Prochazka 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Prochazka AV, Kick S, Steinbrunn C, Miyoshi T, Fryer GE. A randomized trial of nortriptyline combined with transdermal nicotine for smoking cessation. Archives of Internal Medicine 2004;164:2229-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15534159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prochazka AV, Reyes R, Steinbrunn C, Miyoshi T. Randomized trial of nortriptyline combined with transdermal nicotine for smoking cessation (PO3 26). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 7th Annual Meeting, March 23-23 2001, Seattle, Washington. 2001:73.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Rovina 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rovina N, Nikoloutsou I, Katsani G, Dima E, Fransis K, Roussos C, &amp; Gratziou, C. Effectiveness of pharmacotherapy and behavioral interventions for smoking cessation in actual clinical practice. Therapeutic Advances in Respiratory Disease 2009;3:279-87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19934280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Selby 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>GlaxoSmithKline Clinical Trials Register. Study No: ZYB40001. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, 12-week smoking cessation trial of Zyban (150 mg bid) in adult smokers previously treated with Zyban. ctr.glaxowellcome.co.uk-Summary-bupropion-IV_ZYB40001.pdf (accessed 23rd August 2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selby P, Ainslie M, Stepner N, Roberts J. Sustained-release bupropion (Zybanr) is effective in the re-treatment of relapsed adult smokers. American Journal of Respiratory Critical Care Medicine 2003;167(7):A47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selby P, Brands B, Stepner N. Retreatment with ZYban SR: 52 week follow-up of a Canadian multicentre trial (POS3-63). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 9th Annual Meeting, February 19-22, New Orleans. 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selby P, Brosky G, Baker R, Lertzman M, Dakin P, Roberts J. Zyban is effective in the retreatment of relapsed adult smokers (PO4 68). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 7th Annual Meeting March 23-23 Seattle Washington. 2001:114.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Swan 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Catz S, Jack LM, Swan GE, McClure J. Adherence to bupropion SR in a smoking cessation effectiveness trial (POS2-77). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 12th Annual Meeting February 15-18, Orlando, Florida. 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack LM, Swan GE, Thompson E, Curry SJ, McAfee T, Dacey S, et al. Bupropion SR and smoking cessation in actual practice: methods for recruitment, screening, and exclusion for a field trial in a managed-care setting. Preventive Medicine 2003;36:585-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12689804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javitz HS, Swan GE, Zbikowski SM, Curry SJ, McAfee TA, Decker DL, et al. Cost-effectiveness of different combinations of bupropion SR dose and behavioral treatment for smoking cessation: a societal perspective. American Journal of Managed Care 2004;10:217-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15032259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAfee T, Zbikowski SM, Bush T, McClure J, Swan G, Jack LM, et al. The effectiveness of bupropion SR and phone counseling for light and heavy smokers (PA2-1). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 10th Annual Meeting February 18-21, Phoenix, Arizona. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan GE, Jack LM, Curry S, Chorost M, Javitz H, McAfee T, et al. Bupropion SR and counseling for smoking cessation in actual practice: Predictors of outcome. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2003;5:911-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14668075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan GE, Javitz HS, Jack LM, Curry SJ, McAfee T. Heterogeneity in 12-month outcome among female and male smokers. Addiction 2004;99:237-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14756716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan GE, McAfee T, Curry SJ, Jack LM, Javitz H, Dacey S, et al. Effectiveness of bupropion sustained release for smoking cessation in a health care setting: a randomized trial. Archives of Internal Medicine 2003;163:2337-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14581254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan GE, Valdes AM, Ring HZ, Khroyan TV, Jack LM, Ton CC, et al. Dopamine receptor DRD2 genotype and smoking cessation outcome following treatment with bupropion SR. Pharmacogenomics Journal 2005;5:21-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15492764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Tashkin 2001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Patel MK, Tashkin DP, Kanner RE, Bailey WC, Buist A, Anderson PJ, et al. A multicenter evaluation of the effects of bupropion hydrochloride sustained release tablets (Bup SR) versus placebo in a population of smokers with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (PO130). In: 11th World Conference on Tobacco or Health; Aug 6-11 2000; Chicago, ILL. Vol. 1. 2000:118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashkin D, Kanner R, Bailey W, Buist S, Anderson P, Nides M, et al. Smoking cessation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomised trial. Lancet 2001;357:1571-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11377644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Tonstad 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>McRobbie H, Brath H, Astbury C, Hider A, Sweet R. Bupropion hydrochloride sustained release (SR) is an effective and well tolerated aid to smoking cessation in smokers with cardiovascular disease 12 month follow-up phase data (ZYB40014). In: European Respiratory Society meeting, 14-18 September 2002, Stockholm, Sweden. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonstad S, Farsang C, Klaene G, Lewis K, Manolis A, Perruchoud AP, et al. Bupropion SR for smoking cessation in smokers with cardiovascular disease: a multicentre, randomised study. European Heart Journal 2003;24:946-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12714026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Spiegel PI, Lewis K, Seinost G, Astbury C, Hider A, Sweet R. Bupropion hydrochloride (Zyban) is an effective and well tolerated aid to smoking cessation in smokers with cardiovascular disease - a multicountry study. Abstract and presentation at 11th Annual meeting of European Respiratory Society, Berlin, September 22-26. European Respiratory Journal 2001;18(Suppl 33):13s.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD T&#xf8;nnesen 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bolliger CT, Gilljam H, Lebargy F, Van Spiegel PI, Edwards J, Hider A, et al. Bupropion hydrochloride (Zyban) is effective and well tolerated as an aid to smoking cessation - a multicountry study. Abstract and presentation at 11th Annual meeting of European Respiratory Society, Berlin, September 22-26 2001. European Respiratory Journal 2001;18(Suppl 33):12s.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, Tonstad S, Hjalmarson A, Lebargy F, Van Spiegel PI, Hider A, et al. A multicentre, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, 1-year study of bupropion SR for smoking cessation. Journal of Internal Medicine 2003;254:184-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12859700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonstad S, Aaserud E, Hjalmarson A, Peiffer G, Van der Molen T, Hider A, et al. Zyban is an effective and well tolerated aid to smoking cessation in a general smoking population - a multi-country study. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 3rd Europe Conference, September 19-22 2001, Paris, France. 2001:46.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Uyar 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Uyar M, Bayram N, Filiz A, Elbek O, Top&#xe7;u A, Dikensoy O, et al. Comparison of nicotine patch and bupropion in treating tobacco dependence. European Respiratory Journal 2005;26(Suppl 49):388s.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 AD Wagena 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Wagena EJ, Knipschild PG, Huibers MJ, Wouters EF, Van Schayck CP. Efficacy of bupropion and nortriptyline for smoking cessation among people at risk for or with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Archives of Internal Medicine 2005;165:2286-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16246996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Aveyard 2018 {published data only}ISRCTN33031001</Title><Reference><Citation>Aveyard P, Lindson N, Tearne S, Adams R, Ahmed K, Alekna R, et al. Nicotine preloading for smoking cessation: the Preloading RCT. Health Technology Assessment 22;41:1-84. [DOI: 10.3310/hta22410]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3310/hta22410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6099332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30079863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Drovandi 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Drovandi A, Teague P, Glass B, Malau-Aduli B. A randomised controlled trial evaluating the effectiveness and tolerability of step-up and step-down varenicline therapy for smoking cessation: a study protocol. Journal of Smoking Cessation 2018;13(3):179-85. [DOI: 10.1017/jsc.2017.17]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/jsc.2017.17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Hill 1985 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hill JS. Effect of a program of aerobic exercise on the smoking behaviour of a group of adult volunteers. Canadian Journal of Public Health 1985;76:186-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4016652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Hill 1993 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hill RD, Rigdon M, Johnson S. Behavioural smoking cessation treatment for older chronic smokers. Behavioural Therapy 1993;24:321-9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Kinnunen 2008 {unpublished data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kinnunen T, Leeman RF, Korhonen T, Quiles ZN, Terwal DM, Garvey AJ, et al. Exercise as an adjunct to nicotine gum in treating tobacco dependence among women. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2008;10:689-703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3695732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18418791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korhonen T, Goodwin A, Miesmaa P, Dupuis EA, Kinnunen T. Smoking cessation program with exercise improves cardiovascular disease biomarkers in sedentary women. Journal of Women's Health 2011;20(7):1051-64. [CENTRAL: 814607] [39790] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3163461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21675876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quiles ZN, Leeman RF, Molinelli L, Nordstrom BL, Garvey AJ, Hartley LH, et al. Exercise as a behavioural adjunct to nicotine gum for smoking cessation - preliminary findings (PO 42). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 8th Annual Meeting. Vol. 59. Savannah, Georgia, February 20-23, 2002.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Marcus 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Marcus BH, Albrecht AE, Niaura RS, Abrams DB, Thompson PD. Usefulness of physical exercise for maintaining smoking cessation in women. American Journal of Cardiology 1991;68:406-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1858687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Marcus 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Marcus BH, Albrecht AE, Niaura RS, Taylor ER, Simkin LR, Feder SI, et al. Exercise enhances the maintenance of smoking cessation in women. Addictive Behaviours 1995;20:87-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7785485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Martin 1997 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Martin JE, Kalfas KJ, Patten CA. Prospective evaluation of three smoking interventions in 205 recovering alcoholics: One-year results of project SCRAP-Tobacco. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1997;65:190-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9103749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patten CA, Martin JE, Calfas KJ, Brown SA, Schroeder DR. Effect of three smoking cessation treatments on nicotine withdrawal in 141 abstinent alcoholic smokers. Addictive Behaviours 2000;25:301-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10795956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patten CA, Martin JE, Calfas KJ, Wolter TD. Behavioural treatment for smokers with a history of alcoholism: predictors of successful outcome. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 2001;69(5):796-801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11680556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Prapavessis 2007 {unpublished data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Prapavessis H, Cameron l, Baldi JC, Robinson S, Borrie K, Harper T, et al. The effects of exercise and nicotine replacement therapy on smoking rates in women. Addictive Behaviors 2007;32:1416-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17097814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prapavessis H. The effects of exercise and nicotine replacement therapy on smoking rates in women. In: Eighth International Congress of Behavioural Medicine. Mainz, Germany, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17097814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Russell 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Russell PO, Epstein LH, Johnson JJ, Block DR, Blair E. The effects of exercise as maintenance for smoking cessation. Addictive Behaviours 1988;13:215-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3369334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 EX Taylor 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Taylor CB, Houston-Miller N, Haskell WL, Debusk RF. Smoking cessation after acute myocardial infarction: the effects of exercise training. Addictive Behaviours 1988;13:215-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3239464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 LeMao 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Le Mao R, Tromeur C, Paleiron N, Sanchez O, Gagnadoux F, Jouneau S, et al. Effect of early initiation of varenicline on smoking cessation in COPD patients admitted for exacerbation: the Save randomized clinical trial. COPD 2020;17(1):7-14. [DOI: 10.1080/15412555.2019.1703928]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15412555.2019.1703928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31854207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Ahluwalia 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahluwalia JS, McNagny SE, Clark WS. Smoking cessation among inner-city African Americans using the nicotine transdermal patch. Journal of General Internal Medicine 1998;13:1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1496888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9462488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Ahluwalia 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahluwalia JS, Okuyemi K, Nollen N, Choi WS, Kaur H, Pulvers K, et al. The effects of nicotine gum and counseling among African American light smokers: a 2 x 2 factorial design. Addiction 2006;101:883-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16696632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nollen NL, Mayo MS, Sanderson CL, Okuyemi KS, Choi WS, Kaur H, et al. Predictors of quitting among African American light smokers enrolled in a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Journal of General Internal Medicine 2006;21:590-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1924642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16808741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuyemi KS, Cox LS, Nollen NL, Snow TM, Kaur H, Choi W, et al. Baseline characteristics and recruitment strategies in a randomized clinical trial of African-American light smokers. American Journal of Health Promotion 2007;21:183-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17233236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Areechon 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Areechon W, Punnotok J. Smoking cessation through the use of nicotine chewing gum: a double-blind trial in Thailand. Clinical Therapeutics 1988;10:183-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3078903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Blondal 1989 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Blondal T. Controlled trial of nicotine polacrilex gum with supportive measures. Archives of Internal Medicine 1989;149:1818-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2669665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Blondal 1997 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Blondal T, Franzon M, Westin A. A double-blind randomized trial of nicotine nasal spray as an aid in smoking cessation. European Respiratory Journal 1997;10:1585-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9230252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blondal T, Olafsdottir I, Gunnarsdottir R, Franzon M, Westin A. Controlled trial of nicotine nasal spray as an aid to stopping smoking [abstract]. European Respiratory Journal 1993;6(Suppl 17):631S.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Bolin 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bolin LJ, Antonuccio DO, Follette WC, Krumpe P. Transdermal nicotine: the long and the short of it. Psychology of Addictive Behaviors 1999;13:152-6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Br Thor Soc 83 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Research Committee of the British Thoracic Society. Comparison of four methods of smoking withdrawal in patients with smoking related diseases. Report by a subcommittee of the Research Committee of the British Thoracic Society. British Medical Journal 1983;286(6365):595-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1546807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6402162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Buchkremer 88 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Buchkremer G, Bents H, Horstmann M, Opitz K, Tolle R. Combination of behavioral smoking cessation with transdermal nicotine substitution. Addictive Behaviors 1989;14:229-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2728961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchkremer G, Bents H, Minneker E, Opitz K. Long-term effects of a combination of transdermal nicotine administration with behavior therapy for smoking cessation [Langfristige Effekte einer Kombination von transdermaler Nikotinzufuhr mit Verhaltenstherapie zur Raucherentwohnung]. Nervenarzt 1988;59:488-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3050570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Bullen 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bullen C, Howe C, Lin RB, Grigg M, Laugesen M, McRobbie H, Glover M, et al. Pre-cessation nicotine replacement therapy: pragmatic randomized trial. Addiction 2010;105:1474-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20528810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Campbell 1987 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Campbell IA, Lyons E, Prescott R. Do nicotine chewing-gum and postal encouragement add to doctors' advice. Practitioner 1987;231:114-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3671317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Campbell 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Campbell IA, Prescott RJ, Tjeder-Burton SM. Smoking cessation in hospital patients given repeated advice plus nicotine or placebo chewing gum. Respiratory Medicine 1991;85:155-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1887134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Campbell 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Burton S, Campbell IA, Prescott RJ. Nicotine patches versus placebo in 235 hospital patients [abstract 191]. In: 8th World Conference on Tobacco or Health, Mar 30-Apr 3; Buenos Aires, Argentina. 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell IA, Prescott RJ, Tjeder-Burton SM. Transdermal nicotine plus support in patients attending hospital with smoking-related diseases: a placebo-controlled study. Respiratory Medicine 1996;90:47-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8857326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Cinciripini 96 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Cinciripini PM, Cinciripini LG, Wallfisch A, Haque W. Behavior therapy and the transdermal nicotine patch: effects on cessation outcome, affect, and coping. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1996;64:314-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8871416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinciripini PM, Wetter DW, Fouladi RT, Blalock JA, Carter BL, Cinciripini LG, et al. The effects of depressed mood on smoking cessation: mediation by postcessation self-efficacy. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 2003;71:292-301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12699023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Clavel 1985 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Clavel F, Benhamou S, Company Huertas A, Flamant R. Helping people to stop smoking: randomised comparison of groups being treated with acupuncture and nicotine gum with control group. British Medical Journal 1985;291:1538-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1418170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3933739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clavel F, Benhamou S. Tobacco withdrawal. Comparison of the efficacy of various methods. Intermediate results of a comparative study [French] [D&#xe9;sintoxcation tabagique. Comparison de l'efficacit&#xe9; de differentes m&#xe9;thodes. R&#xe9;sultats interm&#xe9;diaires d'une &#xe9;tude comparative]. Presse M&#xe9;dicale 1984;13:975-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6232524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Clavel&#x2010;Cha '92 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Clavel-Chapelon F, Paoletti C, Benhamou S. A randomised 2 x 2 factorial design to evaluate different smoking cessation methods. Revue d'Epidemiologie et de Sante Publique 1992;40:187-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1439060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Croghan 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Croghan GA, Hurt RD, Croghan IT, Sloan J, Novotny P, Loprinzi C. Comparison of a 15 mg transdermal nicotine patch alone versus nicotine nasal spray alone versus both for smoking cessation. Journal of Addictive Diseases 1998;17:121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croghan GA, Sloan JA, Croghan IT, Novotny P, Hurt RD, DeKrey WL, et al. Comparison of nicotine patch alone versus nicotine nasal spray alone versus a combination for treating smokers: a minimal intervention, randomized multicenter trial in a nonspecialized setting. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2003;5(2):181-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12745490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Croghan 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Croghan IT, Hurt RD, Dakhil SR, Croghan GA, Sloan JA, Novotny PJ, et al. Randomized comparison of a nicotine inhaler and bupropion for smoking cessation and relapse prevention. Mayo Clinic.Proceedings 2007;82:186-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17290726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Daughton 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Daughton DM, Heatley SA, Prendergast JJ, Causey D, Knowles M, Rolf CN, et al. Effect of transdermal nicotine delivery as an adjunct to low-intervention smoking cessation therapy. A randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind study. Archives of Internal Medicine 1991;151:749-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2012458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daughton DM, Heatley SA, Prendergast JJ, Causey D, Knowles M, Rolf CN, et al. Effects of transdermal nicotine as an adjunct in smoking cessation therapy. A double-blind randomized study controlled with placebo [Italian] [Effetti del rilascio transdermico di nicotina come terapia di supporto per lo svezzamento dal fumo di sigaretta. Uno studio randomizzato in doppio cieco con controlli trattati con placebo.]. Archivio Monaldi 1992;47:17-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1306633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Daughton 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Daughton D, Susman J, Sitorius M, Belenky S, Millatmal T, Nowak R, et al. Transdermal nicotine therapy and primary care. Importance of counseling, demographic, and participant selection factors on 1-year quit rates. The Nebraska Primary Practice Smoking Cessation Trial Group. Archives of Family Medicine 1998;7:425-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9755734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Dautzenberg 01 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Dautzenberg B, Peiffer G, Toulouse F, Yvinec MJ, Jacob N, Kienzler JL. Randomized trial assessment of nicotinell lozenge 1mg, a new oral nicotine replacement therapy. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 3rd European Conference, Paris. 2001:55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dautzenberg B, Ruff F, Vaucher M, Maillon P, Jacob N, Kienzler JL, et al. First demonstration of the good efficacy/safety ratio of Nicotinell(r) 1mg Lozenge (NL 1mg), a new form of nicotine substitution, by randomised clinical trial. European Respiratory Journal 2001;18(Suppl 33):12s.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Davidson 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Davidson M, Epstein M, Burt R, Schaefer C, Whitworth G, McDonald A. Efficacy and safety of an over-the-counter transdermal nicotine patch as an aid for smoking cessation. Archives of Family Medicine 1998;7:569-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9821833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Etter 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Etter JF, Huguelet P, Perneger TV, Cornuz, J. Nicotine gum treatment before smoking cessation: a randomized trial. Archives of Internal Medicine 2009;169:1028-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19506172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Fagerstr&#xf6;m 1982 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fagerstr&#xf6;m KO. A comparison of psychological and pharmacological treatment in smoking cessation. Journal of Behavioral Medicine 1982;5:343-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7131548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagerstr&#xf6;m KO. Tolerance, withdrawal and dependence on tobacco and smoking termination. International Review of Applied Psychology 1983;32:29-52.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Fagerstr&#xf6;m 1984 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fagerstr&#xf6;m KO. Effects of nicotine chewing gum and follow-up appointments in physician-based smoking cessation. Preventive Medicine 1984;13:517-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6396639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Fee 1982 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fee WM, Stewart MJ. A controlled trial of nicotine chewing gum in a smoking withdrawal clinic. Practitioner 1982;226:148-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7043437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Fortmann 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fortmann SP, Killen JD. Nicotine gum and self-help behavioral treatment for smoking relapse prevention - resuIts from a trial using population-based recruitment. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1995;63:460-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7608359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Garcia 1989 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Quilez Garcia C, Hernando Arizaleta L, Rubio Diaz A, Estruch Riba J, Fornes Ramis MV. Treatment for smoking with nicotine gum in primary care. A double blind trial [Tratamiento del tabaquismo, con chicle de nicotina, en atencion primaria. Estudio a doble ciego]. Revista Clinica Espa&#xf1;ol 1993;192(4):157-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8480058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quilez Garcia C, Hernando Arizaleta L, Rubio Diaz A, Granero Fernandez EJ, Vila Coll MA, Estruch Riba JS. Double-blind study of the efficacy of nicotine chewing gum for smoking cessation in the primary care setting [Estudio doble ciego de la eficacia del chicle de nicotina en la deshabituacion tabaquica dentro del ambito de la atencion primaria]. Atencion Primaria 1989;6:719-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2518898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Gilbert 1989 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Gilbert JR, Wilson DM, Best JA, Taylor DW, Lindsay EA, Singer J, et al. Smoking cessation in primary care. A randomized controlled trial of nicotine-bearing chewing gum. Journal of Family Practice 1989;28:49-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2643672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Glavas 2003a {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Glavas D, Rumboldt M, Rumboldt Z. Smoking cessation with nicotine replacement therapy among health care workers: randomized double-blind study. Croatian Medical Journal 2003;44:219-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12698515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Glavas 2003b {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Glavas D, Rumboldt Z. Smoking cessation using the transdermal nicotine system [Odvikavanje od pusenja transdermalnim nikotinskim sustavom]. Lijecnicki Vjesnik 2003;125(1-2):8-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12812018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Glover 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Glover E, Glover P, Franzon M, Sullivan R, Cerullo C. Safety and efficacy of a nicotine sublingual tablet for smoking cessation [abstract]. In: Smoke Free 21st Century, 2nd European Conference on Tobacco or Health; Las Palmas de Gran Canaria. 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glover ED, Franzon M, Sullivan CR, Cerullo CL. A nicotine sublingual tablet for treating tobacco dependence [Abstract]. In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 3rd Europe Conference, Paris September 2001. 2001:48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glover ED, Glover PN, Franzon M, Sullivan CR, Cerullo CC, Howell RM, et al. A comparison of a nicotine sublingual tablet and placebo for smoking cessation. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2002;4:441-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12521403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glover ED, Glover PN, Franzon M, Sullivan R, Sullivan P, Howell R, et al. A nicotine sublingual tablet for smoking cessation: 6-month data [Abstract]. In: Proceedings of the 10th World Conference on Tobacco or Health; Aug 24-28 Beijing, China. 1997.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Goldstein 1989 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Goldstein MG, Niaura R, Follick MJ, Abrams DB. Effects of behavioral skills training and schedule of nicotine gum administration on smoking cessation. American Journal of Psychiatry 1989;146:56-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2643357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hall 1985 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Tunstall C, Rugg D, Jones R, Benowitz N. Nicotine gum and behavioral treatment in smoking cessation. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1985;53:256-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3998252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hall 1987 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Tunstall CD, Ginsberg D, Benowitz NL, Jones RT. Nicotine gum and behavioral treatment: a placebo controlled trial. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1987;55:603-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3624619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hall 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, Reus VI, Sees KL, Duncan C, Humfleet GL, et al. Mood management and nicotine gum in smoking treatment - a therapeutic contact and placebo-controlled study. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1996;64:1003-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8916629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hand 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hand S, Edwards S, Campbell IA, Cannings R. Controlled trial of three weeks nicotine replacement treatment in hospital patients also given advice and support. Thorax 2002;57:715-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Harackiewicz 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Harackiewicz JM, Blair LW, Sansone C, Epstein JA, Stuchell RN. Nicotine gum and self-help manuals in smoking cessation: an evaluation in a medical context. Addictive Behaviors 1988;13:319-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3239463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hatsukami 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hatsukami D, Mooney M, Murphy S, LeSage M, Babb D, Hecht S. Effects of high dose transdermal nicotine replacement in cigarette smokers. Pharmacology, Biochemistry and Behavior 2007;86:132-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2063438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17267026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hays 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hays JT, Croghan GA, Offord KP, Hurt RD, Schroeder DR, Wolter TD, et al. Over-the-counter nicotine patch therapy for smoking cessation: Results from randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled and open label trials. American Journal of Public Health 1999;89:1701-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1508975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10553392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hays JT, Croghan GA, Offord KP, Wolter TD, Nides MA, Davidson M. Over-the-Counter (OTC) transdermal nicotine patch therapy [abstract]. Journal of Addictive Diseases 1997;16:136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hays JT, Croghan IT, Offord KP, Hurt RD, Schroeder DR, Wolter TD, et al. Over the counter 22mg nicotine patch therapy for smoking cessation: results from randomized double-blind placebo-controlled and open label trials. Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 5th Annual Meeting, San Diego (CA) 1999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1508975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10553392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Herrera 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Herrera N, Franco R, Herrera L, Partidas A, Rolando R, Fagerstr&#xf6;m KO. Nicotine gum, 2 and 4 mg, for nicotine dependence. A double-blind placebo-controlled trial within a behavior modification support program. Chest 1995;108:447-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7634882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hilleman 1994 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hilleman DE, Mohiuddin SM, Delcore MG. Comparison of fixed-dose transdermal nicotine, tapered-dose transdermal nicotine, and buspirone in smoking cessation. Journal of Clinical Pharmacology 1994;34(3):222-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8021329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Huber 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Huber D. Combined and separate treatment effects of nicotine chewing gum and self-control method. Pharmacopsychiatry 1988;21:461-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3244795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hughes 1989 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Gust SW, Keenan RM, Fenwick JW, Healey ML. Nicotine vs placebo gum in general medical practice. JAMA 1989;261:1300-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2644465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hughes 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Gust SW, Keenan RM, Fenwick JW. Effect of dose on nicotine's reinforcing, withdrawal-suppression and self-reported effects. Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics 1990;252:1175-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2319467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hughes 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Wadland WC, Fenwick JW, Lewis J, Bickel WK. Effect of cost on the self-administration and efficacy of nicotine gum: a preliminary study. Preventive Medicine 1991;20:486-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1908080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hughes 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Lesmes GR, Hatsukami DK, Richmond RL, Lichtenstein E, Jorenby DE, et al. Are higher doses of nicotine replacement more effective for smoking cessation? Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 1999;1:169-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hughes 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Novy P, Hatsukami DK, Jensen J, Callas PW. Efficacy of nicotine patch in smokers with a history of alcoholism. Alcoholism, Clinical and Experimental Research 2003;27:946-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12824815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hurt 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hurt RD, Lauger GG, Offord KP, Kottke TE, Dale LC. Nicotine-replacement therapy with use of a transdermal nicotine patch-a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial. Mayo Clinic Proceedings 1990;65:1529-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2255215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Hurt 1994 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hurt RD, Dale LC, Fredrickson PA, Caldwell CC, Lee GA, Offord KP, et al. Nicotine patch therapy for smoking cessation combined with physician advice and nurse follow-up: One-year outcome and percentage of nicotine replacement. JAMA 1994;271:595-600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8301791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT ICRF 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>David SP, Munaf&#xf2; MR, Murphy MF, Walton RT, Johnstone EC. The serotonin transporter 5-HTTLPR polymorphism and treatment response to nicotine patch: follow-up of a randomized controlled trial. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2007;9(2):225-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2031912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17365753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imperial Cancer Research Fund General Practice Research Group. Effectiveness of a nicotine patch in helping people stop smoking: results of a randomised trial in general practice. BMJ 1993;306:1304-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1677770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8518571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imperial Cancer Research Fund General Practice Research Group. Randomised trial of nicotine patches in general practice: results at one year. BMJ 1994;308:1476-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2540289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8019282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnstone EC, Yudkin Pl, Hey K, Roberts SJ, Welch SJ, Murphy MF, et al. Genetic variation in dopaminergic pathways and short-term effectiveness of the nicotine patch. Pharmacogenetics 2004;14(2):83-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yudkin P, Hey K, Roberts S, Welch S, Murphy M, Walton R. Abstinence from smoking eight years after participation in randomised controlled trial of nicotine patch. BMJ 2003;327(7405):28-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12842953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yudkin P, Munaf&#xf2; M, Hey K, Roberts S, Welch S, Johnstone E, et al. Effectiveness of nicotine patches in relation to genotype in women versus men: randomised controlled trial. BMJ 2004;328(7446):989-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC404497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Jamrozik 1984 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jamrozik K, Fowler G, Vessey M, Wald N. Placebo controlled trial of nicotine chewing gum in general practice. British Medical Journal 1984;289:794-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1442980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6434084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Jarvis 1982 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jarvis MJ, Raw M, Russell MA, Feyerabend C. Randomised controlled trial of nicotine chewing-gum. British Medical Journal 1982;285:537-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1499070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6809161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Jensen 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jensen EJ, Schmidt E, Pedersen B, Dahl R. Effect of nicotine, silver acetate, and ordinary chewing gum in combination with group counselling on smoking cessation. Thorax 1990;45:831-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC462778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2256009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen EJ, Schmidt E, Pedersen B, Dahl R. Effect on smoking cessation of silver acetate, nicotine and ordinary chewing gum. Influence of smoking history. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1991;104:470-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1780416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen EJ, Schmidt E, Pedersen B, Dahl R. The effect of nicotine, silver acetate, and placebo chewing gum on the cessation of smoking. The influence of smoking type and nicotine dependence. International Journal of the Addictions 1991;26:1223-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1743819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Jorenby 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jorenby DE, Smith SS, Fiore MC, Hurt RD, Offord KP, Crogham IT, et al. Varying nicotine patch dose and type of smoking cessation counseling. JAMA 1995;274:1347-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7563558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Jorenby 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Durcan MJ, White J, Jorenby DE, Fiore MC, Rennard SI, Leischow SJ, et al. Impact of prior nicotine replacement therapy on smoking cessation efficacy. American Journal of Health Behaviors 2002;26:213-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12018757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamerson BD, Nides M, Jorenby DE, Donahue R, Garrett P, Johnston JA, et al. Late-term smoking cessation despite initial failure: an evaluation of bupropion sustained release, nicotine patch, combination therapy, and placebo. Clinical Therapeutics 2001;23:744-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11394732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorenby DE, Leischow SJ, Nides MA, Rennard SI, Johnston JA, Hughes AR, et al. A controlled trial of sustained-release bupropion, a nicotine patch, or both for smoking cessation. New England Journal of Medicine 1999;340:685-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10053177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Joseph 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Joseph AM, Antonnucio DO. Lack of efficacy of transdermal nicotine in smoking cessation. New England Journal of Medicine 1999;341:1157-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10515763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph AM, Norman SM, Ferry LH, Prochazka AV, Westman EC, Steele BG, et al. The safety of transdermal nicotine as an aid to smoking cessation in patients with cardiac disease. New England Journal of Medicine 1996;335:1792-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8943160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Kalman 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kalman D, Denison H, Penk W, Peer J, Kresman D, Monti P. Early findings from a treatment study of heavy smokers in alcohol recovery (PO2 34). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 7th Annual Meeting March 23-23 Seattle, Washington. 2001:61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalman D, Kahler CW, Garvey AJ, Monti PM. High-dose nicotine patch therapy for smokers with a history of alcohol dependence: 36-week outcomes. Journal of Substance Abuse Treatment 2006;30:213-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16616165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalman D, Kahler CW, Tirch D, Kaschub C, Penk W, Monti PM. Twelve-week outcomes from an investigation of high-dose nicotine patch therapy for heavy smokers with a past history of alcohol dependence. Psychology of Addictive Behaviors 2004;18:78-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15008689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalman D, Tirch D, Penk W, Denison H. An investigation of predictors of nicotine abstinence in a smoking cessation treatment study of smokers with a past history of alcohol dependence. Psychology of Addictive Behaviors 2002;16:346-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12503909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalman D, Tirch D, Penk W, Kaschub C. Preliminary findings from a treatment study of heavy smokers in alcohol recovery: end of treatment outcomes (PO2 38). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 8th Annual Meeting February 20-23 Savannah, Georgia. 2002:58.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Killen 1984 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Maccoby N, Taylor CB. Nicotine gum and self-regulation training in smoking relapse prevention. Behavior Therapy 1984;15:234-48.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Killen 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fortmann SP, Killen JD, Telch MJ, Newman B. Minimal contact treatment for smoking cessation. A placebo controlled trial of nicotine polacrilex and self-directed relapse prevention: initial results of the Stanford Stop Smoking Project. JAMA 1988;260:1575-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3045351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Newman B, Varady A. Evaluation of a treatment approach combining nicotine gum with self-guided behavioral treatments for smoking relapse prevention. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1990;58:85-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2319049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Killen 1997 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Davis L, Varady A. Nicotine patch and self-help video for cigarette smoking cessation. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1997;65:663-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9256568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Killen 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Davis L, Strausberg L, Varady A. Do heavy smokers benefit from higher dose nicotine patch therapy? Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology 1999;7:226-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10472510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Kornitzer 1987 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kornitzer M, Kittel F, Dramaix M, Bourdoux P. A double blind study of 2 mg versus 4 mg nicotine-gum in an industrial setting. Journal of Psychosomatic Research 1987;31:171-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3295212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Kornitzer 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kornitzer M, Boutsen M, Dramaix M, Thijs J, Gustavsson G. Combined use of nicotine patch and gum in smoking cessation: a placebo-controlled clinical trial. Preventive Medicine 1995;24:41-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7740014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornitzer M, Boutsen M, Thijs J, Gustavsson G. Efficiency and safety of combined use of nicotine patches and nicotine gum in smoking cessation: a placebo controlled double-blind trial [abstract]. European Respiratory Journal 1993;6(Suppl 17):630S.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Kralikova 2002 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kralikova E, Kozak J, Rasmussen T, Cort N. The clinical benefits of NRT-supported smoking reduction. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2002;4:243.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Kralikova 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kralikova E, Kozak JT, Rasmussen T, Gustavsson G, Le Houezec, J. Smoking cessation or reduction with nicotine replacement therapy: a placebo-controlled double blind trial with nicotine gum and inhaler. BMC.Public Health 2009;9:433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2792228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19943947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Leischow 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Leischow SJ, Nilsson F, Franzon M, Hill A, Otte P, Merikle EP. Efficacy of the nicotine inhaler as an adjunct to smoking cessation. American Journal of Health Behavior 1996;20:364-71.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Leischow 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Leischow SJ, Muramoto ML, Cook GN, Merikle EP, Castellini SM, Otte PS. OTC nicotine patch: effectiveness alone and with brief physician intervention. American Journal of Health Behavior 1999;23:61-9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Leischow 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Leischow SJ, Ranger-Moore J, Muramoto ML, Matthews E. Effectiveness of the nicotine inhaler for smoking cessation in an OTC setting. American Journal of Health Behavior 2004;28:291-301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15228966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leischow SJ, Ranger-Moore J, Muramoto ML, Matthews E. The safety and effectiveness of the nicotine inhaler for smoking cessation in an over-the-counter setting (POS4-78). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 9th Annual Meeting, New Orleans, LA. 2003:100.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Lewis 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Lewis SF, Piasecki TM, Fiore MC, Anderson JE, Baker TB. Transdermal nicotine replacement for hospitalized patients: a randomized clinical trial. Preventive Medicine 1998;27(2):296-303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9579010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Llivina 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Salvador Llivina T, Marin Tuya D, Gonzalez Quintana J, Iniesta Torres C, Castellvi Barrera E, Muriana Saez C, et al. Treatment of smoking: efficacy of the use of nicotine chewing gum. Double-blind study [Tratamiento del tabaquismo: eficacia de la utilizacion del chicle de nicotina. Estudio a doble ciego]. Medicina Clinica Barcelona 1988;90:646-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3398640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Malcolm 1980 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Malcolm RE, Sillett RW, Turner JA, Ball KP. The use of nicotine chewing gum as an aid to stopping smoking. Psychopharmacology Series 1980;70:295-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6777804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Marshall 1985 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Marshall A, Raw M. Nicotine chewing gum in general practice: effect of follow up appointments. British Medical Journal 1985;290:1397-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1415622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3922510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT McGovern 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>McGovern PG, Lando HA. An assessment of nicotine gum as an adjunct to Freedom from Smoking cessation clinics. Addictive Behaviors 1992;17:137-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1585841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Molyneux 2003 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Molyneux A, Lewis S, Leivers U, Anderton A, Antoniak M, Brackenridge A, et al. Clinical trial comparing nicotine replacement therapy (NRT) plus brief counselling, brief counselling alone, and minimal intervention on smoking cessation in hospital inpatients. Thorax 2003;58(6):484-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12775857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Moolchan 2005 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Franken FH, Pickworth WB, Epstein DH, Moolchan ET. Smoking rates and topography predict adolescent smoking cessation following treatment with nicotine replacement therapy. Cancer Epidemiology, Biomarkers &amp; Prevention 2006;15:154-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16434603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moolchan ET, Robinson ML, Ernst M, Cadet JL, Pickworth WB, Heishman SJ, et al. Safety and efficacy of the nicotine patch and gum for the treatment of adolescent tobacco addiction. Pediatrics 2005;115(4):e407-e414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15805342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson ML, Schroeder JR, Moolchan ET. Adolescent smokers screened for a nicotine replacement treatment trial: Correlates of eligibility and enrollment. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2006;8:447-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16801302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Mori 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Mori T, Shimao T, Yulchiro G, Namiki M, Hyachi T. A clinical trial of nicotine chewing gum for smoking cessation [abstract 428]. 8th World Conference on Tobacco or Health; Buenos Aires, Argentina 1992.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT M&#xfc;ller 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller P, Abelin T, Eshram R, Imhof P, Howald H, Mauli D. The use of transdermal nicotine in smoking cessation. Lung 1990;168:445-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2117147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Nakamura 1990 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Saito J, Oshima A, Miyamoto M, Matushita A, Endo S. Effect of nicotine chewing gun in smoking cessation classes. In: Durston B, Jamrozik K , editors(s). The Global War. Proceedings of the 7th World Conference on Tobacco and Health; Perth, Western Australia. Perth: Health Department of Western Australia, 1990:665-7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Nebot 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Nebot M, Cabezas C. Does nurse counseling or offer of nicotine gum improve the effectiveness of physician smoking-cessation advice? Family Practice Research Journal 1992;12:263-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1414430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Niaura 1994 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Niaura R, Goldstein MG, Abrams DB. Matching high and low-dependence smokers to self-help treatment with or without nicotine replacement. Preventive Medicine 1994;23:70-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8016036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Niaura 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Niaura R, Abrams DB, Shadel WG, Rohsenow DJ, Monti PM, Sirota AD. Cue exposure treatment for smoking relapse prevention: a controlled clinical trial. Addiction 1999;94(5):685-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10563033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Ockene 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ockene JK, Kristeller J, Goldberg R, Amick TL, Pekow PS, Hosmer D, et al. Increasing the efficacy of physician-delivered smoking interventions: a randomized clinical trial. Journal of General Internal Medicine 1991;6:1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1999742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ockene JK, Kristeller J, Pbert L, Hebert JR, Luippold R, Goldberg RJ, et al. The physician-delivered smoking intervention project: can short-term interventions produce long-term effects for a general outpatient population? Health Psychology 1994;13:278-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8055863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Oncken 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Allen AM, Kleppinger A, Lando H, Oncken C. Effect of nicotine patch on energy intake and weight gain in postmenopausal women during smoking cessation. Eating Behaviors 2013;14(4):420-3. [CENTRAL: 918119] [EMBASE: 2013512499] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3817500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24183127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleppinger A, Litt MD, Kenny AM, Oncken CA. Effects of smoking cessation on body composition in postmenopausal women. Journal of Women's Health 2010;19(9):1651-7. [CENTRAL: 793327] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20718625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oncken C, Cooney J, Feinn R, Lando H, Kranzler HR. Transdermal nicotine for smoking cessation in postmenopausal women. Addictive Behaviors 2007;32:296-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16765526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oncken C, Cooney J, Lando H, Feinn R, Kranzler H. Transdermal nicotine for smoking cessation in postmenopausal women (POS1-045). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 11th Annual Meeting, Prague. 2005.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Otero 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Otero UB, Perez CA, Szklo M, Esteves GA, dePinho MM, Szklo AS, et al. Randomized clinical trial: effectiveness of the cognitive-behavioral approach and the use of nicotine replacement transdermal patches for smoking cessation among adults in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil [Ensaio clinico randomizado: efetividade da abordagem cognitivo-comportamental e uso de adesivos transdermicos de reposicao de nicotina, na cessacao de fumar, em adultos residentes no Municipio do Rio de Janeiro, Brasil]. Cadernos de Saude Publica 2006;22:439-49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16501756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Page 1986 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Page AR, Walters DJ, Schlegel RP, Best JA. Smoking cessation in family practice: the effects of advice and nicotine chewing gum prescription. Addictive Behaviors 1986;11:443-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3812055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Paoletti 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Paoletti P, Fornai E, Maggiorelli F, Puntoni R, Viegi G, Carrozzi L, et al. Importance of baseline cotinine plasma values in smoking cessation: results from a double blind study with nicotine patch. European Respiratory Journal 1996;9:643-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8726925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Peng 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Peng RL, Wang SL. Nicotine sublingual tablet for smoking cessation in 115 cases: A double-blind randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial. Journal of Clinical Rehabilitative Tissue Engineering Research 2007;52:10443-6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Perng 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Perng RP, Hsieh WC, Chen YM, Lu CC, Chiang SJ. Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of transdermal nicotine patch for smoking cessation. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine 1999;159(3SS):A735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9747065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perng RP, Hsieh WC, Chen YM, Lu CC, Chiang SJ. Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of transdermal nicotine patch for smoking cessation. Journal of the Formosan Medical Association 1998;97:547-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9747065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Piper 2007 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federman EB, Bolt DM, Smith SS, Fiore MC, Baker TB. Mediators of bupropion treatment effects (PA5-6). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 12th Annual Meeting, Orlando, FL. 2006:27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federman EB, McCarthy DE, Bolt DM, Smith SS, Fiore MC, et al. Efficacy of bupropion alone and in combination with nicotine gum. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2007;9:947-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3030120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17763111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piper ME, Federman EB, Smith SS, Fiore MC, Baker TB. Efficacy of bupropion SR alone and combined with 4-mg gum (PA2-2). In: Society for Research on Nicotine and Tobacco 10th Annual Meeting, Phoenix, AZ. 2004:18.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Puska 1979 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Puska P, Bjorkqvist S, Koskela K. Nicotine-containing chewing gum in smoking cessation: a double blind trial with half year follow-up. Addictive Behaviors 1979;4:141-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">382765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Richmond 1993 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Richmond R, Heather N. General Practitioner interventions for smoking cessation: past results and future prospects. Behaviour Change 1990;7:110-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond RL, Makinson RJ, Giugni AA, Webster IW. General Practitioner smoking interventions in Australia: results of studies over the past ten years. In: Durston B, Jamrozik K , editors(s). The Global War: 7th World Conference on Tobacco and Health. Perth, Western Australia. Perth: Health Department of Western Australia, 1990:657-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond RL, Makinson RJ, Kehoe LA, Giugni AA, Webster IW. One-year evaluation of three smoking cessation interventions administered by general practitioners. Addictive Behaviors 1993;18:187-99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8506790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Rose 1994 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Behm FM, Westman EC, Levin ED, Stein RM, Ripka GV. Mecamylamine combined with nicotine skin patch facilitates smoking cessation beyond nicotine patch treatment alone. Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics 1994;56:86-99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8033499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Westman EC, Behm FM. Nicotine/mecamylamine combination treatment for smoking cessation [published erratum appears in Drug Development Research 1997;40:215]. Drug Development Research 1996;38:243-256.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Rose 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Behm FM, Westman EC. Nicotine-mecamylamine treatment for smoking cessation: the role of pre-cessation therapy. Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology 1998;6:331-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9725117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Westman EC, Behm FM. Nicotine/mecamylamine combination treatment for smoking cessation [published erratum appears in Drug Development Research 1997;40:215]. Drug Development Research 1996;38:243-56.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Rose 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Behm FM, Westman EC, Kukovich P. Precessation treatment with nicotine skin patch facilitates smoking cessation. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2006;8:89-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16497603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Rose 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Rose JE, Herskovic JE, Behm FM, Westman EC. Precessation treatment with nicotine patch significantly increases abstinence rates relative to conventional treatment. Nicotine.and Tobacco.Research 2009;11:1067-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19567826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Roto 1987 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Roto P, Ojala A, Sundman K, Jokinen K, Peltomakl R. Nicotine gum and withdrawal from smoking. Suomen Laakarllehtl 1987;36:3445-8.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Russell 1983 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Russell MA, Merriman R, Stapleton J, Taylor W. Effect of nicotine chewing gum as an adjunct to general practitioner's advice against smoking. British Medical Journal (Clinical Research Ed.) 1983;287:1782-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1549849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6416593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Schneider 1985A {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jarvik ME, Schneider NG. Degree of addiction and effectiveness of nicotine gum therapy for smoking. American Journal of Psychiatry 1984;141:790-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6375399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider NG, Jarvik ME, Forsythe AB, Read LL, Elliott ML, Schweiger A. Nicotine gum in smoking cessation: a placebo-controlled, double-blind trial. Addictive Behaviors 1983;8:253-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6666689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider NG, Jarvik ME. Nicotine gum vs. placebo gum: comparisons of withdrawal symptoms and success rates. NIDA Research Monograph 1985;53:83-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3934548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Schneider 1985B {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Schneider NG, Jarvik ME, Forsythe AB, Read LL, Elliott ML, Schweiger A. Nicotine gum in smoking cessation: a placebo-controlled, double-blind trial. Addictive Behaviors 1983;8:253-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6666689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider NG, Jarvik ME. Nicotine gum vs. placebo gum: comparisons of withdrawal symptoms and success rates. NIDA Research Monograph 1985;53:83-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3934548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Schneider 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Schneider NG, Olmstead R, Mody FV, Doan K, Franzon M, Jarvik ME, et al. Efficacy of a nicotine nasal spray in smoking cessation: a placebo-controlled, double-blind trial. Addiction 1995;90:1671-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8555958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Schneider 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Schneider NG, Olmstead R, Nilsson F, Mody FV, Franzon M, Doan K. Efficacy of a nicotine inhaler in smoking cessation: a double-blind, placebo controlled trial. Addiction 1996;91:1293-306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8854366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider NG, Olmstead R, Nilsson F, Mody FV, Franzon M, Doan K. Efficacy of a nicotine inhaler in smoking cessation: a double-blind, placebo-controlled trial [abstract]. Addiction 1997;92:630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8854366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Schnoll 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Schnoll RA, Martinez E, Tatum KL, Glass M, Bernath A, Ferris D, et al. Nicotine patch vs. nicotine lozenge for smoking cessation: an effectiveness trial coordinated by the Community Clinical Oncology Program. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2010;107:237-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2834192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20004065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnoll RA, Patterson F, Wileyto EP, Heitjan DF, Shields AE, Asch DA, et al. Effectiveness of extended-duration transdermal nicotine therapy: a randomized trial. Annals.of Internal.Medicine 2010;152:144-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3782858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20124230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnoll RA, Wileyto EP, Lerman C. Extended duration therapy with transdermal nicotine may attenuate weight gain following smoking cessation. Addictive Behaviors 2012;37(4):565-8. [CENTRAL: 814662] [EMBASE: 2012097635] [PMID: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3288882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22244706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Schuurmans 04 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Schuurmans MM, Diacon AH, Van Biljon X, Bolliger CT. Effect of pre-treatment with nicotine patch on withdrawal symptoms and abstinence rates in smokers subsequently quitting with the nicotine patch: a randomized controlled trial. Addiction 2004;99:634-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15078238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuurmans MM, Diacon AH, Van Biljon X, Westin A, Landfeldt B, Bolliger CT. Effect of pre-treatment with nicotine patch on withdrawal symptoms in smokers subsequently quitting with the nicotine patch: a double-blind randomised controlled trial (www.ersnetsecure.org/public/prg_congres.abstract?ww_i_presentation=6711). In: European Respiratory Society Annual Congress, Stockholm. 2002.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Segnan 1991 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Segnan N, Ponti A, Battista RN, Senore C, Rosso S, Shapiro SH, et al. A randomized trial of smoking cessation interventions in general practice in Italy. Cancer Causes and Control 1991;2:239-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1873454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senore C, Battista RN, Ponti A, Segnan N, Shapiro SH, Rosso S, et al. Comparing participants and nonparticipants in a smoking cessation trial: selection factors associated with general practitioner recruitment activity. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 1999;52:83-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9973077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senore C, Battista RN, Shapiro SH, Segnan N, Ponti A, Rosso S, et al. Predictors of smoking cessation following physicians' counseling. Preventive Medicine 1998;27:412-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9612831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Shiffman 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Shiffman S, Ferguson SG, Strahs KR. Quitting by gradual smoking reduction using nicotine gum: a randomized controlled trial. American Journal of Preventive Medicine 2009;36:96-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19135903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Sonderskov 97 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Sonderskov J, Olsen J, Meillier L, Overvad OK, Sabroe S. The effect of transdermal nicotine patches in smoking cessation. A randomized trial in pharmacy customers in Denmark. Ugeskrift for Laeger 1999;161:593-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9989194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonderskov J, Olsen J, Sabroe S, Meillier L, Overvad K. Nicotine patches in smoking cessation: a randomized trial among over- the-counter customers in Denmark. American Journal of Epidemiology 1997;145:309-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9054234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Stapleton 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Stapleton JA, Sutherland G. Treating heavy smokers in primary care with the nicotine nasal spray: randomized placebo-controlled trial. Addiction 2011;106:824-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21205043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT T&#xf8;nnesen 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, Fryd V, Hansen M, Helsted J, Gunnersen AB, Forchammer H, et al. Effect of nicotine chewing gum in combination with group counseling on the cessation of smoking. New England Journal of Medicine 1988;318:15-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3336380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT T&#xf8;nnesen 2000 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, Mikkelsen KL. Smoking cessation with four nicotine replacement regimes in a lung clinic. European Respiratory Journal 2000;16:717-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11106218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT T&#xf8;nnesen 2006 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Pbert L. Nurse-conducted smoking cessation in patients with COPD, using nicotine sublingual tablets and behavioral support. Chest 2006;130:314-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16899826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnesen P, Mikkelsen K, Bremann L. Nurse-conducted smoking cessation in patients with COPD using nicotine sublingual tablets and behavioral support. Chest 2006;130:334-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16899830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Veaugh&#x2010;Geiss 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Veaugh-Geiss AM, Chen LH, Kotler ML, Ramsay LR, Durcan MJ. Pharmacokinetic comparison of two nicotine transdermal systems, a 21-mg/24-hour patch and a 25-mg/16-hour patch: a randomized, open-label, single-dose, two-way crossover study in adult smokers. Clinical Therapeutics 2010;32:1140-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20637967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Villa 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Villa RS, Alvarez AB, Hermida JR. Effectiveness of a multicomponent program to quit smoking with and without nicotine chewing gum [Eficacia de un programa multicomponente para dejar de fumar con y sin chicle de nicotina]. Psicologia Conductual 1999;7:107-18.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Westman 1993 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Westman EC, Levin ED, Rose JE. The nicotine patch in smoking cessation. A randomized trial with telephone counseling. Archives of Internal Medicine 1993;153:1917-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8250653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Wisborg 2000 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Wisborg K, Henriksen TB, Jespersen LB, Secher NJ. Nicotine patches for pregnant smokers: a randomized controlled study. Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology 2000;96(6):967-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11084187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Wong 1999 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Wong GY, Wolter TD, Croghan GA, Croghan IT, Offord KP, Hurt RD. A randomized trial of naltrexone for smoking cessation. Addiction 1999;94:1227-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10615738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NRT Zelman 1992 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Zelman DC, Brandon TH, Jorenby DE, Baker TB. Measures of affect and nicotine dependence predict differential response to smoking cessation treatments. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1992;60:943-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1460156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Prapavessis 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Prapavessis H, De Jesus S, Fitzgeorge L, Faulkner G, Maddison R, Batten S. Exercise to enhance smoking cessation: the Getting Physical on Cigarette randomized control trial. Annals of Behavioral Medicine 2016;50(3):358-69. [DOI: 10.1007/s12160-015-9761-9]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12160-015-9761-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Urdapilleta&#x2010;Herrera 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Urdapilleta-Herrera E, Pi&#xf1;a-Rosales MF, Vargas-Rojas, MI, Ram&#xed;rez-Venegas A, Sansores-Mart&#xed;nez R. Bupropion together with cognitive-conductual therapy (CBT) is an alternative for a long-term abstinence of smoking. In: European Respiratory Society Annual Congress; 2013 09 07-11; Barcelona. 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 VA Carson 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Carson KV, Brinn MP, Smith BJ, Garside CG, Goldsworthy SJ, Fitridge RA, Esterman, et al. Varenicline tartrate and counselling versus counselling alone in a randomised controlled trial for inpatient smoking cessation: 3 month interim results [abstract]. Respirology 2010;15:p. A30.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 VA Hajek 2011 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Hajek P, McRobbie HJ, Myers KE, Stapleton J, Dhanji AR. Use of varenicline for 4 weeks before quitting smoking: decrease in ad lib smoking and increase in smoking cessation rates. Archives.of Internal.Medicine 2011;171:770-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21518946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 VA Tsukahara 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Tsukahara H, Noda K, Saku K. A randomized controlled open comparative trial of varenicline vs nicotine patch in adult smokers: efficacy, safety and withdrawal symptoms (the VN-SEESAW study). Circulation 2010;74:771-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20154405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 VA Williams 2007 {published and unpublished data}</Title><Reference><Citation>Reeves K, Watsky E, Williams K, Azoulay S, Billing B, Gong J. The safety of varenicline taken for 52 weeks for smoking cessation. In: [RPOS3-54]. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams KE, Reeves KR, Billing CB, Pennington AM, Gong J. A double-blind study evaluating the long-term safety of varenicline for smoking cessation. Current Medical Research and Opinion 2007;23(4):793-801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17407636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to ongoing studies</Title><ReferenceList><Title>1 Komiyama 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Komiyama M, Ozaki Y, Wada H, Yamakage H, Satoh-Asahara N, Morimoto T, et al. The effects of dietary instruction on cardiovascular risk markers after smoking cessation: study protocol for a multicenter randomized controlled trial in Japan. Trials 2018;19(1):538. [DOI: 10.1186/s13063-018-2919-6]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-018-2919-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6172844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT01892813 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT01892813. Dissemination of a tailored tobacco quitline for rural veteran smokers. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01892813 (first received 4 July 2013).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT02424188 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT02424188. Trial of integrated smoking cessation, exercise and weight management in serious mental illness: TRIUMPH. clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02424188 (first received 22 April 2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT02906787 2016 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT02906787. Behavioral activation for smoking cessation and the prevention of post-cessation weight gain. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02906787 (first received 20 September 2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT03204396 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT03204396. Smoking cessation facilitated by glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) analogues (SKIP). clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03204396 (first received 2 July 2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT03712098 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT03712098. Daily liraglutide for nicotine dependence. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03712098 (first received 19 October 2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT04130698 2019 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT04130698. Comparing two treatments that both target smoking cessation and weight loss at the same time. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04130698 (first received 17 October 2019).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 NCT04332029 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT04332029. Smoking cessation treatment for smokers with obesity. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04332029 (first received 2 April 2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 RBR&#x2010;682px9 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>RBR-682px9. Evaluation of the effect of dietary control in the treatment of female smokers. ensaiosclinicos.gov.br/rg/RBR-682px9 (first received 5 September 2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>1 Salgado Garcia 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Salgado Garc&#xed;a FI, Derefinko KJ, Bursac Z, Klesges RC, Ebbert JO, Womack CR, et al. Fit &amp; quit: an efficacy trial of two behavioral post-cessation weight gain interventions. Contemporary Clinical Trials 2019;76:31-40. [DOI: 10.1016/j.cct.2018.11.009]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2018.11.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6519455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30445176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Berlin 2019 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Berlin I, Dautzenberg B, Lehmann B, Palmyre J, Li&#xe9;gey E, De Rycke Y, et al. Randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind, double-dummy, multicentre trial comparing electronic cigarettes with nicotine to varenicline and to electronic cigarettes without nicotine: the ECSMOKE trial protocol. BMJ open 2019;9(5):e028832. [DOI: 10.1136/bmjopen-2018-028832]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-028832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6538086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31129603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Caponnetto 2019 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Caponnetto P, Maglia M, Polosa R. Efficacy of smoking cessation with varenicline plus counselling for e-cigarettes users (VAREVAPE): a protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Contemporary Clinical Trials communications 2019;15:100412. [DOI: 10.1016/j.conctc.2019.100412]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conctc.2019.100412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6667779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31388599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Cinciripini 2009 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Cinciripini PM. Combining varenicline and bupropion for smoking cessation. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/NCT00943618 (first received 22 July 2009).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Hebert&#x2010;Losier 2020 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;bert-Losier A, Filion KB, Windle SB, Eisenberg MJ. A randomized controlled trial evaluating the efficacy of e-cigarette use for smoking cessation in the general population: E3 Trial Design. CJC Open 2020;2(3):168&#x2013;75. [DOI: 10.1016/j.cjco.2020.03.006]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cjco.2020.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7242503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32462131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 ISRCTN34399445 2020 {published data only}ISRCTN34399445</Title><Reference><Citation>ISRCTN34399445. Smoking cessation support for people with severe mental illness in South Asia. isrctn.com/ISRCTN34399445 (first received 11 December 2019).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NCT02106637 2014 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT02106637. Early In-hospital Initiation of pharmacotherapy for smoking cessation, concomitant with nurse-led support, in patients after an acute coronary syndrome (ACS). clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02106637 (first received 8 April 2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NCT02162849 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT02162849. Reward sensitivity and pharmacotherapy for smoking cessation. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02162849 (first received 14 June 2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NCT03722966 2018 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT03722966. Effectiveness of combination varenicline and oral nicotine replacement therapy (COMBO). clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03722966 (first received 29 October 2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 NCT04088942 2019 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Saeed MI, Sivapalan P, Ekl&#xf6;f J, Ulrik CS, Pisinger C, Lapperre T, et al. TOB-STOP-COP (TOBacco STOP in COPd trial): study protocol-a randomized open-label, superiority, multicenter, two-arm intervention study of the effect of "high-intensity" vs. "low-intensity" smoking cessation intervention in active smokers with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Trials 2020;21(1):730. [DOI: 10.1186/s13063-020-04653-z]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-020-04653-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32825845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>2 Roelsgaard 2017 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Roelsgaard IK, Thomsen T, &#xd8;stergaard M, Christensen R, Hetland ML, Jacobsen S, et al. The effect of an intensive smoking cessation intervention on disease activity in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials 2017;18(1):570. [DOI: 10.1186/s13063-017-2309-5]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-017-2309-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5706378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29183347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Additional references</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Aubin, 2012</Title><Reference><Citation>Aubin HJ, Farley A, Lycett D, Lahmek P, Aveyard P. Weight gain in smokers after quitting cigarettes: meta-analysis. BMJ 2012;345:e4439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3393785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22782848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Audrain&#x2010;McGovern 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Audrain-McGovern J, Benowitz NL. Cigarette smoking, nicotine, and body weight. Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics 2011;90(1):164-8. [DOI: 10.1038/clpt.2011.105]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/clpt.2011.105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3195407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21633341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Boss&#xe9; 1980</Title><Reference><Citation>Boss&#xe9; R, Garvey AJ, Costa PT Jr. Predictors of weight change following smoking cessation. International Journal of the Addictions 1980;15(7):969-91. [DOI: 10.3109/10826088009040072]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10826088009040072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7450953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Cahill 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Cahill K, Lindson&#x2010;Hawley N, Thomas KH, Fanshawe TR, Lancaster T. Nicotine receptor partial agonists for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2016, Issue 5. Art. No: CD006103. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD006103.pub7]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006103.pub7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27158893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Cheskin 2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Cheskin LJ, Hess JM, Henningfield J, Gorelick DA. Calorie restriction increases cigarette use in adult smokers. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2005;179(2):430-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15565433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Chiolero 2008</Title><Reference><Citation>Chiolero A, Faeh D, Paccaud F, Cornuz J. Consequences of smoking for body weight, body fat distribution, and insulin resistance. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 2008;87(4):801-9. [DOI: 10.1093/ajcn/87.4.801]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/87.4.801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18400700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Clair 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Clair C, Rigotti NA, Porneala B, Fox CS, D'Agostino RB, Pencina MJ, et al. Association of smoking cessation and weight change with cardiovascular disease among adults with and without diabetes. JAMA 2013;309(10):1014-21. [DOI: 10.1001/jama.2013.1644]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.1644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3791107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23483176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Clark 2004</Title><Reference><Citation>Clark MM, Decker PA, Offord KP, Patten CA, Vickers KS, Croghan IT, et al. Weight concerns among male smokers. Addictive Behaviors 2004;29(8):1637-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15451131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Clark 2006</Title><Reference><Citation>Clark MM, Hurt RD, Croghan IT, Patten CA, Novotny P, Sloan JA, et al. The prevalence of weight concerns in a smoking abstinence clinical trial. Addictive Behaviors 2006;31(7):1142-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16137833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Collins 1994</Title><Reference><Citation>Collins LC, Cornelius MF, Vogel RL, Walker JF, Stamford BA. Effect of caffeine and/or cigarette smoking on resting energy expenditure. International Journal of Obesity and Related Metabolic Disorders 1994;18(8):551-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7951476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Dallosso 1984</Title><Reference><Citation>Dallosso HM, James WP. The role of smoking in the regulation of energy balance. International Journal of Obesity 1984;8(4):365-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6511171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Davey Smith 2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Davey Smith G, Bracha Y, Svendson KH, Neaton JD, Haffner SM, Kuller LH. Incidence of type II diabetes in the Randomized Multiple Risk Factor Intervention Trial. Annals of Internal Medicine 2005;142(5):313-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15738450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Fidler 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Fidler J, West R. Self-perceived smoking motives and their correlates in a general population sample. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2009;11(10):1182-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19640835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Filozof 2004</Title><Reference><Citation>Filozof C, Fernandez Pinilla MC, Fernandez-Cruz A. Smoking cessation and weight gain. Obesity Reviews 2004;5(2):95-103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15086863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Gratziou 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Gratziou C. Respiratory, cardiovascular and other physiological consequences of smoking cessation. Current Medical Research and Opinion 2009;25(2):535-45. [DOI: 10.1185/03007990802707642]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1185/03007990802707642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19193001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Gritz 1988</Title><Reference><Citation>Gritz ER, Carr CR, Marcus AC. Unaided smoking cessation: the Great American Smokeout and new year's day quitters. Journal of Psychosocial Oncology 1988;6:217-34.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hall 1986</Title><Reference><Citation>Hall SM, Ginsberg D, Jones RT. Smoking cessation and weight gain. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1986;45(3):342-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3722562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hartmann&#x2010;Boyce 2018</Title><Reference><Citation>Hartmann&#x2010;Boyce J, Chepkin SC, Ye W, Bullen C, Lancaster T. Nicotine replacement therapy for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 5. Art. No: CD000146. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD000146.pub5]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD000146.pub5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6353172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29852054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hartmann&#x2010;Boyce 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Hartmann-Boyce J, McRobbie H, Lindson N, Bullen C, Begh R, Theodoulou A, Notley C, Rigotti NA, Turner T, Butler AR, Hajek P. Electronic cigarettes for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2020, Issue 10. Art. No: CD010216. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD010216.pub4]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD010216.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v5.1/.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hofstetter 1986</Title><Reference><Citation>Hofstetter A, Schutz Y, J&#xe9;quier E, Wahren J. Increased 24-hour energy expenditure in cigarette smokers. New England Journal of Medicine 1986;314(2):79-82. [DOI: 10.1056/NEJM198601093140204]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198601093140204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3941694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Howes 2020</Title><Reference><Citation>Howes S, Hartmann-Boyce J, Livingstone-Banks J, Hong B, Lindson N. Antidepressants for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2020, Issue 4. Art. No: CD000031. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD000031.pub5]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD000031.pub5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32319681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hu 2018</Title><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Zong G, Liu G, Wang M, Rosner B, Pan A, et al. Smoking cessation, weight change, type 2 diabetes, and mortality. New England Journal of Medicine 2018;379(7):623-32. [DOI: 10.1056/NEJMoa1803626]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1803626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30110591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hughes 1991</Title><Reference><Citation>Hughes JR, Gust SW, Skoog K, Keenan RM, Fenwick JW. Symptoms of tobacco withdrawal: a replication and extension. Archives of General Psychiatry 1991;84(1):52-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1984762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hutter 2006</Title><Reference><Citation>Hutter HP, Moshammer H, Neuberger M. Smoking cessation at the workplace: 1 year success of short seminars. International Archives of Occupational and Environmental Health 2006;79(1):42-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16133522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Killen 1996</Title><Reference><Citation>Killen JD, Fortmann SP, Kraemer HC, Varady AN, Davis L, Newman B. Interactive effects of depression symptoms, nicotine dependence, and weight change on late smoking relapse. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1996;64(5):1060-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8916636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Kim 2018</Title><Reference><Citation>Kim K, Park SM, Lee K. Weight gain after smoking cessation does not modify its protective effect on myocardial infarction and stroke: evidence from a cohort study of men. European Heart Journal 2018;39(17):1523-31. [DOI: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehx761]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehx761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29324990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Kim 2019</Title><Reference><Citation>Kim K, Choi S, Lee G, Jeong SM, Kim SM, Son JS, et al. Cancer risk among young men with weight gain after smoking cessation: a population-based cohort study. Cancer Epidemiology 2019;60:86-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30933889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Klesges 1988</Title><Reference><Citation>Klesges RC, Brown K, Pascale RW, Murphy M, Williams E, Cigrang JA, et al. Factors associated with participation, attrition and outcome in a smoking cessation program at a workplace. Health Psychology 1988;7(6):575-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3215163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Klesges 1989</Title><Reference><Citation>Klesges RC, Meyers AW, Klesges LM, La Vasque M. Smoking, body weight and their effects on smoking behavior: a comprehensive review of the literature. Psychological Bulletin 1989;106(2):204-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2678202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Klesges 1992</Title><Reference><Citation>Klesges RC, Schumaker SA. Understanding the relations between smoking and body weight and their importance to smoking cessation and relapse. Health Psychology 1992;11(1):1-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1396497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Klesges 1997</Title><Reference><Citation>Klesges RC, Winders SE, Meyers AW, Eck LH, Ward KD, Hultquist CM, et al. How much weight gain occurs following smoking cessation? A comparison of weight gain using both continuous and point prevalence abstinence. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1997;65(2):286-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9086692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Komiyama 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Komiyama M, Wada H, Ura S, Yamakage H, Satoh-Asahara N, Shimatsu A, et al. Analysis of factors that determine weight gain during smoking cessation therapy. PLOS One 2013;8(8):e72010. [DOI: 10.1371/journal.pone.0072010]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0072010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3749100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Leeman 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Leeman RF, O'Malley SS, White MA, McKee SA. Nicotine and food deprivation decrease the ability to resist smoking. Psychopharmacology 2010;212(1):25-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3111597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20585761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Lindson 2019</Title><Reference><Citation>Lindson N, Chepkin SC, Ye W, Fanshawe TR, Bullen C, Hartmann-Boyce J. Different doses, durations and modes of delivery of nicotine replacement therapy for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2019, Issue 4. Art. No: CD013308. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD013308]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD013308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6470854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30997928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Luo 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Luo J, Rossouw J, Tong E, Giovino GA, Lee CC, Chen C, et al. Smoking and diabetes: does the increased risk ever go away? American Journal of Epidemiology 2013;178(6):937-45. [DOI: 10.1093/aje/kwt071]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwt071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3816526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23817918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>McEwen 2006</Title><Reference><Citation>McEwen A, Hajek P, McRobbie H, West R. Manual of Smoking Cessation. A Guide for Counsellors and Practitioners. Oxford (UK): Blackwell Publishing, 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Meyers 1997</Title><Reference><Citation>Meyers AW, Klesges RC, Winders SE, Ward KD, Peterson BA, Eck LH. Are weight concerns predictive of smoking cessation? A prospective analysis. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1997;65(3):448-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9170768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Michie 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Abraham C, Whittington C, McAteer J, Gupta S. Effective techniques in healthy eating and physical activity interventions: a meta-regression. Health Psychology 2009;28(6):690-701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19916637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mizes 1998</Title><Reference><Citation>Mizes JS, Sloan DM, Segraves K, Spring B, Pingitore R, Kristeller J. The influence of weight-related variables on smoking cessation. Behavior Therapy 1998;29(3):371-85.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>NHS 2021</Title><Reference><Citation>National Health Service (NHS). Stop smoking without putting on weight. www.nhs.uk/live-well/quit-smoking/stop-smoking-without-putting-on-weight/ (accessed 18 May 2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>O'Hara 1998</Title><Reference><Citation>O'Hara P, Connett JE, Lee WW, Nides M, Murray R, Wise R. Early and late weight gain following smoking cessation in the Lung Health Study. American Journal of Epidemiology 1998;148(9):821-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9801011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Parsons 2009a</Title><Reference><Citation>Parsons A, Ingram J, Inglis J, Aveyard P, Johnstone E, Brown K, et al. A proof of concept randomised placebo controlled factorial trial to examine the efficacy of St John's Wort for smoking cessation and chromium to prevent weight gain on smoking cessation. Drug and Alcohol Dependence 2009;102(1-3):116-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19328636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Parsons 2009b</Title><Reference><Citation>Parsons A, Lycett D, Aveyard P. Behavioural interventions to prevent weight gain on smoking cessation: a response. Addiction 2009;104(12):2119-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Parsons 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Parsons A, Lycett D, Aveyard P. Response to Spring et al: What is the best method to assess the effect of combined interventions for smoking cessation and post cessation weight gain? Addiction 2011;106:675-76.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Pomerleau 2001</Title><Reference><Citation>Pomerleau CS, Zucker AN, Stewart AJ. Characterizing concerns about post-cessation weight gain: results from a national survey of women smokers. Nicotine &amp; Tobacco Research 2001;3(1):51-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11260811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Scherr 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Scherr A, Seifert B, Kuster M, Meyer A, Fagerstr&#xf6;m KO, Tamm M, et al. Predictors of marked weight gain in a population of health care and industrial workers following smoking cessation. BMC Public Health 2015;15:520. [DOI: 10.1186/s12889-015-1854-7]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1854-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4448294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Serretti 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Serretti A, Mandelli L. Antidepressants and body weight: a comprehensive review and meta-analysis. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry 2010;71(10):1259-72. [DOI: 10.4088/JCP.09r05346blu]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.09r05346blu</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21062615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Spring 2011a</Title><Reference><Citation>Spring B, McFadden HG, Rademaker AW, Hitsman B. Behavioual interventions to promote smoking cessation and prevent weight gain: a reply. Addiction 2011;106(3):674-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20955217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Spring 2011b</Title><Reference><Citation>Spring B, Rademaker AW, Mcfadden HG, Hitsman B. Reducing bias in systematic reviews of behavioral interventions? A response to Parsons et&#xa0;al. Addiction 2011;106:676-78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20955217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Tian 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Tian J, Venn A, Otahal P, Gall S. The association between quitting smoking and weight gain: a systemic review and meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. Obesity Reviews 2015;16(10):883-901. [DOI: 10.1111/obr.12304]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26114839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ussher 2019</Title><Reference><Citation>Ussher MH, Faulkner GE, Angus K, Hartmann-Boyce J, Taylor AH. Exercise interventions for smoking cessation. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2019, Issue 10. Art. No: CD002295. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD002295.pub6]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002295.pub6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6819982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31684691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Veldheer 2015</Title><Reference><Citation>Veldheer S, Yingst J, Zhu J, Foulds J. Ten-year weight gain in smokers who quit, smokers who continued smoking and never smokers in the United States, NHANES 2003-2012. International Journal of Obesity 2015;39(12):1727-32. [DOI: 10.1038/ijo.2015.127]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2015.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4976446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26155918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ward 2001</Title><Reference><Citation>Ward KD, Klesges RC, Vander Weg MW. Cessation of smoking and body weight. In: P Bj&#xf6;rntorp, editors(s). International Textbook of Obesity. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd, 2001:323-36. [DOI: 10.1002/0470846739.ch22]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/0470846739.ch22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Weekley 1992</Title><Reference><Citation>Weekley CK, Klesges RC, Reyle G. Smoking as a weight-control strategy in a university population. Addictive Behaviors 1992;17(3):259-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1636473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Williamson 1991</Title><Reference><Citation>Williamson DF, Madans J, Anda RF, Kleinman JC, Giovino GA, Byers T. Smoking cessation and severity of weight gain in a national cohort. New England Journal of Medicine 1991;324(11):739-45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1997840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Yeh 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Yeh HC, Duncab PB, Schmidt MI, Brancati FL. Smoking, smoking cessation, and risk for type 2 diabetes mellitus: a cohort study. Annals of Internal Medicine 2010;152(1):10-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5726255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to other published versions of this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Parsons 2009c</Title><Reference><Citation>Parsons AC, Shraim M, Inglis J, Aveyard P, Hajek P. Interventions for preventing weight gain after smoking cessation. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2009, Issue 1. Art. No: CD006219. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD006219.pub2]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006219.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19160269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>