<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">29065052</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Energy Drink Doses of Caffeine and Taurine Have a Null or Negative Effect on Sprint Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3475</StartPage><EndPage>3481</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3475-3481</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002299</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Jeffries, O, Hill, J, Patterson, SD, and Waldron, M. Energy drink doses of caffeine and taurine have a null or negative effect on sprint performance. J Strength Cond Res 34(12): 3475-3481, 2020-This study investigated the effects of caffeine and taurine coingestion on repeat-sprint cycling performance and associated physiological and perceptual responses. In a double-blind, cross-over, repeated measures study, 11 male subjects (age 21 &#xb1; 2 years; stature 178 &#xb1; 7 cm; body mass 80 &#xb1; 13 kg) completed 10 &#xd7; 6-second sprints on a cycle ergometer, each separated by 24 seconds, one hour after ingesting: caffeine (80 mg) and taurine (1 g), equivalent to the amount observed in popular commercial energy drinks, or placebo (maltodextrin &#x223c;1 g) in a gelatine capsule. Performance was measured on a cycle ergometer, whereas blood lactate concentration (B[la]), rating of perceived exertion (RPE), and heart rate (HR) were measured at baseline (pre-exercise) and after sprints 5 and 10. Magnitude-based inferences revealed likely, trivial differences in peak power and unclear, trivial intersprint fatigue index after ingestion of the caffeine and taurine supplement. Intrasprint fatigue was greater in the caffeine and taurine condition at sprint 10 (likely, small) and possibly smaller in sprints 6-9. The caffeine and taurine supplement had a likely large effect on HR at baseline (effect size = 0.94) and increases in B[la] after sprints 5 (likely small) and 10 (possibly small). There was no effect of the supplement on RPE (unclear, trivial). Administration of caffeine and taurine at doses equivalent to commercial energy drinks did not improve repeat-sprint cycling performance and seemed to induce greater fatigue within selected sprints, particularly at the end of the trial. This undesirable performance effect occurs in parallel with increased HR and glycolytic metabolic bi-products.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeffries</LastName><ForeName>Owen</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Health and Applied Science, St Mary's University, Twickenham, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Health and Applied Science, St Mary's University, Twickenham, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patterson</LastName><ForeName>Stephen D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Health and Applied Science, St Mary's University, Twickenham, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waldron</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Health and Applied Science, St Mary's University, Twickenham, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Science and Technology, University of New England, Armidale, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>1EQV5MLY3D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013654">Taurine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061215" MajorTopicYN="Y">Energy Drinks</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016552" MajorTopicYN="N">Ergometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013654" MajorTopicYN="N">Taurine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29065052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202012000-00023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alford C, Cox H, Wescott R. The effects of Red Bull energy drink on human performance and mood. Amino Acids 21: 139&#x2013;150, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DE, Hickey MS. Effects of caffeine on the metabolic and catecholamine responses to exercise in 5 and 28&#xb0; C. Med Sci Sports Exerc 26: 453&#x2013;458, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnaud MJ, Welsch C. Theophylline and Caffeine Metabolism in Man. Zurich, Switzerland: Friedr. Vieweg and Sons, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Cottrell T, Talhami Lozano A, Aburto-Pratt K, Duhon J. Effect of caffeine on RPE and perceptions of pain, arousal, and pleasure/displeasure during a cycling time trial in endurance trained and active men. Physiol Behav 106: 211&#x2013;217, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Matera AJ, Basinger J, Evans M, Schurman T, Marquez R. Effects of Red Bull energy drink on repeated sprint performance in women athletes. Amino Acids 42: 1803&#x2013;1808, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Roberson DW. Efficacy of acute caffeine ingestion for short-term high-intensity exercise performance: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 24: 257&#x2013;265, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astrup A, Toubro S, Cannon S, Hein P, Breum L, Madsen J. Caffeine: A double-blind, placebo-controlled study of its thermogenic, metabolic, and cardiovascular effects in healthy volunteers. Am J Clin Nutr 51: 759&#x2013;767, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker AJ, Berg HM. Effect of taurine on sarcoplasmic reticulum function and force in skinned fast-twitch skeletal muscle fibres of the rat. J Physiol 538: 185&#x2013;194, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Bampouras TM, Barry TJ, Sparks SA. The effect of acute taurine ingestion on 3-km running performance in trained middle-distance runners. Amino Acids 44: 555&#x2013;561, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batterham AM, Hopkins WG. Making meaningful inferences about magnitudes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 1: 50&#x2013;57, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bichler A, Swenson A, Harris MA. A combination of caffeine and taurine has no effect on short term memory but induces changes in heart rate and mean arterial blood pressure. Amino Acids 31: 471&#x2013;476, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc 14: 377&#x2013;381, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bracco D, Ferrarra JM, Arnaud MJ, Jequier E, Schutz Y. Effects of caffeine on energy metabolism, heart rate, and methylxanthine metabolism in lean and obese women. Am J Physiol 269: E671&#x2013;E678, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM. Caffeine and sports performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 33: 1319&#x2013;1334, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell B, Wilborn C, La Bounty P, Taylor L, Nelson MT, Greenwood M, Ziegenfuss TN, Lopez HL, Hoffman JR, Stout JR, Schmitz S, Collins R, Kalman DS, Antonio J, Kreider RB. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: Energy drinks. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 10: 1, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Kleisinger AK, Grenier S, Dorsch KD. Effect of sugar-free Red Bull energy drink on high-intensity run time-to-exhaustion in young adults. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1271&#x2013;1275, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Munoz G, Munoz-Guerra J. Prevalence of caffeine use in elite athletes following its removal from the World Anti-Doping Agency list of banned substances. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 36: 555&#x2013;561, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Munoz-Fernandez VE, Munoz G, Fernandez-Elias VE, Ortega JF, Hamouti N, Barbero JC, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J. Effects of a caffeine-containing energy drink on simulated soccer performance. PLoS One 7: e31380, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doerner JM, Kuetting DL, Luetkens JA, Naehle CP, Dabir D, Homsi R, Nadal J, Schild HH, Thomas DK. Caffeine and taurine containing energy drink increases left ventricular contractility in healthy volunteers. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging 31: 595&#x2013;601, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 15: 69&#x2013;78, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durnin JV, Womersley J. Body fat assessed from total body density and its estimation from skinfold thickness: Measurements on 481 men and women aged from 16 to 72 years. Br J Nutr 32: 77&#x2013;97, 1974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzsimons M, Dawson B, Ward D, Wilkinson A. Cycling and running tests of repeated sprint ability. Aust J Sci Med Sport 25: 82&#x2013;87, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Little JP, Magnus C, Chilibeck PD. Effect of Red Bull energy drink on repeated Wingate cycle performance and bench-press muscle endurance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 17: 433&#x2013;444, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm BB, Battig K, Holmen J, Nehlig A, Zvartau EE. Actions of caffeine in the brain with special reference to factors that contribute to its widespread use. Pharmacol Rev 51: 83&#x2013;133, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froiland K, Koszewski W, Hingst J, Kopecky L. Nutritional supplement use among college athletes and their sources of information. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 14: 104&#x2013;120, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galler S, Hutzler C, Haller T. Effects of taurine on Ca2(+)-dependent force development of skinned muscle fibre preparations. J Exp Biol 152: 255&#x2013;264, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganio MS, Klau JF, Lee EC, Yeargin SW, McDermott BP, Buyckx M, Maresh CM, Armstrong LE. Effect of various carbohydrate-electrolyte fluids on cycling performance and maximal voluntary contraction. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 20: 104&#x2013;114, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner AS, Martin DT, Barras M, Jenkins DG, Hahn AG. Power output demands of elite track sprint cycling. Int J Perform Anal Sport 5: 149&#x2013;154, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geiss KR, Jester I, Falke W, Hamm M, Waag KL. The effect of a taurine-containing drink on performance in 10 endurance-athletes. Amino Acids 7: 45&#x2013;56, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghandforoush-Sattari M, Mashayekhi S, Krishna CV, Thompson JP, Routledge PA. Pharmacokinetics of oral taurine in healthy volunteers. J Amino Acids 2010: 346237, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gjedsted J, Buhl M, Nielsen S, Schmitz O, Vestergaard ET, Tonnesen E, M&#xf8;ller N. Effects of adrenaline on lactate, glucose, lipid and protein metabolism in the placebo controlled bilaterally perfused human leg. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 202: 641&#x2013;648, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Spriet LL. Metabolic, catecholamine, and exercise performance responses to various doses of caffeine. J Appl Physiol 78: 867&#x2013;874, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwacham N, Wagner DR. Acute effects of a caffeine-taurine energy drink on repeated sprint performance of American college football players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 22: 109&#x2013;116, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajsadeghi S, Mohammadpour F, Manteghi MJ, Kordshakeri K, Tokazebani M, Rahmani E, Hassanzadeh M. Effects of energy drinks on blood pressure, heart rate, and electrocardiographic parameters: An experimental study on healthy young adults. Anatol J Cardiol 16: 94&#x2013;99, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton EJ, Berg HM, Easton CJ, Bakker AJ. The effect of taurine depletion on the contractile properties and fatigue in fast-twitch skeletal muscle of the mouse. Amino Acids 31: 273&#x2013;278, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Kang J, Ratamess NA, Hoffman MW, Tranchina CP, Faigenbaum AD. Examination of a pre-exercise, high energy supplement on exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 6: 2, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR. Caffeine and energy drinks. Strength Cond J 32: 15&#x2013;20, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Estimating sample size for magnitude-based inferences. Sportscience 10: 63&#x2013;70, 2006. Available from: sportsci.org/2006/wghss.htm Accessed 29 March 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huxtable RJ. Physiological actions of taurine. Physiol Rev 72: 101&#x2013;163, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy JL, Kammer L, Ding Z, Wang B, Bernard JR, Liao YH, H wang J. Improved cycling time-trial performance after ingestion of a caffeine energy drink. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 19: 61&#x2013;78, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laquale KM. Red Bull: The other energy drink and its effect on performance. Athl Ther Today 12: 43&#x2013;45, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Monica MB, Fukuda DH, Beyer KS, Hoffman MW, Miramonti AA, Riffe JJ, Baker KM, Fragala MS, Hoffman JR, Stout JR. Altering work to rest ratios differentially influences fatigue indices during repeated sprint ability testing. J Strength Cond Res 30: 400&#x2013;406, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lourenco R, Camilo ME. Taurine: A conditionally essential amino acid in humans? An overview in health and disease. Nutr Hosp 17: 262&#x2013;270, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan TM, Lieberman HR. Do energy drinks contain active components other than caffeine? Nutr Rev 70: 730&#x2013;744, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins PJ, Goss FL, Nagle EF, Beals K, Robertson RJ, Lovalekar MT, Welton GL. Energy drinks improve 5-kilometer running performance in recreational endurance runners. J Strength Cond Res 30: 2979&#x2013;2990, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan P, Lane J, Aspinall L. Effects of hot tea, coffee and water ingestion on physiological responses and mood: The role of caffeine, water and beverage type. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 134: 164&#x2013;173, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlivan A, Irwin C, Grant GD, Anoopkumar-Dukie S, Skinner T, Leveritt M, Desbrow B. The effects of Red Bull energy drink compared with caffeine on cycling time-trial performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 897&#x2013;901, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbloom C. Energy drinks, caffeine, and athletes. Nutr Today 49: 49&#x2013;54, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford JA, Spriet LL, Stellingwerff T. The effect of acute taurine ingestion on endurance performance and metabolism in well-trained cyclists. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 20: 322&#x2013;329, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherman WM, Peden MC, Wright DA. Carbohydrate feedings 1 h before exercise improves cycling performance. Am J Clin Nutr 54: 866&#x2013;870, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner TL, Jenkins DG, Folling J, Leveritt MD, Coombes JS, Taaffe DR. Influence of carbohydrate on serum caffeine concentrations following caffeine ingestion. J Sci Med Sport 16: 343&#x2013;347, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky M, Cupido C. Caffeine potentiates low frequency skeletal muscle force in habitual and nonhabitual caffeine consumers. J Appl Physiol 89: 1719&#x2013;1724, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbaniak GC, Plous S. Research randomizer (version 4.0) [computer software], 2015. Available from: http://www.randomizer.org/ Accessed 24 February 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldhauen JA, Kilman JW, Abel F. Effects of catecholamines on the heart. Myocardial contractility, cardiac efficiency, and total peripheral resistance. Arch Surg 91: 86&#x2013;91, 1965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnock R, Jeffries O, Patterson S, Waldron M. The effects of caffeine, taurine or caffeine-taurine co-ingestion on repeat-sprint cycling performance and physiological responses. Int J Sports Physiol Perform: 1&#x2013;24, 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>