<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41668945</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>43</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nutrition as a missing piece in the development of youth male soccer players: a scoping review and future directions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>291</StartPage><EndPage>317</EndPage><MedlinePgn>291-317</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2025.151654</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The literature on nutrition in soccer has extensively focused on adult male and female soccer players, while knowledge regarding nutritional issues in youth soccer players remains limited. This review aims to summarize the findings related to nutritional habits and ergogenic aid practices among male youth soccer players. Following the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR) Checklist, four databases were consulted on September 17, 2024. Studies that included youth soccer players and examined daily energy intake or expenditure, as well as the effects of ergogenic aids on performance, met the eligibility criteria for this review. In total, 42 studies were considered. Among these, 22 studies focused on energy expenditure and dietary intake, while 20 studies investigated the effects of ergogenic aids on performance. Overall, a negative energy balance was observed; however, after adjusting for the underestimation of energy intake, an adequate intake compared to energy expenditure was found in this review. Additionally, carbohydrate intake tended to decrease with age, while protein intake remained stable throughout adolescence. The topic of macronutrient periodization in youth players requires further research, as no data is currently available regarding macronutrient intake. Additionally, data concerning the effects of ergogenic aids on performance is limited due to variability in methodological procedures. Nevertheless, caffeine and creatine appear to have a positive effect on physical capabilities. This review provides reference data for nutritionists working with youth soccer players and highlights the need for future research in this area.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Institute of Sport &#x2013; National Research Instutite.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinho</LastName><ForeName>Diogo V</ForeName><Initials>DV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interactive Technologies Institute, Laboratory of Robotics and Engineering Systems, Funchal, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalo-Skok</LastName><ForeName>Oliver</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Communication and Education, Universidad Loyola Andaluc&#xed;a, Seville, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chamari</LastName><ForeName>Karim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Naufar, Wellness and Recovery Center, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Field</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Science, Institute of Sport, Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clemente</LastName><ForeName>Filipe Manuel</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Escola Superior Desporto e Lazer, Instituto Polit&#xe9;cnico de Viana do Castelo, Rua Escola Industrial e Comercial de Nun'&#xc1;lvares, Viana do Castelo, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Physical Activity and Health Research &amp; Innovation Center, Viana do Castelo, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gdansk University of Physical Education and Sport, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rebelo</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Lus&#xf3;fona, CIDEFES, Centro de Investiga&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Desporto, Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica e Exerc&#xed;cio e Sa&#xfa;de, Lisboa, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>COD, Center of Sports Optimization, Sporting Clube de Portugal, Lisboa, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gouveia</LastName><ForeName>&#xc9;lvio R</ForeName><Initials>&#xc9;R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, University of Madeira, Funchal, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interactive Technologies Institute, Laboratory of Robotics and Engineering Systems, Funchal, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Vitor Hugo</ForeName><Initials>VH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nutrition and Food Sciences, University of Porto (FCNAUP), Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre in Physical Activity, Health and Leisure (CIAFEL), Faculty of Sports, University of Porto (FADEUP), Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Integrative and Translational Research in Population Health, ITR, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zmijewski</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport - National Research Institute, 01-982 Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mendes</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Polytechnic of Coimbra, Coimbra Health School, Dietetics and Nutrition, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campos</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Informatics Engineering and Interactive Media Design, University of Madeira, Funchal, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>WoWSystems Inform&#xe1;tica Lda, Funchal, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarmento</LastName><ForeName>Hugo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, CIPER, FCDEF, Coimbra, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbohydrates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary intake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soccer demands</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Talent development</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41668945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12884894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.151654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Relvas H, Littlewood M, Nesti M., Gilbourne D, Richardson D. Organizational Structures and Working Practices in Elite European Professional Football Clubs: Understanding the Relationship between Youth and Professional Domains. Eur Sport Manag Q. 2010; 10(2):165&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1080/16184740903559891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16184740903559891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregson W, Carling C, Gualtieri A, O&#x2019;Brien J, Reilly P, Tavares F, Bonanno D, Lopez E, Marques J, Lolli L, Salvo VD. A survey of organizational structure and operational practices of elite youth football academies and national federations from around the world: A performance and medical perspective. Front Sports Act Living. 2022; 4:1031721. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2022.1031721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.1031721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9727309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36506723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan D, Lewin C, Forsythe S, McCall A. Developing world-class soccer players: An example of the academy physical development program from an English premier league team. Strength Cond J. 2018; 40(3):2&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills A, Butt, J, Maynard I, Harwood C. Toward an understanding of optimal development environments within elite English soccer academies. Sport Psychol. 2014; 28(2):137&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1123/tsp.2013-0018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/tsp.2013-0018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AM, Ford PR, Drust B. Talent identification and development in soccer since the millennium. J Sports Sci. 2020; 38(11&#x2013;12):1199&#x2013;1210. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1766647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1766647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32568000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney DJ, Hannon MP, Coleman NM, Murphy RC, Close GL, Morton JP. An audit of performance nutrition services in English soccer academies: implications for optimising player development. Sci Med Footb. 2023; 7(2):146&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1080/24733938.2022.2055785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2022.2055785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35300580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franceschi A, Robinson MA, Owens DJ, Brownlee T, Bampouras TM, Ferrari Bravo D, Enright K. Training loads and microcycle periodisation in Italian Serie A youth soccer players. J Sports Sci. 2024; 42(15):1410&#x2013;1420. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2024.2391648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2391648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39172819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannon MP, Coleman NM, Parker LJF, McKeown J, Unnithan VB, Close GL, Drust B, Morton JP. Seasonal training and match load and micro-cycle periodization in male Premier League academy soccer players. J Sports Sci. 2021; 39(16):1838&#x2013;1849. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33759688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naughton RJ, Drust B, O&#x2019;Boyle A, Morgans R, Abayomi J, Davies IG, Morton JP, Mahon E. Daily Distribution of Carbohydrate, Protein and Fat Intake in Elite Youth Academy Soccer Players Over a 7-Day Training Period. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2016; 26(5):473&#x2013;480. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27633998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro N, Martinho DV, Pereira JR, Rebelo A, Monasterio X, Gonzalo-Skok O, Valente-Dos-Santos J, Tavares F. Injury Risk in Elite Young Male Soccer Players: A Review on the Impact of Growth, Maturation, and Workload. J Strength Cond Res. 2024. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malina R, Martinho D, Oliveira T, Celis-Moreno J, J.Figueiredo A, Seabra Aet al. Estimated annual increments in stature and weight among soccer players 11&#x2013;18 years. Biol Sport. 2025; 42(2):151&#x2013;160. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2025.144294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.144294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11963133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40182722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng HL, Amatoury M, Steinbeck K. Energy expenditure and intake during puberty in healthy nonobese adolescents: a systematic review. Am J Clin Nutr. 2016; 104(4):1061&#x2013;1074. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.115.129205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.115.129205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27629054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins J, Maughan RJ, Gleeson M, Bilsborough J, Jeukendrup A, Morton JP, Phillips SM, Armstrong L, Burke LM, Close GL, Duffield R, Larson-Meyer E, Louis J, Medina D, Meyer F, Rollo I, Sundgot-Borgen J, Wall BT, Boullosa B, Dupont G, Lizarraga A, Res P, Bizzini M, Castagna C, Cowie CM, D&#x2019;Hooghe M, Geyer H, Meyer T, Papadimitriou N, Vouillamoz M, McCall A. UEFA expert group statement on nutrition in elite football. Current evidence to inform practical recommendations and guide future research. Br J Sports Med. 2021; 55(8):416. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2019-101961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33097528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>North M, Kelly AL, Ranchordas MK, Cole M. Nutritional considerations in high performance youth soccer: A systematic review. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2022; 4(3):195&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1007/s42978-022-00171-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42978-022-00171-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney DJ, Hannon MP, Murphy RC, Close GL, Morton JP. Perspectives on the role of nutrition in influencing academy soccer player development and performance: A qualitative case study of key stakeholders from an English category one soccer academy. J Sports Sci. 2024; 42(1):61&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2024.2321008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2321008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38394029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VJHW. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. 2019. Hoboken: Wiley.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw JM, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu MM, Li T, Loder EW, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness LA, Stewart LA, Thomas J, Tricco AC, Welch VA, Whiting P, Moher D. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021; 372:n71. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, Moher D, Peters MDJ, Horsley T, Weeks L, Hempel S, Akl EA, Chang C, McGowan J, Stewart L, Hartling L, Aldcroft A, Wilson MG, Garritty C, Lewin S, Godfrey CM, Macdonald MT, Langlois EV, Soares-Weiser K, Moriarty J, Clifford T, Tun&#xe7;alp &#xd6;, Straus SE. PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR): Checklist and Explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018; 169(7):467&#x2013;473. doi: 10.7326/M18-0850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, Sheppard J, Burke LM. Defining Training and Performance Caliber: A Participant Classification Framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022; 17(2):317&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinho DV, Field A, Naughton R, Ribeiro AS, Rebelo A, Gouveia &#xc9;R, Sarmento H. Nutritional perspectives in female soccer: a scoping review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2024; 21(1):2366427. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2024.2366427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2366427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11225636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38961627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtyniak JG, Britz H, Selzer D, Schwab M, Lehr T. Data Digitizing: Accurate and Precise Data Extraction for Quantitative Systems Pharmacology and Physiologically-Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling. CPT Pharmacometrics Syst Pharmacol. 2020; 9(6):322&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1002/psp4.12511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/psp4.12511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7306621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32543786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez JA, Page MJ, Lipsey MW, Higgins JPT. Dealing with effect size multiplicity in systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Res Synth Methods. 2018; 9(3). doi: 10.1002/jrsm.1310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29971966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poslusna K, Ruprich J, de Vries JH, Jakubikova M, van&#x2019;t Veer P. Misreporting of energy and micronutrient intake estimated by food records and 24 hour recalls, control and adjustment methods in practice. Br J Nutr. 2009; 101 Suppl 2:S73&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1017/S0007114509990602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114509990602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19594967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capling L, Beck KL, Gifford JA, Slater G, Flood VM, O&#x2019;Connor H. Validity of Dietary Assessment in Athletes: A Systematic Review. Nutrients. 2017; 9(12):1313. doi: 10.3390/nu9121313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9121313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5748763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29207495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: A simple funnel-plot-based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000; 56(2):455&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1111/j.0006-341x.2000.00455.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0006-341x.2000.00455.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman, DG, Cochrane Statistical Methods Group. Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. 2019. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions; pp. 241&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009; 41(1):3&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute. Quality Assessment Tool for Observational Cohort and Cross-Sectional Studies; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashin AG, McAuley JH. Clinimetrics: Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) Scale. J Physiother. 2020; 66(1):59. doi: 10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31521549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rico-Sanz J, Frontera WR, Mol&#xe9; PA, Rivera MA, Rivera-Brown A, Meredith CN. Dietary and performance assessment of elite soccer players during a period of intense training. Int J Sport Nutr. 1998; 8(3):230&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1123/ijsn.8.3.230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsn.8.3.230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9738133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stables RG, Hannon MP, Jacob AD, Topping O, Costello NB, Boddy LM, Hambly C, Speakman JR, Sodhi JS, Close GL, Morton JP. Daily energy requirements of male academy soccer players are greater than age-matched non-academy soccer players: A doubly labelled water investigation. J Sports Sci. 2023; 41(12):1218&#x2013;1230. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2023.2263707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2023.2263707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37811806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell M, Pennock A. Dietary analysis of young professional soccer players for 1 week during the competitive season. J Strength Cond Res. 2011; 25(7):1816&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e7fbdd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e7fbdd</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21478767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs MA, Cockburn E, Rumbold PL, Rae G, Stevenson EJ, Russell M. Assessment of Energy Intake and Energy Expenditure of Male Adolescent Academy-Level Soccer Players during a Competitive Week. Nutrients. 2015; 7(10):8392&#x2013;401. doi: 10.3390/nu7105400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu7105400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4632420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granja DS, Cotovio R, Pinto R, Borrego R, Mendes L, Carolino E, Macedo P, Ferreira D, Caetano C, Mendes B. Evaluation of young elite soccer players food intake on match day and highest training load days. J Hum Sport Exerc. 2017; 12(4):1238&#x2013;1247. doi: 10.14198/jhse.2017.124.10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14198/jhse.2017.124.10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raizel R, da Mata Godois A, Coqueiro AY, Voltarelli FA, Fett CA, Tirapegui J, de Paula Ravagnani FC, de Faria Coelho-Ravagnani C. Pre-season dietary intake of professional soccer players. Nutr Health. 2017; 23(4):215&#x2013;222. doi: 10.1177/0260106017737014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0260106017737014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29037118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ersoy N, Kalkan I, Ersoy, G.. Assessment of nutrition status of Turkish elite young male soccer players in the precompetition period. Prog. Nutr. 2019; 21:12&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannon MP, Parker LJF, Carney DJ, McKeown J, Speakman JR, Hambly C, Drust B, Unnithan VB, Close GL, Morton JP. Energy Requirements of Male Academy Soccer Players from the English Premier League. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021; 53(1):200&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinho DV, Naughton RJ, Le&#xe3;o C, Lemos J, Field A, Faria A, Rebelo A, Gouveia &#xc9;R, Sarmento H. Dietary intakes and daily distribution patterns of macronutrients in youth soccer players. Front Nutr. 2023; 10:1134845. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1134845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1134845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10157276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37153912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter JL, Lee DJ, Perrin CG, Ranchordas MK, Cole M. Significant Changes in Resting Metabolic Rate Over a Competitive Match Week Are Accompanied by an Absence of Nutritional Periodization in Male Professional Soccer Players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2023; 33(6):349&#x2013;359. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2023-0069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2023-0069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37734739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettonviel A EO, Brinkmans N YJ, Russcher K, Wardenaar FC, Witard OC. Nutritional Status and Daytime Pattern of Protein Intake on Match, Post-Match, Rest and Training Days in Senior Professional and Youth Elite Soccer Players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2016; 26(3):285&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26630203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Guti&#xe9;rrez E, Garc&#xed;a-Rov&#xe9;s PM, Rodr&#xed;guez C, Braga S, Garc&#xed;a-Zapico P, Patterson AM. Food habits and nutritional status assessment of adolescent soccer players. A necessary and accurate approach. Can J Appl Physiol. 2005; 30(1):18&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1139/h05-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h05-102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy S, Jeanes Y. Nutritional knowledge and dietary intakes of young professional soccer players. Nutr Food Sci. 2006; 36(5):343&#x2013;348. doi: 10.1108/00346650610703199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/00346650610703199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caccialanza R, Cameletti B, Cavallaro G. Nutritional Intake of Young Italian High-Level Soccer Players: Under-Reporting is the Essential Outcome. J Sports Sci Med. 2007; 6(4):538&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3794496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Guti&#xe9;rrez E, Garc&#xed;a-Rov&#xe9;s PM, Garc&#xed;a A, Patterson AM. Food preferences do not influence adolescent high-level athletes&#x2019; dietary intake. Appetite. 2008; 50(2&#x2013;3):536&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1016/j.appet.2007.11.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.appet.2007.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18155807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinzadeh J, Maghsoudi Z, Abbasi B, Daneshvar P, Hojjati A, Ghiasvand R. Evaluation of Dietary Intakes, Body Composition, and Cardiometabolic Parameters in Adolescent Team Sports Elite Athletes: A Cross-sectional Study. Adv Biomed Res. 2017. 8; 6:107. doi: 10.4103/2277-9175.213667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2277-9175.213667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5590404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28904935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stables RG, Hannon MP, Costello NB, McHaffie SJ, Sodhi JS, Close GL, Morton JP. Acute fuelling and recovery practices of academy soccer players: implications for growth, maturation, and physical performance. Sci Med Footb. 2024; 8(1):37&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1080/24733938.2022.2146178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2022.2146178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36351858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leblanc JCh, Le Gall F, Grandjean V, Verger P. Nutritional intake of French soccer players at the clairefontaine training center. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2002; 12(3):268&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.12.3.268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.12.3.268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12432172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holway F, Biondi B, C&#xe1;mera K, Gioia F. Ingesta nutricional en jugadores adolescentes de f&#xfa;tbol de elite en Argentina. Apunts. Medicina de l&#x2019;Esport. 2011; 46(170):55&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.apunts.2010.10.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apunts.2010.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Guti&#xe9;rrez E, Garc&#xed;a A, Garc&#xed;a-Zapico P, P&#xe9;rez-Landaluce J, Patterson AM, Garc&#xed;a-Rov&#xe9;s PM. Is there a relationship between the playing position of soccer players and their food and macronutrient intake? Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2012; 37(2):225&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1139/h11-152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h11-152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22380725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidalgo y Teran Elizondo R, Mart&#xed;n Bermudo FM, Pe&#xf1;aloza Mendez R, Bern&#xe1; Amor&#xf3;s G, Lara Padilla E, Berral de la Rosa FJ. NUTRITIONAL INTAKE and NUTRITIONAL STATUS IN ELITE MEXICAN TEENAGERS SOCCER PLAYERS OF DIFFERENT AGES. Nutr Hosp. 2015; 32(4):1735&#x2013;43. doi: 10.3305/nh.2015.32.4.8788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3305/nh.2015.32.4.8788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26545544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noronha DC, Santos MIAF, Santos AA, Corrente LGA, Fernandes RKN, Barreto ACA, Santos RGJ, Santos RS, Gomes LPS, Nascimento MVS. Nutrition Knowledge is Correlated with a Better Dietary Intake in Adolescent Soccer Players: A Cross-Sectional Study. J Nutr Metab. 2020; 2020:3519781. doi: 10.1155/2020/3519781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/3519781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6964714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31998535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeederberg C, Leach L, Lambert EV, Noakes TD, Dennis SC, Hawley JA. The effect of carbohydrate ingestion on the motor skill proficiency of soccer players. Int J Sport Nutr. 1996; 6(4):348&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1123/ijsn.6.4.348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsn.6.4.348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8953337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S, Iba&#xf1;ez J, Izquierdo M, Gorostiaga E. Creatine supplementation and sprint performance in soccer players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000. Feb; 32(2):518&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200002000-00039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200002000-00039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM. Creatine supplementation in young soccer players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2004. Feb; 14(1):95&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.14.1.95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.14.1.95</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15129933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arent SM, Pellegrino JK, Williams CA, Difabio DA, Greenwood JC. Nutritional supplementation, performance, and oxidative stress in college soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2010; 24(4):1117&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cb70b8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cb70b8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira LA, Bortolotti H, Pasquarelli BN, Pedroso JAB, Avelar A, Estanislau C, Altimari LR. A cafe&#xed;na melhora o desempenho em teste de sprints repetidos em jovens jogadores de futebol?. Rev Andal Med Deport. 2011; 4(3):109&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell M, Benton D, Kingsley M. Influence of carbohydrate supplementation on skill performance during a soccer match simulation. J Sci Med Sport. 2012; 15(4):348&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2011.12.006.22230353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2011.12.006.22230353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22230353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan JB, Korgaokar A, Farley RS, Coons JM, Caputo JL. Caffeine supplementation and reactive agility in elite youth soccer players. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2014; 26(2):168&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1123/pes.2013-0134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.2013-0134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24277927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersen SA, Krustrup P, Bendiksen M, Randers MB, Brito J, Bangsbo J, Jin Y, Mohr M. Caffeine supplementation does not affect match activities and fatigue resistance during match play in young football players. J Sports Sci. 2014; 32(20):1958&#x2013;1965. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2014.965189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2014.965189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25357189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell M, Benton D, Kingsley M. Carbohydrate ingestion before and during soccer match play and blood glucose and lactate concentrations. J Athl Train. 2014; 49(4):447&#x2013;53. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-49.3.12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-49.3.12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4151832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24933430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Silva A, Buzzachera CF, Pi&#xe7;arro IDC, Januario RSB, Ferreira LHB, McAnulty SR, Utter AC, Souza-Junior TP. Effect of low dose, short-term creatine supplementation on muscle power output in elite youth soccer players. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017; 14:5. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0162-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0162-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28190980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis M, Noon M, Myers T, Clarke N. Low Doses of Caffeine: Enhancement of Physical Performance in Elite Adolescent Male Soccer Players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019; 14(5):569&#x2013;575. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2018-0536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Giustiniani P, Rollo I, Witard OC, Galloway SDR. Ingesting a 12% Carbohydrate-Electrolyte Beverage Before Each Half of a Soccer Match Simulation Facilitates Retention of Passing Performance and Improves High-Intensity Running Capacity in Academy Players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019; 29(4):397&#x2013;405. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2018-0214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2018-0214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30507267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Cholewa JM, Castillo-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Kargarfard M, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J. Effects of chronic betaine supplementation on performance in professional young soccer players during a competitive season: a double blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021; 18(1):67. doi: 10.1186/s12970-021-00464-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00464-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8525016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34663363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari N, Salesi M, Soltani P, Fazeli D. The effects of acute caffeine ingestion on decision-making and pass accuracy in young soccer players: A preliminary randomized controlled trial. Behav Brain Res. 2023:114732. doi: 10.1016/j.bbr.2023.114732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2023.114732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39491109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuru D, Aktitiz S, Atakan MM, K&#xf6;se MG, Turnag&#xf6;l HH, Ko&#x15f;ar &#x15e;N. Effect of Pre-exercise Sodium Citrate Ingestion on Repeated Sprint Performance in Soccer Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2024; 38(3):556&#x2013;562. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38241467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolotti H, Pereira LA, Oliveira RS, Cyrino ES, Altimari LR. Carbohydrate mouth rinse does not improve repeated sprint performance. Revista Brasileira de Cineantropometria &amp; Desempenho Humano. 2013; 15:639&#x2013;645. doi: 10.5007/1980-0037.2013v15n6p639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5007/1980-0037.2013v15n6p639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper LD, Briggs MA, McNamee G, West DJ, Kilduff LP, Stevenson E, Russell M. Physiological and performance effects of carbohydrate gels consumed prior to the extra-time period of prolonged simulated soccer match-play. J Sci Med Sport. 2016; 19(6):509&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2015.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26115589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Azevedo AP, Michelone Acquesta F, Lancha AH Jr, Bertuzzi R, Poortmans JR, Amadio AC, Cerca Serr&#xe3;o J. Creatine supplementation can improve impact control in high-intensity interval training. Nutrition. 2019; 61:99&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2018.09.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2018.09.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30708260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastrz&#x119;bska M, Kaczmarczyk M, Jastrz&#x119;bski Z. Effect of Vitamin D Supplementation on Training Adaptation in Well-Trained Soccer Players. J Strength Cond Res. 2016; 30(9):2648&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26808860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skalska M, Nikolaidis PT, Knechtle B, Rosemann TJ, Radzimi&#x144;ski &#x141;, Jastrz&#x119;bska J, Kaczmarczyk M, My&#x15b;liwiec A, Dragos P, L&#xf3;pez-S&#xe1;nchez GF, Jastrz&#x119;bski Z. Vitamin D Supplementation and Physical Activity of Young Soccer Players during High-Intensity Training. Nutrients. 2019; 11(2):349. doi: 10.3390/nu11020349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11020349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6412881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30736376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson L, Orme P, Naughton RJ, Close GL, Milsom J, Rydings D, O&#x2019;Boyle A, Di Michele R, Louis J, Hambly C, Speakman JR, Morgans R, Drust B, Morton JP. Energy Intake and Expenditure of Professional Soccer Players of the English Premier League: Evidence of Carbohydrate Periodization. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2017; 27(3):228&#x2013;238. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28050927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elferink-Gemser MT, Huijgen BC, Coelho-e-Silva M, Lemmink KA, Visscher C. The changing characteristics of talented soccer players&#x2014;a decade of work in Groningen. J Sports Sci. 2012; 30(15):1581&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2012.725854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.725854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23020141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das JK, Salam RA, Thornburg KL, Prentice AM, Campisi S, Lassi ZS, Koletzko B, Bhutta ZA. Nutrition in adolescents: physiology, metabolism, and nutritional needs. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2017; 1393(1):21&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1111/nyas.13330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.13330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28436102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinho DV, Naughton RJ, Faria A, Rebelo A, Sarmento H. Predicting resting energy expenditure among athletes: a systematic review. Biol Sport. 2023; 40(3):787&#x2013;804. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2023.119986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.119986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10286600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bytomski JR. Fueling for Performance. Sports Health. 2018; 10(1):47&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1177/1941738117743913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738117743913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5753973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannon MP, Carney DJ, Floyd S, Parker LJF, McKeown J, Drust B, Unnithan VB, Close GL, Morton JP. Cross-sectional comparison of body composition and resting metabolic rate in Premier League academy soccer players: Implications for growth and maturation. J Sports Sci. 2020; 38(11&#x2013;12):1326&#x2013;1334. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1717286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1717286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31964230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malina RM, Geithner CA. Body composition of young athletes. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2011; 5(3):262&#x2013;278. doi: 10.1177/1559827610392493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1559827610392493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson-Meyer DE, Woolf K, Burke L. Assessment of Nutrient Status in Athletes and the Need for Supplementation. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018; 28(2):139&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29252049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stables R, Anderson L, Sale C, Hannon MP, Dunn R, Tang JCY, Fraser WD, Costello NB, Close GL, Morton JP. Training with reduced carbohydrate availability affects markers of bone resorption and formation in male academy soccer players from the English Premier League. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024; 124(12):3767&#x2013;3780. doi: 10.1007/s00421-024-05574-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05574-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11569010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39154306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo WL, Tester E, Close GL, Cronin CJ, Morton JP. Professional Male Soccer Players&#x2019; Perspectives of the Nutrition Culture Within an English Premier League Football Club: A Qualitative Exploration Using Bourdieu&#x2019;s Concepts of Habitus, Capital and Field. Sports Med. 2024. doi: 10.1007/s40279-024-02134-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02134-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12011920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39488799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Buchheit M, Hader K, Sarmento H, Afonso J. Building Bridges Instead of Putting Up Walls: Connecting the &#x201c;Teams&#x201d; to Improve Soccer Players&#x2019; Support. Sports Med. 2023; 53(12):2309&#x2013;2320. doi: 10.1007/s40279-023-01887-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01887-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37480484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper AM, Allan J, Hodges D, Catterson P, Mason L, Fitzpatrick J, Grantham N, Morton JP, Hearris MA, Close GL. Nutritional habits of professional team sport athletes: An insight into the carbohydrate, fluid, and caffeine habits of English Premier League football players during match play. J Sports Sci. 2024; 42(17):1589&#x2013;1596. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2024.2402137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2402137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39323036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento H, Martinho DV, Gouveia &#xc9;R, Afonso J, Chmura P, Field A, Savedra NO, Oliveira R, Pra&#xe7;a G, Silva R, Barrera-D&#xed;az J, Clemente FM. the Influence of Playing Position on Physical, Physiological, and Technical Demands in Adult Male Soccer Matches: A Systematic Scoping Review with Evidence Gap Map. Sports Med. 2024; 54(11):2841&#x2013;2864. doi: 10.1007/s40279-024-02088-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02088-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11561100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39259431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. (2006). The conduct of statistical analyses in sport science. Sports Science, 10, 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M. Recommendations for the design of randomized controlled trials in strength and conditioning. Common design and data interpretation. Front Sports Act Living. 2022; 4:981836. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2022.981836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.981836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9493045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark L, Fairhurst C, Torgerson DJ. Allocation concealment in randomised controlled trials: are we getting better? BMJ. 2016; 355:i5663. doi: 10.1136/bmj.i5663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.i5663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27856428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang M, Ragan BG, Park JH. Issues in outcomes research: an overview of randomization techniques for clinical trials. J Athl Train. 2008; 43(2):215&#x2013;21. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-43.2.215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-43.2.215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2267325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18345348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans SR. Fundamentals of clinical trial design. J Exp Stroke Transl Med. 2010. 1; 3(1):19&#x2013;27. doi: 10.6030/1939-067x-3.1.19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6030/1939-067x-3.1.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3083073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21533012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker J, Wilson S, Johnston K, Dehghansai N, Koenigsberg A, de Vegt S, Wattie N. Talent Research in Sport 1990&#x2013;2018: A Scoping Review. Front Psychol.11:607710. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2020.607710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.607710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7723867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Till K, Baker J. Challenges and [Possible] Solutions to Optimizing Talent Identification and Development in Sport. Front Psychol. 2020; 11:664. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2020.00664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.00664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32351427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmento H, Anguera MT, Pereira A, Ara&#xfa;jo D. Talent Identification and Development in Male Football: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2018; 48(4):907&#x2013;931. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0851-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0851-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29299878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puce L, Ceylan H&#x130;, Trompetto C, Cotellessa F, Schenone C, Marinelli L, Zmijewski P, Bragazzi NL, Mori L. Optimizing athletic performance through advanced nutrition strategies: can AI and digital platforms have a role in ultraendurance sports? Biol Sport. 2024; 41(4):305&#x2013;313. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.141063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.141063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11475005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>