<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20507554</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Brain serotonergic and dopaminergic modulators, perceptual responses and endurance exercise performance following caffeine co-ingested with a high fat meal in trained humans.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22</StartPage><MedlinePgn>22</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-7-22</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The present study examined putative modulators and indices of brain serotonergic and dopaminergic function, perceptual responses, and endurance exercise performance following caffeine co-ingested with a high fat meal.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Trained humans (n = 10) performed three constant-load cycling tests at 73% of maximal oxygen uptake (VO2max) until exhaustion at 10 degrees C remove space throughout. Prior to the first test, subjects consumed a 90% carbohydrate meal (Control trial) and for the remaining two tests, a 90% fat meal with (FC trial) and without (F trial) caffeine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Time to exhaustion was not different between the F and FC trials (P &gt; 0.05); [Control trial: 116(88-145) min; F trial: 122(96-144) min; FC trial: 127(107-176) min]. However, leg muscular discomfort during exercise was significantly lower on the FC relative to F trial (P &lt; 0.01). There were no significant differences between F and FC trials in key modulators and indices of brain serotonergic (5-HT) and dopaminergic (DA) function [(i.e. plasma free and total tryptophan (Trp), tyrosine (Tyr), large neutral amino acids (LNAA), Trp:LNAA ratio, free-Trp:Tyr ratio, total Trp:Tyr ratio, and plasma prolactin] (P &gt; 0.05) with the exception of plasma free-Trp:LNAA ratio which was higher at 90 min and at exhaustion during the FC trial (P &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Neither brain 5-HT nor DA systems would appear to be implicated in the fatigue process when exercise is performed without significant thermoregulatory stress, thus indicating fatigue development during exercise in relatively cold temperatures to occur predominantly due to glycogen depletion.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hadjicharalambous</LastName><ForeName>Marios P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative and Systems Biology, Faculty of Biomedical and Life Sciences (FBLS), University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK. Y.Pitsiladis@bio.gla.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kilduff</LastName><ForeName>Liam P</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pitsiladis</LastName><ForeName>Yannis P</ForeName><Initials>YP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20507554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2896923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-7-22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chester N, Wojek N. Caffeine consumption amongst British athletes following changes to the 2004 WADA prohibited list. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29:534&#x2013;528. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-989231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-989231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18027309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill D, Dalsky LGP, Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports. 1978;10:155&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">723503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet LL, MacLean DA, Dyck DJ, Hultman E, Cederblad G, Graham TE. Caffeine ingestion and muscle metabolism during prolonged exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1992;262:E891&#x2013;E898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1616022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox G, Desbrow R, Montgomery P, Anderson M, Bruce C, Macrides T, Martin D, Moquin A, Roberts A, Hawley J, Burke L. Effect of different protocols of caffeine intake on metabolism and endurance performance. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:990&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desbrow B, Barrett C, Minahan CL, Grant G, Leveritt M. Caffeine, Cycling Performance, and Exogenous CHO Oxidation: A Dose-Response Study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:1744&#x2013;1751. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a16cf7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a16cf7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19657295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman M, Wendling P, Friars D, Graham T. Metabolic catecholamine, and endurance responses to caffeine during intense exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:1658&#x2013;1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8904583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Rourke MP, O'Brien BJ, Knez WL, Paton CD. Caffeine has a small effect on 5-km running performance of well-trained and recreational runners. J Sci Med Sports. 2008;11:231&#x2013;233. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2006.12.118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2006.12.118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17544329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Zhao Z, Stock HS, Mehl KA, Buggy J, Hand GA. Central nervous system effects of caffeine and adenosine on fatigue. Am J Physiol. 2003;284:R399&#x2013;R404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12399249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Effect of caffeine on the neuromuscular system - potential as an ergogenic aid. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33:1284&#x2013;1289. doi: 10.1139/H08-121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/H08-121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim B-V, Jang M-H, Shin M-C, Kim H-B, Kim Y-J, Kim Y-P, Chung J-H, Kim H, Shin M-S, Kim S-S, Kim E-H, Kim C-J. Caffeine inhibits exercise-induced increase in tryptophan hydroxylase expression in dorsal and median raphe of Sprague-Dawley rats. Neuroscience Letters. 2001;308:25&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/S0304-3940(01)01980-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0304-3940(01)01980-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm BB, Battig K, Holmen J, Nehlig A, Zvartau EE. Actions of caffeine in the brain with special reference to factors that contribute to its widespread use. Pharmacol Rev. 1999;51:83&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10049999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole KJ, Costill DL, Starling RD, Goodpaster BH, Trappe SW, Fink WJ. Effect of caffeine ingestion on perception of effort and subsequent work production. Int J Sport Nutr. 1996;6:14&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8653101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Bailey SP, Jackson DA, Strasner AB, Morehouse SL. Effect of a serotonin (5-HT) agonist during prolonged exercise to fatigue in humans. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 1993;25:S78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Bailey SP. Possible mechanisms of central nervous system fatigue during exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:45&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9000155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newsholme E, Acworth IN, Blomstrand E. In: Advances in Biochemistry. Benzi G, editor. UK: John Libby Eurotext; 1987. Amino-acids, brain neurotransmitters and a functional link between muscle and brain that is important in sustained exercise; pp. 127&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Simoni MG, Sokola A, Fodritto F, Dal Toso G, Algeri S. Functional meaning of tryptophan-induced increase of 5-HT metabolism as clarified by in vivo voltammetry. Brain Research. 1987;411:89&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1016/0006-8993(87)90684-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0006-8993(87)90684-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2440515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloxam DL, Tricklebank M, Patel A, Curzon G. Effects of albumin amino acids and clofibrate on the uptake of tryptophan by the rat brain. J Neurochem. 1980;34:43&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1111/j.1471-4159.1980.tb04619.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1471-4159.1980.tb04619.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7452245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curzon G, Friedel J, Knott PJ. The effect of fatty acids on the binding of tryptophan to plasma protein. Nature. 1973;242:198&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1038/242198a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/242198a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4695158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland B, Welch A, Unwin I, Buss D, Paul A, Southgate D. Goodfellow Egan Phototypesetting. Cambridge, UK; 1991. The Composition of Foods.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstrom J, Hermansen L, Hultman E, Saltin B. Diet, muscle glycogen and physical performance. Acta Physiol Scand. 1967;71:140&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1967.tb03720.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1967.tb03720.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5584523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forster V, Dempsey J, Thomson J, Vidruk R, DoPico G. Estimation of arterial PO2, PCO2, pH and lactate from arterialised venous blood. J Appl Physiol. 1972;32:134&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5007005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway SDR, Maughan RJ. Effects of ambient temperature on the capacity to perform prolonged cycle exercise in man. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:1240&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9309637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble BJ, Borg GA, Jacobs I, Ceci R, Kaiser P. A category-ratio perceived exertion scale: relationship to blood and muscle lactates and heart rate. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1983;15:523&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6656563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Meirleir K, L'Hermite-Baleriaux M, L'Hermite M, Rost R, Hollmann W. Evidence for serotoninergic control of exercise-induced prolactin secretion. Horm Metab Res. 1985;17:380&#x2013;381. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1013551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1013551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3161814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Meirleir K, Baeyens LL, L'Hermite-Baleriaux M, L'Hermite M, Hollmann W. Exercise-induced prolactin release is related to anaerobiosis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1985;60:1250&#x2013;1252. doi: 10.1210/jcem-60-6-1250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jcem-60-6-1250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3998069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farris JW, Hinchcliff KW, McKeever KH, Lamb DR, Thompson DL. Effect of tryptophan and of glucose on exercise capacity of horses. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85:807&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9729551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Jonathan N, Arbogast LA, Hyde JF. Neuroendocrine [corrected] regulation of prolactin release. Progress in Neurobiol. 1989;33:399&#x2013;447. doi: 10.1016/0301-0082(89)90008-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0301-0082(89)90008-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2695976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy GM, Arendt A, Banky Z, Halasz B. Dehydration attenuates plasma prolactin response to suckling through a dopaminergic mechanism. Endocrinology. 1992;130:819&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1210/en.130.2.819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/en.130.2.819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1733729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar LD Van De, Rittenhouse PA, Li Q, Levy AD. Serotonergic regulation of renin and prolactin secretion. Behaviour &amp; Brain Res. 1996;73:203&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8788503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaouloff F, Elghozi JL, Guezennec Y, Laude D. Effects of conditioned running on plasma, liver and brain tryptophan and on brain 5-hydroxytryptamine metabolism of the rat. Br J Pharmacol. 1985;86:33&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1916847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2413941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struder H, Hollmann W, Platen P, Duperly J, Fischer H, Weber K. Alterations in plasma free tryptophan and large neutral amino acids do not affect perceived exertion and prolactin during 90 min of treadmill exercise. Int J Sports Med. 1996;17:73&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-972811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-972811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8833706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardridge WM. Blood-brain transport of nutrients: Introduction. Fed Proc. 1986;45:2047&#x2013;2049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3519288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Celsing F, Newsholme EA. Changes in plasma concentrations of aromatic and branched-chain amino acids during sustained exercise in man and their possible role in fatigue. Acta Physiol Scand. 1988;133:115&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1988.tb08388.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1988.tb08388.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3227900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto T, Newsholme EA. Diminished central fatigue by inhibition of the L-system transporter for the uptake of tryptophan. Brain Res Bullettin. 2000;52:35&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1016/S0361-9230(99)00276-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0361-9230(99)00276-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10779700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares DD, Lima NR, Coimbra CC, Marubayash U. Evidence that tryptophan reduces mechanical efficiency and running performance in rats. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 2003;74:357&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/S0091-3057(02)01003-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0091-3057(02)01003-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12479955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitsiladis YP, Smith I, Maughan RJ. Increased fat availability enhances the capacity of trained individuals to perform prolonged exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:1570&#x2013;1579. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199911000-00012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199911000-00012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10589859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson P, Hasegawa H, Roelands B, Piacentini MF, Looverie R, Meeusen R. Acute dopamine/noradrenaline reuptake inhibition enhances human exercise performance in warm, but not temperate conditions. J Physiol. 2005;565(13):873&#x2013;883. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2004.079202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2004.079202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelands B, Goekint M, Heyman E, Piacentini MF, Watson P, Hasegawa H, Buyse L, Pauwels F, De Schutter G, Meeusen R. Acute norepinephrine reuptake inhibition decreases performance in normal and high ambient temperature. J Appl Physiol. 2008;105:206&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.90509.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.90509.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18499777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slaap BR, van Vliet IM, Westenberg HGM, Den Boer JA. Responders and non-responders to drug treatment in social phobia: differences at baseline and prediction of response. J Affective Disorders. 1996;39:13&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1016/0165-0327(96)00013-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-0327(96)00013-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8835649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kampf-Sherf O, Zlotogorski Z, Gilboa A, Speedie L, Lereya J, Rosca P, Shavit Y. Neuropsychological functioning in major depression and responsiveness to selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors antidepressants. J Affect Disord. 1996;82:453&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15555698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin EA, Nicholson WT, Eisenach JH, Charkoudian N, Joyner MJ. Influences of adenosine receptor antagonism on vasodilator responses to adenosine and exercise in adenosine responders and nonresponders. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:1678&#x2013;1684. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00546.2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00546.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16946029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadjicharalambous M, Georgiades E, Kilduff LP, Turner AP, Tsofliou F, Pitsiladis YP. Influence of caffeine on effort perception, metabolism and exercise performance following a high fat meal. J Sports Sci. 2006;24(8):875&#x2013;887. doi: 10.1080/02640410500249399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410500249399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16815783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>