<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41451419</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multidisciplinary cognitive performance optimization for mission-critical decision makers: delivering "the whole pizza".</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1636406</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1636406</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1636406</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2025.1636406</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite the promise of artificial intelligence, there remains no substitute for human analytical acumen and decision-making. Human cognitive performance is not fixed; it can often be substantially improved through specific interventions. The field of cognitive performance optimization is multidisciplinary, often involving contributions from physicians, psychologists, athletic trainers, therapists, executive coaches, and many other professionals. Key domains include lifestyle factors, treatment of potentially cognitively impairing disorders, careful use of stimulants, and additional personalized interventions. Modifiable lifestyle factors such as sleep, physical exercise, toxic substances, stress management, and diet play a crucial role. Treatable cognitively impairing disorders include sleep apnea, restless leg syndrome, major depressive disorder, persistent depressive disorder, seasonal affective disorder, anxiety disorders, post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), migraine with or without neurological aura, vitamin B12 deficiency, hypothyroidism, and obesity. Stimulants, including both prescription stimulants like methylphenidate and non-prescription stimulants like caffeine, can improve fatigue, sustained attention and processing speed with manageable risks when used carefully. Personalized interventions include correction of vision and hearing deficits, cognitive rehabilitation under professional therapist guidance, computer-based cognitive skills training, cognitive performance coaching, and non-invasive brain stimulation. Taken together, addressing these domains in a multidisciplinary fashion can result in meaningful benefits in terms of cognitive performance. However, cognitive performance optimization requires substantial time and effort on the part of the providers and participants as there are rarely any "easy fixes." Importantly, cognitive performance optimization is an evolving science with great promise for future advanced interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Brody.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brody</LastName><ForeName>David L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences (USUHS) and Walter Reed National Military Medical Center, Bethesda, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stimulants</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declares that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41451419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12728740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2025.1636406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brody DL. Concussion Care Manual. 2nd ed. Oxford University Press (2019). p. 254. doi: 10.1093/med/9780190054793.001.0001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/med/9780190054793.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charest J, Grandner MA. Sleep and athletic performance: impacts on physical performance, mental performance, injury risk and recovery, and mental health. Sleep Med Clin. (2020) 15:41&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1016/j.jsmc.2019.11.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsmc.2019.11.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9960533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32005349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupp TL, Wesensten NJ, Bliese PD, Balkin TJ. Banking sleep: realization of benefits during subsequent sleep restriction and recovery. Sleep. (2009) 32:311&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1093/sleep/32.3.311</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/32.3.311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2647785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19294951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamdar BB, Kaplan KA, Kezirian EJ, Dement WC. The impact of extended sleep on daytime alertness, vigilance, and mood. Sleep Med. (2004) 5:441&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.sleep.2004.05.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2004.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15341888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandolesi L, Polverino A, Montuori S, Foti F, Ferraioli G, Sorrentino P, et al. Effects of physical exercise on cognitive functioning and wellbeing: biological and psychological benefits. Front Psychol. (2018) 9:509. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5934999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29755380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo-G&#xf3;mez D, Del Pozo-Cruz J, Noetel M, &#xc1;lvarez-Barbosa F, Alfonso-Rosa RM, Del Pozo Cruz B. Optimal dose and type of exercise to improve cognitive function in older adults: a systematic review and bayesian model-based network meta-analysis of RCTs. Ageing Res Rev. (2022) 76:101591. doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2022.101591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2022.101591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35182742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topiwala A, Ebmeier KP. Effects of drinking on late-life brain and cognition. Evid Based Ment Health. (2018) 21:12&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1136/eb-2017-102820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/eb-2017-102820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10270452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29273599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subhani M, Dhanda A, King JA, Warren FC, Creanor S, Davies MJ, et al. Association between glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists use and change in alcohol consumption: a systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. (2024) 78:102920. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102920</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11701477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39764544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond DM, Campbell AM, Park CR, Halonen J, Zoladz PR. The temporal dynamics model of emotional memory processing: a synthesis on the neurobiological basis of stress-induced amnesia, flashbulb and traumatic memories, and the Yerkes-Dodson law. Neural Plast. (2007) 2007:60803. doi: 10.1155/2007/60803</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2007/60803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1906714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17641736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornfield J. The Wise Heart: A Guide to the Universal Teachings of Buddhist Psychology. New York, NY: Bantam Books; (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gothe NP, McAuley E. Yoga and cognition: a meta-analysis of chronic and acute effects. Psychosom Med. (2015) 77:784&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1097/PSY.0000000000000218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PSY.0000000000000218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26186435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soni S, Joshi LN, Datta A. Effect of controlled deep breathing on psychomotor and higher mental functions in normal individuals. Indian J Physiol Pharmacol. (2015) 59:41&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26571983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong Y, Clark E, Furbish K, Maggiolo N, West E, Sylvia L. Evidence for improved cognitive health with diet: a narrative review. Altern Ther Health Med. (2023) 29:12&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez DE, McAllister MJ, Waldman HS, Ferrando AA, Joyce J, Barringer ND, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: tactical athlete nutrition. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2022) 19:267&#x2013;315. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2022.2086017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2022.2086017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9261739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35813846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra A, Grunstein RR, Fietze I, Weaver TE, Redline S, Azarbarzin A, et al. Tirzepatide for the treatment of obstructive sleep apnea and obesity. N Engl J Med. (2024) 391:1193&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2404881</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2404881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11598664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38912654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buie JJ, Watson LS, Smith CJ, Sims-Robinson C. Obesity-related cognitive impairment: the role of endothelial dysfunction. Neurobiol Dis. (2019) 132:104580. doi: 10.1016/j.nbd.2019.104580</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2019.104580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31454547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts CA, Jones A, Sumnall H, Gage SH, Montgomery C. How effective are pharmaceuticals for cognitive enhancement in healthy adults? A series of meta-analyses of cognitive performance during acute administration of modafinil, methylphenidate and D-amphetamine. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. (2020) 38:40&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2020.07.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2020.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32709551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Repantis D, Bovy L, Ohla K, Kuhn S, Dresler M. Cognitive enhancement effects of stimulants: a randomized controlled trial testing methylphenidate, modafinil, and caffeine. Psychopharmacology. (2021) 238:441&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1007/s00213-020-05691-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-020-05691-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33201262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rees JLC, Saunders R, Krynicki CR, Belli A, Ahmed Z, Di Pietro V, et al. Methylphenidate for the cognitive and neurobehavioural sequelae of traumatic brain injury in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Neurol. (2025) 16:1546080. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2025.1546080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2025.1546080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11919662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40109849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GE, Housen P, Yaffe K, Ruff R, Kennison RF, Mahncke HW, et al. A cognitive training program based on principles of brain plasticity: results from the improvement in memory with plasticity-based adaptive cognitive training (IMPACT) study. J Am Geriatr Soc. (2009) 57:594&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2008.02167.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2008.02167.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4169294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19220558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahncke HW, Kim SJ, Rose A, Stasio C, Buckley P, Caroff S, et al. Evaluation of a plasticity-based cognitive training program in schizophrenia: results from the eCaesar trial. Schizophr Res. (2019) 208:182&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.schres.2019.03.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2019.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire A, Sandrone S, Hellyer PJ. A large-scale, cross-sectional investigation into the efficacy of brain training. Front Hum Neurosci. (2019) 13:221. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2019.00221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2019.00221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6629869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31338032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JX, Rogers LM, Gross EZ, Ryals AJ, Dokucu ME, Brandstatt KL, et al. Targeted enhancement of cortical-hippocampal brain networks and associative memory. Science. (2014) 345:1054&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1126/science.1252900</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1252900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4307924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25170153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg ND, Iverson GL, Panenka W. Cogniphobia in mild traumatic brain injury. J Neurotrauma. (2017) 34:2141&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1089/neu.2016.4719</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2016.4719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28114873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert V, Kyle SD, Pratt D. Does cognitive behavioural therapy for insomnia improve cognitive performance? A systematic review and narrative synthesis. Sleep Med Rev. (2018) 39:37&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1016/j.smrv.2017.07.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2017.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28918315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair KL, Ponsford JL, Taffe J, Lockley SW, Rajaratnam SM. Randomized controlled trial of light therapy for fatigue following traumatic brain injury. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. (2014) 28:303&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1177/1545968313508472</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968313508472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24213962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>