<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35969166</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine Increases Endurance Performance via Changes in Neural and Muscular Determinants of Performance Fatigability.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1591</StartPage><EndPage>1603</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1591-1603</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002944</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">In the present study, we tested the hypothesis that caffeine would increase endurance performance via attenuation of neural and muscular determinants of performance fatigability during high-intensity, whole-body exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Ten healthy males cycled until exhaustion (89% &#xb1; 2% of V&#x307;O2max) after the ingestion of caffeine or placebo. During another four visits, the same exercise was performed after either caffeine or placebo ingestion but with exercise discontinued after completing either 50% or 75% of the duration of placebo trial. An additional trial with caffeine ingestion was also performed with interruption at the placebo time to exhaustion (isotime). Performance fatigability was measured via changes in maximal voluntary contraction, whereas neural and muscular determinants of performance fatigability were quantified via preexercise to postexercise decrease in quadriceps voluntary activation (VA) and potentiated twitch force, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with the placebo, caffeine increased time to exhaustion (+14.4 &#xb1; 1.6%, P = 0.017, 314.4 &#xb1; 47.9 vs 354.9 &#xb1; 40.8 s). Caffeine did not change the rate of decline in maximal voluntary contraction (P = 0.209), but caffeine reduced the twitch force decline at isotime when stimulating at single twitch (-58.6 &#xb1; 22.4 vs -45.7 &#xb1; 21.9%, P = 0.014) and paired 10 Hz electrical stimuli (-37.3 &#xb1; 13.2 vs -28.2 &#xb1; 12.9%, P = 0.025), and reduced the amplitude of electromyography signal during cycling at isotime (P = 0.034). The decline in VA throughout the trial was lower (P = 0.004) with caffeine (-0.5 &#xb1; 4.2%) than with placebo (-5.8 &#xb1; 8.5%). Caffeine also maintained peripheral oxygen saturation at higher levels (95.0 &#xb1; 1.9%) than placebo (92.0 &#xb1; 6.2%, P = 0.016).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Caffeine ingestion improves performance during high-intensity, whole-body exercise via attenuation of exercise-induced reduction in VA and contractile function.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cristina-Souza</LastName><ForeName>Gislaine</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santos</LastName><ForeName>Pamela Souza</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santos-Mariano</LastName><ForeName>Ana Carla</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coelho</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Boari</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Engineering, Federal University of ABC, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodacki</LastName><ForeName>Andre</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Paran&#xe1;, Paran&#xe1;, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE-Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Fernando Roberto</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Lavras, Minas Gerais, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bertuzzi</LastName><ForeName>Romulo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endurance Performance Research Group (GEDAE-USP), University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lima-Silva</LastName><ForeName>Adriano Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Research Group, Federal University of Technology Paran&#xe1;, Paran&#xe1;, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001642" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bicycling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35969166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202209000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bowtell JL, Mohr M, Fulford J, et al. Improved exercise tolerance with caffeine is associated with modulation of both peripheral and central neural processes in human participants. Front Nutr . 2018;5:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silveira R, Andrade-Souza VA, Arcoverde L, et al. Caffeine increases work done above critical power, but not anaerobic work. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2018;50(1):131&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick J, Winter SL, Burnley M. Caffeine ingestion attenuates fatigue-induced loss of muscle torque complexity. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2018;50(2):236&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Nielsen JJ, Bangsbo J. Caffeine intake improves intense intermittent exercise performance and reduces muscle interstitial potassium accumulation. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2011;111(5):1372&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Kavouras SA. Caffeine use in sports, pharmacokinetics in man, and cellular mechanisms of action. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr . 2005;45(7&#x2013;8):535&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar JM, Cafarelli E. Effects of caffeine on neuromuscular function. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1999;87(2):801&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton C, Kalmar J, Cafarelli E. Caffeine increases spinal excitability in humans. Muscle Nerve . 2003;28(3):359&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felippe LC, Ferreira GA, Learsi SK, Boari D, Bertuzzi R, Lima-Silva AE. Caffeine increases both total work performed above critical power and peripheral fatigue during a 4-km cycling time trial. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2018;124(6):1491&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmonds MJ, Minahan CL, Sabapathy S. Caffeine improves supramaximal cycling but not the rate of anaerobic energy release. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2010;109(2):287&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J, Duncan MJ, James RS. What can isolated skeletal muscle experiments tell us about the effects of caffeine on exercise performance? Br J Pharmacol . 2015;172(15):3703&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Mau-Moeller A, Heise S, Skripitz R, Bader R, Bruhn S. Alteration in neuromuscular function of the plantar flexors following caffeine ingestion. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2015;25(1):e50&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Mau-Moeller A, Weippert M, et al. Caffeine-induced increase in voluntary activation and strength of the quadriceps muscle during isometric, concentric and eccentric contractions. Sci Rep . 2015;5:10209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neyroud D, Cheng AJ, Donnelly C, et al. Toxic doses of caffeine are needed to increase skeletal muscle contractility. Am J Phys Cell Phys . 2019;316(2):C246&#x2013;C51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Pickering C, Schoenfeld BJ, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z. Wake up and smell the coffee: caffeine supplementation and exercise performance - an umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses. Br J Sports Med . 2020;54(11):681&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima-Silva AE, Cristina-Souza G, Silva-Cavalcante MD, Bertuzzi R, Bishop DJ. Caffeine during high-intensity whole-body exercise: an integrative approach beyond the central nervous system. Nutrients . 2021;13(8):2503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas K, Goodall S, Stone M, Howatson G, St Clair Gibson A, Ansley L. Central and peripheral fatigue in male cyclists after 4-, 20-, and 40-km time trials. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2015;47(3):537&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romer LM, Dempsey JA. Effects of exercise-induced arterial hypoxaemia on limb muscle fatigue and performance. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol . 2006;33(4):391&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman RF, Stager JM. Caffeine stimulates ventilation in athletes with exercise-induced hypoxemia. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2008;40(6):1080&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen HB. Arterial desaturation during exercise in man: implication for O2 uptake and work capacity. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2003;13(6):339&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Romer LM, Pegelow DF, Jacques AJ, Hess CJ, Dempsey JA. Effects of arterial oxygen content on peripheral locomotor muscle fatigue. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2006;101(1):119&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Calbet JA. Convective oxygen transport and fatigue. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2008;104(3):861&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyers BM, Cafarelli E. Caffeine increases time to fatigue by maintaining force and not by altering firing rates during submaximal isometric contractions. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2005;99(3):1056&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weavil JC, Amann M. Neuromuscular fatigue during whole body exercise. Curr Opin Physiol . 2019;10:128&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Translating fatigue to human performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2016;48(11):2228&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hureau TJ, Weavil JC, Sidhu SK, et al. Ascorbate attenuates cycling exercise-induced neuromuscular fatigue but fails to improve exertional dyspnea and exercise tolerance in COPD. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2021;130(1):69&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey R, Aboodarda SJ, Kruger R, Culos-Reed SN, Temesi J, Millet GY. Neuromuscular fatigue during exercise: methodological considerations, etiology and potential role in chronic fatigue. Neurophysiol Clin . 2017;47(2):95&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences . 2nd ed. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; 1988. 567 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig CL, Marshall AL, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, et al. International physical activity questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2003;35(8):1381&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;hler E, Lachenmeier D, Schlegel K, Winkler G. Development of a tool to assess the caffeine intake among teenagers and young adults. Ernahrungs-Umschau . 2013;61(4):58&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Generalized equations for predicting body density of men. Br J Nutr . 1978;40(3):497&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romer LM, Haverkamp HC, Lovering AT, Pegelow DF, Dempsey JA. Effect of exercise-induced arterial hypoxemia on quadriceps muscle fatigue in healthy humans. Am J Phys Regul Integr Comp Phys . 2006;290(2):R365&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1982;14(5):377&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whipp BJ, Davis JA, Torres F, Wasserman K. A test to determine parameters of aerobic function during exercise. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol . 1981;50(1):217&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midgley AW, McNaughton LR, Polman R, Marchant D. Criteria for determination of maximal oxygen uptake: a brief critique and recommendations for future research. Sports Med . 2007;37(12):1019&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, St-Pierre DM, Perez D. Muscle inactivation: assessment of interpolated twitch technique. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1996;81(5):2267&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GY, Bachasson D, Temesi J, et al. Potential interests and limits of magnetic and electrical stimulation techniques to assess neuromuscular fatigue. Neuromuscul Disord . 2012;22(3 Suppl):S181&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strojnik V, Komi PV. Neuromuscular fatigue after maximal stretch-shortening cycle exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1998;84(1):344&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Husmann F, Gube M, et al. Intersession reliability of the interpolated twitch technique applied during isometric, concentric, and eccentric actions of the human knee extensor muscles. Muscle Nerve . 2017;56(2):324&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A, Poole D. Oxygen uptake kinetics in sport, exercise and medicine. J Sports Sci Med . 2005;4(1):84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whipp B, Rossiter H. The kinetics of oxygen uptake: physiological inferences from the parameters. In: Poole DC, Jones AM, editors. Oxygen Uptake Kinetics in Sport, Exercise and Medicine: Routledge . London: Routledge; 2005. pp. 62&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos PS, Felippe LC, Ferreira GA, et al. Caffeine increases peripheral fatigue in low- but not in high-performing cyclists. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2020;45(11):1208&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin V, Millet GY, Martin A, Deley G, Lattier G. Assessment of low-frequency fatigue with two methods of electrical stimulation. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2004;97(5):1923&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M. The effects of caffeine on the maximal accumulated oxygen deficit and short-term running performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 1998;8(2):95&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnley M, Jones AM. Power-duration relationship: physiology, fatigue, and the limits of human performance. Eur J Sport Sci . 2018;18(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M. Central and peripheral fatigue: interaction during cycling exercise in humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2011;43(11):2039&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2004;96(4):1486&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Muro M, Nagata A. Intramuscular and surface electromyogram changes during muscle fatigue. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1986;60(4):1179&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: a meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2005;15(2):69&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hureau TJ, Romer LM, Amann M. The &#x2018;sensory tolerance limit&#x2019;: a hypothetical construct determining exercise performance? Eur J Sport Sci . 2018;18(1):13&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond GH. Action of caffeine and aminophylline as respiratory stimulants in man. J Appl Physiol . 1949;2(1):16&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru&#xed;z-Moreno C, Lara B, Brito de Souza D, et al. Acute caffeine intake increases muscle oxygen saturation during a maximal incremental exercise test. Br J Clin Pharmacol . 2020;86(5):861&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels JW, Mol&#xe9; PA, Shaffrath JD, Stebbins CL. Effects of caffeine on blood pressure, heart rate, and forearm blood flow during dynamic leg exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1998;85(1):154&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA. High-and low-frequency fatigue revisited. Acta Physiol Scand . 1996;156(3):265&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerblad H, Bruton JD, Allen DG, L&#xe4;nnergren J. Functional significance of Ca2+ in long-lasting fatigue of skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2000;83(2&#x2013;3):166&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green HJ, Duhamel TA, Smith IC, et al. Muscle fatigue and excitation&#x2013;contraction coupling responses following a session of prolonged cycling. Acta Physiol . 2011;203(4):441&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J, James RS, Cox VM, Duncan MJ. The effect of a physiological concentration of caffeine on the endurance of maximally and submaximally stimulated mouse soleus muscle. J Physiol Sci . 2013;63(2):125&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky M, Cupido C. Caffeine potentiates low frequency skeletal muscle force in habitual and nonhabitual caffeine consumers. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2000;89(5):1719&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Place N, Lepers R, Deley G, Millet GY. Time course of neuromuscular alterations during a prolonged running exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2004;36(8):1347&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin V, Kerherv&#xe9; H, Messonnier LA, et al. Central and peripheral contributions to neuromuscular fatigue induced by a 24-h treadmill run. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2010;108(5):1224&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GY, Martin V, Martin A, Verg&#xe8;s S. Electrical stimulation for testing neuromuscular function: from sport to pathology. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2011;111(10):2489&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harms CA, Stager JM. Low chemoresponsiveness and inadequate hyperventilation contribute to exercise-induced hypoxemia. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1995;79(2):575&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JM, Olenick A, Eastep C, Winchester L. Caffeine influences cadence at lower but not higher intensity RPE-regulated cycling. Physiol Behav . 2017;169:46&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC, Allen GM, Butler JE, Taylor JL. Supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue: evidence for suboptimal output from the motor cortex. J Physiol . 1996;490(Pt 2):529&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shield A, Zhou S. Assessing voluntary muscle activation with the twitch interpolation technique. Sports Med . 2004;34(4):253&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruet M, Temesi J, Rupp T, Levy P, Verges S, Millet GY. Dynamics of corticospinal changes during and after high-intensity quadriceps exercise. Exp Physiol . 2014;99(8):1053&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froyd C, Millet GY, Noakes TD. The development of peripheral fatigue and short-term recovery during self-paced high-intensity exercise. J Physiol . 2013;591(5):1339&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>