<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">33587551</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nonplacebo Controls to Determine the Magnitude of Ergogenic Interventions: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1766</StartPage><EndPage>1777</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1766-1777</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002635</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Placebos are used as a control treatment that is meant to be indistinguishable from the active intervention. However, where substantive placebo effects may occur, studies that do not include a nonplacebo control arm may underestimate the overall effect of the intervention (active plus placebo components). This study aimed to determine the relative magnitude of the placebo effect associated with nutritional supplements (caffeine and extracellular buffers) by meta-analyzing data from studies containing both placebo and nonplacebo control sessions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Bayesian multilevel meta-analysis models were used to estimate pooled effects and express the placebo effect as a percentage of the overall intervention effect.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Thirty-four studies were included, with the median pooled effect size (ES0.5) indicating a very small (ES0.5 = 0.09 (95% credible interval (CrI), 0.01-0.17)) improvement in the performance of placebo compared with control. There was no moderating effect of exercise type (capacity or performance), exercise duration, or training status. The comparison between active intervention and control indicated a small to medium effect (ES0.5 = 0.37 (95% CrI, 0.20-0.56)). Expressed in relative terms, the placebo effect was equivalent to 25% (75% CrI, 16%-35%) and 59% (75% CrI, 34%-94%) of the total intervention effect for buffers and caffeine.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">These results demonstrate a very small but potentially important placebo effect with nutritional supplementation studies. A substantive proportion of supplement effects may be due to placebo effects, with the relative proportion influenced by the magnitude of the overall ergogenic effect. Where feasible, intervention studies should use nonplacebo control-arm comparators to identify the proportion of the effect estimated to come from placebo effects and avoid underestimating the overall benefits that the physiological plus psychobiological aspects associated with an intervention provide in the real world.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marticorena</LastName><ForeName>Felipe Miguel</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group, School of Physical Education and Sport, Rheumatology Division, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de Sao Paulo (University of S&#xe3;o Paulo), S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Arthur</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group, School of Physical Education and Sport, Rheumatology Division, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de Sao Paulo (University of S&#xe3;o Paulo), S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Luana Farias DE</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group, School of Physical Education and Sport, Rheumatology Division, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de Sao Paulo (University of S&#xe3;o Paulo), S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dolan</LastName><ForeName>Eimear</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group, School of Physical Education and Sport, Rheumatology Division, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de Sao Paulo (University of S&#xe3;o Paulo), S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gualano</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swinton</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saunders</LastName><ForeName>Bryan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010919">Placebos</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015990" MajorTopicYN="Y">Placebo Effect</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010919" MajorTopicYN="N">Placebos</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202108000-00025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis AJ, Hettinga F, Beedie C. You don&#x2019;t need to administer a placebo to elicit a placebo effect: social factors trigger neurobiological pathways to enhance sports performance. Eur J Sport Sci . 2020;20:302&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst P, Schipof-Godart L, Szabo A, et al. The placebo and nocebo effect on sports performance: a systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci . 2020;20:279&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, et al. IOC consensus statement: dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Br J Sports Med . 2018;52(7):439&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie CJ, Stuart EM, Coleman DA, Foad AJ. Placebo effects of caffeine on cycling performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2006;38(12):2159&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, de Oliveira LF, da Silva RP, et al. Placebo in sports nutrition: a proof-of-principle study involving caffeine supplementation. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2017;27(11):1240&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foad AJ, Beedie CJ, Coleman DA. Pharmacological and psychological effects of caffeine ingestion in 40-km cycling performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2008;40(1):158&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClung M, Collins D. &#x201c;Because I know it will!&#x201d;: placebo effects of an ergogenic aid on athletic performance. J Sport Exerc Psychol . 2007;29(3):382&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst P, Schipof-Godart L, Hettinga F, Roelands B, Beedie C. Improved 1000-m running performance and pacing strategy with caffeine and placebo: a balanced placebo design study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2019;1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG; Group P. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Open Med . 2009;3(3):e123&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouzzani M, Hammady H, Fedorowicz Z, Elmagarmid A. Rayyan&#x2014;a web and mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev . 2016;5(1):210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Elliott-Sale K, Artioli GG, et al. &#x3b2;-Alanine supplementation to improve exercise capacity and performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med . 2017;51(8):658&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson RM, Saunders B, Ball G, Harris R, Sale C. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on exercise performance: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sport Exer . 2012;44:446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;rdi M, K&#xf6;teles F, Hevesi K, B&#xe1;rdos G, Szabo A. Elite athletes&#x2019; attitudes towards the use of placebo-induced performance enhancement in sports. Eur J Sport Sci . 2015;15(4):315&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong J, Spaeth R, Cook A, et al. Are all placebo effects equal? Placebo pills, sham acupuncture, cue conditioning and their association. PloS one . 2013;8(7):e67485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Craen AJ, Tijssen JG, de Gans J, Kleijnen J. Placebo effect in the acute treatment of migraine: subcutaneous placebos are better than oral placebos. J Neurol . 2000;247(3):183&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Craen AJ, Roos PJ, de Vries AL, Kleijnen J. Effect of colour of drugs: systematic review of perceived effect of drugs and of their effectiveness. BMJ . 1996;313(7072):1624&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ . 2019;366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs SH, Black N. The feasibility of creating a checklist for the assessment of the methodological quality both of randomised and non-randomised studies of health care interventions. J Epidemiol Community Health . 1998;52(6):377&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB, DeShon RP. Combining effect size estimates in meta-analysis with repeated measures and independent-groups designs. Psychol Methods . 2002;7(1):105&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox DR. Principles of Statistical Inference . Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Castilla B, Jamshidi L, Declercq L, Beretvas SN, Onghena P, Van den Noortgate W. The application of meta-analytic (multi-level) models with multiple random effects: a systematic review. Behav Res Methods . 2020;52:2031&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawilowsky SS. New effect size rules of thumb. J Mod Appl Stat Method . 2009;8(2):597&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;rkner PC. brms: an R package for Bayesian multilevel models using Stan. J Stat Softw . 2017;80(1):28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman A. Prior distributions for variance parameters in hierarchical models. Bayesian Analysis . 2006;1(3):515&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelman A, Carlin JB, Stern HS, Rubin DB. Bayesian Data Analysis . Abingdon (UK): Taylor &amp; Francis; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridge CA, Jones MA. The effect of caffeine ingestion on 8 km run performance in a field setting. J Sports Sci . 2006;24(4):433&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke N, Baxter H, Fajemilua E. Coffee and caffeine ingestion have little effect on repeated sprint cycling in relatively untrained males. Sports (Basel) . 2016;4(3):45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan P, Witherbee KE, Peterson KM, Kerksick CM. Effect of carbohydrate, caffeine, and carbohydrate + caffeine mouth rinsing on intermittent running performance in collegiate male lacrosse athletes. J Strength Cond Res . 2017;31(9):2473&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flinn S, Gregory J, McNaughton LR, Tristram S, Davies P. Caffeine ingestion prior to incremental cycling to exhaustion in recreational cyclists. Int J Sports Med . 1990;11(3):188&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karayi&#x11f;it R, Ya&#x15f;li B&#xc7;, Karabiyik H, Koz M, Ers&#xf6;z G. Effect of serial caffeine mouth rinse on Wingate anaerobic performance. SPORMETRE . 2017;15(4):191&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mc Naughton LR, Lovell RJ, Siegler JC, Midgley AW, Sandstrom M, Bentley DJ. The effects of caffeine ingestion on time trial cycling performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness . 2008;48(3):320&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles JD, Coleman D, Tegerdine M, Swaine IL. The effects of caffeine ingestion on performance time, speed and power during a laboratory-based 1 km cycling time-trial. J Sports Sci . 2006;24(11):1165&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei S, Akbari K, Gahreman DE, et al. Caffeine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation alone or together improve karate performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2019;16(1):44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Venier S, Mikulic P. Both caffeine and placebo improve vertical jump performance compared with a nonsupplemented control condition. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2020;1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SR, Wiles J, Robbins J. The effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on 1500-m racing time. J Sports Sci . 1995;13(5):399&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr AJ, Slater GJ, Gore CJ, Dawson B, Burke LM. Reliability and effect of sodium bicarbonate: buffering and 2000-m rowing performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2012;7(2):152&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coombes J, McNaughton LR. Effects of bicarbonate ingestion on leg strength and power during isokinetic knee flexion and extension. J Strength Cond Res . 1993;7(4):241&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppoolse R, Barstow TJ, Stringer WW, Carithers E, Casaburi R. Effect of acute bicarbonate administration on exercise responses of COPD patients. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1997;29(6):725&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfinch J, Mc Naughton L, Davies P. Induced metabolic alkalosis and its effects on 400-m racing time. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1988;57(1):45&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffen C, Rogerson D, Ranchordas M, Ruddock A. Effects of creatine and sodium bicarbonate coingestion on multiple indices of mechanical power output during repeated Wingate tests in trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2015;25(3):298&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindh AM, Peyrebrune MC, Ingham SA, Bailey DM, Folland JP. Sodium bicarbonate improves swimming performance. Int J Sports Med . 2008;29(6):519&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Materko W, Santos E, Novaes JS. Effect of bicarbonate supplementation on the muscular strength. Med Sci Sport Exer . 2008;11(5):25&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan T, Jacobs I, Lewis W. Acute altitude exposure and altered acid&#x2013;base states. II. Effects on exercise performance and muscle and blood lactate. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1988;57(4):445&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR. Sodium citrate and anaerobic performance: implications of dosage. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1990;61(5&#x2013;6):392&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Curtin R, Goodman G, Perry D, Turner B, Showell C. Anaerobic work and power output during cycle ergometer exercise: effects of bicarbonate loading. J Sports Sci . 1991;9(2):151&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR. Bicarbonate ingestion: effects of dosage on 60 s cycle ergometry. J Sports Sci . 1992;10(5):415&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion and its effects on anaerobic exercise of various durations. J Sports Sci . 1992;10(5):425&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Cedaro R. Sodium citrate ingestion and its effects on maximal anaerobic exercise of different durations. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1992;64(1):36&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR, Ford S, Newbold C. Effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on high intensity exercise in moderately trained women. J Strength Cond Res . 1997;11(2):98&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Dalton B, Palmer G. Sodium bicarbonate can be used as an ergogenic aid in high-intensity, competitive cycle ergometry of 1 h duration. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1999;80(1):64&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller P, Robinson AL, Sparks SA, Bridge CA, Bentley DJ, McNaughton LR. The effects of novel ingestion of sodium bicarbonate on repeated sprint ability. J Strength Cond Res . 2016;30(2):561&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris DM, Shafer RS, Fairbrother KR, Woodall MW. Effects of lactate consumption on blood bicarbonate levels and performance during high-intensity exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2011;21(4):311&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira LF, de Salles Painelli V, Nemezio K, et al. Chronic lactate supplementation does not improve blood buffering capacity and repeated high-intensity exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2017;27(11):1231&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painelli Vde S, Roschel H, Jesus Fd, et al. The ergogenic effect of beta-alanine combined with sodium bicarbonate on high-intensity swimming performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2013;38(5):525&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce EF, Eastman NW, Hammer WH, Lynn TD. Effect of induced alkalosis on swimming time trials. J Sports Sci . 1992;10(3):255&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiryaki GR, Atterbom HA. The effects of sodium bicarbonate and sodium citrate on 600 m running time of trained females. J Sports Med Phys Fitness . 1995;35(3):194&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkes D, Gledhill N, Smyth R. Effect of acute induced metabolic alkalosis on 800-m racing time. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1983;15(4):277&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuinness LA, Higgins JPT. Risk-of-bias VISualization (robvis): an R package and shiny web app for visualizing risk-of-bias assessments. Res Synth Methods . 2021;12:55&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best R, McDonald K, Hurst P, Pickering C. Can taste be ergogenic? Eur J Nutr . 2020;60:45&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundh LG. Placebo, belief, and health. A cognitive&#x2013;emotion model. Scand J Psychol . 1987;28(2):128&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price DD, Finniss DG, Benedetti F. A comprehensive review of the placebo effect: recent advances and current thought. Annu Rev Psychol . 2008;59:565&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Saito T, Klosterhoff R, et al. &#x201c;I put it in my head that the supplement would help me&#x201d;: open-placebo improves exercise performance in female cyclists. PLoS One . 2019;14(9):e0222982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito T, Barreto G, Saunders B, Gualano B. Is open-label placebo a new ergogenic aid? A commentary on existing studies and guidelines for future research. Sports Med . 2020;50:1225&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Pickering C, Schoenfeld BJ, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z. Wake up and smell the coffee: caffeine supplementation and exercise performance-an umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses. Br J Sports Med . 2020;54:681&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie C, Benedetti F, Barbiani D, et al. Consensus statement on placebo effects in sports and exercise: the need for conceptual clarity, methodological rigour, and the elucidation of neurobiological mechanisms. Eur J Sport Sci . 2018;18(10):1383&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>