<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21156078</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of acute and prolonged CRAM supplementation on reaction time and subjective measures of focus and alertness in healthy college students.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39</StartPage><MedlinePgn>39</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-7-39</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The purpose of this study was to examine the effect of acute and prolonged (4-weeks) ingestion of a supplement designed to improve reaction time and subjective measures of alertness, energy, fatigue, and focus compared to placebo.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nineteen physically-active subjects (17 men and 2 women) were randomly assigned to a group that either consumed a supplement (21.1 &#xb1; 0.6 years; body mass: 80.6 &#xb1; 9.4 kg) or placebo (21.3 &#xb1; 0.8 years; body mass: 83.4 &#xb1; 18.5 kg). During the initial testing session (T1), subjects were provided 1.5 g of the supplement (CRAM; &#x3b1;-glycerophosphocholine, choline bitartrate, phosphatidylserine, vitamins B3, B6, and B12, folic acid, L-tyrosine, anhydrous caffeine, acetyl-L-carnitine, and naringin) or a placebo (PL), and rested quietly for 10-minutes before completing a questionnaire on subjective feelings of energy, fatigue, alertness and focus (PRE). Subjects then performed a 4-minute quickness and reaction test followed by a 10-min bout of exhaustive exercise. The questionnaire and reaction testing sequence was then repeated (POST). Subjects reported back to the lab (T2) following 4-weeks of supplementation and repeated the testing sequence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Reaction time significantly declined (p = 0.050) between PRE and POST at T1 in subjects consuming PL, while subjects under CRAM supplementation were able to maintain (p = 0.114) their performance. Significant performance declines were seen in both groups from PRE to POST at T2. Elevations in fatigue were seen for CRAM at both T1 and T2 (p = 0.001 and p = 0.000, respectively), but only at T2 for PL (p = 0.029). Subjects in CRAM maintained focus between PRE and POST during both T1 and T2 trials (p = 0.152 and p = 0.082, respectively), whereas significant declines in focus were observed between PRE and POST in PL at both trials (p = 0.037 and p = 0.014, respectively). No difference in alertness was seen at T1 between PRE and POST for CRAM (p = 0.083), but a significant decline was recorded at T2 (p = 0.005). Alertness was significantly lower at POST at both T1 and T2 for PL (p = 0.040 and p = 0.33, respectively). No differences in any of these subjective measures were seen between the groups at any time point.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Results indicate that acute ingestion of CRAM can maintain reaction time, and subjective feelings of focus and alertness to both visual and auditory stimuli in healthy college students following exhaustive exercise. However, some habituation may occur following 4-weeks of supplementation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Jay R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL 32816-1250, USA. jrhoffma@mail.ucf.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratamess</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beller</LastName><ForeName>Noah A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Mattan W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olson</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purpura</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J&#xe4;ger</LastName><ForeName>Ralf</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2010</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21156078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3009695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-39</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-7-39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Purpura M, Kingsley M. Phospholipids and sports performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1997116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amenta F, Tayebati SK. Pathwasy of acetylcholine synthesis, transport and release as targets for treatment of adult-onset cognitive dysfunction. Curr Med Chem. 2008;15:488&#x2013;498. doi: 10.2174/092986708783503203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/092986708783503203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18289004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchman AL, Sohel M, Brown M, Jenden DJ, Ahn C, Roch M, Brawley TL. Verbal and visual memory improve after choline supplementation in long-term total parenteral nutrition: a pilot study. J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2001;25:30&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1177/014860710102500130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/014860710102500130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11190987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canal N, Franceschi M, Alberoni M, Castiglioni C, De Moliner P, Longoni A. Effect of L-alpha-glyceryl-phoshorylcholine on amnesia caused by scopolamine. Int J Clin Pharmacol Ther Toxicol. 1991;29:103&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2071257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiPerri R, Coppola G, Ambrosio LA, Grasso A, Puca FM, Rizzo M. A multicentre trial to evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of alpha-glycerylphosphorylcholine versus cystosine diphosphocholine in patients with vascular dementia. J Int Med Res. 1991;19:330&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1916007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gossell-Williams M, Simon O, Young L, West M. Choline supplementation facilitates short-term memory consolidation into intermediate long-term memory of young Sprague-Dawley rats. West Indian Med J. 2006;55:4&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16755811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlay LA, Wurtman RJ, Blusztajn JK, Coviella ILG, Maher TJ, Evoniuk GE. Decreased plasma choline concentrations in marathon runners. N Engl J Med. 1986;315:892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3748109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penry JT, Manore MM. Choline: an important micronutrient for maximal endurance-exercise performance? Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18:191&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18458362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deuster PA, Singh A, Coll R, Hyde DE, Becker WJ. Choline ingestion does not modify physical or cognitive performance. Mil Med. 2002;167:1020&#x2013;1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12502178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warber JP, Patton JF, Tharion WJ, Zeisel SH, Mello RP, Kemnitz CP, Lieberman HR. The effects of choline supplementation on physical performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2000;10:170&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10861337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch MJ, Growdon JH, Wurtman RJ. Relations between dietary choline or lecithin intake, serum choline levels, and various metabolic indices. Metabolism. 1978;27:953&#x2013;960. doi: 10.1016/0026-0495(78)90139-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0026-0495(78)90139-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">672614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wurtman RJ, Hirsch MJ, Growdon JH. Lecithin consumption raises serum-free-choline levels. Lancet. 1977;2:68&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(77)90067-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(77)90067-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">69151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegenfuss T, Landis J, Hofheins J. Acute supplementation with alpha-glycerylphosphorylcholine augments growth hormone response to, and peak force production during, resistance exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2008;5(Suppl 1):P15. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-5-S1-P15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-5-S1-P15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blokland A, Honig W, Browns F, Jolles J. Cognition-enhancing properties of subchronic phosphatidylserine (ps) treatment in middle-aged rats: comparision of bovine cortex ps with eggs ps and soybean ps. Nutrition. 1999;15:778&#x2013;783. doi: 10.1016/S0899-9007(99)00157-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0899-9007(99)00157-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starks MA, Starks SL, Kingsley M, Purpura M, J&#xe4;ger R. The effects of phosphotidylserine on endocrine response to moderate intensity exercise. J Inter Soc Sports Nutr. 2008;5:11. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-5-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-5-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2503954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18662395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh ML, Fadok VA, Henson PM. Phosphatidylserine-dependent ingestion of apoptotic cells promotes tgf-&#x3b2;1 secretion and the resolution of inflammation. J Clin Invest. 2002;109:41&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC150814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11781349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteleone P, Beinat L, Tanzillo C, Maj M, Kemall D. Effects of phosphatidylserine on the neuroendocrine response to physical stress in humans. Neuroendocrinology. 1990;52:243&#x2013;248. doi: 10.1159/000125593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000125593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2170852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dacaranhe CD, Terao J. A unique antioxidant activity of phosphatidylserine on iron-induced lipid peroxidation of phospholipid bilayers. Lipids. 2001;36:1105&#x2013;1110. doi: 10.1007/s11745-001-0820-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11745-001-0820-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11768154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lactorraca S, Piersanti P, Tesco G, Piacentini S, Amaducci L, Sorbi S. Effect of phosphatidylserine on free radical susceptibility in human diploid fibroblasts. J Neural Transm Park Dis Dement Sect. 1993;6:73&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1007/BF02252625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02252625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8216761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley M, Wadsworth D, Kilduff LP, McEneny J, Benton D. Effects of phosphatidylserine on oxidative stress following intermittent running. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1300&#x2013;1306. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000175306.05465.7e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000175306.05465.7e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16118575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley M, Miller M, Kilduff LP, McEneny J, Benton D. Effects of phosphatidylserine on exercise capacity during cycling in active males. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:64&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000183195.10867.d0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000183195.10867.d0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16394955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley M, Kilduff LP, McEneny J, Dietzig R, Benton D. Phosphatidylserine supplementation and recovery following downhill running. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:1617&#x2013;1625. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000183195.10867.d0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000183195.10867.d0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KA, Hicks G, Nino-Murcia G. Validity and reliability of a scale to assess fatigue. Psychiatry Res. 1991;36:291&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1016/0165-1781(91)90027-M.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(91)90027-M</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haubrich DR, Wang PFL, Clody DE, Wedeking PW. Increase in rat brain acetylcholine induced by choline or deanol. Life Sci. 1975;17:975&#x2013;980. doi: 10.1016/0024-3205(75)90451-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0024-3205(75)90451-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1195991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trammer BA, Schmidt DE, Wecker L. Exogenous choline enhances the synthesis of acetylcholine only under conditions of increased cholinergic neuronal activity. J Neurochem. 1982;39:1704&#x2013;1709. doi: 10.1111/j.1471-4159.1982.tb08006.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1471-4159.1982.tb08006.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7142996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spector SA, Jackman MR, Sabounjian LA, Sakkas C, Landers DM, Willis WT. Effect of choline supplementation on fatigue in trained cyclists. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27:668&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7674870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlay LA, Sabounjian LA, Wurtman RJ. Exercise and neuromodulators: choline and acetylcholine in marathon runners. Int J Sports Med. 1992;13:S141&#x2013;S142. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1024619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1024619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1483754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Allworden HN, Horn S, Kahl J, Feldheim W. The influence of lecithin on plasma choline concentrations in triathletes and adolescent runners during exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1993;67:87&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1007/BF00377711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00377711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8375373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno MDJM. Cognitive improvement in mild to moderate alzheimer's dementia after treatment with the acetylcholine precursor choline alfoscerate: A multicenter, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Ther. 2003;25:178&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1016/S0149-2918(03)90023-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0149-2918(03)90023-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12637119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton D, Donohoe RT, Silance B, Nabb S. The influence of phosphatidylserine supplementation on mood and heart rate when faced with an acute stressor. Nutr Neurosci. 2001;4:169&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11842886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Purpura M, Geiss KR, Wei&#xdf; M, Baumeister J, Amatulli F, Schr&#xf6;der L, Herwegen H. The effect of phosphatidylserine on golf performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2217563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18053194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, French DN, Rubin MR, Sharman MJ, G&#xf3;mez AL, Ratamess NA, Newton RU, Jemiolo B, Craig BW, H&#xe4;kkinen K. The effects of L-carnitine L-tartrate supplementation on hormonal responses to resistance exercise and recovery. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:455&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12930169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Kraemer WJ, Rubin MR, G&#xf3;mez AL, Ratamess NA, Gaynor P. L-Carnitine L-tartrate supplementation favorably affects markers of recovery from exercise stress. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2002;282:E474&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11788381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR. Caffeine and Energy Drinks. Strength and Cond J. 2010;12:15&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181bdafa0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181bdafa0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachan DS, Hongu N. Increases in VO2max and metabolic markers of fat oxidation by caffeine, carnitine, and choline supplementation in rats. J Nutr Biochem. 2000;11:521&#x2013;526. doi: 10.1016/S0955-2863(00)00119-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0955-2863(00)00119-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11120451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchy J, Chan A, Shea TB. Dietary supplementation with a combination of &#x3b1;-lipoic acid, acetyl-L-carnitine, glycerophosphocoline, docosahexaenoic acid, and phosphatidylserine reduces oxidative damage to murine brain and improves cognitive performance. Nutr Res. 2009;29:70&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2008.11.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2008.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19185780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidd PM. Neurodegeneration from mitochondrial insufficiency: nutrients, stem cells, growth factors, and prospects for brain rebuilding using integrative management. Altern Med Rev. 2005;10:268&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16366737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhitavat S, Ortiz D, Shea TB, Rivera ER. Acetyl-L-carnitine protects against amyloid-beta neurotoxicity: roles of oxidative buffering and ATP levels. Neurochem Res. 2002;27:501&#x2013;505. doi: 10.1023/A:1019800703683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1019800703683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12199155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>