<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24303144</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-817X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>1</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiological reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of the ergogenic effect of caffeine supplementation on mood, anticipation timing, and muscular strength in older adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e00072</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e00072</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e00072</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/phy2.72</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The effect of caffeine to promote improvements in mood, cognition, and exercise performance has been well established in young and athletic adults. However, little is known about whether such nutritional ergogenic aids are effective in enhancing psychological well-being, physiological or cognitive performance in older adults. This study assesses the ergogenic effect of caffeine on mood, perceptual-motor coupling, and muscular strength in an older human population. Following a familiarization session, 12 apparently healthy volunteers (nine females and three males; 69 &#xb1; 6 years) completed two laboratory visits. "Pre ingestion" trials of mood state Brunel Mood State Inventory (BRUMS) and coincidence anticipation performance (Bassin anticipation timer) at slow (3 mph) and fast (8 mph) stimulus speeds were completed on both visits. Using a randomized, double-blind, cross-over design, participants consumed either caffeine (3 mg/kg body mass) or a placebo. Sixty minutes postingestion participants repeated the trials before completing a set of 10 consecutive repetitions of maximal knee extension using isokinetic dynamometry. Rating of perceived exertion (RPE) was assessed following the fifth and final repetition. Caffeine ingestion significantly improved mood state scores for vigor by 17% (P = 0.009) and reduced absolute error by 35% (P = 0.045) during coincidence anticipation assessment at 8 mph compared to placebo. There were no other significant effects. Caffeine ingestion failed to augment maximal voluntary contraction of the knee extensors and RPE did not prove to be significantly different to from placebo (P &gt; 0.33 in each case). Acute caffeine ingestion may not be an effective ergogenic aid for improving muscular strength in older adults but could possibly be used as a nutrition supplement for enhancing mood and improving cognitive performance in daily living tasks where interceptive timing skills are required.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tallis</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomolecular and Sport Sciences, Coventry University James Starley Building, Priory Street, Coventry, CV1 5FB, U.K.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duncan</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wright</LastName><ForeName>Sheila Leddington</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eyre</LastName><ForeName>Emma L J</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bryant</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langdon</LastName><ForeName>Dominic</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>James</LastName><ForeName>Rob S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101607800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-817X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anticipation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isokinetic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maximal voluntary contraction</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24303144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3835022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/phy2.72</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Ormsbee MJ. Relationship of blood pressure, behavioural mood state and physical activity following caffeine ingestion in younger and older women. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 2009;34:754&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19767812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Roberson DW. Efficacy of acute caffeine ingestion for short-term high-intensity exercise performance: a systematic review. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2010;24:257&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19924012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Rohmann RL, Firth K. Effect of caffeine ingestion on one-repetition maximum muscular strength. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2008;102:127&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17851681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Terzi MN, Roberson DW, Burnett TR. Effect of two doses of caffeine on muscular function during isokinetic exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2010;24:2205&#x2013;2210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20421833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Martin BJ, Schachtsiek L, Wong K, Ng K. Minimal effect of acute caffeine ingestion on intense resistance training performance. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2011;25:1752&#x2013;1758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21293304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell DG, Mclellan TM. Exercise endurance 1, 3, and 6 hours after caffeine ingestion in caffeine users and non-users. J. Appl. Physiol. 2002;93:1227&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BHF. 2013.  Physical activity guidelines for older adults (Online). BHF National Centre Physical Activity + Health.  http://www.bhfactive.org.uk/olderadultsguidelines/index.html (accessed 24 July 2013)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Perceived exertion as an indicator of somatic stress. Scand. J. Rehabil. Med. 1970;2:92&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5523831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brice C, Smith A. The effects of caffeine on simulated driving, subjective alertness and sustained attention. Hum. Psychopharmacol. 2001;16:523&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12404548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherniak EP. Ergogenic dietary aids for the elderly. Nutrition. 2012;22:225&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22189194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JK, Green JM. Caffeine and anaerobic performance: ergogenic value and mechanisms of action. Sports Med. 2009;39:813&#x2013;832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19757860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbono O, O'Rourke KS, Ettinger WH. Excitation-calcium release uncoupling in aged single human skeletal muscle fibers. J. Membr. Biol. 1995;148:211&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8747553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: a meta-analysis. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 2005;15:69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15773860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Oxford SW. The effect of caffeine ingestion on mood state and bench press performance to failure. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2011;25:178&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21157384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Smith M, Lyons M. The effect of exercise intensity on coincidence anticipation performance at different stimulus speeds. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2013 In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24050474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Einother S, Giesbrect T. Caffeine as an attention enhancer: revising existing assumptions. Psychopharmacology. 2013;225:251&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23241646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleury M, Bard C. Age, stimulus velocity and task complexity as determiners of coincident timing behaviour. J. Hum. Mov. Studies. 1985;11:305&#x2013;317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Chomentowski P, Ward BK, Rossi A, Glynn NW, Delmonico MJ, et al. Effects of physical activity on strength and skeletal muscle fat infiltration in older adults: a randomized controlled trial. J. Appl. Physiol. 2008;105:1498&#x2013;1503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2584841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18818386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Caffeine and exercise. Metabolism, endurance and performance. Sports Med. 2001;31:785&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11583104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haywood KM. Coincidence-anticipation accuracy across the life span. Exp. Aging Res. 1980;6:451&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7227412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacs LD, Pohlman RL. Effects of exercise intensity on an accompanying timing task. J. Hum. Mov. Studies. 1991;20:123&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs I, Pasternal H, Bell DG. Effects of ephedrine, caffeine, and their combination on muscular endurance. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2003;35:987&#x2013;994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MB, Norager CB, Fenger-Gron M, Weimann A, Moller N, Madsen MR, et al. Caffeine supplementation had no effect on endurance capacity on elderly subjects who had abstained from caffeine-containing nutrition of 8 hours. J. Caff. Res. 2011;1:109&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones G. Caffeine and other sympathomimetic stimulants: modes of action and effects on sports performance. Essays Biochem. 2008;44:109&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18384286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahneman D. Attention and effort. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall; 1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar JM, Cafarelli E. Caffeine: a valuable tool to study central fatigue in humans? Exerc. Sport Sci. Rev. 2004;32:143&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15604932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keisler BD, Armsey TD. Caffeine as an ergogenic aid. Curr. Sports Med. Rep. 2006;5:215&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16822345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenemans JL, Verbaten MN. Caffeine and visuo-spatial attention. Psychopharmacology. 1998;135:353&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9539259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobjos R, Benguigui N, Bertch J. The effect of aging and tennis playing on coincidence-timing accuracy. J. Aging Phys. Act. 2006;14:74&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16648653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorist MM, Snel J, Gijsbertus M, Kok A. Aging, caffeine, and information processing: an event-related potential analysis. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1995;96:453&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7555918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons M, Al-Nakeeb Y, Nevill A. The effect of moderate and high intensity fatigue on coincidence anticipation in expert and novice Gaelic games players. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2008;8:205&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Keen P. Effect of exercise on simple reaction times of recreational athletes. Percept. Mot. Skills. 1994;78:123&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8177649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeuwsen HJ, Goode SL, Goggin NL. Effects of aging on coincidence anticipation timing in females. J. Aging Phys. Act. 1997;5:285&#x2013;297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momsen AH, Hensen MB, Norager CB, Madsen MR, Vestergaard-Anderson T, Lindholt JS. Randomized double-blind placebo-controlled crossover study of caffeine in patients with intermittent claudication. Br. J. Surg. 2010;97:1503&#x2013;1510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20629111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehlig A. Is caffeine a cognitive enhancer? J. Alzheimers Dis. 2010;20:S85&#x2013;S94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20182035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norager CB, Jensen MB, Madsen MR, Laurberg S. Caffeine improves endurance in 75-yr-old citizens; a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study. J. Appl. Physiol. 2005;99:2302&#x2013;2306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallar&#xe9;s JG, Fern&#xe1;ndez VE, Ortega JF, Munoz G, Munoz-Guerra J, Mora-Rodriguez R. Neuromuscular responses to incremental caffeine doses: performance and side effects. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2013 [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23669879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne VG. The effects of stimulus runway length on coincidence anticipation timing performance. J. Hum. Mov. Studies. 1986;12:289&#x2013;295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renganathan M, Messi ML, Delbono O. Dihydropyride receptor-ryanodine receptor uncoupling in aged skeletal muscle. J. Membr. Biol. 1997;157:247&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9178612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein AL, Wughalter EH. Motor learning. American alliance for health, physical education, recreation, and dance. Reston, VA: 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders G. Sex differences in coincidence anticipation timing (CAT): a review. Percept. Mot. Skills. 2011;112:61&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21466081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt RA. Motor control and learning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AP. Caffeine, performance, mood and status of reduced alertness. Pharmacopsychoecologia. 1994;7:75&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A. Effects of caffeine on human behavior. Food Chem. Toxicol. 2002;40:1243&#x2013;1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12204388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BD, Tola K. Caffeine: effects on psychological functioning and performance. In: Spiller GA, editor. Caffeine. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press; 1998. pp. 251&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelmach GE, Nahom A. Cognitive motor abilities of the elderly drivers. Hum. Factors. 1992;34:53&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1577503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift CG, Tiplady B. The effects of age on the response to caffeine. Psychopharmacology. 1988;94:29&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3126525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taguchi N, Higaki Y, Inoue S, Kimura H, Tanaka K. Effects of a 12-monthmulticomponent exercise program on physical performance, daily physical activity, and quality of life in very elderly people with minor disabilities: an intervention study. J. Epidemiol. 2010;20:21&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19897943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J. U.K: Coventry University; 2013. Effects of physiological caffeine concentration on isolated muscle force, power and fatigue resistance. [Ph.D. Thesis]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J, James RS, Cox VM, Duncan MJ. The effect of physiological concentrations of caffeine on the power output of maximally and sub maximally stimulated mouse EDL (fast) and soleus (slow) muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2012;112:64&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21979804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry PC, Lane AM. Development of normative data for the profile of mood states for use with athletic samples. J. Appl. Sport Psych. 2000;12:69&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry P, Lane A. User guide for the Brunel Mood State Inventory (BRUMS) Queensland, Australia: University of Southern Australia; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry PC, Lane AM, Lane HJ, Keohane L. Development and validation of a mood measure for adolescents. J. Sports Sci. 1999;17:861&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10585166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry PC, Lane AM, Fogarty GJ. Construct validity of the Profile of Mood States &#x2013; Adolescents for use with adults. Psychol. Sport Exerc. 2003;4:125&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Duinen H, Lorist MM, Zijdewind I. The effect of caffeine on cognitive task performance and motor fatigue. Psychopharmacology. 2005;180:539&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15723227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gelder BM, Buijsee B, Tijhuis M, Kalminj S, Giampaoli S, Nissinen A, et al. Coffee consumption is inversely associated with cognitive decline in elderly European men: the FINE Study. Eur. J. Clin. Nutr. 2007;61:226&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16929246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren GL, Park ND, Maresca RD, Mckibans KI, Millard-Stafford ML. Effects of caffeine ingestion on muscular strength and endurance: a meta-analysis. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1375&#x2013;1387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>