<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34472160</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>106</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiological complexity: influence of ageing, disease and neuromuscular fatigue on muscle force and torque fluctuations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2046</StartPage><EndPage>2059</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2046-2059</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP089711</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="NEW FINDINGS">What is the topic of this review? Physiological complexity in muscle force and torque fluctuations, specifically the quantification of complexity, how neuromuscular complexityis altered by perturbations and the potential mechanism underlying changes in neuromuscular complexity. What advances does it highlight? The necessity to calculate both magnitude- and complexity-based measures for the thorough evaluation of force/torque fluctuations. Also the need for further research on neuromuscular complexity, particularly how it relates to the performance of functional activities (e.g. manual dexterity, balance, locomotion).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT">Physiological time series produce inherently complex fluctuations. In the last 30&#xa0;years, methods have been developed to characterise these fluctuations, and have revealed that they contain information about the function of the system producing them. Two broad classes of metrics are used: (1) those which quantify the regularity of the signal (e.g. entropy metrics); and (2) those which quantify the fractal properties of the signal (e.g. detrended fluctuation analysis). Using these techniques, it has been demonstrated that ageing results in a loss of complexity in the time series of a multitude of signals, including heart rate, respiration, gait and, crucially, muscle force or torque output. This suggests that as the body ages, physiological systems become less adaptable (i.e. the systems' ability to respond rapidly to a changing external environment is diminished). More recently, it has been shown that neuromuscular fatigue causes a substantial loss of muscle torque complexity, a process that can be observed in a few minutes, rather than the decades it requires for the same system to degrade with ageing. The loss of torque complexity with neuromuscular fatigue appears to occur exclusively above the critical torque (at least for tasks lasting up to 30&#xa0;min). The loss of torque complexity can be exacerbated with previous exercise of the same limb, and reduced by the administration of caffeine, suggesting both peripheral and central mechanisms contribute to this loss. The mechanisms underpinning the loss of complexity are not known but may be related to altered motor unit behaviour as the muscle fatigues.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Experimental Physiology &#xa9; 2021 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pethick</LastName><ForeName>Jamie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1547-9459</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Rehabilitation and Exercise Sciences, University of Essex, Colchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Winter</LastName><ForeName>Samantha L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burnley</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3407-561X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endurance Research Group, School of Sport and Exercise Sciences, University of Kent, Chatham Maritime, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="Y">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019415" MajorTopicYN="N">Torque</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ageing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complexity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fractal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle force/torque</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular fatigue</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34472160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP089711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adam, A., &amp; De Luca, C. J. (2005). Firing rates of motor units in human vastus lateralis muscle during fatiguing isometric contractions. Journal of Applied Physiology, 99, 268-280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann, M., &amp; Dempsey, J. A. (2008). Locomotor muscle-fatigue modifies central motor drive in healthy humans and imposes a limitation to exercise performance. Journal of Physiology, 586, 161-173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arjunan, S. P., &amp; Kumar, D. K. (2013). Age-associated changes in muscle activity during isometric contraction. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 47, 545-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beretta-Piccoli, M., D'Antona, G., Barbero, M., Fisher, B., Dieli-Conwright, C. M., Clijsen, R., &amp; Cescon, C. (2015). Evaluation of central and peripheral fatigue in the quadriceps using fractal dimension and conduction velocity un young females. PLoS One, 10, e0123921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boccia, G., Dardanello, D., Beretta-Piccoli, M., Cescon, C., Coratella, G., Rinaldo, N., Barbero, M., Lanza, M., Schena, F., &amp; Rainoldi, A. (2015). Muscle fiber conduction velocity and fractal dimension of EMG during fatiguing contraction of young and elderly active men. Physiological Measurement, 37, 162-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce, E. N. (1996). Temporal variations in the pattern of breathing. Journal of Applied Physiology, 80, 1079-1087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnley, M., Vanhatalo, A., &amp; Jones, A. M. (2012). Distinct profiles of neuromuscular fatigue during muscle contractions below and above the critical torque in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 113, 215-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzzi, U. H., Stergiou, N., Kurz, M. J., Hageman, P. A., &amp; Heidel, J. (2003). Nonlinear dynamics indicates aging affects variability during gait. Clinical Biomechanics, 18, 435-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carnavale, B. F., Fiogb&#xe9;, E., Farche, A. C. S., Catai, A. M., Porta, A., &amp; Takahashi, A. C. M. (2020). Complexity of knee extensor torque in patients with frailty syndrome: a cross-sectional study. Brazilian Journal of Physical Therapy, 24, 30-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpentier, A., Duchateau, J., &amp; Hainaut, K. (2001). Motor unit behaviour and contractile changes during fatigue in the human first dorsal interosseus. Journal of Physiology, 534, 903-912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashaback, J. G., Cluff, T., &amp; Potvin, J. R. (2013). Muscle fatigue and contraction intensity modulates the complexity of surface electromyography. Journal of Electromyography &amp; Kinesiology, 23, 78-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castronovo, A. M., Mrachacz-Kersting, N., Stevenson, A. J. T., Holobar, A., Enoka, R. M., &amp; Farina, D. (2018). Decrease in force steadiness with aging is associated with increased power of the common but not independent input to motor neurons. Journal of Neurophysiology, 120, 1616-1624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castronovo, A. M., Negro, F., Conforto, S., &amp; Farina, D. (2015). The proportion of common synaptic input to motor neurons increases with an increase in net excitatory input. Journal of Applied Physiology, 119, 1337-1346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Challis, J. H. (2006). Aging, regularity and variability in maximum isometric moments. Journal of Biomechanics, 39, 1543-1546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow, J. W., &amp; Stokic, D. S. (2014). Variability, frequency composition, and complexity of submaximal isometric knee extension force from subacute to chronic stroke. Neuroscience, 273, 189-198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes, N., Onate, J., &amp; Morrison, S. (2014). Differential effects of fatigue on movement variability. Gait &amp; Posture, 39, 888-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa, M., Goldberger, A. L., &amp; Peng, C. K. (2002). Multiscale entropy analysis of complex physiologic time series. Physical Review Letters, 89, p068102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Montecinos, C., Calatyud, J., Iturriaga, C., Bustos, C., Mena, B., Espa&#xf1;a-Romero, V., &amp; Carpes, F. P. (2018). Influence of a self-regulated cognitive dual task on time to failure and complexity of submaximal isometric force control. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 118, 2021-2027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, L. A., Allen, S. P., Hamilton, L. D., Grabowski, A. M., &amp; Enoka, R. M. (2020). Differences in postural sway among healthy adults are associated with the ability to perform steady contractions with leg muscles. Experimental Brain Research, 238, 487-497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca, C. J., LeFever, R. S., McCue, M. P., &amp; Xenakis, A. P. (1982). Behaviour of human motor units in different muscles during linearly varying contractions. Journal of Physiology, 329, 113-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enders, H., Von Tscharner, V., &amp; Nigg, B. M. (2015). Neuromuscular strategies during cycling at different muscular demands. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 47, 1450-1459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka, R. M., Christou, E. A., Hunter, S. K., Kornatz, K. W., Semmler, J. G., Taylor, A. M., &amp; Tracy, B. L. (2003). Mechanisms that contribute to differences in motor performance between young and old adults. Journal of Electromyography &amp; Kinesiology, 13, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina, D., &amp; Negro, F. (2015). Common synaptic input to motor neurons, motor unit synchronization, and force control. Exercise &amp; Sport Science Reviews, 43, 23-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feeney, D. F., Mani, D., &amp; Enoka, R. M. (2018). Variability in common synaptic input to motor neurons modulates both force steadiness and pegboard times in young and older adults. Journal of Physiology, 596, 3793-3806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiogb&#xe9;, E., Vassimon-Barroso, V., Catai, A. M., de Melo, R. C., Quit&#xe9;rio, R. J., Porta, A., &amp; Takahashi, A. C. M. (2021). Complexity of knee extensor torque: Effect of aging and contraction intensity. Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research, 35, 1050-1057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flood, M. W., Jensen, B. R., Malling, A. S., &amp; Lowery, M. M. (2019). Increased EMG intermuscular coherence and reduced signal complexity in Parkinson's disease. Clinical Neurophysiology, 130, 259-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitts, P. M. (1954). The information capacity of the human motor system in controlling the amplitude of movement. Journal of Experimental Psychology, 47, 381-391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forestier, N., &amp; Nougier, V. (1998). The effects of muscular fatigue on the coordination of a multijoint movement in human. Neuroscience Letters, 252, 187-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrest, S. M., Challis, J. H., &amp; Winter, S. L. (2014). The effect of signal acquisition and processing choices in ApEn values: Towards a &#x201c;gold standard&#x201d; for distinguishing effort levels from isometric force records. Medical Engineering &amp; Physics, 36, 676-683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia, S. C. (2001). Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiological Reviews, 81, 1725-1789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitter, J. A., &amp; Czerniecki, M. J. (1995). Fractal analysis of the electromyographic interference pattern. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 58, 103-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberger, A. L., Amaral, L. A., Hausdorff, J. M., Ivanov, P. C., Peng, C. K., &amp; Stanley, H. E. (2002a). Fractal dynamics in physiology: alterations with disease and aging. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, USA, 99, 2466-2472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberger, A. L., Peng, C. K., &amp; Lipsitz, L. A. (2002b). What is physiologic complexity and how does it change with aging and disease? Neurobiology of Aging, 23, 23-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliday, D. M., Conway, B. A., Farmer, S. F., &amp; Rosenberg, J. R. (1999). Load-independent contributions from motor-unit synchronization to human physiological tremor. Journal of Neurophysiology, 82, 664-675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton, A. F. C., Jones, K. E., &amp; Wolpert, D. M. (2004). The scaling of motor noise with muscle strength and motor unit number in humans. Experimental Brain Research, 157, 417-430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausdorff, J. M., Peng, C. K., Ladin, Z. V. I., Wei, J. Y., &amp; Goldberger, A. L. (1995). Is walking a random walk? Evidence for long-range correlations in stride interval of human gait. Journal of Applied Physiology, 78, 349-358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter, S. K., &amp; Enoka, R. M. (2003). Changes in muscle activation can prolong the endurance time of a submaximal isometric contraction in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 94, 108-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hureau, T. J., Romer, L. M., &amp; Amann, M. (2018). The &#x201c;sensory tolerance limit&#x201d;: A hypothetical construct determining exercise performance? European Journal of Sport Science, 18, 13-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, K. E., Hamilton, A. F. C., &amp; Wolpert, D. M. (2002). Sources of signal-dependent noise during isometric force production. Journal of Neurophysiology, 88, 1533-1544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, H. G., Costa, M. D., Priplata, A. A., Starobinets, O. V., Goldberger, A. L., Peng, C. K., Kiely, D. K., Cupples, L. A., &amp; Lipsitz, L. A. (2009). Frailty and the degradation of complex balance dynamics during a dual-task protocol. Journal of Gerontology, 64, 1304-1311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, H. G., &amp; Dingwell, J. B. (2016). Differential changes with age in multiscale entropy of electromyography signals from leg muscles during treadmill walking. PLoS One, 11, e0162034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan, D. T., Furman, M. I., Pincus, S. M., Ryan, S. M., Lipsitz, L. A., &amp; Goldberger, A. L. (1991). Aging and the complexity of cardiovascular dynamics. Biophysics Journal, 59, 945-949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenan, K. G., Farina, D., Merletti, R., &amp; Enoka, R. M. (2006). Amplitude cancellation reduces the size of motor unit potentials averaged from the surface EMG. Journal of Applied Physiology, 100, 1928-1937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keogh, J. W., Morrison, S., &amp; Barrett, R. (2007). Strength training improves the tri-digit finger-pinch force control of older adults. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 88, 1055-1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsitz, L. A. (2002). Dynamics of stability: the physiology basis of functional health and frailty. Journal of Gerontology, 57, B115-B125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsitz, L. A., &amp; Goldberger, A. L. (1992). Loss of &#x201c;complexity&#x201d; and aging: potential applications of fractals and chaos theory to senescence. Journal of the American Medical Association, 267, 1806-1809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macklem, P. T. (2009). Emergent phenomena and the secrets of life. Journal of Applied Physiology, 104, 1844-1846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;kikallio, T. H., H&#xf8;iber, S., K&#xf8;ber, L., Torp-Pedersen, C., Peng, C. K., Goldberger, A. L., Huikuri, H. V., &amp; Trace Investigators (1999). Fractal analysis of heart rate dynamics as a predictor of mortality in patients with depressed left ventricular function after acute myocardial infarction. American Journal of Cardiology, 83, 836-839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandelbrot, B. (1967). How long is the coast of Britain? Statistical self-similarity and fractional dimension. Science, 156, 636-638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor, B., Costa, M. D., Hu, K., Newton, E, Starobinets, O, Kang, H. G., Peng, C. K., Novak, V., &amp; Lipsitz, L. A. (2010). Physiological complexity and system adaptability: Evidence from postural control dynamics of older adults. Journal of Applied Physiology, 109, 1786-1791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manor, B., &amp; Lipsitz, L. A. (2013). Physiological complexity and aging: Implications for physical function and rehabilitation. Progress in Neuro-psychopharmacology &amp; Biological Psychiatry, 45, 287-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Valdes, E., Negro, F., Falla, D., Dideriksen, J. L., Heckman, C. J., &amp; Farina, D. (2020). Inability to increase the neural drive to muscle is associated with task failure during submaximal contractions. Journal of Neurophysiology, 124, 1110-1121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley, J. H., &amp; Marsden, C. D. (2000). Physiological and pathological tremors and rhythmic central motor control. Brain, 123, 1545-1567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus, L., Flood, M. W., &amp; Lowery, M. M. (2019). Beta-band motor unit coherence and nonlinear surface EMG features of the first dorsal interosseous muscle vary with force. Journal of Neurophysiology, 122, 1147-1162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesin, L., Cescon, C., Gazzoni, M., Merletti, R., &amp; Rainoldi, A. (2009). A bi-dimensional index for the selective assessment of myoelectric manifestations of peripheral and central muscle fatigue. Journal of Electromyography &amp; Kinesiology, 19, 851-863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison, S., &amp; Newell, K. M. (2012). Aging, neuromuscular decline, and the change in physiological and behavioral complexity of upper-limb movement dynamics. Journal of Aging Research, 2012, 891218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison, S., Sosnoff, J. J., Sandroff, B. M., Pula, J. H., &amp; Motl, R. W. (2013). The dynamics of finger tremor in multiple sclerosis is affected by whole body position. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 324, 84-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negro, F., Holobar, A., &amp; Farina, D. (2009). Fluctuations in isometric muscle force can be described by one linear projection of low-frequency components of motor unit discharge rates. Journal of Physiology, 587, 5925-5938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newell, K. M. (2020). What are the fundamental motor skills and what is fundamental about them? Journal of Motor Learning and Development, 8, 280-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oomen, N. M., &amp; van Di&#xeb;en, J. H. (2017). Effects of age on force steadiness: a literature review and meta-analysis. Aging Research Reviews, 35, 312-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, C. K., Buldyrev, S. V., Havlin, S., Simons, M., Stanley, H. E., &amp; Goldberger, A. L. (1994). Mosaic organization of DNA nucleotides. Physical Review, 49, 1685-1689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, C. K., Costa, M., &amp; Goldberger, A. L. (2009). Adaptive data analysis of complex fluctuations in physiologic time series. Advances in Adaptive Data Analysis, 1, 61-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Casselton, C., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2021a). Ischaemic pre-conditioning attenuates fatigue-induced loss of knee extensor torque complexity. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 53, 306-315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2015). Fatigue reduces the complexity of knee extensor torque fluctuations during maximal and submaximal intermittent isometric contractions in man. Journal of Physiology, 593, 2085-2096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2016). Loss of knee extensor torque complexity during fatiguing isometric muscle contractions occurs exclusively above the critical torque. American Journal of Physiology, 310, R1144-R1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2018a). Effects of ipsilateral and contralateral fatigue and muscle blood flow occlusion on the complexity of knee-extensor torque output in humans. Experimental Physiology, 103, 956-967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2018b). Caffeine ingestion attenuates fatigue-induced loss of muscle torque complexity. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 50, 236-245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2019a). Fatigue reduces the complexity of knee extensor torque during fatiguing sustained isometric contractions. European Journal of Sport Science, 19, 1349-1358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2019b). Prolonged depression of knee-extensor torque complexity following eccentric exercise. Experimental Physiology, 104, 100-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2020). Physiological evidence that the critical torque is a phase transition, not a Threshold. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 52, 2390-2401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick, J., Winter, S. L., &amp; Burnley, M. (2021b). Fatigue-induced changes in knee-extensor torque complexity and muscle metabolic rate are dependent on joint angle. European Journal of Applied Physiology. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-021-04779-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincus, S. M. (1991). Approximate entropy as a measure of system complexity. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, USA, 88, 2297-2301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole, D. C., Burnley, M., Vanhatalo, A., Rossiter, H. B., &amp; Jones, A. M. (2016). Critical power: an important fatigue threshold in exercise physiology. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 48, 2320-2334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potvin, J. R., &amp; Brown, S. H. M. (2004). Less is more: high pass filtering, to remove up to 99% of the surface EMG power, improves EMG-based biceps brachii force estimates. Journal of Electromyography &amp; Kinesiology, 14, 389-399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richman, J. S., &amp; Moorman, J. R. (2000). Physiological time-series analysis using approximate entropy and sample entropy. American Journal of Physiology, 278, H2039-H2049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose, M. H., L&#xf8;kkegaard, A., Sonne-Holm, S., &amp; Jensen, B. R. (2013). Tremor irregularity, torque steadiness and rate of force development in Parkinson's disease. Motor Control, 17, 203-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seely, A. J., &amp; Macklem, P. T. (2004). Complex systems and the technology of variability analysis. Critical Care, 8, R367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon, C. E. (1948). A mathematical theory of communication. Bell System Technical Journal, 27, 379-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slifkin, A. B., &amp; Newell, K. M. (1998). Is variability in human performance a reflection of system noise? Current Directions in Psychological Science, 7, 170-177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slifkin, A. B., &amp; Newell, K. M. (1999). Noise, information transmission, and force variability. Journal of Experimental Psychology, 25, 837-851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosnoff, J. J., &amp; Newell, K. M. (2006). Aging, visual intermittency, and variability in isometric force output. Journal of Gerontology, 61, P117-P124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosnoff, J. J., &amp; Newell, K. M. (2008). Age-related loss of adaptability to fast time scales in motor variability. Journal of Gerontology, 63, P344-P352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stergiou, N., &amp; Decker, L. M. (2011). Human movement variability, nonlinear dynamics and pathology: is there a connection? Human Movement Science, 30, 869-888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturman, M. E., Vaillancourt, D. E., &amp; Corcos, D. M. (2005). Effects of aging on the regularity of physiological tremor. Journal of Neurophysiology, 93, 3064-3074.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suda, E. Y., Madeleine, P., Hirata, R. P., Samani, A., Kawamura, T. T., &amp; Sacco, I. C. (2017). Reduced complexity of force and muscle activity during low level isometric contractions of the ankle in diabetic individuals. Clinical Biomechanics, 42, 38-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svendsen, J. H., &amp; Madeleine, P. (2010). Amount and structure of force variability during short, ramp and sustained contractions in males and females. Human Movement Science, 29, 35-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, A. M., Christou, E. A., &amp; Enoka, R. M. (2003). Multiple features of motor-unit activity influence force fluctuations during isometric contractions. Journal of Neurophysiology, 90, 1350-1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, C. K., Negro, F., Johnson, M. D., Holmes, M. R., McPherson, L. M., Powers, R. K., Farina, D., &amp; Heckman, C. J. (2018). Robust and accurate decoding of motoneuron behaviour and prediction of the resulting force output. Journal of Physiology, 596, 2643-2659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaillancourt, D. E., Larsson, L., &amp; Newell, K. M. (2002). Time-dependent structure in the discharge rate of human motor units. Clinical Neurophysiology, 113, 1325-1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaillancourt, D. E., &amp; Newell, K. M. (2000). The dynamics of resting and postural tremor in Parkinson's disease. Clinical Neurophysiology, 111, 2046-2056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaillancourt, D. E., &amp; Newell, K. M. (2003). Aging and the time and frequency structure of force output variability. Journal of Applied Physiology, 94, 903-912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaillancourt, D. E., Slifkin, A. B., &amp; Newell, K. M., (2001). Regularity of force tremor in Parkinson's disease. Clinical Neurophysiology, 112, 1594-1603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaillancourt, D. E., Sosnoff, J. J., &amp; Newell, K. M. (2004). Age-related changes in complexity depend on task dynamics. Journal of Applied Physiology, 97, 454-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yentes, J. M., Hunt, N., Schmid, K. K., Kaipust, J. P., McGrath, D., &amp; Stergiou, N. (2013). The appropriate use of approximate entropy and sample entropy with short data sets. Annals of Biomedical Engineering, 41, 349-365.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>