<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28479951</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute Effects of 24-h Sleep Deprivation on Salivary Cortisol and Testosterone Concentrations and Testosterone to Cortisol Ratio Following Supplementation with Caffeine or Placebo.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108</StartPage><EndPage>120</EndPage><MedlinePgn>108-120</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Caffeine has become a popular ergogenic aid amongst athletes and usage to improve athletic performance has been well documented. The effect of caffeine on anabolic and catabolic hormones in a sleep-deprived s tate has had little investigation to date. The purpose of the current study was to investigate the potential of caffeine to offset the effects, if any, of short-term sleep deprivation and exercise on an athlete's testosterone and cortisol concentrations via salivary technique. Eleven competitive male athletes volunteered to be part of this prospective double-blinded study. Three test days were scheduled for each athlete; one non-sleep deprived, one sleep-deprived with caffeine supplementation (6 mg.kg<sup>-1</sup>) and one sleep-deprived with placebo ingestion. Sleep deprivation was defined as 24-h without sleep. Each test day was composed of 2 aerobic components: a modified Hoff test and a Yo-Yo test. Testosterone and cortisol concentrations were measured via salivary analysis at 4 different time-points; T1 to T4, representing baseline, and pre- and post-aerobic components, respectively. Overall no significant differences were detected comparing the different sleep states for testosterone or cortisol concentrations. A trend existed whereby the sleep-deprived with caffeine ingestion state mirrored the non-sleep deprived state for cortisol concentration. Therefore, caffeine supplementation may have potential benefits for athletes during short-term aerobic exercise when sleep-deprived. An increase in mean testosterone concentration post-aerobic exercise was only observed in the sleep-deprived with caffeine ingestion state.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donald</LastName><ForeName>Ciaran Mc</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports &amp; Exercise Medicine, Trinity College, Dublin, IRELAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Joss</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports &amp; Exercise Medicine, Trinity College, Dublin, IRELAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McIntyre</LastName><ForeName>Alan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports &amp; Exercise Medicine, Trinity College, Dublin, IRELAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carmody</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports &amp; Exercise Medicine, Trinity College, Dublin, IRELAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donne</LastName><ForeName>Bernard</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports &amp; Exercise Medicine, Trinity College, Dublin, IRELAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ergogenic-Aid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hormone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Deprivation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28479951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5214660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/YABF8773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdelmalek S, Souissi N, Chtourou H, Denguezli M, Aouichaoui C, Ajina M, Aloui A, Dogui M, Haddouk S, Tabka Z. Effects of partial sleep deprivation on pro-inflammatory cytokines, growth hormone, and steroid hormone concentrations during repeated brief sprint interval exercise. Chronobiol Int. 2013;30(4):502&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen M, Tufik S. The effects of testosterone on sleep and sleep-disordered breathing in men: Its bidirectional interaction with erectile function. Sleep Med Rev. 2008;12(5):365&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaven C, Hopkins W, Hansen K, Wood M, Cronin J, Lowe T. Dose effect of caffeine on testosterone and cortisol responses to resistance exercise. J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18(2):131&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18458357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blimkie C, Sale D. Pediatric anaerobic performance. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 1988. Strength development and trainability during childhood.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bremner W. Testosterone deficiency and replacement in older men. N Engl J Med. 2010;363(2):189&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadouxhudson T, Few J, Imms F. The effect of exercise on the production and clearance of testosterone in well trained young men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1985;54(3):321&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4065118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook C, Beaven C, Kilduff L, Drawer S. Acute caffeine ingestion&#x2019;s increase of voluntarily chosen resistance-training load after limited sleep. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc. 2012;22(3):157&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22349085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debono M, Ghobadi C, Rostami-Hodjegan A, Huatan H, Campbell M, Newell-Price J, Darzy K, Merke D, Arlt W, Ross R. Modified-release hydrocortisone to provide circadian cortisol profiles. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009;94(5):1548&#x2013;1554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2684472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19223520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desbrow B, Biddulph C, Devlin B, Grant G, Anoopkumar-Dukie S, Leveritt M. The effects of different doses of caffeine on endurance cycling time-trial performance. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(2):115&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22142020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S, Jeukendrup A. Does overtraining exist? An analysis of overreaching and overtraining research. Sports Med. 2004;34(14):967&#x2013;981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15571428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff J, Wisloff U, Engen L, Kemi O, Helgerud J. Soccer specific aerobic endurance training. Br J Sports Med. 2002;36(3):218&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12055120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jezowa D, Vigas M, Tatar P, Kvetnansk&#xfd; R, Nazar K, Kaciuba-U&#x15b;cilko H, Kozlowski S. Plasma testosterone and catecholamine responses to physical exercise of different intensities in men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1985;54(1):62&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4018056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Mohr M, Nybo L, Jensen J, Nielsen J, Bangsbo J. The Yo-Yo IR2 test: Physiological response, reliability, and application to elite soccer. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(9):1666&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Proult R, van Cauter E. Effect of 1 week of sleep restriction on testosterone levels in young healthy men. J Am Med Assoc. 2011;305(21):2173&#x2013;2174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4445839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21632481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet L. Exercise and sport performance with low doses of caffeine. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 2):175&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25355191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas N, Leyshon A, Hughes M, Davies B, Graham M, Baker J. The effect of anaerobic exercise on salivary cortisol, testosterone and immunoglobulin A in boys aged 15&#x2013;16 years. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(4):455&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19669787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urhausen A, Gabriel H, Kindermann W. Blood hormones as markers of training stress and overtraining. Sports Med. 1995;20(4):251&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8584849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Treuer K, Norman T, Armstrong S. Overnight human plasma melatonin, cortisol, prolactin, TSH, under conditions of normal sleep, sleep deprivation, and sleep recovery. J Pineal Res. 1996;20(1):7&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8648563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters P. Sleep, the athlete, and performance. Strength Cond J. 2002;24(2):17&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weibel L, Follenius M, Spiegel K, Ehrhart J, Brandenberger G. Comparative effect of night and daytime sleep on the 24-hour cortisol secretory profile. Sleep. 1995;18(7):549&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8552925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkerson J, Horvath S, Gutin B. Plasma testosterone during treadmill exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1980;49(2):249&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7400007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu B. Dose effects of caffeine ingestion on acute hormonal responses to resistance exercise. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2014;55(10):1242&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24867603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>