<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34079171</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine metabolites are associated with different forms of caffeine supplementation and with perceived exertion during endurance exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>261</StartPage><EndPage>267</EndPage><MedlinePgn>261-267</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2020.98455</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This investigation compared the urine caffeine metabolites produced from different forms of caffeine supplementation given to runners 15 minutes before a series of 5-km running trials. Fourteen amateur competitive runners completed a series of self-paced outdoor time trials following ingestion of placebo or one of three alternate forms of caffeine supplement. Trials were randomized in a crossover design with equivalent doses of caffeine (4.0 mg.kg<sup>-1</sup>) administered 15 minutes before each trial via chewing gum, a novel dissolvable mouth strip or tablet. Runners produced a urine sample following each caffeinated trial that was tested for caffeine and its metabolites by high-performance liquid chromatography. The tablet form of caffeine produced a lower (p = 0.04) urinary ratio of the metabolite paraxanthine to caffeine compared with either gum or strip. Independently of caffeine delivery mode, subjects who metabolized a higher proportion of caffeine to paraxanthine recorded a lower (p = 0.01) perceived exertion. We demonstrate that oral swallowed caffeine administered 15 minutes before 5-km running is less metabolized compared with caffeinated products designed to be chewed or dissolved in the mouth. We suggest the metabolism of caffeine to paraxanthine has an inverse relationship with perceived exertion independently of caffeine delivery mode.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whalley</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Eastern Institute of Technology, School of Health and Sport Science, Napier, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paton</LastName><ForeName>Carl</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Eastern Institute of Technology, School of Health and Sport Science, Napier, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dearing</LastName><ForeName>Chey G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Eastern Institute of Technology, School of Nursing, Napier, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34079171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.98455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">98455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Southward K, Rutherfurd-Markwick KJ, Ali A. The effect of acute caffeine ingestion on endurance performance: a systematic review and meta&#x2013;analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(8):1913&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29876876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren GL, Park ND, Masresca RD, McKibans KI, Millard-stafford ML. Effect of Caffeine Ingestion on Muscular Strength and Endurance: A Meta-Analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(7):1375&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen JG, Brooks MB, Cincotta J, Manjourides JD. Establishing a relationship between the effect of caffeine and duration of endurance athletic time trial events: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22(2):232&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30170953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JK, Green JM. Caffeine and anaerobic performance: ergogenic value and mechanisms of action. Sports Med. 2009;39(10):813&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19757860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith P. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: a metaanalysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2005;15(2):69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15773860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering C, Kiely J. Are the current guidelines on caffeine use in sport optimal for everyone? Inter-individual variation in caffeine ergogenicity, and a move towards personalised sports nutrition. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):7&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28853006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles JD, Coleman D, Tegerdine M, Swaine IL. The effects of caffeine ingestion on performance time, speed and power during a laboratory-based 1 km cycling time-trial. J Sports Sci. 2006;24(11):1165&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17035165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelands B, Buyse L, Pauwels F, Delbeke F, Deventer K, Meeusen R. No effect of caffeine on exercise performance in high ambient temperature. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(12):3089&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21461761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest NS. Genetic Modifiers of Caffeine and Endurance Performance in Athletes. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham KA, Spriet LL. Administration of caffeine in alternate forms. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):79&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5790855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamimori GH, Karyekar CS, Otterstetter R, Cox DS, Balkin TJ, Belenky GL, Eddington ND. The rate of absorption and relative bioavailability of caffeine administered in chewing gum versus capsules to normal healthy volunteers. Int J Pharm. 2002;234(1&#x2013;2):159&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11839447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pataky M, Womack C, Saunders M, Goffe J, D&#x2019;lugos A, El-Sohemy A, Luden N. Caffeine and 3-km cycling performance: Effects of mouth rinsing, genotype, and time of day. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;26(6):613&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26062916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris C, Viriot SM, Mirza QUF, Morris G, Lynn A. Caffeine release and absorption from caffeinated gums. Food Funct. 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30919868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian DD, Natesan S, White JR, Paine MF. Effects of Common CYP 1A2 Genotypes and Other Key Factors on Intraindividual Variation in the Caffeine Metabolic Ratio: An Exploratory Analysis. Clin Transl Sci. 2019;12(1):39&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6342244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30387917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furge LL, Fletke KJ. HPLC determination of caffeine and paraxanthine in urine: An assay for cytochrome P450 1A2 activity. Biochem Mol Biol Educ. 2007;35(2):138&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21591074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Choi MS, Rehman SU, Ji YS, Yu JS, Nakamura K, Yoo HH. Determination of Urinary Caffeine Metabolites as Biomarkers for Drug Metabolic Enzyme Activities. Nutrients. 2019;11(8):1947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31430927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest N, Corey P, Vescovi J, El-Sohemy A. Caffeine, CYP1A2 Genotype, and Endurance Performance in Athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(8):1570&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29509641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whalley PJ, Dearing CG, Paton CD. The Effects of Different Forms of Caffeine Supplement on 5-km Running Performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;1(aop):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31605520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giesbrecht FG, Gumpertz ML. Planning, construction, and statistical analysis of comparative experiments. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckman MA, Weil J, De Mejia EG. Caffeine (1, 3, 7-trimethylxanthine) in foods: a comprehensive review on consumption, functionality, safety, and regulatory matters. J Food Sci. 2010;75(3):R77&#x2013;R87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20492310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner TL, Jenkins DG, Leveritt MD, McGorm A, Bolam KA, Coombes JS, Taaffe DR. Factors influencing serum caffeine concentrations following caffeine ingestion. J Sci Med Sport. 2014;17(5):516&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23932441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang A, Palmer AA, de Wit H. Genetics of caffeine consumption and responses to caffeine. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2010;211(3):245&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4242593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20532872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonati M, Latini R, Galletti F, Young JF, Tognoni G, Garattini S. Caffeine disposition after oral doses. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1982;32(1):98&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7083737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan GB, Greenblatt DJ, Ehrenberg BL, Goddard JE, Cotreau MM, Harmatz JS, Shader RI. Dose-dependent pharmacokinetics and psychomotor effects of caffeine in humans. J Clin Pharmaco. 1997;37(8):693&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9378841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslani A, Jalilian F. Design, formulation and evaluation of caffeine chewing gum. Adv Bio Res. 2013:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3814650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24223387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadek P, Pan X, Shepherd P, Malandain E, Carney J, Coleman H. A randomized, two-way crossover study to evaluate the pharmacokinetics of caffeine delivered using caffeinated chewing gum versus a marketed caffeinated beverage in healthy adult volunteers. J Caf Res. 2017;7(4):125&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5724581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29230348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>