<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24330705</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1743-7075</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of caffeine, nicotine, ethanol, and tetrahydrocannabinol on exercise performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>71</StartPage><MedlinePgn>71</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1743-7075-10-71</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Caffeine, nicotine, ethanol and tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) are among the most prevalent and culturally accepted drugs in western society. For example, in Europe and North America up to 90% of the adult population drinks coffee daily and, although less prevalent, the other drugs are also used extensively by the population. Smoked tobacco, excessive alcohol consumption and marijuana (cannabis) smoking are addictive and exhibit adverse health effects. These drugs are not only common in the general population, but have also made their way into elite sports because of their purported performance-altering potential. Only one of the drugs (i.e., caffeine) has enough scientific evidence indicating an ergogenic effect. There is some preliminary evidence for nicotine as an ergogenic aid, but further study is required; cannabis and alcohol can exhibit ergogenic potential under specific circumstances but are in general believed to be ergolytic for sports performance. These drugs are currently (THC, ethanol) or have been (caffeine) on the prohibited list of the World Anti-Doping Agency or are being monitored (nicotine) due to their potential ergogenic or ergolytic effects. The aim of this brief review is to evaluate the effects of caffeine, nicotine, ethanol and THC by: 1) examining evidence supporting the ergogenic or ergolytic effects; 2) providing an overview of the mechanism(s) of action and physiological effects; and 3) where appropriate, reviewing their impact as performance-altering aids used in recreational and elite sports.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pesta</LastName><ForeName>Dominik H</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Angadi</LastName><ForeName>Siddhartha S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burtscher</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Christian K</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Metabolic Disease Research Laboratory, Translational Sciences Section, School of Nursing, University of California, Los Angeles, CA, USA. croberts@ucla.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>J 3267</GrantID><Acronym>FWF_</Acronym><Agency>Austrian Science Fund FWF</Agency><Country>Austria</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-7075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24330705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3878772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-10-71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1743-7075-10-71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Crocq MA. Alcohol, nicotine, caffeine, and mental disorders. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2003;10:175&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22033899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JH, Pritchard WS. The role of nicotine in tobacco use. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1992;10:397&#x2013;407. doi: 10.1007/BF02247412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02247412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1410152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturm R. The effects of obesity, smoking, and drinking on medical problems and costs. Health Aff (Millwood) 2002;10:245&#x2013;253. doi: 10.1377/hlthaff.21.2.245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.21.2.245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11900166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WADA. WADA - World Anti Doping Agency. Montreal; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou T. Wake up and smell the coffee. Caffeine, coffee, and the medical consequences. West J Med. 1992;10:544&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1022034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1441496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statland BE, Demas TJ. Serum caffeine half-lives. Healthy subjects vs. patients having alcoholic hepatic disease. Am J Clin Pathol. 1980;10:390&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7361718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall AL, Millington WR, Wurtman RJ. Blood&#x2013;brain barrier transport of caffeine: dose-related restriction of adenine transport. Life Sci. 1982;10:2709&#x2013;2715. doi: 10.1016/0024-3205(82)90715-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0024-3205(82)90715-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell ME, Grant DM, Inaba T, Kalow W. Biotransformation of caffeine, paraxanthine, theophylline, and theobromine by polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon-inducible cytochrome(s) P-450 in human liver microsomes. Drug Metab Dispos. 1987;10:237&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2882985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtzman SG, Mante S, Minneman KP. Role of adenosine receptors in caffeine tolerance. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1991;10:62&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1846425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro JA, Sebastiao AM. Caffeine and adenosine. J Alzheimers Dis. 2010;10(Suppl 1):S3&#x2013;S15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20164566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron OG, Modell JG, Hariharan M. Caffeine and human cerebral blood flow: a positron emission tomography study. Life Sci. 1990;10:1141&#x2013;1146. doi: 10.1016/0024-3205(90)90174-P.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0024-3205(90)90174-P</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2122148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namdar M, Schepis T, Koepfli P, Gaemperli O, Siegrist PT, Grathwohl R, Valenta I, Delaloye R, Klainguti M, Wyss CA. et al. Caffeine impairs myocardial blood flow response to physical exercise in patients with coronary artery disease as well as in age-matched controls. PLoS One. 2009;10:e5665. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0005665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0005665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19479069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet LL, MacLean DA, Dyck DJ, Hultman E, Cederblad G, Graham TE. Caffeine ingestion and muscle metabolism during prolonged exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1992;10:E891&#x2013;E898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1616022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JW, Spriet LL. Skeletal muscle glycogen phosphorylase a kinetics: effects of adenine nucleotides and caffeine. J Appl Physiol. 2001;10:2071&#x2013;2078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11641346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umemura T, Ueda K, Nishioka K, Hidaka T, Takemoto H, Nakamura S, Jitsuiki D, Soga J, Goto C, Chayama K. et al. Effects of acute administration of caffeine on vascular function. Am J Cardiol. 2006;10:1538&#x2013;1541. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2006.06.058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2006.06.058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17126666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesley A, Hultman E, Spriet LL. Effects of epinephrine infusion on muscle glycogenolysis during intense aerobic exercise. Am J Physiol. 1995;10:E127&#x2013;E134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7840170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Caffeine and exercise: metabolism, endurance and performance. Sports Med. 2001;10:785&#x2013;807. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200131110-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200131110-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11583104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor C, Higham D, Close GL, Morton JP. The effect of adding caffeine to postexercise carbohydrate feeding on subsequent high-intensity interval-running capacity compared with carbohydrate alone. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2011;10:410&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21832305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battram DS, Shearer J, Robinson D, Graham TE. Caffeine ingestion does not impede the resynthesis of proglycogen and macroglycogen after prolonged exercise and carbohydrate supplementation in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2004;10:943&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14617526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen DJ, Lessard SJ, Coffey VG, Churchley EG, Wootton AM, Ng T, Watt MJ, Hawley JA. High rates of muscle glycogen resynthesis after exhaustive exercise when carbohydrate is coingested with caffeine. J Appl Physiol. 2008;10:7&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01121.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01121.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18467543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supinski GS, Deal EC Jr, Kelsen SG. The effects of caffeine and theophylline on diaphragm contractility. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1984;10:429&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6476593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo M. Calcium release from the sarcoplasmic reticulum. Physiol Rev. 1977;10:71&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky M, Cupido C. Caffeine potentiates low frequency skeletal muscle force in habitual and nonhabitual caffeine consumers. J Appl Physiol. 2000;10:1719&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echeverri D, Montes FR, Cabrera M, Galan A, Prieto A. Caffeine&#x2019;s Vascular mechanisms of action. Int J Vasc Med. 2010;10:834060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3003984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21188209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Effect of caffeine on the neuromuscular system&#x2013;potential as an ergogenic aid. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;10:1284&#x2013;1289. doi: 10.1139/H08-121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/H08-121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein ER, Ziegenfuss T, Kalman D, Kreider R, Campbell B, Wilborn C, Taylor L, Willoughby D, Stout J, Graves BS. et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: caffeine and performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;10:5. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-7-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osswald H, Schnermann J. Methylxanthines and the kidney. Handb Exp Pharmacol. 2011;10:391&#x2013;412. doi: 10.1007/978-3-642-13443-2_15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-13443-2_15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3275788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20859805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawrot P, Jordan S, Eastwood J, Rotstein J, Hugenholtz A, Feeley M. Effects of caffeine on human health. Food Addit Contam. 2003;10:1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12519715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paluska SA. Caffeine and exercise. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2003;10:213&#x2013;219. doi: 10.1249/00149619-200308000-00008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00149619-200308000-00008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12834577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JK, Green JM. Caffeine and anaerobic performance: ergogenic value and mechanisms of action. Sports Med. 2009;10:813&#x2013;832. doi: 10.2165/11317770-000000000-00000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11317770-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19757860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Caffeine and endurance performance. Sports Med. 1994;10:109&#x2013;125. doi: 10.2165/00007256-199418020-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199418020-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9132918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolf K, Bidwell WK, Carlson AG. The effect of caffeine as an ergogenic aid in anaerobic exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;10:412&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18708685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox GR, Desbrow B, Montgomery PG, Anderson ME, Bruce CR, Macrides TA, Martin DT, Moquin A, Roberts A, Hawley JA, Burke LM. Effect of different protocols of caffeine intake on metabolism and endurance performance. J Appl Physiol. 2002;10:990&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mc Naughton LR, Lovell RJ, Siegler JC, Midgley AW, Sandstrom M, Bentley DJ. The effects of caffeine ingestion on time trial cycling performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2008;10:320&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18974717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Estevez E, Mora-Rodriguez R. Caffeine effects on short-term performance during prolonged exercise in the heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;10:744&#x2013;751. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181621336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181621336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18317369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer F, Friars D, Graham TE. Comparison of caffeine and theophylline ingestion: exercise metabolism and endurance. J Appl Physiol. 2000;10:1837&#x2013;1844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez JT, Stevenson EJ. New perspectives on nutritional interventions to augment lipid utilisation during exercise. Br J Nutr. 2012;10:339&#x2013;349. doi: 10.1017/S0007114511006684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114511006684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22136984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donsmark M, Langfort J, Holm C, Ploug T, Galbo H. Contractions activate hormone-sensitive lipase in rat muscle by protein kinase C and mitogen-activated protein kinase. J Physiol. 2003;10:845&#x2013;854. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2003.042333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2003.042333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12794177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann R, Strauss JG, Haemmerle G, Schoiswohl G, Birner-Gruenberger R, Riederer M, Lass A, Neuberger G, Eisenhaber F, Hermetter A, Zechner R. Fat mobilization in adipose tissue is promoted by adipose triglyceride lipase. Science. 2004;10:1383&#x2013;1386. doi: 10.1126/science.1100747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1100747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15550674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy JL, Costill DL, Fink WJ, Lower RW. Influence of caffeine and carbohydrate feedings on endurance performance. Med Sci Sports. 1979;10:6&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">481158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehlig A, Debry G. Caffeine and sports activity: a review. Int J Sports Med. 1994;10:215&#x2013;223. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1021049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1021049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7960313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm BB, Battig K, Holmen J, Nehlig A, Zvartau EE. Actions of caffeine in the brain with special reference to factors that contribute to its widespread use. Pharmacol Rev. 1999;10:83&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10049999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Helge JW, MacLean DA, Kiens B, Richter EA. Caffeine ingestion does not alter carbohydrate or fat metabolism in human skeletal muscle during exercise. J Physiol. 2000;10(Pt 3):837&#x2013;847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11118510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egawa T, Hamada T, Kameda N, Karaike K, Ma X, Masuda S, Iwanaka N, Hayashi T. Caffeine acutely activates 5&#x2032;adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase and increases insulin-independent glucose transport in rat skeletal muscles. Metabolism. 2009;10:1609&#x2013;1617. doi: 10.1016/j.metabol.2009.05.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2009.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foskett A, Ali A, Gant N. Caffeine enhances cognitive function and skill performance during simulated soccer activity. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;10:410&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19827465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collomp K, Ahmaidi S, Audran M, Chanal JL, Prefaut C. Effects of caffeine ingestion on performance and anaerobic metabolism during the Wingate test. Int J Sports Med. 1991;10:439&#x2013;443. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1024710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1024710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1752708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorino AJ, Lloyd LK, Crixell SH, Walker JL. The effects of caffeine on athletic agility. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;10:851&#x2013;854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Rodriguez R, Garcia Pallares J, Lopez-Samanes A, Ortega JF, Fernandez-Elias VE. Caffeine ingestion reverses the circadian rhythm effects on neuromuscular performance in highly resistance-trained men. PLoS One. 2012;10:e33807. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0033807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0033807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3319538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22496767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Hibbert E, Sathasivam P. Metabolic and exercise endurance effects of coffee and caffeine ingestion. J Appl Physiol. 1998;10:883&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9729561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan TM, Bell DG. The impact of prior coffee consumption on the subsequent ergogenic effect of anhydrous caffeine. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2004;10:698&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15657474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles JD, Bird SR, Hopkins J, Riley M. Effect of caffeinated coffee on running speed, respiratory factors, blood lactate and perceived exertion during 1500-m treadmill running. Br J Sports Med. 1992;10:116&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.26.2.116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.26.2.116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1478936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1623356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgson AB, Randell RK, Jeukendrup AE. The metabolic and performance effects of caffeine compared to coffee during endurance exercise. PLoS One. 2013;10:e59561. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0059561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0059561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3616086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23573201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Dalsky GP, Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports. 1978;10:155&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">723503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butts N. Effect of caffeine ingestion on cardiorespiratory endurance in men and women. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1985;10:301&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1080/02701367.1985.10605333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.1985.10605333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamina S, Musa DI. Ergogenic effect of varied doses of coffee-caffeine on maximal aerobic power of young African subjects. Afr Health Sci. 2009;10:270&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3074398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21503180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup A, Saris WH, Brouns F, Kester AD. A new validated endurance performance test. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;10:266&#x2013;270. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199602000-00017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199602000-00017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8775164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derry CJ, Derry S, Moore RA. Caffeine as an analgesic adjuvant for acute pain in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;10 CD009281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22419343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman A, Sutton JR. Endorphins: what are they? How are they measured? What is their role in exercise? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1985;10:74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2858810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: a meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2005;10:69&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2005.00445.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2005.00445.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15773860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Soeren MH, Sathasivam P, Spriet LL, Graham TE. Caffeine metabolism and epinephrine responses during exercise in users and nonusers. J Appl Physiol. 1993;10:805&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mottram DR. Drugs in sport. 2. London; New York: E. &amp; F.N. Spon, an imprint of Chapman &amp; Hall; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prohibited list - questions and answers.   http://www.wada-ama.org/en/Resources/Q-and-A/2012-Prohibited-List/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenster L, Quale C, Hiatt RA, Wilson M, Windham GC, Benowitz NL. Rate of caffeine metabolism and risk of spontaneous abortion. Am J Epidemiol. 1998;10:503&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1093/oxfordjournals.aje.a009477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.aje.a009477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9525538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temple JL. Caffeine use in children: what we know, what we have left to learn, and why we should worry. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2009;10:793&#x2013;806. doi: 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2009.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2009.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19428492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desbrow B, Barrett CM, Minahan CL, Grant GD, Leveritt MD. Caffeine, cycling performance, and exogenous CHO oxidation: a dose&#x2013;response study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;10:1744&#x2013;1751. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a16cf7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a16cf7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19657295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JM, Wickwire PJ, McLester JR, Gendle S, Hudson G, Pritchett RC, Laurent CM. Effects of caffeine on repetitions to failure and ratings of perceived exertion during resistance training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2007;10:250&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19168925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutrel B, Koob GF. What keeps us awake: the neuropharmacology of stimulants and wakefulness-promoting medications. Sleep. 2004;10:1181&#x2013;1194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15532213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M. Pulmonary system limitations to endurance exercise performance in humans. Exp Physiol. 2012;10:311&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1113/expphysiol.2011.058800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2011.058800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3934509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22125308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark MA, Finkel R, Rey JA, Whalen K. Lippincott&#x2019;s Illustrated Reviews: Pharmacology. Baltimore/Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvette H, Hoff EC, Larson PS, Haag HB. The actions of nicotine on central nervous system functions. Pharmacol Rev. 1962;10:137&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13912982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narkiewicz K, van de Borne PJ, Hausberg M, Cooley RL, Winniford MD, Davison DE, Somers VK. Cigarette smoking increases sympathetic outflow in humans. Circulation. 1998;10:528&#x2013;534. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.98.6.528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.98.6.528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9714109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irving DW, Yamamoto T. Cigarette smoking and cardiac output. Br Heart J. 1963;10:126&#x2013;132. doi: 10.1136/hrt.25.1.126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/hrt.25.1.126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1017969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13956724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bargeron LM Jr, Bing RJ, Castellanos A, Ehmke D, Gonlubol F, Siegel A. Effect of cigarette smoking on coronary blood flow and myocardial metabolism. Circulation. 1957;10:251&#x2013;257. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.15.2.251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.15.2.251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13396948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usuki K, Kanekura T, Aradono K, Kanzaki T. Effects of nicotine on peripheral cutaneous blood flow and skin temperature. J Dermatol Sci. 1998;10:173&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1016/S0923-1811(97)00049-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0923-1811(97)00049-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9651814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorensen LT, Jorgensen S, Petersen LJ, Hemmingsen U, Bulow J, Loft S, Gottrup F. Acute effects of nicotine and smoking on blood flow, tissue oxygen, and aerobe metabolism of the skin and subcutis. J Surg Res. 2009;10:224&#x2013;230. doi: 10.1016/j.jss.2008.02.066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jss.2008.02.066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18468640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leow YH, Maibach HI. Cigarette smoking, cutaneous vasculature, and tissue oxygen. Clin Dermatol. 1998;10:579&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9787969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goniewicz ML, Kuma T, Gawron M, Knysak J, Kosmider L. Nicotine levels in electronic cigarettes. Nicotine Tob Res. 2013;10:158&#x2013;166. doi: 10.1093/ntr/nts103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/nts103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22529223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benowitz NL, Jacob P 3rd, Jones RT, Rosenberg J. Interindividual variability in the metabolism and cardiovascular effects of nicotine in man. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1982;10:368&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7077531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barik J, Wonnacott S. Molecular and cellular mechanisms of action of nicotine in the CNS. Handb Exp Pharmacol. 2009;10:173&#x2013;207. doi: 10.1007/978-3-540-69248-5_7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-540-69248-5_7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19184650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma G, Vijayaraghavan S. Modulation of presynaptic store calcium induces release of glutamate and postsynaptic firing. Neuron. 2003;10:929&#x2013;939. doi: 10.1016/S0896-6273(03)00322-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0896-6273(03)00322-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12818178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryder MI. Nicotine effects on neutrophil F-actin formation and calcium release: implications for tobacco use and pulmonary diseases. Exp Lung Res. 1994;10:283&#x2013;296. doi: 10.3109/01902149409064388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/01902149409064388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7988493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taioli E. Gene-environment interaction in tobacco-related cancers. Carcinogenesis. 2008;10:1467&#x2013;1474. doi: 10.1093/carcin/bgn062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/carcin/bgn062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2733188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinsen M, Sundgot-Borgen J. Adolescent elite athletes&#x2019; cigarette smoking, use of snus, and alcohol. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2012. DOI: 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2012.01505.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22830488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm H, Jarvis MJ, Russell MA, Feyerabend C. Nicotine intake and dependence in Swedish snuff takers. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1992;10:507&#x2013;511. doi: 10.1007/BF02247429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02247429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1410167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker JF, Collins LC, Rowell PP, Goldsmith LJ, Moffatt RJ, Stamford BA. The effect of smoking on energy expenditure and plasma catecholamine and nicotine levels during light physical activity. Nicotine Tob Res. 1999;10:365&#x2013;370. doi: 10.1080/14622299050011501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14622299050011501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber F, Anlauf M, Muller RD. Changes in muscle blood flow after smoking a cigarette determined by a new noninvasive method. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 1989;10:517&#x2013;520. doi: 10.1007/BF00558134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00558134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2598992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson K, Arner P. Systemic nicotine stimulates human adipose tissue lipolysis through local cholinergic and catecholaminergic receptors. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2001;10:1225&#x2013;1232. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0801654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0801654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11477508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marclay F, Grata E, Perrenoud L, Saugy M. A one-year monitoring of nicotine use in sport: frontier between potential performance enhancement and addiction issues. Forensic Sci Int. 2011;10:73&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1016/j.forsciint.2011.05.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.forsciint.2011.05.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21719221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alaranta A, Alaranta H, Patja K, Palmu P, Prattala R, Martelin T, Helenius I. Snuff use and smoking in Finnish olympic athletes. Int J Sports Med. 2006;10:581&#x2013;586. doi: 10.1055/s-2005-865826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2005-865826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16802255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin ED, McClernon FJ, Rezvani AH. Nicotinic effects on cognitive function: behavioral characterization, pharmacological specification, and anatomic localization. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2006;10:523&#x2013;539. doi: 10.1007/s00213-005-0164-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-005-0164-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16220335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzilli TS, Willhoit KF, Guadagnoli M. Effects of information processing load in abstinent and nonabstinent smokers&#x2019; psychomotor task performance. Nicotine Tob Res. 2006;10:425&#x2013;433. doi: 10.1080/14622200600672757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14622200600672757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16801300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hus&#xf8; T. Anti-Doping Database. Norway: (ADDB); 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mundel T, Jones DA. Effect of transdermal nicotine administration on exercise endurance in men. Exp Physiol. 2006;10:705&#x2013;713. doi: 10.1113/expphysiol.2006.033373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2006.033373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16627574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier J. Effect of nicotine and muscle performance using a Wingate anaerobic tests of collegiate football players. Wisconsin: The University of Wisconsin-Whitewater; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucha O, Lange KW. Effects of nicotine chewing gum on a real-life motor task: a kinematic analysis of handwriting movements in smokers and non-smokers. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2004;10:49&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1007/s00213-003-1690-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-003-1690-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14668975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heishman SJ, Snyder FR, Henningfield JE. Performance, subjective, and physiological effects of nicotine in non-smokers. Drug Alcohol Depend. 1993;10:11&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/0376-8716(93)90041-N.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0376-8716(93)90041-N</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8174498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindmarch I, Kerr JS, Sherwood N. Effects of nicotine gum on psychomotor performance in smokers and non-smokers. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1990;10:535&#x2013;541. doi: 10.1007/BF02244008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02244008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2320715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West RJ, Jarvis MJ. Effects of nicotine on finger tapping rate in non-smokers. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1986;10:727&#x2013;731. doi: 10.1016/0091-3057(86)90377-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0091-3057(86)90377-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3786334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenz TL, Gillespie N. Transdermal patch drug delivery interactions with exercise. Sports Med. 2011;10:177&#x2013;183. doi: 10.2165/11586080-000000000-00000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11586080-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21395361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolerman IP, Jarvis MJ. The scientific case that nicotine is addictive. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1995;10:2&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1007/BF02245088. discussion 14&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02245088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7724697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burtscher M, Likar R, Pechlaner C, Kunz F, Philadelphy M. Motor symptoms similar to parkinsonism in heavy smokers. Int J Sports Med. 1994;10:207&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1021048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1021048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8063470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scerbo F, Faulkner G, Taylor A, Thomas S. Effects of exercise on cravings to smoke: the role of exercise intensity and cortisol. J Sports Sci. 2010;10:11&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1080/02640410903390089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410903390089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19967594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haasova M, Warren FC, Ussher M, Janse Van Rensburg K, Faulkner G, Cropley M, Byron-Daniel J, Everson-Hock ES, Oh H, Taylor AH. The acute effects of physical activity on cigarette cravings: systematic review and meta-analysis with individual participant data. Addiction. 2013;10:26&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1111/j.1360-0443.2012.04034.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1360-0443.2012.04034.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22861822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heishman SJ, Kleykamp BA, Singleton EG. Meta-analysis of the acute effects of nicotine and smoking on human performance. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2010;10:453&#x2013;469. doi: 10.1007/s00213-010-1848-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-010-1848-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3151730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20414766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamner LD, Girdler SS, Shapiro D, Jarvik ME. Pain inhibition, nicotine, and gender. Exp Clin Psychopharmacol. 1998;10:96&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9526150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marclay F, Saugy M. Determination of nicotine and nicotine metabolites in urine by hydrophilic interaction chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry: Potential use of smokeless tobacco products by ice hockey players. J Chromatogr A. 2010;10:7528&#x2013;7538. doi: 10.1016/j.chroma.2010.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chroma.2010.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20980010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray N. Mixed feelings on snus. Lancet. 2005;10:966&#x2013;967. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(05)67352-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(05)67352-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16168760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattila VM, Raisamo S, Pihlajamaki H, Mantysaari M, Rimpela A. Sports activity and the use of cigarettes and snus among young males in Finland in 1999&#x2013;2010. BMC Public Health. 2012;10:230. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-12-230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-12-230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22439614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sayed MS, Ali N, El-Sayed Ali Z. Interaction between alcohol and exercise: physiological and haematological implications. Sports Med. 2005;10:257&#x2013;269. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200535030-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535030-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15730339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutt DJ, King LA, Phillips LD. Drug harms in the UK: a multicriteria decision analysis. Lancet. 2010;10:1558&#x2013;1565. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61462-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61462-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21036393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman LS, Gilman A, Gilman AG. Goodman and Gilman&#x2019;s The pharmacological basis of therapeutics. 7. New York: Macmillan; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichtenstein AH, Appel LJ, Brands M, Carnethon M, Daniels S, Franch HA, Franklin B, Kris-Etherton P, Harris WS, Howard B. et al. Diet and lifestyle recommendations revision 2006: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association Nutrition Committee. Circulation. 2006;10:82&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.176158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.176158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16785338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poikolainen K. Alcohol and mortality: a review. J Clin Epidemiol. 1995;10:455&#x2013;465. doi: 10.1016/0895-4356(94)00174-O.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0895-4356(94)00174-O</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7722599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien CP, Lyons F. Alcohol and the athlete. Sports Med. 2000;10:295&#x2013;300. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200029050-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200029050-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10840864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutgesell M, Canterbury R. Alcohol usage in sport and exercise. Addict Biol. 1999;10:373&#x2013;383. doi: 10.1080/13556219971353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13556219971353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20575805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson P, McKenna W, Bristow M, Maisch B, Mautner B, O'Connell J, Olsen E, Thiene G, Goodwin J, Gyarfas I. et al. Report of the 1995 World Health Organization/International Society and Federation of Cardiology Task Force on the Definition and Classification of cardiomyopathies. Circulation. 1996;10:841&#x2013;842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8598070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husain K, Somani SM. Response of cardiac antioxidant system to alcohol and exercise training in the rat. Alcohol. 1997;10:301&#x2013;307. doi: 10.1016/S0741-8329(96)00211-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0741-8329(96)00211-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9160808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Borow KM, Neumann A, Feldman T. Adverse cardiac effects of acute alcohol ingestion in young adults. Ann Intern Med. 1985;10:742&#x2013;747. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-102-6-742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-102-6-742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3994186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spolarics Z, Bagby GJ, Pekala PH, Dobrescu C, Skrepnik N, Spitzer JJ. Acute alcohol administration attenuates insulin-mediated glucose use by skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol. 1994;10:E886&#x2013;E891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7810630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trounce I, Byrne E, Dennett X. Biochemical and morphological studies of skeletal muscle in experimental chronic alcoholic myopathy. Acta Neurol Scand. 1990;10:386&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2291400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vila L, Ferrando A, Voces J, Cabral de Oliveira C, Prieto JG, Alvarez AI JG, Alvarez AI. Effect of chronic ethanol ingestion and exercise training on skeletal muscle in rat. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2001;10:27&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/S0376-8716(00)00223-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0376-8716(00)00223-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11470338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vella LD, Cameron-Smith D. Alcohol, athletic performance and recovery. Nutrients. 2010;10:781&#x2013;789. doi: 10.3390/nu2080781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu2080781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3257708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22254055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cofan M, Nicolas JM, Fernandez-Sola J, Robert J, Tobias E, Sacanella E, Estruch R, Urbano-Marquez A. Acute ethanol treatment decreases intracellular calcium-ion transients in mouse single skeletal muscle fibres in vitro. Alcohol Alcohol. 2000;10:134&#x2013;138. doi: 10.1093/alcalc/35.2.134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/alcalc/35.2.134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10787387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltin B, Kiens B, Savard G, Pedersen PK. Role of hemoglobin and capillarization for oxygen delivery and extraction in muscular exercise. Acta Physiol Scand Suppl. 1986;10:21&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3471054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altura BM, Altura BT, Gebrewold A. Comparative effects of ethanol, acetaldehyde and acetate on arterioles and venules in skeletal muscle: direct in situ studies on the microcirculation and their possible relationship to alcoholic myopathy. Microcirc Endothelium Lymphatics. 1990;10:107&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2247021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardies CM, Morris GS, Erickson CK, Farrar RP. Both acute and chronic exercise enhance in vivo ethanol clearance in rats. J Appl Physiol. 1989;10:555&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2708188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sayed M, Omar A, Lin X. Post-exercise alcohol ingestion perturbs blood haemostasis during recovery. Thromb Res. 2000;10:523&#x2013;530. doi: 10.1016/S0049-3848(00)00293-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0049-3848(00)00293-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10974336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catto AJ, Grant PJ. Risk factors for cerebrovascular disease and the role of coagulation and fibrinolysis. Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis. 1995;10:497&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1097/00001721-199509000-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00001721-199509000-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7578890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillbom M, Haapaniemi H, Juvela S, Palomaki H, Numminen H, Kaste M. Recent alcohol consumption, cigarette smoking, and cerebral infarction in young adults. Stroke. 1995;10:40&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1161/01.STR.26.1.40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.26.1.40</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7839395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillbom M, Kaste M, Rasi V. Can ethanol intoxication affect hemocoagulation to increase the risk of brain infarction in young adults? Neurology. 1983;10:381&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1212/WNL.33.3.381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.33.3.381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6219300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sayed MS. Effects of alcohol ingestion post-exercise on platelet aggregation. Thromb Res. 2002;10:147&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1016/S0049-3848(02)00008-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0049-3848(02)00008-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11958805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes MJ, Mundel T, Stannard SR. Post-exercise alcohol ingestion exacerbates eccentric-exercise induced losses in performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;10:1009&#x2013;1014. doi: 10.1007/s00421-009-1311-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1311-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20012446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay A, Wouters E, Wenker M, St-Pierre S, Bouchard C, Despres J. Alcohol and a high-fat diet: a combination favoring overfeeding. Am J Clin Nutr. 1995;10:639&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7661127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonko BJ, Prentice AM, Murgatroyd PR, Goldberg GR, van de Ven ML, Coward WA. Effect of alcohol on postmeal fat storage. Am J Clin Nutr. 1994;10:619&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8116538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suter PM, Schutz Y, Jequier E. The effect of ethanol on fat storage in healthy subjects. N Engl J Med. 1992;10:983&#x2013;987. doi: 10.1056/NEJM199204093261503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199204093261503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1545851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crouse JR, Grundy SM. Effects of alcohol on plasma lipoproteins and cholesterol and triglyceride metabolism in man. J Lipid Res. 1984;10:486&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6736783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colditz GA, Giovannucci E, Rimm EB, Stampfer MJ, Rosner B, Speizer FE, Gordis E, Willett WC. Alcohol intake in relation to diet and obesity in women and men. Am J Clin Nutr. 1991;10:49&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2058587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lands WE, Zakhari S. The case of the missing calories. Am J Clin Nutr. 1991;10:47&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2058586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiirst P, Riccardi G, Roberfroid M, Vogel M. Functional food science and substrate metabolism. Br J Nutr. 1998;10:S47&#x2013;S75. doi: 10.1079/BJN19980105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/BJN19980105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9849354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Preece D. Alcohol and its effects on sprint and middle distance running. Br J Sports Med. 1986;10:56&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.20.2.56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.20.2.56</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1478291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3730755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendrick ZV, Affrime MB, Lowenthal DT. Effect of ethanol on metabolic responses to treadmill running in well-trained men. J Clin Pharmacol. 1993;10:136&#x2013;139. doi: 10.1002/j.1552-4604.1993.tb03933.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.1552-4604.1993.tb03933.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8440761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecoultre V, Schutz Y. Effect of a small dose of alcohol on the endurance performance of trained cyclists. Alcohol Alcohol. 2009;10:278&#x2013;283. doi: 10.1093/alcalc/agn108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/alcalc/agn108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19136497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cofan M, Fernandez-Sola J, Nicolas JM, Poch E, Urbano-Marquez A. Ethanol decreases basal cytosolic-free calcium concentration in cultured skeletal muscle cells. Alcohol Alcohol. 1995;10:617&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8554644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond V, Franks BD, Howley ET. Effects of small and moderate doses of alcohol on submaximal cardiorespiratory function, perceived exertion and endurance performance in abstainers and moderate drinkers. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1983;10:221&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6632863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houmard JA, Langenfeld M, Wiley R, Siefert J. Effects of the acute ingestion of small amounts of alcohol upon 5-mile run times. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1987;10:253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3657134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Collier GR, Broad EM, Davis PG, Martin DT, Sanigorski AJ, Hargreaves M. Effect of alcohol intake on muscle glycogen storage after prolonged exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2003;10:983&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12740311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang CH, Pruznak AM, Nystrom GJ, Vary TC. Alcohol-induced decrease in muscle protein synthesis associated with increased binding of mTOR and raptor: comparable effects in young and mature rats. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2009;10:4. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-6-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-6-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2651172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19154606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winterfeldt J. Ein bisschen Alkohol macht dich schneller. Germany: Die Welt; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado CE, Gortuin NJ, Ross RS. Acute effects of low doses of alcohol on left ventricular function by echocardiography. Circulation. 1975;10:535&#x2013;540. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.51.3.535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.51.3.535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1139762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Administratio SAaMHS, editor. H-46 NS. Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, Results from the 2012 National Survey on Drug Use and Health: Summary of National Findings. 4795. Rockville, MD: HHS Publication No. (SMA) 13; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pertwee RG. Pharmacology of cannabinoid CB1 and CB2 receptors. Pharmacol Ther. 1997;10:129&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9336020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand P, Whiteside G, Fowler CJ, Hohmann AG. Targeting CB2 receptors and the endocannabinoid system for the treatment of pain. Brain Res Rev. 2009;10:255&#x2013;266. doi: 10.1016/j.brainresrev.2008.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresrev.2008.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4549801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19150370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuinness TM, Newell D. Risky recreation: synthetic cannabinoids have dangerous effects. J Psychosoc Nurs Ment Health Serv. 2012;10:16&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22801822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steadward RD, Singh M. The effects of smoking marihuana on physical performance. Med Sci Sports. 1975;10:309&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1235156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renaud AM, Cormier Y. Acute effects of marihuana smoking on maximal exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1986;10:685&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3097453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avakian EV, Horvath SM, Michael ED, Jacobs S. Effect of marihuana on cardiorespiratory responses to submaximal exercise. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1979;10:777&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">498720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashkin DP, Soares JR, Hepler RS, Shapiro BJ, Rachelefsky GS. Cannabis, 1977. Ann Intern Med. 1978;10:539&#x2013;549. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-89-4-539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-89-4-539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">358885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird KD, Boleyn T, Chesher GB, Jackson DM, Starmer GA, Teo RK. Intercannabinoid and cannabinoid-ethanol interactions on human performance. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1980;10:181&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1007/BF00434409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00434409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6777818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lach E, Schachter EN. Marihuana and exercise testing. N Engl J Med. 1979;10:438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">460355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashkin DP, Shapiro BJ, Lee YE, Harper CE. Effects of smoked marijuana in experimentally induced asthma. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1975;10:377&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1099949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vachon L, FitzGerald MX, Solliday NH, Gould IA, Gaensler EA. Single-dose effects of marihuana smoke. Bronchial dynamics and respiratory-center sensitivity in normal subjects. N Engl J Med. 1973;10:985&#x2013;989. doi: 10.1056/NEJM197305102881902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM197305102881902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4696254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorente FO, Peretti-Watel P, Grelot L. Cannabis use to enhance sportive and non-sportive performances among French sport students. Addict Behav. 2005;10:1382&#x2013;1391. doi: 10.1016/j.addbeh.2005.01.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2005.01.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16022934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thevis M, Kuuranne T, Geyer H, Sch&#xe4;nzer W. Annual banned-substance review: the Prohibited List 2008&#x2014;analytical approaches in human sports drug testing. Drug Test Anal. 2009;10:4&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1002/dta.9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dta.9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20355153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leson G, Pless P, Grotenhermen F, Kalant H, ElSohly MA. Evaluating the impact of hemp food consumption on workplace drug tests. J Anal Toxicol. 2001;10:691&#x2013;698. doi: 10.1093/jat/25.8.691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jat/25.8.691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11765026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cone EJ, Johnson RE, Darwin WD, Yousefnejad D, Mell LD, Paul BD, Mitchell J. Passive inhalation of marijuana smoke: urinalysis and room air levels of delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol. J Anal Toxicol. 1987;10:89&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1093/jat/11.3.89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jat/11.3.89</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3037193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElSohly MA. Practical challenges to positive drug tests for marijuana. Clin Chem. 2003;10:1037&#x2013;1038. doi: 10.1373/49.7.1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1373/49.7.1037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12816896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenneisen R, Meyer P, Chtioui H, Saugy M, Kamber M. Plasma and urine profiles of &#x394;9-tetrahydrocannabinol and its metabolites 11-hydroxy-&#x394;9-tetrahydrocannabinol and 11-nor-9-carboxy-&#x394;9-tetrahydrocannabinol after cannabis smoking by male volunteers to estimate recent consumption by athletes. Anal Bioanal Chem. 2010;10:2493&#x2013;2502. doi: 10.1007/s00216-009-3431-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00216-009-3431-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20112012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azcona O, Barbanoj MJ, Torrent J, Jane F. Evaluation of the central effects of alcohol and caffeine interaction. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 1995;10:393&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2125.1995.tb04562.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2125.1995.tb04562.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1365159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8554942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panlilio LV, Ferre S, Yasar S, Thorndike EB, Schindler CW, Goldberg SR. Combined effects of THC and caffeine on working memory in rats. Br J Pharmacol. 2012;10:2529&#x2013;2538. doi: 10.1111/j.1476-5381.2011.01554.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1476-5381.2011.01554.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3423236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21699509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown CR, Jacob P 3rd, Wilson M, Benowitz NL. Changes in rate and pattern of caffeine metabolism after cigarette abstinence. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1988;10:488&#x2013;491. doi: 10.1038/clpt.1988.63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/clpt.1988.63</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3365914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George J, Murphy T, Roberts R, Cooksley WG, Halliday JW, Powell LW. Influence of alcohol and caffeine consumption on caffeine elimination. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 1986;10:731&#x2013;736. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1681.1986.tb02414.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1681.1986.tb02414.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smits P, Temme L, Thien T. The cardiovascular interaction between caffeine and nicotine in humans. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1993;10:194&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1038/clpt.1993.131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/clpt.1993.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8354027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WE, Johnson JA. Pharmacogenomics: the inherited basis for interindividual differences in drug response. Annu Rev Genomics Hum Genet. 2001;10:9&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1146/annurev.genom.2.1.9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.genom.2.1.9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11701642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>