<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26471759</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-817X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiological reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine and contraction synergistically stimulate 5'-AMP-activated protein kinase and insulin-independent glucose transport in rat skeletal muscle.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e12592</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14814/phy2.12592</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>5'-Adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase (AMPK) has been identified as a key mediator of contraction-stimulated insulin-independent glucose transport in skeletal muscle. Caffeine acutely stimulates AMPK in resting skeletal muscle, but it is unknown whether caffeine affects AMPK in contracting muscle. Isolated rat epitrochlearis muscle was preincubated and then incubated in the absence or presence of 3&#xa0;mmol/L caffeine for 30 or 120&#xa0;min. Electrical stimulation (ES) was used to evoke tetanic contractions during the last 10&#xa0;min of the incubation period. The combination of caffeine plus contraction had additive effects on AMPK&#x3b1; Thr(172) phosphorylation, &#x3b1;-isoform-specific AMPK activity, and 3-O-methylglucose (3MG) transport. In contrast, caffeine inhibited basal and contraction-stimulated Akt Ser(473) phosphorylation. Caffeine significantly delayed muscle fatigue during contraction, and the combination of caffeine and contraction additively decreased ATP and phosphocreatine contents. Caffeine did not affect resting tension. Next, rats were given an intraperitoneal injection of caffeine (60&#xa0;mg/kg body weight) or saline, and the extensor digitorum longus muscle was dissected 15&#xa0;min later. ES of the sciatic nerve was performed to evoke tetanic contractions for 5&#xa0;min before dissection. Similar to the findings from isolated muscles incubated in&#xa0;vitro, the combination of caffeine plus contraction in&#xa0;vivo had additive effects on AMPK phosphorylation, AMPK activity, and 3MG transport. Caffeine also inhibited basal and contraction-stimulated Akt phosphorylation in&#xa0;vivo. These findings suggest that caffeine and contraction synergistically stimulate AMPK activity and insulin-independent glucose transport, at least in part by decreasing muscle fatigue and thereby promoting energy consumption during contraction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2015 The Authors. Physiological Reports published by Wiley Periodicals, Inc. on behalf of the American Physiological Society and The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuda</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sports and Exercise Medicine, Graduate School of Human and Environmental Studies, Kyoto University, Kyoto, 606-8501, Japan tsuda.satoshi.55u@st.kyoto-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egawa</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sports and Exercise Medicine, Graduate School of Human and Environmental Studies, Kyoto University, Kyoto, 606-8501, Japan Department of Physiology, Graduate School of Health Sciences, Toyohashi SOZO University, Toyohashi, 440-0016, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kitani</LastName><ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sports and Exercise Medicine, Graduate School of Human and Environmental Studies, Kyoto University, Kyoto, 606-8501, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oshima</LastName><ForeName>Rieko</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sports and Exercise Medicine, Graduate School of Human and Environmental Studies, Kyoto University, Kyoto, 606-8501, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Puer Tea Science, Ministry of Education, Yunnan Agricultural University, Kunming, 650201, Yunnan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sports and Exercise Medicine, Graduate School of Human and Environmental Studies, Kyoto University, Kyoto, 606-8501, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101607800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-817X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">5&#x2032;&#x2010;AMP&#x2010;activated protein kinase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy deprivation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucose metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle contraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle fatigue</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26471759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4632959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">3/10/e12592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbott MJ, Edelman AM. Turcotte LP. CaMKK is an upstream signal of AMP-activated protein kinase in regulation of substrate metabolism in contracting skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2009;297:R1724&#x2013;R1732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19812359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramoff MD, Magelhaes PJ. Ram SJ. Image processing with ImageJ. Biophotonics Int. 2004;11:36&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DG. Westerblad H. The effects of caffeine on intracellular calcium, force and the rate of relaxation of mouse skeletal muscle. J. Physiol. 1995;487(Pt 2):331&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1156576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8558467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassoli BK, Cassolla P, Borba-Murad GR, Constantin J, Salgueiro-Pagadigorria CL, Bazotte RB, et al. Chlorogenic acid reduces the plasma glucose peak in the oral glucose tolerance test: effects on hepatic glucose release and glycaemia. Cell Biochem. Funct. 2008;26:320&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17990295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchi CP. Kinetics of radiocaffeine uptake and release in frog sartorius. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 1962;138:41&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13968044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canto C, Gerhart-Hines Z, Feige JN, Lagouge M, Noriega L, Milne JC, et al. AMPK regulates energy expenditure by modulating NAD+ metabolism and SIRT1 activity. Nature. 2009;458:1056&#x2013;1060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3616311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19262508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng JT, Liu IM, Tzeng TF, Chen WC, Hayakawa S. Yamamoto T. Release of beta-endorphin by caffeic acid to lower plasma glucose in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Horm. Metab. Res. 2003;35:251&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12778369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung PC, Salt IP, Davies SP, Hardie DG. Carling D. Characterization of AMP-activated protein kinase gamma-subunit isoforms and their role in AMP binding. Biochem. J. 2000;346(Pt 3):659&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1220898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10698692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Dalsky GP. Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med. Sci. Sports. 1978;10:155&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">723503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding M, Bhupathiraju SN, Chen M, van Dam RM. Hu FB. Caffeinated and decaffeinated coffee consumption and risk of type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and a dose-response meta-analysis. Diabetes Care. 2014;37:569&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3898757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24459154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egawa T, Hamada T, Kameda N, Karaike K, Ma X, Masuda S, et al. Caffeine acutely activates 5&#x2032;adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase and increases insulin-independent glucose transport in rat skeletal muscles. Metabolism. 2009;58:1609&#x2013;1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egawa T, Hamada T, Ma X, Karaike K, Kameda N, Masuda S, et al. Caffeine activates preferentially alpha1-isoform of 5&#x2032;AMP-activated protein kinase in rat skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol. (Oxf.) 2011a;201:227&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egawa T, Tsuda S, Ma X, Hamada T. Hayashi T. Caffeine modulates phosphorylation of insulin receptor substrate-1 and impairs insulin signal transduction in rat skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2011b;111:1629&#x2013;1636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21940847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JS, Gao J, Han DH, Holloszy JO. Nolte LA. Activation of AMP kinase enhances sensitivity of muscle glucose transport to insulin. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2002;282:E18&#x2013;E23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11739078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foukas LC, Daniele N, Ktori C, Anderson KE, Jensen J. Shepherd PR. Direct effects of caffeine and theophylline on p110 delta and other phosphoinositide 3-kinases. Differential effects on lipid kinase and protein kinase activities. J. Biol. Chem. 2002;277:37124&#x2013;37130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12145276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrichsen M, Mortensen B, Pehmoller C, Birk JB. Wojtaszewski JF. Exercise-induced AMPK activity in skeletal muscle: role in glucose uptake and insulin sensitivity. Mol. Cell. Endocrinol. 2013;366:204&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii N, Jessen N. Goodyear LJ. AMP-activated protein kinase and the regulation of glucose transport. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2006;291:E867&#x2013;E877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16822958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funai K. Cartee GD. Inhibition of contraction-stimulated AMP-activated protein kinase inhibits contraction-stimulated increases in PAS-TBC1D1 and glucose transport without altering PAS-AS160 in rat skeletal muscle. Diabetes. 2009;58:1096&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19208911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Spriet LL. Metabolic, catecholamine, and exercise performance responses to various doses of caffeine. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 1995;78:867&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7775331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardie DG. Sensing of energy and nutrients by AMP-activated protein kinase. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2011;93:891S&#x2013;896S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21325438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi T, Hirshman MF, Fujii N, Habinowski SA, Witters LA. Goodyear LJ. Metabolic stress and altered glucose transport: activation of AMP-activated protein kinase as a unifying coupling mechanism. Diabetes. 2000;49:527&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10871188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu FL, Chen YC. Cheng JT. Caffeic acid as active principle from the fruit of Xanthium strumarium to lower plasma glucose in diabetic rats. Planta Med. 2000;66:228&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10821047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter RW, Treebak JT, Wojtaszewski JF. Sakamoto K. Molecular mechanism by which AMP-activated protein kinase activation promotes glycogen accumulation in muscle. Diabetes. 2011;60:766&#x2013;774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huxley R, Lee CM, Barzi F, Timmermeister L, Czernichow S, Perkovic V, et al. Coffee, decaffeinated coffee, and tea consumption in relation to incident type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Arch. Intern. Med. 2009;169:2053&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20008687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias MA, Ye JM, Frangioudakis G, Saha AK, Tomas E, Ruderman NB, et al. AICAR administration causes an apparent enhancement of muscle and liver insulin action in insulin-resistant high-fat-fed rats. Diabetes. 2002;51:2886&#x2013;2894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12351423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwanaka N, Egawa T, Satoubu N, Karaike K, Ma X, Masuda S, et al. Leucine modulates contraction- and insulin-stimulated glucose transport and upstream signaling events in rat skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2010;108:274&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19940100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jager S, Handschin C, St-Pierre J. Spiegelman BM. AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) action in skeletal muscle via direct phosphorylation of PGC-1alpha. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2007;104:12017&#x2013;12022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1924552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen TE, Rose AJ, Hellsten Y, Wojtaszewski JF. Richter EA. Caffeine-induced Ca(2+) release increases AMPK-dependent glucose uptake in rodent soleus muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2007;293:E286&#x2013;E292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17405829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung UJ, Lee MK, Park YB, Jeon SM. Choi MS. Antihyperglycemic and antioxidant properties of caffeic acid in db/db mice. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 2006;318:476&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16644902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolnes AJ, Ingvaldsen A, Bolling A, Stuenaes JT, Kreft M, Zorec R, et al. Caffeine and theophylline block insulin-stimulated glucose uptake and PKB phosphorylation in rat skeletal muscles. Acta Physiol. (Oxf.) 2010;200:65&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20180783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F. Kavouras SA. Caffeine use in sports, pharmacokinetics in man, and cellular mechanisms of action. Crit. Rev. Food Sci. Nutr. 2005;45:535&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16371327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto L, Toyoda T, Hayashi T, Yonemitsu S, Nakano M, Tanaka S, et al. Effect of acute activation of 5&#x2032;-AMP-activated protein kinase on glycogen regulation in isolated rat skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2007;102:1007&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17122373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki E, Yabu H. Takahashi M. Increasing effect of caffeine on the oxygen consumption of the skeletal muscle. Jpn. J. Physiol. 1962;12:113&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14474835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musi N, Hayashi T, Fujii N, Hirshman MF, Witters LA. Goodyear LJ. AMP-activated protein kinase activity and glucose uptake in rat skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2001;280:E677&#x2013;E684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11287349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano M, Hamada T, Hayashi T, Yonemitsu S, Miyamoto L, Toyoda T, et al. alpha2 Isoform-specific activation of 5&#x2032;adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase by 5-aminoimidazole-4-carboxamide-1-beta-d-ribonucleoside at a physiological level activates glucose transport and increases glucose transporter 4 in mouse skeletal muscle. Metabolism. 2006;55:300&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16483872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesher R, Karl IE, Kaiser KE. Kipnis DM. Epitrochlearis muscle. I. Mechanical performance, energetics, and fiber composition. Am. J. Physiol. 1980;239:E454&#x2013;E460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6449876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raney MA. Turcotte LP. Evidence for the involvement of CaMKII and AMPK in Ca2+-dependent signaling pathways regulating FA uptake and oxidation in contracting rodent muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 2008;104:1366&#x2013;1373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rockl KS, Hirshman MF, Brandauer J, Fujii N, Witters LA. Goodyear LJ. Skeletal muscle adaptation to exercise training: AMP-activated protein kinase mediates muscle fiber type shift. Diabetes. 2007;56:2062&#x2013;2069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17513699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu S, Choi SK, Joung SS, Suh H, Cha YS, Lee S, et al. Caffeine as a lipolytic food component increases endurance performance in rats and athletes. J. Nutr. Sci. Vitaminol. (Tokyo) 2001;47:139&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11508705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakamoto K, Hirshman MF, Aschenbach WG. Goodyear LJ. Contraction regulation of Akt in rat skeletal muscle. J. Biol. Chem. 2002;277:11910&#x2013;11917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakamoto K, Arnolds DE, Fujii N, Kramer HF, Hirshman MF. Goodyear LJ. Role of Akt2 in contraction-stimulated cell signaling and glucose uptake in skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2006;291:E1031&#x2013;E1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16803855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmonds MJ, Minahan CL. Sabapathy S. Caffeine improves supramaximal cycling but not the rate of anaerobic energy release. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2010;109:287&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20082092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stapleton D, Mitchelhill KI, Gao G, Widmer J, Michell BJ, Teh T, et al. Mammalian AMP-activated protein kinase subfamily. J. Biol. Chem. 1996;271:611&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8557660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein SC, Woods A, Jones NA, Davison MD. Carling D. The regulation of AMP-activated protein kinase by phosphorylation. Biochem. J. 2000;345(Pt 3):437&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1220775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky M. Cupido C. Caffeine potentiates low frequency skeletal muscle force in habitual and nonhabitual caffeine consumers. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 2000;89:1719&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyoda T, Hayashi T, Miyamoto L, Yonemitsu S, Nakano M, Tanaka S, et al. Possible involvement of the alpha1 isoform of 5&#x2032;AMP-activated protein kinase in oxidative stress-stimulated glucose transport in skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2004;287:E166&#x2013;E173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15026306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuda S, Egawa T, Ma X, Oshima R, Kurogi E. Hayashi T. Coffee polyphenol caffeic acid but not chlorogenic acid increases 5&#x2032;AMP-activated protein kinase and insulin-independent glucose transport in rat skeletal muscle. J. Nutr. Biochem. 2012;23:1403&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22227267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vavvas D, Apazidis A, Saha AK, Gamble J, Patel A, Kemp BE, et al. Contraction-induced changes in acetyl-CoA carboxylase and 5&#x2032;-AMP-activated kinase in skeletal muscle. J. Biol. Chem. 1997;272:13255&#x2013;13261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9148944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winder WW. Hardie DG. Inactivation of acetyl-CoA carboxylase and activation of AMP-activated protein kinase in muscle during exercise. Am. J. Physiol. 1996;270(2 Pt 1):E299&#x2013;E304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8779952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtaszewski JF, Birk JB, Frosig C, Holten M, Pilegaard H. Dela F. 5&#x2032;AMP activated protein kinase expression in human skeletal muscle: effects of strength training and type 2 diabetes. J. Physiol. 2005;564(Pt 2):563&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright DC, Hucker KA, Holloszy JO. Han DH. Ca2+ and AMPK both mediate stimulation of glucose transport by muscle contractions. Diabetes. 2004;53:330&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M, Falasca M. Blough ER. Akt/protein kinase B in skeletal muscle physiology and pathology. J. Cell. Physiol. 2011;226:29&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20672327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young DA, Uhl JJ, Cartee GD. Holloszy JO. Activation of glucose transport in muscle by prolonged exposure to insulin. Effects of glucose and insulin concentrations. J. Biol. Chem. 1986;261:16049&#x2013;16053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3536920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng D, MacLean PS, Pohnert SC, Knight JB, Olson AL, Winder WW, et al. Regulation of muscle GLUT-4 transcription by AMP-activated protein kinase. J. Appl. Physiol. 2001;91:1073&#x2013;1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Takatsu S, Wang H. Hasegawa H. Acute intraperitoneal injection of caffeine improves endurance exercise performance in association with increasing brain dopamine release during exercise. Pharmacol. Biochem. Behav. 2014;122:136&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24726708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>