<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32796411</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Pre-exercise Acute Vibration Training on Symptoms of Exercise-Induced Muscle Damage: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2339</StartPage><EndPage>2348</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2339-2348</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003789</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tan, J, Shi, X, Witchalls, J, Waddington, G, Lun Fu, AC, Wu, S, Tirosh, O, Wu, X, and Han, J. Effects of pre-exercise acute vibration training on symptoms of exercise-induced muscle damage: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 36(8): 2339-2348, 2022-Exercise-induced muscle damage (EIMD) normally occurs after unaccustomed high-intensity eccentric exercises. Symptoms of EIMD include delayed-onset muscle soreness (DOMS), tenderness, stiffness, swelling, reduced strength, and increased creatine kinase (CK) levels in the blood. Vibration training (VT) may be useful as a pre-exercise intervention in attenuating EIMD on the basis of tonic vibration reflex (TVR) through a more efficient distribution of contractile stress over muscle fibers. The objective of this meta-analysis is to examine the effects of acute VT on symptoms of EIMD when performed as the pre-exercise intervention. Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) published in the 8 databases of Cochrane Library, PubMed, Embase, Web of Science, EBSCO, China National Knowledge Infrastructure, Airiti Library and WanFang Data from 1966 (the earliest available time) to January 2019 were searched. A total of 2,324 records were identified and 448 articles were screened with the title and abstract. Two investigators identified eligible studies, extracted data, and assessed the risk of bias independently. Review Manager 5.3 designed by Cochrane was used for the current meta-analysis. Six RCTs involving 180 subjects were included in the analysis. A low-to-moderate methodological quality of the included studies was revealed using the physiotherapy evidence database scale. The results showed that acute VT was superior to the control group for the reduction of DOMS on pain visual analogue scale at 24, 48 hours and pressure pain threshold at 24 hours. In addition, superior effects of acute VT were also found on the indirect markers of muscle damage including CK at 24, 72 hours, and lactate dehydrogenase at 24 hours. The current meta-analysis has collated the evidence to demonstrate that receiving acute VT before unaccustomed high-intensity eccentric exercises may be effective in attenuating markers of muscle damage and the development of DOMS when compared with a control group. The possible mechanisms of this effect could be attributed to an improved synchronization of muscle fiber caused by TVR, which could result in even distribution of exterior loads and eventually attenuate disruptions of muscle fibers. In addition, increased blood flow may also be helpful to prevent accumulation of metabolic substances and attenuate subsequent symptoms of EIMD. Vibration training may be used as a pre-exercise intervention to alleviate symptoms of EIMD caused by unaccustomed high-intensity eccentric exercise. Because of the limited quantity and quality of included studies, more high-quality studies are required to ascertain the effect of VT on symptoms of EIMD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Jingwang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Witchalls</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Bruce, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waddington</LastName><ForeName>Gordon</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Bruce, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lun Fu</LastName><ForeName>Allan C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Physiotherapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, the University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Sam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Arts and Design, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tirosh</LastName><ForeName>Oren</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Arts and Design, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xueping</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport Training, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Bruce, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Arts and Design, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026741" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Therapy Modalities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014732" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vibration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202208000-00041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aminian-Far A, Hadian MR, Olyaei G, Talebian S, Bakhtiary AH. Whole-body vibration and the prevention and treatment of delayed-onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train 46: 43&#x2013;49, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB. Mechanisms of exercise-induced delayed onset muscular soreness: A brief review. Med Sci Sports Exerc 16: 529&#x2013;538, 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhtiary AH, Safavi-Farokhi Z, Aminian-Far A. Influence of vibration on delayed onset of muscle soreness following eccentric exercise. Br J Sports Med 41: 145&#x2013;148, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges LS, Cerqueira MS, Rocha JADS, et al. Light-emitting diode pexerchototherapy improves muscle recovery after a damaging exercise. Lasers Med Sci 29: 1139&#x2013;1144, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Cardinale M, Tsarpela O. Influence of vibration on mechanical power and electromyogram activity in human arm flexor muscles. Eur J Appl Physiol 79: 306&#x2013;311, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinale M, Bosco C. The use of vibration as an exercise intervention. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 31: 3&#x2013;7, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung K, Hume P, Maxwell L. Delayed onset muscle soreness: Treatment strategies and performance factors. Sports Med 33: 145&#x2013;164, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane DJ. Effectiveness of using wearable vibration therapy to alleviate muscle soreness. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 1&#x2013;9, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane DJ, Stannard SR, Sargeant AJ, Rittweger J. The rate of muscle temperature increase during acute whole-body vibration exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 103: 441&#x2013;448, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly DA, Sayers SP, Mchugh MP. Treatment and prevention of delayed onset muscle soreness. J Strength Cond Res 17: 197&#x2013;208, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, Deane RS, Triplett NT, Mcbride JM. Acute effects of whole-body vibration on muscle activity, strength, and power. J Strength Cond Res 20: 257&#x2013;261, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabbs NC, Black CD, Garner J. Whole-body vibration while squatting and delayed-onset muscle soreness in women. J Athl Train 50: 1233&#x2013;1239, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Morton NA. The PEDro scale is a valid measure of the methodological quality of clinical trials: A demographic study. Aust J Physiother 55: 129&#x2013;133, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira LC, De Oliveira RG, Piresoliveira DADA. Effects of whole body vibration on bone mineral density in postmenopausal women: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoporos Int 27: 2913&#x2013;2933, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuy O, Douzi W, Theurot D, Bosquet L, Dugue B. An evidence-based approach for choosing post-exercise recovery techniques to reduce markers of muscle damage, soreness, fatigue, and inflammation: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Physiol 9: 1&#x2013;15, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernst E. Does post-exercise massage treatment reduce delayed onset muscle soreness? A systematic review. Br J Sports Med 32: 212&#x2013;214, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eston R, Peters D. Effects of cold water immersion on the symptoms of exercise-induced muscle damage. J Sports Sci 17: 231&#x2013;238, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu CL, Yung SH, Law KY, et al. The effect of early whole-body vibration therapy on neuromuscular control after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med 41: 804&#x2013;814, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Games KE, Sefton JM, Wilson AE. Whole-body vibration and blood flow and muscle oxygenation: A meta-analysis. J Athl Train 50: 542&#x2013;549, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Li L, Gong Y, et al. Massage alleviates delayed onset muscle soreness after strenuous exercise: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol 8: 747&#x2013;812, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahne AJ, Ford JJ, Mcmeeken JM. Conservative management of lumbar disc herniation with associated radiculopathy: A systematic review. Spine 35: E488&#x2013;E504, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiss R, Lutter C, Freiwald J, et al. Advances in delayed-onset muscle soreness (DOMS)&#x2014;Part II: Treatment and prevention. Sportverletz Sportschaden 33: 21&#x2013;29, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert RD, De NM, Kamper SJ. Stretching to prevent or reduce muscle soreness after exercise. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 7: 1&#x2013;48, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert RD, Gabriel M, Herbert RD, Gabriel M. Effects of stretching before and after exercising on muscle soreness and risk of injury: Systematic review. BMJ 325: 468&#x2013;470, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, Gotzsche PC, et al. The cochrane collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 343: 1&#x2013;9, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Milak A. Exercise-induced muscle damage following a bout of sport specific repeated sprints. J Strength Cond Res 23: 2419&#x2013;2424, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl RD, Chen TC, Nosaka K. Mechanisms and mediators of the skeletal muscle repeated bout effect. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 45: 24&#x2013;33, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB, Tenenbaum G. Acute and residual effects of vibratory stimulation on explosive strength in elite and amateur athletes. J Sports Sci 17: 177&#x2013;182, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamandani R, Ghazalian F, Ebrahim K, et al. The effect of acute vibration training on delayed onset muscle soreness in young non-athlete women. Health Scope 2: 119&#x2013;124, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerschanschindl K, Grampp S, Henk C, et al. Whole-body vibration exercise leads to alterations in muscle blood volume. Clin Physiol 21: 377&#x2013;382, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Kang DH, Lee JH, Se-Min O, Jeon JK. The effects of pre-exercise vibration stimulation on the exercise-induced muscle damage. J Phys Ther Sci 29: 119&#x2013;122, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau WY, Nosaka K. Effect of vibration treatment on symptoms associated with eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 90: 648&#x2013;657, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Gissane C, Van Someren K, Gregson W, Howatson G. Cold water immersion and recovery from strenuous exercise: A meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 46: 233&#x2013;240, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Loreto C, Ranchelli A, Lucidi P, et al. Effects of whole-body vibration exercise on the endocrine system of healthy men. J Endocrinol Invest 27: 323&#x2013;327, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Wang Y, Lu J, et al. Does vibration benefit delayed-onset muscle soreness? A meta-analysis and systematic review. J Int Med Res 47: 3&#x2013;18, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magoffin R, Parcell AC, Hyldahl RD, et al. Whole-body vibration as a warm-up before exercise-induced muscle damage on symptoms of delayed-onset muscle soreness in trained subjects. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1123&#x2013;1132, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahbub MH, Hiroshige K, Yamaguchi N, et al. A systematic review of studies investigating the effects of controlled whole&#x2010;body vibration intervention on peripheral circulation. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 39: 363&#x2013;377, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mar&#xed;n PJ, Rhea MR. Effects of vibration training on muscle power: A meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 24: 871&#x2013;878, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mar&#xed;n PJ, Rhea MR. Effects of vibration training on muscle strength: A meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 24: 548&#x2013;556, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin PJ, Zarzuela R, Zarzosa F, et al. Whole-body vibration as a method of recovery for soccer players. Eur J Appl Physiol 12: 2&#x2013;8, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG; PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLoS Med 6: e1000097, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nampo F, Cavalheri V, Ramos S, Camargo E. Effect of low-level phototherapy on delayed onset muscle soreness: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Lasers Med Sci 31: 165&#x2013;177, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM. Muscle damage following repeated bouts of high force eccentric exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 27: 1263&#x2013;1269, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osawa Y, Oguma Y. Effects of vibration on flexibility: A meta-analysis. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 13: 442&#x2013;453, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearcey GEP, Bradburysquires DJ, Kawamoto J, et al. Foam rolling for delayed-onset muscle soreness and recovery of dynamic performance measures. J Athl Train 50: 5&#x2013;13, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehn B, Lidstr&#xf6;m J, Skoglund J, Lindstr&#xf6;m B. Effects on leg muscular performance from whole-body vibration exercise: A systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports 17: 2&#x2013;11, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittweger J, Ehrig J, Just K, et al. Oxygen uptake in whole-body vibration exercise: Influence of vibration frequency, amplitude, and external load. Int J Sports Med 23: 428&#x2013;432, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittweger J, Schiessl H, Felsenberg D. Oxygen uptake during whole-body vibration exercise: Comparison with squatting as a slow voluntary movement. Eur J Appl Physiol 86: 169&#x2013;173, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson CC, Barreto RPG, Sbruzzi G, Plentz RDM. The effects of whole body vibration in patients with type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Braz J Phys Ther 20: 4&#x2013;14, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelants M, Verschueren SM, Delecluse C, Levin O, Stijnen V. Whole-body-vibration-induced increase in leg muscle activity during different squat exercises. J Strength Cond Res 20: 124&#x2013;129, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva UD, Ortega DJ. Effects of whole-body vibration over delayed-onset muscle soreness in physical active persons. Eur J Phys Educ Sport Sci 3: 28&#x2013;37, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon VS, Wolfgang K, Michael B, Klaus E, Kalender WA. Effects of whole-body vibration training on different devices on bone mineral density. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1071&#x2013;1079, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LL, Keating MN, Holbert D, et al. The effects of athletic massage on delayed onset muscle soreness, creatine kinase, and neutrophil count: A preliminary report. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 19: 93&#x2013;99, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza-Silva E, Wittrup CS, Hirata RP, Larsen RG, Graven-Nielsen T. Blood flow after contraction and cuff occlusion is reduced in subjects with muscle soreness after eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports 28: 29&#x2013;39, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stay JC, Richard MD, Draper DO, Schulthies SS, Durrant E. Pulsed ultrasound fails to diminish delayed-onset muscle soreness symptoms. J Athl Train 33: 341&#x2013;346, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torvinen S, Kannus P, Sievanen H, et al. Effect of a vibration exposure on muscular performance and body balance. Randomized cross&#x2010;over study. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 22: 145&#x2013;152, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veqar Z, Imtiyaz S. Vibration therapy in management of delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS). J Clin Diagn Res 8: LE01&#x2013;LE04, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verducci FM. Interval cryotherapy decreases fatigue during repeated weight lifting. J Athl Train 35: 422&#x2013;426, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhagen AP, De Vet HC, De Bie RA, et al. The Delphi list: A criteria list for quality assessment of randomized clinical trials for conducting systematic reviews developed by Delphi consensus. J Clin Epidemiol 51: 1235&#x2013;1241, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu BH, Yeh NC, Wu CC. Effects of whole body vibration and static stretching on attenuation of delayed onset of muscle soreness following eccentric exercise. Sports Exerc Res 13: 470&#x2013;478, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zainuddin ZA, Newton M, Sacco P, Nosaka K. Effects of massage on delayed-onset muscle soreness, swelling, and recovery of muscle function. J Athl Train 40: 174&#x2013;180, 2005.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>