<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41618893</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1557-9891</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Feb</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of men's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Mens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Carbohydrate Combined with Caffeine on the Sports Performance of Basketball Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15579883251412111</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15579883251412111</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">15579883251412111</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15579883251412111</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this study is to investigate the effects of combined carbohydrate (CH) and caffeine (CAF) supplementation on the sports performance of basketball players. A randomized crossover controlled experimental design was employed. A total of 32 collegiate-level basketball players were randomly assigned to one of the four groups: placebo (PLA), CH (30 g/h glucose solution) group, CAF (3 mg/kg body mass) group, and CH + CAF (combined intervention) group. Participants underwent a series of tests, including the countermovement jump (CMJ), 20-m sprint (20 m), change-of-direction and acceleration test (CODAT), Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test level 1 (Yo-Yo), free throw (FT) test, and straight-line dribbling speed (SLDS) test. Heart rate (HR) and blood lactic acid (BLA) levels were also monitored during the tests. The results revealed that, in the CMJ, 20 m, and CODAT tests, the CAF and CH + CAF groups outperformed the PLA group significantly (<i>p</i> &lt; .05). In the Yo-Yo test, both the CH and CH + CAF groups demonstrated significantly better performance compared with the PLA group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01). However, no significant differences were observed among the groups in the FT and SLDS tests (<i>p</i> &gt; .05). Notably, the BLA levels in the CAF group were significantly higher than those in the PLA and CH groups 1-min postexercise (<i>p</i> &lt; .05), and also significantly higher than in the CH + CAF group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01). Three min after exercise, BLA levels in both the CH + CAF and PLA groups increased significantly (<i>p</i> &lt; .05), with the CH + CAF group showing a greater increase compared with the CH group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01). During exercise, the HR in the CH group was significantly lower than in the PLA group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01), while the HR in the CAF group was significantly higher than in the PLA group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01). Furthermore, the HR in the CH group was significantly lower compared with the CAF group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01), and the HR in the CH + CAF group was significantly higher than in the CAF group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01). After exercise, the HR in the CH group remained significantly lower than in the CAF group (<i>p</i> &lt; .01). In conclusion, the combined supplementation of CH + CAF can effectively improve the overall sports performance of basketball players, with a certain recovery effect on physiological responses, but has no significant impact on professional skills. Overall, joint supplementation has not shown significant synergistic effects, but it can still be used as one of the nutritional strategies, with flexible selection of usage based on actual needs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>XiaoDong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8409-1496</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blockchain and Healthcare, Health Service Research Center Xi'an, Xi'an Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Naichun</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blockchain and Healthcare, Health Service Research Center Xi'an, Xi'an Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Liangzhi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Blockchain and Healthcare, Health Service Research Center Xi'an, Xi'an Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Weilong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of physical education, Xi'an Physical Education University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Bao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty Education College, Shaoxing University, Shaoxing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Mens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101287723</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1557-9883</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004040">Dietary Carbohydrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001490" MajorTopicYN="Y">Basketball</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004040" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Carbohydrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">basketball players</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbohydrates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41618893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12861393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15579883251412111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abian-Vicen J., Puente C., Salinero J. J., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mill&#xe1;n C., Areces F., Munoz G., .&#x2004;.&#x2004;. Del Coso J. (2014). A caffeinated energy drink improves jump performance in adolescent basketball players. Amino Acids, 46(5), 1333&#x2013;1341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24599611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker L. B., Rollo I., Stein K. W., Jeukendrup A. E. (2015). Acute effects of carbohydrate supplementation on intermittent sports performance. Nutrients, 7(7), 5733&#x2013;5763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4517026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26184303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougrine H., Ammar A., Salem A., Trabelsi K., Jahrami H., Chtourou H., Souissi N. (2024). Optimizing short-term maximal exercise performance: The superior efficacy of a 6 mg/kg caffeine dose over 3 or 9 mg/kg in young female team-sports athletes. Nutrients, 16(5), 640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10935148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38474768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns S. P., Lindinger M. I. (2025). Lactic acidosis: Implications for human exercise performance. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 125, 1761&#x2013;1795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12227488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40088272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell B., Wilborn C., La Bounty P., Taylor L., Nelson M. T., Greenwood M., .&#x2004;.&#x2004;. Stout J. R. (2013). International society of sports nutrition position stand: Energy drinks. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition, 10(1), 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3538552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle E., Hagberg J., Hurley B., Martin W., Ehsani A., Holloszy J. (1983). Carbohydrate feeding during prolonged strenuous exercise can delay fatigue. Journal of Applied Physiology, 55(1), 230&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6350247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delextrat A., Cohen D. (2008). Physiological testing of basketball players: Toward a standard evaluation of anaerobic fitness. The Journal of Strength Conditioning Research, 22(4), 1066&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douligeris A., Methenitis S., Lazou A., Panayiotou G., Feidantsis K., Voulgaridou G., .&#x2004;.&#x2004;. Papadopoulou S. K. (2023). The effect of acute pre-workout supplement ingestion on basketball-specific performance of well-trained athletes. Nutrients, 15(10), 2304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10220844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37242187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein M. L., Brockfeld A., Haupt S., Schierbauer J. R., Zimmer R. T., Wachsmuth N. B., .&#x2004;.&#x2004;. Obermayer-Pietsch B. (2022). Acute changes in heart rate variability to glucose and fructose supplementation in healthy individuals: A double-blind randomized crossover placebo-controlled trial. Biology, 11(2), 338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8869760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35205205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faude O., Kindermann W., Meyer T. (2009). Lactate threshold concepts: How valid are they? Sports Med, 39(6), 469&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19453206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F., Erdfelder E., Lang A.-G., Buchner A. (2007). G* Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behavior Research Methods, 39(2), 175&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gant N., Ali A., Foskett A. (2010). The influence of caffeine and carbohydrate coingestion on simulated soccer performance. International Journal of Sport Nutrition Exercise Metabolism, 20(3), 191&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20601736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb R., Shalom A., Alcaraz P. E., Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. (2022). Validity and reliability of a unique aerobic field test for estimating VO2max among basketball players. Scientific Journal of Sport Performance, 1(2), 112&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. (2022). A comprehensive assessment of caffeine&#x2019;s effects on components of countermovement jump performance. Biology of Sport, 39(3), 515&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9331331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35959339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heydari N., Shojaee M., Nemati J., Dehghani A. R., Niknam A., Eftekhari F., Hemmatinafar M. (2025). Combined effects of postactivation performance enhancement and caffeine intake on explosive and anaerobic power in recreationally active males. Current Developments in Nutrition, 9(5), 107437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12243049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40641656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karjalainen V. (2021). Developing endurance for sports performance in a basketball team. Haaga-Helia University of Applied Sciences, Available from Cnki.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaviani M., Salari S. (2025). Caffeine and its molecular and physiological effects on skeletal muscle. In Preedy V. R., Patel V. B. (Eds.), Coffee in health and disease prevention (pp. 565&#x2013;574). Elsevier.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keane J., Shovlin A., Devenney S., Malone S., Young D., Coratella G., .&#x2004;.&#x2004;. Shortall M. (2020). The performance effect of scheduled carbohydrate and caffeine intake during simulated team sport match-play. Nutrients, 12(7), 1926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32610573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause J. V., Nelson C. (2019). Basketball skills &amp; drills. Human Kinetics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krings B. M., Rountree J. A., McAllister M. J., Cummings P. M., Peterson T. J., Fountain B. J., Smith J. W. (2016). Effects of acute carbohydrate ingestion on anaerobic exercise performance. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition, 13, 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5105234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27843418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima-Silva A. E., Cristina-Souza G., Silva-Cavalcante M. D., Bertuzzi R., Bishop D. J. (2021). Caffeine during high-intensity whole-body exercise: An integrative approach beyond the central nervous system. Nutrients, 13(8), 2503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8400708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H.-S., Liu C.-C., Shiu Y.-J., Lan P.-T., Wang A.-Y., Chiu C.-H. (2024). Caffeinated chewing gum improves basketball shooting accuracy and physical performance indicators of trained basketball players: A double-blind crossover trial. Nutrients, 16(9), 1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11085922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38732503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Seoane J., Buitrago-Morales M., Jim&#xe9;nez S. L., Del Coso J., Pareja-Galeano H. (2024). Synergy of carbohydrate and caffeine ingestion on physical performance and metabolic responses to exercise: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Critical Reviews in Food Science Nutrition, 64(10), 2941&#x2013;2959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36178302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorino A. J., Lloyd L. K., Crixell S. H., Walker J. L. (2006). The effects of caffeine on athletic agility. The Journal of Strength Conditioning Research, 20(4), 851&#x2013;854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdavi R., Daneghian S., Jafari A., Homayouni A. (2015). Effect of acute caffeine supplementation on anaerobic power and blood lactate levels in female athletes. Journal of Caffeine Research, 5(2), 83&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher R. (2018). New perspectives on choking at the free-throw line. Victoria University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArdle W. D. (2018). Sports and exercise nutrition. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderi A., Gobbi N., Ali A., Berjisian E., Hamidvand A., Forbes S. C., .&#x2004;.&#x2004;. Saunders B. (2023). Carbohydrates and endurance exercise: A narrative review of a food first approach. Nutrients, 15(6), 1367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10054587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36986096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olteanu M., Oancea B. M., Badau D. (2023). Improving effectiveness of basketball free throws through the implementation of technologies in the technical training process. Applied Sciences, 13(4), 2650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puente C., Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J., Salinero J. J., Lara B., Areces F., Del Coso J. (2017). Caffeine improves basketball performance in experienced basketball players. Nutrients, 9(9), 1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28925969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo D. J., Clemente-Suarez V. J., Cupeiro R., Benitez-Munoz J. A., Andreu Caravaca L., Rubio-Arias J. &#xc1;. (2024). The ergogenic effects of acute carbohydrate feeding on endurance performance: A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression. Critical Reviews in Food Science Nutrition, 64(30), 11196&#x2013;11205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37449467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J., Scanlan A. T., Soto-C&#xe9;lix M., Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez A., Castillo D. (2021). Caffeine ingestion improves performance during fitness tests but does not alter activity during simulated games in professional basketball players. International Journal of Sports Physiology Performance, 16(3), 387&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33401238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts S. P., Stokes K. A., Trewartha G., Doyle J., Hogben P., Thompson D. (2010). Effects of carbohydrate and caffeine ingestion on performance during a rugby union simulation protocol. Journal of Sports Sciences, 28(8), 833&#x2013;842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20521199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlan A. T., Dalbo V. J., Conte D., Stojanovi&#x107; E., Stojiljkovi&#x107; N., Stankovi&#x107; R., .&#x2004;.&#x2004;. Milanovi&#x107; Z. (2019). No effect of caffeine supplementation on dribbling speed in elite basketball players. International Journal of Sports Physiology Performance, 14(7), 997&#x2013;1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30569790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovi&#x107; E., Scanlan A. T., Milanovi&#x107; Z., Fox J. L., Stankovi&#x107; R., Dalbo V. J. (2022). Acute caffeine supplementation improves jumping, sprinting, and change-of-direction performance in basketball players when ingested in the morning but not evening. European Journal of Sport Science, 22(3), 360&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovi&#x107; E., Stojiljkovi&#x107; N., Scanlan A. T., Dalbo V. J., Stankovi&#x107; R., Anti&#x107; V., Milanovi&#x107; Z. (2019). Acute caffeine supplementation promotes small to moderate improvements in performance tests indicative of in-game success in professional female basketball players. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, Metabolism, 44(8), 849&#x2013;856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30633542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama T., Maeo S., Kurihara T., Kanehisa H., Isaka T. (2021). Change of direction speed tests in basketball players: A brief review of test varieties and recent trends. Frontiers in Sports Active Living, 3, Article 645350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33997779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szerej K., Dorobek W., Stankiewicz K., &#x15a;wieczkowski-Feiz J. (2024). The role of caffeine in enhancing physical performance: From metabolism to muscle function. Journal of Education, Health and Sport, 59, 158&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Z. S., Sim A., Kawabata M., Burns S. F. (2022). A systematic review of the effects of caffeine on basketball performance outcomes. Biology-Basel, 11(3), 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8773249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35053015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenbogaerde T. J., Hopkins W. G. (2011). Effects of acute carbohydrate supplementation on endurance performance: A meta-analysis. Sports Medicine, 41(9), 773&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21846165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale K., Getzin A. (2019). Nutrition and supplement update for the endurance athlete: Review and recommendations. Nutrients, 11(6), 1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6628334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31181616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen N., Dalbo V. J., Burgos B., Pyne D. B., Scanlan A. T. J. T. J., o S. (2018). Power testing in basketball: Current practice and future recommendations. The journal of Strength Conditioning Research, 32(9), 2677&#x2013;2691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29401204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>