<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34861076</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of caffeine on rate of force development: A meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>644</StartPage><EndPage>653</EndPage><MedlinePgn>644-653</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.14109</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This review aimed to conduct a meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of caffeine on rate of force development (RFD). Ten databases were searched to find relevant studies. Risk of bias (RoB) of the included studies was evaluated. Data were analyzed in a random-effects meta-analysis. Eleven studies with "some concerns" regarding RoB were included. In the main meta-analysis, there was a significant ergogenic effect of caffeine ingestion on RFD (Hedges' g&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.37; 95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.21, 0.52; p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001). An ergogenic effect of caffeine was also found on RFD during resistance exercises (Hedges' g&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.49; 95% CI: 0.30, 0.67; p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001), but not during the countermovement jump test (Hedges' g&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.18; 95% CI: -0.02, 0.39; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.08), with a significant difference between the subgroups (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.03). Small-to-moderate (3-5&#xa0;mg/kg; Hedges' g&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.25; 95% CI: 0.09, 0.41; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.002) and moderate-to-high caffeine doses (6-10&#xa0;mg/kg) enhanced RFD (Hedges' g&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.57; 95% CI: 0.30, 0.85; p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001), even though the effects were larger with higher caffeine doses (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.04). Overall, caffeine ingestion increases RFD, which is relevant given that RFD is commonly associated with sport-specific tasks. From a practical perspective: (1) individuals interested in the acute enhancement of RFD in resistance exercise may consider supplementing with caffeine; and (2) given that evaluation of RFD is most commonly used for testing purposes, caffeine ingestion (3-10&#xa0;mg/kg 60&#xa0;min before exercise) should be standardized before RFD assessments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grgic</LastName><ForeName>Jozo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6929-2844</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Vic, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mikulic</LastName><ForeName>Pavle</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1244-631X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">data synthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ergogenic aids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supplements</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34861076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:1318-1326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, Folland J, Tillin N, Duchateau J. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:1091-1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Pain MT, Folland J. Explosive force production during isometric squats correlates with athletic performance in rugby union players. J Sports Sci. 2013;31:66-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Sabido R. Rate of force development: reliability, improvements and influence on performance. A Review. Eur J Hum Mov. 2014;33:46-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Suetta C, Caserotti P, Magnusson SP, Kjaer M. Role of the nervous system in sarcopenia and muscle atrophy with aging: strength training as a countermeasure. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:49-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Pickering C, Schoenfeld BJ, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z. Wake up and smell the coffee: caffeine supplementation and exercise performance-an umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:681-688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Mu&#xf1;oz G, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J. Prevalence of caffeine use in elite athletes following its removal from the world anti-doping agency list of banned substances. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2011;36:555-561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren GL, Park ND, Maresca RD, McKibans KI, Millard-Stafford ML. Effect of caffeine ingestion on muscular strength and endurance: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1375-1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Trexler ET, Lazinica B, Pedisic Z. Effects of caffeine intake on muscle strength and power: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pickering C. The effects of caffeine ingestion on isokinetic muscular strength: a meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22:353-360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Del Coso J. Ergogenic effects of acute caffeine intake on muscular endurance and muscular strength in women: a meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:5773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Effects of caffeine on resistance exercise: a review of recent research. Sports Med. 2021;51(11):2281-229. 10.1007/s40279-021-01521-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Mau-Moeller A, Weippert M, et al. Caffeine-induced increase in voluntary activation and strength of the quadriceps muscle during isometric, concentric and eccentric contractions. Sci Rep. 2015;5:10209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norum M, Risvang LC, Bj&#xf8;rnsen T, et al. Caffeine increases strength and power performance in resistance-trained females during early follicular phase. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30:2116-2129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson BM, Brown LE, Judelson DA, Gallo-Rebert S, Coburn JW. Caffeine increases rate of torque development without affecting maximal torque. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2019;1:248-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, et al. IOC consensus statement: dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:439-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Mau-Moeller A, Heise S, Skripitz R, Bader R, Bruhn S. Alteration in neuromuscular function of the plantar flexors following caffeine ingestion. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25:e50-e58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J, Bradford C, Duncan MJ, Leddington-Wright S, Higgins MF, Hill M. The effect of acute caffeine ingestion on cognitive dual task performance during assessment of static and dynamic balance in older adults. Nutrients. 2020;12:3653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevino MA, Coburn JW, Brown LE, Judelson DA, Malek MH. Acute effects of caffeine on strength and muscle activation of the elbow flexors. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:513-520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Li T, Sterne J, et al. Revised cochrane risk of bias tool for randomized trials (RoB 2). additional considerations for crossover trials. Cochrane. 2020;1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction-GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64:383-394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest NS, VanDusseldorp TA, Nelson MT, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: caffeine and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JP, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d4002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkatan MF, Dowling EA, Branch DJ, Grieco C, Kollock RO, Williams MH. Effect of caffeine on maximum strength and rate of force development in male weight lifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloms LP, Fitzgerald JS, Short MW, Whitehead JR. The effects of caffeine on vertical jump height and execution in collegiate athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:1855-1861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke BI, Travis SK, Gentles JA, Sato K, Lang HM, Bazyler CD. The effects of caffeine on jumping performance and maximal strength in female collegiate athletes. Nutrients. 2021;13:2496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merino Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Ruiz-Moreno C, Gir&#xe1;ldez-Costas V, et al. Caffeine doses of 3 mg/kg increase unilateral and bilateral vertical jump outcomes in elite traditional Jiu-Jitsu athletes. Nutrients. 2021;13:1705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbinden-Foncea H, Rada I, Gomez J, et al. Effects of caffeine on countermovement-jump performance variables in elite male volleyball players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13:145-150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Caffeine ingestion enhances Wingate performance: a meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18:219-225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinero JJ, Lara B, Del Coso J. Effects of acute ingestion of caffeine on team sports performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Res Sports Med. 2019;27(2):238-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hori N, Newton RU, Kawamori N, McGuigan MR, Kraemer WJ, Nosaka K. Reliability of performance measurements derived from ground reaction force data during countermovement jump and the influence of sampling frequency. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:874-882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza AA, Bottaro M, Rocha VA, Lage V, Tufano JJ, Vieira A. Reliability and test-retest agreement of mechanical variables obtained during countermovement jump. Int J Exerc Sci. 2020;13:6-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currell K, Jeukendrup AE. Validity, reliability and sensitivity of measures of sporting performance. Sports Med. 2008;38:297-316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallar&#xe9;s JG, Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as VE, Ortega JF, Mu&#xf1;oz G, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R. Neuromuscular responses to incremental caffeine doses: performance and side effects. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:2184-2192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A, Negro F, Holobar A, et al. You are as fast as your motor neurons: speed of recruitment and maximal discharge of motor neurons determine the maximal rate of force development in humans. J Physiol. 2019;597:2445-2456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black CD, Waddell DE, Gonglach AR. Caffeine&#x2019;s ergogenic effects on cycling: neuromuscular and perceptual factors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(6):1145-1158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitts RH. The cross-bridge cycle and skeletal muscle fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104:551-558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metzger JM, Moss RL. Calcium-sensitive cross-bridge transitions in mammalian fast and slow skeletal muscle fibers. Science. 1990;247:1088-1090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J, Duncan MJ, James RS. What can isolated skeletal muscle experiments tell us about the effects of caffeine on exercise performance? Br J Pharmacol. 2015;172:3703-3713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DG, Westerblad H. The effects of caffeine on intracellular calcium, force and the rate of relaxation of mouse skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 1995;487:331-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James RS, Wilson RS, Askew GN. Effects of caffeine on mouse skeletal muscle power output during recovery from fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 2004;96:545-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Pain MT, Folland JP. Short-term unilateral resistance training affects the agonist-antagonist but not the force-agonist activation relationship. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43:375-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR. A basic introduction to fixed-effect and random-effects models for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010;1:97-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabol F, Grgic J, Mikulic P. The effects of 3 different doses of caffeine on jumping and throwing performance: a randomized, double-blind, crossover study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:1170-1177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Wilson CJ, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias JA. Effects of resistance training movement pattern and velocity on isometric muscular rate of force development: a systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. Sports Med. 2020;50:943-963.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>