<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41058995</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of dietary supplements on sports performance outcomes: a systematic review of evidence in elite athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1675654</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1675654</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1675654</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2025.1675654</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To systematically evaluate the efficacy of dietary supplements for enhancing athletic performance specifically in elite athletes, considering supplement type, dosing protocols, and sport-specific demands.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This PRISMA-adherent systematic review (INPLASY202411036) searched PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus, and SportDiscus (Jan 2014-Nov 2024) for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) or controlled clinical trials examining dietary supplement interventions in elite athletes, compared to placebo/no intervention, reporting quantitative performance outcomes. Methodological quality was assessed using the PEDro scale; risk of bias was evaluated with the Cochrane Risk of Bias Tool V.2. Narrative synthesis was performed due to outcome heterogeneity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Forty-six studies (<i>n</i> = 928 participants) met inclusion criteria, with predominantly male participants (60%). Performance enhancers showed varying efficacy: caffeine (3-6 mg/kg) consistently improved power output and technical performance; beta-alanine demonstrated sport-specific benefits; while nitrate supplementation showed limited effects in elite populations. Recovery supplements displayed mixed results, with amino acids and probiotics showing promise for fatigue prevention and exercise tolerance. Studies demonstrated high methodological quality (average PEDro score: 10.65/11), though female athletes were underrepresented (10% of studies).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Dietary supplement efficacy in elite athletes is highly variable, contingent upon supplement type, sport-specific demands, individualized dosing protocols, and athlete characteristics (including potential gender differences). Caffeine and certain amino acid/probiotic formulations demonstrate the most consistent benefits. Findings strongly support individualized, evidence-based supplementation strategies over generic protocols. Future research must address the significant gender gap and underrepresentation of specific sports.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Yu and Ding.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Tongwu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Communications Vocational and Technical College, Hefei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Chuanwei</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary supplements</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elite athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ergogenic aids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41058995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12498230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1675654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, Larson-Meyer DE, Peeling P, Phillips SM, et al. IOC consensus statement: dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Br J Sports Med. (2018) 52:439&#x2013;55. 10.1136/bjsports-2018-099027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29540367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi F, Yazdani A, Nematolahi F, Hosseini-Roknabadi SM, Sharifi N, Hosseini-Roknabadi SM, et al. Prevalence of supplement usage and related attitudes and reasons among fitness athletes in the gyms of Kashan and its relationship with feeding behavior: a cross-sectional study. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. (2024) 16:150. 10.1186/s13102-024-00940-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-024-00940-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11229390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38978090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIH . Dietary Supplements for Exercise and Athletic Performance. Bethesda: Office of Dietary Supplements, National Institute of Health. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Markets Bureau . Overview of the Global Sports Nutrition Market: Food, Beverages and Supplements. Ottawa: Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada, International Markets Bureau; (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcimed . Trends and Challenges in the Sports Nutrition Market. (2024) Available online at: http://www.alcimed.com/en/insights/sports-nutrition-market/ (Accessed 17 November, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catalani V, Negri A, Townshend H, Simonato P, Prilutskaya M, Tippett A, et al. The market of sport supplement in the digital era: a netnographic analysis of perceived risks, side-effects and other safety issues. Emerg Trends Drugs, Addict Health. (2021) 1:100014. 10.1016/j.etdah.2021.100014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.etdah.2021.100014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garthe I, Maughan RJ. Athletes and Supplements: Prevalence and Perspectives. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2018) 28:126&#x2013;38. 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29580114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garthe I, Ramsbottom R. Elite athletes, a rationale for the use of dietary supplements: a practical approach. PharmaNutrition. (2020) 14:100234. 10.1016/j.phanu.2020.100234</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phanu.2020.100234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman MW, Roche M, Fredericson M. The impact of supplements on sports performance for the trained athlete: a critical analysis. Curr Sports Med Rep. (2022) 21:232&#x2013;8. 10.1249/JSR.0000000000000972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000000972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35801724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeling P, Binnie MJ, Goods PSR, Sim M, Burke LM. Sim M, Burke LM. Evidence-based supplements for the enhancement of athletic performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2018) 28:178&#x2013;87. 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29465269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfieri A, D'Angelo S, Mazzeo F. Role of nutritional supplements in sport, exercise and health. Nutrients. (2023) 15:4429. 10.3390/nu15204429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15204429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapik JJ, Steelman RA, Hoedebecke SS, Austin KG, Farina EK, Lieberman HR, et al. Prevalence of dietary supplement use by athletes: systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. (2016) 46:103&#x2013;23. 10.1007/s40279-015-0387-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0387-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4697915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26442916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo D, Sun Y. Efficacy of dietary supplements on athlete performance outcomes: a systematic review of evidence in competitive athletes. In: INPLASY - International Platform of Registered Systematic Review and Meta-analysis Protocols. London: INPLASY International Registry; (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armijo-Olivo S, da Costa BR, Cummings GG, Ha C, Fuentes J, Saltaji H, et al. PEDro or cochrane to assess the quality of clinical trials? A meta-epidemiological study. PLoS ONE. (2015) 10:e0132634. 10.1371/journal.pone.0132634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0132634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4498768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26161653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Morton NA. The PEDro scale is a valid measure of the methodological quality of clinical trials: a demographic study. Aust J Physiother. (2009) 55:129&#x2013;33. 10.1016/S0004-9514(09)70043-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0004-9514(09)70043-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19463084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. (2019) 366:l4898. 10.1136/bmj.l4898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moseley AM, Rahman P, Wells GA, Zadro JR, Sherrington C, Toupin-April K, et al. Agreement between the Cochrane risk of bias tool and Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) scale: a meta-epidemiological study of randomized controlled trials of physical therapy interventions. PLoS ONE. (2019) 14:e0222770. 10.1371/journal.pone.0222770</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0222770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6752782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31536575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. (2011) 343:d5928. 10.1136/bmj.d5928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acar K, Mor A, Mor H, Kargin Z, Alexe DI, Abdioglu M, et al. Caffeine improves sprint time in simulated freestyle swimming competition but not the vertical jump in female swimmers. Nutrients. (2024) 16:1253. 10.3390/nu16091253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16091253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11085104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38732500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;vila-Gand&#xed;a V, Torregrosa-Garc&#xed;a A, P&#xe9;rez-Pi&#xf1;ero S, Ortolano R, Abell&#xe1;n-Ruiz MS, L&#xf3;pez-Rom&#xe1;n FJ, et al. One-week high-dose &#x3b2;-alanine loading improves world tour cyclists' time-trial performance. Nutrients. (2021) 13:2543. 10.3390/nu13082543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13082543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8401416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisola GMP, Milioni F, Papoti M, Zagatto AM. Effects of 4 weeks of &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on swim-performance parameters in water polo players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2017) 12:943&#x2013;50. 10.1123/ijspp.2016-0133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27967270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broelz EK, Wolf S, Schneeweiss P, Niess AM, Enck P, Weimer K. Niess AM, Enck P, Weimer K. Increasing effort without noticing: a randomized controlled pilot study about the ergogenic placebo effect in endurance athletes and the role of supplement salience. PLoS ONE. (2018) 13:e0198388. 10.1371/journal.pone.0198388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0198388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5995445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29889868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzdagli Y, Eyipinar CD, &#xd6;get F, Siktar E, Forbes SC, Tekin A. Siktar E, Forbes SC, Tekin A. Taurine supplementation enhances anaerobic power in elite speed skaters: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, crossover study. Biol Sport. (2023) 40:741&#x2013;51. 10.5114/biolsport.2023.119990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.119990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10286601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camerino SR, Lima RC, Fran&#xe7;a TC, Herculano EdeA, Rodrigues DS, Gouveia MG, et al. Keto analogue and amino acid supplementation and its effects on ammonemia and performance under thermoneutral conditions. Food Funct. (2016) 7:872&#x2013;80. 10.1039/C5FO01054C</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5FO01054C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26679329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Peixoto J, Moura MRL, Cunha FA, Lollo PC, Monteiro WD, Carvalho LM, et al. Consumption of a&#xe7;ai (<i>Euterpe oleracea</i> Mart.) functional beverage reduces muscle stress and improves effort tolerance in elite athletes: a randomized controlled intervention study. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. (2015) 40:725&#x2013;733. 10.1139/apnm-2014-0518
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2014-0518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26140415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen IF, Wu HJ, Chen CY, Chou KM, Chang CK. Branched-chain amino acids, arginine, citrulline alleviate central fatigue after 3 simulated matches in taekwondo athletes: a randomized controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2016) 13:28. 10.1186/s12970-016-0140-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-016-0140-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4944315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27418883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delleli S, Ouergui I, Messaoudi H, Bridge C, Ardig&#xf2; LP, Chtourou H, et al. Warm-up music and low-dose caffeine enhance the activity profile and psychophysiological responses during simulated combat in female taekwondo athletes. Sci Rep. (2024) 14:14302. 10.1038/s41598-024-64880-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-64880-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11192912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38906894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Jeszka J, Podg&#xf3;rski T. The effect of a 12-week beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) supplementation on highly-trained combat sports athletes: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled crossover study. Nutrients. (2017) 9:753. 10.3390/nu9070753</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9070753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28708126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Zawieja EE, Podg&#xf3;rski T, Zawieja BE, Micha&#x142;owska P, &#x141;oniewski I, et al. The effect of a new sodium bicarbonate loading regimen on anaerobic capacity and wrestling performance. Nutrients. (2018) 10:697. 10.3390/nu10060697</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10060697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec&#x2013;Michalski K, Zawieja EE, Zawieja BE, Micha&#x142;owska P, Podg&#xf3;rski T. The gender dependent influence of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on anaerobic power and specific performance in female and male wrestlers. Sci Rep. (2020) 10:1878. 10.1038/s41598-020-57590-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-57590-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, G&#x142;&#xf3;wka N, Podg&#xf3;rski T, Szymocha M, Przybylik B, Wochna K, et al. Does colostrum bovinum supplementation affect swimming performance in endurance-trained males? A randomized placebo-controlled crossover study. Nutrients. (2024) 16:3204. 10.3390/nu16183204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16183204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11435245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39339805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans M, Tierney P, Gray N, Hawe G, Macken M, Egan B. Hawe G, Macken M, Egan B. Acute ingestion of caffeinated chewing gum improves repeated sprint performance of team sport athletes with low habitual caffeine consumption. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2018) 28:221&#x2013;7. 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29091470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbairn KA, Ceelen IJM, Skeaff CM, Cameron CM, Perry TL, Cameron CM, et al. Vitamin D3 supplementation does not improve sprint performance in professional rugby players: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind intervention study. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2018) 28:1&#x2013;9. 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0157</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28771064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filip-Stachnik A, Krawczyk R, Krzysztofik M, Rzeszutko-Belzowska A, Dornowski M, Zajac A, et al. Effects of acute ingestion of caffeinated chewing gum on performance in elite judo athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2021) 18:49. 10.1186/s12970-021-00448-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00448-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34147116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fye H, Pass C, Dickman K, Bredahl E, Eckerson J, Siedlik J, et al. The Effect of a Multi-Ingredient Pre-Workout Supplement on Time to Fatigue in NCAA Division I Cross-Country Athletes. Nutrients. (2021) 13:1823. 10.3390/nu13061823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13061823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8228073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34071868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambardella J, Fiordelisi A, Spigno L, Boldrini L, Lungonelli G, Di Vaia E, et al. Effects of Chronic Supplementation of L-Arginine on Physical Fitness in Water Polo Players. Oxid Med Cell Longev. (2021) 2021:6684568. 10.1155/2021/6684568</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/6684568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7994081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33815657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham-Paulson TS, Perret C, Watson P, Goosey-Tolfrey VL. Improvement of sprint performance in wheelchair sportsmen with caffeine supplementation. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2016) 11:214&#x2013;20. 10.1123/ijspp.2015-0073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26182441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Wang S. Physiological and performance adaptations to beta alanine supplementation and short sprint interval training in volleyball players. Sci Rep. (2024) 14:16833. 10.1038/s41598-024-67974-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-67974-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11263668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39039103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurton WH, Gough LA, Siegler JC, Lynn A, Ranchordas MK, Lynn A, et al. Oral but not topical sodium bicarbonate improves repeated sprint performance during simulated soccer match play exercise in collegiate athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2024) 34:362&#x2013;71. 10.1123/ijsnem.2024-0059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2024-0059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39222921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jodra P, Lago-Rodr&#xed;guez A, S&#xe1;nchez-Oliver AJ, L&#xf3;pez-Samanes A, P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez A, Veiga-Herreros P, et al. Effects of caffeine supplementation on physical performance and mood dimensions in elite and trained-recreational athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2020) 17:2. 10.1186/s12970-019-0332-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-019-0332-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31900166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonvik KL, Nyakayiru J, Van Dijk JW, Maase K, Ballak SB, Senden JMG, et al. Repeated-sprint performance and plasma responses following beetroot juice supplementation do not differ between recreational, competitive and elite sprint athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. (2018) 18:524&#x2013;33. 10.1080/17461391.2018.1433722</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1433722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29412076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karayigit R, Naderi A, Akca F, Cruz CJGD, Sarshin A, Yasli BC, et al. Effects of different doses of caffeinated coffee on muscular endurance, cognitive performance, and cardiac autonomic modulation in caffeine naive female athletes. Nutrients. (2020) 13:2. 10.3390/nu13010002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13010002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33374947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopec BJ, Dawson BT, Buck C, Wallman KE. Effects of sodium phosphate and caffeine ingestion on repeated-sprint ability in male athletes. J Sci Med Sport. (2016) 19:272&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.jsams.2015.04.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25953613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara B, Ruiz-Vicente D, Areces F, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J, Salinero JJ, Gonzalez-Mill&#xe1;n C, et al. Acute consumption of a caffeinated energy drink enhances aspects of performance in sprint swimmers. Br J Nutr. (2015) 114:908&#x2013;14. 10.1017/S0007114515002573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114515002573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26279580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis EJH, Radonic PW, Wolever TMS, Wells GD. 21 days of mammalian omega-3 fatty acid supplementation improves aspects of neuromuscular function and performance in male athletes compared to olive oil placebo. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2015) 12:28. 10.1186/s12970-015-0089-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-015-0089-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26085822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HS, Liu CC, Shiu YJ, Lan PT, Wang AY, Chiu CH. Caffeinated chewing gum improves basketball shooting accuracy and physical performance indicators of trained basketball players: a double-blind crossover trial. Nutrients. (2024) 16:1256. 10.3390/nu16091256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16091256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11085922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38732503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuillan JA, Dulson DK, Laursen PB, Kilding AE. Dietary nitrate fails to improve 1 and 4 km cycling performance in highly trained cyclists. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2017) 27:255&#x2013;63. 10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27997263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Ruiz-Moreno C, Gir&#xe1;ldez-Costas V, Gonzalez-Mill&#xe1;n C, Matos-Duarte M, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Hell&#xed;n J, et al. Caffeine doses of 3 mg/kg increase unilateral and bilateral vertical jump outcomes in elite traditional Jiu-Jitsu athletes. Nutrients. (2021) 13:1705. 10.3390/nu13051705</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13051705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8157547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34069892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielgo-Ayuso J, Zourdos MC, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, C&#xf3;rdova A, Fernandez-L&#xe1;zaro D, Caballero-Garc&#xed;a A, et al. Eleven weeks of iron supplementation does not maintain iron status for an entire competitive season in elite female volleyball players: a follow-up study. Nutrients. (2018) 10:1526. 10.3390/nu10101526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10101526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6213587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30336598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miraftabi H, Avazpoor Z, Berjisian E, Sarshin A, Rezaei S, Dom&#xed;nguez R, et al. Effects of beetroot juice supplementation on cognitive function, aerobic and anaerobic performances of trained male taekwondo athletes: a pilot study. IJERPH. (2021) 18:10202. 10.3390/ijerph181910202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph181910202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8507686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34639501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyakayiru JM, Jonvik KL, Pinckaers PJ, Senden J, van Loon LJ, Verdijk LB. No effect of acute and 6-day nitrate supplementation on vo2 and time-trial performance in highly trained cyclists. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2017) 27:11&#x2013;7. 10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0034</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27616745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda &#xc1;H, Barahona-Fuentes G, Galdames Maliqueo S, Guzm&#xe1;n Solis M, Cabrera MMY, Jorquera-Aguilera C, et al. Acute supplementation with beta-alanine improves performance in aerobic-anaerobic transition zones in endurance athletes. J Am Nutr Assoc. (2023) 42:187&#x2013;94. 10.1080/07315724.2021.2020183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.2021.2020183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35512767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlando P, Silvestri S, Galeazzi R, Antonicelli R, Marcheggiani F, Cirilli I, et al. Effect of ubiquinol supplementation on biochemical and oxidative stress indexes after intense exercise in young athletes. Redox Report. (2018) 23:136&#x2013;45. 10.1080/13510002.2018.1472924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13510002.2018.1472924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6748686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29734881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paryab N, Taheri M, H'Mida C, Irandoust K, Mirmoezzi M, Trabelsi K, et al. Melatonin supplementation improves psychomotor and physical performance in collegiate student-athletes following a sleep deprivation night. Chronobiol Int. (2021) 38:753&#x2013;61. 10.1080/07420528.2021.1889578</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07420528.2021.1889578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portillo J, Del Coso J, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J. Effects of caffeine ingestion on skill performance during an international female rugby sevens competition. J Strength Cond Res. (2017) 31:3351&#x2013;7. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28002181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przew&#x142;&#xf3;cka K, Kujach S, Sawicki P, Berezka P, Bytowska ZK, Folwarski M, et al. Effects of probiotics and vitamin D3 supplementation on sports performance markers in male mixed martial arts athletes: a randomized trial. Sports Med Open. (2023) 9:31. 10.1186/s40798-023-00576-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00576-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10188824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37193828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puente C, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J, Salinero JJ, Lara B, Areces F, Del Coso J. Caffeine improves basketball performance in experienced basketball players. Nutrients. (2017) 9:1033. 10.3390/nu9091033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9091033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28925969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo DJ, P&#xe9;rez A, &#xc1;vila-Gand&#xed;a V, P&#xe9;rez-Pi&#xf1;ero S, Rubio-Arias J&#xc1;, P&#xe9;rez-Pi&#xf1;ero S, et al. Impact of caffeine intake on 800-m running performance and sleep quality in trained runners. Nutrients. (2019) 11:2040. 10.3390/nu11092040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11092040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31480553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber C, Tamir S, Golan R, Weinstein A, Weinstein Y. Weinstein A, Weinstein Y. The effect of probiotic supplementation on performance, inflammatory markers and gastro-intestinal symptoms in elite road cyclists. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2021) 18:36. 10.1186/s12970-021-00432-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00432-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8127283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34001168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu K, Kon M, Tanimura Y, Hanaoka Y, Kimura F, Akama T, et al. Coenzyme Q10 supplementation downregulates the increase of monocytes expressing toll-like receptor 4 in response to 6-day intensive training in kendo athletes. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. (2015) 40:575&#x2013;81. 10.1139/apnm-2014-0556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2014-0556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25941765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadheim HK, Stensrud T, Brage S, Jensen J. Caffeine increases exercise performance, maximal oxygen uptake, and oxygen deficit in elite male endurance athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2021) 53:2264&#x2013;73. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002704</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson JL, Krishnan S, Inigo MM, Stamatikos AD, Gonzales JU, Cooper JA, et al. Echinacea-based dietary supplement does not increase maximal aerobic capacity in endurance-trained men and women. J Diet Suppl. (2016) 13:324&#x2013;38. 10.3109/19390211.2015.1036189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/19390211.2015.1036189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26317662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz U, Buzdagli Y, Polat ML, Bakir Y, Ozhanci B, Alkazan S, et al. Effect of single or combined caffeine and L-Theanine supplementation on shooting and cognitive performance in elite curling athletes: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2023) 20:2267536. 10.1080/15502783.2023.2267536</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2023.2267536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10566444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37815006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garnacho-Casta&#xf1;o MV, Palau-Salv&#xe0; G, Cuenca E, Mu&#xf1;oz-Gonz&#xe1;lez A, Garc&#xed;a-Fern&#xe1;ndez P, Del Carmen Lozano-Estevan M, et al. Effects of a single dose of beetroot juice on cycling time trial performance at ventilatory thresholds intensity in male triathletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2018) 15:49. 10.1186/s12970-018-0255-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-018-0255-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6172780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sil A, Kumar P, Kumar R, Das NK. Selection of control, randomization, blinding, and allocation concealment. Indian Dermatol Online J. (2019) 10:601. 10.4103/idoj.IDOJ_149_19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/idoj.IDOJ_149_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6743387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31544090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaghan TF, Agudelo CW, Rahman SN, Wein AJ, Lazar JM, Everaert K, et al. Blinding in clinical trials: seeing the big picture. Medicina. (2021) 57:647. 10.3390/medicina57070647</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina57070647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8308085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34202486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Roberts MD, Smith-Ryan A, Kleiner SM, J&#xe4;ger R, et al. ISSN exercise &amp; sports nutrition review update: research &amp; recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2018) 15:38. 10.1186/s12970-018-0242-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-018-0242-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30068354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke R, Jones A. Recruiting adult participants to physical activity intervention studies using sport: a systematic review. BMJ Open Sport &#x2014; Exerc Med. (2017) 3:e000231. 10.1136/bmjsem-2017-000231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2017-000231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5530105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28761714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2021) 17:317&#x2013;331. 10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosscher VD, Descheemaeker K, Shibli S. Starting and specialisation ages of elite athletes across olympic sports: an international cross-sectional study. Eur J Sport Sci. (2023) 2:9&#x2013;19. 10.24018/ejsport.2023.2.5.100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24018/ejsport.2023.2.5.100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filip-Stachnik A, Wilk M, Krzysztofik M, Luli&#x144;ska E, Tufano JJ, Zajac A, et al. The effects of different doses of caffeine on maximal strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2021) 18:1&#x2013;16. 10.1186/s12970-021-00421-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00421-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Lara J, Nieto-Acevedo R, Abian-Vicen J, Del Coso J. Can caffeine change the game? Effects of acute caffeine intake on ecologically valid sport-specific actions: a meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2024) 19:1180&#x2013;96. 10.1123/ijspp.2023-0232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2023-0232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39168455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran-Bowen T, Guedes da Silva A, Barreto G, Buckley J, Saunders B. Sodium bicarbonate and beta-alanine supplementation: Is combining both better than either alone? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Biol Sport. (2024) 41:79&#x2013;87. 10.5114/biolsport.2024.132997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.132997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11167468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38952910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Del Coso J, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Effects of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on exercise performance: an umbrella review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2021) 18:71. 10.1186/s12970-021-00469-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00469-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8600864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34794476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macuh M, Knap B. Effects of nitrate supplementation on exercise performance in humans: a narrative review. Nutrients. (2021) 13:3183. 10.3390/nu13093183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13093183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8465461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34579061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RL, Stellingwerff T, Artioli GG, Saunders B, Cooper S, Sale C, et al. Dose-response of sodium bicarbonate ingestion highlights individuality in time course of blood analyte responses. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2016) 26:445&#x2013;53. 10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoon MW, Hopkins WG, Jones AM, Martin DT, Halson SL, West NP, et al. Nitrate supplementation and high-intensity performance in competitive cyclists. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. (2014) 39:1043&#x2013;9. 10.1139/apnm-2013-0574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2013-0574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24951296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poon ET-C, Pedlar C, McCord T, Wylie LJ, Jones AM. Dietary nitrate supplementation and exercise performance: an umbrella review of 20 published systematic reviews with meta-analyses. Sports Med. (2025). 10.1007/s40279-025-02194-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02194-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12106159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40085422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Xiang M, An N, Tan Q, Shao J, Wang Q. Effects of vitamin D3 supplementation on strength of lower limb muscles in athletes: an updated meta-analysis. Front Nutr. (2024) 11:1381301. 10.3389/fnut.2024.1381301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1381301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11163122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38860160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Dio M, Calella P, Pelullo CP, Liguori F, Di Onofrio V, Gall&#xe8; F, et al. Effects of probiotic supplementation on sports performance and performance-related features in athletes: a systematic review. Int J Environm Res Public Health. (2023) 20:2226. 10.3390/ijerph20032226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20032226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9914962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36767593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teglas T, Radak Z. Probiotic supplementation for optimizing athletic performance: Current evidence and future perspectives for microbiome-based strategies. Front Nutr. (2025) 12:1572687. 10.3389/fnut.2025.1572687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1572687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12306019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40735239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porepp ODSC, Xavier MG, da Silveira LM, Lindenau I, Schellin AS, Piccoli RC, et al. (2024). Effect of probiotic supplementation on gut microbiota and sport performance in athletes and physically active individuals: a systematic review. J Diet Supplem. 21:634&#x2013;54. 10.1080/19390211.2023.2293842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19390211.2023.2293842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38148685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viribay A, Burgos J, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Landa J, Seco-Calvo J, Mielgo-Ayuso J. Effects of arginine supplementation on athletic performance based on energy metabolism: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. (2020) 12:1300. 10.3390/nu12051300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12051300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32370176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavci Z, Ozan M, Buzdagli Y, Sava&#x15f; A, U&#xe7;ar H. Investigation of the effect of nitrate and L-arginine intake on aerobic, anaerobic performance, balance, agility, and recovery in elite taekwondo athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2024) 22:2445609. 10.1080/15502783.2024.2445609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2445609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11703352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39714103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talebi S, Pourgharib Shahi MH, Zeraattalab-Motlagh S, Asoudeh F, Ranjbar M, Hemmati A, et al. The effects of coenzyme Q10 supplementation on biomarkers of exercise-induced muscle damage, physical performance, and oxidative stress: a GRADE-assessed systematic review and dose&#x2013;response meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clini Nutr ESPEN. (2024) 60:122&#x2013;34. 10.1016/j.clnesp.2024.01.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2024.01.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38479900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes MSS, Fidelis DEDS, Aidar FJ, Badicu G, Greco G, Cataldi S, et al. Coenzyme Q10 supplementation in athletes: a systematic review. Nutrients. (2023) 15:3990. 10.3390/nu15183990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15183990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10535924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37764774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xe1;zaro D, Arribalzaga S, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Abej&#xf3;n E, Azarbayjani MA, Mielgo-Ayuso J, Roche E. Omega-3 fatty acid supplementation on post-exercise inflammation, muscle damage, oxidative response, and sports performance in physically healthy adults&#x2014;a systematic review of RCTs. Nutrients. (2024) 16:2044. 10.3390/nu16132044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16132044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11243702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38999792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salem A, Ben Maaoui K, Jahrami H, AlMarzooqi MA, Boukhris O, Messai B, et al. Attenuating muscle damage biomarkers and muscle soreness after an exercise-induced muscle damage with Branched-Chain Amino Acid (BCAA) supplementation: a systematic review and meta-analysis with meta-regression. Sports Med - Open. (2024) 10:29. 10.1186/s40798-024-00686-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00686-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11021390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38625669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest NS, VanDusseldorp TA, Nelson MT, Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Jenkins NDM, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: caffeine and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2021) 18:1&#x2013;37. 10.1186/s12970-020-00383-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-020-00383-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7777221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33388079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldas LC, Salgueiro RB, Clarke ND, Tallis J, Barauna VG, Guimaraes-Ferreira L. Effect of caffeine ingestion on indirect markers of exercise-induced muscle damage: a systematic review. Nutrients. (2022) 14:1803. 10.3390/nu14091769</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14091769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9099525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35565741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loureiro LMR, Reis CE, da Costa THM. Coffee increases post-exercise muscle glycogen resynthesis: a randomized trial. Nutrients. (2021) 13:3441. 10.3390/nu13103335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13103335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8537367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiou GD, Somerville M, Starr J, Rosenbloom C. Effect of beta-alanine supplementation on maximal intensity exercise in trained young males: systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2024) 34:397&#x2013;413. 10.1123/ijsnem.2024-0027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2024-0027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39032921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Shin Y-O. Pre-sleep casein protein ingestion: new paradigm in post-exercise recovery nutrition. J Exerc Rehabil. (2020) 16:479&#x2013;485. 10.20463/pan.2020.0009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2020.0009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7451833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trommelen J, Holwerda AM, Kouw IWK. Pre-sleep protein ingestion increases myofibrillar protein synthesis rates during overnight recovery. Nutrients. (2023) 15:1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10289916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salem A, Abouelyazid A, Abdelghaffar E. Branched-chain amino acid supplementation attenuates muscle damage biomarkers and soreness: systematic review &amp; meta-analysis of RCTs. Nutrients. (2024) 16:1091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulios A, Theodoropoulos V, Chatzinikolaou A. The effects of antioxidant supplementation on soccer performance and recovery: a systematic review. Antioxidants. (2024) 13:1564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11597853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39599590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason SA, Trewin AJ, Parker L, Wadley GD. Antioxidant supplements and endurance exercise: current evidence and practical considerations. Free Radic Biol Med. (2020) 160:117&#x2013;28. 10.1016/j.redox.2020.101471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.redox.2020.101471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32127289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Cumming KT, Holden G, Hall&#xe9;n J, R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Sveen O, et al. Vitamin C and E supplementation hampers cellular adaptation to endurance training in humans: RCT. J Physiol. (2014) 592:1887&#x2013;1901. 10.1113/jphysiol.2013.267419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2013.267419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4001759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24492839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x141;agowska K, Bajerska J, Kami&#x144;ski S, Del Bo' C. Effects of probiotics supplementation on gastrointestinal symptoms in athletes: a systematic review of RCTs. Nutrients. (2022) 14:2645. 10.3390/nu14132645</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14132645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9268154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35807826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abreu R, Oliveira CB, Costa JA, Brito J, Teixeira VH. Brito J, Teixeira VH. Effects of dietary supplements on athletic performance in elite soccer players: a systematic review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2023) 20:2236060. 10.1080/15502783.2023.2236060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2023.2236060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10355692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D. Dietary supplements and team-sport performance. Sports Med. (2010) 40:995&#x2013;1017. 10.2165/11536870-000000000-00000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11536870-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21058748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM. Dietary nitrate supplementation and exercise performance. Sports Med. (2014) 44:35. 10.1007/s40279-014-0149-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0149-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallien G, Bellar D, Davis GR. The efficacy of a pre-workout vegan supplement on high-intensity cycling performance in healthy college-aged males. J Diet Suppl. (2017) 14:697&#x2013;705. 10.1080/19390211.2017.1310780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19390211.2017.1310780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28429998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petr&#xf3;czi A, Naughton DP, Mazanov J, Holloway A, Bingham J. Holloway A, Bingham J. Performance enhancement with supplements: incongruence between rationale and practice. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2007) 4:19. 10.1186/1550-2783-4-19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-4-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2214727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17997853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petr&#xf3;czi A, Naughton DP, Pearce G, Bailey R, Bloodworth A, McNamee M, et al. Nutritional supplement use by elite young UK athletes: fallacies of advice regarding efficacy. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2008) 5:22. 10.1186/1550-2783-5-22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-5-22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19077317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa M, Fernandes MJ, Carvalho P, Soares J, Moreira P, Teixeira VH, et al. Nutritional supplements use in high-performance athletes is related with lower nutritional inadequacy from food. J Sport Health Sci. (2016) 5:368&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.jshs.2015.01.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2015.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6188619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlRuthia Y, Balkhi B, Alrasheed M, Altuwaijri A, Alarifi M, Alzahrani H, et al. Use of dietary and performance-enhancing supplements among male fitness center members in Riyadh: a cross-sectional study. PLoS ONE. (2018) 13:e0199289. 10.1371/journal.pone.0199289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0199289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6013215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29928034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>