<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34033621</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine Increases Exercise Performance, Maximal Oxygen Uptake, and Oxygen Deficit in Elite Male Endurance Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2264</StartPage><EndPage>2273</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2264-2273</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002704</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">The aims of the present study were to test the hypothesis that caffeine increases maximal oxygen uptake (V&#x2d9;O2max) and to characterize the physiological mechanisms underpinning improved high-intensity endurance capacity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Twenty-three elite endurance-trained male athletes were tested twice with and twice without caffeine (four tests) in a randomized, double-blinded, and placebo-controlled study with crossover design. Caffeine (4.5 mg&#xb7;kg-1) or placebo was consumed 45 min before standardized warm-up. Time to exhaustion during an incremental test (running 10.5&#xb0; incline, start speed 10.0 km&#xb7;h-1, and 0.5 km&#xb7;h-1 increase in speed every 30 s) determined performance. Oxygen uptake was measured continuously to determine V&#x2d9;O2max and O2 deficit was calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Caffeine increased time to exhaustion from 355 &#xb1; 41 to 375 &#xb1; 41 s (&#x394;19.4 &#xb1; 16.5 s; P &lt; 0.001). Importantly, caffeine increased V&#x2d9;O2max from 75.8 &#xb1; 5.6 to 76.7 &#xb1; 6.0 mL&#xb7;kg-1&#xb7;min-1 (&#x394; 0.9 &#xb1; 1.7 mL&#xb7;kg-1&#xb7;min-1; P &lt; 0.003). Caffeine increased maximal heart rate (HRpeak) and ventilation (VEpeak). Caffeine increased O2 deficit from 63.1 &#xb1; 18.2 to 69.5 &#xb1; 17.5 mL&#xb7;kg-1 (P &lt; 0.02) and blood lactate compared with placebo. The increase in time to exhaustion after caffeine ingestion was reduced to 11.7 s after adjustment for the increase in V&#x2d9;O2max. Caffeine did not significantly increase V&#x2d9;O2max after adjustment for VEpeak and HRpeak. Adjustment for O2 deficit and lactate explained 6.2 s of the caffeine-induced increase in time to exhaustion. The increase in V&#x2d9;O2max, VE, HR, O2 deficit, and lactate explained 63% of the increased performance after caffeine intake.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Caffeine increased V&#x2d9;O2max in elite athletes, which contributed to improvement in high-intensity endurance performance. Increases in O2 deficit and lactate also contributed to the caffeine-induced improvement in endurance performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stadheim</LastName><ForeName>Hans Kristian</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Ullev&#xe5;l Stadion, NORWAY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stensrud</LastName><ForeName>Trine</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Ullev&#xe5;l Stadion, NORWAY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brage</LastName><ForeName>S&#xf8;ren</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Epidemiology Unit, University of Cambridge School of Clinical Medicine, Institute of Metabolic Sciences, Cambridge Biomedical Campus, England, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jensen</LastName><ForeName>J&#xf8;rgen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Ullev&#xe5;l Stadion, NORWAY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MC_UU_00006/4</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S88TT14065</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010100">Oxygen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001628" MajorTopicYN="Y">Beverages</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="N">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010100" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012123" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Ventilation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="N">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202111000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Dalsky GP, Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports . 1978;10(3):155&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadheim HK, Kvamme B, Olsen R, Drevon CA, Ivy JL, Jensen J. Caffeine increases performance in cross-country double-poling time trial exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2013;45(11):2175&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Caffeine and exercise: metabolism, endurance and performance. Sports Med . 2001;31(11):785&#x2013;807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: a meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2005;15(2):69&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzucchi I, Felici F, Montini M, Figura F, Sacchetti M. Caffeine improves neuromuscular function during maximal dynamic exercise. Muscle Nerve . 2011;43(6):839&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Spriet LL. Performance and metabolic responses to a high caffeine dose during prolonged exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1991;71(6):2292&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridge CA, Jones MA. The effect of caffeine ingestion on 8 km run performance in a field setting. J Sports Sci . 2006;24(4):433&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy JL, Costill DL, Fink WJ, Lower RW. Influence of caffeine and carbohydrate feedings on endurance performance. Med Sci Sports . 1979;11(1):6&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadheim HK, Spencer M, Olsen R, Jensen J. Caffeine and performance over consecutive days of simulated competition. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2014;46(9):1787&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Gissane C. Caffeine and physiological responses to submaximal exercise: a meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2018;13(4):402&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Caffeine ingestion enhances Wingate performance: a meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci . 2017;18:219&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tangen DS, Nielsen SR, Kolnes KJ, Jensen J. Caffeine increases vertical jumping height in young trained males before but not after a maximal effort strength training session. Journal of Sciences in Sport and Exercise . 2020;2:145&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M. The effects of caffeine on the maximal accumulated oxygen deficit and short-term running performance. Int J Sport Nutr . 1998;8(2):95&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desbrow B, Biddulph C, Devlin B, Grant GD, Anoopkumar-Dukie S, Leveritt MD. The effects of different doses of caffeine on endurance cycling time trial performance. J Sports Sci . 2012;30(2):115&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves MN, Ferrari-Auarek WM, Pinto KM, et al. Effects of caffeine and tryptophan on rectal temperature, metabolism, total exercise time, rate of perceived exertion and heart rate. Braz J Med Biol Res . 1995;28(6):705&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olcina GJ, Mu&#xf1;oz D, Tim&#xf3;n R, et al. Effect of caffeine on oxidative stress during maximum incremental exercise. J Sports Sci Med . 2006;5(4):621&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman RF, Stager JM. Caffeine stimulates ventilation in athletes with exercise-induced hypoxemia. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2008;40(6):1080&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadheim HK, Nossum EM, Olsen R, Spencer M, Jensen J. Caffeine improves performance in double poling during acute exposure to 2,000-m altitude. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2015;119(12):1501&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AS Jr, Speck AE, Canas PM, Cunha RA. Neuronal adenosine A2A receptors signal ergogenic effects of caffeine. Sci Rep . 2020;10(1):13414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm BB, B&#xe4;ttig K, Holm&#xe9;n J, Nehlig A, Zvartau EE. Actions of caffeine in the brain with special reference to factors that contribute to its widespread use. Pharmacol Rev . 1999;51(1):83&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassett DR Jr, Howley ET. Limiting factors for maximum oxygen uptake and determinants of endurance performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2000;32(1):70&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day JR, Rossiter HB, Coats EM, Skasick A, Whipp BJ. The maximally attainable V&#x2d9;O 2 during exercise in humans: the peak vs. maximum issue. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2003;95(5):1901&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole DC, Wilkerson DP, Jones AM. Validity of criteria for establishing maximal O 2 uptake during ramp exercise tests. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2008;102(4):403&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine BD. VO 2max : what do we know, and what do we still need to know? J Physiol . 2008;586(1):25&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noakes TD. Maximal oxygen uptake: &#x201c;classical&#x201d; versus &#x201c;contemporary&#x201d; viewpoints: a rebuttal. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1998;30(9):1381&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz DS, Reiman MP, Lehecka BJ, Naylor A. What performance characteristics determine elite versus nonelite athletes in the same sport? Sports Health . 2013;5(6):542&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin JE, Howley ET, Bassett DR Jr, Thompson DL, Fitzhugh EC. Test of the classic model for predicting endurance running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2010;42(5):991&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luc&#xed;a A, Hoyos J, P&#xe9;rez M, Santalla A, Chicharro JL. Inverse relationship between VO 2max and economy/efficiency in world-class cyclists. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2002;34(12):2079&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Prampero PE. Factors limiting maximal performance in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2003;90(3&#x2013;4):420&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders PU, Garvican-Lewis LA, Schmidt WF, Gore CJ. Relationship between changes in haemoglobin mass and maximal oxygen uptake after hypoxic exposure. Br J Sports Med . 2013;47(1 Suppl):i26&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist CG, Saltin B. Cardiovascular adaptations to physical training. Annu Rev Physiol . 1983;45:169&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltin B, Calbet JA. Point: in health and in a normoxic environment, V&#x2d9;O 2 max is limited primarily by cardiac output and locomotor muscle blood flow. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2006;100(2):744&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman RF, Mickleborough TD. The effects of caffeine on ventilation and pulmonary function during exercise: an often-overlooked response. Phys Sportsmed . 2009;37(4):97&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrados N, Mizuno M, Andersen H. Reduction in maximal oxygen uptake at low altitudes; role of training status and lung function. Clin Physiol . 1985;5(3 Suppl):75&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey JA, Wagner PD. Exercise-induced arterial hypoxemia. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1999;87(6):1997&#x2013;2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers SK, Lawler J, Dempsey JA, Dodd S, Landry G. Effects of incomplete pulmonary gas exchange on V&#x2d9;O 2 max. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1989;66(6):2491&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen HB. Arterial desaturation during exercise in man: implication for O 2 uptake and work capacity. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2003;13(6):339&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medb&#xf8; JI, Mohn AC, Tabata I, Bahr R, Vaage O, Sejersted OM. Anaerobic capacity determined by maximal accumulated O 2 deficit. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1988;64(1):50&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Perceived exertion as an indicator of somatic stress. Scand J Rehabil Med . 1970;2:92&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller MR, Hankinson J, Brusasco V, et al; ATS/ERS Task Force. Standardisation of spirometry. Eur Respir J . 2005;26(2):319&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quanjer PH, Tammeling GJ, Cotes JE, Pedersen OF, Peslin R, Yernault JC. Lung volumes and forced ventilatory flows. Report Working Party Standardization of Lung Function Tests, European Community for Steel and Coal. Official Statement of the European Respiratory Society. Eur Respir J Suppl . 1993;16:5&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rustad PI, Sailer M, Cumming KT, et al. Intake of protein plus carbohydrate during the first two hours after exhaustive cycling improves performance the following day. PLoS One . 2016;11(4):e0153229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brietzke C, Asano RY, De Russi de Lima F, et al. Caffeine effects on VO 2max test outcomes investigated by a placebo perceived-as-caffeine design. Nutr Health . 2017;23(4):231&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara B, Ruiz-Moreno C, Salinero JJ, Del CJ. Time course of tolerance to the performance benefits of caffeine. PLoS One . 2019;14(1):e0210275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headrick JP, Ashton KJ, Rose'meyer RB, Peart JN. Cardiovascular adenosine receptors: expression, actions and interactions. Pharmacol Ther . 2013;140(1):92&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin AC, Brooks R, Ruskin JN, McGovern BA. Adenosine and the treatment of supraventricular tachycardia. Am J Med . 1992;92(6):655&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JN, Wang Y, Garcia-Roves PM, Bjornholm M, Fredholm BB. Adenosine A(3) receptors regulate heart rate, motor activity and body temperature. Acta Physiol (Oxf) . 2010;199(2):221&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman RF, Emery M, Stager JM. Degree of arterial desaturation in normoxia influences VO 2max decline in mild hypoxia. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1999;31(5):658&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodrich JA, Ryan BJ, Byrnes WC. The influence of oxygen saturation on the relationship between hemoglobin mass and V&#x2d9;O 2 max. Sports Med Int Open . 2018;2(4):E98&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson CN, Nadeem A, Spina D, Brown R, Page CP, Mustafa SJ. Adenosine receptors and asthma. Handb Exp Pharmacol . 2009;193:329&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calzetta L, Spina D, Cazzola M, et al. Pharmacological characterization of adenosine receptors on isolated human bronchi. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol . 2011;45(6):1222&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh EJ, Bara A, Barley E, Cates CJ. Caffeine for asthma. Cochrane Database Syst Rev . 2010;2010(1):CD001112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Cavalcante MD, Correia-Oliveira CR, Santos RA, et al. Caffeine increases anaerobic work and restores cycling performance following a protocol designed to lower endogenous carbohydrate availability. PLoS One . 2013;8(8):e72025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Muniz-Pumares D, Patterson SD, Foley P, McInnes G. Caffeine supplementation and peak anaerobic power output. Eur J Sport Sci . 2015;15(5):400&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felippe LC, Ferreira GA, Learsi SK, Boari D, Bertuzzi R, Lima-Silva AE. Caffeine increases both total work performed above critical power and peripheral fatigue during a 4-km cycling time trial. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2018;124(6):1491&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Nielsen JJ, Bangsbo J. Caffeine intake improves intense intermittent exercise performance and reduces muscle interstitial potassium accumulation. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2011;111(5):1372&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hostrup M, Bangsbo J. Limitations in intense exercise performance of athletes&#x2014;effect of speed endurance training on ion handling and fatigue development. J Physiol . 2017;595(9):2897&#x2013;913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foukas LC, Daniele N, Ktori C, Anderson KE, Jensen J, Shepherd PR. Direct effects of caffeine and theophylline on p110 delta and other phosphoinositide 3-kinases. Differential effects on lipid kinase and protein kinase activities. J Biol Chem . 2002;277(40):37124&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolnes AJ, Ingvaldsen A, Bolling A, et al. Caffeine and theophylline block insulin-stimulated glucose uptake and PKB phosphorylation in rat skeletal muscles. Acta Physiol (Oxf) . 2010;200(1):65&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawynok J. Adenosine receptor targets for pain. Neuroscience . 2016;338:1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried NT, Elliott MB, Oshinsky ML. The role of adenosine signaling in headache: a review. Brain Sci . 2017;7(3):30.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>