<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31873185</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Caffeine and Acute Aerobic Exercise on Working Memory and Caffeine Withdrawal.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19644</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19644</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19644</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-019-56251-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Studies show that a single bout of exercise confers cognitive benefits. However, many individuals use psychoactive substances such as caffeine to enhance cognitive performance. The effects of acute exercise in comparison to caffeine on cognition remain unknown. Furthermore, caffeine use is associated with withdrawal symptoms upon cessation. Whether acute exercise can reduce withdrawal symptoms also remains unknown. The objectives of this study were to compare the effects of acute moderate intensity aerobic exercise to caffeine on working memory (WM) and caffeine withdrawal symptoms (CWS). In Phase I, non-caffeine (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;29) and caffeine consumers (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;30) completed a WM assessment, followed by acute exercise and caffeine. In Phase II, caffeine consumers (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;25) from Phase I underwent the WM assessment and reported CWS following a 12-hour deprivation period. Acute moderate intensity aerobic exercise and caffeine (1.2&#x2009;mg/kg) significantly improved WM accuracy and reduced CWS comparably. WM performance was not reduced following caffeine deprivation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morava</LastName><ForeName>Anisa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9350-9639</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western University, Exercise and Health Psychology Lab, Department of Kinesiology, Arthur and Sonia Labatt Health Sciences Building, London, Ontario, N6A 5B9, Canada. amorava@uwo.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fagan</LastName><ForeName>Matthew James</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of British Columbia, Population Physical Activity Lab, School of Kinesiology, Lower Mall Research Station, British Columbia, V6T 1Z4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prapavessis</LastName><ForeName>Harry</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western University, Exercise and Health Psychology Lab, Department of Kinesiology, Arthur and Sonia Labatt Health Sciences Building, London, Ontario, N6A 5B9, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000697">Central Nervous System Stimulants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000697" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System Stimulants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008570" MajorTopicYN="N">Memory, Short-Term</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013375" MajorTopicYN="N">Substance Withdrawal Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31873185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6927973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-56251-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-019-56251-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lee MT, Jang Y, Chang WY. How do impairments in cognitive functions affect activities of daily living functions in older adults? PloS One. 2019;14:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6555549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y-K, Labban JD, Gapin JI, Etnier JL. The effects of acute exercise on cognitive performance: a meta-analysis. Brain Res. 2012;1453:87&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22480735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambourne K, Tomporowski P. The effect of exercise-induced arousal on cognitive task performance: a meta-regression analysis. Brain Res. 2010;1341:12&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomporowski PD. Effects of acute bouts of exercise on cognition. Acta Psychol. 2003;112:297&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12595152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Psychoactive substances and their sociolegal status. <i>Neuroscience of Psychoactive Substance Use and Dependence</i>, https://www.who.int/substance_abuse/publications/en/Neuroscience.pdf (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temple JL, Dewey AM, Briatico LN. Effects of acute caffeine administration on adolescents. Exp. Clin. Psychopharm. 2010;18:510&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21186925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeomans MR. Understanding individual differences in acquired flavour liking in humans. Chemosens. Percept. 2010;3:34&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addicott MA, Laurienti PJ. A comparison of the effects of caffeine following abstinence and normal caffeine use. Psychopharmacology. 2009;207:423&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2941158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19777214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagan D, Swift CG, Tiplady B. Effects of caffeine on vigilance and other performance tests in normal subjects. J. Psychopharmacol. 1988;2:19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22159665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine BJ, et al. Effects of caffeine or diphenhydramine on visual vigilance. Psychopharmacology. 1994;114:233&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7838913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman HR, Wurtman RJ, Emde GG, Roberts C, Coviella ILG. The effects of low doses of caffeine on human performance and mood. Psychopharmacology. 1987;92:308&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3114783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit HJ, Rogers PJ. Effects of low doses of caffeine on cognitive performance, mood and thirst in low and higher caffeine consumers. Psychopharmacology. 2005;152:167&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11057520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsene K, Deckert J, Sand P, de Wit H. Association between A 2a receptor gene polymorphisms and caffeine-induced anxiety. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2003;28:1694&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12825092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childs E, de Wit H. Subjective, behavioral, and physiological effects of acute caffeine in light, nondependent caffeine users. Psychopharmacology. 2006;185:514&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16541243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bovim G, N&#xe6;ss P, Helle J, Sand T. Caffeine influence on the motor steadiness battery in neuropsychological tests. J. Clin. Exp. Neuropsychol. 1995;17:472&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7650108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands HR, et al. Mood and psychomotor tremor changes following acute caffeine consumption in moderate and minimal caffeine consumers. J. Caffeine. Res. 2015;5:42&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliano LM, Griffiths RR. A critical review of caffeine withdrawal: empirical validation of symptoms and signs, incidence, severity, and associated features. Psychopharmacology. 2004;176:1&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James JE. Acute and chronic effects of caffeine on performance, mood, headache, and sleep. Neuropsychobiology. 1998;38:32&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9701720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane JD, Phillips-Bute BG. Caffeine deprivation affects vigilance performance and mood. Physiol. Behav. 1998;65:171&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9811379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeomans MR, Ripley T, Davies LH, Rusted J, Rogers PJ. Effects of caffeine on performance and mood depend on the level of caffeine abstinence. Psychopharmacology. 2002;164:241&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12424547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haasova M, et al. The acute effects of physical activity on cigarette cravings: systematic review and meta-analysis with individual participant data. Addiction. 2013;108:26&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22861822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts V, Maddison R, Simpson C, Bullen C, Prapavessis H. The acute effects of exercise on cigarette cravings, withdrawal symptoms, affect, and smoking behaviour: systematic review update and meta-analysis. Psychopharmacology. 2012;222:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22585034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, J. <i>Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences</i>. (1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ussher M, Cropley M, Playle S, Mohidin R, West R. Effect of isometric exercise and body scanning on cigarette cravings and withdrawal symptoms. Addiction. 2009;104:1251&#x2013;1257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19563567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huertas F, Blasco E, Moratal C, Lupia&#xf1;ez J. Caffeine intake modulates the functioning of the attentional networks depending on consumption habits and acute exercise demands. Scientific reports. 2019;9:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6624295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31296908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy DO, Haskell CF. Cerebral blood flow and behavioural effects of caffeine in habitual and non-habitual consumers of caffeine: A near infrared spectroscopy study. Biol. Psychol. 2011;86:298&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21262317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu LZ, Barnes JL. The fitness-fatigue model revisited: Implications for planning short-and long-term training. Strength. Cond. J. 2003;25:42&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DM, Bray SR. Isometric exercise and cognitive function: an investigation of acute dose&#x2013;response effects during submaximal fatiguing contractions. J. Sports Sci. 2015;33:487&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25260112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans SM, Griffiths RR. Caffeine withdrawal: a parametric analysis of caffeine dosing conditions. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 1999;289:285&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10087016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell CF, Kennedy DO, Wesnes KA, Scholey AB. Cognitive and mood improvements of caffeine in habitual consumers and habitual non-consumers of caffeine. Psychopharmacology. 2005;179:813&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15678363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Sproule J, Turner A, Hale BJ. Acute, intermediate intensity exercise, and speed and accuracy in working memory tasks: a meta-analytical comparison of effects. Physiol. Behav. 2011;102:421&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21163278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan GB, et al. Dose-dependent pharmacokinetics and psychomotor effects of caffeine in humans. J. Clin. Pharmacol. 1997;37:693&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9378841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed AV. Speed-accuracy trade-off in recognition memory. Science. 1973;181:574&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17777808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giesbrecht T, Rycroft JA, Rowson MJ, De Bruin EA. The combination of L-theanine and caffeine improves cognitive performance and increases subjective alertness. Nutritional neuroscience. 2010;13:283&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21040626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppelstaetter F, et al. Does caffeine modulate verbal working memory processes? An fMRI study. Neuroimage. 2008;39:492&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17936643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loy BD, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Dishman RK. The effect of a single bout of exercise on energy and fatigue states: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Fatigue. 2013;1:223&#x2013;242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maraki M, et al. Acute effects of a single exercise class on appetite, energy intake and mood. Is there a time of day effect? Appetite. 2005;45:272&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16157416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles GE, et al. Differential cognitive effects of energy drink ingredients: caffeine, taurine, and glucose. Pharmacol. Biochem. Behav. 2012;102:569&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22819803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heatherley SV, Hayward RC, Seers HE, Rogers PJ. Cognitive and psychomotor performance, mood, and pressor effects of caffeine after 4, 6 and 8 h caffeine abstinence. Psychopharmacology. 2005;178:461&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15696321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epperson CN, Amin Z, Ruparel K, Gur R, Loughead J. Interactive effects of estrogen and serotonin on brain activation during working memory and affective processing in menopausal women. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2012;37:372&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3226892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21820247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulus R, et al. Impact of various caffeine vehicles on mood and cognitive, neurological, and physiological functions over five hours. Ohio J Sci. 2015;115:12&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barella LA, Etnier JL, Chang YK. The immediate and delayed effects of an acute bout of exercise on cognitive performance of healthy older adults. J Aging Phys Act. 2010;18:87&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20181996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G* Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behavior Research Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliano LM, Huntley ED, Harrell PT, Westerman AT. Development of the caffeine withdrawal symptom questionnaire: caffeine withdrawal symptoms cluster into 7 factors. Drug Alcohol Depen. 2012;124:229&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas S, Reading J, Shephard RJ. Revision of the physical activity readiness questionnaire (PAR-Q) Can. J. Sport Sci. 1992;17:338&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1330274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendel-Vos GCW, Schuit AJ, Saris WHM, Kromhout D. Reproducibility and relative validity of the short questionnaire to assess health-enhancing physical activity. J. Clin. Epidemiol. 2003;56:1163&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14680666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irons JG, Bassett DT, Prendergast CO, Landrum RE, Heinz AJ. Development and initial validation of the caffeine consumption questionnaire-revised. J. Caffeine Res. 2016;6:20&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baddeley A. Working memory. Science. 1992;255:556&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1736359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway ARA, et al. Working memory span tasks: A methodological review and user&#x2019;s guide. Psychon. Bull. Rev. 2005;12:769&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16523997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonides J, et al. Verbal working memory load affects regional brain activation as measured by PET. J. Cogn. Neurosci. 1997;9:462&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23968211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson F, et al. Working memory deficits predict short-term smoking resumption following brief abstinence. Drug Alcohol Dep. 2010;106:61&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2815089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19733449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karvonen, M. J., Kentala, E. &amp; Mustala, O. The effects of training on heart rate. <i>Ann. Med. Exp. Biol. Fenn</i>. <b>35</b> (1957).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13470504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. <i>ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription</i>. (ed. ACSM) 4-5 (Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers PJ, Martin J, Smith C, Heatherley SV, Smit HJ. Absence of reinforcing, mood and psychomotor performance effects of caffeine in habitual non-consumers of caffeine. Psychopharmacology. 2003;167:54&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12601503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>