<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">33188564</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1942-7611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Drug testing and analysis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Drug Test Anal</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of theophylline and theobromine on exercise performance and implications for competition sport: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>36</StartPage><EndPage>43</EndPage><MedlinePgn>36-43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/dta.2970</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A systematic review was undertaken to evaluate studies on the effects of theophylline and theobromine on exercise performance in normal (healthy) subjects. Theophylline was found to have been studied on eight occasions and theobromine on one, the number of subjects per study ranging from seven to 15. In two exercise investigations, theophylline was superior to placebo at a p &lt; 0.05 level and no different in four including one that was conducted in artificial hypoxia. In a treadmill time trial over 3 km, theobromine was superior to placebo and equal to caffeine, at the &lt;0.05 level. In strength studies, theophylline increased wrist strength in one and showed a slight but not statistically significant increase in limb strength in four of the seven subjects in the other. Theophylline caused adverse effects in six participants. There were no adverse effects in the theobromine investigation. Although the studies showed contradicting results and/or insufficient data to draw solid conclusions, it appears both drugs have potential to enhance performance and could be considered for inclusion on the WADA banned list.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kennedy</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5676-2010</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacology and Toxicology, St. Vincent's Hospital Medical School, UNSW, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Drug Test Anal</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101483449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1942-7603</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001993">Bronchodilator Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>C137DTR5RG</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013806">Theophylline</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>OBD445WZ5P</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013805">Theobromine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001993" MajorTopicYN="N">Bronchodilator Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="N">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="N">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013805" MajorTopicYN="N">Theobromine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013806" MajorTopicYN="N">Theophylline</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">theobromine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">theophylline</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33188564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dta.2970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Burke L, Desbrow B, Spriet L. Permissibility of caffeine use in sport. In: Burke L, Desbrow B, Spriet L, eds. Caffeine for Sports Performance. 1st ed. Illinois: Human Kinetics; 2013:109-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbeke FT, De BP. Threshold level for theophylline in doping analysis. J Chromatogr B. 1996;687(1):247-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machnik M, Kaiser S, Koppe S, et al. Control of methylxanthines in the competition horse: pharmacokinetic studies on caffeine, theobromine and theophylline for the assessment of irrelevant concentrations. Drug Test Anal. 2017;9:1372-1384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellami M, Slimeni O, Pokrywka A, et al. Herbal medicine for sports: a review. J Int Soc Sport Nutr. 2018;15(1). Article number 14. (Accessed 19th November 2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theobromine as a pre-workout https://supplements in review.com/theobromine. accessed 14 June 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesta DH, Angadi SS, Burtscher M, Roberts CK, The effects of caffeine, nicotine, ethanol and tetrahydrocannabinol on exercise performance. Nutr Metab. 2013;10(1):71. http://www.nutritionandmetabolism.com.content/10/1/71 (accessed 19th November 2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes PJ. Theophylline. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013;188(8):901-906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conradson TB. Cardiovascular effects of two different xanthines in healthy subjects. Studies at rest, during exercise and in combination with a beta-agonist, terbutaline. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 1984;27:319-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogilvie RI, Fernandez PG, Winsberg F. Cardiovascular response to increasing theophylline concentrations. Europ J Clin Pharmacol. 1977;12(6):409-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthomiou J, Fleming J, Edwards RHT, Spiro SG. Effects of aminophylline on fatigue of the sternomastoid muscle in man. Thorax. 1986;41(2):122-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA, Howell S, Roussos C, Edwards HT. Low-frequency fatigue in isolated skeletal muscles and the effects of methylxanthines. Clin Sci. 1982;63(2):161-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubier M. Pharmacotherapy of respiratory muscles. Clin Chest Med. 1988;9(2):311-324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moxham J. Aminophylline and the respiratory muscles. Clin Chest Med. 1988;9(2):325-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thebault JJ, Aiache JM, Mazoyer F, Cardot JM. The influence of food on the bioavailability of a slow release theophylline preparation. Clin Pharmacokin. 1987;13(4):267-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlaeffer F, Engelberg I, Kapansky J, Danon A. Effects of exercise and environmental heat on theophylline kinetics. Respiration. 1984;14:438-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bierman CW, Williams PV. Therapeutic monitoring of theophylline. Rationale and current status. Clin Pharmacokin. 1989;17(6):377-384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman LS, Gilman A. eds. The Pharmacological Basis of Therapeutics. Editors, 2nd ed. New York: The Macmillan Company; 1958: 340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell ES, Sletteanaar M, Meer NVD, et al. Differential contributions of theobromine and caffeine on mood, psychomotor performance and blood pressure. Physiol Behav. 2011;104(5):816-822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggott MJ, Childs E, Hart AB, et al. Psychopharmacology of theobromine in healthy volunteers. Psychopharmacology. 2013;228(1):109-118. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00213-013-3021-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahrke M. Determining the efficacy of sport performance enhancing substances. in Bahrke MS, Yesalis CE eds. Performance Enhancing Substances in Sport and Exercise. Human Kinetics. 2002; p21-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidney KH, Lefcoe NM. Effects of anti-asthmatic medication (ephedrine plus theophylline) upon the physical performance and work capacity of healthy track athletes. Can J Appl Sport Sci. 1978;3:93-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palakovich HL. &#x201c;Theophylline and Ambrisentan combination: Effects on human performance,AMS and physiological responses to altitude&#x201d; (2014). Graduate Student Theses, Dissertations, &amp; Professional Papers. 4217. https://scholarworks.umt.edu/etd/4217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Jie. Ergogenic effects of salbutamol, caffeine and theobromine on non-asthmatic subjects PhD Thesis Liverpool John Moores University 2016. https://doi.org/10.24377/LJMU.t.0000 4797</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigozzi F, Sacchetti M, Di Salvo V, Alabisio A, Fagnani F, Parasi A. Oral theophylline supplementation and high-intensity intermittent exercise. J Sport Med Phy Fit. 2003;43(4):535-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer F, Friars D, Graham TE. Comparison of caffeine and theophylline ingestion; exercise metabolism and endurance. J Appl Physiol. 2000;89(5):1837-1844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott CG, Nietrzeba RM, Adams TD, Crapo RO, Jensen TL, Yanowitz FG. Effect of intravenous aminophylline upon the incremental exercise performance of healthy men. Respiration. 1985;47(4):260-266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Violante B, Pellegrino P, Vinay C, Selleri R, Ghinamo G. Failure of aminophylline and salbutamol to improve respiratory muscle function and exercise tolerance in healthy humans. Respiration. 1989;55(4):227-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton AR, Scott CA, Fitch KD. The effects of theophylline on the physical performance and work capacity of well-trained athletes. J Allergy Clin Immun. 1989;83(1):55-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scalzo RL, Binns SE, Klochak AL, et al. Methazolamide plus aminophylline abrogates hypoxia-mediated endurance exercise. High Alt Med and Biol. 2015;16(4):331-342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh GD, McFadden RG, Nicholson RL, Leasa DJ, Thompson T. Theophylline delays skeletal muscle fatigue during progressive exercise. Am Rev of Respir Dis. 1993;147(4):876-887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeGarmo C, Cerny F, Conboy K, Ellis EF. In vivo effects of theophylline on diaphragm, bicep, and quadriceps strength and fatigability. J Allergy Clin Immun. 1988;82(6):1041-1046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonzon B, Sylven C, Kauser L. Theophylline decreases pain in the ischaemic forearm test. Cardiovasc Res. 1989;23(9):807-809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesarz J, Schuster AK, Hartmann M, Gerhart A, Eich W. Pain perception in athletes compared to normally active controls: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain. 2012;153(6):1253-1262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke op cit 80-96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Anti-Doping Agency (WADA). www.wada-ama.org accessed 14 June 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buyuktuncel SE. Simultaneous determination of theobromine, paraxanthine, theophylline and caffeine in urine by reversed-phase liquid chromatography with diode array UV detection. Anal Lett. 2010;43(16):2518-2524.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>