<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39691170</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reliability, biological variability, and accuracy of multi-frequency bioelectrical impedance analysis for measuring body composition components.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1491931</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1491931</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1491931</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2024.1491931</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA) systems are gaining popularity for use in research and fitness assessments as the technology improves and becomes more affordable and easier to use. Multifrequency BIA (MF-BIA) may improve accuracy and precision using octopolar contacts for segmental analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Evaluate reliability, biological variability, and accuracy of component measures (total body water, mass, and composition) of commercially available MF-BIA system (InBody 770, Cerritos, California, USA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fourteen healthy military-age adults were assessed by MF-BIA in duplicate on five laboratory visits across 3&#x202f;weeks (10 measures each). Participants were evaluated at the same time of day after refraining from strenuous exercise (&gt; 48&#x202f;h), alcohol consumption (&gt; 24&#x202f;h), and caffeine, nicotine, and food (&gt; 10&#x202f;h). Systematic error (test-retest reliability) and biological variability (day-to-day reliability) were summarized by intraclass correlation coefficient (ICC) values determined for body mass (fat, fat-free, total) and body water (extracellular, intracellular, total). Body composition measurements derived from BIA on the second visit were also tested for accuracy compared to dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Test-retest reliability was very high for all measurements of whole-body water and mass (ICC&#x202f;&#x2265;&#x202f;0.999) and high for regional body water and mass (ICC 0.973-1.000). Biological variability was observable with very minor differences between tests (same day) for total and regional body water (0.0-0.2&#x202f;L) and total and regional body mass measurements (0.0-0.2&#x202f;kg); while between day differences were slightly higher (0.0-0.5&#x202f;L and 0.1-0.7&#x202f;kg). Compared to DXA, the MF-BIA whole-body measures showed an offset in %BF (Bias -4.0&#x202f;&#xb1;&#x202f;2.8%; Standard error of the estimate (SEE), 2.6%), an overprediction for total body fat-free mass (Bias 2.8&#x202f;&#xb1;&#x202f;2.1&#x202f;kg; SEE 2.2&#x202f;kg) and an underprediction of total body fat mass (Bias -2.9&#x202f;&#xb1;&#x202f;2.0&#x202f;kg; SEE 1.9&#x202f;kg).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Under controlled conditions with fit and healthy men and women, this MF-BIA system has high methodological reliability and demonstrates stable day-to-day measurements of major body composition components. Previously reported ~3% body fat offset compared to criterion methods was again confirmed. Precision of the InBody 770 shows consistency and supports further testing of this specific device as a new military standards method and suitability across a wider range of %BF.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Looney, Schafer, Chapman, Pryor, Potter, Roberts and Friedl.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Looney</LastName><ForeName>David P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine (USARIEM), Natick, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Maximize Human Performance, LLC, Framingham, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CoachMePlus, Buffalo, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schafer</LastName><ForeName>Erica A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine (USARIEM), Natick, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education (ORISE), Oak Ridge, TN, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chapman</LastName><ForeName>Christopher L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine (USARIEM), Natick, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education (ORISE), Oak Ridge, TN, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pryor</LastName><ForeName>Riana R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research and Education in Special Environments, Department of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Potter</LastName><ForeName>Adam W</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine (USARIEM), Natick, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Brandon M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine (USARIEM), Natick, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friedl</LastName><ForeName>Karl E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine (USARIEM), Natick, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BIA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BMI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DXA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FMI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body water</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>DL was employed by Maximize Human Performance, LLC and CoachMePlus. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39691170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11649400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1491931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ward LC. Electrical bioimpedance: from the past to the future. J Electr Bioimpedance. (2021) 12:1&#x2013;2. doi: 10.2478/joeb-2021-0001, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/joeb-2021-0001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8336311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34413916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskirk ER. Underwater weighing and body density: a review of procedures In: Brozek J, Henschel A, editors. Techniques for measuring body composition. National Academy of Sciences: Washington DC; (1961). 90&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health . Bioelectrical impedance analysis in body composition measurement: National Institutes of Health technology assessment conference statement. Washington DC: US Department of Health and Human Services; (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis KJ, Bell SJ, Chertow GM, Chumlea WC, Knox TA, Kotler DP, et al. Bioelectrical impedance methods in clinical research: a follow-up to the NIH technology assessment conference. Nutr. (1999) 15:874&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1016/S0899-9007(99)00147-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0899-9007(99)00147-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10575664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumlea WC, Guo SS. Bioelectrical impedance: a history, research issues, and recent consensus In: Emerging technologies for nutrition research - potential for assessing military performance capability. Committee on military nutrition research. eds. Carlson-Newberry SJ, Costello RB. Washington DC: National Academy Press; (1997). 169&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25121304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedl KE, DeWinne CM, Taylor RL. The use of the Durnin-Womersley generalized equations for body fat estimation and their impact on the Army weight control program. Mil Med. (1987) 152:150&#x2013;5. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3104831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukaski HC, Johnson PE, Bolonchuk WW, Lykken GI. Assessment of fat-free mass using bioelectrical impedance measurements of the human body. Am J Clin Nutr. (1985) 41:810&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/41.4.810</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/41.4.810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3984933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafer KJ, Siders WA, Johnson LK, Lukaski HC. Validity of segmental multiple-frequency bioelectrical impedance analysis to estimate body composition of adults across a range of body mass indexes. Nutr. (2009) 25:25&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2008.07.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2008.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18723322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward LC, Brantlov S. Bioimpedance basics and phase angle fundamentals. Rev Endocr Metab Disorders. (2023) 24:381&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1007/s11154-022-09780-3, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11154-022-09780-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10140124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36749540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter AW, Nindl LJ, Soto LD, Pazmino A, Looney DP, Tharion WJ, et al. High precision but systematic offset in a standing bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA) compared with dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA). BMJ Nutr Prev Health. (2022) 5:254&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1136/bmjnph-2022-000512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjnph-2022-000512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9813632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36619314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States Marine Corps . Marine corps order 6110.3A W/CH-3, body composition and military appearance program. Washington DC: Headquarters United States Marine Corps; (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of the Army . All Army activities memorandum (ALARACT). 2023;046/2023. Notification of new Army body fat assessment for Army body composition program. Washington DC: Secretary of the Army; (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter AW, Chin GC, Looney DP, Friedl KE. Defining overweight and obesity by percent body fat instead of body mass index. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. (2024) 15:dgae341. doi: 10.1210/clinem/dgae341, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/clinem/dgae341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11913102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38747476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward LC. Segmental bioelectrical impedance analysis: an update. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. (2012) 15:424&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1097/MCO.0b013e328356b944</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0b013e328356b944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey BW, LeCheminant G, Hope T, Bell M, Tucker LA. A comparison of the agreement, internal consistency, and 2-day test stability of the InBody 720, GE iDXA, and BOD POD&#xae; gold standard for assessing body composition. Measurement Phys Educ Exerc Sci. (2018) 22:231&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1080/1091367X.2017.1422129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1091367X.2017.1422129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team . R: A language and environment for statistical computing. Foundation for statistical computing. Vienna, Austria: (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Johnson PCD, Schielzeth H. The coefficient of determination R(2) and intra-class correlation coefficient from generalized linear mixed-effects models revisited and expanded. J Royal Soc Interface. (2017) 14:20170213&#x2013;1. doi: 10.1098/rsif.2017.0213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsif.2017.0213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5636267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28904005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker B, Walker S. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. J Stat Softw. (2015) 67:1&#x2013;48. doi: 10.18637/jss.v067.i01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerke O. Reporting standards for a bland-Altman agreement analysis. Diagnostics. (2020) 10:334. doi: 10.3390/diagnostics10050334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics10050334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7278016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32456091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker RA, Weir CJ, Rubio N, Rabinovich R, Pinnock H, Hanley J, et al. Application of mixed effects limits of agreement in the presence of multiple sources of variability: exemplar from the comparison of several devices to measure respiratory rate in COPD patients. PLoS One. (2016) 11:e0168321. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0168321, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0168321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5156413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27973556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esco MR, Snarr RL, Leatherwood MD, Chamberlain NA, Redding ML, Flatt AA, et al. Comparison of total and segmental body composition using DXA and multifrequency bioimpedance in collegiate female athletes. J Strength Cond Res. (2015) 29:918&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25353076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mecherques-Carini M, Albaladejo-Saura M, Vaquero-Crist&#xf3;bal R, Baglietto N, Esparza-Ros F. Validity and agreement between dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, anthropometry and bioelectrical impedance in the estimation of fat mass in young adults. Front Nutr. (2024) 11:1421950. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2024.1421950, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1421950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11198126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38919386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day K, Kwok A, Evans A, Mata F, Verdejo-Garcia A, Hart K, et al. Comparison of a bioelectrical impedance device against the reference method dual energy X-ray absorptiometry and anthropometry for the evaluation of body composition in adults. Nutrients. (2018) 10:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.3390/nu10101469, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10101469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6213252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30308974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Kenyon M, Ellerbroek A, Carson C, Burgess V, Tyler-Palmer D, et al. Comparison of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) versus a multi-frequency bioelectrical impedance (InBody 770) device for body composition assessment after a 4-week Hypoenergetic diet. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. (2019) 4:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.3390/jfmk4020023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk4020023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahav Y, Goldstein N, Gepner Y. Comparison of body composition assessment across body mass index categories by two multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis devices and dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry in clinical settings. Eur J Clin Nutr. (2021) 75:1275&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1038/s41430-020-00839-5, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-020-00839-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLester CN, Nickerson BS, Kliszczewicz BM, McLester JR. Reliability and agreement of various InBody body composition analyzers as compared to dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry in healthy men and women. J Clin Densitom. (2020) 23:443&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.jocd.2018.10.008, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocd.2018.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30472111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymond CJ, Dengel DR, Bosch TA. Total and segmental body composition examination in collegiate football players using multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis and dual X-ray absorptiometry. J Strength Cond Res. (2018) 32:772&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002320, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29120982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart NH, Nimphius S, Spiteri T, Cochrane JL, Newton RU. Segmental musculoskeletal examinations using dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA): positioning and analysis considerations. J Sports Sci Med. (2015) 14:620&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4541127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26336349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moonen H, van Zanten FJL, Driessen L, de Smet V, Slingerland-Boot R, Mensink M, et al. Association of bioelectric impedance analysis body composition and disease severity in COVID-19 hospital ward and ICU patients: the BIAC-19 study. Clin Nutr. (2021) 40:2328&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2020.10.023, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2020.10.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33129597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>