<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41364357</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1970-9366</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Internal and emergency medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Intern Emerg Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Targeting the cognitive failures of fatigue: a randomized, double-blind, crossover pilot trial of a rapid countermeasure in night-shift emergency physicians.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11739-025-04224-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose is to investigate the effects of caffeinated chewing gum on the cognitive performance of emergency physicians (EPs) during a night shift. In this randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled crossover exploratory pilot trial, 14 young male EPs (mean age: 29.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.44) working an 8-h night shift received either caffeinated gum (200&#xa0;mg) or a placebo mid-shift. A comprehensive cognitive battery assessing executive function, cognitive flexibility, and spatial memory was administered at three time points: pre-shift (baseline), mid-shift (10&#xa0;min post-intervention), and end-of-shift. Performance changes between conditions were analyzed using the Wilcoxon signed-rank test, with effect sizes quantified via rank-biserial correlation. Caffeinated gum elicited immediate and large improvements in key executive functions. Compared to placebo, the caffeine condition was associated with significantly enhanced cognitive flexibility (reduced task-switching interference: r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.784, 95% CI [-1.000 to -0.354], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.009; improved accuracy: r&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.673, 95% CI [0.154-1.000], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.026) and superior cognitive inhibition (improved Incongruent Stroop task performance: r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.745, 95% CI [-1.000 to -0.273], p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.015). These benefits were not sustained at the end-of-shift assessment, and no significant effects were observed for spatial memory or other cognitive domains at any time point. This exploratory trial found that 200&#xa0;mg of caffeinated gum produced immediate, domain-specific gains in cognitive flexibility and response inhibition, functions closely linked to medical error risk. As the effects were transient, caffeinated gum may serve as a short-term "tactical safety tool" in high-risk scenarios, aligning with strategies in aviation and military operations, though larger studies are needed to confirm these findings and test for a direct impact on clinical performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Societ&#xe0; Italiana di Medicina Interna (SIMI).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Shuang-Yu</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, China Medical University Hospital, No.2, Yude Rd., Taichung, 404, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Po-Sheng</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, China Medical University Hospital, No.2, Yude Rd., Taichung, 404, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Fen-Wei</ForeName><Initials>FW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, China Medical University Hospital, No.2, Yude Rd., Taichung, 404, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Chun</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, National Taiwan University of Sport, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiu</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Hui</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Department of Exercise Health Science, National Taiwan University of Sport, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Yan-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, China Medical University Hospital, No.2, Yude Rd., Taichung, 404, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Hao</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7625-7193</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, China Medical University Hospital, No.2, Yude Rd., Taichung, 404, Taiwan. ambertwu@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan. ambertwu@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Intern Emerg Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263418</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1828-0447</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical error</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shift worker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroop test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Task-switching paradigm</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: No other author has reported a potential conflict of interest relevant to this article. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The project was approved by the Institutional Review Board of China Medical University Hospital (CMUH111-REC2-169). This study was conducted following the Declaration of Helsinki. Written and informed consent was obtained from all subjects at the beginning of the study. Consent for publication: This study does not contain any individual person&#x2019;s data in any form (including any individual details, images, or videos).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41364357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11739-025-04224-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11739-025-04224-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Skaugset LM, Farrell S, Carney M, Wolff M, Santen SA, Perry M, Cico SJ (2016) Can you multitask? Evidence and limitations of task switching and multitasking in emergency medicine. Ann Emerg Med 68(2):189&#x2013;195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annemergmed.2015.10.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26585046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad RV, Gupta SL, Swaminathan S (2021) Evaluation of cognitive and psychomotor functional changes in anesthesiology residents after 12 hours of continuous work in operation theater: an observational study. Anesth Essays Res 15(4):362&#x2013;367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/aer.aer_153_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35422545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persico N, Maltese F, Ferrigno C, Bablon A, Marmillot C, Papazian L, Roch A (2018) Influence of shift duration on cognitive performance of emergency physicians: a prospective cross-sectional study. Ann Emerg Med 72(2):171&#x2013;180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annemergmed.2017.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29174830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machi MS, Staum M, Callaway CW, Moore C, Jeong K, Suyama J, Patterson PD, Hostler D (2012) The relationship between shift work, sleep, and cognition in career emergency physicians. Acad Emerg Med 19(1):85&#x2013;91</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1553-2712.2011.01254.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22221346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltese F, Adda M, Bablon A, Hraeich S, Guervilly C, Lehingue S, Wiramus S, Leone M, Martin C, Vialet R et al (2016) Night shift decreases cognitive performance of ICU physicians. Intensive Care Med 42(3):393&#x2013;400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-015-4115-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26556616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westbrook JI, Raban MZ, Walter SR, Douglas H (2018) Task errors by emergency physicians are associated with interruptions, multitasking, fatigue and working memory capacity: a prospective, direct observation study. BMJ Qual Saf 27(8):655&#x2013;663</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2017-007333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29317463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6204927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamimori GH, Karyekar CS, Otterstetter R, Cox DS, Balkin TJ, Belenky GL, Eddington ND (2002) The rate of absorption and relative bioavailability of caffeine administered in chewing gum versus capsules to normal healthy volunteers. Int J Pharm 234(1&#x2013;2):159&#x2013;167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-5173(01)00958-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11839447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C-H, Wu S-H, Shiu Y-J, Yu S-Y, Chiu C-H (2023) Acute enhancement of Romanian deadlift performance after consumption of caffeinated chewing gum. Sci Rep 13(1):22016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-49453-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38086915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10716112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellar D, Judge LW, Craig BW (2011) Use of caffeinated chewing gum as an ergogenic aid. Strength Cond J 33(4):66&#x2013;68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e31821b1308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwan K, Li T, Altman DG, Elbourne D: CONSORT 2010 statement: extension to randomised crossover trials. bmj 2019, 366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broverman DM, Vogel W, Klaiber EL, Majcher D, Shea D, Paul V (1981) Changes in cognitive task performance across the menstrual cycle. J Comp Physiol Psychol 95(4):646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0077796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7276285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers PJ, Edwards S, Green MW, Jas P (1992) Nutritional influences on mood and cognitive performance: the menstrual cycle, caffeine and dieting. Proc Nutr Soc 51(3):343&#x2013;351</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/PNS19920048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1480629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S-H, Chen Y-C, Chen C-H, Liu H-S, Liu Z-X, Chiu C-H (2024) Caffeine supplementation improves the cognitive abilities and shooting performance of elite e-sports players: a crossover trial. Sci Rep 14(1):2074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-52599-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38267565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10808346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris C, Viriot SM, Mirza QUF, Morris GA, Lynn A (2019) Caffeine release and absorption from caffeinated gums. Food Funct 10(4):1792&#x2013;1796</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9FO00431A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30919868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoet G (2017) PsyToolkit: a novel web-based method for running online questionnaires and reaction-time experiments. Teach Psychol 44(1):24&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0098628316677643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoet G (2010) PsyToolkit: a software package for programming psychological experiments using Linux. Behav Res Methods 42(4):1096&#x2013;1104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BRM.42.4.1096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21139177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L-J, Fox KR, Ku P-W, Chang Y-W (2016) Effects of aquatic exercise on sleep in older adults with mild sleep impairment: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Behav Med 23:501&#x2013;506</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12529-015-9492-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Actigraph L: ActiLife 6 users manual. Pensacola, FL, USA: ActiGraph, LLC 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan Bisson AN, Robinson SA, Lachman ME (2019) Walk to a better night of sleep: testing the relationship between physical activity and sleep. Sleep Health 5(5):487&#x2013;494</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleh.2019.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31358470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J (2013) Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Routledge</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780203771587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang H, Ni L, Davis CE (2004) Assessment of blinding in clinical trials. Control Clin Trials 25(2):143&#x2013;156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2003.10.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15020033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pembury Smith MQ, Ruxton GD (2020) Effective use of the McNemar test. Behav Ecol Sociobiol 74:1&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00265-020-02916-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller J, Makara G, Kruk M (1997) Catecholaminergic involvement in the control of aggression: hormones, the peripheral sympathetic, and central noradrenergic systems. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 22(1):85&#x2013;97</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0149-7634(97)00023-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamimori GH, McLellan TM, Tate CM, Voss DM, Niro P, Lieberman HR (2015) Caffeine improves reaction time, vigilance and logical reasoning during extended periods with restricted opportunities for sleep. Psychopharmacology 232:2031&#x2013;2042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-014-3834-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25527035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartels C, Wegrzyn M, Wiedl A, Ackermann V, Ehrenreich H (2010) Practice effects in healthy adults: a longitudinal study on frequent repetitive cognitive testing. BMC Neurosci 11:1&#x2013;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2202-11-118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calamia M, Markon K, Tranel D (2012) Scoring higher the second time around: meta-analyses of practice effects in neuropsychological assessment. Clin Neuropsychol 26(4):543&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13854046.2012.680913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22540222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikoff D, Welsh BT, Henderson R, Brorby GP, Britt J, Myers E, Goldberger J, Lieberman HR, O&#x2019;Brien C, Peck J (2017) Systematic review of the potential adverse effects of caffeine consumption in healthy adults, pregnant women, adolescents, and children. Food Chem Toxicol 109:585&#x2013;648</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2017.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry D, Iqbal S, Harrap I, Oeppen R, Brennan P (2023) Caffeine: benefits and drawbacks for technical performance. Br J Oral Maxillofac Surg 61(3):198&#x2013;201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjoms.2023.01.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36914458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodur M, Kaya S, Ilhan-Esgin M, &#xc7;akiro&#x11f;lu FP, &#xd6;z&#xe7;elik A&#xd6; (2024) The caffeine dilemma: unraveling the intricate relationship between caffeine use disorder, caffeine withdrawal symptoms and mental well-being in adults. Public Health Nutr 27(1):e57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1368980024000399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38305102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10882539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattab FN (2023) Chewing gum for oral and dental health: a review. J Oral Health Commun Dent 17(1):13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam MK, Shayeb MA, Natarajan PM, Abutayyem H, Di Blasio M, Marrapodi MM, Cicci&#xf9; M, Minervini G (2025) Association of temporomandibular disorders and other jaw anomalies in chewing gum users--a systematic review. J Oral Facial Pain Headache. https://doi.org/10.22514/jofph.2025.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22514/jofph.2025.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41070532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12520423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappelletti S, Piacentino D, Fineschi V, Frati P, Cipolloni L, Aromatario M (2018) Caffeine-related deaths: manner of deaths and categories at risk. Nutrients 10(5):611</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10050611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29757951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5986491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan GB, Greenblatt DJ, Ehrenberg BL, Goddard JE, Cotreau MM, Harmatz JS, Shader RI (1997) Dose-dependent pharmacokinetics and psychomotor effects of caffeine in humans. J Clin Pharmacol 37(8):693&#x2013;703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.1552-4604.1997.tb04356.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9378841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oravsky J. (2023). High Reliability Organizations (HRO) in Healthcare-A Mixed Methods Study for Evaluating Efficacy of Implementing HRO with Existing Cultural Practices: Alliant International University</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell JA, Caldwell JL (2005) Fatigue in military aviation: an overview of US military-approved pharmacological countermeasures. Aviat Space Environ Med 76(7):C39&#x2013;C51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16018329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>