<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">11118510</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2001</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-3751</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>529 Pt 3</Volume><Issue>Pt 3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2000</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine ingestion does not alter carbohydrate or fat metabolism in human skeletal muscle during exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>837</StartPage><EndPage>847</EndPage><MedlinePgn>837-47</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>This study examined the effect of ingesting caffeine (6 mg kg-1) on muscle carbohydrate and fat metabolism during steady-state exercise in humans. Young male subjects (n = 10) performed 1 h of exercise (70% maximal oxygen consumption (VO2,max)) on two occasions (after ingestion of placebo and caffeine) and leg metabolism was quantified by the combination of direct Fick measures and muscle biopsies. Following caffeine ingestion serum fatty acid and glycerol concentration increased (P&lt; or =0.05) at rest, suggesting enhanced adipose tissue lipolysis. In addition circulating adrenaline concentration was increased (P&lt; or =0.05) at rest following caffeine ingestion and this, as well as leg noradrenaline spillover, was elevated (P&lt; or =0.05) above placebo values during exercise. Caffeine resulted in a modest increase (P&lt; or =0.05) in leg vascular resistance, but no difference was found in leg blood flow. Arterial lactate and glucose concentrations were increased (P&lt; or =0.05) by caffeine, while the rise in plasma potassium was dampened (P&lt; or =0.05). There were no differences in respiratory exchange ratio or in leg glucose uptake, net muscle glycogenolysis, leg lactate release or muscle lactate, or glucose 6-phosphate concentration. Similarly there were no differences between treatments in leg fatty acid uptake, glycerol release or muscle acetyl CoA concentration. These findings indicate that caffeine ingestion stimulated the sympathetic nervous system but did not alter the carbohydrate or fat metabolism in the monitored leg. Other tissues must have been involved in the changes in circulating potassium, fatty acids, glucose and lactate.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Graham</LastName><ForeName>T E</ForeName><Initials>TE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Biology and Nutritional Sciences, University of Guelph, Guelph, Ontario, Canada. terrygra@uoguelph.ca</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helge</LastName><ForeName>J W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacLean</LastName><ForeName>D A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiens</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richter</LastName><ForeName>E A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002395">Catecholamines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000697">Central Nervous System Stimulants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005223">Fats</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>RWP5GA015D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011188">Potassium</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050260" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carbohydrate Metabolism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002395" MajorTopicYN="N">Catecholamines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000697" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System Stimulants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005223" MajorTopicYN="N">Fats</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006321" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011188" MajorTopicYN="N">Potassium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2000</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2001</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2000</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2001</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11118510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2000.00837.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PHY_1184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersen P, Saltin B. Maximal perfusion of skeletal muscle in man. Journal Physiology. 1985;366:233&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1193029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4057091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anselme F, Collomp K, Mercier B, Ahmaidi S, Prefaut Ch. Caffeine increases maximal anaerobic power and blood lactate concentration. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 1992;65:188&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1396643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmeyer HU, Bernt E, Schmidt F, Stork H. D-glucose determination with hexokinase and glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase. In: Bergmeyer HU, editor. Methods of Enzymatic Analysis. Vol. 3. New York: Academic Press; 1974. pp. 1196&#x2013;1201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernt E, Bermeyer HU, Mollering H. Creatine. In: Bermeyer HU, editor. Methods of Enzymatic Analysis. Vol. 4. New York: Academic Press; 1974. pp. 1772&#x2013;1776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buxton DB, Fisher RA, Robertson SM, Olson MS. Stimulation of glycogenolysis and vasoconstriction by adenosine analogs in the perfused rat liver. Biochemical Journal. 1997;248:35&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1148497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2829826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederblad G, Carlin D, Constantin-Teodosiu P, Humphrey LD. Radioisotopic assays of CoASH and carnitine and their acetylated forms in human skeletal muscle. Analytical Biochemistry. 1990;185:274&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2339783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesley A, Howlett RA, Heigenhauser JF, Hultman E, Spriet LL. Regulation of muscle glycogenolytic flux during intense aerobic exercise following caffeine ingestion. American Journal of Physiology. 1998;275:R596&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesley A, Hultman E, Spriet LL. Effects of epinephrine infusion on muscle glycogenolysis during intense aerobic exercise. American Journal of Physiology. 1995;268:E127&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7840170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crist GH, Xu B, Lanoue KFLCH. Tissue-specific effects of in vivo adenosine receptor blockade on glucose uptake by Zucker rats. FASEB Journal. 1998;12:1301&#x2013;1308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9761773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly JW. Mechanism of action of caffeine. In: Garattini S, editor. Caffeine, Coffee, and Health. New York: Raven Press; 1993. pp. 97&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels JW, Mole PA, Shaffrath JD, Steele PM. Effects of caffeine on blood pressure, heart rate, and forearm blood flow during dynamic leg exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1998;85:154&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9655769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derave W, Hespel P. Role of adenosine in regulating glucose uptake during contractions and hypoxia in rat skeletal muscle. The Journal of Physiology. 1999;515:255&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2269136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9925895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson MA, Schwarzkopf RJ, McKenzie RD. Effects of caffeine, fructose, and glucose ingestion on muscle glycogen utilization during exercise. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 1987;19:579&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3431374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essig D, Costill DL, van Handel PJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on utilization of muscle glycogen and lipid during leg ergometer cycling. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 1980;1:86&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. The possible actions of methylxanthines on various tissues. In: Reilly T, Orme M, editors. The Clinical Pharmacology of Sport and Exercise. Amsterdam: Elsvier Science B. V.; 1997. pp. 257&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Spriet LL. Performance and metabolic responses to a high caffeine dose during prolonged exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1991;71:2292&#x2013;2298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1778925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Spriet LL. Metabolic, catecholamine, and exercise performance responses to various doses of caffeine. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1995;78:867&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7775331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer F, Friars D, Graham TE. Comparison of caffeine and theophylline ingestion: exercise metabolism and endurance. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2000a;89:1837&#x2013;1844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer F, Hudson R, Ross R, Graham TE. Adenosine receptor antagonism decreases glucose disposal in humans. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2000b;32:S291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutmann I, Wahlefeld AW. L-(+)-Lactate determination with lactate dehydrogenase and NAD. In: Bergmeyer HU, editor. Methods of Enzymatic Analysis. Vol. 3. New York: Academic Press; 1974. pp. 1464&#x2013;1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han D-H, Hansen PA, Nolte LA, Holloszy JO. Removal of adenosine decreases the responsiveness of muscle glucose transport to insulin and contractions. Diabetes. 1998;47:1671&#x2013;1675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9792534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Hultman E, Nordesjo L-O. Glycogen, glycolytic intermediates and high-energy phosphates determined in biopsy samples of musculus quadriceps femoris of man at rest. Methods and variance of values. Scandinavian Journal of Clinical Laboratory Investigation. 1974;33:109&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4852173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellsten Y, MacLean D, Radergran G, Saltin B, Bangsbo J. Adenosine concentrations in the interstitium of resting and contracting human skeletal muscle. Circulation. 1998;98:6&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman M, Wendling P, Friars D, Graham T. Metabolic, catecholamine, and endurance responses to caffeine during intense exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1996;81:1658&#x2013;1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8904583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kather H, Wieland E, Fischer B, Schlierf G. Antilipolytic effects of N6-phenylisopropyladenosine and prostaglandin E2 in fat-cells of obese volunteers before and during energy restriction. Biochemical Journal. 1985;231:531&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1152783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3865651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindinger MI, Willmets RG, Hawke TJ. Stimulation of Na+, K+-pump activity in skeletal muscle by methylxanthines: evidence and proposed mechanisms. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica. 1996;156:347&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8729695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowry OH, Passonneau JV. Towowa, NJ, USA: Humana Press; 1993. Enzymatic Analysis: A Practical Guide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntosh BR, Wright BM. Caffeine ingestion and performance of a 1500 meter swim. Canadian Journal of Applied Physiology. 1995;20:168&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7640644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLane MP, Black PR, Law WR, Raymond RM. Adenosine reversal of in vivo hepatic responsiveness to insulin. Diabetes. 1990;39:62&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2210062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr T, van Soeren M, Graham TE, Kjaer M. Caffeine ingestion and metabolic responses of tetraplegic humans during electrical cycling. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1998;85:979&#x2013;985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9729573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer TM, Taberner PV, Houslay MD. Alterations in G-protein expression, Gi function and stimulatory receptor-mediated regulation of adipocyte adenylyl cyclase in a model of insulin-resistant diabetes with obesity. Cellular Signalling. 1992;4:365&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1419480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passonneau JV, Brown JG. Citrate: fluorimetric determination. In: Bermeyer HU, editor. Methods of Enzymatic Analysis. Vol. 3. New York: Academic Press; 1974. pp. 1565&#x2013;1569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prefaut C, Collomp K, Audran M, Ahmaidi S, Chatard JC. Benefits of caffeine ingestion on sprint performance in trained and untrained swimmers. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 1992;64:377&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1592065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raguso CA, Coggan AR, Sidossis LS, Gastaldelli A, Wolfe RR. Effect of theophylline on substrate metabolism during exercise. Metabolism. 1996;45:1153&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8781304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Aagaard T, Hargreaves M, Kjaer M. Effect of arm-cranking on leg blood flow and noradrenaline spillover during leg exercise in man. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica. 2000;144:9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1595357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Ruderman NB, Gavras H, Belur ER, Galbo H. Muscle glycogenolysis during exercise: dual control by epinephrine and contractions. American Journal of Physiology. 1982;242:E25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7058885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Sonne B, Christensen NJ, Galbo H. Role of epinephrine for muscular glycogenolysis and pacncreatic hormonal secretion in running rats. American Journal of Physiology. 1981;240:E526&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7015878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson D, Wade D, Workman R, Woosley RL, Oates JA. Tolerance to the humoral and hemodynamic effects of caffeine in man. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 1981;67:1111&#x2013;1117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC370671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7009653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savard G, Strange S, Kiens B, Richter EA, Christensen NJ, Saltin B. Noradrenaline spillover during exercise in active versus resting skeletal muscle in man. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica. 1987;131:507&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3442240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savard GK, Richter EA, Strange S, Kiens B, Christensen NJ, Saltin B. Norepinephrine spillover from skeletal muscle during exercise in humans: role of muscle mass. American Journal of Physiology. 1989;257:H1812&#x2013;1818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2603969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet LL, MacLean DA, Dyck DJ, Hultman E, Cederblad G, Graham TE. Caffeine ingestion and muscle metabolism during prolonged exercise in humans. American Journal of Physiology. 1992;262:E891&#x2013;898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1616022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Atkinson SA, Macdougall JD, Sale DG, Sutton JR. Physiological responses to caffeine during endurance running in habitual caffeine users. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 1989;21:418&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2674593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Soeren M, Mohr T, Kjaer M, Graham TE. Acute effects of caffeine ingestion at rest in humans with impaired epinephrine responses. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1996;80:999&#x2013;1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8964766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vannucci SJ, Klim CM, Martin LF, Lanoue KF. A1-adenosine receptor-mediated inhibition of adipocyte adenylate cyclase and lipolysis in Zucker rats. American Journal of Physiology. 1989;257:E871&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2558574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergauwen L, Hespel P, Richter EA. Adenosine receptors mediate synergistic stimulation of glucose uptake and transport by insulin and by contractions in rat skeletal muscle. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 1994;93:974&#x2013;981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC294012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8132783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergauwen L, Richter EA, Hespel P. Adenosine exerts a glycogen-sparing action in contracting rat skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology. 1997;272:E762&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9176173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiker H, Feraudi M, Hagele H, Pluto R. Electrochemical determination of catecholamines in urine and plasma separations with HPLC. Clinical Chemistry Acta. 1984;141:17&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6467618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson DH, Mellander S. D-(-)-3-Hydroxybutyrate. In: Bergmeyer HU, editor. Methods of Enzymatic Analysis. Vol. 4. New York: Academic Press; 1974. pp. 1836&#x2013;1839.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>