<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">22348079</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a caffeine-containing energy drink on simulated soccer performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e31380</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e31380</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e31380</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0031380</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">To investigate the effects of a caffeine-containing energy drink on soccer performance during a simulated game. A second purpose was to assess the post-exercise urine caffeine concentration derived from the energy drink intake.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY/PRINCIPAL FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Nineteen semiprofessional soccer players ingested 630 &#xb1; 52 mL of a commercially available energy drink (sugar-free Red Bull&#xae;) to provide 3 mg of caffeine per kg of body mass, or a decaffeinated control drink (0 mg/kg). After sixty minutes they performed a 15-s maximal jump test, a repeated sprint test (7 &#xd7; 30 m; 30 s of active recovery) and played a simulated soccer game. Individual running distance and speed during the game were measured using global positioning satellite (GPS) devices. In comparison to the control drink, the ingestion of the energy drink increased mean jump height in the jump test (34.7 &#xb1; 4.7 v 35.8 &#xb1; 5.5 cm; P&lt;0.05), mean running speed during the sprint test (25.6 &#xb1; 2.1 v 26.3 &#xb1; 1.8 km &#xb7; h(-1); P&lt;0.05) and total distance covered at a speed higher than 13 km &#xb7; h(-1) during the game (1205 &#xb1; 289 v 1436 &#xb1; 326 m; P&lt;0.05). In addition, the energy drink increased the number of sprints during the whole game (30 &#xb1; 10 v 24 &#xb1; 8; P&lt;0.05). Post-exercise urine caffeine concentration was higher after the energy drink than after the control drink (4.1 &#xb1; 1.0 v 0.1 &#xb1; 0.1 &#xb5;g &#xb7; mL(-1); P&lt;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS/SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A caffeine-containing energy drink in a dose equivalent to 3 mg/kg increased the ability to repeatedly sprint and the distance covered at high intensity during a simulated soccer game. In addition, the caffeinated energy drink increased jump height which may represent a meaningful improvement for headers or when players are competing for a ball.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Coso</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Camilo Jos&#xe9; Cela University, Exercise Physiology Laboratory, Madrid, Spain. jdelcoso@ucjc.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu&#xf1;oz-Fern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>V&#xed;ctor E</ForeName><Initials>VE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu&#xf1;oz</LastName><ForeName>Gloria</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as</LastName><ForeName>Valent&#xed;n E</ForeName><Initials>VE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortega</LastName><ForeName>Juan F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamouti</LastName><ForeName>Nassim</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbero</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra</LastName><ForeName>Jes&#xfa;s</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000652" MajorTopicYN="N">urine</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061215" MajorTopicYN="Y">Energy Drinks</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="N">Running</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="N">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22348079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3279366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0031380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-11-20846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Coso JD, Mu&#xf1;oz G, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J. Prevalence of caffeine use in elite athletes following its removal from the World Anti-Doping Agency list of banned substances. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2011;36:555&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21854160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauson KA, Shields KM, McQueen CE, Persad N. Safety issues associated with commercially available energy drinks. J Am Pharm Assoc (2003) 2008;48:e55&#x2013;63; quiz e64&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froiland K, Koszewski W, Hingst J, Kopecky L. Nutritional supplement use among college athletes and their sources of information. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2004;14:104&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15129934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristiansen M, Levy-Milne R, Barr S, Flint A. Dietary supplement use by varsity athletes at a Canadian university. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2005;15:195&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16089277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR. Caffeine and energy drinks. Strength and Conditioning Journal. 2010;32:15&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM. Caffeine and sports performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33:1319&#x2013;1334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coso J, Estevez E, Mora-Rodriguez R. Caffeine effects on short-term performance during prolonged exercise in the heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:744&#x2013;751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18317369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coso J, Estevez E, Mora-Rodriguez R. Caffeine during exercise in the heat: thermoregulation and fluid-electrolyte balance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:164&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on exercise testing: a meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2004;14:626&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15657469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alford C, Cox H, Wescott R. The effects of red bull energy drink on human performance and mood. Amino Acids. 2001;21:139&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira SE, de Mello MT, Rossi MV, Souza-Formigoni ML. Does an energy drink modify the effects of alcohol in a maximal effort test? Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 2004;28:1408&#x2013;1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15365313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Little JP, Magnus C, Chilibeck PD. Effect of Red Bull energy drink on repeated Wingate cycle performance and bench-press muscle endurance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17:433&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18046053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Kang J, Ratamess NA, Hoffman MW, Tranchina CP, et al. Examination of a pre-exercise, high energy supplement on exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2621122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Matera AJ, Basinger J, Evans M, Schurman T, et al. Effects of red bull energy drink on repeated sprint performance in women athletes. Amino Acids 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21461905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy JL, Kammer L, Ding Z, Wang B, Bernard JR, et al. Improved cycling time-trial performance after ingestion of a caffeine energy drink. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19:61&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Kleisinger AK, Grenier S, Dorsch KD. Effect of sugar-free Red Bull energy drink on high-intensity run time-to-exhaustion in young adults. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:1271&#x2013;1275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Spriet LL. Metabolic, catecholamine, and exercise performance responses to various doses of caffeine. J Appl Physiol. 1995;78:867&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7775331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins NT, Trilk JL, Singhal A, O'Connor PJ, Cureton KJ. Ergogenic effects of low doses of caffeine on cycling performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18:328&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18562777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Howatson G, Abraham CS, Lockey RA, Goodwin JE, et al. Caffeine supplementation and multiple sprint running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1835&#x2013;1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart GR, Hopkins WG, Cook C, Cairns SP. Multiple effects of caffeine on simulated high-intensity team-sport performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1998&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16286872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbero-&#xc1;lvarez JC, Coutts A, Granda J, Barbero-&#xc1;lvarez V, Castagna C. The validity and reliability of a global positioning satellite system device to assess speed and repeated sprint ability (RSA) in athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2009;13:232&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rampinini E, Coutts AJ, Castagna C, Sassi R, Impellizzeri FM. Variation in top level soccer match performance. Int J Sports Med. 2007;28:1018&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17497575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara AJ, Abian J, Alegre LM, Jimenez L, Aguado X. Assessment of power output in jump tests for applicants to a sports sciences degree. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2006;46:419&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16998446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ, Duffield R. Validity and reliability of GPS devices for measuring movement demands of team sports. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13:133&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19054711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castagna C, D'Ottavio S, Abt G. Activity profile of young soccer players during actual match play. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:775&#x2013;780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr A, Dawson B, Schneiker K, Goodman C, Lay B. Effect of caffeine supplementation on repeated sprint running performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2008;48:472&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gant N, Ali A, Foskett A. The influence of caffeine and carbohydrate coingestion on simulated soccer performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20:191&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20601736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts SP, Stokes KA, Trewartha G, Doyle J, Hogben P, et al. Effects of carbohydrate and caffeine ingestion on performance during a rugby union simulation protocol. J Sports Sci. 2010;28:833&#x2013;842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20521199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbero-&#xc1;lvarez JC, Alvarez VB, Granda Vera J. Activity profile in young soccer players. Apunts: Sports and Physical Education. 2007;90:33&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira Da Silva N, Kirkendall DT, Leite De Barros Neto T. Movement patterns in elite Brazilian youth soccer. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2007;47:270&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17641592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Santisteban J, Impellizzeri FM, Castagna C. Fitness determinants of success in men's and women's football. J Sports Sci. 2009;27:107&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19058090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Mendez-Villanueva A, Bishop D. Repeated-sprint ability - part I: factors contributing to fatigue. Sports Med. 2011;41:673&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21780851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner TL, Jenkins DG, Coombes JS, Taaffe DR, Leveritt MD. Dose response of caffeine on 2000-m rowing performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:571&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M. The effects of caffeine on the maximal accumulated oxygen deficit and short-term running performance. Int J Sport Nutr. 1998;8:95&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9637189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith P, Hughes M, Davison R. Caffeine lowers perceptual response and increases power output during high-intensity cycling. J Sports Sci. 2004;22:637&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15370494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles JD, Coleman D, Tegerdine M, Swaine IL. The effects of caffeine ingestion on performance time, speed and power during a laboratory-based 1 km cycling time-trial. J Sports Sci. 2006;24:1165&#x2013;1171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17035165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce CR, Anderson ME, Fraser SF, Stepto NK, Klein R, et al. Enhancement of 2000-m rowing performance after caffeine ingestion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1958&#x2013;1963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Nieuwenhoven MA, Brummer RM, Brouns F. Gastrointestinal function during exercise: comparison of water, sports drink, and sports drink with caffeine. J Appl Physiol. 2000;89:1079&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo SE, Jentjens RL, Wallis GA, Jeukendrup AE. Caffeine increases exogenous carbohydrate oxidation during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99:844&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Izumi I, Kagamimori S, Sokejima S, Yamagami T, et al. Role of taurine supplementation to prevent exercise-induced oxidative stress in healthy young men. Amino Acids. 2004;26:203&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15042451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierno S, De Luca A, Camerino C, Huxtable RJ, Camerino DC. Chronic administration of taurine to aged rats improves the electrical and contractile properties of skeletal muscle fibers. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1998;286:1183&#x2013;1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9732377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suboticanec K, Stavljenic A, Schalch W, Buzina R. Effects of pyridoxine and riboflavin supplementation on physical fitness in young adolescents. Int J Vitam Nutr Res. 1990;60:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2387675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbeke FT, Debackere M. Caffeine: use and abuse in sports. Int J Sports Med. 1984;5:179&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6480201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce CR, Anderson ME, Fraser SF, Stepto NK, Klein R, et al. Enhancement of 2000-m rowing performance after caffeine ingestion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1958&#x2013;1963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox GR, Desbrow B, Montgomery PG, Anderson ME, Bruce CR, et al. Effect of different protocols of caffeine intake on metabolism and endurance performance. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:990&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasman WJ, van Baak MA, Jeukendrup AE, de Haan A. The effect of different dosages of caffeine on endurance performance time. Int J Sports Med. 1995;16:225&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7657415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lelo A, Miners JO, Robson RA, Birkett DJ. Quantitative assessment of caffeine partial clearances in man. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 1986;22:183&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1401107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3756066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Kavouras SA. Caffeine use in sports, pharmacokinetics in man, and cellular mechanisms of action. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2005;45:535&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16371327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>