<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34033601</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0374</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Menopause (New York, N.Y.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Menopause</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Independent association of palpitation with vasomotor symptoms and anxiety in middle-aged women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>741</StartPage><EndPage>747</EndPage><MedlinePgn>741-747</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/GME.0000000000001776</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Palpitation, or the sensation of rapid or irregular heartbeats, is common in menopausal women; however, the precise underlying mechanisms are unknown. We aimed to investigate factors associated with palpitation in middle-aged women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Medical records of 394 women aged 40 to 59&#x200a;years (108 premenopausal, 85 perimenopausal, and 201 postmenopausal) were analyzed cross-sectionally. Palpitation severity was estimated based on responses to the Menopausal Symptom Scale. Effects of background characteristics, including age, menopausal status, body composition, cardiovascular parameters, basal metabolism, physical fitness, lifestyle factors, vasomotor, and psychological symptoms on palpitation were assessed using multivariate logistic regression analysis. The association between autonomic nervous system activity and palpitation was also analyzed in 198 participants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Prevalence of palpitation by severity was as follows: none, 26.4%; mild, 32.7%; moderate, 29.4%; severe, 11.4%. In univariate analyses, the more severely the women were affected by palpitation, 1) the higher their systolic blood pressure, 2) the less exercise they performed, 3) the lower they scored in the sit-and-reach test, 4) the higher their vasomotor symptoms score in the Menopausal Health Related-Quality of Life questionnaire, and 5) the higher their Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale. Multiple logistic regression analysis revealed that moderate to severe palpitation was independently associated with the vasomotor symptom score (adjusted odds ratio [95% confidence interval]: 1.18 [1.07-1.31]) and Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale anxiety subscale score (1.19 [1.12-1.27]).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Rapid or irregular heartbeats are highly prevalent in middle-aged women. It is not associated with age, menopausal status, heart rate, arrhythmia, autonomic nervous system activity, caffeine, or alcohol consumption, but with vasomotor symptoms and anxiety.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by The North American Menopause Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Enomoto</LastName><ForeName>Haruka</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Terauchi</LastName><ForeName>Masakazu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's Health, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Odai</LastName><ForeName>Tamami</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's Health, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Kiyoko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Women's Health, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iizuka</LastName><ForeName>Makoto</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Saitama Medical Center, Dokkyo Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akiyoshi</LastName><ForeName>Mihoko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Nutrition, Bunkyo University, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyasaka</LastName><ForeName>Naoyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Menopause</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9433353</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1072-3714</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Menopause. 2021 Jul 1;28(7):731-734. doi: 10.1097/GME.0000000000001808.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34165445</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001145" MajorTopicYN="N">Arrhythmias, Cardiac</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019584" MajorTopicYN="N">Hot Flashes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008593" MajorTopicYN="N">Menopause</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014666" MajorTopicYN="N">Vasomotor System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Financial disclosures/conflicts of interest: M.T. reports research grants from Ibaraki Prefecture and personal fees for speaker's bureau from Fuji Pharma Co Ltd, Bayer Holding Ltd and Hisamitsu Pharmaceutical Co, Inc, Kikkioman Corporation. The other authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GME.0000000000001776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042192-202107000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goyal A, Robinson KJ, Katta S, Sanchack KE. Palpitations, StatPearls. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing LLC; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terauchi M, Hiramitsu S, Akiyoshi M, et al. Associations between anxiety, depression and insomnia in peri- and post-menopausal women. Maturitas 2012; 72:61&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terauchi M, Hirose A, Akiyoshi M, Owa Y, Kato K, Kubota T. Prevalence and predictors of storage lower urinary tract symptoms in perimenopausal and postmenopausal women attending a menopause clinic. Menopause 2015; 22:1084&#x2013;1090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terauchi M, Hirose A, Akiyoshi M, Kato K, Miyasaka N. Feelings of unattractiveness in peri- and postmenopausal women are associated with depressed mood, poor memory and unsatisfactory sexual relationships. Climacteric 2017; 20:228&#x2013;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odai T, Terauchi M, Hirose A, Kato K, Akiyoshi M, Miyasaka N. Severity of hot flushes is inversely associated with dietary intake of vitamin B(6) and oily fish. Climacteric 2019; 22:617&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terauchi M, Odai T, Hirose A, Kato K, Miyasaka N. Chilliness in Japanese middle-aged women is associated with anxiety and low n-3 fatty acid intake. Climacteric 2020; 23:178&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terauchi M, Obayashi S, Akiyoshi M, Kato K, Matsushima E, Kubota T. Effects of oral estrogen and hypnotics on Japanese peri- and postmenopausal women with sleep disturbance. J Obstet Gynaecol Res 2011; 37:741&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terauchi M, Obayashi S, Akiyoshi M, Kato K, Matsushima E, Kubota T. Insomnia in Japanese peri- and postmenopausal women. Climacteric 2010; 13:479&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter M, Battersby R, Whitehead M. Relationships between psychological symptoms, somatic complaints and menopausal status. Maturitas 1986; 8:217&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter M. The south-east England longitudinal study of the climacteric and postmenopause. Maturitas 1992; 14:117&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terauchi M, Hirose A, Akiyoshi M, Owa Y, Kato K, Kubota T. Subgrouping of Japanese middle-aged women attending a menopause clinic using physical and psychological symptom profiles: a cross-sectional study. BMC Women's Health 2014; 14:148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand 1983; 67:361&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyasaka N, Akiyoshi M, Kubota T. Relationship between autonomic nervous system activity and bone mineral density in non-medicated perimenopausal women. J Bone Miner Metab 2014; 32:588&#x2013;592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neugarten BL, Kraines RJ. Menopausal symptoms in women of various ages. Psychosom Med 1965; 27:266&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold EB, Sternfeld B, Kelsey JL, et al. Relation of demographic and lifestyle factors to symptoms in a multi-racial/ethnic population of women 40-55&#x200a;years of age. Am J Epidemiol 2000; 152:463&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson D, Yoshizawa T, Gollschewski S, Atogami F, Courtney M. Menopause in Australia and Japan: effects of country of residence on menopausal status and menopausal symptoms. Climacteric 2004; 7:165&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott AV. Diagnostic approach to palpitations. Am Fam Physician 2005; 71:743&#x2013;750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conen D, Tedrow UB, Cook NR, Moorthy MV, Buring JE, Albert CM. Alcohol consumption and risk of incident atrial fibrillation in women. JAMA 2008; 300:2489&#x2013;2496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirlow MJ, Mathers CD. A study of caffeine consumption and symptoms; indigestion, palpitations, tremor, headache and insomnia. Int J Epidemiol 1985; 14:239&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf8;chen ML, Rasmussen K. Palpitations and lifestyle: impact of depression and self-rated health. The Nordland Health Study. Scand J Soc Med 1996; 24:140&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosano GM, Rillo M, Leonardo F, Pappone C, Chierchia SL. Palpitations: what is the mechanism, and when should we treat them? Int J Fertil Womens Med 1997; 42:94&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishizuka B, Kudo Y, Tango T. Cross-sectional community survey of menopause symptoms among Japanese women. Maturitas 2008; 61:260&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeldis SM, Levine BJ, Michelson EL, Morganroth J. Cardiovascular complaints. Correlation with cardiac arrhythmias on 24-hour electrocardiographic monitoring. Chest 1980; 78:456&#x2013;461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipski J, Cohen L, Espinoza J, Motro M, Dack S, Donoso E. Value of Holter monitoring in assessing cardiac arrhythmias in symptomatic patients. Am J Cardiol 1976; 37:102&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsky AJ. Palpitations, arrhythmias, and awareness of cardiac activity. Ann Intern Med 2001; 134:832&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold EB, Colvin A, Avis N, et al. Longitudinal analysis of the association between vasomotor symptoms and race/ethnicity across the menopausal transition: study of women's health across the nation. Am J Public Health 2006; 96:1226&#x2013;1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politi MC, Schleinitz MD, Col NF. Revisiting the duration of vasomotor symptoms of menopause: a meta-analysis. J Gen Intern Med 2008; 23:1507&#x2013;1513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentini A, Petraglia F, De Vita D, et al. Changes of plasma calcitonin gene-related peptide levels in postmenopausal women. Am J Obstet Gynecol 1996; 175:638&#x2013;642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyon YA, Spetz AC, Theodorsson GE, Hammar ML. Concentrations of calcitonin gene-related peptide and neuropeptide Y in plasma increase during flushes in postmenopausal women. Menopause 2000; 7:25&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JT, Shiraki M. Menopausal hot flash and calciotonin gene-related peptide; effect of Keishi-bukuryo-gan, a kampo medicine, related to plasma calciotonin gene-related peptide level. Maturitas 2003; 45:199&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labastida-Ram&#xed;rez A, Rubio-Beltr&#xe1;n E, Villal&#xf3;n CM, MaassenVanDenBrink A. Gender aspects of CGRP in migraine. Cephalalgia 2019; 39:435&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyengar S, Ossipov MH, Johnson KW. The role of calcitonin gene-related peptide in peripheral and central pain mechanisms including migraine. Pain 2017; 158:543&#x2013;559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell FA, King R, Smillie SJ, Kodji X, Brain SD. Calcitonin gene-related peptide: physiology and pathophysiology. Physiol Rev 2014; 94:1099&#x2013;1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorby-Adams AJ, Marcoionni AM, Dempsey ER, Woenig JA, Turner RJ. The role of neurogenic inflammation in blood-brain barrier disruption and development of cerebral oedema following acute central nervous system (CNS) injury. Int J Mol Sci 2017; 18:1788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima WG, Marques-Oliveira GH, da Silva TM, Chaves VE. Role of calcitonin gene-related peptide in energy metabolism. Endocrine 2017; 58:3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brain SD, Grant AD. Vascular actions of calcitonin gene-related peptide and adrenomedullin. Physiol Rev 2004; 84:903&#x2013;934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray DW, Marshall I. Human alpha-calcitonin gene-related peptide stimulates adenylate cyclase and guanylate cyclase and relaxes rat thoracic aorta by releasing nitric oxide. Br J Pharmacol 1992; 107:691&#x2013;696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeller J, Poulsen KT, Sutton JE, et al. CGRP function-blocking antibodies inhibit neurogenic vasodilatation without affecting heart rate or arterial blood pressure in the rat. Br J Pharmacol 2008; 155:1093&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braasch DC, Deegan EM, Grimm ER, Griffin JD. Calcitonin gene-related peptide alters the firing rates of hypothalamic temperature sensitive and insensitive neurons. BMC Neurosci 2008; 9:64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassen LH, Haderslev PA, Jacobsen VB, Iversen HK, Sperling B, Olesen J. CGRP may play a causative role in migraine. Cephalalgia 2002; 22:54&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen JM, Hauge AW, Olesen J, Ashina M. Calcitonin gene-related peptide triggers migraine-like attacks in patients with migraine with aura. Cephalalgia 2010; 30:1179&#x2013;1186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen CE, Younis S, Deen M, Khan S, Ghanizada H, Ashina M. Migraine induction with calcitonin gene-related peptide in patients from erenumab trials. J Headache Pain 2018; 19:105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mai TH, Wu J, Diedrich A, Garland EM, Robertson D. Calcitonin gene-related peptide (CGRP) in autonomic cardiovascular regulation and vascular structure. J Am Soc Hypertens 2014; 8:286&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberger JT, Kravitz HM, Chang Y, et al. Does risk for anxiety increase during the menopausal transition? Study of women's health across the nation. Menopause 2013; 20:488&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu MX, Milaneschi Y, Lamers F, et al. The association of depression and anxiety with cardiac autonomic activity: the role of confounding effects of antidepressants. Depress Anxiety 2019; 36:1163&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu MX, Lamers F, Penninx B, de Geus EJC. Temporal stability and drivers of change in cardiac autonomic nervous system activity. Auton Neurosci 2017; 208:117&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonsbu E, Dammen T, Morken G, Lied A, Vik-Mo H, Martinsen EW. Cardiac and psychiatric diagnoses among patients referred for chest pain and palpitations. Scand Cardiovasc J 2009; 43:256&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsky AJ, Cleary PD, Coeytaux RR, Ruskin JN. Psychiatric disorders in medical outpatients complaining of palpitations. J Gen Intern Med 1994; 9:306&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>