<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22152427</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of carbohydrates-BCAAs-caffeine ingestion on performance and neuromuscular function during a 2-h treadmill run: a randomized, double-blind, cross-over placebo-controlled study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22</StartPage><MedlinePgn>22</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-8-22</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Carbohydrates (CHOs), branched-chain amino acids (BCAAs) and caffeine are known to improve running performance. However, no information is available on the effects of a combination of these ingredients on performance and neuromuscular function during running.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The present study was designed as a randomized double-blind cross-over placebo-controlled trial. Thirteen trained adult males completed two protocols, each including two conditions: placebo (PLA) and Sports Drink (SPD: CHOs 68.6 g.L-1, BCAAs 4 g.L-1, caffeine 75 mg.L-1). Protocol 1 consisted of an all-out 2 h treadmill run. Total distance run and glycemia were measured. In protocol 2, subjects exercised for 2 h at 95% of their lowest average speeds recorded during protocol 1 (whatever the condition). Glycemia, blood lactate concentration and neuromuscular function were determined immediately before and after exercise. Oxygen consumption (V&#x2d9;O2), heart rate (HR) and rate of perceived exertion (RPE) were recorded during the exercise. Total fluids ingested were 2 L whatever the protocols and conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared to PLA, ingestion of SPD increased running performance (p = 0.01), maintained glycemia and attenuated central fatigue (p = 0.04), an index of peripheral fatigue (p = 0.04) and RPE (p = 0.006). Maximal voluntary contraction, V&#x2d9;O2, and HR did not differ between the two conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study showed that ingestion of a combination of CHOs, BCAAs and caffeine increased performance by about 2% during a 2-h treadmill run. The results of neuromuscular function were contrasted: no clear cut effects of SPD were observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov, http://www.clinicaltrials.gov, NCT00799630.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peltier</LastName><ForeName>S&#xe9;bastien L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire Lescuyer, Aytr&#xe9;, France. sebastien.peltier@laboratoire-lescuyer.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vincent</LastName><ForeName>Lucile</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Millet</LastName><ForeName>Guillaume Y</ForeName><Initials>GY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sirvent</LastName><ForeName>Pascal</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morin</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Beno&#xee;t</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guerraz</LastName><ForeName>Michel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geyssant</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lescuyer</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Fran&#xe7;ois</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feasson</LastName><ForeName>L&#xe9;onard</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Messonnier</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT00799630</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22152427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3248356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-8-22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-8-22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Coyle EF. Carbohydrate supplementation during exercise. J Nutr. 1992;122:788&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1542049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Convertino VA, Armstrong LE, Coyle EF, Mack GW, Sawka MN, Senay LC Jr, Sherman WM. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and fluid replacement. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:i&#x2013;vii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9303999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake J, Nosaka K, Suzuki K. Characterization of inflammatory responses to eccentric exercise in humans. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2005;11:64&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16385845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E. A role for branched-chain amino acids in reducing central fatigue. J Nutr. 2006;136:544S&#x2013;547S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle EF, Coggan AR, Hemmert MK, Ivy JL. Muscle glycogen utilization during prolonged strenuous exercise when fed carbohydrate. J Appl Physiol. 1986;61:165&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3525502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup A, Brouns F, Wagenmakers AJ, Saris WH. Carbohydrate-electrolyte feedings improve 1 h time trial cycling performance. Int J Sports Med. 1997;18:125&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9081269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup AE, Jentjens R. Oxidation of carbohydrate feedings during prolonged exercise: current thoughts, guidelines and directions for future research. Sports Med. 2000;29:407&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10870867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsintzas K, Williams C. Human muscle glycogen metabolism during exercise. Effect of carbohydrate supplementation. Sports Med. 1998;25:7&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9458524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullo A, Monda M, Brizzi G, Meninno V, Papa A, Lombardi P, Fabbri B. The effect of a carbohydrate loading on running performance during a 25-km treadmill time trial by level of aerobic capacity in athletes. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 1998;2:195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10710819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Nieuwenhoven MA, Brouns F, Kovacs EM. The effect of two sports drinks and water on GI complaints and performance during an 18-km run. Int J Sports Med. 2005;26:281&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15795812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch AN, Dennis SC, Noakes TD. Influence of carbohydrate ingestion on fuel substrate turnover and oxidation during prolonged exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76:2364&#x2013;2372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7928859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karelis AD, Smith JW, Passe DH, Peronnet F. Carbohydrate administration and exercise performance: what are the potential mechanisms involved? Sports Med. 2010;40:747&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20726621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Summers RW, Schedl HP, Flanagan SW, Chang R, Gisolfi CV. Effects of carbohydrate type and concentration and solution osmolality on water absorption. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27:1607&#x2013;1615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8614315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup AE. Carbohydrate intake during exercise and performance. Nutrition. 2004;20:669&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15212750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup AE, Moseley L, Mainwaring GI, Samuels S, Perry S, Mann CH. Exogenous carbohydrate oxidation during ultraendurance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:1134&#x2013;1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16322366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray B. The role of salt and glucose replacement drinks in the marathon. Sports Med. 2007;37:358&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17465607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adopo E, Peronnet F, Massicotte D, Brisson GR, Hillaire-Marcel C. Respective oxidation of exogenous glucose and fructose given in the same drink during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76:1014&#x2013;1019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8005840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jandrain BJ, Pallikarakis N, Normand S, Pirnay F, Lacroix M, Mosora F, Pachiaudi C, Gautier JF, Scheen AJ, Riou JP. et al. Fructose utilization during exercise in men: rapid conversion of ingested fructose to circulating glucose. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74:2146&#x2013;2154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8335542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahlborg G, Bjorkman O. Splanchnic and muscle fructose metabolism during and after exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1990;69:1244&#x2013;1251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2262441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decombaz J, Jentjens R, Ith M, Scheurer E, Buehler T, Jeukendrup A, Boesch C. Fructose and galactose enhance postexercise human liver glycogen synthesis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1964&#x2013;1971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21407126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacs EM, Stegen J, Brouns F. Effect of caffeinated drinks on substrate metabolism, caffeine excretion, and performance. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85:709&#x2013;715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo SE, Jentjens RL, Wallis GA, Jeukendrup AE. Caffeine increases exogenous carbohydrate oxidation during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99:844&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar JM, Cafarelli E. Caffeine: a valuable tool to study central fatigue in humans? Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2004;32:143&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15604932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Newsholme EA. Effect of branched-chain amino acid supplementation on the exercise-induced change in aromatic amino acid concentration in human muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1992;146:293&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1481685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Ek S, Newsholme EA. Influence of ingesting a solution of branched-chain amino acids on plasma and muscle concentrations of amino acids during prolonged submaximal exercise. Nutrition. 1996;12:485&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8878139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newsholme EA, Blomstrand E. Branched-chain amino acids and central fatigue. J Nutr. 2006;136:274S&#x2013;276S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Watson P, Hasegawa H, Roelands B, Piacentini MF. Central fatigue: the serotonin hypothesis and beyond. Sports Med. 2006;36:881&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17004850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foissac MJ, Berthollet R, Seux J, Belli A, Millet GY. Effects of hiking pole inertia on energy and muscular costs during uphill walking. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1117&#x2013;1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18460993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholander PF. Simple Syringe Burette. Science. 1947;105:581&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17746228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messonnier L, Freund H, Feasson L, Prieur F, Castells J, Denis C, Linossier MT, Geyssant A, Lacour JR. Blood lactate exchange and removal abilities after relative high-intensity exercise: effects of training in normoxia and hypoxia. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;84:403&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11417427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Ratings of perceived exertion and heart rates during short-term cycle exercise and their use in a new cycling strength test. Int J Sports Med. 1982;3:153&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7129724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merton PA. Interaction between muscle fibres in a twitch. J Physiol. 1954;124:311&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1366269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13175134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Hassmen P, Ek S, Ekblom B, Newsholme EA. Influence of ingesting a solution of branched-chain amino acids on perceived exertion during exercise. Acta Physiol Scand. 1997;159:41&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9124069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassmen P, Blomstrand E, Ekblom B, Newsholme EA. Branched-chain amino acid supplementation during 30-km competitive run: mood and cognitive performance. Nutrition. 1994;10:405&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7819652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybo L. CNS fatigue and prolonged exercise: effect of glucose supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:589&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12673141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Bailey SP. Possible mechanisms of central nervous system fatigue during exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:45&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9000155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Alderson NL, Welsh RS. Serotonin and central nervous system fatigue: nutritional considerations. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72:573S&#x2013;578S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10919962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar JM, Cafarelli E. Effects of caffeine on neuromuscular function. J Appl Physiol. 1999;87:801&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10444642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GY, Martin V, Lattier G, Ballay Y. Mechanisms contributing to knee extensor strength loss after prolonged running exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2003;94:193&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GY, Lepers R. Alterations of neuromuscular function after prolonged running, cycling and skiing exercises. Sports Med. 2004;34:105&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14965189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski K, Rohde T, Zacho M, Asp S, Pedersen BK. Evidence that interleukin-6 is produced in human skeletal muscle during prolonged running. J Physiol. 1998;508(Pt 3):949&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2230908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9518745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JL, Todd G, Gandevia SC. Evidence for a supraspinal contribution to human muscle fatigue. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2006;33:400&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16620309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>