<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23946663</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-6388</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>4</Volume><PubDate><Year>2011</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition and metabolic insights</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab Insights</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of acute caffeinated coffee consumption on energy utilization related to glucose and lipid oxidation from short submaximal treadmill exercise in sedentary men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>65</StartPage><EndPage>72</EndPage><MedlinePgn>65-72</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4137/NMI.S8299</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Aim of this study was to evaluate the short term effect of coffee drinking on energy utilization in sedentary men.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study was performed in healthy sedentary men, who were randomized into three groups, control (n = 6), decaffeinated (n = 10), and caffeine (n = 10). The caffeine dose in coffee was rechecked and calculated for individual volunteers at 5 mg/kg. Baseline before drinking, complete blood count (CBC), glucose, antioxidant capacity, lipid peroxide, and caffeine in blood was evaluated. After drinking coffee for 1 hr, the submaximal exercise test with a modified Bruce protocol was carried out, and the VO2 and RER were analyzed individually at 80% maximal heart rate, then the blood was repeat evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Three groups showed a nonsignificant difference in CBC results and physical characteristics. The caffeine group showed significant changes in all parameters; higher VO2 levels, (P = 0.037) and lower RER (P = 0.047), when compared to the baseline. Furthermore, the glucose level after exercise test increased significantly (P = 0.033) as well as lipid peroxide levels (P = 0.005), whereas antioxidant capacity did not change significantly (P = 0.759), when compared to the before exercise testing. In addition, the blood caffeine level also increased only in the caffeine group (P = 0.008).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Short consumption of caffeinated coffee (5 mg/kg of caffeine), improves energy utilization and relates to glucose derivation and lipid oxidation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leelarungrayub</LastName><ForeName>Donrawee</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxidative Stress, Nutrition and Exercise Biochemistry Laboratory, Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Associated Medical Sciences, Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai 50200, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sallepan</LastName><ForeName>Maliwan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charoenwattana</LastName><ForeName>Sukanya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab Insights</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550186</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-6388</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RER</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VO2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antioxidant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipid</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23946663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4137/NMI.S8299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">nmi-4-2011-065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Caffeine and Creatine Use in sport. Ann Nutr Metab. 2010;57:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21346331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandel HG. Update on caffeine consumption, disposition, and action. Food Chem Toxicol. 2002;40:1231&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12204386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Caffeine and endurance performance. Sport Med. 1994;18:109&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9132918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Dalsky GP, Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports. 1978;10:155&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">723503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ. Nutritional ergoneic aids and exercise performance. Nutr Research Reviews. 1999;12:255&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Effect of caffeine on the neuromuscular system-potential as an ergogenic aid. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33:1284&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent D, Schneider KE, Prusaczyk WK, et al. Effects of caffeine on muscle glycogen utilization and the neuroendocrine axis during exercise. J Clin Endocrinal Metab. 2000;85:2170&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10852448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ping WC, Keong CC, Bandyopadhyay A. Effect of acute supplementation of caffeine on cardiorespiratory responses during endurance running in a hot and humid climate. Indian J Med Res. 2010;132:36&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20693587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco FSC, Costa NMB, Ferreira SA, et al. The effects of a high dosage of creatine and caffeine supplementation on the lean body mass composition of rats submitted to vertical jumping training. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2011;8:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3063821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21362194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein ER, Ziegenfuss T, Kalman D, et al. J International society of sports nutrition position stand: caffeine and performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C. Antioxidant ability of caffeine and its metabolites based on the study of oxygen radical absorbing capacity and inhibition of LDL peroxidation. Clin Chim Acta. 2000;295:141&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10767400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Ruiz JA, Leake DS, Ames JM. In vitro antioxidant activity of coffee compounds and their metabolites. J Agric Food Chem. 2007;55:6962&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17655324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kot M, Daniel WA. Caffeine as a marker substrate for testing cytochrome P450 activity in human and rat. Pharmacol Rep. 2008;60:789&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19211970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sport Medicine (ACSM) ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leelarungrayub D, Pratanaphon S, Pothongsunun P, et al. Vernonia cinerea Less. supplementation and strenuous exercise reduce smoking rate; relation to oxidative stress status and beta-endorphin release in active smokers. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;26:21. 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2891663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20500899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Re R, Pellegrini N, Proteggente A, et al. Antioxidant activity applying an improved ABTS radical cation decolorization assay. Free Radic Biol Med. 1999;26:1231&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10381194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin MJ, Pablos F, Gonzalez AG. Simutaneous determination of caffeine and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs in pharmaceutical formulations and blood plasma by reversed-phase HPLC form linear gradient elution. Talanta. 1999;49:453&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18967618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamimori GH, Karyekar CS, Otterstetter R, et al. The rate of absorption and relative bioavailability of caffeine administrated in chewing gum versus capsules to normal healthy volunteers. Int J Pharm. 2002;234:159&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11839447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorina TA, Roberson DW. Efficay of acute caffeine ingestion for short-term high-intensity exercise performance: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19924012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collomp K, Ahmaid S, Audran M, et al. Effects of caffeine ingestion on performance and anaerobic metabolism during the Wingate test. Int J Sports Med. 1991;12:439&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1752708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer F, Morales J, Coles M. Wingate performance and surface EMG frequency variables are not affected by caffeine ingestion. Appl Physiol Nutri Metab. 2006;31:597&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17111014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Howatson G, Abraham CS, et al. Caffeine supplementation and multiple sprint running performance. Med Sci Sports Exer. 2008;40:1835&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles JD, Coleman D, Tegerdine M, et al. The effects of caffeine ingestion on performance time, speed, and power during a laboratory-based 1 km cycling time-trial. J Sports Sci. 2006;24:1165&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17035165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA. Effect of increased fat availability on metabolism and exercise capacity. Med Sci Sports Exercise. 2002:1485&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12218743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arner P, Kriegholm E, Engfeldt P, Bolinder J. Adrenergic regulation of lipolysis in situ at rest and during exercise. J Clin Invest. 1990;85:893&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC296507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2312732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet LL, MacLean DA, Dyck DJ, et al. Caffeine ingestion and muscle metabolism during prolonged exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1992;262:E891&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1616022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman A, Sutton JR. Endorphins: What are they? How are they measured? What is their role in exercise? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1985;17:74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2858810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demura S, Yamada T, Terasawa N. Effect of coffee ingestion on physiological responses and ratings of perceived exertion during submaximal endurance exercise. Percept Mot Skills. 2007;105:1109&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18380106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet LL. Caffeine and performance. Int J of Sport Nutr. 1995;5:S84&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7550260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm BB, Holmen J, Nehlig A, et al. Actions of caffeine in the brain with special reference to factors that contribute to its widespread use. Pharmacol Rev. 1999;51:83&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10049999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CL, Lin JC, Cheng CF. Effect of caffeine ingestion after creatine supplementation on intermittent high-intensity sprint performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011. p. xx. (In press).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21207054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>