<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36719416</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine Augments the Lactate and Interleukin-6 Response to Moderate-Intensity Exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>982</StartPage><EndPage>990</EndPage><MedlinePgn>982-990</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003121</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">The release of interleukin (IL)-6 from contracting skeletal muscle is thought to contribute to some of the health benefits bestowed by exercise. This IL-6 response seems proportional to exercise volume and to lactate production. Unfortunately, high volumes of exercise are not feasible for all people. Caffeine augments the magnitude of increase in circulating IL-6 in response to high-intensity and long-duration exercise. Caffeine also increases circulating concentrations of lactate during exercise. We hypothesized that caffeine, ingested before short-duration, moderate-intensity exercise, would lead to greater circulating concentrations of lactate and IL-6 in a study population comprising both male and female individuals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Twenty healthy adults (10 men and 10 women age 25 &#xb1; 7 yr (mean &#xb1; SD)) completed 30 min of moderate-intensity cycle ergometer exercise, at an intensity corresponding to 60% peak oxygen uptake, after ingesting either caffeine (6 mg&#xb7;kg -1 ) or placebo. Arterialized-venous blood was collected throughout each of the exercise sessions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with placebo, caffeine increased circulating concentrations of lactate at the end of exercise (5.12 &#xb1; 3.67 vs 6.45 &#xb1; 4.40 mmol&#xb7;L -1 , P &lt; 0.001) and after 30 min of inactive recovery (1.83 &#xb1; 1.59 vs 2.32 &#xb1; 2.09 mmol&#xb7;L -1 , P = 0.006). Circulating IL-6 concentrations were greatest after 30 min of inactive recovery ( P &lt; 0.001) and higher with caffeine (2.88 &#xb1; 2.05 vs 4.18 &#xb1; 2.97, pg&#xb7;mL -1 , P &lt; 0.001). Secondary analysis indicated sex differences; caffeine increased the IL-6 response to exercise in men ( P = 0.035) but not in women ( P = 0.358).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In response to moderate-intensity exercise, caffeine evoked greater circulating lactate concentrations in men and women but only increased the IL-6 response to exercise in men. These novel findings suggest that for men unwilling or unable to perform high-intensity and/or long-duration exercise, caffeine may augment the health benefits of relatively short, moderate-intensity exercise.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbotts</LastName><ForeName>Kieran Shay Struebin</ForeName><Initials>KSS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Exercise Science, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ewell</LastName><ForeName>Taylor Russell</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bomar</LastName><ForeName>Matthew Charles</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Butterklee</LastName><ForeName>Hannah Michelle</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bell</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015850">Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015850" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-6</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202306000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tauler P, Martinez S, Martinez P, Lozano L, Moreno C, Aguil&#xf3; A. Effects of caffeine supplementation on plasma and blood mononuclear cell interleukin-10 levels after exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2016;26(1):8&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tauler P, Mart&#xed;nez S, Moreno C, Monjo M, Mart&#xed;nez P, Aguil&#xf3; A. Effects of caffeine on the inflammatory response induced by a 15-km run competition. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2013;45(7):1269&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodas L, Martinez S, Aguilo A, Tauler P. Caffeine supplementation induces higher IL-6 and IL-10 plasma levels in response to a treadmill exercise test. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2020;17(1):47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira GA, Felippe LC, Bertuzzi R, et al. The effects of acute and chronic sprint-interval training on cytokine responses are independent of prior caffeine intake. Front Physiol . 2018;9:671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker GJ, Finlay O, Griffiths H, Sylvester J, Williams M, Bishop NC. Immunoendocrine response to cycling following ingestion of caffeine and carbohydrate. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2007;39(9):1554&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Panissa VLG, Monteiro PA, et al. Caffeine supplementation affects the immunometabolic response to concurrent training. J Exerc Rehabil . 2017;13(2):179&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salicio VMM, Fett CA, Salicio MA, et al. The effect of caffeine supplementation on trained individuals subjected to maximal treadmill test. Afr J Tradit Complement Altern Med . 2017;14(1):16&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daou HN. Exercise as an anti-inflammatory therapy for cancer cachexia: a focus on interleukin-6 regulation. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol . 2020;318(2):R296&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wedell-Neergaard AS, Lang Lehrskov L, Christensen RH, et al. Exercise-induced changes in visceral adipose tissue mass are regulated by IL-6 signaling: a randomized controlled trial. Cell Metab . 2019;29(4):844&#x2013;55.e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steensberg A, Fischer CP, Keller C, M&#xf8;ller K, Pedersen BK. IL-6 enhances plasma IL-1ra, IL-10, and cortisol in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab . 2003;285(2):e433&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starkie R, Ostrowski SR, Jauffred S, Febbraio M, Pedersen BK. Exercise and IL-6 infusion inhibit endotoxin-induced TNF-&#x3b1; production in humans. FASEB J . 2003;17(8):884&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano AL, Baeza-Raja B, Perdiguero E, Jard&#xed; M, Mu&#xf1;oz-C&#xe1;noves P. Interleukin-6 is an essential regulator of satellite cell-mediated skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell Metab . 2008;7(1):33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey AL, Steinberg GR, Macaulay SL, et al. Interleukin-6 increases insulin-stimulated glucose disposal in humans and glucose uptake and fatty acid oxidation in vitro via AMP-activated protein kinase. Diabetes . 2006;55(10):2688&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellingsgaard H, Hauselmann I, Schuler B, et al. Interleukin-6 enhances insulin secretion by increasing glucagon-like peptide-1 secretion from L cells and alpha cells. Nat Med . 2011;17(11):1481&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hojman P, Brolin C, N&#xf8;rgaard-Christensen N, et al. IL-6 release from muscles during exercise is stimulated by lactate-dependent protease activity. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab . 2019;316(5):E940&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen T, Thomas AW, Webb R, Hughes MG. Interleukin-6 and associated cytokine responses to an acute bout of high-intensity interval exercise: the effect of exercise intensity and volume. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2016;41(8):803&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minetto MA, Rainoldi A, Gazzoni M, Ganzit GP, Saba L, Paccotti P. Interleukin-6 response to isokinetic exercise in elite athletes: relationships to adrenocortical function and to mechanical and myoelectric fatigue. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2006;98(4):373&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Caffeine and exercise: metabolism, endurance and performance. Sports Med . 2001;31(11):785&#x2013;807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Gissane C. Caffeine and physiological responses to submaximal exercise: a meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2018;13(4):402&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgson AB, Randell RK, Jeukendrup AE. The metabolic and performance effects of caffeine compared to coffee during endurance exercise. PLoS One . 2013;8(4):e59561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suvi S, Timpmann S, Tamm M, Aedma M, Kreegipuu K, &#xd6;&#xf6;pik V. Effects of caffeine on endurance capacity and psychological state in young females and males exercising in the heat. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2016;42(1):68&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberlin-Brown KT, Siegel R, Kilding AE, Laursen PB. Oral presence of carbohydrate and caffeine in chewing gum: independent and combined effects on endurance cycling performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2016;11(2):164&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz RS, de Aguiar RA, Turnes T, Guglielmo LG, Beneke R, Caputo F. Caffeine affects time to exhaustion and substrate oxidation during cycling at maximal lactate steady state. Nutrients . 2015;7(7):5254&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaesser GA, Rich RG. Influence of caffeine on blood lactate response during incremental exercise. Int J Sports Med . 1985;6(4):207&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams NNB, Ewell TR, Abbotts KSS, et al. Comparison of five oral cannabidiol preparations in adult humans: pharmacokinetics, body composition, and heart rate variability. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) . 2021;14(1):35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewell TR, Abbotts KSS, Williams NNB, et al. Pharmacokinetic investigation of commercially available edible marijuana products in humans: potential influence of body composition and influence on glucose control. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) . 2021;14(8):817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewell TR, Harms KJ, Abbotts KSS, Bell C. Scheduling sprint interval training at a constant rather than variable time of day does not influence the gains in endurance performance. J Exerc Nutr . 2020;3(4):79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaver WL, Wasserman K, Whipp BJ. A new method for detecting anaerobic threshold by gas exchange. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1986;60(6):2020&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forster HV, Dempsey JA, Thomson J, Vidruk E, DoPico GA. Estimation of arterial PO 2 , PCO 2 , pH, and lactate from arterialized venous blood. J Appl Physiol . 1972;32(1):134&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Kavouras SA. Caffeine use in sports, pharmacokinetics in man, and cellular mechanisms of action. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr . 2005;45(7&#x2013;8):535&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Dalsky GP, Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports . 1978;10(3):155&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadheim HK, Kvamme B, Olsen R, Drevon CA, Ivy JL, Jensen J. Caffeine increases performance in cross-country double-poling time trial exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2013;45(11):2175&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadheim HK, Spencer M, Olsen R, Jensen J. Caffeine and performance over consecutive days of simulated competition. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2014;46(9):1787&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles D, Maclaren D. Effects of caffeine and glucose ingestion on metabolic and respiratory functions during prolonged exercise. J Sports Sci . 1984;2(1):35&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo SE, Jentjens RL, Wallis GA, Jeukendrup AE. Caffeine increases exogenous carbohydrate oxidation during exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2005;99(3):844&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acker-Hewitt TL, Shafer BM, Saunders MJ, Goh Q, Luden ND. Independent and combined effects of carbohydrate and caffeine ingestion on aerobic cycling performance in the fed state. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2012;37(2):276&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casal DC, Leon AS. Failure of caffeine to affect substrate utilization during prolonged running. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1985;17(1):174&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins NT, Trilk JL, Singhal A, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Cureton KJ. Ergogenic effects of low doses of caffeine on cycling performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2008;18(3):328&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce CR, Anderson ME, Fraser SF, et al. Enhancement of 2000-m rowing performance after caffeine ingestion. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2000;32(11):1958&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara B, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Hell&#xed;n J, Garc&#xed;a-Bataller A, Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez P, Romero-Moraleda B, Del Coso J. Ergogenic effects of caffeine on peak aerobic cycling power during the menstrual cycle. Eur J Nutr . 2020;59(6):2525&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Moraleda B, Coso J Del, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Hell&#xed;n J, Lara B. The effect of caffeine on the velocity of half-squat exercise during the menstrual cycle: a randomized controlled trial. Nutrients 2019;11(11):2662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara B, Guti&#xe9;rrez Hell&#xed;n J, Ru&#xed;z-Moreno C, Romero-Moraleda B, Del Coso J. Acute caffeine intake increases performance in the 15-s Wingate test during the menstrual cycle. Br J Clin Pharmacol . 2020;86(4):745&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennigar SR, McClung JP, Pasiakos SM. Nutritional interventions and the IL-6 response to exercise. FASEB J . 2017;31(9):3719&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller C, Keller P, Marshal S, Pedersen BK. IL-6 gene expression in human adipose tissue in response to exercise&#x2014;effect of carbohydrate ingestion. J Physiol . 2003;550(Pt 3):927&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JW, Spriet LL. Skeletal muscle glycogen phosphorylase a kinetics: effects of adenine nucleotides and caffeine. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2001;91(5):2071&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colosio AL, Caen K, Bourgois JG, Boone J, Pogliaghi S. Bioenergetics of the VO 2 slow component between exercise intensity domains. Pflugers Arch . 2020;472(10):1447&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho A, Marticorena FM, Grecco BH, Barreto G, Saunders B. Can I have my coffee and drink it? A systematic review and meta-analysis to determine whether habitual caffeine consumption affects the ergogenic effect of caffeine. Sports Med . 2022;52(9):2209&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>