<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23626880</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-7802</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of preventive medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Prev Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep disorders as a cause of motor vehicle collisions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>246</StartPage><EndPage>257</EndPage><MedlinePgn>246-57</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Studies have shown that a large proportion of traffic accidents around the world are related to inadequate or disordered sleep. Recent surveys have linked driver fatigue to 16% to 20% of serious highway accidents in the UK, Australia, and Brazil. Fatigue as a result of sleep disorders (especially obstructive sleep apnea), excessive workload and lack of physical and mental rest, have been shown to be major contributing factors in motor vehicle accidents. A number of behavioral, physiological, and psychometric tests are being used increasingly to evaluate the impact of fatigue on driver performance. These include the oculography, polysomnography, actigraphy, the maintenance of wakefulness test, and others. Various strategies have been proposed for preventing or reducing the impact of fatigue on motor vehicle accidents. These have included: Educational programs emphasizing the importance of restorative sleep and the need for drivers to recognize the presence of fatigue symptoms, and to determine when to stop to sleep; The use of exercise to increase alertness and to promote restorative sleep; The use of substances or drugs to promote sleep or alertness (i.e. caffeine, modafinil, melatonin and others), as well as specific sleep disorders treatment; The use of CPAP therapy for reducing excessive sleepiness among drivers who have been diagnosed with obstructive sleep apnea. The evidence cited in this review justifies the call for all efforts to be undertaken that may increase awareness of inadequate sleep as a cause of traffic accidents. It is strongly recommended that, for the purpose of promoting highway safety and saving lives, all disorders that cause excessive sleepiness should be investigated and monitored.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Mello</LastName><ForeName>Marco T&#xfa;lio</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Psicobiologia, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo/SP, Brazil ; Centro de Estudos em Psicobiologia e Exerc&#xed;cio, S&#xe3;o Paulo/SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narciso</LastName><ForeName>Fernanda Veruska</ForeName><Initials>FV</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tufik</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paiva</LastName><ForeName>Teresa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spence</LastName><ForeName>David Warren</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bahammam</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verster</LastName><ForeName>Joris C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandi-Perumal</LastName><ForeName>Seithikurippu R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Prev Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535380</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-7802</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alertness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rest</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">traffic accident</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest:</b> S. R. Pandi-Perumal is a stockholder and the President and Chief Executive Officer of Somnogen Canada Inc., a Canadian Corporation. He declared no competing interests that might be perceived to influence the content of this article. All remaining authors declare that they have no proprietary, financial, professional, nor any other personal interest of any kind in any product or services and/or company that could be construed or considered to be a potential conflict of interest that might have influenced the views expressed in this manuscript</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23626880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3634162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Spiegel K, Leproult R, Van Cauter E. Impact of sleep debt on metabolic and endocrine function. Lancet. 1999;354:1435&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10543671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullington JM, Chan JL, Van Dongen HP, Szuba MP, Samaras J, Price NJ, et al. Sleep loss reduces diurnal rhythm amplitude of leptin in healthy men. J Neuroendocrinol. 2003;15:851&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12899679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldabal L, Bahammam AS. Metabolic, endocrine, and immune consequences of sleep deprivation. Open Respir Med J. 2011;5:31&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3132857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21754974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayas NT, White DP, Al-Delaimy WK, Manson JE, Stampfer MJ, Speizer FE, et al. A prospective study of self-reported sleep duration and incident diabetes in women. Diabetes Care. 2003;26:380&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12547866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel K, Knutson K, Leproult R, Tasali E, Van Cauter E. Sleep loss: A novel risk factor for insulin resistance and Type 2 diabetes. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99:2008&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16227462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayas NT, White DP, Manson JE, Stampfer MJ, Speizer FE, Malhotra A, et al. A prospective study of sleep duration and coronary heart disease in women. Arch Intern Med. 2003;163:205&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12546611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kripke DF, Garfinkel L, Wingard DL, Klauber MR, Marler MR. Mortality associated with sleep duration and insomnia. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2002;59:131&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11825133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Tanaka H Fukuoka Heart Study Group. Overtime work, insufficient sleep and risk of non-fatal acute myocardial infarction in Japanese men. Occup Environ Med. 2002;59:447&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1740308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12107292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard ME, Desai AV, Grunstein RR, Hukins C, Armstrong JG, Joffe D, et al. Sleepiness, sleep-disordered breathing, and accident risk factors in commercial vehicle drivers. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2004;170:1014&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15317672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandi-Perumal SR, Verster JC, Kayumov L, Lowe AD, Santana MG, Pires ML, et al. Sleep disorders, sleepiness and traffic safety: A public health menace. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2006;39:863&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip P. Sleepiness of Occupational Driver. Ind Health. 2005;43:30&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15732301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crummy F, Cameron PA, Swann P, Kossmann T, Naughton MT. Prevalence of sleepiness in surviving drivers of motor vehicle collisions. Intern Med J. 2008;38:769&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18492056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip P, Sagaspe P, Moore N, Taillard J, Charles A, Guilleminault C, et al. Fatigue, sleep restriction and driving performance. Accid Anal Prev. 2005;37:473&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15784201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabi H, Gu&#xe9;guen A, Chiron M, Lafont S, Zins M, Lagarde E. Awareness of driving while sleepy and road traffic accidents: Prospective study in GAZEL cohort. Research. BMJ. 2006;333:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16798754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanlaar W, Simpson H, Mayhew D, Robertson R. Fatigued and drowsy driving: A survey of attitudes, opinions and behaviors. J Safety Res. 2008;39:303&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18571572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tregear S, Reston J, Schoelles K, Phillips B. Obstructive sleep apnea and risk of motor vehicle crash: Systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Sleep Med. 2009;5:573&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2792976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20465027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vakulin A, Baulk SD, Catcheside PG, Antic NA, van den Heuvel CJ, Dorrian J, et al. Effects of alcohol and sleep restriction on simulated driving performance in untreated patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151:447&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodenstein D. Sleep apnea: Traffic and occupational accidents--individual risks, socioeconomic and legal implications. Respiration. 2009;78:241&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19494476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip P, Sagaspe P, Lagarde E, Leger D, Ohayon MM, Bioulac B, et al. Sleep disorders and accidental risk in a large group of regular registered highway drivers. Sleep Med. 2010;11:973&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne JA, Reyner LA. Driver sleepiness. J Sleep Res. 1995;4:23&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10607207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driver fatigue and road accidents: A literature review and position paper. ROSPA. 2001. Feb,  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.rospa.com/roadsafety/info/fatigue.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO), 2010.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Global Plan for the Decade of Action for Road Safety 2011-2020, WHO, Geneva.  Available from:
http://www.roadsafetyfund.org/UnDecadeOfAction/Documents/global_plan_en.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO), 2009.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Global status report on road safety time for action, WHO, Geneva.  Available from:
http://www.whqlibdoc.who.int/publications/2009/9789241563840_eng.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundesanstalt f&#xfc;r StraBenwesen-BASt: Federal Highway Research Institute.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.bast.de/nn_76784/EN/e-Statistik/e-Unfalldaten-Downloads/e-getoetete-gesamt-ortslage,templateId=raw,property=publicationFile.pdf/e-getoetete-gesamt-ortslage.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dead and injured in road traffic accidents by province. Country's total. Years: 2004-8. National Institute of Statistics and Census-INDEC.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.indec.gov.ar/nuevaweb/cuadros/8/ c030603.xls .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sehat M, Naieni KH, Asadi-Lari M, Foroushani AR, Malek-Afzali H. Socioeconomic status and incidence of traffic accidents in metropolitan tehran: A populationbased study. Int J Prev Med. 2012;3:181&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3309632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22448311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistical Yearbook of the Federal Highway 2009: Traffic Accidents and Actions to Combat Crime. National Department of Transport Infrastructure /The Brazilian Federal Highway Police. 2009.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.dnit.gov.br/rodovias/operacoes-rodoviarias/estatisticas-de-acidentes/anuario-2009.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smolensky MH, Di Milia L, Ohayon MM, Philip P. Sleep disorders, medical conditions, and road accident risk. Accid Anal Prev. 2011;43:533&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21130215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verster JC, Taillard J, Sagaspe P, Olivier B, Philip P. Prolonged nocturnal driving can be as dangerous as severe alcohol-impaired driving. J Sleep Res. 2011;20:585&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21226780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonderis A, Barbe F, Bonsignore M, Calverley P, De Backer W, Diefenbach K, et al. Medico-legal implications of sleep apnoea syndrome: Driving license regulations in Europe. Sleep Med. 2008;9:362&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17765641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mello MT, Bittencourt LR, Cunha Rde C, Esteves AM, Tufik S. Sleep and transit in Brazil: New legislation. J Clin Sleep Med. 2009;5:164&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2670337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19968051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An Analysis of the Significant Decline in Motor Vehicle Traffic Fatalities in 2008. NHTSA. 2010.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www-nrd.nhtsa.dot.gov/Pubs/811346.pdf .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21943573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Road safety Information: Driver fatigue and road accidents. ROSPA. 2011.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.rospa.com/roadsafety/info/driver_fatigue_2011.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heavy vehicle driver fatigue final regulatory impact statement. National Transport Comission-NTC Australia.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.ntc.gov.au/filemedia/Reports/3HVDFHVDFRISFeb2007.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Road crash facts for South Australia. Government of South Australia/Department for transport, energy and Infrastructure.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.transport.sa.gov.au/pdfs/safety/road_crash/Crash_Facts.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tefft B. AAA Foundation for Traffic Safety. Washington, D.C: 2010. Asleep at the Wheel: The Prevalence and Impact of Drowsy Driving.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics Operations.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];The Brazilian Federal Highway Police.  Available from:
http:// www.dprf.gov.br/PortalInternet/estatistica.faces .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza JC, Paiva T, Reimao R. Sleep habits, sleepiness and accidents among truck drivers. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2005;63:925&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16400406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva-Junior FP, de Pinho RS, de Mello MT, de Bruin VM, de Bruin PF. Risk factors for depression in truck drivers. Soc Psychiat Psychiat Epidem. 2009;44:125&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18642121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson D, Reid K. Fatigue, alcohol and performance impairment. Nature. 1997;388:235&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9230429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson AM, Feyer AM. Moderate sleep deprivation produces impairments in cognitive and motor performance equivalent to legally prescribed levels of alcohol intoxication. Occup Environ Med. 2000;57:649&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10984335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagaspe P, Taillard J, Bayon V, Lagarde E, Moore N, Boussuge J, et al. Sleepiness, near-misses and driving accidents among a representative population of French drivers. J Sleep Res. 2010;19:578&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20408921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komada Y, Nishida Y, Namba K, Abe T, Tsuiki S, Inoue Y. Elevated risk of motor vehicle accident for male drivers with obstructive sleep apnea syndrome in the Tokyo metropolitan area. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2009;219:11&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19713679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amra B, Dorali R, Mortazavi S, Golshan M, Farajzadegan Z, Fietze I, et al. Sleep apnea symptoms and accident risk factors in Persian commercial vehicle drivers. Sleep Breath. 2012:187&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21210229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George CF. Sleep apnea, alertness, and motor vehicle crashes. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2007;176:954&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiomi T, Arita AT, Sasanabe R, Banno K, Yamakawa H, Hasegawa R, et al. Falling asleep while driving and automobile accidents among patients with obstructive sleep apnea-hypopnea syndrome. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2002;56:333&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12047620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hack M. Obstructive sleep apnoea: Accidents waiting to happen.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Airways J. 2004 2:37&#x2013;8. Available from:
http://www.welshsas.org/documents/AJ_Mar_37-38.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prilipko O, Huynh N, Schwartz S, Tantrakul V, Kim JH, Peralta AR, et al. Task positive and default mode networks during a parametric working memory task in obstructive sleep apnea patients and healthy controls. Sleep. 2011;34:293&#x2013;301A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3041705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21358846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulgrew AT, Nasvadi G, Butt A, Cheema R, Fox N, Fleetham JA, et al. Risk and severity of motor vehicle crashes in patients with obstructive sleep apnoea/hypopnoea. Thorax. 2008;63:536&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18234904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vakulin A, Baulk SD, Catcheside PG, Antic NA, van den Heuvel CJ, Dorrian J, et al. Driving simulator performance remains impaired in patients with severe OSA after CPAP treatment. J Clin Sleep Med. 2011;7:246&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3113962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21677893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vennelle M, Engleman HM, Douglas NJ. Sleepiness and sleep-related accidents in commercial bus drivers. Sleep Breath. 2010;14:39&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tippin J, Sparks J, Rizzo M. Visual vigilance in drivers with obstructive sleep apnea. J Psychosom Res. 2009;67:143&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19616141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell NB, Schechtman KB, Riley RW, Guilleminault C, Chiang RP, Weaver EM. Sleepy driver near-misses may predict accident risks. Sleep. 2007;30:331&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17425230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donjacour CE, Mets AJ, Verster JC.  Driving and Traffic Safety. In: Goswami M, Pandi-Perumal SR, Thorpy MJ, editors. Narcolepsy: A Clinical guide. New York, USA: Springer Science; 2010.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-1-4419-0854-4_19 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Chada D, Videla AJ, O&#x2019;Flaherty ME, Palermo P, Meoni J, Sarchi MI, et al. Sleep habits and accident risk among truck drivers: A cross-sectional study in Argentina. Sleep. 2005;28:1103&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16268379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkanen H, Summala H. Sleepiness at Work Among Commercial Truck Drivers. Sleep. 2000;23:49&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10678465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Pinho RS, da Silva-Junior FP, Bastos JP, Maia WS, de Mello MT, de Bruin VM, et al. Hypersomnolence and accidents in truck drivers: A cross-sectional study. Chronobiol Int. 2006;23:963&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17050211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mello MT, Esteves AM, Pires ML, Santos DC, Bittencourt LR, Silva RS, et al. Relationship between Brazilian airline pilot errors and time of day. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2008;41:1129&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19148377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar M, Valenca J, Felizardo M, Caeiro F, Moreira S, Staats R, et al. Obstructive sleep apnoea syndrome as a cause of road traffic accidents. Rev Port Pneumol. 2009;15:419&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19401792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger J. Sleep apnoea and driving: How can this be dealt with? Eur Respir Rev. 2007;16:189&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Brazilian Health Surveillance Secretariat/Ministry of Health of Brazil.  [Last accessed on 2008].  Available from:
http://www.datasus.gov.br .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leger D, Massuel MA, Metlaine A SISYPHE Study Group. Professional correlates of insomnia. Sleep. 2006;29:171&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16494084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daley M, Morin CM, LeBlanc M, Gregoire JP, Savard J, Baillargeon L. Insomnia and its relationship to health-care utilization, work absenteeism, productivity and accidents. Sleep Med. 2009;10:427&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18753000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson A, Lombardi DA, Folkard S, Stutts J, Courtney TK, Connor JL. The link between fatigue and safety. Accid Anal Prev. 2011;43:498&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21130213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verster JC, Roth T. The prevalence and nature of stopped on-the-road driving tests and the relationship with objective performance impairment. Accid Anal Prev. 2012;45:498&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22269535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verster JC, Roth T. Standard operation procedures for conducting the on-the-road driving test, and measurement of the standard deviation of lateral position (SDLP) Int J Gen Med. 2011;4:359&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21625472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mets MA, Ketzer S, Blom C, van Gerven MH, van Willigenburg GM, Olivier B, et al. Positive effects of Red Bull (R) Energy Drink on driving performance during prolonged driving. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2011;214:737&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3053448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21063868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mets M, Baas D, van Boven I, Olivier B, Verster J. Effects of coffee on driving performance during prolonged simulated highway driving. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2012;222:337&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3382640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22315048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verster JC, Veldhuijzen DS, Volkerts ER. Residual effects of sleep medication on driving ability. Sleep Med Rev. 2004;8:309&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15233958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verster JC, Veldhuijzen DS, Patat A, Olivier B, Volkerts ER. Hypnotics and driving safety: Meta-analyses of randomized controlled trials applying the on-the-road driving test. Curr Drug Saf. 2006;1:63&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18690916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verster JC, Spence DW, Shahid A, Pandi-Perumal SR, Roth T. Zopiclone as positive control in studies examining the residual effects of hypnotic drugs on driving ability. Curr Drug Saf. 2011;6:209&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22129315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mets MA, de Vries JM, de Senerpont Domis LM, Volkerts ER, Olivier B, Verster JC. Next-day effects of ramelteon (8 mg), zopiclone (7.5 mg), and placebo on highway driving performance, memory functioning, psychomotor performance, and mood in healthy adult subjects. Sleep. 2011;34:1327&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3173578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21966064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbone F, McMahon AD, Davey PG, Morris AD, Reid IC, McDevitt DG, et al. Association of road-traffic accidents with benzodiazepine use. Lancet. 1998;352:1331&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9802269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns M, Tucker A, Chapman R, Crowley K, Michael N. Monitoring eye and eyelid movements by infrared reflectance oculography to measure drowsiness in drivers.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Somnologie. 2007 11:234&#x2013;42. The manuscript is Available from:
http://www.mwjohns.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/murray_papers/johns_et_al_2007_monitoring_eye_and_eyelid_movements_by_ir_reflectance_oculography_to_measure_drowsiness_in_drivers.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns M, Chapman R, Crowley K, Tucker A. A new method for assessing the risks of drowsiness while driving ;12:66-74.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Somnologie. 2008 12:66&#x2013;14. The manuscript is Available from:
http://www.mwjohns.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/murray_papers/johns_et_al_2008_a_new_method_for_assessing_the_risks_of_drowsiness_while_driving.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, 3rd, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The pittsburgh sleep quality index: A new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28:193&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carskadon MA, Dement WC, Mitler MM, Roth T, Westbrook PR, Keenan S. Guidelines for the multiple sleep latency test (MSLT): A standard measure of sleepiness. Sleep. 1986;9:519&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3809866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwyghuizen-Doorenbos A, Roehrs T, Schaefer M, Roth T. Test-retest reliability of the MSLT. Sleep. 1988;11:562&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3238258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathis J, Hess CW. Sleepiness and vigilance tests. Swiss Med Wkly. 2009;139:214&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19418304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett LS, Stradling JR, Davies RJ. A behavioural test to assess daytime sleepiness in obstructive sleep apnoea. J Sleep Res. 1997;6:142&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9377534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitler MM, Gujavarty KS, Browman CP. Maintenance of wakefulness test: A polysomnographic technique for evaluation treatment efficacy in patients with excessive somnolence. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1982;53:658&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2480525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6177511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilhelm B, Giedke H, Ludtke H, Bittner E, Hofmann A, Wilhelm H. Daytime variations in central nervous system activation measured by a pupillographic sleepiness test. J Sleep Res. 2001;10:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11285049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balkin TJ, Bliese PD, Belenky G, Sing H, Thorne DR, Thomas M, et al. Comparative utility of instruments for monitoring sleepiness-related performance decrements in the operational environment. J Sleep Res. 2004;13:219&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15339257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sack RL, Auckley D, Auger RR, Carskadon MA, Wright KP, Jr, Vitiello MV, et al. Circadian rhythm sleep disorders: Part I, basic principles, shift work and jet lag disorders. An American academy of sleep medicine review. Sleep. 2007;30:1460&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2082105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18041480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iber C, Ancoli-Israel S, Chesson A, Jr, Quan S, Thomas M. The AASM manual for the scoring of sleep and associated events: Rules, terminology and technical specifications. Westchester: American Academy of Sleep Medicine; 2007. pp. 2&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgenthaler TI, Lee-Chiong T, Alessi C, Friedman L, Aurora RN, Boehlecke B, et al. Practice parameters for the clinical evaluation and treatment of circadian rhythm sleep disorders. An American academy of sleep medicine. Report Standards Of Practice Committee Of The AASM. Sleep. 2007;30:1445&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2082098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18041479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sack RL, Auckley D, Auger RR, Carskadon MA, Wright KP, Jr, Vitiello MV, et al. Circadian rhythm sleep disorders: Part II, advanced sleep phase disorder, delayed sleep phase disorder, free-running disorder, and irregular sleep-wake rhythm. An American Academy of Sleep Medicine review. Sleep. 2007;30:1484&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2082099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18041481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassani A, Findley LJ, Kryger M, Goldlust E, George C, Davidson TM. Reducing motor-vehicle collisions, costs, and fatalities by treating obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Sleep. 2004;27:453&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15164898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartenbaum N, Collop N, Rosen IM, Phillips B, George CF, Rowley JA, et al. Sleep apnea and commercial motor vehicle operators: Statement from the joint task force of the American college of chest physicians, the American college of occupational and environmental medicine, and the national sleep foundation. Chest. 2006;130:902&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16963693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodenstein D Cost-B26 Action on Sleep Apnoea Syndrome. Driving in Europe: The need of a common policy for drivers with obstructive sleep apnoea syndrome. J Sleep Res. 2008;17:281&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18651866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepanski EJ, Wyatt JK. Use of sleep hygiene in the treatment of insomnia. Sleep Med Rev. 2003;7:215&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12927121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufik S. I Consenso Brasileiro de Ins&#xf4;nia 2003;3-45.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Hypnos. 2003 :3&#x2013;45. Available from:
http://www.ic.unicamp.br/~wainer/cursos/2s2008/ia/pdf_consenso.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crispim CA, Zalcman I, Dattilo M, Padilha HG, Edwards B, Waterhouse J, et al. The influence of sleep and sleep loss upon food intake and metabolism. Nutr Res Rev. 2007;20:195&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19079870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crispim C, Zalcman I, Dattilo M, Padilha H, Tufik S, Mello M. Shift work and nutritional aspects.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Nutrire. 2009 34:213&#x2013;27. Available from:
http://www.files.bvs.br/upload/S/1519-8928/2009/v34n2/a213-227.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youngstedt SD. Effects of exercise on sleep. Clin Sports Med. 2005;24:355&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15892929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antunes H, Andersen M, Tufik S, Mello M. Priva&#xe7;&#xe3;o de Sono e Exerc&#xed;cio F&#xed;sico.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06];Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2008 14:51&#x2013;6. Available from:
http://www.scielo.br/pdf/rbme/v14n1/a10v14n1.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi M. The role of prescribed napping in sleep medicine. Sleep Med Rev. 2003;7:227&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12927122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagaspe P, Taillard J, Chaumet G, Moore N, Bioulac B, Philip P. Aging and nocturnal driving: Better with coffee or a nap. A randomized study? Sleep. 2007;30:1808&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2276135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooley JJ. Treatment of circadian rhythm sleep disorders with light. Ann Acad Med. 2008;37:669&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18797560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purnell MT, Feyer AM, Herbison GP. The impact of a nap opportunity during the night shift on the performance and alertness of 12-h shift workers. J Sleep Res. 2002;11:219&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12220318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahl O, Wispel C, Willigens B, Pietrowsky R. An ultra short episode of sleep is sufficient to promote declarative memory performance. J Sleep Res. 2008;17:3&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18275549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyner LA, Horne JA. Early morning driver sleepiness: Effectiveness of 200 mg caffeine. Psychophysiology. 2000;37:251&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaoka S, Abe T, Komada Y, Inoue Y. The factors associated with preferences for napping and drinking coffee as countermeasures for sleepiness at the wheel among Japanese drivers. Sleep Med. 2012;13:354&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22305608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Sleep Foundation (NSF) Sleep Studies.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.sleepfoundation.org/article/sleep-topics/sleep-studies .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NSF. Fatigue and Excessive Sleepiness.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.sleepfoundation.org/article/sleep-related-problems/excessive-sleepiness-and-sleep .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NSF. Sleep Drive and Your Body Clock.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.sleepfoundation.org/article/sleep-topics/sleep-drive-and-your-body-clock .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NSF. Let Sleep Work for You.  [Last accessed on 2012 Feb 06].  Available from:
http://www.sleepfoundation.org/article/hot-topics/let-sleep-work-you .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rial RV, Nicolau MC, Gamundi A, Akaarir M, Aparicio S, Garau C, et al. The trivial function of sleep. Sleep Med Rev. 2007;11:311&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17481932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies KA, Macfarlane GJ, Nicholl BI, Dickens C, Morriss R, Ray D, et al. Restorative sleep predicts the resolution of chronic widespread pain: Results from the EPIFUND study. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2008;47:1809&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2582170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18842606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels C. Sleep, recovery, and performance: The new frontier in high-performance athletics. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2009;20:149&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19084768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oluwole OS. Sleep habits in Nigerian undergraduates. Acta Neurol Scand. 2010;121:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19951272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Komada Y, Nishida Y, Hayashida K, Inoue Y. Short sleep duration and long spells of driving are associated with the occurrence of Japanese drivers&#x2019; rear-end collisions and single-car accidents. J Sleep Res. 2010;19:310&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmdahl C, Schollin IL, Alton M, Nilsson K. CPAP treatment in obstructive sleep apnoea: A randomised, controlled trial of follow-up with a focus on patient satisfaction. Sleep Med. 2009;10:869&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19179111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDaid C, Griffin S, Weatherly H, Dur&#xe9;e K, van der Burgt M, van Hout S, et al. Continuous positive airway pressure devices for the treatment of obstructive sleep apnoea&#x2013;hypopnoea syndrome: A systematic review and economic analysis. Health Technol Assess. 2009;13:1&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19103134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto H, Akashiba T, Kosaka N, Ito D, Horie T. Long-term effects nasal continuous positive airway pressure on daytime sleepiness, mood and traffic accidents in patients with obstructive sleep apnoea. Respir Med. 2000;94:87&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10714485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barb&#xe9; F, Sunyer J, De La Pe&#xf1;a A, Pericas J, Mayoralas LR, Ant&#xf3; JM, et al. Effect of Continuous Positive Airway Pressure on the Risk of Road Accidents in Sleep Apnea Patients. Respiration. 2007;74:44&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16804289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>