<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39850296</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2277-9531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of education and health promotion</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Educ Health Promot</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence of urinary incontinence and its associated predictor and Self-care behavior among the elderly females in Chaiyaphum Province, Thailand: Cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>468</StartPage><MedlinePgn>468</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">468</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jehp.jehp_2065_23</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Urinary incontinence (UI) has been overlooked by elderly females because it is considered an embarrassment and physical dysfunction that occurs naturally in older women. However, UI is problematic if symptoms are ignored, and the condition becomes chronic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This cross-sectional descriptive research was conducted in a community context using semi-structured interviews as data collection methods. The interviews involved 1475 elderly females who live in Muang district, Chaiyaphum province and were analyzed by Chi-square, Pearson Product Moment Correlation Coefficient, Stepwise multiple regression, Bivariate and Multivariate at 0.05 statistical significance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study found a 30.37% prevalence of UI. Nine factors are related to the cause: Pelvic muscle exercise, water intake, caffeine and alcohol intake, diabetes, environmental obstacles, activities, constipation, urination frequency, and exercise. Elderly females who had their highest education at primary school to high school also had the possibility to experience 64% and a diploma had the possibility to experience 68% less UI than illiterate ones. The elderly females who had more than 23 kilograms per square meter (kg/m<sup>2</sup>) for body mass index (BMI) tend to have 2.64 times more than those who had 18.5-22.9 kg/m<sup>2</sup> at 0.05 statistical significance. UI self-care behavior on overall prediction was moderate, whereas behavioral change and self-care performance were high.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nine factors are related to this cause. The possibility is also related to educational level and BMI. The overall UI self-care behavior showed a moderate level of prediction, but a high level of behavioral change and self-care performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2024 Journal of Education and Health Promotion.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chompoowisate</LastName><ForeName>Patchareepon</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Mahasarakham University, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glangkarn</LastName><ForeName>Sumattana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Mahasarakham University, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Namyota</LastName><ForeName>Chaloemporn</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Mahasarakham University, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Educ Health Promot</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101593794</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2277-9531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-care behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urinary incontinence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39850296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11756654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_2065_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JEHP-13-468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  Integrated care for older people (ICOPE) Guidelines on community-level interventions to manage declines in intrinsic capacity Evidence profile: urinary incontinence: World Health Organization 2017.  Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29608259/ . [Last accessed on 2024 March 27]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29608259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saboia DM, Firmiano MLV, Bezerra KC, Vasconcelos NJA, Oria MOB. and Vasconcelos CTM. Impact of urinary incontinence types on women&#x2019;s quality of life. Journal of School of Nursing University of Sao Paulo. 2017;51:e03266. Doi: 10.1590/S1980220X2016032603266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29267732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KJ, Shin J, Choi J, Park JM, Park HK, Lee J, et al. Association of geriatric syndromes with urinary incontinence according to sex and urinary-incontinence-related quality of life in older inpatients: a cross-sectional study of an acute care hospital. Korean J Fam Med. 2019;40:235&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6669396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30400699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley JE, Adams EV. Rapid geriatric assessment. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2015;16:808&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26433860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshkoor SA, Hamid TA, Shahar S, Mun CY. Factors related to urinary incontinence among the malaysian elderly. J Nutr Health Aging. 2017;21:220&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28112780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Condon M, Mannion E, Molloy DW, O&#x2019;Caoimh R. Urinary and faecal incontinence: point prevalence and predictors in a university hospital. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16:194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6352131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30641927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuo DU, Zhao JP, Shi-hao DU, Wei GUO, Xiao-long X, Guan-qun W. et al. Systematic review and meta-analysis of moxibustion on urinary incontinence among women. WJAM. 2023;33:314&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler M, Facchini LA, Soares MU, Nunes BP, Franca SM, Thume E. Prevalence of urinary incontinence among the elderly and relationship with physical and mental health indicators. Rev bras geriatr Gerontol. 2019;21:397&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo LS, Ercole FF, Oliveira DU, Pinto TS, Victoriano MA, Alcoforado CLGC. Urinary tract infection: A cohort of older people with urinary incontinence. Rev Bras Enferm. 2017;70:838&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28793116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohn K, Lee CK, Shin J, Lee J. Association between female urinary incontinence and geriatric health problems: Results from korean longitudinal study of ageing (2006) Korean J Fam Med. 2018;39:10&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5788839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29383206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murukesu RR, Singh DKA, Shahar S. Prevalence of urinary incontinence and its association with declined cognitive and physical function among community dwelling older adults: A review. Malaysian Journal of Public Health Medicine. 2019;19:31&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Zhao L, Cui L, Wang Z, Wang D, Liu P, et al. A critical overview of systematic reviews and meta-analyses of acupuncture for female stress urinary incontinence. Pain Res Manag. 2022:5887862. doi: 10.1155 / 2022/5887862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9129990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35619992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padungkul L, Mantangkul S. Urinary incontinence management and perceptive quality of life of female clients at the gynecological clinic. Songklanagarind Journal of Nursing. 2017;37:75&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poursadeqiyan M, Arefi MF, Pouya AB, Jafari M. Quality of life in health Iranian elderly population approach in health promotion: A systematic review. J Educ Health Promot. 2021;10:449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35233396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter RM, Palanisamy K, Kumar D, Joseph A. Prevalence of activity limitation and its associated predictor among the elderly in Tamil Nadu, India: A community-based cross-sectional study. J Educ Health Promot. 2023;12:202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10402771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37545989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Wang S, Gao L, Jia Y, Wang H, Sun X, et al. Analysis of characteristics and quality of life of elderly women with mild to moderate urinary incontinence in community dwellings. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:5609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9105851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35565009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaisri S, Sarit-apirak S, Udomsubpayakul U, Monomai J. Proficiency and health-related behaviors regarding pelvic organ prolapse and urinary incontinence among personal in a private hospital. Rama Med J. 2017;40:11&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultan AH, Monga A, Lee J, Emmanuel A, Norton C, Santoro G, et al. An International Urogynecological Association (IUGA)/International Continence Society (ICS) joint report on the terminology for female anorectal dysfunction. Neurourol Urodyn. 2017;36:10&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27770550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orem D. 5th. Mosby; 1995. Nursing: Concepts of practice.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel WW, Cross CL. 10th. Wiley; 2017. Biostatistics: basic concepts and methodology for the health sciences.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radzimi&#x144;ska A, Str&#x105;czy&#x144;ska A, Weber-Rajek M, Styczy&#x144;ska H, Strojek K, Piekorz Z. The impact of pelvic floor muscle training on the quality of life of women with urinary incontinence: A systematic literature review. Clin Interv Aging. 2018;13:957&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5962309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29844662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Lacomba M, Navarro-Braz&#xe1;lez B, Yuste-S&#xe1;nchez MJ, S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez B, Prieto-G&#xf3;mez V, Vergara-P&#xe9;rez F. Women&#x2019;s Experiences with compliance with pelvic floor home exercise therapy and lifestyle changes for pelvic organ prolapse symptoms: a qualitative study. J Pers Med. 2022;12:498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8950721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35330497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>