<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29795732</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute Specific Effects of Caffeine-containing Energy Drink on Different Physical Performances in Resistance-trained Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>260</StartPage><EndPage>268</EndPage><MedlinePgn>260-268</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Caffeine containing energy drink (ED) is frequently used as ergogenic aid, but its effect on performance need more investigation. Thus, the aim of this study was to analyze the effects of acute ingestion of an ED on the physical performance of resistance-trained men subjected to successive tests in the same experimental protocol. Fifteen resistance-trained males (21.0 &#xb1; 0.3 yrs; 177.4 &#xb1; 1.8 cm; 79.6 &#xb1; 1.8 kg) ingested 2.5 mg caffeine per kg of body weight (619.5 &#xb1; 14.6 mL of ED) or a placebo in a double-blind randomized cross-over design. Physical performance was randomized for the maximum repetition tests (80% 1RM) in the bench press exercise and unilateral knee extension (dominant leg), maximal isometric hand-grip test in both hands, standing long jump and repeated sprint ability test. The paired Student-t test showed that ED intake increased performance compared to the placebo for the number of repetitions in the unilateral knee extension test of the dominant leg (11.5 &#xb1; 0.9 reps vs 9.5 &#xb1; 0.8 reps; P = 0.001) and bench press (10.2 &#xb1; 0.4 reps vs 8.1 &#xb1; 0.5 reps; P = 0.01); and also increased isometric strength in the hand-grip maximal test in the right (53.7 &#xb1; 1.5 kg vs. 47.7 &#xb1; 1.6 kg; P = 0.02) and left hand (52.9 &#xb1; 1.5 kg vs. 45.9 &#xb1; 1.3 kg; P = 0.02). In conclusion, acute ingestion of ED increased performance only in specific strength tests in resistance-trained men.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Astley</LastName><ForeName>Camilla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>D Physical Education Department, Londrina State University, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souza</LastName><ForeName>Diego B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>D Physical Education Department, Londrina State University, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polito</LastName><ForeName>Marcos D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>D Physical Education Department, Londrina State University, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance-enhancing substances</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">taurine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5955291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/KQVQ5193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahrendt M. Ergogenic aids: Counseling the athlete. Am Fam Physiciam. 2001;63:913&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11261867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alford C, Cox H, Wescott R. The effects of Red Bull energy drink on human performance and mood. Amino Acids. 2001;21:139&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An S, Park J, Kim S. Effect of energy drink dose on exercise capacity, heart rate recovery and heart rate variability after high-intensity exercise. J Exerc Nutr Biochem. 2014;18:31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25566437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrew W, Cribb P, Cooke M, Hayes A. The effect of ephedra and caffeine on maximal strenght and power in resistance-trained athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:464&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino T, Martin B, Schachtsiek L, Wong K, Ng K. Minimal effect of acute caffeine ingestion on intense resistance training performance. J Strength Con Res. 2011;26:1752&#x2013;1758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21293304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino T, Rohmann R, Firth K. Effect of caffeine ingestion on one-repetition maximum muscular strength. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102:127&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17851681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino T, Roupoli L, Valdivieso B. Caffeine does not alter RPE or pain perception during intense exercise in active women. Appetite. 2012;59:585&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22813436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens M, Mau-Moeller A, Weippert M, Fuhrmann J, Wegner K, Skripitz R, Bader R, Bruhn S. Caffeine-induced increase in voluntary activation and strength of the quadriceps muscle during isometric, concentric and eccentric contractions. Sci Rep. 2015;13:102&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4429543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis G. Effects of physical activity and inactivity on muscle fatigue. Front Physiol. 2012;18:142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3355468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22629249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow D, Kleisinger A, Grenier S, Dorsch K. Effect of sugar-free red bull energy drink on high-intensity run time-to-exhaustion in young adults. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:1271&#x2013;1275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr A, Dawson B, Schneiker K, Goodman C, Lay B. Effect of caffeine supplementation on repeated sprint running performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2008;48:472&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole KJ, Costill Dl. Effect of caffeine ingestion on perception of effort and subsequent work production. Int J Sport Nutr. 1996;6:14&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8653101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlay L, Conant J, DeBros F, Wurtman R. Caffeine alters plasma adenosine levels. Nature. 1997;389:136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9296490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis J, Zhao Z, Stock H, Mehl K, Buggy J, Hand G. Central nervous system effects of caffeine and adenosine on fatigue. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2002;284:399&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12399249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Mu&#xf1;oz-Fernandez V, Mu&#xf1;oz G, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Elias V, Ortega J, Hamouti N, Barbero J, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J. Effects of a caffeine-containing energy drink on simulated soccer performance. PLoS ONE. 2012;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3279366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22348079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Portillo J, Mu&#xf1;oz G, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J, Gonzalez-Millan C, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J. Caffeine-containing energy drink improves sprint performance during an international rugby sevens competitions. Amino Acids. 2013;44:1511&#x2013;1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23462927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan M, Hankey J. The effect of a caffeinated energy drink on various psychological measures during submaximal cycling. Physiol Behav. 2013;60&#x2013;65:116&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23542532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckerson J, Bull A, Baechle T, Fischer C, O&#x2019;brien D, Moore G, Yee J, Pulverenti T. Acute ingestion of sugar-free red bull energy drink has no effect on upper body strength and muscular endurance in resistance trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:2248&#x2013;2254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23880655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo M. Calcium-induced calcium release in skeletal muscle. Physiol Rev. 2009;89:1153&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19789379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes S, Candow D, Little J, Magnus C, Chilibeck P. Effect of Red Bull Energy Drink on repeated wingate cycle performance and bench-press muscle endurance. Int J Sports Nutr Exerc Metabol. 2007;17:433&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18046053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm B. Adenosine, adenosine receptors and the actions of caffeine. Pharmacol Toxicol. 1995;76:93&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7746802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganio M, Klau J, Lee E, Yeargin S, McDermott B, Buyckx M, Maresh C, Armstrong L. Effect of various carbohydrate-electrolyte fluids on cycling performance and maximal voluntary contraction. Int J of Sport Nutr Exerc Metabol. 2010;20:104&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Howatson G, Abraham C, Lockey R, Goodwin J, Foley P, McInnes G. Caffeine supplementation and multiple sprint running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1835&#x2013;1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein E, Ziegenfuss T, Kalman D, Kreider R, Campbell B, Wilborn C, Taylor L, Willoughby D, Stout J, Graves B, Wildman R, Ivy J, Spano M, Smith A, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition Position Stand: caffeine and performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez A, Walsh A, Ratamess N, Kang J, Hoffman J. Effect of a pre-workout energy supplement on acute multi-joint resistance exercise. J Sports Sci Med. 2011;10:261&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin C, Desbrow B, Ellis A, O&#x2019;Keeffe B, Grant G, Leveritt M. Caffeine withdrawal and high-intensity endurance cycling performance. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:509&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21279864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy J, Kammer L, Ding Z, Wang B, Bernard J, Liao Y, Hwang J. Improved cycling time-trial performance after ingestion of a caffeine energy drink. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metabol. 2009;19:61&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally K, Robertson R. Construct validity of the OMNI resistance exercise scale. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:252&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormack W, Hoffman J. Caffeine, energy drinks and strength-power performance. Strength Cond J. 2012;34:11&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehlig A, Daval JL, Debry G. Caffeine and the central nervous system: mechanisms of action, biochemical, metabolic and psychostimulant effects. Brain Res Rev. 1992;17:139&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1356551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olcina G, Munoz D, Kemp J, Timon R, Maynar J, Caballero M, Maynar M. Total plasma fatty acid responses to maximal incremental exercise after caffeine ingestion. J Exerc Sci Fitness. 2012;10:33&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillis J. Adenosine A2A receptor ligands: effects on neuronal excitability. Drug Develop. 2001;52:331&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza DB, Del Coso J, Casonatto J, Polito MD. Acute effects of caffeine-containing energy drinks on physical performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Nutr. 2017;56:13&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27757591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker M, Hargreaves J, Clarke J, Dale D, Blackwell G. The effect of caffeine on maximal oxygen uptake and vertical jump performance in male basketball players. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:382&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22561972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren G, Park N, Maresca R, Mckibans K, Millard-Stafford M. Effect of caffeine ingestion on muscular strength and endurance: A meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1375&#x2013;1387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>