<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34503527</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: sodium bicarbonate and exercise performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>61</StartPage><MedlinePgn>61</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">61</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12970-021-00458-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Based on a comprehensive review and critical analysis of the literature regarding the effects of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on exercise performance, conducted by experts in the field and selected members of the International Society of Sports Nutrition (ISSN), the following conclusions represent the official Position of the Society: 1. Supplementation with sodium bicarbonate (doses from 0.2 to 0.5 g/kg) improves performance in muscular endurance activities, various combat sports, including boxing, judo, karate, taekwondo, and wrestling, and in high-intensity cycling, running, swimming, and rowing. The ergogenic effects of sodium bicarbonate are mostly established for exercise tasks of high-intensity that last between 30 s and 12 min. 2. Sodium bicarbonate improves performance in single- and multiple-bout exercise. 3. Sodium bicarbonate improves exercise performance in both men and women. 4. For single-dose supplementation protocols, 0.2 g/kg of sodium bicarbonate seems to be the minimum dose required to experience improvements in exercise performance. The optimal dose of sodium bicarbonate dose for ergogenic effects seems to be 0.3 g/kg. Higher doses (e.g., 0.4 or 0.5 g/kg) may not be required in single-dose supplementation protocols, because they do not provide additional benefits (compared with 0.3 g/kg) and are associated with a higher incidence and severity of adverse side-effects. 5. For single-dose supplementation protocols, the recommended timing of sodium bicarbonate ingestion is between 60 and 180 min before exercise or competition. 6. Multiple-day protocols of sodium bicarbonate supplementation can be effective in improving exercise performance. The duration of these protocols is generally between 3 and 7 days before the exercise test, and a total sodium bicarbonate dose of 0.4 or 0.5 g/kg per day produces ergogenic effects. The total daily dose is commonly divided into smaller doses, ingested at multiple points throughout the day (e.g., 0.1 to 0.2 g/kg of sodium bicarbonate consumed at breakfast, lunch, and dinner). The benefit of multiple-day protocols is that they could help reduce the risk of sodium bicarbonate-induced side-effects on the day of competition. 7. Long-term use of sodium bicarbonate (e.g., before every exercise training session) may enhance training adaptations, such as increased time to fatigue and power output. 8. The most common side-effects of sodium bicarbonate supplementation are bloating, nausea, vomiting, and abdominal pain. The incidence and severity of side-effects vary between and within individuals, but it is generally low. Nonetheless, these side-effects following sodium bicarbonate supplementation may negatively impact exercise performance. Ingesting sodium bicarbonate (i) in smaller doses (e.g., 0.2 g/kg or 0.3 g/kg), (ii) around 180 min before exercise or adjusting the timing according to individual responses to side-effects, (iii) alongside a high-carbohydrate meal, and (iv) in enteric-coated capsules are possible strategies to minimize the likelihood and severity of these side-effects. 9. Combining sodium bicarbonate with creatine or beta-alanine may produce additive effects on exercise performance. It is unclear whether combining sodium bicarbonate with caffeine or nitrates produces additive benefits. 10. Sodium bicarbonate improves exercise performance primarily due to a range of its physiological effects. Still, a portion of the ergogenic effect of sodium bicarbonate seems to be placebo-driven.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grgic</LastName><ForeName>Jozo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2349-8078</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia. jozo.grgic@live.vu.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedisic</LastName><ForeName>Zeljko</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2886-3556</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saunders</LastName><ForeName>Bryan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0995-9077</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group, School of Physical Education and Sport; Rheumatology Division; Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de Sao Paulo, Sao Paulo, SP, BR, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Faculty of Medicine FMUSP, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Artioli</LastName><ForeName>Guilherme G</ForeName><Initials>GG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8463-2213</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Bioscience, Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester, M1 5GD, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4979-5783</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Lehman College, Bronx, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McKenna</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9998-0093</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6956-9188</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreider</LastName><ForeName>Richard B</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3906-1658</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sport Nutrition Lab, Human Clinical Research Facility, Department of Health &amp; Kinesiology, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stout</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6114-1649</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiology of Work and Exercise Response (POWER) Laboratory, Institute of Exercise Physiology and Rehabilitation Science, School of Kinesiology and Physical Therapy, University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalman</LastName><ForeName>Douglas S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0882-9748</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrion Department, College of Osteopathic Medicine, Nova Southeastern University, Fort Lauderdale, FL, 33314, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scientific Affairs. Nutrasource, Guelph, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arent</LastName><ForeName>Shawn M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0647-0591</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, Arnold School of Public Health, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>VanDusseldorp</LastName><ForeName>Trisha A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9057-2720</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Sport Management, Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopez</LastName><ForeName>Hector L</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0666-4222</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Applied Health Sciences, Stow, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Supplement Safety Solutions, Bedford, MA, 01730, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziegenfuss</LastName><ForeName>Tim N</ForeName><Initials>TN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5644-3263</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Applied Health Sciences, Stow, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burke</LastName><ForeName>Louise M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8866-5637</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Nutrition Research Program, Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antonio</LastName><ForeName>Jose</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8930-1058</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Sport Science, Nova Southeastern University, Davie, FL, 33314, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Bill I</ForeName><Initials>BI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4106-3871</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance &amp; Physique Enhancement Laboratory, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL, 33612, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8MDF5V39QO</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017693">Sodium Bicarbonate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017693" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sodium Bicarbonate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064132" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports Nutritional Sciences</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>J.G, Z.P, B.S, G.G.A, B.J.S, and M.J.M have no competing interests. R.B.K. has conducted industry sponsored studies at the universities he has been affiliated with and occasionally serves as a scientific and legal consultant related to exercise and nutrition intervention studies. J.R.S. has conducted industry-sponsored research on nutraceuticals over the past 25 years. Further, J.R.S. has also received financial support for presenting on the science of various nutraceuticals at industry-sponsored scientific conferences. D.S.K. declares that in part, he works for a contract research company that conducts research and human clinical trials for industries including dietary supplements, medical foods, beverages, foods, pharmaceuticals and medical devices. He also sits on the Scientific Advisory Board for Dymatize Nutrition (BellRing Brands). At the time this review was developed and published, Dymatize Nutrition was not producing any supplements containing sodium bicarbonate. S.M.A. has received grants to evaluate the effects of dietary supplements, and serves or has served on scientific advisory boards for sport nutrition companies. D.J.B. and T.A.V. have received research grants related to dietary supplements. H.L.L. has no conflict in terms of financial or business interests related to this manuscript. He has received grants to conduct research on dietary supplements; has served as a paid consultant for industry on Nutravigilance, post-market safety and regulatory compliance; receives royalties from the licensing of several patents in the dietary supplements industry (but not on sodium bicarbonate supplements). T.N.Z. has no conflict in terms of financial or business interests related to this manuscript. T.N.Z. has received grants and contracts to conduct research on dietary supplements; has served as a paid consultant for industry; has received honoraria for speaking at conferences and writing lay articles about sports nutrition ingredients; receives royalties from the sale of several sports nutrition products (but not on sodium bicarbonate supplements); and has served as an expert witness on behalf of the plaintiff and defense in cases involving dietary supplements. L.M.B. is a Director of the International Olympic Committee Diploma in Sports Nutrition. J.A. is the CEO of the ISSN. B.I.C. is on the scientific advisory board for Dymatize Nutrition (BellRing Brands), a manufacturer of sports supplements. At the time this review was developed and published, Dymatize Nutrition was not producing any supplements containing sodium bicarbonate</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34503527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8427947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00458-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12970-021-00458-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, Larson-Meyer DE, Peeling P, Phillips SM, Rawson ES, Walsh NP, Garthe I, Geyer H, Meeusen R, van Loon L, Shirreffs SM, Spriet LL, Stuart M, Vernec A, Currell K, Ali VM, Budgett RGM, Ljungqvist A, Mountjoy M, Pitsiladis Y, Soligard T, Erdener U, Engebretsen L. IOC consensus statement: dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28(2):104&#x2013;125. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2018-0020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2018-0020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29589768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afman G, Garside RM, Dinan N, Gant N, Betts JA, Williams C. Effect of carbohydrate or sodium bicarbonate ingestion on performance during a validated basketball simulation test. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2014;24(6):632&#x2013;644. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2013-0168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2013-0168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24901305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansdell P, Dekerle J. Sodium bicarbonate supplementation delays neuromuscular fatigue without changes in performance outcomes during a basketball match simulation protocol. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(5):1369&#x2013;1375. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29023327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli GG, Gualano B, Coelho DF, Benatti FB, Gailey AW, Lancha AH., Jr Does sodium-bicarbonate ingestion improve simulated judo performance? Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(2):206&#x2013;217. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.17.2.206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.17.2.206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschenbach W, Ocel J, Craft L, Ward C, Spangenburg E, Williams J. Effect of oral sodium loading on high-intensity arm ergometry in college wrestlers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(3):669&#x2013;675. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200003000-00018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200003000-00018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SR, Wiles J, Robbins J. The effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on 1500-m racing time. J Sports Sci. 1995;13(5):399&#x2013;403. doi: 10.1080/02640419508732255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640419508732255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8558626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D, Edge J, Davis C, Goodman C. Induced metabolic alkalosis affects muscle metabolism and repeated-sprint ability. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(5):807&#x2013;813. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000126392.20025.17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000126392.20025.17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15126714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D, Claudius B. Effects of induced metabolic alkalosis on prolonged intermittent-sprint performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(5):759&#x2013;767. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000161803.44656.3C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000161803.44656.3C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15870629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boegman S, Stellingwerff T, Shaw G, Clarke N, Graham K, Cross R, Siegler JC. The impact of individualizing sodium bicarbonate supplementation strategies on world-class rowing performance. Front Nutr. 2020;7:138. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2020.00138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2020.00138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouissou P, Defer G, Guezennec CY, Estrade PY, Serrurier B. Metabolic and blood catecholamine responses to exercise during alkalosis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20(3):228&#x2013;232. doi: 10.1249/00005768-198806000-00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-198806000-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3386500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brien DM, McKenzie DC. The effect of induced alkalosis and acidosis on plasma lactate and work output in elite oarsmen. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1989;58(8):797&#x2013;802. doi: 10.1007/BF02332209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02332209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2548862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisola GM, Miyagi WE, da Silva HS, Zagatto AM. Sodium bicarbonate supplementation improved MAOD but is not correlated with 200-and 400-m running performances: a double-blind, crossover, and placebo-controlled study. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2015;40(9):931&#x2013;937. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2015-0036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2015-0036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26300016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron SL, McLay-Cooke RT, Brown RC, Gray AR, Fairbairn KA. Increased blood pH but not performance with sodium bicarbonate supplementation in elite rugby union players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20(4):307&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.20.4.307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.20.4.307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos EZ, Sangali EB, Neto JG, Gobbi RB, Freitas Junior IF, Papoti M. Effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion during an intermittent exercise on blood lactate, stroke parameters, and performance of swimmers. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2012;15(6):84&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr AJ, Slater GJ, Gore CJ, Dawson B, Burke LM. Reliability and effect of sodium bicarbonate: buffering and 2000-m rowing performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2012;7(2):152&#x2013;160. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.7.2.152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.7.2.152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22634964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr BM, Webster MJ, Boyd JC, Hudson GM, Scheett TP. Sodium bicarbonate supplementation improves hypertrophy-type resistance exercise performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(3):743&#x2013;752. doi: 10.1007/s00421-012-2484-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-012-2484-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22941193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholewa JM, Grannis DJ, Jaffe DA, Guimar&#xe3;es-Ferreira L, Matthews TD, Paolone VJ. The effects of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on a soccer specific conditioning test in division III soccer players. J Trainol. 2015;4:19&#x2013;24. doi: 10.17338/trainology.4.1_19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17338/trainology.4.1_19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coombes J, McNaughton LR. Effects of bicarbonate ingestion on leg strength and power during isokinetic knee flexion and extension. J Strength Cond Res. 1993;7(4):241&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Verstappen F, Kuipers H, Janssen E, Fink W. Acid-base balance during repeated bouts of exercise: influence of HCO3. Int J Sports Med. 1984;5(5):228&#x2013;231. doi: 10.1055/s-2008-1025910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1025910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6094373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalle S, De Smet S, Geuns W, Rompaye BV, Hespel P, Koppo K. Effect of stacked sodium bicarbonate loading on repeated all-out exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40(11):711&#x2013;716. doi: 10.1055/a-0978-5139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0978-5139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31434137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalle S, Koppo K, Hespel P. Sodium bicarbonate improves sprint performance in endurance cycling. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(3):301&#x2013;306. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2020.09.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2020.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34756350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb SK, Gough LA, Sparks SA, McNaughton LR. Determinants of curvature constant (W') of the power duration relationship under normoxia and hypoxia: the effect of pre-exercise alkalosis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(5):901&#x2013;912. doi: 10.1007/s00421-017-3574-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3574-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb SK, Gough LA, Sparks SA, McNaughton LR. Sodium bicarbonate supplementation improves severe-intensity intermittent exercise under moderate acute hypoxic conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(3):607&#x2013;615. doi: 10.1007/s00421-018-3801-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-018-3801-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5805802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29344729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delextrat A, Mackessy S, Arceo-Rendon L, Scanlan A, Ramsbottom R, Calleja-Gonzalez J. Effects of three-day serial sodium bicarbonate loading on performance and physiological parameters during a simulated basketball test in female university players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28(5):547&#x2013;552. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon H, Baker CE, Baker JS, Dewhurst S, Hayes LD. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion improves Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test 1 performance: a randomized crossover trial. Nutr Diet Suppl. 2017;9:23&#x2013;27. doi: 10.2147/NDS.S131947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDS.S131947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douroudos II, Fatouros IG, Gourgoulis V, Jamurtas AZ, Tsitsios T, Hatzinikolaou A, Margonis K, Mavromatidis K, Taxildaris K. Dose-related effects of prolonged NaHCO3 ingestion during high-intensity exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(10):1746&#x2013;1753. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000230210.60957.67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000230210.60957.67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17019296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Gregory JR, Williams AD, Fell JW. The effects of serial and acute NaHCO3 loading in well-trained cyclists. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(10):2791&#x2013;2797. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318241e18a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318241e18a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23001395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller M, Williams A, Bellinger P, Howe S, Fell J. The effects of NaHCO3 and NaCl loading on hematocrit and high-intensity cycling performance. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2012;15(1):47&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Gregory JR, Williams AD, Fell JW. The effects of chronic sodium bicarbonate ingestion and interval training in highly trained rowers. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013;23(1):40&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.23.1.40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.23.1.40</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22899814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Weldon A, Price MJ. The effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on back squat and bench press exercise to failure. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(5):1358&#x2013;1366. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Zawieja EE, Podg&#xf3;rski T, &#x141;oniewski I, Zawieja BE, Warzybok M, Jeszka J. The effect of chronic progressive-dose sodium bicarbonate ingestion on CrossFit-like performance: a double-blind, randomized cross-over trial. PLoS One. 2018;13(5):e0197480. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0197480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0197480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5957406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29771966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Zawieja EE, Podg&#xf3;rski T, Zawieja BE, Micha&#x142;owska P, &#x141;oniewski I, Jeszka J. The effect of a new sodium bicarbonate loading regimen on anaerobic capacity and wrestling performance. Nutrients. 2018;10(6):697. doi: 10.3390/nu10060697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10060697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Nowaczyk PM, Adrian J, Kami&#x144;ska J, Podg&#xf3;rski T. The influence of progressive-chronic and acute sodium bicarbonate supplementation on anaerobic power and specific performance in team sports: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled crossover study. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2020;17:38. doi: 10.1186/s12986-020-00457-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-020-00457-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32489393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Zawieja EE, Zawieja BE, Micha&#x142;owska P, Podg&#xf3;rski T. The gender dependent influence of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on anaerobic power and specific performance in female and male wrestlers. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):1878. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-57590-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-57590-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edge J, Bishop D, Goodman C. Effects of chronic NaHCO3 ingestion during interval training on changes to muscle buffer capacity, metabolism, and short-term endurance performance. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101(3):918&#x2013;925. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01534.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01534.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16627675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger F, Meyer T, Such U, Hecksteden A. Effects of sodium bicarbonate on high-intensity endurance performance in cyclists: a double-blind, randomized cross-over trial. PLoS One. 2014;9(12):e114729. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0114729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0114729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4262454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25494054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farney TM, MacLellan MJ, Hearon CM, Johannsen NM, Nelson AG. The effect of aspartate and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on muscle contractile properties among trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(3):763&#x2013;770. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30095737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira LHB, Smolarek AC, Chilibeck PD, Barros MP, McAnulty SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Zandona BA, Souza-Junior TP. High doses of sodium bicarbonate increase lactate levels and delay exhaustion in a cycling performance test. Nutrition. 2019;60:94&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2018.09.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2018.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30551121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freis T, Hecksteden A, Such U, Meyer T. Effect of sodium bicarbonate on prolonged running performance: A randomized, double-blind, cross-over study. PLoS One. 2017;12(8):e0182158. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0182158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0182158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5552294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28797049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Froio de Araujo Dias G, da Eira Silva V, de Salles Painelli V, Sale C, Giannini Artioli G, Gualano B, Saunders B. (In)consistencies in responses to sodium bicarbonate supplementation: a randomised, repeated measures, counterbalanced and double-blind study. PLoS One. 2015;10(11):e0143086. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0143086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0143086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4648485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26574755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaitanos GC, Nevill ME, Brooks S, Williams C. Repeated bouts of sprint running after induced alkalosis. J Sports Sci. 1991;9(4):355&#x2013;370. doi: 10.1080/02640419108729896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640419108729896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1664869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao JP, Costill DL, Horswill CA, Park SH. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion improves performance in interval swimming. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1988;58(1-2):171&#x2013;174. doi: 10.1007/BF00636622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00636622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2849539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George KP, MacLaren DP. The effect of induced alkalosis and acidosis on endurance running at an intensity corresponding to 4 mM blood lactate. Ergonomics. 1988;31(11):1639&#x2013;1645. doi: 10.1080/00140138808966813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140138808966813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3229410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfinch J, Mc Naughton L, Davies P. Induced metabolic alkalosis and its effects on 400-m racing time. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1988;57(1):45&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1007/BF00691236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00691236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2830108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gough LA, Rimmer S, Osler CJ, Higgins MF. Ingestion of sodium bicarbonate (NaHCO3) following a fatiguing bout of exercise accelerates postexercise acid-base balance recovery and improves subsequent high-intensity cycling time to exhaustion. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2017;27(5):429&#x2013;438. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28530505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gough LA, Deb SK, Sparks AS, McNaughton LR. The reproducibility of 4-km time trial (TT) performance following individualised sodium bicarbonate supplementation: a randomised controlled trial in trained cyclists. Sports Med Open. 2017;3(1):34. doi: 10.1186/s40798-017-0101-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-017-0101-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5608656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28936625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gough LA, Brown D, Deb SK, Sparks SA, McNaughton LR. The influence of alkalosis on repeated high-intensity exercise performance and acid-base balance recovery in acute moderate hypoxic conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(12):2489&#x2013;2498. doi: 10.1007/s00421-018-3975-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-018-3975-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6244684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gough LA, Deb SK, Sparks SA, McNaughton LR. Sodium bicarbonate improves 4 km time trial cycling performance when individualised to time to peak blood bicarbonate in trained male cyclists. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(15):1705&#x2013;1712. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2017.1410875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2017.1410875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29183257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gough LA, Rimmer S, Sparks SA, McNaughton LR, Higgins MF. Post-exercise supplementation of sodium bicarbonate improves acid base balance recovery and subsequent high-intensity boxing specific performance. Front Nutr. 2019;6:155. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2019.00155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6779834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31632978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gough LA, Deb SK, Brown D, Sparks SA, McNaughton LR. The effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on cycling performance and acid base balance recovery in acute normobaric hypoxia. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(13):1464&#x2013;1471. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2019.1568173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2019.1568173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30668281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurton WH, Gough LA, Sparks SA, Faghy MA, Reed KE. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion improves time-to-exhaustion cycling performance and alters estimated energy system contribution: a dose-response investigation. Front Nutr. 2020;7:154. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2020.00154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2020.00154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7506131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins MF, James RS, Price MJ. The effects of sodium bicarbonate (NaHCO3) ingestion on high intensity cycling capacity. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(9):972&#x2013;981. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2012.758868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.758868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23323673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilton NP, Leach NK, Hilton MM, Sparks SA, McNaughton LR. Enteric-coated sodium bicarbonate supplementation improves high-intensity cycling performance in trained cyclists. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120(7):1563&#x2013;1573. doi: 10.1007/s00421-020-04387-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-020-04387-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7295736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32388584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson RM, Harris RC, Martin D, Smith P, Macklin B, Elliott-Sale KJ, Sale C. Effect of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on 2000-m rowing performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(1):139&#x2013;144. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2013-0086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2013-0086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23579002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horswill CA, Costill DL, Fink WJ, Flynn MG, Kirwan JP, Mitchell JB, Houmard JA. Influence of sodium bicarbonate on sprint performance: relationship to dosage. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20(6):566&#x2013;569. doi: 10.1249/00005768-198812000-00008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-198812000-00008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3237047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inbar O, Rotstein A, Jacobs I, Kaiser P, Dlin R, Dotan R. The effects of alkaline treatment on short-term maximal exercise. J Sports Sci. 1983;1(2):95&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1080/02640418308729666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640418308729666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwaoka K, Okagawa S, Mutoh Y, Miyashita M. Effects of bicarbonate ingestion on the respiratory compensation threshold and maximal exercise performance. Jpn J Physiol. 1989;39(2):255&#x2013;265. doi: 10.2170/jjphysiol.39.255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2170/jjphysiol.39.255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2761122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones NL, Sutton JR, Taylor R, Toews CJ. Effect of pH on cardiorespiratory and metabolic responses to exercise. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol. 1977;43(6):959&#x2013;964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce S, Minahan C, Anderson M, Osborne M. Acute and chronic loading of sodium bicarbonate in highly trained swimmers. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(2):461&#x2013;469. doi: 10.1007/s00421-011-1995-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1995-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21584683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz A, Costill DL, King DS, Hargreaves M, Fink WJ. Maximal exercise tolerance after induced alkalosis. Int J Sports Med. 1984;5(2):107&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1055/s-2008-1025890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1025890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6325355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalchuk JM, Heigenhauser GJ, Jones NL. Effect of pH on metabolic and cardiorespiratory responses during progressive exercise. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol. 1984;57(5):1558&#x2013;1563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6520052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozak-Collins K, Burke ER, Schoene RB. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion does not improve performance in women cyclists. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1994;26(12):1510&#x2013;1515. doi: 10.1249/00005768-199412000-00015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-199412000-00015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7869886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Ermidis G, Mohr M. Sodium bicarbonate intake improves high-intensity intermittent exercise performance in trained young men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2015;12:25. doi: 10.1186/s12970-015-0087-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-015-0087-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4475610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26097440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumst&#xe1;t M, Hlinsk&#xfd; T, Struh&#xe1;r I, Thomas A. Does sodium citrate cause the same ergogenic effect as sodium bicarbonate on swimming performance? J Hum Kinet. 2018;65:89&#x2013;98. doi: 10.2478/hukin-2018-0022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2018-0022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6341953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30687422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavender G, Bird SR. Effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion upon repeated sprints. Br J Sports Med. 1989;23(1):41&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.23.1.41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.23.1.41</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1478644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2730998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limmer M, de Mar&#xe9;es M, Platen P. Effects of daily ingestion of sodium bicarbonate on acid-base status and anaerobic performance during an altitude sojourn at high altitude: a randomized controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2020;17(1):22. doi: 10.1186/s12970-020-00351-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-020-00351-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7168960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32307012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindh AM, Peyrebrune MC, Ingham SA, Bailey DM, Folland JP. Sodium bicarbonate improves swimming performance. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29(6):519&#x2013;523. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-989228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-989228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18004687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes-Silva JP, Da Silva Santos JF, Artioli GG, Loturco I, Abbiss C, Franchini E. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion increases glycolytic contribution and improves performance during simulated taekwondo combat. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(3):431&#x2013;440. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2018.1424942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1424942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29355092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marriott M, Krustrup P, Mohr M. Ergogenic effects of caffeine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on intermittent exercise performance preceded by intense arm cranking exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2015;12:13. doi: 10.1186/s12970-015-0075-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-015-0075-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4351945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25750597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx JO, Gordon SE, Vos NH, Nindl BC, G&#xf3;mez AL, Volek JS, Pedro J, Ratamess N, Newton RU, French DN, Rubin MR, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Kraemer WJ. Effect of alkalosis on plasma epinephrine responses to high intensity cycle exercise in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;87(1):72&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1007/s00421-002-0591-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-002-0591-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12012079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Materko W, Santos EL, Novaes JDS. Effect of bicarbonate supplementation on muscular strength. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2008;11(6):25&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuura R, Arimitsu T, Kimura T, Yunoki T, Yano T. Effect of oral administration of sodium bicarbonate on surface EMG activity during repeated cycling sprints. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101(4):409&#x2013;417. doi: 10.1007/s00421-007-0512-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0512-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17628824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Leiper JB, Litchfield PE. The effects of induced acidosis and alkalosis on isometric endurance capacity in man. In: Dotson CO, Humphrey JH, editors. Exercise physiology, current selected research. New York: AMS Press; 1986. pp. 73&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney N, Heigenhauser GJ, Jones NL. Effects of pH on maximal power output and fatigue during short-term dynamic exercise. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol. 1983;55(1 Pt 1):225&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6885575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie DC, Coutts KD, Stirling DR, Hoeben HH, Kuzara G. Maximal work production following two levels of artificially induced metabolic alkalosis. J Sports Sci. 1986;4(1):35&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1080/02640418608732096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640418608732096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3735482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Curtin R, Goodman G, Perry D, Turner B, Showell C. Anaerobic work and power output during cycle ergometer exercise: effects of bicarbonate loading. J Sports Sci. 1991;9(2):151&#x2013;160. doi: 10.1080/02640419108729876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640419108729876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1910096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR. Bicarbonate ingestion: effects of dosage on 60 s cycle ergometry. J Sports Sci. 1992;10(5):415&#x2013;423. doi: 10.1080/02640419208729940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640419208729940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1331493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion and its effects on anaerobic exercise of various durations. J Sports Sci. 1992;10(5):425&#x2013;435. doi: 10.1080/02640419208729941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640419208729941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1331494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR, Ford S, Newbold C. Effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on high intensity exercise in moderately trained women. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(2):98&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Dalton B, Palmer G. Sodium bicarbonate can be used as an ergogenic aid in high-intensity, competitive cycle ergometry of 1 h duration. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1999;80(1):64&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1007/s004210050559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10367725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Backx K, Palmer G, Strange N. Effects of chronic bicarbonate ingestion on the performance of high-intensity work. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1999;80(4):333&#x2013;336. doi: 10.1007/s004210050600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10483803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Strange N, Backx K. The effects of chronic sodium bicarbonate ingestion on multiple bouts of anaerobic work and power output. J Hum Mov Stud. 2000;38:307&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton L, Thompson D. Acute versus chronic sodium bicarbonate ingestion and anaerobic work and power output. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2001;41(4):456&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11687764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller P, Robinson AL, Sparks SA, Bridge CA, Bentley DJ, McNaughton LR. The effects of novel ingestion of sodium bicarbonate on repeated sprint ability. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(2):561&#x2013;568. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26815179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ndel T. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion improves repeated high-intensity cycling performance in the heat. Temperature. 2018;5(4):343&#x2013;347. doi: 10.1080/23328940.2018.1436393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23328940.2018.1436393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6298489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30574526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller SM, Gehrig SM, Frese S, Wagner CA, Boutellier U, Toigo M. Multiday acute sodium bicarbonate intake improves endurance capacity and reduces acidosis in men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10(1):16. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-10-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23531361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northgraves MJ, Peart DJ, Jordan CA, Vince RV. Effect of lactate supplementation and sodium bicarbonate on 40-km cycling time trial performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(1):273&#x2013;280. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182986a4c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182986a4c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23660571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira LF, de Salles PV, Nemezio K, Gon&#xe7;alves LS, Yamaguchi G, Saunders B, Gualano B, Artioli GG. Chronic lactate supplementation does not improve blood buffering capacity and repeated high-intensity exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(11):1231&#x2013;1239. doi: 10.1111/sms.12792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry-Billings M, MacLaren DP. The effect of sodium bicarbonate and sodium citrate ingestion on anaerobic power during intermittent exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1986;55(5):524&#x2013;529. doi: 10.1007/BF00421648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00421648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3021445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peart DJ, McNaughton LR, Midgley AW, Taylor L, Towlson C, Madden LA, Vince RV. Pre-exercise alkalosis attenuates the heat shock protein 72 response to a single-bout of anaerobic exercise. J Sci Med Sport. 2011;14(5):435&#x2013;440. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2011.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2011.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21498114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peinado AB, Holgado D, Luque-Casado A, Rojo-Tirado MA, Sanabria D, Gonz&#xe1;lez C, Mateo-March M, S&#xe1;nchez-Mu&#xf1;oz C, Calder&#xf3;n FJ, Zabala M. Effect of induced alkalosis on performance during a field-simulated BMX cycling competition. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22(3):335&#x2013;341. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2018.08.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2018.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30170952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce EF, Eastman NW, Hammer WH, Lynn TD. Effect of induced alkalosis on swimming time trials. J Sports Sci. 1992;10(3):255&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1080/02640419208729924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640419208729924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1318391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potteiger JA, Webster MJ, Nickel GL, Haub MD, Palmer RJ. The effects of buffer ingestion on metabolic factors related to distance running performance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1996;72(4):365&#x2013;371. doi: 10.1007/BF00599698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00599698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8851907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price M, Moss P, Rance S. Effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on prolonged intermittent exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(8):1303&#x2013;1308. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000079067.46555.3C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000079067.46555.3C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price MJ, Simons C. The effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on high-intensity intermittent running and subsequent performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(7):1834&#x2013;1842. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e06e4a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e06e4a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20555273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymer GH, Marsh GD, Kowalchuk JM, Thompson RT. Metabolic effects of induced alkalosis during progressive forearm exercise to fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 2004;96(6):2050&#x2013;2056. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01261.2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01261.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14766777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson RJ, Falkel JE, Drash AL, Swank AM, Metz KF, Spungen SA, LeBoeuf JR. Effect of induced alkalosis on physical work capacity during arm and leg exercise. Ergonomics. 1987;30(1):19&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1080/00140138708969674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140138708969674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3030725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Sale C, Harris RC, Sunderland C. Sodium bicarbonate and high-intensity-cycling capacity: variability in responses. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(4):627&#x2013;632. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2013-0295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2013-0295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24155093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schauf M, Ball TE. Effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on anaerobic performance of women: dosage effect. J Hum Mov Stud. 1996;31(4):179&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Hirscher K. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion and boxing performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(1):103&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181a392b2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181a392b2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, McNaughton LR, Midgley AW, Keatley S, Hillman A. Metabolic alkalosis, recovery and sprint performance. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31(11):797&#x2013;802. doi: 10.1055/s-0030-1261943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0030-1261943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20703975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Gleadall-Siddall D. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion and repeated swim sprint performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(11):3105&#x2013;3111. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181f55eb1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181f55eb1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20881504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Marshall PW, Bray J, Towlson C. Sodium bicarbonate supplementation and ingestion timing: does it matter? J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(7):1953&#x2013;1958. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182392960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182392960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21964428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Marshall PW, Raftry S, Brooks C, Dowswell B, Romero R, Green S. The differential effect of metabolic alkalosis on maximum force and rate of force development during repeated, high-intensity cycling. J Appl Physiol. 2013;115(11):1634&#x2013;1640. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00688.2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00688.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24092691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Marshall P, Pouslen MK, Nielsen NP, Kennedy D, Green S. The effect of pH on fatigue during submaximal isometric contractions of the human calf muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(3):565&#x2013;577. doi: 10.1007/s00421-014-3027-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-014-3027-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25351788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Marshall P. The effect of metabolic alkalosis on central and peripheral mechanisms associated with exercise-induced muscle fatigue in humans. Exp Physiol. 2015;100(5):519&#x2013;530. doi: 10.1113/EP085054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP085054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25727892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Mudie K, Marshall P. The influence of sodium bicarbonate on maximal force and rates of force development in the triceps surae and brachii during fatiguing exercise. Exp Physiol. 2016;101(11):1383&#x2013;1391. doi: 10.1113/EP085933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP085933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27634487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Marshall PWM, Finn H, Cross R, Mudie K. Acute attenuation of fatigue after sodium bicarbonate supplementation does not manifest into greater training adaptations after 10-weeks of resistance training exercise. PLoS One. 2018;13(5):e0196677. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0196677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0196677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5931633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29718968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sostaric SM, Skinner SL, Brown MJ, Sangkabutra T, Medved I, Medley T, Selig SE, Fairweather I, Rutar D, McKenna MJ. Alkalosis increases muscle K+ release, but lowers plasma [K+] and delays fatigue during dynamic forearm exercise. J Physiol. 2006;570(Pt 1):185&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2005.094615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2005.094615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens TJ, McKenna MJ, Canny BJ, Snow RJ, McConell GK. Effect of sodium bicarbonate on muscle metabolism during intense endurance cycling. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(4):614&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton JR, Jones NL, Toews CJ. Effect of pH on muscle glycolysis during exercise. Clin Sci. 1981;61(3):331&#x2013;338. doi: 10.1042/cs0610331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0610331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7261554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan F, Polglaze T, Cox G, Dawson B, Mujika I, Clark S. Effects of induced alkalosis on simulated match performance in elite female water polo players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20(3):198&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.20.3.198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.20.3.198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20601737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka S, Yamaguchi D, Igawa S. Effect of low-dose sodium bicarbonate sup-plementation on intermittent endurance performance. Food Nutr Sci. 2018;9:1316&#x2013;1326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Montfoort MC, Van Dieren L, Hopkins WG, Shearman JP. Effects of ingestion of bicarbonate, citrate, lactate, and chloride on sprint running. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(7):1239&#x2013;1243. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000132378.73975.25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000132378.73975.25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15235332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhatalo A, McNaughton LR, Siegler J, Jones AM. Effect of induced alkalosis on the power-duration relationship of "all-out" exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(3):563&#x2013;570. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181b71a4a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181b71a4a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbitsky O, Mizrahi J, Levin M, Isakov E. Effect of ingested sodium bicarbonate on muscle force, fatigue, and recovery. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83(2):333&#x2013;337. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1997.83.2.333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1997.83.2.333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9296948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Qiu J, Yi L, Hou Z, Benardot D, Cao W. Effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion during 6&#x2009;weeks of HIIT on anaerobic performance of college students. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2019;16(1):18. doi: 10.1186/s12970-019-0285-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-019-0285-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6466775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30987663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster MJ, Webster MN, Crawford RE, Gladden LB. Effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on exhaustive resistance exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1993;25(8):960&#x2013;965. doi: 10.1249/00005768-199308000-00012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-199308000-00012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8396707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkes D, Gledhill N, Smyth R. Effect of acute induced metabolic alkalosis on 800-m racing time. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1983;15(4):277&#x2013;280. doi: 10.1249/00005768-198315040-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-198315040-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6312244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CL, Shih MC, Yang CC, Huang MH, Chang CK. Sodium bicarbonate supplementation prevents skilled tennis performance decline after a simulated match. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:33. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-7-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2978121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20977701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong GY, Yin LH, Hoe WE. Effects of different dosage of sodium bicarbonate on 200 m freestyle swimming performance in competitive swimmers. Int J Life Sci Pharma Res. 2018;1:66&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabala M, Requena B, S&#xe1;nchez-Mu&#xf1;oz C, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Garc&#xed;a I, O&#xf6;pik V, P&#xe4;&#xe4;suke M. Effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on performance and perceptual responses in a laboratory-simulated BMX cycling qualification series. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(5):1645&#x2013;1653. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318181febe.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318181febe</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabala M, Peinado AB, Calder&#xf3;n FJ, Sampedro J, Castillo MJ, Benito PJ. Bicarbonate ingestion has no ergogenic effect on consecutive all out sprint tests in BMX elite cyclists. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(12):3127&#x2013;3134. doi: 10.1007/s00421-011-1938-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1938-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21465247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajac A, Cholewa J, Poprzecki S, Waskiewicz Z, Langfort J. Effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on swim performance in youth athletes. J Sports Sci Med. 2009;8(1):45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24150555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinner C, Wahl P, Achtzehn S, Sperlich B, Mester J. Effects of bicarbonate ingestion and high intensity exercise on lactate and H+-ion distribution in different blood compartments. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(8):1641&#x2013;1648. doi: 10.1007/s00421-010-1800-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1800-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21197542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber JJ, McDermott AY, McGaughey KJ, Olmstead JD, Hagobian TA. Effects of combined creatine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on repeated sprint performance in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(1):252&#x2013;258. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318252f6b7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318252f6b7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23254493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellinger PM, Howe ST, Shing CM, Fell JW. Effect of combined &#x3b2;-alanine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on cycling performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(8):1545&#x2013;1551. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc08d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc08d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22330016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callahan MJ, Parr EB, Hawley JA, Burke LM. Single and combined effects of beetroot crystals and sodium bicarbonate on 4-km cycling time trial performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2017;27(3):271&#x2013;278. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27834492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr AJ, Gore CJ, Dawson B. Induced alkalosis and caffeine supplementation: effects on 2,000-m rowing performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2011;21(5):357&#x2013;364. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.21.5.357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.21.5.357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen PM, Petersen MH, Friis SN, Bangsbo J. Caffeine, but not bicarbonate, improves 6 min maximal performance in elite rowers. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2014;39(9):1058&#x2013;1063. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2013-0577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2013-0577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24999004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva RP, de Oliveira LF, Saunders B, de Andrade KC, de Salles PV, da Eira SV, Marins JCB, Franchini E, Gualano B, Artioli GG. Effects of &#x3b2;-alanine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on the estimated energy system contribution during high-intensity intermittent exercise. Amino Acids. 2019;51(1):83&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1007/s00726-018-2643-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-018-2643-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30182286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danaher J, Gerber T, Wellard RM, Stathis CG. The effect of &#x3b2;-alanine and NaHCO3 co-ingestion on buffering capacity and exercise performance with high-intensity exercise in healthy males. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(8):1715&#x2013;1724. doi: 10.1007/s00421-014-2895-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-014-2895-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4097338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles Painelli Vde S, Roschel H, Fd J, Sale C, Harris RC, Solis MY, Benatti FB, Gualano B, Lancha AH, Jr, Artioli GG. The ergogenic effect of beta-alanine combined with sodium bicarbonate on high-intensity swimming performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2013;38(5):525&#x2013;532. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2012-0286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2012-0286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23668760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducker KJ, Dawson B, Wallman KE. Effect of beta alanine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on repeated-sprint performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(12):3450&#x2013;3460. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828fd310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828fd310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23524361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felippe LC, Lopes-Silva JP, Bertuzzi R, McGinley C, Lima-Silva AE. Separate and combined effects of caffeine and sodium-bicarbonate intake on judo performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(2):221&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2015-0020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26182440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffen C, Rogerson D, Ranchordas M, Ruddock A. Effects of creatine and sodium bicarbonate coingestion on multiple indices of mechanical power output during repeated Wingate tests in trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2015;25(3):298&#x2013;306. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2014-0146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2014-0146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25203421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins MF, Wilson S, Hill C, Price MJ, Duncan M, Tallis J. Evaluating the effects of caffeine and sodium bicarbonate, ingested individually or in combination, and a taste-matched placebo on high-intensity cycling capacity in healthy males. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41(4):354&#x2013;361. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2015-0371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2015-0371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26988768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson RM, Harris RC, Martin D, Smith P, Macklin B, Gualano B, Sale C. Effect of beta-alanine, with and without sodium bicarbonate, on 2000-m rowing performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013;23(5):480&#x2013;487. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.23.5.480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.23.5.480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilding AE, Overton C, Gleave J. Effects of caffeine, sodium bicarbonate, and their combined ingestion on high-intensity cycling performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2012;22(3):175&#x2013;183. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.22.3.175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.22.3.175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22693238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero AA, Keskinen KL, Malvela MT, Sallinen JM. Combined creatine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation enhances interval swimming. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(2):306&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero AA, Hirvonen P, Saarela J, Hulmi JJ, Hoffman JR, Stout JR. Effect of sodium bicarbonate and beta-alanine supplementation on maximal sprint swimming. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10(1):52. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-10-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-52</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4176133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24215679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruscino CL, Ross ML, Gregory JR, Savage B, Flanagan TR. Effects of sodium bicarbonate, caffeine, and their combination on repeated 200-m freestyle performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18(2):116&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.18.2.116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.18.2.116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18458356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei S, Akbari K, Gahreman DE, Sarshin A, Tabben M, Kaviani M, Sadeghinikoo A, Koozehchian MS, Naderi A. Caffeine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation alone or together improve karate performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2019;16(1):44. doi: 10.1186/s12970-019-0313-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-019-0313-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6798418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31623659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale C, Saunders B, Hudson S, Wise JA, Harris RC, Sunderland CD. Effect of &#x3b2;-alanine plus sodium bicarbonate on high-intensity cycling capacity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(10):1972&#x2013;1978. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182188501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182188501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21407127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarshin A, Fallahi V, Forbes SC, Rahimi A, Koozehchian MS, Candow DG, Kaviani M, Khalifeh SN, Abdollahi V, Naderi A. Short-term co-ingestion of creatine and sodium bicarbonate improves anaerobic performance in trained taekwondo athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18(1):10. doi: 10.1186/s12970-021-00407-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00407-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7819230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33478522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Sale C, Harris RC, Sunderland C. Effect of sodium bicarbonate and beta-alanine on repeated sprints during intermittent exercise performed in hypoxia. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2014;24(2):196&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2013-0102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2013-0102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24225816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias G, Benatti FB, de Salles PV, Roschel H, Gualano B, Sale C, Harris RC, Lancha AH, Jr, Artioli GG. Additive effects of beta-alanine and sodium bicarbonate on upper-body intermittent performance. Amino Acids. 2013;45(2):309&#x2013;317. doi: 10.1007/s00726-013-1495-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-013-1495-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3714561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23595205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennig H, Talbott JH, Edwards HT, Dill DB. Effect of acidosis and alkalosis upon capacity for work. J Clin Invest. 1931;9(4):601&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1172/JCI100324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI100324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC435718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16693953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson WR, Black DH. Comparison of effects of certain blood alkalinizers and glucose upon competitive endurance performance. J Appl Physiol. 1953;5(10):577&#x2013;578. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1953.5.10.577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1953.5.10.577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13044733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margaria R, Aghemo P, Sassi G. Effect of alkalosis on performance and lactate formation in supramaximal exercise. Int Z Angew Physiol. 1971;29(3):215&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5565589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons RW, Hardt AB. The effect of alkali ingestion on the performance of trained swimmers. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1973;13(3):159&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4771448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindinger MI, Franklin TW, Lands LC, Pedersen PK, Welsh DG, Heigenhauser GJ. Role of skeletal muscle in plasma ion and acid-base regulation after NaHCO3 and KHCO3 loading in humans. Am J Physiol. 1999;276(1):R32&#x2013;R43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9887175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollidge-Horvat MG, Parolin ML, Wong D, Jones NL, Heigenhauser GJ. Effect of induced metabolic alkalosis on human skeletal muscle metabolism during exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2000;278(2):E316&#x2013;E329. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.2000.278.2.E316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.2000.278.2.E316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10662717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fordtran JS, Morawski SG, Santa Ana CA, Rector FC., Jr Gas production after reaction of sodium bicarbonate and hydrochloric acid. Gastroenterology. 1984;87(5):1014&#x2013;1021. doi: 10.1016/S0016-5085(84)80059-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0016-5085(84)80059-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6090255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrovic S, Ju X, Barone S, Seidler U, Alper SL, Lohi H, Kere J, Soleimani M. Identification of a basolateral Cl-/HCO3- exchanger specific to gastric parietal cells. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2003;284(6):G1093&#x2013;G1103. doi: 10.1152/ajpgi.00454.2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpgi.00454.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12736153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosco M, Orsenigo MN, Gastaldi G, Faelli A. pH dependence of Cl/HCO3 exchanger in the rat jejunal enterocyte. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1998;1372(2):323&#x2013;330. doi: 10.1016/S0005-2736(98)00068-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0005-2736(98)00068-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9675329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnberg LA, Fordtran JS, Carter NW, Rector FC., Jr Mechanism of bicarbonate absorption and its relationship to sodium transport in the human jejunum. J Clin Invest. 1970;49(3):548&#x2013;556. doi: 10.1172/JCI106265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI106265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC322503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5415681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilmi N, &#xc4;yr&#xe4;m&#xf6; S, Nummela A, Pullinen T, Linnamo V, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Mero AA. Oxygen uptake, acid-base balance and anaerobic energy system contribution in maximal 300-400 m running in child, adolescent and adult athletes. Athl Enhanc. 2016;5:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Monica MB, Fukuda DH, Starling-Smith TM, Clark NW, Panissa VLG. Alterations in energy system contribution following upper body sprint interval training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120(3):643&#x2013;651. doi: 10.1007/s00421-020-04304-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-020-04304-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31974857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastin PB. Energy system interaction and relative contribution during maximal exercise. Sports Med. 2001;31(10):725&#x2013;741. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200131100-00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200131100-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11547894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson MJ, Gadian DG, Wilkie DR. Muscular fatigue investigated by phosphorus nuclear magnetic resonance. Nature. 1978;274(5674):861&#x2013;866. doi: 10.1038/274861a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/274861a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">308189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns SP, Lindinger MI. Do multiple ionic interactions contribute to skeletal muscle fatigue? J Physiol. 2008;586(17):4039&#x2013;4054. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.155424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.155424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2652190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18591187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindinger MI, Cairns SP. Regulation of muscle potassium: exercise performance, fatigue and health implications. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121(3):721&#x2013;748. doi: 10.1007/s00421-020-04546-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-020-04546-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33392745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitts RH. The role of acidosis in fatigue: pro perspective. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(11):2335&#x2013;2338. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27755382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debold EP, Fitts RH, Sundberg CW, Nosek TM. Muscle fatigue from the perspective of a single crossbridge. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(11):2270&#x2013;2280. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27434086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna MJ, Bangsbo J, Renaud JM. Muscle K+, Na+, and Cl disturbances and Na+-K+ pump inactivation: implications for fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(1):288&#x2013;295. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01037.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01037.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17962569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen KK, Cheng AJ, Westerblad H, Olesen JH, Overgaard K. Moderately elevated extracellular [K+] potentiates submaximal force and power in skeletal muscle via increased [Ca2+]i during contractions. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2019;317(5):C900&#x2013;C909. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.00104.2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00104.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31411922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortune E, Lowery MM. Effect of extracellular potassium accumulation on muscle fiber conduction velocity: a simulation study. Ann Biomed Eng. 2009;37(10):2105&#x2013;2117. doi: 10.1007/s10439-009-9756-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10439-009-9756-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juel C, Pilegaard H, Nielsen JJ, Bangsbo J. Interstitial K(+) in human skeletal muscle during and after dynamic graded exercise determined by microdialysis. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2000;278(2):R400&#x2013;R406. doi: 10.1152/ajpregu.2000.278.2.R400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.2000.278.2.R400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10666141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DG, Lamb GD, Westerblad H. Impaired calcium release during fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(1):296&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00908.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00908.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17962573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mainwood GW, Worsley-Brown P. The effects of extracellular pH and buffer concentration on the efflux of lactate from frog sartorius muscle. J Physiol. 1975;250(1):1&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.1975.sp011040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1975.sp011040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1348336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16992502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debold EP. Recent insights into muscle fatigue at the cross-bridge level. Front Physiol. 2012;3:151. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2012.00151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2012.00151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3365633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22675303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntosh BR, Holash RJ, Renaud JM. Skeletal muscle fatigue--regulation of excitation-contraction coupling to avoid metabolic catastrophe. J Cell Sci. 2012;125(Pt 9):2105&#x2013;2114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22627029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart PA. Modern quantitative acid-base chemistry. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 1983;61(12):1444&#x2013;1461. doi: 10.1139/y83-207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/y83-207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6423247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen WB. The Lewis Acid-Base Concepts: An Overview. Krieger Pub Co., 1979. 1st edition.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Street D, Nielsen JJ, Bangsbo J, Juel C. Metabolic alkalosis reduces exercise-induced acidosis and potassium accumulation in human skeletal muscle interstitium. J Physiol. 2005;566(Pt 2):481&#x2013;489. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2005.086801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2005.086801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on measures of Wingate test performance: a meta-analysis. J Am Coll Nutr. 2020. 10.1080/07315724.2020.1850370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33314967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faria EW, Parker DL, Faria IE. The science of cycling: physiology and training - part 1. Sports Med. 2005;35(4):285&#x2013;312. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200535040-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535040-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia FM, Krustrup P. The Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test: a useful tool for evaluation of physical performance in intermittent sports. Sports Med. 2008;38(1):37&#x2013;51. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200838010-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200838010-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18081366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Garofolini A, Pickering C, Duncan MJ, Tinsley GM, Del Coso J. Isolated effects of caffeine and sodium bicarbonate ingestion on performance in the Yo-Yo test: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2020;23(1):41&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2019.08.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31466868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagerman FC. Applied physiology of rowing. Sports Med. 1984;1(4):303&#x2013;326. doi: 10.2165/00007256-198401040-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-198401040-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6390606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnes T, Cruz RSO, Caputo F, De Aguiar RA. The impact of preconditioning strategies designed to improve 2000-m rowing ergometer performance in trained rowers: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(7):871&#x2013;879. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2019-0247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TB, Hopkins WG. Variability and predictability of finals times of elite rowers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(11):2155&#x2013;2160. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31821d3f8e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31821d3f8e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Mikulic P. Ergogenic effects of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on middle, but not short-distance swimming tests: a meta-analysis. J Diet Suppl. 2021. 10.1080/19390211.2021.1942381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34151681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trewin CB, Hopkins WG, Pyne DB. Relationship between world-ranking and Olympic performance of swimmers. J Sports Sci. 2004;22(4):339&#x2013;345. doi: 10.1080/02640410310001641610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410310001641610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15161107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, Zinner C, Heilemann I, Kjendlie PL, Holmberg HC, Mester J. High-intensity interval training improves VO(2peak), maximal lactate accumulation, time trial and competition performance in 9-11-year-old swimmers. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(5):1029&#x2013;1036. doi: 10.1007/s00421-010-1586-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1586-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2974202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20683609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchini E, Artioli GG, Brito CJ. Judo combat: time-motion analysis and physiology. Int J Perf Anal Spor. 2013;13(3):624&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amtmann JA, Amtmann KA, Spath WK. Lactate and rate of perceived exertion responses of athletes training for and competing in a mixed martial arts event. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(2):645&#x2013;647. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318166018e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318166018e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Rodriguez RF, Garofolini A, Saunders B, Bishop DJ, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Effects of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on muscular strength and endurance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(7):1361&#x2013;1375. doi: 10.1007/s40279-020-01275-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01275-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32096113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1419&#x2013;1449. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0486-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0486-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Haas S, Bishop D, Dawson B, Goodman C, Edge J. Effects of rest interval during high-repetition resistance training on strength, aerobic fitness, and repeated-sprint ability. J Sports Sci. 2007;25(6):619&#x2013;628. doi: 10.1080/02640410600874849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410600874849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17454528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spriet LL, Lindinger MI, Heigenhauser GJ, Jones NL. Effects of alkalosis on skeletal muscle metabolism and performance during exercise. Am J Physiol. 1986;251(5 Pt 2):R833&#x2013;R839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3777210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pate E, Bhimani M, Franks-Skiba K, Cooke R. Reduced effect of pH on skinned rabbit psoas muscle mechanics at high temperatures: implications for fatigue. J Physiol. 1995;486(3):689&#x2013;694. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.1995.sp020844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1995.sp020844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1156556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7473229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody L, Pollock M, Roy S, De Luca C, Celli B. pH-induced effects on median frequency and conduction velocity of the myoelectric signal. J Appl Physiol. 1991;71(5):1878&#x2013;1885. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1991.71.5.1878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1991.71.5.1878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1761486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methenitis S, Terzis G, Zaras N, Stasinaki AN, Karandreas N. Intramuscular fiber conduction velocity, isometric force and explosive performance. J Hum Kinet. 2016;51:93&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1515/hukin-2015-0174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hukin-2015-0174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5260554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28149372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Pain MT, Folland J. Explosive force production during isometric squats correlates with athletic performance in rugby union players. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(1):66&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2012.720704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.720704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22938509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, Folland J, Tillin N, Duchateau J. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(6):1091&#x2013;1116. doi: 10.1007/s00421-016-3346-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3346-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4875063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26941023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop DJ, Thomas C, Moore-Morris T, Tonkonogi M, Sahlin K, Mercier J. Sodium bicarbonate ingestion prior to training improves mitochondrial adaptations in rats. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2010;299(2):E225&#x2013;E233. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00738.2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00738.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20484007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Oliveira LF, Dolan E, Durkalec-Michalski K, McNaughton L, Artioli GG, et al. Sodium bicarbonate supplementation and the female athlete: A brief commentary with small scale systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021. 10.1080/17461391.2021.1880649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33487131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNulty KL, Elliott-Sale KJ, Dolan E, Swinton PA, Ansdell P, Goodall S, Thomas K, Hicks KM. The effects of menstrual cycle phase on exercise performance in eumenorrheic women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(10):1813&#x2013;1827. doi: 10.1007/s40279-020-01319-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01319-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RL, Stellingwerff T, Artioli GG, Saunders B, Cooper S, Sale C. Dose-response of sodium bicarbonate ingestion highlights individuality in time course of blood analyte responses. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2016;26(5):445&#x2013;453. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heibel AB, Perim PHL, Oliveira LF, McNaughton LR, Saunders B. Time to optimize supplementation: modifying factors influencing the individual responses to extracellular buffering agents. Front Nutr. 2018;5:35. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2018.00035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2018.00035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5951986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29868599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira LF, Saunders B, Yamaguchi G, Swinton P, Giannini AG. Is individualization of sodium bicarbonate ingestion based on time to peak necessary? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(8):1801&#x2013;1808. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32102054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middlebrook I, Peacock J, Tinnion DJ, Leach NK, Hilton NP, Saunders B, Sparks SA, Mc Naughton LR. Capsule size alters the timing of metabolic alkalosis following sodium bicarbonate supplementation. Front Nutr. 2021;8:634465. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2021.634465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2021.634465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7933015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes-Silva JP, Reale R, Franchini E. Acute and chronic effect of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on Wingate test performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(7):762&#x2013;771. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2018.1524739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2018.1524739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30319077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancha Junior AH, Painelli Vde S, Saunders B, Artioli GG. Nutritional strategies to modulate intracellular and extracellular buffering capacity during high-intensity exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45(Suppl 1):S71&#x2013;S81. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0397-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0397-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4672007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurton WH, Faulkner SH, James RM. Effect of warm-up and sodium bicarbonate ingestion on 4-km cycling time-trial performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021. 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33831843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RL, Stellingwerff T, Swinton P, Artioli GG, Saunders B, Sale C. Warm-up intensity does not affect the ergogenic effect of sodium bicarbonate in adult men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2021. In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahle LE, Kelly PV, Eliot KA, Weiss EP. Acute sodium bicarbonate loading has negligible effects on resting and exercise blood pressure but causes gastrointestinal distress. Nutr Res. 2013;33(6):479&#x2013;486. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2013.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2013.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3680785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23746564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr AJ, Slater GJ, Gore CJ, Dawson B, Burke LM. Effect of sodium bicarbonate on [HCO3-], pH, and gastrointestinal symptoms. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2011;21(3):189&#x2013;194. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.21.3.189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.21.3.189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21719899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira LF, Saunders B, Artioli GG. Is bypassing the stomach a means to optimize sodium bicarbonate supplementation? A case study with a postbariatric surgery individual. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28(6):660&#x2013;663. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29722576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark VR, Hopkins WG, Hawley JA, Burke LM. Placebo effect of carbohydrate feedings during a 40-km cycling time trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(9):1642&#x2013;1647. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200009000-00019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200009000-00019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10994918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marticorena FM, Carvalho A, de Oliveira LF, Dolan E, Gualano B, Swinton S, et al. Nonplacebo controls to determine the magnitude of ergogenic interventions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Venier S, Mikulic P. Both caffeine and placebo improve vertical jump performance compared with a nonsupplemented control condition. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16(3):448&#x2013;451. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2019-1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-1028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32707561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins MF, Shabir A. Expectancy of ergogenicity from sodium bicarbonate ingestion increases high-intensity cycling capacity. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41(4):405&#x2013;410. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2015-0523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2015-0523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26863442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClung M, Collins D. "Because I know it will!": placebo effects of an ergogenic aid on athletic performance. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2007;29(3):382&#x2013;394. doi: 10.1123/jsep.29.3.382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsep.29.3.382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, de Oliveira LF, da Silva RP, de Salles PV, Gon&#xe7;alves LS, Yamaguchi G, Mutti T, Maciel E, Roschel H, Artioli GG, Gualano B. Placebo in sports nutrition: a proof-of-principle study involving caffeine supplementation. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(11):1240&#x2013;1247. doi: 10.1111/sms.12793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM. Practical issues in evidence-based use of performance supplements: supplement interactions, repeated use and individual responses. Sports Med. 2017;47(Suppl 1):79&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0687-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0687-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5371635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Tallon MJ, Dunnett M, Boobis L, Coakley J, Kim HJ, Fallowfield JL, Hill CA, Sale C, Wise JA. The absorption of orally supplied beta-alanine and its effect on muscle carnosine synthesis in human vastus lateralis. Amino Acids. 2006;30(3):279&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0299-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0299-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16554972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale C, Saunders B, Harris RC. Effect of beta-alanine supplementation on muscle carnosine concentrations and exercise performance. Amino Acids. 2010;39(2):321&#x2013;333. doi: 10.1007/s00726-009-0443-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-009-0443-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20091069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Elliott-Sale K, Artioli GG, Swinton PA, Dolan E, Roschel H, Sale C, Gualano B. &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation to improve exercise capacity and performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(8):658&#x2013;669. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27797728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on Yo-Yo test performance: A meta-analysis. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;43:158&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1016/j.clnesp.2021.03.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2021.03.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest NS, VanDusseldorp TA, Nelson MT, Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Jenkins NDM, Arent SM, Antonio J, Stout JR, Trexler ET, Smith-Ryan AE, Goldstein ER, Kalman DS, Campbell BI. International society of sports nutrition position stand: caffeine and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18(1):1. doi: 10.1186/s12970-020-00383-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-020-00383-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7777221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33388079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Trexler ET, Lazinica B, Pedisic Z. Effects of caffeine intake on muscle strength and power: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15:11. doi: 10.1186/s12970-018-0216-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-018-0216-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5839013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29527137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Caffeine ingestion enhances Wingate performance: a meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(2):219&#x2013;225. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2017.1394371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1394371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29087785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Mikulic P. Caffeine ingestion acutely enhances muscular strength and power but not muscular endurance in resistance-trained men. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(8):1029&#x2013;1036. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2017.1330362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1330362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28537195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabol F, Grgic J, Mikulic P. The effects of 3 different doses of caffeine on jumping and throwing performance: a randomized, double-blind, crossover study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(9):1170&#x2013;1177. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2018-0884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30702372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan TM, Caldwell JA, Lieberman HR. A review of caffeine's effects on cognitive, physical and occupational performance. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2016;71:294&#x2013;312. doi: 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2016.09.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2016.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27612937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Effects of caffeine on resistance exercise: a review of recent research. Sports Med. 2021. 10.1007/s40279-021-01521-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34291426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Effects of combining caffeine and sodium bicarbonate on exercise performance: a review with suggestions for future research. J Diet Suppl. 2021;18(4):444&#x2013;460. doi: 10.1080/19390211.2020.1783422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19390211.2020.1783422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32583697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, Ziegenfuss TN, Wildman R, Collins R, Candow DG, Kleiner SM, Almada AL, Lopez HL. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:18. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0173-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0173-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>