<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32222015</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1442-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical &amp; experimental ophthalmology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of caffeine consumption on intraocular pressure during low-intensity endurance exercise: A placebo-controlled, double-blind, balanced crossover study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>602</StartPage><EndPage>609</EndPage><MedlinePgn>602-609</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ceo.13755</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE">Intraocular pressure (IOP) is sensitive to caffeine intake and physical exercise. However, the combined effect of caffeine intake and physical exercise on IOP levels remains unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">We aimed to assess the effects of caffeine consumption before exercise on the IOP behaviour during low-intensity endurance exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">A placebo-controlled, double-blind, balanced crossover study at the University of Granada.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS">Eighteen physically active young adults (age = 23.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.4&#x2009;years) participated in this study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Participants performed 30&#x2009;minutes of cycling at 10% of maximal power production after 30&#x2009;minutes of ingesting a capsule of caffeine (~4 mg/kg) and placebo in two different days and following a double-blind procedure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURE">IOP was measured at baseline (before caffeine/placebo ingestion), after 5 minutes of warm-up, during cycling (6, 12, 18, 24 and 30&#x2009;minutes) and recovery (5 and 10 minutes) by rebound tonometry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There was a significant effect of caffeine consumption (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001, &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup> = 0.50), showing that the ingestion of caffeine before exercise counteracted the IOP-lowering response to low-intensity endurance exercise. Greater IOP values at 12, 18, 24 and 30&#x2009;minutes (corrected P-values&lt;.05, ds = 0.90-1.08) of cycling were observed for the caffeine in comparison to the placebo condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE">The ingestion of caffeine (~4 mg/kg) 30&#x2009;minutes before performing low-intensity endurance exercise counteracts the IOP-lowering effect of low-intensity exercise. These results highlight that the ingestion of a considerable amount of caffeine before exercise should be discouraged for individuals who would benefit from the IOP reduction associated with low-intensity exercise (ie, glaucoma patients or those at risk).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Royal Australian and New Zealand College of Ophthalmologists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vera</LastName><ForeName>Jes&#xfa;s</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8091-2373</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Optics, Faculty of Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redondo</LastName><ForeName>Beatriz</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4571-873X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Optics, Faculty of Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bard&#xf3;n</LastName><ForeName>Anabel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Optics, Faculty of Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P&#xe9;rez-Castilla</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Amador</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Sciences and Physical Conditioning, Faculty of Education, Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de la Sant&#xed;sima Concepci&#xf3;n, Concepci&#xf3;n, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jim&#xe9;nez</LastName><ForeName>Raimundo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8036-2532</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Optics, Faculty of Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Ophthalmol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100896531</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1442-6404</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caffeine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005901" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glaucoma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007429" MajorTopicYN="N">Intraocular Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014065" MajorTopicYN="N">Tonometry, Ocular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glaucoma management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glaucoma prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ocular hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rebound tonometry</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32222015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ceo.13755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chia EM, Wang JJ, Rochtchina E, Smith W, Cumming RR, Mitchell P. Impact of bilateral visual impairment on health-related quality of life: the Blue Mountains Eye Study. Investig Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2004;45:71-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinreb RN, Aung T, Medeiros FA. The pathophysiology and treatment of glaucoma. JAMA. 2014;311:1901-1911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tham YC, Li X, Wong TY, Quigley HA, Aung T, Cheng CY. Global prevalence of glaucoma and projections of glaucoma burden through 2040: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ophthalmology. 2014;121:2081-2090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Moraes CG, Juthani VJ, Liebmann JM, et al. Risk factors for visual field progression in treated glaucoma. Arch Ophthalmol. 2011;129:562-568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocular Hypertension Treatment Study Group, European Glaucoma Prevention Study Group, Gordon MO, Torri V, Miglior S, et al. Validated prediction model for the development of primary open-angle glaucoma in individuals with ocular hypertension. Ophthalmology. 2007;114:10-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prata TS, De Moraes CG, Kanadani FN, Ritch R, Paranhos A Jr. Posture-induced intraocular pressure changes: considerations regarding body position in glaucoma patients. Surv Ophthalmol. 2010;55:445-453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez R, Vera J. Effect of examination stress on intraocular pressure in university students. Appl Ergon. 2018;67:252-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuman JS, Massicotte EC, Connolly S, Hertzmark E, Mukherji B, Kunen MZ. Increased intraocular pressure and visual field defects in high resistance wind instrument players. Ophthalmology. 2000;107:127-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu MM, Lai JSM, Choy BNK, et al. Physical exercise and glaucoma: a review on the roles of physical exercise on intraocular pressure control, ocular blood flow regulation, neuroprotection and glaucoma-related mental health. Acta Ophthalmol. 2018;96:676-691. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2018-100278. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giaconi JA, Yu F, Stone KL, et al. The association of consumption of fruits/vegetables with decreased risk of glaucoma among older African-American women in the study of osteoporotic fractures. Am J Ophthalmol. 2012;154:635-644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman AL, Stone KL, Kodjebacheva G, et al. Glaucoma risk and the consumption of fruits and vegetables among older women in the study of osteoporotic fractures. Am J Ophthalmol. 2008;145:1081-1089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natsis K, Asouhidou I, Nousios G, Chatzibalis T, Vlasis K, Karabatakis V. Aerobic exercise and intraocular pressure in normotensive and glaucoma patients. BMC Ophthalmol. 2009;9:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najmanova E, Pluhacek F, Botek M. Intraocular pressure response to moderate exercise during 30-min recovery. Optom Vis Sci. 2016;93:281-285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;fer F, Schiller J, Klettner A, Lanzl I, Roider J, Weisser B. Comparison of the influence of aerobic and resistance exercise of the upper and lower limb on intraocular pressure. Acta Ophthalmol. 2014;92:249-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyl&#x119;ga&#x142;a A. The effects of physical exercises on ocular physiology. J Glaucoma. 2016;25:e843-e849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Wang M, Guo W, Wang J, Sun X. The effect of caffeine on intraocular pressure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2011;249:435-442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera J, Redondo B, Molina R, Berm&#xfa;dez J, Jim&#xe9;nez R. Effects of caffeine on intraocular pressure are subject to tolerance: a comparative study between low and high caffeine consumers. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 2019;236:811-819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecht I, Achiron A, Man V, Burgansky-Eliash Z. Modifiable factors in the management of glaucoma: a systematic review of current evidence. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2017;255:789-796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Pickering C, Schoenfeld BJ, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z. Wake up and smell the coffee: caffeine supplementation and exercise performance-an umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses. Br J Sports Med. 2019;1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham KA, Spriet LL. Administration of caffeine in alternate forms. Sports Med. 2018;48:79-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogervorst E, Bandelow S, Schmitt J, et al. Caffeine improves physical and cognitive performance during exhaustive exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1841-1851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan TM, Caldwell JA, Lieberman HR. A review of caffeine's effects on cognitive, physical and occupational performance. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2016;71:294-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Torrej&#xf3;n A, Morales-Artacho AJ, P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Jaric S. Optimal resistive forces for maximizing the reliability of leg muscles' capacities tested on a cycle ergometer. J Appl Biomech. 2018;34:47-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaric S. Force-velocity relationship of muscles performing multi-joint maximum performance tasks. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36:699-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Monta&#xf1;&#xe9;s J, Mart&#xed;nez-de-la-Casa JM, Sabater AL, Morales-Fernandez L, S&#xe1;enz C, Garcia-Feijoo J. Clinical evaluation of the new rebound tonometers Icare PRO and Icare ONE compared with the Goldmann tonometer. J Glaucoma. 2015;24:527-532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgson AB, Randell RK, Jeukendrup AE. The metabolic and performance effects of caffeine compared to coffee during endurance exercise. PLoS One. 2013;8(4):e59561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR, Lovell RJ, Siegler J, Midgley AW, Sandstrom M, Bentley DJ. The effects of caffeine ingestion on time trial cycling performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2008;3:157-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa VP, Harris A, Anderson D, et al. Ocular perfusion pressure in glaucoma. Acta Ophthalmol. 2014;92:252-266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurminen ML, Niittynen L, Korpela R, Vapaatalo H. Coffee, caffeine and blood pressure: a critical review. Eur J Clin Nutr. 1999;53:831-839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt AP, Feigl B, Stewart IB. The intraocular pressure response to dehydration: a pilot study. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:1963-1966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Caffeine and exercise: metabolism, endurance and performance. Sports Med. 2001;31:785-807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Casa DJ, Maresh CM, Ganio MS. Caffeine, fluid-electrolyte balance, temperature regulation, and exercise-heat tolerance. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2007;35:135-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leske M, Heijl A, Hussein M, et al. Factors for glaucoma progression and the effect of treatment: the early manifest glaucoma trial. Arch Ophthalmol. 2003;121:48-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan S, Choudhari NS, Baskaran M, George RJ, Shantha B, Vijaya L. Diurnal intraocular pressure fluctuation and its risk factors in angle-closure and open-angle glaucoma. Eye. 2016;30:362-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susanna R, Clement C, Goldberg I, Hatanaka M. Applications of the water drinking test in glaucoma management. Clin Experiment Ophthalmol. 2017;45:625-631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox GR, Desbrow B, Montgomery PG, et al. Effect of different protocols of caffeine intake on metabolism and endurance performance. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:990-999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan PT, Lane J, Moore KL, Aspen J, Rycroft JA, O'Brien DC. The acute physiological and mood effects of tea and coffee. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 2000;66:19-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Parrish TB. Caffeine dose effect on activation-induced BOLD and CBF responses. Neuroimage. 2009;46:577-583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mort JR, Kruse HR. Timing of blood pressure measurement related to caffeine consumption. Ann Pharmacother. 2008;42:105-110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera J, Jim&#xe9;nez R, Redondo B, Torrej&#xf3;n A, de Moraes CG, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A. Effect of the level of effort during resistance training on intraocular pressure. Eur J Sport Sci. 2019;19:394-401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera J, Jim&#xe9;nez R, Redondo B, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, C&#xe1;rdenas D. Effect of a maximal treadmill test on intraocular pressure and ocular perfusion pressure: the mediating role of fitness level. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2019;1120672119832840. https://doi.org/10.1177/1120672119832840. [Epub ahead of print]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera J, Jim&#xe9;nez R, Redondo B, et al. Investigating the immediate and cumulative effects of isometric squat exercise for different weight loads on intraocular pressure: a pilot study. Sports Health. 2019;11:247-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Melkebeke L, Barbosa-Breda J, Huygens M, Stalmans I. Optical coherence tomography angiography in glaucoma care. Ophthalmic Res. 2018;60:139-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojikian KD, Chen PP, Wen JC. Optical coherence tomography angiography in glaucoma. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2019;30:110-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galambos P, Vafiadis J, Vilchez SE, et al. Compromised autoregulatory control of ocular hemodynamics in glaucoma patients after postural change. Ophthalmology. 2006;113:1832-1836.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>