<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23626495</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1544-2896</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Season>Fall</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of undergraduate neuroscience education : JUNE : a publication of FUN, Faculty for Undergraduate Neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Undergrad Neurosci Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of personal EEG monitors in a behavioral neuroscience course to investigate natural setting sleep patterns and the factors affecting them in college students.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>A65</StartPage><EndPage>A70</EndPage><MedlinePgn>A65-70</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Sleep is often a topic of avid interest to college students, yet it is one that does not yield itself well to hands-on, interactive learning modules. Supplementing classroom learning with interactive "real world" laboratory activities provides students with a deeper understanding of behavior and its neural control. The project described here was designed to supplement the teaching of EEGs, sleep and circadian rhythms and involved students in the empirical process from hypothesizing about the factors that affect sleep, to personal data collection, data analysis and writing in the style of a peer-reviewed manuscript. Students enrolled in Behavioral Neuroscience at Connecticut College were provided with a home-based personal EEG monitor used to collect sleep data in their natural sleep setting. Participants recorded sleep data with the use of the ZEO&#xae; Personal Sleep Coach system and completed a nightly sleep journal questionnaire for seven nights. The ZEO&#xae; system uses EEG patterns to define sleep stages including wakefulness, light, deep and REM sleep. The journal included questions about factors known to affect sleep such as stress, caffeine, academic activity, exercise and alcohol. A class data set was compiled and used by students to perform univariate correlations examining the relationships between ZEO&#xae; variables and sleep journal variables. The data set allowed students to choose specific variables to investigate, analyze and write a peer-reviewed style manuscript. Significant class-wide correlations were found between specific sleep stages and behavioral variables suggesting that the ZEO&#xae; system is sophisticated yet inexpensive enough to be used as an effective tool in the classroom setting. Overall student feedback on the exercise was positive with many students indicating that it significantly enhanced their understanding of sleep architecture and made them keenly aware of the factors that affect quality of sleep.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>Jillian C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Behavioral Neuroscience Program, Connecticut College, New London, CT 06320.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malerba</LastName><ForeName>Julie R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schroeder</LastName><ForeName>Joseph A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Undergrad Neurosci Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101229224</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1544-2896</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alcohol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bedtime stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">daily stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electroencephalogram (EEG)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep architecture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep latency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep quality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23626495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3598179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jean-Louis G, von Gizycki H, Zizi F, Nunes J. Mood states and sleepiness in college students: influences of age, sex, habitual sleep, and substance use. Percept Mot Skills. 1998;87:507&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landolt HP, Re&#x2019;tey JV, T&#xf6;nz K, Gotteslig JM, Khatami R, Buckelm&#xfc;ller I, Achermann P. Caffeine attenuates waking and sleep electroencephalographic markers of sleep homeostasis in humans. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2004;29:1933&#x2013;1939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15257305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund HG, Reider BD, Whiting AB, Prichard JR. Sleep patterns and predictors of disturbed sleep in a large population of college students. J Adolesc Health. 2010;46:124&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20113918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilcher JJ, Walters AS. How sleep deprivation affects psychological variables related to college students&#x2019; cognitive performance. J Am Coll Health. 1997;46:121&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9394089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trockel MD, Barnes MD, Egget DS. Health-related variables and academic performance among first-year college students: implications for sleep and other behaviors. J Am Coll Health. 2000;49:125&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11125640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsui YY, Wing YK. A study on the sleep patterns and problems of university business students in Hong Kong. J Am Coll Health. 2009;58:167&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19892654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeo Inc   (n.d.) What is Zeo? Retrieved April 17, 2011, from  http://whatiszeo3.myzeo.com/hp/3/whatiszeo.php.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>