<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">29210957</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiological and Performance Effects of Caffeine Gum Consumed During a Simulated Half-Time by Professional Academy Rugby Union Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>145</StartPage><EndPage>151</EndPage><MedlinePgn>145-151</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002185</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Russell, M, Reynolds, NA, Crewther, BT, Cook, CJ, and Kilduff, L. Physiological and performance effects of caffeine gum consumed during a simulated half-time by professional academy rugby union players. J Strength Cond Res 34(1): 145-151, 2020-Despite the prevalence of caffeine (CAF) as an ergogenic aid, few studies have examined the use of caffeinated gums, especially during half-time in team sports. The physiological (blood lactate and salivary hormone concentrations) and performance (repeated sprints and cognitive function) effects of consuming CAF gum during a simulated half-time were examined. Professional academy rugby union players (n = 14) completed this double-blind, randomized, counterbalanced study. After pre-exercise measurements, players chewed a placebo (PLC) gum for 5 minutes before a standardized warm-up and completing repeated sprint testing (RSSA1). Thereafter, during a 15-minute simulated half-time period, players chewed either CAF (400 mg; 4.1 &#xb1; 0.5 mg&#xb7;kg) or PLC gum for 5 minutes before completing a second repeated sprint test (RSSA2). Blood lactate, salivary testosterone and cortisol concentrations, and indices of cognitive function (i.e., reaction time and Stroop test) were measured at baseline, pre-RSSA1, post-RSSA1, pre-RSSA2, and post-RSSA2. Sprint performance was not affected by CAF (p = 0.995) despite slower sprint times after the first sprint of both RSSA tests (all p &lt; 0.002). After half-time, salivary testosterone increased by 70% (+97 &#xb1; 58 pg&#xb7;ml) in CAF vs. PLC (p &lt; 0.001), whereas salivary cortisol remained unchanged (p = 0.307). Cognitive performance was unaffected by time and trial (all p &gt; 0.05). Although performance effects were absent, chewing CAF gum increased the salivary testosterone concentrations of professional rugby union players over a simulated half-time. Practitioners may, therefore, choose to recommend CAF gum between successive exercise bouts because of the increases in salivary testosterone observed; a variable associated with increased motivation and high-intensity exercise performance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russell</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Social and Health Sciences, Leeds Trinity University, Leeds, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reynolds</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Sports Technology Exercise and Medicine Research Center (A-STEM), Swansea University, Swansea, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crewther</LastName><ForeName>Blair T</ForeName><Initials>BT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport-National Research Institute, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cook</LastName><ForeName>Christian J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Health and Exercise Sciences, Bangor University, Bangor, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kilduff</LastName><ForeName>Liam P</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Sports Technology Exercise and Medicine Research Center (A-STEM), Swansea University, Swansea, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Welsh Institute of Performance Sciences (WIPS), Swansea University, Swansea, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002638">Chewing Gum</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XMK78S47O</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013739">Testosterone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WI4X0X7BPJ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006854">Hydrocortisone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002638" MajorTopicYN="N">Chewing Gum</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="N">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006854" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrocortisone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="N">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="N">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012463" MajorTopicYN="N">Saliva</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013739" MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063996" MajorTopicYN="N">Warm-Up Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29210957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202001000-00017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beaven CM, Hopkins WG, Hansen KT, Wood MR, Cronin JB, Lowe TE. Dose effect of caffeine on testosterone and cortisol responses to resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 18: 131&#x2013;141, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Crewther BT. Changes in salivary testosterone concentrations and subsequent voluntary squat performance following the presentation of short video clips. Horm Behav 61: 17&#x2013;22, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Crewther BT, Kilduff L. Are free testosterone and cortisol concentrations associated with training motivation in elite athletes? Psychol Sport Ex 14: 882&#x2013;885, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousineau D, Chartier S. Outlier detection and treatment: A review. Int J Psychol Res 3: 58&#x2013;67, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther BT, Cook CJ, Gaviglio CM, Kilduff LP, Drawer S. Baseline strength can influence the ability of salivary free testosterone to predict squat and sprinting performance. J Strength Cond Res 26: 261&#x2013;268, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowe MJ, Leicht AS, Spinks WL. Physiological and cognitive responses to caffeine during repeated, high-intensity exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 16: 528&#x2013;544, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JK, Green JM. Caffeine and anaerobic performance: Ergogenic value and mechanisms of action. Sports Med 39: 813&#x2013;832, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Ramirez JA, Munoz G, Portillo J, Gonzalez-Millan C, Munoz V, Barbero-Alvarez JC, Munoz-Guerra J. Caffeine-containing energy drink improves physical performance of elite rugby players during a simulated match. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 38: 368&#x2013;374, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutsch MU, Kearney GA, Rehrer NJ. Time&#x2013;motion analysis of professional rugby union players during match-play. J Sports Sci 25: 461&#x2013;472, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duthie G, Pyne D, Hooper S. Applied physiology and game analysis of rugby union. Sports Med 33: 973&#x2013;991, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaviglio CM, Crewther BT, Kilduff LP, Stokes KA, Cook CJ. Relationship between pregame concentrations of free testosterone and outcome in rugby union. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 9: 324&#x2013;331, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Howatson G, Abraham CS, Lockey RA, Goodwin JE, Foley P, McInnes G. Caffeine supplementation and multiple sprint running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 40: 1835&#x2013;1840, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Rampinini E, Castagna C, Bishop D, Ferrari Bravo D, Tibaudi A, Wisloff U. Validity of a repeated-sprint test for football. Int J Sports Med 29: 899&#x2013;905, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar JM. The influence of caffeine on voluntary muscle activation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 2113&#x2013;2119, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamimori GH, Karyekar CS, Otterstetter R, Cox DS, Balkin TJ, Belenky GL, Eddington ND. The rate of absorption and relative bioavailability of caffeine administered in chewing gum versus capsules to normal healthy volunteers. Int J Pharm 234: 159&#x2013;167, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med 35: 339&#x2013;361, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell R, Barrett S, Portas M, Weston M. Re-examination of the post half-time reduction in soccer work-rate. J Sci Med Sport 16: 250&#x2013;254, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Kavouras SA. Caffeine use in sports, pharmacokinetics in man, and cellular mechanisms of action. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 45: 535&#x2013;562, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Nielsen JJ, Bangsbo J. Caffeine intake improves intense intermittent exercise performance and reduces muscle interstitial potassium accumulation. J Appl Physiol (1985) 111: 1372&#x2013;1379, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton CD, Hopkins WG, Vollebregt L. Little effect of caffeine ingestion on repeated sprints in team-sport athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 822&#x2013;825, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton CD, Lowe T, Irvine A. Caffeinated chewing gum increases repeated sprint performance and augments increases in testosterone in competitive cyclists. Eur J Appl Physiol 110: 1243&#x2013;1250, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell M, West DJ, Briggs MA, Bracken RM, Cook CJ, Giroud T, Gill N, Kilduff LP. A passive heat maintenance strategy implemented during a simulated half-time improves lower body power output and repeated sprint ability in professional Rugby Union players. PLoS One 10: e0119374, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell M, West DJ, Harper LD, Cook CJ, Kilduff LP. Half-time strategies to enhance second-half performance in team-sports players: A review and recommendations. Sports Med 45: 353&#x2013;364, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan EJ, Kim CH, Fickes EJ, Williamson M, Muller MD, Barkley JE, Gunstad J, Glickman EL. Caffeine gum and cycling performance: A timing study. J Strength Cond Res 27: 259&#x2013;264, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt JA, Benton D, Kallus KW. General methodological considerations for the assessment of nutritional influences on human cognitive functions. Eur J Nutr 44: 459&#x2013;464, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvage DJ, Lee SY, Parsons LH, Seo DO, Rivier CL. A hypothalamic-testicular neural pathway is influenced by brain catecholamines, but not testicular blood flow. Endocrinology 145: 1750&#x2013;1759, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart D, Hopkins WG, Quarrie KL, Gill N. The relationship between physical fitness and game behaviours in rugby union players. Eur J Sport Sci 1(14 Suppl): S8&#x2013;S17, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spratt DI, O'Dea LS, Schoenfeld D, Butler J, Rao PN, Crowley WF Jr. Neuroendocrine-gonadal axis in men: Frequent sampling of LH, FSH, and testosterone. Am J Physiol 254: E658&#x2013;E666, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart GR, Hopkins WG, Cook C, Cairns SP. Multiple effects of caffeine on simulated high-intensity team-sport performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 1998&#x2013;2005, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Towlson C, Midgley AW, Lovell R. Warm-up strategies of professional soccer players: Practitioners' perspectives. J Sports Sci 31: 1393&#x2013;1401, 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>