<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32148617</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neither a Multi-Ingredient Pre-Workout Supplement nor Caffeine Were Effective at Improving Markers of Blood Flow or Upper-Body Resistance Exercise Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>167</StartPage><EndPage>182</EndPage><MedlinePgn>167-182</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Few studies have measured the effects of multi-ingredient pre-workout supplements on blood flow or heart rate variability or have compared a multi-ingredient pre-workout supplement to a matched single ingredient. This study examined the effects of a multi-ingredient pre-workout supplement, an equivalent amount of caffeine, and placebo on markers of resistance training performance, blood flow, blood pressure, and heart rate variability. The study utilized a randomized, placebo-controlled, repeated-measures, crossover design. Twelve resistance-trained males (22.75 &#xb1; 4.51 yrs; 183.4 &#xb1; 7.37 cm; 91.05 &#xb1; 17.77 kg) completed the study. Resistance exercise performance was defined as total work performed during elbow flexion and extension on an isokinetic dynamometer. Blood flow was calculated using time-averaged mean velocity and blood vessel diameter of the right brachial artery, which were measured via Doppler ultrasound. Heart rate was recorded using an electrocardiogram. Neither a multi-ingredient pre-workout supplement nor caffeine alone improved upper-body resistance exercise performance or markers of blood flow relative to placebo. No differences in heart rate variability were observed across treatments. A multi-ingredient pre-workout supplement was not effective at improving performance or blood flow and did not alter autonomic nervous system function.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blake</LastName><ForeName>Michael S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle, Metabolism, and Ergogenics Workgroup, Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Nathaniel R</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle, Metabolism, and Ergogenics Workgroup, Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trautman</LastName><ForeName>Kara A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle, Metabolism, and Ergogenics Workgroup, Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grier</LastName><ForeName>James W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stastny</LastName><ForeName>Sherri N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle, Metabolism, and Ergogenics Workgroup, Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackney</LastName><ForeName>Kyle J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle, Metabolism, and Ergogenics Workgroup, Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Sciences, North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">L-arginine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nitrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vasodilation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32148617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/PHUM1873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anselme F, Collomp K, Mercier B, Ahmaidi S, Prefaut C. Caffeine increases maximal anaerobic power and blood lactate concentration. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1992;65(2):188&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1396643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Roberson DW. Efficacy of acute caffeine ingestion for short-term high-intensity exercise performance: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(1):257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19924012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Terzi MN, Roberson DW, Burnett TR. Effect of two doses of caffeine on muscular function during isokinetic exercise. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2010;42(12):2205&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20421833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey SJ, Fulford J, Vanhatalo A, Winyard PG, Blackwell JR, DiMenna FJ, et al. Dietary nitrate supplementation enhances muscle contractile efficiency during knee-extensor exercise in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(1):135&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20466802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey SJ, Winyard P, Vanhatalo A, Blackwell JR, DiMenna FJ, Wilkerson DP, et al. Dietary nitrate supplementation reduces the O2 cost of low-intensity exercise and enhances tolerance to high-intensity exercise in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(4):1144&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey SJ, Winyard PG, Vanhatalo A, Blackwell JR, DiMenna FJ, Wilkerson DP, et al. Acute l-arginine supplementation reduces the O2 cost of moderate-intensity exercise and enhances high-intensity exercise tolerance. J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(5):1394&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20724562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstrom HC, Byrd MT, Wallace BJ, Clasey JL. Examination of a multi-ingredient pre-workout supplement on total volume of resistance exercise and subsequent strength and power performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(6):1479&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29401192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besc&#xf3;s R, Sureda A, Tur JA, Pons A. The effect of nitric-oxide-related supplements on human performance. Sport Med. 2012;42(2):99&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22260513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco P. Volumetric blood flow measurement using Doppler ultrasound: Concerns about the technique. J Ultrasound. 2015;18:201&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4504867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26191112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer RJ, Farney TM, Trepanowski JF, McCarthy CG, Canale RE, Schilling BK. Comparison of pre-workout nitric oxide stimulating dietary supplements on skeletal muscle oxygen saturation, blood nitrate/nitrite, lipid peroxidation, and upper body exercise performance in resistance trained men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7(16):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;n&#xf6;czk P, Guly&#xe1;s B, Adam-Vizi V, Nemes A, K&#xe1;rp&#xe1;ti E, Kiss B, et al. Role of sodium channel inhibition in neuroprotection: Effect of vinpocetine. Brain Res Bull. 2000;53(3):245&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11113577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford BN, Koch AJ. Glycine-arginine-ketoisocaproic acid improves performance of repeated cycling sprints. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2004;36(4):583&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron M, Camic CL, Doberstein S, Erickson JL, Jagim AR. The acute effects of a multi-ingredient pre-workout supplement on resting energy expenditure and exercise performance in recreationally active females. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5755346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29311763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camic CL, Housh TJ, Mielke M, Zuniga JM, Hendrix CR, Johnson GO, et al. The effects of 4 weeks of an arginine-based supplement on the gas exchange threshold and peak oxygen uptake. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2010;35(3):286&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20555372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camic CL, Housh TJ, Zuniga JM, Hendrix RC, Mielke M, Johnson GO, et al. Effects of arginine-based supplements on the physical working capacity at the fatigue threshold. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(5):1306&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MJ, Fan X, Moe ST. Criterion-related validity of the Borg ratings of perceived exertion scale in healthy individuals: A meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2002;20(11):873&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12430990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipryan L, Laursen PB, Plews DJ. Cardiac autonomic response following high-intensity running work-to-rest interval manipulation. Eur J Sport Sci. 2015;16(7):808&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26523343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins P, Earnest C, Dalton R, Sowinski R, Grubic T, Favot C, et al. Short-term effects of a ready-to-drink pre-workout beverage on exercise performance and recovery. Nutrients. 2017;9(823):1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5579616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28763003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collomp K, Ahmaidi S, Audran M, Chanal J-L, Pr&#xe9;faut C. Effects of caffeine ingestion on performance and anaerobic metabolism during the Wingate Test. Int J Sports Med. 1991;12(5):439&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1752708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels JW, Mol&#xe9; PA, Shaffrath JD, Stebbins CL. Effects of caffeine on blood pressure, heart rate, and forearm blood flow during dynamic leg exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85(1):154&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9655769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeGiorgio CM, Miller P, Meymandi S, Chin A, Epps J, Gordon S, et al. RMSSD, a measure of vagus-mediated heart rate variability, is associated with risk factors for SUDEP: The SUDEP-7 Inventory. Epilepsy Behav. 2010;19:78&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2943000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20667792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sport. 2005;15:69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15773860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM, Hughes MGRc, Davison R, Davison RCR. Caffeine lowers perceptual response and increases power output during high-intensity cycling. J Sports Sci. 2004;22(7):637&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15370494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draghici AE, Taylor JA. The physiological basis and measurement of heart rate variability in humans. J Physiol Anthropol. 2016;35(22):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5039876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27680542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson J, Jagim A, Wright G, Foster C, Camic C. Effects of a thermogenic pre-workout supplement on fat oxidation rates during moderate-intensity running in females. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2018;50(5S):596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flatt AA, Esco MR, Nakamura FY, Plews DJ. Interpreting daily heart rate variability changes in collegiate female soccer players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2017;57(6):907&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26997322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fricke O, Baecker N, Heer M, Tutlewski B, Schoenau E. The effect of l-arginine administration on muscle force and power in postmenopausal women. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2008;28(5):307&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18510549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnon BJ. Effect of caffeine and a pre-workout supplement on heart rate variability before and after exercise. North Dakota State University; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Pattison JR, Muniz-Pumares D, Patterson SD, Foley P. Effects of dietary nitrate, caffeine, and their combination on 20-km cycling time trial performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(1):165&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24978834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein ER, Ziegenfuss T, Kalman D, Kreider R, Campbell B, Wilborn C, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: Caffeine and performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7(5):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Walsh AL, Ratamess NA, Kang J, Hoffman JR. Effect of a pre-workout energy supplement on acute multi-joint resistance exercise. J Sports Sci Med. 2011;10:261&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Caffeine, coffee and ephedrine: Impact on exercise performance and metabolism. Can J Appl Physiol. 2001;26(S1):S186&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11897887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn CJ, Jagim AR, Camic CL, Andre MJ. Acute effects of a caffeine-containing supplement on anaerobic power and subjective measurements of fatigue in recreationally active men. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(4):1029&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29337831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris BF, Winn C, Ableman TB. Hemorrhagic stroke in a young healthy male following use of pre-workout supplement Animal Rage XL. Mil Med. 2017;182(9):e2030&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28885973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RA, Nishiyama SK, Wray DW, Richardson RS. Tutorial ultrasound assessment of flow-mediated dilation. Hypertension. 2010;55:1075&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2878744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20351340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harty PS, Zabriskie HA, Erickson JL, Molling PE, Kerksick CM, Jagim AR. Multi-ingredient pre-workout supplements, safety implications, and performance outcomes: A brief review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15(41):1&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6083567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30089501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Kang J, Ratamess NA, Hoffman MW, Tranchina CP, Faigenbaum AD. Examination of a pre-exercise, high energy supplement on exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6(2):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2621122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Gonzalez A, Beller NA, Hoffman MW, Olson M, et al. The effects of acute and prolonged CRAM supplementation on reaction time and subjective measures of focus and alertness in healthy college students. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7(39):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3009695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21156078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Ross R, Shanklin M, Kang J, Faigenbaum AD. Effect of a pre-exercise energy supplement on the acute hormonal response to resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(3):874&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoon MW, Johnson NA, Chapman PG, Burke LM. The effect of nitrate supplementation on exercise performance in healthy individuals: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013;23(5):522&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23580439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hord NG, Tang Y, Bryan NS. Food sources of nitrates and nitrites: The physiologic context for potential health benefits. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;90(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang P, Willoughby DS. Intracellular mechanistic role of nitric oxide: A comparative analysis of the effectiveness of l-arginine and l-citrulline supplementation on nitric oxide synthesis and subsequent exercise performance in humans. Int J Food Nutr Sci. 2015;2(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs PL. The acute effects of a commercial pre workout product, wodFuel&#xae;, on performance of a Crossfit exercise series, the Cindy. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014;11(S1):P21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson BH, Kulling FA. Health and ergogenic effects of caffeine. Br J Sports Med. 1989;23(1):34&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1478653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2659130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Jones MT, Wright GA, StAntoine C, Kovacs A, Oliver JM. The acute effects of multi-ingredient pre-workout ingestion on strength performance, lower body power, and anaerobic capacity. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2016;13(11):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4784458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26962303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung YP, Earnest CP, Koozehchian M, Galvan E, Dalton R, Walker D, et al. Effects of acute ingestion of a pre-workout dietary supplement with and without p-synephrine on resting energy expenditure, cognitive function and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14(3):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5234109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28096758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kedia AW, Hofheins JE, Habowski SM, Ferrando AA, Gothard MD, Lopez HL. Effects of a pre-workout supplement on lean mass, muscular performance, subjective workout experience and biomarkers of safety. Int J Med Sci. 2014;11(2):116&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3894395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24465156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig J, Jarczok MN, Karl T, Srh H, Heidelberg H, Thayer JF, et al. Impact of caffeine on heart rate variability: A systematic review. J Caffeine Res. 2013;3(1):1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laborde S, Mosley E, Thayer JF. Heart rate variability and cardiac vagal tone in psychophysiological research &#x2013; recommendations for experiment planning, data analysis, and data reporting. Front Psychol. 2017;8(213):1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5316555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28265249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane M, Byrd M, Lane MT, Byrd MT. Effects of pre-workout supplements on power maintenance in lower body and upper body tasks. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2018;3(11):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansley KE, Winyard PG, Bailey SJ, Vanhatalo A, Wilkerson DP, Blackwell JR, et al. Acute dietary nitrate supplementation improves cycling time trial performance. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2011;43(6):1125&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21471821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansley KE, Winyard PG, Fulford J, Vanhatalo A, Bailey SJ, Blackwell JR, et al. Dietary nitrate supplementation reduces the O2 cost of walking and running: A placebo-controlled study. J Appl Physiol. 2011;110(3):591&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21071588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu V, Huang P. Cardiovascular roles of nitric oxide: A review of insights from nitric oxide synthase gene disrupted mice. Cardiovasc Res. 2007;77(1):19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17658499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg JO, Weitzberg E, Cole JA, Benjamin N. Nitrate, bacteria and human health. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2004;2(7):593&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15197394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magrini MA, Colquhoun RJ, Dawes JJ, Smith DB. Effects of a pre-workout energy drink supplement on upper body muscular endurance performance. Int J Exerc Sci. 2016;9(5):667&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5154715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27990227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez N, Campbell B, Franek M, Buchanan L, Colquhoun R. The effect of acute pre-workout supplementation on power and strength performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2016;13(29):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4947244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27429596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, Enette Larson-Meyer D, Peeling P, Phillips SM, et al. IOC consensus statement: Dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28:104&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29589768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modi A, Morou-Bermudez E, Vergara J, Patel RP, Nichols A, Joshipura K. Validation of two point-of-care tests against standard lab measures of NO in saliva and in serum. Nitric Oxide. 2017;64:16&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5569892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical issues relating to scientific discovery in exercise science. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson MT, Biltz GR, Dengel DR. Cardiovascular and ride time-to-exhaustion effects of an energy drink. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014;11(2):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24447726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outlaw JJ, Wilborn CD, Smith-Ryan AE, Hayward SE, Urbina SL, Taylor LW, et al. Acute effects of a commercially available pre-workout supplement on markers of training: A double-blind study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014;11(40):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4190923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25302053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Hoffman JR, Ross R, Shanklin M, Faigenbaum AD, Kang J. Effects of an amino acid/creatine energy supplement on the acute hormonal response to resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(6):608&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18156665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbloom C. Energy drinks, caffeine, and athletes. Nutr Today. 2014;49(2):49&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer F, Ginsberg JP. An overview of heart rate variability metrics and norms. Front Public Heal. 2017;5(258):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5624990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29034226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spradley BD, Crowley KR, Tai C-Y, Kendall KL, Fukuda DH, Esposito EN, et al. Ingesting a pre-workout supplement containing caffeine, B-vitamins, amino acids, creatine, and beta-alanine before exercise delays fatigue while improving reaction time and muscular endurance. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2012;9:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3361498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22463603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thayer JF, Yamamoto SS, Brosschot JF. The relationship of autonomic imbalance, heart rate variability and cardiovascular disease risk factors. Int J Cardiol. 2010;141(2):122&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Hamm MA, Hurtado AK, Cross AG, Pineda JG, Martin AY, et al. Effects of two pre-workout supplements on concentric and eccentric force production during lower body resistance exercise in males and females: A counterbalanced, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14(46):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5704438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29209154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uehata A, Lieberman EH, Gerhard MD, Anderson TJ, Ganz P, Polak JF, et al. Noninvasive assessment of endothelium-dependent flow-mediated dilation of the brachial artery. Vasc Med. 1997;2(2):87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9546961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh AL, Gonzalez AM, Ratamess NA, Kang J, Hoffman JR. Improved time to exhaustion following ingestion of the energy drink Amino Impact&#x2122;. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7(14):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2861014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20398312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young C, Oladipo O, Frasier S, Putko R, Chronister S, Marovich M. Hemorrhagic Stroke in young healthy male following use of sports supplement Jack3d. Mil Med. 2012;177(12):1450&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23397687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>