<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34168694</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>77</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Nutritional Supplements on Judo-Related Performance: A Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>81</StartPage><EndPage>96</EndPage><MedlinePgn>81-96</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2021-0013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The potential ergogenic effect of nutritional supplements depends on their dosage and the type of exercise executed. Aiming at reviewing the research literature regarding sport supplements utilized in judo in order to improve performance, a literature search was performed at the following databases: Dialnet, PubMed, Scielo, Scopus and SportDiscus. A total of 11 articles met the inclusion criteria and were selected. Evidence revised indicates that supplementation with caffeine, &#x3b2;-alanine, sodium bicarbonate, creatine, and &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate has a positive effect on judo-related performance. Moreover, there is evidence suggesting that combining some of these nutritional supplements may produce an additive effect.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Leonardo Simoncini, &#xc1;ngel Lago-Rodr&#xed;guez, &#xc1;lvaro L&#xf3;pez-Samanes, Alberto P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez, Ra&#xfa;l Dom&#xed;nguez, published by Sciendo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simoncini</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Alfonso X El Sabio University. Madrid. Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lago-Rodr&#xed;guez</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;ngel</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Facultad de Ciencias de la Salud de la Universidad Isabel I. www.ui1.es. Burgos. Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf3;pez-Samanes</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;lvaro</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physiotherapy, Faculty of Health Sciences, Francisco de Vitoria University. Madrid. Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences. Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences. University of Alcal&#xe1;. Madrid. Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dom&#xed;nguez</LastName><ForeName>Ra&#xfa;l</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Escuela Universitaria de Osuna (Centro adscrito a la Universidad de Sevilla) Osuna, Sevilla. Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Educaci&#xf3;n F&#xed;sica y Deporte, Universidad de Sevilla. Sevilla. Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Studies Research Group in Neuromuscular Responses (GEPREN), University of Lavras Lavras. Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combat sports performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ergogenic supplementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport nutrition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2021-0013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2021-0013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abo-Salem OM.. Antinociceptive Effects of Novel A2B Adenosine Receptor Antagonists. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2003;308(1):358&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14563788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli GG, Gualano B, Coelho DF, Benatti FB, Gailey AW, Lancha AH. Does sodium-bicarbonate ingestion improve simulated judo performance? Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(2):206&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli GG, Gualano B, Franchini E, Scagliusi FB, Takesian M, Fuchs M, Lancha AH. Prevalence, magnitude, and methods of rapid weight loss among judo competitors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010a;42(3):436&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli GG, Iglesias RT, Franchini E, Gualano B, Kashiwagura DB, Solis MY, Benatti FB, Fuchs M, Junior AHL. Rapid weight loss followed by recovery time does not affect judo-related performance. J Sports Sci. 2010b;28(1):21&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20035492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astley C, Souza D, Polito M. Acute Caffeine Ingestion on Performance in Young Judo Athletes. Ped Exerc Sci. 2017;29(3):336&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28050917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaven CM, Hopkins WG, Hansen KT, Wood MR, Cronin JB, Lowe TE. Dose effect of caffeine on testosterone and cortisol responses to resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18(2):131&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18458357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begum G, Cunliffe A, Leveritt M. Physiological role of carnosine in contracting muscle. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2005;15(5):493&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16327029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blancquaert L, Everaert I, Missinne M, Baguet A, Stegen S, Volkaert A, Petrovic M, Vervaet C, Achten E, De Maeyer M, De Henauw S, Derave W.. Effects of Histidine and &#x3b2;-alanine Supplementation on Human Muscle Carnosine Storage. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(3):602&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28106620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldyrev AA. Carnosine: New concept for the function of an old molecule. Biochemistry (Mosc.) 2012;77(4):313&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22809149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM. Practical Issues in Evidence-Based Use of Performance Supplements: Supplement Interactions, Repeated Use and Individual Responses. Sports Med. 2017;47(Suppl 1):79&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5371635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso J, Charles J, Unruh K, Giebel R, Learmonth L, Potter W. Ergogenic effects of &#x3b2;-alanine and carnosine: Proposed future research to quantify their efficacy. Nutrients. 2012;4(7):585&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22852051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casals C, Huertas JR, Franchini E, Sterkowicz-Przybycie&#x144; K, Sterkowicz S, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Garc&#xed;a C, Escobar-Molina R.. Special judo fitness test level and anthropometric profile of elite Spanish Judo athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(5):1229&#x2013;1235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck P, Kaviani M, Candow D, Zello GA. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Open Access J Sports Med. 2017;8:213&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper R, Naclerio F, Allgrove J, Jimenez A. Creatine supplementation with specific view to exercise/sports performance: An update. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22817979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JK, Green JM. Caffeine and anaerobic performance: Ergogenic value and mechanisms of action. Sports Med. 2009;39(10):813&#x2013;832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19757860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Andrade Kratz C, de Salles Painelli V, de Andrade Nemezio KM, da Silva RP, Franchini E, Zagatto AM, Gualano B, Artioli GG.. Beta-alanine supplementation enhances judo-related performance in highly-trained athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(4):403&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27601217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Salinero JJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mill&#xe1;n C, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J, P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez B.. Dose response effects of a caffeine-containing energy drink on muscle performance: A repeated measures design. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3461468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22569090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2005;15(2):69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15773860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez R, Lougedo JH, Mat&#xe9;-Mu&#xf1;oz JL, Garnacho-Casta&#xf1;o MV.. Effects of &#xdf;-alanine supplementation on athletic performance. Nutr Hosp. 2015;31(1):155&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25561107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douroudos II, Fatouros IG, Gourgoulis V, Jamurtas AZ, Tsitsios T, Hatzinikolaou A, Margonis K, Mavromatidis K, Taxildaris K. Dose-related effects of prolonged NaHCO3 ingestion during high-intensity exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(10):1746&#x2013;1753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17019296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Jeszka J.. The efficacy of a &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate supplementation on physical capacity, body composition and biochemical markers in elite rowers: A randomised, double-blind, placebocontrolled crossover study. J Int Soci Sports Nutr. 2015;12(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4518594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26225130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Jeszka J, Podg&#xf3;rski T.. The effect of a 12-week beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) supplementation on highly-trained combat sports athletes: A randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled crossover study. Nutrients. 2017;9(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28708126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durkalec-Michalski K, Podg&#xf3;rski T, Soko&#x142;owski M, Jeszka J.. Relationship between body composition indicators and physical capacity of the combat sports athletes. Arch Budo. 2016;12:247&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutka TL, Lamb GD. Effect of carnosine on excitation-contraction coupling in mechanically-skinned rat skeletal muscle. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 2004;25(3):203&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15467383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eley HL, Russell ST, Tisdale MJ. Attenuation of depression of muscle protein synthesis induced by lipopolysaccharide, tumor necrosis factor, and angiotensin II by &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate. AJP Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295(6):1409&#x2013;1416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18854427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabiato A, Fabiato F. Effects of pH on the myofilaments and the sarcoplasmic reticulum of skinned cells from cardiace and skeletal muscles. J Physiol. 1978;276:233&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1282422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felippe LC, Lopes-Silva JP, Bertuzzi R, McGinley C, Lima-Silva AE. Separate and combined effects of caffeine and sodium-bicarbonate intake on judo performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(2):221&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26182440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foskett A, Ali A, Gant N. Caffeine enhances cognitive function and skill performance during simulated soccer activity. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19(4):410&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19827465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchini E, Artioli GG, Brito CJ. Judo combat: Time-motion analysis and physiology. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2013;13(3):624&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchini E, Brito CJ, Fukuda DH, Artioli GG. The physiology of judo-specific training modalities. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(5):1474&#x2013;1481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchini E, Del Vecchio FB, Matsushigue KA, Artioli GG.. Physiological profiles of elite judo athletes. Sports Med. 2011;41(2):147&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21244106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredholm BB, Abbracchio MP, Burnstock G, Daly JW, Harden TK, Jacobson KA, Leff P, Williams M. Nomenclature and classification of purinoceptors. Pharmacol Rev. 1994;46(2):143&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4976594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7938164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein E, Jacobs PL, Whitehurst M, Penhollow T, Antonio J. Caffeine enhances upper body strength in resistance-trained women. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20470411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granier PL, Dubouchaud H, Mercier BM, Mercier JG, Ahmaidi S, Pr&#xe9;faut CG. Effect of NaHCO3on lactate kinetics in forearm muscles during leg exercise in man. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28(6):692&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8784757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Tallon MJ, Dunnett M, Boobis L, Coakley J, Kim HJ, Fallowfield JL, Hill CA, Sale C, Wise JA. The absorption of orally supplied &#x3b2;-alanine and its effect on muscle carnosine synthesis in human vastus lateralis. Amino Acids. 2006;30(3):279&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16554972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SH, Johnson K, Pipe AL. The use of dietary supplements and medications by Canadian athletes at the Atlanta and Sydney olympic games. Clin J Sport Med. 2006;16(1):27&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16377972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung W, Liu TH, Chen CY, Chang CK. Effect of &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate Supplementation During Energy Restriction in Female Judo Athletes. J Exerc Sci Fitness. 2010;8(1):50&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmar JM. The influence of caffeine on voluntary muscle activation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;37(12):2113&#x2013;2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16331138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Cho HC, Jung HS, Yoon JD. Influence of performance level on anaerobic power and body composition in elite male Judoists. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(5):1346&#x2013;1354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20975602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornasio R, Riederer I, Butler-Browne G, Mouly V, Uni Z, Halevy O. &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (HMB) stimulates myogenic cell proliferation, differentiation and survival via the MAPK/ERK and PI3K/Akt pathways. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2009;1793(5):755&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19211028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, Ziegenfuss TN, Wildman R, Collins R, Candow DG, Kleiner SM, Almada AL, Lopez HL. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: Safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14(1):18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancha Junior AH, de Salles Painelli V, Saunders B, Artioli GG.. Nutritional Strategies to Modulate Intracellular and Extracellular Buffering Capacity During High-Intensity Exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45:71&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4672007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latini S, Pedata F. Adenosine in the central nervous system: Release mechanisms and extracellular concentrations. J Neurochem. 2001;79(3):463&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11701750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes-Silva JP, Felippe LJC, Silva-Cavalcante MD, Bertuzzi R, Lima-Silva AE.. Caffeine ingestion after rapid weight loss in judo athletes reduces perceived effort and increases plasma lactate concentration without improving performance. Nutrients. 2014;6(7):2931&#x2013;2945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25054553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Gonz&#xe1;lez LM, S&#xe1;nchez-Oliver AJ, Mata F, Jodra P, Antonio J, Dom&#xed;nguez R.. Acute caffeine supplementation in combat sports: a systematic review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15(1):60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6310931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30594211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Grueso R, Aracil A, Sarabia JM, Montero C.. Beta-alanine supplementation seems to increase physical performance and acute recovery in competitive judokas. Eur J Hum Movement. 2014;33:123&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Samanes A, Moreno-Perez D, Mate-Munoz JL, Dominguez R, Pallares JG, Mora-Rodriguez R, Ortega JF.. Circadian rhythm effect on physical tennis performance in trained male players. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(21):2121&#x2013;2128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mat&#xe9;-Mu&#xf1;oz JL, Lougedo JH, Barba M, Garcia-Fernandez P, Garnacho-Castano MV, Dominguez R.. Muscular fatigue in response to different modalities of CrossFit sessions. PLoS One. 2017;12(7):e0181855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5533437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28753624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, Larson-Meyer DE, Peeling P, Phillips SM, Rawson ES, Walsh NP, Garthe I, Geyer H, Meeusen R, Van Loon L, Shirreffes SM, Spriet LL, Stuart M, Vernec A, Currell K, Ali VM, Budgett RGM, Ljunqvist A, Mountjoy M, Pitsiladis Y, Soligard T, Erdener U, Engebretsen L.. IOC consensus statement: Dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28(2):104&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29589768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan TM, Caldwell JA, Lieberman HR.. A review of caffeine&#x2019;s effects on cognitive, physical and occupational performance. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2016;71:294&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27612937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Nielsen JJ, Bangsbo J.. Caffeine intake improves intense intermittent exercise performance and reduces muscle interstitial potassium accumulation. J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(5):1372&#x2013;1379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21836046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Rodriguez R, Garcia Pallares J, Lopez-Samanes A, Ortega JF, Fernandez-Elias VE.. Caffeine ingestion reverses the circadian rhythm effects on neuromuscular performance in highly resistance-trained men. PLoS One. 2012;7(4):e33807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3319538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22496767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallar&#xe9;s JG, Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as VE, Ortega JF, Mu&#xf1;oz G, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R.. Neuromuscular responses to incremental caffeine doses: Performance and side effects. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(11):2184&#x2013;2192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23669879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persky AM, Brazeau GA. Clinical pharmacology of the dietary supplement creatine monohydrate. Pharmacol Rev. 2001;53(2):161&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11356982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price M, Moss P. The effects of work:rest duration on physiological and perceptual responses during intermittent exercise and performance. J Sports Sci. 2007;25(14):1613&#x2013;1621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn PJ, Boldyrev AA, Formazuyk VE. Carnosine: Its properties, functions and potential therapeutic applications. Mol Aspects Med. 1992;13(5):379&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9765790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson RJ, Falkel JE, Drash AL, Metz KF, Spungen SA, LeBoeuf JR. Effect of induced alkalosis on physical work capacity during arm and leg exercise. Ergonomics. 1987;30(1):19&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3030725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruijter J, De Ruiter MB, Snel J.. The effects of caffeine on visual selective attention to color: an ERP study. Psychophysiology. 2000;37(4):427&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10934901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Elliott-Sale K, Artioli GG, Swinton PA, Dolan E, Roschel H, Sale C, Gualano B. &#x3b2;-Alanine supplementation to improve exercise capacity and performance: A systematic review and meta-Analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(8):658&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27797728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegler JC, Marshall PW, Bishop D, Shaw G, Green S. Mechanistic Insights into the Efficacy of Sodium Bicarbonate Supplementation to Improve Athletic Performance. Sports Med Open. 2016;2(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5059234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27747796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmonds MJ, Minahan CL, Sabapathy S. Caffeine improves supramaximal cycling but not the rate of anaerobic energy release. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(2):287&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20082092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith HJ, Wyke SM, Tisdale MJ. Mechanism of the attenuation of proteolysis-inducing factor stimulated protein degradation in muscle by beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate. Cancer Res. 2004;64(23):8731. &#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi M, Abedelmalek S, Chtourou H, Atheymen R, Hakim A, Sahnoun Z. Effects of morning caffeine&#x2019; ingestion on mood States, simple reaction time, and short-term maximal performance on elite judoists. Asian J Sports Med. 2012;3(3):161&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23012635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi M, Abedelmalek S, Chtourou H, Boussita A, Hakim A, Sahnoun Z. Effects of time-of-day and caffeine ingestion on mood states, simple reaction time, and short-term maximal performance in elite judoists. Biol Rhythm Res. 2013;44(6):897&#x2013;907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi M, Aloui A, Chtourou H, Aouicha HB, Atheymen R, Sahnoun Z. Caffeine ingestion does not affect afternoon muscle power and fatigue during the Wingate test in elite judo players. Biol Rhythm Res. 2015;46(2):291&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellingwerff T, Anwander H, Egger A, Buehler T, Kreis R, Decombaz J, Boesch C. Effect of two beta-alanine dosing protocols on muscle carnosine synthesis and washout. Amino Acids. 2012;42(6):2461&#x2013;2472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21847611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterkowicz S, Tyka AK, Chwastowski M, Sterkowicz-Przybycie&#x144; K, Tyka A, Klys A.. The effects of training and creatine malate supplementation during preparation period on physical capacity and special fitness in judo contestants. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3447702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22943072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swietach P, Youm JB, Saegusa N, Leem CH, Spitzer KW, Vaughan-Jones RD. Coupled Ca2+/H+ transport by cytoplasmic buffers regulates local Ca2+ and H+ ion signaling. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2013;110(22):2064&#x2013;2073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3670334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23676270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor AD, Bronks R, Bryant AL. The relationship between electromyography and work intensity revisited: a brief review with references to lacticacidosis and hyperammonia. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1997;37(7):387&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9402427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira FJ, Matias CN, Monteiro CP, Valamatos MJ, Reis JF, Batista A, Oliveira AC, Sardinha LB, Phillips SM. No effect of HMB or &#x3b1;-HICA supplementation on training-induced changes in body composition. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;27:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30588860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias G, Benatti FB, de Salles Painelli V, Roschel H, Gualano B, Sale C, Harris RC, Lancha AH Jr, Artioli GG.. Additive effects of beta-alanine and sodium bicarbonate on upper-body intermittent performance. Amino Acids. 2013;45(2):309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3714561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23595205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlin DL, Wenger HA. The relationship between aerobic fitness and recovery from high intensity intermittent exercise. Sports Med. 2001;31(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11219498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Duinen H, Lorist MM, Zijdewind I.. The effect of caffeine on cognitive task performance and motor fatigue. Psychopharmacology. 2005;180(3):539&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15723227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Kraemer WJ. Creatine Supplementation: Its Effect on Human Muscular Performance and Body Composition. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10(3):200&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Hossain T, Hill DS, Phillips BE, Crossland H, Williams J, Loughna P, Churchward-Venne TA, Breen L, Phillips SM, Etherdidge T, Rathmacher JA, Smith K, Szewczyk NJ, Atherton PJ. Effects of leucine and its metabolite &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate on human skeletal muscle protein metabolism. J Physiol. 2013;591(11):2911&#x2013;2923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23551944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>