<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31490424</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Caffeine and Citrus Aurantium on Performance During Repeated Maximal Anaerobic Exercise Bouts in Habitual Caffeine Users.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3394</StartPage><EndPage>3399</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3394-3399</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003360</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>McLester, CN, Bailey, P, Bechke, EE, Williamson, CM, McLester, JR, and Kliszczewicz, B. The effects of caffeine and Citrus aurantium on performance during repeated maximal anaerobic exercise bouts in habitual caffeine users. J Strength Cond Res 35(12): 3394-3399, 2021-The combination of caffeine (CAF) and Citrus aurantium (CA) have demonstrated the potential to improve various types of performance. To date, few studies have explored this relationship in purely anaerobic-based exercise. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to examine the influence of an acute dose of CAF + CA on peak anaerobic performance and the attenuation of power over multiple anaerobic bouts and to determine any differences in perceived effort or fatigue. Ten active men (25.1 &#xb1; 3.9 years) who habitually consumed caffeine volunteered to perform repeated anaerobic bouts on a cycle ergometer on 2 separate days, consuming either a placebo or 100 mg CAF + 100 mg CA. Significance was set at p &#x2264; 0.05 and repeated measures analysis of variance showed no main effects for peak power p = 0.520, mean power p = 0.926, minimum power p = 0.321, total work p = 0.924, time to peak power p = 0.536, or rate of fatigue p = 0.284. There was a time effect for all variables (p &#x2264; 0.05) with the exception of time to peak power (p = 0.181). There were no differences in any measures of perceived effort or fatigue between conditions (p &#x2265; 0.05), but there were time-dependent differences observed each day (p &#x2264; 0.05). Overall, an acute dosage of 100 mg CAF and 100 mg CA did not elicit any differences in anaerobic performance or in perceived measures of effort and fatigue in young males who habitually consume caffeine. Therefore, caution should be used when pairing CAF and CA for the goal of improving anaerobic performance, because no clear benefit was realized in this population at this dosage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLester</LastName><ForeName>Cherilyn N</ForeName><Initials>CN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Sport Management, Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bechke</LastName><ForeName>Emily E</ForeName><Initials>EE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williamson</LastName><ForeName>Cassie M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLester</LastName><ForeName>John R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kliszczewicz</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000693" MajorTopicYN="N">Anaerobiosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002957" MajorTopicYN="Y">Citrus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31490424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202112000-00017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ali A, O'Donnell J, Foskett A, Rutherfurd-Markwick K. The influence of caffeine ingestion on strength and power performance in female team-sport players. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 13: 1&#x2013;9, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. Preparticipation health screening. In: ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Philadelphia, PA: Wolters Kluwer Health/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkens, 2014. pp. 19&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andre TL, Green JM, Gann JJ, O'Neal EK, Coates TE. Effects of caffeine on repeated upper/lower body wingates and handgrip performance. Int J Exerc Sci 8: 243&#x2013;255, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Roberson DW. Efficacy of acute caffeine ingestion for short-term high-intensity exercise performance: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 24: 257&#x2013;265, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzucchi I, Felici F, Montini M, Figura F, Sacchetti M. Caffeine improves neuromuscular function during maximal dynamic exercise. Muscle Nerve 43: 839&#x2013;844, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc 14: 377&#x2013;381, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunsawat K, White DW, Kappus RM, Baynard T. Caffeine delays autonomic recovery following acute exercise. Eur J Prev Cardiol 22: 1473&#x2013;1479, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collomp K, Ahmaidi S, Audran M, Chanal JL, Pr&#xe9;faut C. Effects of caffeine ingestion on performance and anaerobic metabolism during the Wingate Test. Int J Sports Med 12: 439&#x2013;443, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Dalsky GP, Fink WJ. Effects of caffeine ingestion on metabolism and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports 10: 155&#x2013;158, 1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JK, Green JM. Caffeine and anaerobic performance: Ergogenic value and mechanisms of action. Sports Med 39: 813&#x2013;832, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on rating of perceived exertion during and after exercise: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 15: 69&#x2013;78, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Wharton RP, Church TS, Lucia A. Reliability of the lode excalibur sport ergometer and applicability to computrainer electromagnetically braked cycling training device. J Strength Cond Res 19: 344&#x2013;348, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frikha M, Cha&#xe2;ri N, Mezghanni N, Souissi N. Influence of warm-up duration and recovery interval prior to exercise on anaerobic performance. Biol Sport 33: 361&#x2013;366, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein ER, Ziegenfuss T, Kalman D, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: Caffeine and performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 7: 1&#x2013;15, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Battram DS, Dela F, El-Sohemy A, Thong FSL. Does caffeine alter muscle carbohydrate and fat metabolism during exercise? Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 33: 1311&#x2013;1318, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutierrez-Hellin J, Del Coso J. Acute p-synephrine ingestion increases fat oxidation rate during exercise. Br J Clin Pharmacol 82: 362&#x2013;368, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Hell&#xed;n J, Salinero JJ, Ab&#xed;an-Vicen J, et al. Acute consumption of p-synephrine does not enhance performance in sprint athletes. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 41: 63&#x2013;69, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn CJ, Jagim AR, Camic CL, Andrem MJ. Acute effects of a caffeine-containing supplement on anaerobic power and subjective measurements of fatigue in recreationally active men. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1029&#x2013;1035, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harbili S. The effect of different recovery duration on repeated anaerobic performance in elite cyclists. J Hum Kinet 49: 171&#x2013;178, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung YP, Earnest CP, Koozehchian M, et al. Effects of acute ingestion of a pre-workout dietary surpplement with and without p-synephrine on resting energy expenditure, cognitive function and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 14: 1&#x2013;15, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H, Kim H, Kim B. Acute effects of caffeine intake on maximal anaerobic power during the 30s wingate cycling test. J Exerc Physiol Online 1, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall BJ. The acute effects of static stretching compared to dynamic stretching with and without an active warm up on anaerobic performance. Int J Exerc Sci 10: 53, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killen LG, Green JM, O'Neal EK, et al. Effects of caffeine on session ratings of perceived exertion. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 721&#x2013;727, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leith&#xe4;user RM, B&#xf6;ning D, H&#xfc;tler M, Beneke R. Enhancement on wingate anaerobic test performance with hyperventilation. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 627&#x2013;634, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntosh BR, Rishaug P, Svedahl K. Assessment of peak power and short-term work capacity. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 572&#x2013;579, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone JK, Blake C, Caulfield B. Test-retest reliability of the 30-sec wingate cycle test in a trained male cohort. Isokinet Exerc Sc 22: 251&#x2013;258, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mana Salicio VM, Fett CA, Adriano Salicio M, et al. The effect of caffeine supplementation on trained individuals subjected to maximal treadmill test Afr. J Tradit Complement Altern Med 14: 16&#x2013;23, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Bush JA, Kang J, et al. The effects of supplementation with p-synephrine alone and in combination with caffeine on resistance exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 12: 1&#x2013;11, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shara M, Stohs SJ, Mukattash TL. Cardiovascular safety of oral p-synephrine (bitter orange) in healthy subjects: A randomized placebo-controlled cross-over clinical trial. Phytother Res 30: 842&#x2013;847, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohs SJ. Safety, efficacy, and mechanistic studies regarding citrus aurantium (bitter orange) extract and p-synephrine. Phytother Res 31: 1463&#x2013;1474, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stohs SJ, Ratamess NA. Effects of p-synephrine in combination with caffeine: A review. Nutr Diet Suppl 9: 87&#x2013;96, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner RK, Fuller KL, Ross MLR. Evaluation of three portable blood lactate analysers: Lactate pro, lactate scout and lactate plus. Eur J Appl Physiol 109: 551&#x2013;559, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Caffeine and endurance performance. Sports Med 18: 109&#x2013;125, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Under Armour. My Fitness Pal. Available at: www.wada-ama.org . Accessed: May 15, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Under Armour. My Fitness Pal. Available at: https://www.myfitnesspal.com/ . Accessed: April 10, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas NT, Robergs RA, Klopp DM. Optimal loads for a 30-s maximal power cycle ergometer test using a stationary start. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 1087&#x2013;1094, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>