<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">27819409</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interventions for chronic kidney disease-associated restless legs syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>CD010690</StartPage><MedlinePgn>CD010690</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD010690</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Restless legs syndrome (RLS) is defined as the spontaneous movement of the limbs (mainly legs) associated with unpleasant, sometimes painful sensation which is relieved by moving the affected limb. Prevalence of RLS among people on dialysis has been estimated between 6.6% and 80%. RLS symptoms contribute to impaired quality of life and people with RLS are shown to have increased cardiovascular morbidity and mortality.Various pharmacological and non-pharmacological interventions have been used to treat primary RLS. However, the evidence for use of these interventions in people with chronic kidney disease (CKD) is not well established. The agents used in the treatment of primary RLS may be limited by the side effects in people with CKD due to increased comorbidity and altered drug pharmacokinetics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">The aim of this review was to critically look at the benefits, efficacy and safety of various treatment options used in the treatment of RLS in people with CKD and those undergoing renal replacement therapy (RRT). We aimed to define different group characteristics based on CKD stage to assess the applicability of a particular intervention to an individual patient.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">We searched the Cochrane Kidney and Transplant Specialised Register to 12 January 2016 through contact with the Information Specialist using search terms relevant to this review.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">Randomised controlled trials (RCT) and quasi-RCTs that assessed the efficacy of an intervention for RLS in adults with CKD were eligible for inclusion. Studies investigating idiopathic RLS or RLS secondary to other causes were excluded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">Two authors independently assessed studies for eligibility and conducted risk of bias evaluation. Results were expressed as risk ratios (RR) and their 95% confidence intervals (CI) for dichotomous outcomes, and mean difference (MD) and 95% CI for continuous outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">We included nine studies enrolling 220 dialysis participants. Seven studies were deemed to have moderate to high risk of bias. All studies were small in size and had a short follow-up period (two to six months). Studies evaluated the effects of six different interventions against placebo or standard treatment. The interventions studied included aerobic resistance exercise, gabapentin, ropinirole, levodopa, iron dextran, and vitamins C and E (individually and in combination).Aerobic resistance exercise showed a significant reduction in severity of RLS compared to no exercise (2 studies, 48 participants: MD -7.56, 95% CI -14.20 to -0.93; I<sup>2</sup> = 65%), and when compared to exercise with no resistance (1 study, 24 participants: MD -11.10, 95% CI -17.11 to -5.09), however there was no significant reduction when compared to ropinirole (1 study, 22 participants): MD -0.55, 95% CI -6.41 to 5.31). There were no significant differences between aerobic resistance exercise and either no exercise or ropinirole in the physical or mental component summary scores (using the SF-36 form). Improvement in sleep quality varied. There was no significant difference in subjective sleep quality between exercise and no exercise; however one study reported a significant improvement with ropinirole compared to resistance exercise (MD 3.71, 95% CI 0.89 to 6.53). Using the Epworth Sleepiness Scale there were no significant differences between resistance exercise and no exercise, ropinirole, or exercise with no resistance. Two studies reported there were no adverse events and one study did not mention if there were any adverse events. In one study, one patient in each group dropped out but the reason for dropout was not reported. Two studies reported no adverse events and one study did not report adverse events.Gabapentin was associated with reduced RLS severity when compared to placebo or levodopa, and there was a significant improvement in sleep quality, latency and disturbance reported in one study when compared to levodopa. Three patients dropped out due to lethargy (2 patients), and drowsiness, syncope and fatigue (1 patient).Because of a short duration of action, rebound and augmentation were noted with levodopa treatment even though it conferred some benefit in reducing the symptoms of RLS. Reported adverse events were severe vomiting, agitation after caffeine intake, headaches, dry mouth, and gastrointestinal symptoms.One study (25 participants) reported iron dextran reduced the severity of RLS at weeks one and two, but not at week four. Vitamins C, E and C plus E (1 study, 60 participants) helped the symptoms of RLS with minimal side effects (nausea and dyspepsia) but more evidence is needed before any conclusions can be drawn.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">Given the small size of the studies and short follow-up, it can only be concluded that pharmacological interventions and intra-dialytic exercise programs have uncertain effects on RLS in haemodialysis patients. There have been no studies performed in non-dialysis CKD, peritoneal dialysis patients, or kidney transplant recipients. Further studies are warranted before any conclusions can be drawn. Aerobic resistance exercise and ropinirole may be suitable interventions for further evaluation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gopaluni</LastName><ForeName>Seerapani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Hills Road, Cambridge, UK, CB2 0QQ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sherif</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmadouk</LastName><ForeName>Naim A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000588">Amines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000927">Anticonvulsants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003509">Cyclohexanecarboxylic Acids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018491">Dopamine Agonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007211">Indoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014815">Vitamins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>030PYR8953</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C046649">ropinirole</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>1406-18-4</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014810">Vitamin E</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>46627O600J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007980">Levodopa</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>56-12-2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005680">gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>6CW7F3G59X</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077206">Gabapentin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9004-66-4</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007505">Iron-Dextran Complex</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>PQ6CK8PD0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001205">Ascorbic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD010690</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000588" MajorTopicYN="N">Amines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000927" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticonvulsants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001205" MajorTopicYN="N">Ascorbic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003509" MajorTopicYN="N">Cyclohexanecarboxylic Acids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018491" MajorTopicYN="N">Dopamine Agonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077206" MajorTopicYN="N">Gabapentin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007211" MajorTopicYN="N">Indoles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007505" MajorTopicYN="N">Iron-Dextran Complex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007980" MajorTopicYN="N">Levodopa</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051436" MajorTopicYN="N">Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017582" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Replacement Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012148" MajorTopicYN="N">Restless Legs Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014810" MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamin E</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014815" MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005680" MajorTopicYN="N">gamma-Aminobutyric Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>  Seerapani Gopaluni: none known.   Mohamed Sheriff: none known.   Naim A Ahmadouk: none known; </CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27819409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD010690.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies included in this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Giannaki 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Giannaki CD, Sakkas GK, Karatzaferi C, Hadjigeorgiou GM, Lavdas E, Kyriakides T, et al. Effect of exercise training and dopamine agonists in patients with uremic restless legs syndrome: a six&#x2010;month randomized, partially double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled comparative study. BMC Nephrology 2013;14:194. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3847208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24024727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Giannaki 2013a {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Giannaki CD, Hadjigeorgiou GM, Karatzaferi C, Maridaki MD, Koutedakis Y, Founta P, et al. A single&#x2010;blind randomized controlled trial to evaluate the effect of 6 months of progressive aerobic exercise training in patients with uraemic restless legs syndrome. Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation 2013;28(11):2834&#x2010;40. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23929523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Micozkadioglu 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Micozkadioglu H, Ozdemir FN, Kut A, Sezer S, Saatci U, Haberal M. Gabapentin versus levodopa for the treatment of restless legs syndrome in hemodialysis patients: an open&#x2010;label study. Renal Failure 2004;26(4):393&#x2010;7. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15462107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mortazavi 2013 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Mortazavi M, Vahdatpour B, Ghasempour A, Taheri D, Shahidi S, Moeinzadeh F, et al. Aerobic exercise improves signs of restless leg syndrome in end stage renal disease patients suffering chronic hemodialysis. Thescientificworldjournal 2013;2013:628142. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24307876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortazavi M, Vahdatpour B, Shahidi S, Ghasempour A, Taheri D, Dolatkhah S, et al. Aerobic exercise improves signs of restless leg syndrome in end stage renal disease patients suffering chronic hemodialysis [abstract]. Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation 2012;27(Suppl 2):ii281. [EMBASE: 70766123]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24307876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortazavi M, Vahdatpour B, Shahidi S, Ghasempour A, Taheri S, Ghasami M. The effect of aerobic exercise on the symptoms of restless leg syndrome and quality of life in hemodialysis patients [abstract no: P407]. Iranian Journal of Kidney Diseases 2011;5(Suppl 2):63&#x2010;4. [EMBASE: 70673915]</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Pellecchia 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Pellecchia MT, Vitale C, Sabatini M, Longo K, Amboni M, Bonavita V, et al. Ropinirole as a treatment of restless legs syndrome in patients on chronic hemodialysis: an open randomized crossover trial versus levodopa sustained release. Clinical Neuropharmacology 2004;27(4):178&#x2010;81. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15319704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sagheb 2012 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Fallahzadeh MK, Akbari H, Sohrabi Nazari S, Sagheb MM. Efficacy of vitamins C, E and their combination for treatment of restless legs syndrome in hemodialysis patients; a randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial [abstract no: 404]. Iranian Journal of Kidney Diseases 2011;5(Suppl 2):22&#x2010;3. [EMBASE: 70673845]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22317944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagheb MM, Dormanesh B, Fallahzadeh MK, Akbari H, Sohrabi NS, Heydari ST, et al. Efficacy of vitamins C, E, and their combination for treatment of restless legs syndrome in hemodialysis patients: a randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Sleep Medicine 2012;13(5):542&#x2010;5. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22317944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sloand 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Halterman MW, Sloand JA. An update on the use of intravenous iron for the treatment of restless legs syndrome in end stage renal disease [Actualizacion sobre el uso de hierro intravenoso para el tratamiento del sindrome de piernas inquietas asociado a insuficiencia renal terminal]. Salud(i)Ciencia 2007;15(5):860&#x2010;5. [EMBASE: 2007548364]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloand JA, Shelly MA, Feigin A, Bernstein P, Monk RD. A double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial of intravenous iron dextran therapy in patients with ESRD and restless legs syndrome. American Journal of Kidney Diseases 2004;43(4):663&#x2010;70. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15042543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Thorp 2001 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Thorp ML, Morris CD, Bagby SP. A crossover study of gabapentin in treatment of restless legs syndrome among hemodialysis patients. American Journal of Kidney Diseases 2001;38(1):104&#x2010;8. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11431189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Trenkwalder 1995 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Trenkwalder C, Stiasny K, Pollmacher T, Wetter T, Schwarz J, Kohnen R, et al. L&#x2010;dopa therapy of uremic and idiopathic restless legs syndrome: a double&#x2010;blind, crossover trial. Sleep 1995;18(8):681&#x2010;8. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8560135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetter TC, Trenkwalder C, Pollmacher T, Stiasny K, Kohnen R, Kazenwadel J, et al. Effect of levodopa therapy of idiopathic and uremic restless legs syndrome: a double blind crossover trial [abstract]. Journal of Neurology 1995;242(6 Suppl 2):S81. [CENTRAL: CN&#x2010;00507525]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetter TC, Trenkwalder C, Stiasny K, Pollmacher T, Kazenwadel J, Kohnen R, et al. Treatment of idiopathic and uremic restless legs syndrome with L&#x2010;dopa&#x2010;&#x2010;a double&#x2010;blind cross&#x2010;over study [Behandlung des idiopathischen und uramischen restless&#x2010;legs&#x2010;syndrom mit L&#x2010;Ddpa&#x2010;&#x2010;eine doppelblinde cross&#x2010;over&#x2010;studie]. Wiener Medizinische Wochenschrift 1995;145(17&#x2010;18):525&#x2010;7. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8588396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Ausserwinkler 1989 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Ausserwinkler M, Schmidt P. Clonidine is effective in the treatment of 'restless leg' syndrome in chronic uraemic patients [abstract]. Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation 1988;3(4):530. [CENTRAL: CN&#x2010;00260393]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausserwinkler M, Schmidt P. Successful clonidine treatment of restless leg syndrome in chronic kidney insufficiency [Erfolgreiche behandlung des "restless legs"&#x2010;syndroms bei chronischer Niereninsuffizienz mit clonidin]. Schweizerische Medizinische Wochenschrift [Journal Suisse de Medicine] 1989;119(6):184&#x2010;6. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2928741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Facchini 2004 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Facchini MG, 
Mambelli E, 
Checchia G, 
Balboni M, 
Bainotti S, 
Santoro A. 
Lorenz therapy<sup>TM</sup> a new treatment of uremic neuropathy [abstract no: SU&#x2010;PO379]. 
Journal of the American Society of Nephrology 2004;15(Oct):616A. 
[CENTRAL: CN&#x2010;00583895]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facchini MG, Mambelli E, Checchia G, Gaggi R, Santoro A. The Lorenz&#x2122; therapy: a new tool in the treatment of uremic neuropathy [abstract]. 41st Congress. European Renal Association. European Dialysis and Transplantation Association; 2004 May 15&#x2010;18; Lisbon, Portugal. 2004:375. [CENTRAL: CN&#x2010;00509181]</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>FINESSE Study 2010 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Jardine M, Krishnan A, Gallagher M, Snelling P, Hawley C, Pussell B, et al. Uraemic neuropathy remains ubiquitious: rationale and feasibility of the FINESSE (Filtration in the Neuropathy of End Stage kidney disease Symptom Evolution) trial [abstract no: 235]. Nephrology 2010;15(Suppl 4):88. [EMBASE: 70467239]</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Kramer 1988 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Kramer G, Suss W, Kohler H, Schneider B, Hopf HC. Ganglioside therapy in uremic polyneuropathy [Gangliosid&#x2010;therapie der uramischen polyneuropathie]. Medizinische Klinik 1988;83(1):7&#x2010;11. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3352557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>N0203077917 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Bingham C. Pergolide for restless legs in uraemia. www.nihr.ac.uk/Profile/Pages/NRRResults.aspx?publication_id=N0203077917 (link no longer active) 2002.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Okada 2000 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Okada H, Moriwaki K, Kanno Y, Sugahara S, Nakamoto H, Yoshizawa M, et al. Vitamin B6 supplementation can improve peripheral polyneuropathy in patients with chronic renal failure on high&#x2010;flux haemodialysis and human recombinant erythropoietin. Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation 2000;15(9):1410&#x2010;3. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10978399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Pieta 1998 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Pieta J, Millar T, Zacharias J, Fine A, Kryger M. Effect of pergolide on restless legs and leg movements in sleep in uremic patients. Sleep 1998;21(6):617&#x2010;22. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9779521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sprenger 1983 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Sprenger KB, Bundschu D, Lewis K, Spohn B, Schmitz J, Franz HE. Improvement of uremic neuropathy and hypogeusia by dialysate zinc supplementation: a double&#x2010;blind study. Kidney International &#x2010; Supplement 1983;16:S315&#x2010;8. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Walker 1996 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Walker SL, Fine A, Kryger MH. L&#x2010;DOPA/carbidopa for nocturnal movement disorders in uremia. Sleep 1996;19(3):214&#x2010;8. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8723378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies awaiting assessment</Title><ReferenceList><Title>NCT00996944 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT00996944. Clinical evaluation of ropinirole IR (immediate release) tablets in patients who are diagnosed with symptomatic restless legs syndrome (RLS) associated with chronic kidney disease (CKD) managed with haemodialysis (including haemofiltration and haemodiafiltration). www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/study/NCT00996944 (accessed 21 July 2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>NCT01537042 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>NCT01537042. A sleep laboratory study to investigate the safety and efficacy of the rotigotine skin patch in subjects with restless legs syndrome and end&#x2010;stage renal disease requiring hemodialysis. www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01537042 (accessed 21 July 2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>NCT02011191 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Moretti H. Biotin deficiency and restless legs syndrome: evidence for a causal relationship from randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02011191 (accessed 21 July 2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Razazian 2015 {published data only}</Title><Reference><Citation>Razazian N, Azimi H, Heidarnejadian J, Afshari D, Ghadami MR. Gabapentin versus levodopa&#x2010;c for the treatment of restless legs syndrome in hemodialysis patients: a randomized clinical trial. Saudi Journal of Kidney Diseases &amp; Transplantation 2015;26(2):271&#x2010;8. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25758874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Additional references</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Agarwal 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Agarwal P, Sia C, Vaish N, Roy&#x2010;Faderman I. Pilot trial of onabotulinumtoxina (Botox) in moderate to severe restless legs syndrome. International Journal of Neuroscience 2011;121(11):622&#x2010;5. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21740308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Akpinar 1982</Title><Reference><Citation>Akpinar S. Treatment of restless legs syndrome with levodopa plus benserazide. Archives of Neurology 1982;39(11):739. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7126008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Al&#x2010;Jahdali 2009</Title><Reference><Citation>Al&#x2010;Jahdali HH, Al&#x2010;Qadhi WA, Khogeer HA, Al&#x2010;Hejaili FF, Al&#x2010;Ghamdi SM, Al Sayyari AA. Restless legs syndrome in patients on dialysis. Saudi Journal of Kidney Diseases &amp; Transplantation 2009;20(3):378&#x2010;85. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19414938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Allen 2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Allen RP, Picchietti D, Hening WA, Trenkwalder C, Walters AS, Montplaisi J, et al. Restless legs syndrome: diagnostic criteria, special considerations, and epidemiology. A report from the restless legs syndrome diagnosis and epidemiology workshop at the National Institutes of Health. Sleep Medicine 2003;4(2):101&#x2010;19. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>de Oliveira 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Oliveira MM, Conti CF, Valbuza JS, Carvalho LB, do Prado GF. The pharmacological treatment for uremic restless legs syndrome: evidence&#x2010;based review. Movement Disorders 2010;25(10):1335&#x2010;42. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20544816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Ekbom 1945</Title><Reference><Citation>Ekbom K. Restless legs. Acta Medica Scandinavica 1945;121(S158):7&#x2010;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13726240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Giannaki 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Giannaki CD, Sakkas GK, Hadjigeorgiou GM, Karatzaferi C, Patramani G, Lavdas E, et al. Non&#x2010;pharmacological management of periodic limb movements during hemodialysis session in patients with uremic restless legs syndrome. ASAIO Journal 2010;56(6):538&#x2010;42. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21245801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta&#x2010;analyses. BMJ 2003;327(7414):557&#x2010;60. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Higgins 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Green S (editors). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 [updated March 2011]. The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from www.cochrane&#x2010;handbook.org.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Hornyak 2014</Title><Reference><Citation>Hornyak M, Scholz H, Kohnen R, Bengel J, Kassubek J, Trenkwalder C. What treatment works best for restless legs syndrome? Meta&#x2010;analyses of dopaminergic and non&#x2010;dopaminergic medications.[Erratum appears in Sleep Med Rev. 2014 Aug;18(4):367&#x2010;8]. Sleep Medicine Reviews 2014;18(2):153&#x2010;64. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23746768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Kavanagh 2004</Title><Reference><Citation>Kavanagh D, Siddiqui S, Geddes CC. Restless legs syndrome in patients on dialysis. American Journal of Kidney Diseases 2004;43(5):763&#x2010;71. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15112166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>La Manna 2011</Title><Reference><Citation>Manna G, Pizza F, Persici E, Baraldi O, Comai G, Cappuccilli ML, et al. Restless legs syndrome enhances cardiovascular risk and mortality in patients with end&#x2010;stage kidney disease undergoing long&#x2010;term haemodialysis treatment. Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation 2011;26(6):1976&#x2010;83. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21056943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Lee 2016</Title><Reference><Citation>Lee DO, Buchfuhrer MJ, Garcia&#x2010;Borreguero D, Avidan AY, Ahmed M, Hays R, et al. Efficacy of gabapentin enacarbil in adult patients with severe primary restless legs syndrome. Sleep Medicine 2016;19:50&#x2010;6. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27198947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Manley 2003</Title><Reference><Citation>Manley HJ, McClaran ML, Overbay DK, Wright MA, Reid GM, Bender WL, et al. Factors associated with medication&#x2010;related problems in ambulatory hemodialysis patients. American Journal of Kidney Diseases 2003;41(2):386&#x2010;93. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12552501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Mucsi 2005</Title><Reference><Citation>Mucsi I, Molnar MZ, Ambrus C, Szeifert L, Kovacs AZ, Zoller R, et al. Restless legs syndrome, insomnia and quality of life in patients on maintenance dialysis. Nephrology Dialysis Transplantation 2005;20(3):571&#x2010;7. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15671074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Sun 1998</Title><Reference><Citation>Sun ER, Chen CA, Ho G, Earley CJ, Allen RP. Iron and the restless legs syndrome. Sleep 1998;21(4):371&#x2010;7. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9646381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Walters 1995</Title><Reference><Citation>Walters AS. Toward a better definition of the restless legs syndrome. The International Restless Legs Syndrome Study Group. Movement Disorders 1995;10(5):634&#x2010;42. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8552117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Walters 2010</Title><Reference><Citation>Walters A, Rye D. Evidence continues to mount on the relationship of restless legs syndrome/periodic limb movements in sleep to hypertension, cardiovascular disease, and stroke. Sleep 2010;33(3):287. [MEDLINE: ]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2831421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20337185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Winkelmann 2001</Title><Reference><Citation>Winkelmann J, Schadrack J, Wetter TC, Zieglgansberger W, Trenkwalder C. Opioid and dopamine antagonist drug challenges in untreated restless legs syndrome patients. Sleep Medicine 2001;2(1):57&#x2010;61. [EMBASE: 2001086037]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11152983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to other published versions of this review</Title><ReferenceList><Title>Gopaluni 2013</Title><Reference><Citation>Gopaluni S, Sherif M, Ahmadouk NA. Interventions for chronic kidney disease&#x2010;associated restless legs syndrome. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2013, Issue 9. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD010690]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD010690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27819409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>