<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34937961</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The prevalence and practices of caffeine use as an ergogenic aid in English professional soccer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>525</StartPage><EndPage>534</EndPage><MedlinePgn>525-534</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2021.101125</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The ergogenic properties of caffeine are well established, with evidence supporting beneficial effects for physical and technical elements of performance required for successful soccer match play. Despite this, recommended caffeine practices for professional soccer have not been established. Therefore, the present study aimed to evaluate the use and behaviours surrounding caffeine use in elite English soccer clubs. Representatives of 36 clubs from the top four tiers of English professional football (40%) completed an online survey that sought to determine if, when, how and why caffeine was prescribed to players as a means of improving sports performance. Of the clubs sampled, 97% indicated that caffeine is provided to players as a means of improving performance. Caffeine is most commonly administered prior to (&gt; 94%) and during a game (&gt; 48%), with frequency uninfluenced by time of matches. There was a broad range and lack of consistency in the timing, dose and mode of caffeine administration, but doses were typically low. Evidence from the present study indicate a translational gap between science and practice, highlighting a need for future work to better understand how caffeine consumption can be optimised with respect to the specific demands and constraints in professional soccer.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tallis</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Alison Gingell Building, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clarke</LastName><ForeName>Neil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Alison Gingell Building, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morris</LastName><ForeName>Rhys</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Alison Gingell Building, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richardson</LastName><ForeName>Darren</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Alison Gingell Building, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ellis</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Health, Newman University, Genners Lane, B32 3NT, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eyre</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Alison Gingell Building, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duncan</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Alison Gingell Building, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noon</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport, Exercise and Life Sciences, Alison Gingell Building, Coventry University, Priory Street, Coventry CV1 5FB, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caffeine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ergogenic Aids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.101125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">101125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Pickering C, Schoenfeld BJ, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z. Wake up and smell the coffee: caffeine supplementation and exercise performance-an umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(11):681&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30926628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinero JJ, Lara B, Del Coso J. Effects of acute ingestion of caffeine on team sports performance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Res Sports Med. 2019;27(2):238&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30518253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia JS, Barrett LA, Chow JY, Burns SF. Effects of caffeine supplementation on performance in ball games. Sports Med. 2017;47(12):2453&#x2013;2471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28741186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gant N, Ali A, Foskett A. The influence of caffeine and carbohydrate coingestion on simulated soccer performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20(3):191&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20601736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duvnjak-Zaknich DM, Dawson BT, Wallman KE, Henry G. Effect of caffeine on reactive agility time when fresh and fatigued. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(8):1523&#x2013;1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis M, Noon M, Myers T, Clarke N. Low doses of caffeine: Enhancement of physical performance in elite adolescent male soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(5):569&#x2013;575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foskett A, Ali A, Gant N. Caffeine enhances cognitive function and skill performance during simulated soccer activity. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19(4):410&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19827465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan TM, Caldwell JA, Lieberman HR. A review of caffeine&#x2019;s effects on cognitive, physical and occupational performance. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2016;71:294&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27612937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JK, Green JM. Caffeine and anaerobic performance: ergogenic value and mechanisms of action. Sports Med. 2009;39(10):813&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19757860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali A, O&#x2019;Donnell J, Foskett A, Rutherfurd-Markwick K. The influence of caffeine ingestion on strength and power performance in female team-sport players. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2016;13(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5139084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27980499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Munoz G, Munoz-Guerra J. Prevalence of caffeine use in elite athletes following its removal from the World Anti-Doping Agency list of banned substances. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2011;36(4):555&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21854160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham KA, Spriet LL. Administration of caffeine in alternate forms. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):79&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5790855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielgo-Ayuso J, Calleja-Gonzalez J, Del Coso J, Urdampilleta A, Le&#xf3;n-Guere&#xf1;o P, Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xe1;zaro D. Caffeine supplementation and physical performance, muscle damage and perception of fatigue in soccer players: A systematic review. Nutrients. 2019;11(2):440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6412526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltazar-Martins G, de Souza DB, Aguilar-Navarro M, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J, del Mar Plata M, Del Coso J. Prevalence and patterns of dietary supplement use in elite Spanish athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2019;16(1):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6639916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31319850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce CR, Anderson ME, Fraser SF, Stepto NK, Klein R, Hopkins WG, Hawley JA. Enhancement of 2000-m rowing performance after caffeine ingestion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(11):1958&#x2013;1963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM. Caffeine and sports performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33(6):1319&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A. Effects of caffeine on human behavior. Food Chem Toxicol. 2002;40(9):1243&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12204388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo R, Silva-Cavalcante MD, Gualano B, Lima-Silva AE, Bertuzzi R. Effects of caffeine ingestion on endurance performance in mentally fatigued individuals. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(11-12):2293&#x2013;2303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27695980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Taylor S, Lyons M. The effect of caffeine ingestion on field hockey skill performance following physical fatigue. Res Sports Med. 2012;20(1):25&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22242735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chester N, Wojek N. Caffeine consumption amongst British athletes following changes to the 2004 WADA prohibited list. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29(06):524&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18027309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE. Caffeine and exercise: metabolism, endurance and performance. Sports Med. 2001;31(11):785&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11583104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Kavouras SA. Caffeine use in sports, pharmacokinetics in man, and cellular mechanisms of action. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2005;45(7-8):535&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16371327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negaresh R, Del Coso J, Mokhtarzade M, Lima-Silva AE, Baker JS, Willems ME, Talebvand S, Khodadoost M, Farhani F. Effects of different dosages of caffeine administration on wrestling performance during a simulated tournament. Eur J Sport Sci. 2019;19(4):499&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30378465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venier S, Grgic J, Mikulic P. Acute enhancement of jump performance, muscle strength, and power in resistance-trained men after consumption of caffeinated chewing gum. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(10):1415&#x2013;1421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30958062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton CD, Lowe T, Irvine A. Caffeinated chewing gum increases repeated sprint performance and augments increases in testosterone in competitive cyclists. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(6):1243&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20737165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering C, Kiely J. Are the current guidelines on caffeine use in sport optimal for everyone? Inter-individual variation in caffeine ergogenicity, and a move towards personalised sports nutrition. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):7&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28853006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Sabol F, Venier S, Tallis J, Schoenfeld BJ, Del Coso J, Mikulic P. Caffeine supplementation for powerlifting competitions: An evidence-based approach. J Hum Kinet. 2019;68:37&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6724591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31531131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering C, Kiely J. Are low doses of caffeine as ergogenic as higher doses? A critical review highlighting the need for comparison to current best practice in caffeine research. Nutrition. 2019;67-68:110535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31400738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabol F, Grgic J, Mikulic P. The Effects of 3 Different Doses of Caffeine on Jumping and Throwing Performance: A Randomized, Double-Blind, Crossover Study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(9):1170&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30702372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Sabol F, Venier S, Mikulic I, Bratkovic N, Schoenfeld BJ, Pickering C, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z, Mikulic P. What dose of caffeine to use: acute effects of 3 doses of caffeine on muscle endurance and strength. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;15(4):470&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31575825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins NT, Trilk JL, Singhal A, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Cureton KJ. Ergogenic effects of low doses of caffeine on cycling performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18(3):328&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18562777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Hoseinihaji M, Eghbali E. The effects of different doses of caffeine on performance, rating of perceived exertion and pain perception in teenagers female karate athletes. Braz J Pharm Sci. 2016;52(4):685&#x2013;692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Terzi MN, Roberson DW, Burnett TR. Effect of two doses of caffeine on muscular function during isokinetic exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(12):2205&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20421833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawrot P, Jordan S, Eastwood J, Rotstein J, Hugenholtz A, Feeley M. Effects of caffeine on human health. Food Addit Contam. 2003;20(1):1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12519715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Dobell AP, Caygill CL, Eyre E, Tallis J. The effect of acute caffeine ingestion on upper body anaerobic exercise and cognitive performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2019;19(1):103&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30102874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara B, Ruiz-Moreno C, Salinero JJ, Del Coso J. Time course of tolerance to the performance benefits of caffeine. PLoS One. 2019;14(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6343867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30673725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaumont R, Cordery P, Funnell M, Mears S, James L, Watson P. Chronic ingestion of a low dose of caffeine induces tolerance to the performance benefits of caffeine. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(19):1920&#x2013;1927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27762662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasman WJ, van Baak MA, Jeukendrup AE, de Haan A. The effect of different dosages of caffeine on endurance performance time. Int J Sports Med. 1995;16(4):225&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7657415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Krzysztofik M, Filip A, Zajac A, Del Coso J. The Effects of High Doses of Caffeine on Maximal Strength and Muscular Endurance in Athletes Habituated to Caffeine. Nutrients. 2019;11(8):1912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A. Effects of caffeine on human behavior. Food Chem Toxicol. 2002;40(9):1243&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12204388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali A, O&#x2019;Donnell J, Starck C, Rutherfurd-Markwick K. The effect of caffeine ingestion during evening exercise on subsequent sleep quality in females. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36(6):433&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AM. Sleep and Athletic Performance. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2017;16(6):413&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29135639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird S. Sleep, Recovery, and Athletic Performance: A Brief Review and Recommendations. Strength Con J. 2013;35(5):43&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabir A, Hooton A, Tallis J, Higgins MF. The influence of caffeine expectancies on sport, exercise, and cognitive performance. Nutrients. 2018;10(10):1528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6212857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30336606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabir A, Hooton A, Spencer G, Storey M, Ensor O, Sandford L, Tallis J, Saunders B, Higgins MF. The Influence of Caffeine Expectancies on Simulated Soccer Performance in Recreational Individuals. Nutrients. 2019;11(10):2289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31557945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>