<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37929237</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1658-3639</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Nov-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Health Sci (Qassim)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine, lactic acid, or nothing: What effect does expectation have on men's performance and perceived exertion during an upper body muscular endurance task?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39</StartPage><EndPage>42</EndPage><MedlinePgn>39-42</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We tested the impact of subjects' belief in an ingested substance's ergogenic or ergolytic properties on muscular endurance performance and perceived exertion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Trained men (<i>n</i> = 15, age = 41 &#xb1; 4 y; body mass = 82.1 &#xb1; 15.8 kg; height = 173 &#xb1; 8 cm; experience = 7.4 &#xb1; 2.3 y) completed one set to failure at 80% repetition maximum of the bench press under three conditions. In all conditions, subjects ingested capsules of an identical, inert substance (300 mg cellulose), but, in a randomized order, subjects were told that they were either ingesting caffeine (Placebo), lactic acid (Nocebo), or cellulose (Control) and received information on the respective alleged ergogenic/ergolytic/neutral effects of each. Repetitions completed and rating of perceived exertion (RPE) were recorded. The data were analyzed among conditions using a Friedman test with <i>post hoc</i> analyses accomplished through Durbin-Conover tests. Spearman correlations were used to compare repetitions performed and RPE between Nocebo and Placebo conditions. Statistical significance was set at <i>P</i> &#x2264; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Subjects lifted more (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001) repetitions in the Placebo condition (14.1 &#xb1; 3.0) versus Control (10.3 &#xb1; 2.9) or Nocebo (7.5 &#xb1; 2.6), while Control and Nocebo performances were similar (<i>P</i> = 0.192). Lower RPE was noted in Placebo versus Control (<i>P</i> = 0.003) and Nocebo (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001) and lower in Control versus Nocebo (<i>P</i> = 0.025). Subjects who performed more repetitions with Placebo tended to perform fewer repetitions under the Nocebo condition (Spearman's Rho =-0.578).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study believes that the ergogenic or ergolytic properties of a substance can measurably impact upper-body muscular endurance performance and RPE in trained men.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; International Journal of Health Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campelo</LastName><ForeName>Dara</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Physiology and Biokinetic, Faculty of Biological Sciences and Health, Itaperuna, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koch</LastName><ForeName>Alexander J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Exercise Sciences Program, Lenoir-Rhyne University, Hickory, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Machado</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Physiology and Biokinetic, Faculty of Biological Sciences and Health, Itaperuna, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o Universit&#xe1;ria de Itaperuna, Itaperuna, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Health Sci (Qassim)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528042</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1658-3639</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Placebo effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors certify that there is no conflict of interest with any financial organization regarding the material discussed in the manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37929237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10624800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJHS-17-39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA, Schabort EJ, Noakes TD, Dennis SC. Carbohydrate-loading and exercise performance. An update. Sports Med. 1997;24:73&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9291549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, Ziegenfuss TN, Wildman R, Collins R, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand:Safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw DM, Merien F, Braakhuis A, Maunder ED, Dulson DK. Effect of a ketogenic diet on submaximal exercise capacity and efficiency in runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:2135&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31033901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pedisic Z, Saunders B, Artioli GG, Schoenfeld BJ, McKenna MJ, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand:Sodium bicarbonate and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18:61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8427947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34503527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Clair Gibson A, Lambert ML, Noakes TD. Neural control of force output during maximal and submaximal exercise. Sports Med. 2001;31:637&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11508520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst P, Schipof-Godart L, Szabo A, Raglin J, Hettinga F, Roelands B, et al. The Placebo and Nocebo effect on sports performance:A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020;20:279&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31414966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo PH, Oliveira MG, Tanaka K, Pereira PE, Esteves G, Tenan MS. Perceived exertion and performance modulation:Effects of caffeine ingestion and subject expectation. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2021;61:1185&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33472353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest NS, VanDusseldorp TA, Nelson MT, Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Jenkins ND, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand:Caffeine and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7777221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33388079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, Larson-Meyer DE, Peeling P, Phillips SM, et al. IOC consensus statement:Dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28:104&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29589768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Rendo-Urteaga T, Dom&#xed;nguez R, Castillo D, Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez A, Grgic J. Acute effects of caffeine supplementation on movement velocity in resistance exercise:A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50:717&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Lyons M, Hankey J. Placebo effects of caffeine on short-term resistance exercise to failure. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2009;4:244&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19567927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollo A, Carlino E, Benedetti F. The top-down influence of ergogenic placebos on muscle work and fatigue. Eur J Neurosci. 2008;28:379&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18702709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morishita S, Tsubaki A, Takabayashi T, Fu JB. Relationship between the rating of perceived exertion scale and the load intensity of resistance training. Strength Cond J. 2018;40:94&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29674945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fry AC. Strength testing:Development and evaluation of methodology. In: Maud P, Foster C, editors. Physiological Assessment of Human Fitness. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1995. pp. 115&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rovetta A. Raiders of the lost correlation:A guide on using Pearson and spearman coefficients to detect hidden correlations in medical sciences. Cureus. 2020;12:e11794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33409040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Barroso R, Beneke R, Bok D, Boullosa D, Casado A, et al. How to succeed as an athlete:What we know, what we need to know. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17:333&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35168195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>