<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33312286</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>74</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine Increases Muscle Performance During a Bench Press Training Session.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>185</StartPage><EndPage>193</EndPage><MedlinePgn>185-193</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2020-0024</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Previous investigations have established the ergogenic effect of caffeine on maximal muscle strength, power output and strength-endurance. However, these investigations used testing protocols that do not replicate the structure of a regular strength training session. Thus, the aim of this study was to investigate the effect of acute caffeine ingestion on muscle performance during a simulated velocity-based training workout. In a double-blind, randomized and counterbalanced experiment, 12 participants performed two experimental trials after ingesting 3 mg/kg/b.m. of caffeine or a placebo. The trials consisted of 4 sets of 8 repetitions of the bench press exercise at 70% of their one-repetition maximum performed at maximal velocity. Bar velocity was recorded with a rotatory encoder and force, power output and work were calculated. Regarding the whole workout, caffeine increased mean bar velocity (+7.8%; p=0.002), peak bar velocity (+8.7%; p=0.006), mean force (+1.5%; p=0.002), mean power output (+10.1%; p=0.003) and peak power output (+8.2%; p=0.004) when compared to the placebo. The total work performed in the caffeine trial was superior to the placebo trial (7.01&#xb1;2.36 vs 6.55&#xb1;2.20 kJ, p=0.001). These results suggest that the acute intake of 3 mg/kg/b.m. of caffeine before a velocity-based strength workout increased muscle performance and the total work performed across the whole training session. Thus, caffeine can be considered as an effective strategy to enhance muscle performance during the bench press training sessions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Ver&#xf3;nica Gir&#xe1;ldez-Costas, Jaime Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garc&#xed;a, Beatriz Lara, Juan Del Coso, Michal Wilk, Juan Jos&#xe9; Salinero, published by Sciendo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gir&#xe1;ldez-Costas</LastName><ForeName>Ver&#xf3;nica</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Camilo Jos&#xe9; Cela University. Exercise Physiology Laboratory. Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autonomus University of Madrid. Department of Physical Education, Sport and Human Movement. Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garc&#xed;a</LastName><ForeName>Jaime</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Camilo Jos&#xe9; Cela University. Exercise Physiology Laboratory. Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lara</LastName><ForeName>Beatriz</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Camilo Jos&#xe9; Cela University. Exercise Physiology Laboratory. Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coso</LastName><ForeName>Juan Del</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rey Juan Carlos University. Centre for Sport Studies. Fuenlabrada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilk</LastName><ForeName>Michal</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Sciences, Jerzy Kukuczka Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salinero</LastName><ForeName>Juan Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4153-5100</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Camilo Jos&#xe9; Cela University. Exercise Physiology Laboratory. Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Castilla-La Mancha University. Faculty of Sport Sciences. Toledo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ergogenic aid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2020-0024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aguilar-Navarro M, Mu&#xf1;oz G, Salinero JJ, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J, Fern&#xe1;ndez-&#xc1;lvarez M, Plata MDM, Del Coso J. Urine Caffeine Concentration in Doping Control Samples from 2004 to 2015. Nutrients. 2019;11(2):286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6412495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30699902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Rohmann RL, Firth K. Effect of caffeine ingestion on one-repetition maximum muscular strength. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102(2):127&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17851681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW, Housh TJ, Schmidt RJ, Johnson GO, Housh DJ, Coburn JW, Malek MH. The acute effects of a caffeine-containing supplement on strength, muscular endurance, and anaerobic capabilities. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):506&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Salinero JJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mill&#xe1;n C, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J, P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez B. Dose response effects of a caffeine-containing energy drink on muscle performance: A repeated measures design. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3461468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22569090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Lara FJ, Del Coso J, Garc&#xed;a JM, Portillo LJ, Areces F, Abi&#xe1;n-Vic&#xe9;n J. Caffeine improves muscular performance in elite Brazilian Jiu-jitsu athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26863885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fett CA, Aquino NM, Schantz Junior J, Brand&#xe3;o CF, De Ara&#xfa;jocavalcanti JD, Fett WC. Performance of muscle strength and fatigue tolerance in young trained women supplemented with caffeine. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2018;58(3):249&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28409508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Pickering C, Schoenfeld BJ, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z. Wake up and smell the coffee: Caffeine supplementation and exercise performance - An umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses. Br J Sports Med. 2019;54(11):681&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30926628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Mikulic P. Caffeine ingestion acutely enhances muscular strength and power but not muscular endurance in resistance-trained men. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(8):1029&#x2013;1036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28537195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pickering C, Bishop DJ, Del Coso J, Schoenfeld BJ, Tinsley GM, Pedisic Z. ADORA2A C Allele Carriers Exhibit Ergogenic Responses to Caffeine Supplementation. Nutrients. 2020;12(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32168870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Sabol F, Venier S, Tallis J, Schoenfeld BJ, Del Coso J, Mikulic P. Caffeine Supplementation for Powerlifting Competitions: an Evidence-Based Approach. J Hum Kinet. 2019;68(1):37&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6724591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31531131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs I, Pasternak H, Bell DG. Effects of ephedrine, caffeine, and their combination on muscular endurance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(6):987&#x2013;994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten B, Fu Y. Larumbe-Zabala E, Seijo M, Naclerio F. Impact of Two High-Volume Set Configuration Workouts on Resistance Training Outcomes in Recreationally Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019:1. Leon.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31365457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara B, Ruiz-Moreno C, Salinero JJ, Del Coso J. Time course of tolerance to the performance benefits of caffeine. PLoS One. 2019;14(1):e0210275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6343867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30673725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Teo WP, Drinkwater EJ, Kendall K, Haff GG. Sport Med. Springer International Publishing; 2019. The Acute Neuromuscular Responses to Cluster Set Resistance Training: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. December 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6851217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31506904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Reliability of technologies to measure the barbell velocity: Implications for monitoring resistance training. PLoS One. 2020;15(6):e0232465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32520952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielgo-Ayuso J, Marques-Jim&#xe9;nez D, Refoyo I, Del Coso J, Le&#xf3;n-Guere&#xf1;o P, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. Effect of Caffeine Supplementation on Sports Performance Based on Differences Between Sexes: A Systematic Review. Nutrients. 2019;11(10):2313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31574901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R, Pallar&#xe9;s JG, L&#xf3;pez-Gull&#xf3;n JM, L&#xf3;pez-Samanes &#xc1;, Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as VE, Ortega JF. Improvements on neuromuscular performance with caffeine ingestion depend on the time-of-day. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;18(3):338&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24816164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi R. The effect of CYP1A2 genotype on the ergogenic properties of caffeine during resistance exercise: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study. Ir J Med Sci. 2019;188(1):337&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson DL, Clarke ND. Effect of coffee and caffeine ingestion on resistance exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(10):2892&#x2013;2900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26890974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Moraleda B, Del Coso J, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Hell&#xed;n J, Lara B. The Effect of Caffeine on the Velocity of Half-Squat Exercise during the Menstrual Cycle: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Nutrients. 2019;11(11):2662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6893702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31690049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Moraleda B, Del Coso J, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Hell&#xed;n J, Ruiz-Moreno C, Grgic J, Lara B. The Influence of the Menstrual Cycle on Muscle Strength and Power Performance. J Hum Kinet. 2019;68:123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6724592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31531138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salatto RW, Arevalo JA, Brown LE, Wiersma LD, Coburn JW. Caffeine&#x2019;s Effects on an Upper-Body Resistance Exercise Workout. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(6):1643&#x2013;1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29933355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinero J., Lara B, Del Coso J. Effects of acute ingestion of caffeine on team sports performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Res Sport Med. 2019;27(2):238&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30518253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinero JJ, Lara B, Abian-Vicen J, Gonzalez-Mill&#xe1;n C, Areces F, Gallo-Salazar C. Del Coso J. The use of energy drinks in sport: Perceived ergogenicity and side effects in male and female athletes. Br J Nutr. 2014;112(9):1494&#x2013;1502. &#x2026;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25212095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard J, Tripplet N. Essential of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2016. Design for resistance training.In; pp. 439&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J, Yavuz HCM. The effects of low and moderate doses of caffeine supplementation on upper and lower body maximal voluntary concentric and eccentric muscle force. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(3):274&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29065278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venier S, Grgic J, Mikulic P. Caffeinated gel ingestion enhances jump performance, muscle strength, and power in trained men. Nutrients. 2019;11(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31027246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Filip A, Krzysztofik M, Gepfert M, Zajac A, Del Coso J. Acute Caffeine Intake Enhances Mean Power Output and Bar Velocity during the Bench Press Throw in Athletes Habituated to Caffeine. Nutrients. 2020;12(2):406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7071256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Filip A, Krzysztofik M, Maszczyk A, Zajac A. The acute effect of various doses of caffeine on power output and velocity during the bench press exercise among athletes habitually using caffeine. Nutrients. 2019;11(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6682895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31252655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Golas A, Krzysztofik M, Nawrocka M, Zajac A. The effects of eccentric cadence on power and velocity of the bar during the concentric phase of the bench press movement. J Sport Sci Med. 2019;18(2):191&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Krzysztofik M, Filip A, Zajac A, Del Coso J. Correction: Wilk et al. &#x201c;The Effects of High Doses of Caffeine on Maximal Strength and Muscular Endurance in Athletes Habituated to Caffeine&#x201d;. Nutrients. 2019;11(8):1912. Nutrients, 2019a; 11(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Krzysztofik M, Filip A, Zajac A, Del Coso J. The effects of high doses of caffeine on maximal strength and muscular endurance in athletes habituated to caffeine. Nutrients. 2019b;11(8):1912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>