<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37844569</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caffeine, CYP1A2 Genotype, and Exercise Performance: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>328</StartPage><EndPage>339</EndPage><MedlinePgn>328-339</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003313</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to summarize and meta-analyze existing evidence regarding the influence of CYP1A2 genotypes on the acute effects of caffeine for exercise performance and to investigate the interaction between genotype, dosage, and timing of caffeine supplementation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Six databases were searched for studies determining the effect of caffeine (except mouth rinsing) on exercise performance between CYP1A2 genotypes. Three-level meta-analyses were performed using standardized mean differences (SMD; Hedge's g ) to determine the effect of caffeine on exercise outcomes within and between CYP1A2 genotypes (AA, AC, and CC). Meta-regressions were performed for dose, timing, and presence of reported conflict of interests (RCOI). A meta-analysis was also performed with placebo values to assess for imbalances between genotypes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirteen studies, totaling 119 outcomes and 440 participants, were included (233 AA, 175 AC, ad 34 CC). Caffeine improved performance for AA (SMD = 0.30, 95% confidence interval [CI] = 0.21-0.39, P &lt; 0.0001) and AC (SMD = 0.16, 95% CI = 0.06-0.25, P = 0.022) but worsened performance for CC (SMD = -0.22, 95% CI = -0.44 to -0.01, P &lt; 0.0001). Dose affected only CC, with greater doses generating more positive SMD (CC-dose estimate: +0.19/1 mg&#xb7;kg -1 body mass, 95% CI = 0.04-0.33, P = 0.01). Timing influenced only CC, with better performance with later onset of exercise after supplementation (CC-timing estimate: +0.01/min, 95% CI = 0.00-0.02, P = 0.02). RCOI only affected SMD of CC (CC-RCOI estimate: -0.57, 95% CI = -1.02 to -0.12, P = 0.01). After excluding studies with RCOI, no influence of genotype was seen (all P &#x2265; 0.19). Small, nonsignificant differences were seen in placebo between genotypes (SMD AA vs CC: -0.13; AA vs AC: -0.12; AC vs CC: -0.05; all P &#x2265; 0.26).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Caffeine improved performance for AA and AC but worsened performance for CC. Dose and timing moderated the efficacy of caffeine for CC only. Caution is advised because baseline differences and studies with RCOI could have influenced these results.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barreto</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group-Center of Lifestyle Medicine, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esteves</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel P</ForeName><Initials>GP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group-Center of Lifestyle Medicine, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marticorena</LastName><ForeName>Felipe</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group-Center of Lifestyle Medicine, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Tamires N</ForeName><Initials>TN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group-Center of Lifestyle Medicine, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grgic</LastName><ForeName>Jozo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, VIC, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saunders</LastName><ForeName>Bryan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3G6A5W338E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002110">Caffeine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.14.14.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019388">Cytochrome P-450 CYP1A2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.14.14.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C504573">CYP1A2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caffeine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019388" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytochrome P-450 CYP1A2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Six databases were searched for studies determining the effect of caffeine (except mouth rinsing) on exercise performance between CYP1A2 genotypes. Three-level meta-analyses were performed using standardized mean differences (SMD; Hedge&#x2019;s g ) to determine the effect of caffeine on exercise outcomes within and between CYP1A2 genotypes (AA, AC, and CC). Meta-regressions were performed for dose, timing, and presence of reported conflict of interests (RCOI). A meta-analysis was also performed with placebo values to assess for imbalances between genotypes.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37844569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202402000-00017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Pickering C, Schoenfeld BJ, Bishop DJ, Pedisic Z. Wake up and smell the coffee: caffeine supplementation and exercise performance-an umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses. Br J Sports Med . 2020;54(11):681&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pickering C. The effects of caffeine ingestion on isokinetic muscular strength: a meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport . 2019;22(3):353&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM. Effects of caffeine ingestion on exercise testing: a meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2004;14(6):626&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly JW, Butts-Lamb P, Padgett W. Subclasses of adenosine receptors in the central nervous system: interaction with caffeine and related methylxanthines. Cell Mol Neurobiol . 1983;3(1):69&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamone JD, Correa M, Randall PA, Nunes EJ, Pardo M, Lopez-Cruz L. The role of adenosine in the ventral striatal circuits regulating behavioral activation and effort-related decision making: importance for normal and pathological aspects of motivation. In: Adenosine . Springer; 2013. pp. 493&#x2013;512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM, Zhao Z, Stock HS, Mehl KA, Buggy J, Hand GA. Central nervous system effects of caffeine and adenosine on fatigue. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol . 2003;284(2):R399&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southward K, Rutherfurd-Markwick K, Badenhorst C, Ali A. The role of genetics in moderating the inter-individual differences in the ergogenicity of caffeine. Nutrients . 2018;10(10):1352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering C, Grgic J. Caffeine and exercise: what next? Sports Med . 2019;49(7):1007&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinton PA, Hemingway BS, Saunders B, Gualano B, Dolan E. A statistical framework to interpret individual response to intervention: paving the way for personalized nutrition and exercise prescription. Front Nutr . 2018;5:41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Williamson P, Batterham AM. Issues in the determination of &#x2018;responders&#x2019; and &#x2018;non-responders&#x2019; in physiological research. Exp Physiol . 2019;104(8):1215&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis CEG, Saunders B, da Costa THM. Absence of dietary control precludes solid conclusions for sport nutrition trials. J Sci Med Sport . 2021;24(6):518&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marticorena FM, Carvalho A, Oliveira LF, et al. Nonplacebo controls to determine the magnitude of ergogenic interventions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(8):1766&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho A, Marticorena FM, Grecco BH, Barreto G, Saunders B. Can I have my coffee and drink it? A systematic review and meta-analysis to determine whether habitual caffeine consumption affects the ergogenic effect of caffeine. Sports Med . 2022;52(9):2209&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreto G, Grecco B, Merola P, Reis CEG, Gualano B, Saunders B. Novel insights on caffeine supplementation, CYP1A2 genotype, physiological responses and exercise performance. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2021;121(3):749&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pickering C, Del Coso J, Schoenfeld BJ, Mikulic P. CYP1A2 genotype and acute ergogenic effects of caffeine intake on exercise performance: a systematic review. Eur J Nutr . 2021;60(3):1181&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Womack CJ, Saunders MJ, Bechtel MK, et al. The influence of a CYP1A2 polymorphism on the ergogenic effects of caffeine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2012;9(1):7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu L, Gonzalez FJ, Kalow W, Tang BK. Biotransformation of caffeine, paraxanthine, theobromine and theophylline by cDNA-expressed human CYP1A2 and CYP2E1. Pharmacogenetics . 1992;2(2):73&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachse C, Brockmoller J, Bauer S, Roots I. Functional significance of a C&#x2013; &gt; a polymorphism in intron 1 of the cytochrome P450 CYP1A2 gene tested with caffeine. Br J Clin Pharmacol . 1999;47(4):445&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest N, Corey P, Vescovi J, El-Sohemy A. Caffeine, CYP1A2 genotype, and endurance performance in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2018;50(8):1570&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong O, Marshall K, Sicova M, Guest NS, Garcia-Bailo B, El-Sohemy A. CYP1A2 genotype modifies the effects of caffeine compared with placebo on muscle strength in competitive male athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2021;31(5):420&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sicova M, Guest NS, Tyrrell PN, El-Sohemy A. Caffeine, genetic variation and anaerobic performance in male athletes: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2021;121(12):3499&#x2013;513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Chopra K, Pereira De Sena AL, Sternbach C, Morina L, Mavrommatis Y. Caffeine, exercise physiology, and time-trial performance: no effect of ADORA2A or CYP1A2 genotypes. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2021;46(6):541&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spineli H, Pinto MP, Dos Santos BP, et al. Caffeine improves various aspects of athletic performance in adolescents independent of their 163 C &gt; A CYP1A2 genotypes. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2020;30(10):1869&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carswell AT, Howland K, Martinez-Gonzalez B, Baron P, Davison G. The effect of caffeine on cognitive performance is influenced by CYP1A2 but not ADORA2A genotype, yet neither genotype affects exercise performance in healthy adults. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2020;120(7):1495&#x2013;508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pickering C, Bishop DJ, Schoenfeld BJ, Mikulic P, Pedisic Z. CYP1A2 genotype and acute effects of caffeine on resistance exercise, jumping, and sprinting performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2020;17(1):21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giersch GE, Boyett JC, Hargens TA, et al. The effect of the CYP1A2-163 C &gt; a polymorphism on caffeine metabolism and subsequent cycling performance. J Caffeine Adenosine Res . 2018;8(2):65&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein CS, Clawson A, Martin M, et al. The effect of caffeine on performance in collegiate tennis players. J Caffeine Res . 2012;2(3):111&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algrain HA, Thomas RM, et al; Carrillo. The effects of a polymorphism in the cytochrome P450 CYP1A2 gene on performance enhancement with caffeine in recreational cyclists. J Caffeine Res 2016;6(1):34&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinero JJ, Lara B, Ruiz-Vicente D, et al. CYP1A2 genotype variations do not modify the benefits and drawbacks of caffeine during exercise: a pilot study. Nutrients . 2017;9(3):269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pataky MW, Womack CJ, Saunders MJ, et al. Caffeine and 3-km cycling performance: effects of mouth rinsing, genotype, and time of day. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2016;26(6):613&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djordjevic N, Ghotbi R, Jankovic S, Aklillu E. Induction of CYP1A2 by heavy coffee consumption is associated with the CYP1A2-163C &gt; A polymorphism. Eur J Clin Pharmacol . 2010;66(7):697&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ . 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouzzani M, Hammady H, Fedorowicz Z, Elmagarmid A. Rayyan&#x2014;a web and mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev . 2016;5(1):210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Elliott-Sale K, Artioli GG, et al. beta-alanine supplementation to improve exercise capacity and performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med . 2017;51(8):658&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi R. The effect of CYP1A2 genotype on the ergogenic properties of caffeine during resistance exercise: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover study. Ir J Med Sci . 2019;188(1):337&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minaei S, Jourkesh M, Kreider RB, et al. CYP1A2 genotype polymorphism influences the effect of caffeine on anaerobic performance in trained males. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2022;32(1):16&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potgieter S. The Effect of Caffeine Supplementation on Olympic-Distance Triathletes and Triathlon Performance in the Western Cape, South Africa [dissertation] . Stellenbosch: Stellenbosch University; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puente C, Abian-Vicen J, Del Coso J, Lara B, Salinero JJ. The CYP1A2-163C &gt; a polymorphism does not alter the effects of caffeine on basketball performance. PLoS One . 2018;13(4):e0195943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Alonso-Coello P, Guyatt GH, et al. GRADE guidelines: 19. Assessing the certainty of evidence in the importance of outcomes or values and preferences-risk of bias and indirectness. J Clin Epidemiol . 2019;111:94&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovic J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ . 2019;366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR. Multiple outcomes or time-points within a study. In: Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR, editors. Introduction to meta-analysis .&#xa0;Wiley; 2009. pp. 225&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawilowsky SS. New effect size rules of thumb. J Mod Appl Stat Methods . 2009;8(2):26&#x2013;599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trowman R, Dumville JC, Torgerson DJ, Cranny G. The impact of trial baseline imbalances should be considered in systematic reviews: a methodological case study. J Clin Epidemiol . 2007;60(12):1229&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley RD, Kauser I, Bland M, et al. Meta-analysis of randomised trials with a continuous outcome according to baseline imbalance and availability of individual participant data. Stat Med . 2013;32(16):2747&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koonrungsesomboon N, Khatsri R, Wongchompoo P, Teekachunhatean S. The impact of genetic polymorphisms on CYP1A2 activity in humans: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pharmacogenomics J . 2018;18(6):760&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreto G, Esteves GP, Marticorena FM, Saunders B. Comment on &#x201c;CYP1A2 genotype modifies the effects of caffeine compared with placebo on muscle strength in competitive male athletes&#x201d;. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2022;32(1):62&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens CJ, Dascombe BJ. The reliability and validity of protocols for the assessment of endurance sports performance: an updated review. Meas Phys Educ Exerc . 2015;19(4):177&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, et al. IOC consensus statement: dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2018;28(2):104&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz A, Lopez-Samanes A, Aguilar-Navarro M, et al. Effects of CYP1A2 and ADORA2A genotypes on the ergogenic response to caffeine in professional handball players. Genes (Basel) . 2020;11(8):933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesser LI, Ebbeling CB, Goozner M, Wypij D, Ludwig DS. Relationship between funding source and conclusion among nutrition-related scientific articles. PLoS Med . 2007;4(1):e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Zhu M, Su Z. The pursuit of balance: an overview of covariate-adaptive randomization techniques in clinical trials. Contemp Clin Trials . 2015;45(Pt A):21&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei L, Zhang J. Analysis of data with imbalance in the baseline outcome variable for randomized clinical trials. Drug Inf J . 2001;35(4):1201&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG; Group obotCSM. Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions . 2019. pp. 241&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egbewale BE, Lewis M, Sim J. Bias, precision and statistical power of analysis of covariance in the analysis of randomized trials with baseline imbalance: a simulation study. BMC Med Res Methodol . 2014;14:49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers AJ. Analysis of variance is easily misapplied in the analysis of randomized trials: a critique and discussion of alternative statistical approaches. Psychosom Med . 2005;67(4):652&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Caffeine ingestion enhances Wingate performance: a meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci . 2018;18(2):219&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southward K, Rutherfurd-Markwick KJ, Ali A. Correction to: the effect of acute caffeine ingestion on endurance performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2018;48(10):2425&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinero JJ, Lara B, Del Coso J. Effects of acute ingestion of caffeine on team sports performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Res Sports Med . 2019;27(2):238&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira TT, da Silva JVF, Bueno NB. Effects of caffeine supplementation on muscle endurance, maximum strength, and perceived exertion in adults submitted to strength training: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr . 2021;61(15):2587&#x2013;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childs E, Hohoff C, Deckert J, Xu K, Badner J, de Wit H. Association between ADORA2A and DRD2 polymorphisms and caffeine-induced anxiety. Neuropsychopharmacology . 2008;33(12):2791&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes GF, Reis CEG, Nakano EY, et al. Can the Brazilian Caffeine Expectancy Questionnaires differentiate the CYP1A2 and ADORA2A gene polymorphisms? &#x2014; an exploratory study with Brazilian athletes. Nutrients . 2022;14(16):3355.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>