<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40401903</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6519</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in clinical nutrition and metabolic care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nutrition support whilst on glucagon-like peptide-1 based therapy. Is it necessary?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>351</StartPage><EndPage>357</EndPage><MedlinePgn>351-357</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCO.0000000000001130</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM OF THE REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Weight loss is a primary goal in the treatment of obesity, but its effect on body composition - particularly fat-free mass (FFM) and skeletal muscle mass (SM) - is of increasing concern. This review examines the effects of antiobesity medications, particularly glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor analogs (GLP-1 RA), on body composition, the risk of sarcopenia, and strategies to preserve muscle mass during pharmacological weight loss.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Studies have shown that while GLP-1 RA are effective in reducing fat mass, up to 40% of the total weight loss can come from FFM. However, it is important to distinguish between FFM and SM, as FFM includes nonmuscle components. Resistance training and adequate protein intake can mitigate muscle loss, but the evidence for their efficacy in the context of GLP-1 RA therapy is mixed. If these measures are insufficient to prevent and maintain muscle mass, the use of some nutrients, such as branched chain amino acids, creatine, leucine, omega-3 fatty acids and vitamin D, may be beneficial. Newer pharmacological approaches, such as bimagrumab, a human monoclonal antibody that acts by binding to the activin type II receptor II (ActRII), and other activin or myostatin inhibitors, show promise in preserving muscle mass while promoting fat loss.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">GLP-1 RA therapy for obesity should include resistance training, optimal protein intake and, if needed, specific nutrients and possibly pharmacological interventions to preserve muscle mass. Further research is needed to assess the long-term effects of GLP-1 RA on muscle health and to refine strategies to prevent sarcopenia in patients undergoing pharmacological weight loss.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chavez</LastName><ForeName>Alvaro M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Nutrition, University Hospital 12 de Octubre, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carrasco Barria</LastName><ForeName>Ruben</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le&#xf3;n-Sanz</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804399</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1363-1950</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>89750-14-1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D052216">Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019440">Anti-Obesity Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000067757">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000097789">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glucagon-Like Peptide 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018529" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutritional Support</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019440" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anti-Obesity Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067757" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000097789" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40401903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000001130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00075197-990000000-00219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Yang S, McCarthy C, et al. Proportion of caloric restriction-induced weight loss as skeletal muscle. Obesity (SilverSpring) 2024; 32:32&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao R, Lin C, Cai X, et al. Characterizing body composition modifying effects of a glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor-based agonist: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab 2025; 27:259&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal AA, Narayan A, Stanford FC. Body composition in anti obesity medication trials&#x2014;beyond scales. JAMA Intern Med 2024; 184:341&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubin RL, Heymsfield SB, Ravussin E, Greenway FL. Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist-based agents and weight loss composition: Filling the gaps. Diabetes Obes Metab 2024; 26:5503&#x2013;5518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Heymsfield SB. Fundamental body composition principles provide context for fat-free and skeletal muscle loss with GLP-1 RA treatments. J Endocr Soc 2024; 8:bvae164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Gonzalez MCC, Shen W, et al. Weight loss composition is one-fourth fat-free mass: a critical re view and critique of this widely cited rule. Obes Rev 2014; 15:310&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen TAH, Van Every DW, Phillips SM. The impact and utility of very low-calorie diets: the role of exercise and protein in preserving skeletal muscle mass. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 2023; 26:521&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x17d;i&#x17e;ka O, Haluz&#xed;k M, Jude EB. Pharmacological treatment of obesity in older adults. Drugs Aging 2024; 41:881&#x2013;896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heise T, DeVries JH, Urva S, et al. Tirzepatide reduces appetite, energy intake, and fat mass in people with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care 2023; 46:998&#x2013;1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeland IJ, Linge J, Birkenfeld AL. Changes in lean body mass with glucagon-like peptide-1-based therapies and mitigation strategies. Diabetes Obes Metab 2024; 26: (Suppl 4): 16&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong J, Park S, Kim TH, et al. Worldwide burden of antidiabetic drug-induced sarcopenia: An international pharmacovigilance study. Arch Gerontol Geriatr 2025; 129:105656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linge J, Birkenfeld AL, Neeland IJ. Muscle mass and glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists: adaptive or maladaptive response to weight loss? Circulation 2024; 150:1288&#x2013;1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey A, Patel KV, Segar MW, et al. Effect of liraglutide on thigh muscle fat and muscle composition in adults with overweight or obesity: results from a randomized clinical trial. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2024; 15:1072&#x2013;1083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakegawa T, Sugimoto K, Saito K, et al. Favorable liver and skeletal muscle changes in patients with MASLD and T2DM receiving glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist: a prospective cohort study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2024; 103:e38444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte C, Hall KD, Klein S. Is weight loss-induced muscle mass loss clinically relevant? JAMA 2024; 332:9&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Abildstrom SZ, Borlaug BA, et al. Semaglutide in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity. N Engl J Med 2023; 389:1069&#x2013;1084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driggin E, Goyal P. Malnutrition and sarcopenia as reasons for caution with GLP-1 receptor agonist use in HFpEF. J Card Fail 2024; 30:610&#x2013;612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair AJ, Abdelhafiz AH. Metabolic impact of frailty changes diabetes trajectory. Metabolites 2023; 13:295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bikou A, Dermiki-Gkana F, Penteris M, et al. A systematic review of the effect of semaglutide on lean mass: insights from clinical trials. Expert Opin Pharmacother 2024; 25:611&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcleod JC, Currier BS, Lowisz CV, Phillips SM. The influence of resistance exercise training prescription variables on skeletal muscle mass, strength, and physical function in healthy adults: an umbrella review. J Sport Health Sci 2024; 13:47&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanick JI, Butsch WS, Christensen SM, et al. Strategies for minimizing muscle loss during use of incretin-mimetic drugs for treatment of obesity. Obes Rev 2025; 26:e13841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisco G, Disoteo OE, De Tullio A, et al. Sarcopenia and diabetes: a detrimental liaison of advancing age. Nutrients 2023; 16:63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Kackley ML, Buga A. Nutritional considerations during major weight loss therapy: focus on optimal protein and a low-carbohydrate dietary pattern. Curr Nutr Rep 2024; 13:422&#x2013;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dash S. Opportunities to optimize lifestyle interventions in combination with glucagon-like peptide-1-based therapy. Diabetes Obes Metab 2024; 26: (Suppl 4): 3&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigo-Carb&#xf3; C, Madinaveitia-Nisarre L, P&#xe9;rez-Calahorra S, et al. Low-calorie, high-protein diets, regardless of protein source, improve glucose metabolism and cardiometabolic profiles in subjects with prediabetes or type 2 diabetes and overweight or obesity. Diabetes Obes Metab 2025; 27:268&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-G&#xf3;mez JJ, Ramos-Bachiller B, Primo-Mart&#xed;n D, et al. Effect on body composition of a meal-replacement progression diet in patients 1&#x200a;month after bariatric surgery. Nutrients 2023; 16:106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locatelli JC, Costa JG, Haynes A, et al. Incretin-based weight loss pharmacotherapy: can resistance exercise optimize changes in body composition? Diabetes Care 2024; 47:1718&#x2013;1730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellen RH, Girotto OS, Marques EB, et al. Insights into pathogenesis, nutritional and drug approach in Sarcopenia: a systematic review. Biomedicines 2023; 11:136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao CD, Huang SW, Chen HC, et al. Comparative efficacy of different protein supplements on muscle mass, strength, and physical indices of sarcopenia among community-dwelling, hospitalized or institutionalized older adults undergoing resistance training: a network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Nutrients 2024; 16:941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoonin W, Shantavasinkul PC, Santivarangkna C, et al. Eicosapentaenoic acid and branched-chain amino acids fortified complete nutrition drink improved muscle strength in older individuals with inadequate protein intake. Front Nutr 2023; 10:1164469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcangeli V, Youssef L, Dulac M, et al. Impact of high-intensity interval training with or without l-citrulline on physical performance, skeletal muscle, and adipose tissue in obese older adults. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2022; 13:1526&#x2013;1540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang MC, Choo YJ. Effects of whey protein, leucine, and vitamin D supplementation in patients with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 2023; 19:521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson MI, Xhuti D, de Maat NM, et al. Obesity and metabolic disease impair the anabolic response to protein supplementation and resistance exercise: a retrospective analysis of a randomized clinical trial with implications for aging, sarcopenic obesity, and weight management. Nutrients 2024; 16:4407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang J, Qin L, Zhong J, et al. GLP-1RA liraglutide and semaglutide improves obesity-induced muscle atrophy via SIRT1 pathway. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes 2023; 16:2433&#x2013;2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng F, Wu W, Fan X, et al. Dulaglutide protects mice against diabetic sarcopenia-mediated muscle injury by inhibiting inflammation and regulating the differentiation of myoblasts. Int J Endocrinol 2023; doi: 10.1155/2023/9926462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/9926462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papakonstantinou I, Tsioufis K, Katsi V. Spotlight on the mechanism of action of semaglutide. Curr Issues Mol Biol 2024; 46:14514&#x2013;14541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufail E, Sanyal S, Mithal A, et al. The role of glucagon-like peptides in osteosarcopenia. J Endocrinol 2025; 264:e240210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osaka T, Hamaguchi M, Fukui M. Favorable appendicular skeletal muscle mass changes in older patients with type 2 diabetes receiving glp-1 receptor agonist and basal insulin co-therapy. Clin Med Insights Endocrinol Diabetes 2023; 16:11795514231161885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witham MD, Granic A, Pearson E, et al. Repurposing drugs for diabetes mellitus as potential pharmacological treatments for sarcopenia &#x2013; a narrative review. Drugs Aging 2023; 40:703&#x2013;719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melson E, Ashraf U, Papamargaritis D, et al. What is the pipeline for future medications for obesity? Int J Obes 2024; 49:433&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled multicenter study of intravenous bimagrumab, alone or in addition to open label subcutaneous semaglutide, to investigate the efficacy and safety in overweight or obese men and women. Clinical Trial.Gov NCT05616013. Last Update Posted 2025/01/28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanakis K, Kokkorakis M, Mantzoros CS. The impact of weight loss on fat-free mass, muscle, bone and hematopoiesis health: Implications for emerging pharmacotherapies aiming at fat reduction and lean mass preservation. Metabolism 2024; 161:156057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Study to test if trevogrumab or trevogrumab with garetosmab when taken with semaglutide is safe and how well they work in adult patients with obesity for weight loss and fat loss (COURAGE). ClinicalTrials.gov ID NCT06299098. Last Update Posted 2024/11/25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moiz A, Filion KB, Toutounchi H, et al. Efficacy and safety of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists for weight loss among adults without diabetes: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Ann Intern Med 2025; 178:199&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgojo-Mart&#xed;nez JJ, Mezquita-Raya P, Carretero-G&#xf3;mez J. Clinical recommendations to manage gastrointestinal adverse events in patients treated with glp-1 receptor agonists: a multidisciplinary expert consensus. J Clin Med 2022; 12:145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen S, Robinson K, Thomas S, Williams DR. Dietary intake by patients taking GLP-1 and dual GIP/GLP-1 receptor agonists: a narrative review and discussion of research needs. Obes Pillars 2024; 11:100121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almandoz JP, Wadden TA, Tewksbury C, et al. Nutritional considerations with antiobesity medications. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2024; 32:1613&#x2013;1631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadden TA, Chao AM, Moore M, et al. The role of lifestyle modification with second-generation antiobesity medications: comparisons, questions, and clinical opportunities. Curr Obes Rep 2023; 12:453&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>