<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34652335</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute Neuromuscular Response to Team Sports-Specific Running, Resistance, and Concurrent Training: A Crossover Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>456</StartPage><EndPage>465</EndPage><MedlinePgn>456-465</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002804</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">This study aimed to examine the changes in muscle contractile function, voluntary activation, and muscle damage after lower limb resistance training (RT), intermittent sprint exercise, and concurrent training (CT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Ten male, recreational team sport athletes with a history of RT participated in a randomized crossover study involving an intermittent sprint protocol (ISP), lower limb RT, and CT (ISP and RT separated by 1 h). Before (PRE), immediately after (POST), 24 h and 48 h after each exercise condition, quadriceps muscle activation, voluntary activation, muscle contractile function (evoked twitch responses), creatine kinase, muscle soreness, and Profile of Mood States (POMS)-fatigue were recorded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Quadriceps contractile function was hampered in all conditions, with a significantly greater decline observed POST RT (58.4% &#xb1; 18.0%) and CT (54.8% &#xb1; 8.6%) compared with ISP (35.9% &#xb1; 10.7%, P &lt; 0.05), recovering at 48 h after all exercise conditions. POMS-fatigue ratings increased at POST in all conditions with CT and ISP eliciting the greatest increase, returning to baseline 48 h after all exercise conditions. Quadriceps muscle soreness remained elevated from PRE at 48 h after all exercise conditions. No changes across time were observed for voluntary activation and quadriceps surface EMG amplitude after any exercise condition. The volume and load lifted in the RT session was unaffected by previous intermittent exercise (ISP) in CT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">RT impairs contractile function, which is not exacerbated when performed 1 h after the ISP. Contractile function after all exercise conditions displayed the same recovery profile (48 h) despite the postexercise decrement being smaller after the ISP compared with RT and CT. Previous intermittent sprint exercise does not negatively affect the volume of exercise performed in a lower limb RT session.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cross</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Science, Western Sydney University, Penrith, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lovell</LastName><ForeName>Ric</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Science, Western Sydney University, Penrith, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>Paul W</ForeName><Initials>PW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siegler</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035002" MajorTopicYN="N">Lower Extremity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="N">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000085944" MajorTopicYN="Y">Team Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34652335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202203000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Enright K, Morton J, Iga J, Drust B. Implementing concurrent-training and nutritional strategies in professional football: a complex challenge for coaches and practitioners. Sci Med Football . 2017;1(1):65&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones TW, Smith A, Macnaughton LS, French DN. Strength and conditioning and concurrent training practices in elite rugby union. J Strength Cond Res . 2016;30(12):3354&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross R, Siegler J, Marshall P, Lovell R. Scheduling of training and recovery during the in-season weekly micro-cycle: insights from team sport practitioners. Eur J Sport Sci . 2019;19(10):1287&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bishop DJ, Stepto NK. Interference between concurrent resistance and endurance exercise: molecular bases and the role of individual training variables. Sports Med . 2014;44(6):743&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownstein CG, Dent JP, Parker P, et al. Etiology and recovery of neuromuscular fatigue following competitive soccer match-play. Front Physiol . 2017;8:831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pointon M, Duffield R. Cold water immersion recovery after simulated collision sport exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2012;44(2):206&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparkes W, Turner A, Weston M, Russell M, Johnston M, Kilduff L. Neuromuscular, biochemical, endocrine, and mood responses to small-sided games&#x2019; training in professional soccer. J Strength Cond Res . 2018;32(9):2569&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PWM, Cross R, Haynes M. The fatigue of a full body resistance exercise session in trained men. J Sci Med Sport . 2018;21(4):422&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metcalf E, Hagstrom AD, Marshall PW. Trained females exhibit less fatigability than trained males after a heavy knee extensor resistance exercise session. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2019;119(1):181&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas K, Brownstein CG, Dent J, Parker P, Goodall S, Howatson G. Neuromuscular fatigue and recovery after heavy resistance, jump, and sprint training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2018;50(12):2526&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall S, Thomas K, Harper LD, et al. The assessment of neuromuscular fatigue during 120 min of simulated soccer exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2017;117(4):687&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eklund D, Schumann M, Kraemer WJ, Izquierdo M, Taipale RS, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute endocrine and force responses and long-term adaptations to same-session combined strength and endurance training in women. J Strength Cond Res . 2016;30(1):164&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann M, Eklund D, Taipale RS, et al. Acute neuromuscular and endocrine responses and recovery to single-session combined endurance and strength loadings: &#x201c;order effect&#x201d; in untrained young men. J Strength Cond Res . 2013;27(2):421&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale RS, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute hormonal and force responses to combined strength and endurance loadings in men and women: the &#x201c;order effect.&#x201d; PLoS One . 2013;8(2):e55051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale RS, Schumann M, Mikkola J, et al. Acute neuromuscular and metabolic responses to combined strength and endurance loadings: the &#x201c;order effect&#x201d; in recreationally endurance trained runners. J Sports Sci . 2014;32(12):1155&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastin PB, Hunkin SL, Fahrner B, Robertson S. Deceleration, acceleration, and impacts are strong contributors to muscle damage in professional Australian football. J Strength Cond Res . 2019;33(12):3374&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton REM, Twist C. Number of directional changes alters the physiological, perceptual, and neuromuscular responses of netball players during intermittent shuttle running. J Strength Cond Res . 2015;29(10):2731&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston MJ, Cook CJ, Drake D, Costley L, Johnston JP, Kilduff LP. The neuromuscular, biochemical, and endocrine responses to a single-session vs. double-session training day in elite athletes. J Strength Cond Res . 2016;30(11):3098&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparkes W, Turner A, Cook C, et al. The neuromuscular, endocrine and mood responses to a single versus double training session day in soccer players. J Sci Med Sport . 2020;23(1):69&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gathercole RJ, Sporer BC, Stellingwerff T, Sleivert GG. Comparison of the capacity of different jump and sprint field tests to detect neuromuscular fatigue. J Strength Cond Res . 2015;29(9):2522&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone JJ, Murtagh CF, Morgans R, Burgess DJ, Morton JP, Drust B. Countermovement jump performance is not affected during an in-season training microcycle in elite youth soccer players. J Strength Cond Res . 2015;29(3):752&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DG, Lamb GD, Westerblad H. Skeletal muscle fatigue: cellular mechanisms. Physiol Rev . 2008;88(1):287&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC. Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiol Rev . 2001;81(4):1725&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster DT, Gill N, Cronin J, McGuigan M. The development, retention and decay rates of strength and power in elite rugby union, rugby league and American football: a systematic review. Sports Med . 2013;43(5):367&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffield R, Marino FE. Effects of pre-cooling procedures on intermittent-sprint exercise performance in warm conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2007;100(6):727&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murlasits Z, Kneffel Z, Thalib L. The physiological effects of concurrent strength and endurance training sequence: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci . 2018;36(11):1212&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNair DM, Lorr M, Droppleman LF. Manual for Profile of Mood States . San Diego (CA): Education and Industrial Testing Service; 1971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijur PE, Silver W, Gallagher EJ. Reliability of the visual analog scale for measurement of acute pain. Acad Emerg Med . 2001;8(12):1153&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res . 2001;15(1):109&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, Folland J, Tillin N, Duchateau J. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2016;116(6):1091&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merton PA. Voluntary strength and fatigue. J Physiol . 1954;123(3):553&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strojnik V, Komi PV. Neuromuscular fatigue after maximal stretch-shortening cycle exercise. J Appl Physiol . 1998;84(1):344&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences . Academic Press; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G* Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods . 2007;39(2):175&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM. Mechanisms of muscle fatigue: central factors and task dependency. J Electromyogr Kinesiol . 1995;5(3):141&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker AJ, Kostov KG, Miller RG, Weiner MW. Slow force recovery after long-duration exercise: metabolic and activation factors in muscle fatigue. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1993;74(5):2294&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Hubal MJ. Exercise-induced muscle damage in humans. Am J Phys Med Rehabil . 2002;81(11 Suppl):S52&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Giannini D, Milner-Brown HS, et al. Effects of fatiguing exercise on high-energy phosphates, force, and EMG: evidence for three phases of recovery. Muscle Nerve . 1987;10(9):810&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skurvydas A, Mamkus G, Kamandulis S, Dudoniene V, Valanciene D, Westerblad H. Mechanisms of force depression caused by different types of physical exercise studied by direct electrical stimulation of human quadriceps muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2016;116(11):2215&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownstein CG, Ansdell P, &#x160;karabot J, et al. The effect of phase change material on recovery of neuromuscular function following competitive soccer match-play. Front Physiol . 2019;10:647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Van Someren KA. The prevention and treatment of exercise-induced muscle damage. Sports Med . 2008;38(6):483&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza EO, Tricoli V, Franchini E, Paulo AC, Regazzini M, Ugrinowitsch C. Acute effect of two aerobic exercise modes on maximum strength and strength endurance. J Strength Cond Res . 2007;21(4):1286&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveritt M, Abernethy PJ. Acute effects of high-intensity endurance exercise on subsequent resistance activity. J Strength Cond Res . 1999;13(1):47&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Kang J, Porfido TM, et al. Acute resistance exercise performance is negatively impacted by prior aerobic endurance exercise. J Strength Cond Res . 2016;30(10):2667&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed JP, Schilling BK, Murlasits Z. Acute neuromuscular and metabolic responses to concurrent endurance and resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res . 2013;27(3):793&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AN, Stewart PF. Strength and conditioning for soccer players. Strength Cond J . 2014;36(4):1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryman N, Mujika I, Bosquet L. Concurrent training for sports performance: the 2 sides of the medal. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2019;14(3):279&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Muscle fatigue: what, why and how it influences muscle function. J Physiol . 2008;586(1):11&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twist C, Highton J. Monitoring fatigue and recovery in rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2013;8(5):467&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK. The relevance of sex differences in performance fatigability. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2016;48(11):2247&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>