<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">12937451</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-162X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2001</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of athletic training</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Athl Train</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Low-Dose Creatine Supplementation Versus Creatine Loading in Collegiate Football Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>124</StartPage><EndPage>129</EndPage><MedlinePgn>124-129</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>OBJECTIVE: To compare the effects of low doses of creatine and creatine loading on strength, urinary creatinine concentration, and percentage of body fat. DESIGN AND SETTING: Division IA collegiate football players took creatine monohydrate for 10 weeks during a sport-specific, periodized, off-season strength and conditioning program. One-repetition maximum (1-RM) squat, urinary creatinine concentrations, and percentage of body fat were analyzed. SUBJECTS: Twenty-five highly trained, Division IA collegiate football players with at least 1 year of college playing experience. MEASUREMENTS: We tested strength with a 1-RM squat exercise before, during, and after creatine supplementation. Percentage of body fat was measured by hydrostatic weighing before and after supplementation. Urinary creatinine concentration was measured via light spectrophotometer at 0, 1, 3, 7, 14, 21, 28, 35, 42, 48, 56, and 63 days. An analysis of variance with repeated measures was computed to compare means for all variables. RESULTS: Creatine supplementation had no significant group, time, or interaction effects on strength, urinary creatinine concentration, or percentage of body fat. However, significant time effects were found for 1-RM squat and fat-free mass in all groups. CONCLUSIONS: Our data suggest that creatine monohydrate in any amount does not have any beneficial ergogenic effects in highly trained collegiate football players. However, a proper resistance training stimulus for 10 weeks can increase strength and fat-free mass in highly trained athletes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilder</LastName><ForeName>Nathan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ohio University, Athens, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deivert</LastName><ForeName>Richard G.</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagerman</LastName><ForeName>Frederick</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilders</LastName><ForeName>Roger</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Athl Train</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9301647</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1062-6050</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2003</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2003</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2003</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2001</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC155521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Balsom PD, Ekblom B, S&#xf6;derlund K, Sjodin B, Hultman E. Creatine supplementation and dynamic high intensity intermittent exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 1993;3:143&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey A, Constantin-Theodosiu D, Howell S, Hultman E, Greenhaff PL. Creatine ingestion favorably affects performance and muscle metabolism during maximal exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1996;271(1 pt 1):E31&#x2013;E37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8760078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekblom B. Effects of creatine supplementation on performance. Am J Sports Med. 1996;24(suppl 6):S38&#x2013;S39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8947425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becque MD, Lochmann JD, Melrose D. Effects of creatine supplementation during strength training on 1RM and body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;27(suppl):146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Snell PG, Rodriguez R, Almada AL, Mitchell TL. The effect of creatine monohydrate ingestion on anaerobic power indices, muscular strength and body composition. Acta Physiol Scand. 1995;153:207&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7778463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson B, Cutler M, Moody A, Lawerence S, Goodman C, Randall N. Effects of oral creatine loading on single and repeated maximal short sprints. Aust J Sci Med Sport. 1995;27:56&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8599745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Pyne DB, Telford RD. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on single-effort sprint performance in elite swimmers. Int J Sport Nutr. 1996;6:222&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8876342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke WH, Grandjean PW, Barnes WS. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on power output and fatigue during bicycle ergometry. J Appl Physiol. 1995;78:670&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7759438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Chatard JC, Lacoste L, Barale F, Geyssant A. Creatine supplementation does not improve sprint performance in competitive swimmers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:1435&#x2013;1441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8933496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odland ML, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA, Elorriaga A, Borgmann A. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on muscle [Pcr] and short-term maximum power output. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:216&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9044225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegenfuss TN, Lemon P, Rogers MR, Ross R, Yarasheski YE. Acute creatine ingestion: effects on muscle volume, anaerobic power, fluid volumes, and protein turnover. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27(suppl):127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisk SS, Kreider RB. Creatine controversy? Strength Condition J. 1999;21:14&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Bodin K, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on skeletal muscle phosphocreatine resynthesis. Am J Physiol. 1994;266(5 pt 1):E725&#x2013;E730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8203511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Casey A, Short AH, Harris R, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Influence of oral creatine supplementation of muscle torque during repeated bouts of maximal voluntary exercise in man. Clin Sci (Colch) 1993;84:565&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8504634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson KD, Smodic B, Hill R. The effects of creatine monohydrate supplementation on muscular power and work. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:S251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan D, Berg K, Latin RW, Wagner JC, Reimers K. Effects of varying dosages of oral creatine relative to fat-free body mass on strength and body composition. J Strength Condition Res. 1998;12:104&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly VG, Jenkins DG. Effects of oral creatine supplementation on near maximal strength and repeated sets of high intensity bench press exercise. J Strength Condition Res. 1998;12:109&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters BM, Lantz CD, Mayhew JL. Effects of oral creatine monohydrate and creatine phosphate supplementation on maximal strength indices, body composition, and blood pressure. J Strength Condition Res. 1999;13:3&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Goris M, Van Hecke P, Leemputte M, Vangerven L, Hespel P. Long-term creatine intake is beneficial to muscle performance during resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:2055&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Soderlund K, Timmons JA, Cederblad G, Greenhaff PL. Muscle creatine loading in men. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:232&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8828669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossiter HB, Cannell ER, Jakeman PM. The effect of oral creatine supplementation on the 1000-m performance of competitive rowers. J Sports Sci. 1996;14:175&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8737325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Colch) 1992;83:367&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JF. Creatine and phosphocreatine: a review of their use in exercise and sport. J Athl Train. 1997;32:45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1319235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Boetes M, Bush JA, Putukian M, Sebastianelli WJ, Kraemer WJ. Response of testosterone and cortisol concentrations to high-intensity resistance exercise following creatine supplementation. J Strength Condition Res. 1997;11:182&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL. Creatine and its application as an ergogenic aid. Int J Sport Nutr. 1995;5:S100&#x2013;S110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7550252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsom PD, Soderlund K, Sjodin B, Ekblom B. Skeletal muscle metabolism during short duration high-intensity exercise: influence of creatine supplementation. Acta Physiol Scand. 1995;154:303&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7572228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Contantin-Teodosiu D, Casey A, Hultman E. The effect of oral creatine supplementation on skeletal muscle ATP degradation during repeated bouts of maximal voluntary exercise in man. J Physiol. 1994;476:84P.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birch R, Noble D, Greenhaff PL. The influence of dietary creatine supplementation on performance during repeated bouts of maximal isokinetic cycling in man. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69:268&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8001541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson B, Goodman C, Lawrence S, et al. Muscle phosphocreatine repletion following single and repeated short sprint efforts. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 1997;7:206&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9241025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Van Hecke P, Van Leemputte M, Vanstapel F, Hespel P. Phosphocreatine resynthesis is not affected by creatine loading. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:236&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10063812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Ferreira M, Wilson M, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on body composition, strength, and sprint performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30:73&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>