<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30363292</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2061-1617</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Interventional medicine &amp; applied science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Interv Med Appl Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Response of creatine kinase and lactate dehydrogenase enzymes to rest interval between sets and set-repetition configuration during bouts of eccentric exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>83</StartPage><EndPage>86</EndPage><MedlinePgn>83-86</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1556/1646.10.2018.09</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Various studies have demonstrated that different rest intervals and set-repetition have a significant effect on hormonal and metabolic responses. These factors can lead to different muscle damage responses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty untrained subjects (25.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.068 years, height: 1.74&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.97&#xa0;cm, and weight: 30.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.48&#xa0;kg) in three sessions of eccentric resistance exercise with 24-h rest between each session participated in this study. Subjects were divided into four groups of 10 subjects who performed 50 eccentric contractions with different number of 5 and 10 sets, 5 and 10 repetitions, and the interset rest interval 1 and 3&#xa0;min with 85% of one repetition maximum (1RM). Creatine kinase and lactate dehydrogenase were measured immediately before each session, immediately after each session, and 24&#xa0;h after the last training session. Variance analysis with repeated measurement and Bonferroni post hoc test were used for statistical analysis of data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There is no significant difference in creatine kinase and lactate dehydrogenase between four groups at different time points (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The repetition of eccentric exercise for three consecutive days causes muscle damage that is independent of manipulating the interset rest intervals and the number of set-repetition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Hossein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, University of Birjand, Birjand, I.R. Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afzalpour</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Esmaiel</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, University of Birjand, Birjand, I.R. Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ievary</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Hossein Abtahi</ForeName><Initials>SHA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Department, University of Gonabad, Gonabad, I.R. Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Hungary</Country><MedlineTA>Interv Med Appl Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101539233</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2061-1617</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">creatine kinase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eccentric exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lactate dehydrogenase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rest interval</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6167626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/1646.10.2018.09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Frid&#xe9;n J, Lieber RL: Eccentric exercise-induced injuries to contractile and cytoskeletal muscle fibre components. Acta Physiol Scand 171, 321&#x2013;326 (2001)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11412144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Donnelly AE, Gleeson M, Whiting PH, Walker KA, Clough PJ: Delayed-onset muscle damage and lipid peroxidation in man after a downhill run. Muscle Nerve 12, 332&#x2013;336 (1989)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2770784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frid&#xe9;n J, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, Ekblom B: Myofibrillar damage following intense eccentric exercise in man. Int J Sports Med 4, 170&#x2013;176 (1983)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6629599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne C, Twist C, Eston R: Neuromuscular function after exercise-induced muscle damage: Theoretical and applied implications. Sports Med 34, 49&#x2013;69 (2004)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiPasquale DM, Bloch RJ, Lovering RM: Determinants of the repeated bout effect following lengthening contractions. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 90, 816&#x2013;824 (2011)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3169747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi L: Effect of subcutaneous nerve stimulation and massage on delayed onset muscle soreness of functional markers for the students of Tehran. Faculty of Physical Education, Master&#x2019;s Thesis, School of Physical Education, Central Tehran Branch, Tehran: (2002)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Sakamoto K, Newton M, Sacco P: How long does the protective effect on eccentric exercise induce muscle damage last? Med Sci Sports Exerc 33, 1490&#x2013;1495 (2001)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11528337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodenburg JB, Steenbeek D, Schiereck P, B&#xe4;r PR: Warm-up, stretching and massage diminish harmful effects of eccentric exercise. Int J Sports Med 15, 414&#x2013;419 (1994)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8002121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Gaze D, van Someren KA: The efficacy of ice massage in the treatment of exercise-induced muscle damage. Scand J Med Sci Sports 15, 416&#x2013;422 (2005)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16293154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM: Muscle damage following repeated bouts of high force eccentric exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 27, 1263&#x2013;1269 (1995)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8531624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary MA, Kimura IF, Sitler MR, Kendrick ZV: Temporal pattern of the repeated bout effect of eccentric exercise on delayed onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train 37, 32&#x2013;36 (2002)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues BM, Dantas E, Salles BF, Miranda H, Koch AJ, Willardson JM: Creatine kinase and lactate dehydrogenase responses after upper body resistance exercise with different rest intervals. J Strength Cond Res 24, 1657&#x2013;1662 (2010)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20508471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew D, Thyfault J, Koch A: Rest-interval length affects leukocyte levels during heavy resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res 19, 16&#x2013;22 (2005)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazpour N, Carroll TJ, Riek S, Carson RG: Early alterations in serum creatine kinase and total cholesterol following high intensity eccentric muscle actions. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 44, 193&#x2013;199 (2004)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15470318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson K, Van Someren K, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T: Repeated bout effect after maximal eccentric exercise. Int J Sports Med 28, 557&#x2013;563 (2007)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17373600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan R, Newton M, Nosaka K: Effects of set-repetition configuration in eccentric exercise on muscle damage and the repeated bout effect. Eur J Appl Physiol 7, 2653&#x2013;2661 (2011)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Hsieh SS: Effects of a 7-days eccentric training period on muscle damage and inflammation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33, 1732&#x2013;1738 (2001)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi H, Sahebazamani M, Ghahraman Tabrizi K: The effect of repeated bouts of eccentric exercise on some of biochemical markers of delayed onset muscle soreness. Int J Appl Exerc Physiol 4, 34&#x2013;39 (2015)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Rahimi R: The effect of different rest intervals between multiple bench press bouts. S Afr J Res Sport Phys Educ Recreation 33, 1&#x2013;8 (2011)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM: A brief review: Factors affecting the length of the rest interval between resistance exercise sets. J Strength Cond Res 20, 978&#x2013;984 (2006)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira R, Machado M: Resistance exercise- induced microinjuries do not depend on 1 or 3 minutes rest time interval between series. Int J Sci 4, 1885&#x2013;3137 (2007)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>