<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37650704</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6519</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in clinical nutrition and metabolic care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evidence-based nutritional approaches to enhance exercise adaptations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>514</StartPage><EndPage>520</EndPage><MedlinePgn>514-520</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000975</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The purpose of this opinion paper is to provide current-day and evidence-based information regarding dietary supplements that support resistance training adaptations or acutely enhance strength-power or endurance performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Several independent lines of evidence support that higher protein diets, which can be readily achieved through animal-based protein supplements, optimize muscle mass during periods of resistance training, and this likely facilitates strength increases. Creatine monohydrate supplementation and peri-exercise caffeine consumption also enhance strength and power through distinct mechanisms. Supplements that favorably affect aspects of endurance performance include peri-exercise caffeine, nitrate-containing supplements (e.g., beet root juice), and sodium bicarbonate consumption. Further, beta-alanine supplementation can enhance high-intensity endurance exercise efforts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Select dietary supplements can enhance strength and endurance outcomes, and take-home recommendations will be provided for athletes and practitioners aiming to adopt these strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moulding</LastName><ForeName>Blake</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology and Health Studies, University of Regina, Regina, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forbes</LastName><ForeName>Scott C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education Studies, Faculty of Education, Brandon University, Brandon, MB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Candow</LastName><ForeName>Darren G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology and Health Studies, University of Regina, Regina, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804399</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1363-1950</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37650704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00075197-202311000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title/><Reference><Citation>Nutritional Supplements Market Size, Share &amp; Trends Analysis Report By Product, By Consumer Group, By Formulation, By Application, By Packaging, By Composition, By Gender, By Sales Channel, and Segment Forecasts, 2022&#x2013;2030. Available at: www.grandviewresearch.com .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher J, Mallick M, El Khoury D. Prevalence of dietary supplement use among athletes worldwide: a scoping review. Nutrients 2022; 14:4109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Roberts MD, et al. Exercise &amp; sports nutrition review update: research &amp; recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2018; 15:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale K, Getzin A. Nutrition and supplement update for the endurance athlete: review and recommendations. Nutrients 2019; 11:1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeling P, Castell LM, Derave W, et al. Sports foods and dietary supplements for optimal function and performance enhancement in track-and-field athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 2019; 29:198&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, et al. IOC consensus statement: dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 2018; 28:104&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. The impact of protein quality on the promotion of resistance exercise-induced changes in muscle mass. Nutr Metab 2016; 13:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatri M, Naughton RJ, Clifford T, et al. The effects of collagen peptide supplementation on body composition, collagen synthesis, and recovery from joint injury and exercise: a systematic review. Amino Acids 2021; 53:1493&#x2013;1506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermans WJH, Senden JM, Churchward-Venne TA, et al. Insects are a viable protein source for human consumption: from insect protein digestion to postprandial muscle protein synthesis in vivo in humans: a double-blind randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr 2021; 114:934&#x2013;944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Pinckaers PJ, Smeets JS, et al. Myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis rates do not differ in young men following the ingestion of carbohydrate with whey, soy, or leucine-enriched soy protein after concurrent resistance-and endurance-type exercise. J Nutr 2019; 149:210&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oikawa SY, Bahniwal R, Holloway TM, et al. Potato protein isolate stimulates muscle protein synthesis at rest and with resistance exercise in young women. Nutrients 2020; 12:1235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vliet S, Shy EL, Abou Sawan S, et al. Consumption of whole eggs promotes greater stimulation of postexercise muscle protein synthesis than consumption of isonitrogenous amounts of egg whites in young men. Am J Clin Nutr 2017; 106:1401&#x2013;1412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaromskyte G, Prokopidis K, Ioannidis T, et al. Evaluating the leucine trigger hypothesis to explain the postprandial regulation of muscle protein synthesis in young and older adults: a systematic review. Front Nutr 2021; 8:685165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, McKellar SR, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med 2018; 52:376&#x2013;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, McLellan TM, Lieberman HR. The effects of protein supplements on muscle mass, strength, and aerobic and anaerobic power in healthy adults: a systematic review. Sports Med 2015; 45:111&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim MT, Pan BJ, Toh DWK, et al. Animal protein versus plant protein in supporting lean mass and muscle strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Nutrients 2021; 13:661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Bryan KR, Doering TM, Morton RW, et al. Do multiingredient protein supplements augment resistance training-induced gains in skeletal muscle mass and strength? A systematic review and meta-analysis of 35 trials. Br J Sports Med 2020; 54:573&#x2013;581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon AA, Krieger JW. The effect of protein timing on muscle strength and hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2013; 10:53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J. High-protein diets in trained individuals. Res Sports Med 2019; 27:195&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzulla M, Abou Sawan S, Williamson E, et al. Protein intake to maximize whole-body anabolism during postexercise recovery in resistance-trained men with high habitual intakes is severalfold greater than the current recommended dietary allowance. J Nutr 2020; 150:505&#x2013;511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Candow DG, Forbes SC, et al. Common questions and misconceptions about creatine supplementation: what does the scientific evidence really show? J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2017; 14:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaviani M, Shaw K, Chilibeck PD. Benefits of creatine supplementation for vegetarians compared to omnivorous athletes: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2020; 17:3041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsevier, Negro M, Avanzato I, D&#x2019;Antona G. Creatine in skeletal muscle physiology. Nonvitamin and nonmineral nutritional supplements. 2019; 59&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Kaviani M, Candow DG, Zello GA. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Open Access J Sports Med 2017; 8:213&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delpino FM, Figueiredo LM, Forbes SC, et al. Influence of age, sex, and type of exercise on the efficacy of creatine supplementation on lean body mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Nutrition 2022; 103&#x2013;104:111791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos EEP, de Araujo RC, Candow DG, et al. Efficacy of creatine supplementation combined with resistance training on muscle strength and muscle mass in older females: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 2021; 13:3757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Ostojic SM, et al. Meta-analysis examining the importance of creatine ingestion strategies on lean tissue mass and strength in older adults. Nutrients 2021; 13:1912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke R, Pi&#xf1;ero A, Coleman M, et al. The effects of creatine supplementation combined with resistance training on regional measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Nutrients 2023; 15:2116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the national strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res 2019; 33:2019&#x2013;2052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chvasta TE, Cooke AR. Emptying and absorption of caffeine from the human stomach. Gastroenterology 1971; 61:838&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest NS, VanDusseldorp TA, Nelson MT, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: caffeine and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima-Silva AE, Cristina-Souza G, Silva-Cavalcante MD, et al. Caffeine during high-intensity whole-body exercise: an integrative approach beyond the central nervous system. Nutrients 2021; 13:2503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreto G, Loureiro LMR, Reis CEG, Saunders B. Effects of caffeine chewing gum supplementation on exercise performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 2023; 23:714&#x2013;725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira TT, da Silva JVF, Bueno NB. Effects of caffeine supplementation on muscle endurance, maximum strength, and perceived exertion in adults submitted to strength training: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 2021; 61:2587&#x2013;2600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Exploring the minimum ergogenic dose of caffeine on resistance exercise performance: a meta-analytic approach. Nutrition 2022; 97:111604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Del Coso J. Ergogenic effects of acute caffeine intake on muscular endurance and muscular strength in women: a meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18:5773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Caffeine ingestion enhances Wingate performance: a meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 2018; 18:219&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pickering C. The effects of caffeine ingestion on isokinetic muscular strength: a meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 2019; 22:353&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Mikulic P, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. The influence of caffeine supplementation on resistance exercise: a review. Sports Med 2019; 49:17&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindinger MI, Graham TE, Spriet LL. Caffeine attenuates the exercise-induced increase in plasma [K+] in humans. J Appl Physiol 1993; 74:1149&#x2013;1155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AS Jr, Speck AE, Canas PM, Cunha RA. Neuronal adenosine A(2A) receptors signal ergogenic effects of caffeine. Sci Rep 2020; 10:13414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Qiu B, Gao J, Del Coso J. Effects of caffeine intake on endurance running performance and time to exhaustion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 2022; 15:148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren GL, Park ND, Maresca RD, et al. Effect of caffeine ingestion on muscular strength and endurance: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2010; 42:1375&#x2013;1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poderoso JJ, Helfenberger K, Poderoso C. The effect of nitric oxide on mitochondrial respiration. Nitric Oxide 2019; 88:61&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamim CJR, Porto AA, Valenti VE, et al. Nitrate derived from beetroot juice lowers blood pressure in patients with arterial hypertension: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Nutr 2022; 9:823039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez R, Cuenca E, Mate-Munoz JL, et al. Effects of beetroot juice supplementation on cardiorespiratory endurance in athletes. A systematic review. Nutrients 2017; 9:43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM, Vanhatalo A, Seals DR, et al. Dietary nitrate and nitric oxide metabolism: mouth, circulation, skeletal muscle, and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2021; 53:280&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milton-Laskibar I, Martinez JA, Portillo MP. Current knowledge on beetroot bioactive compounds: role of nitrate and betalains in health and disease. Foods 2021; 10:1314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao C, Gupta S, Adli T, et al. The effects of dietary nitrate supplementation on endurance exercise performance and cardiorespiratory measures in healthy adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Pedisic Z, Saunders B, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: sodium bicarbonate and exercise performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Grgic I, Del Coso J, et al. Effects of sodium bicarbonate supplementation on exercise performance: an umbrella review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsevier, Varanoske AN, Stout JR, Hoffman JR. Effects of &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation and intramuscular carnosine content on exercise performance and health. Nutrition and enhanced sports performance. 2019; 327&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trexler ET, Smith-Ryan AE, Stout JR, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: beta-alanine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2015; 12:30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Hall R, Heikura IA, et al. Neither beetroot juice supplementation nor increased carbohydrate oxidation enhance economy of prolonged exercise in elite race walkers. Nutrients 2021; 13:2767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor LW, Wilborn C, Roberts MD, et al. Eight weeks of pre and postexercise whey protein supplementation increases lean body mass and improves performance in Division III collegiate female basketball players. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 2016; 41:249&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy MJ, Rushing BR, Sumner SJ, Hackney AC. Dietary supplements for athletic performance in women: beta-alanine, caffeine, and nitrate. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 2022; 32:311&#x2013;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B, Elliott-Sale K, Artioli GG, et al. Beta-alanine supplementation to improve exercise capacity and performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 2017; 51:658&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Chilibeck PD, Davidson KS, et al. The effect of whey protein supplementation with and without creatine monohydrate combined with resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscle strength. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 2001; 11:349&#x2013;364.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>