<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31692257</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4833</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>182</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of medical genetics. Part A</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Med Genet A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Myokine levels after resistance exercise in young adults with Prader-Willi syndrome (PWS).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>115</StartPage><EndPage>121</EndPage><MedlinePgn>115-121</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajmg.a.61391</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Individuals with PWS require marked caloric restriction and daily exercise to prevent morbid obesity. Lower energy expenditure, hypotonia, decreased muscle mass, and cognitive impairment make exercise challenging for this population. Exercise guidelines include resistance training as an important component. Myokine responses to resistance exercise may mediate beneficial metabolic effects. We aimed to determine if young PWS adults can perform a resistance exercise program and to measure myokine responses in PWS versus age- and BMI-matched controls. Each group included 11 participants (7M/4F). Ages and BMI for PWS and controls were 30.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.6 versus 30.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.3 years and 28.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.3 versus 28.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.2 kg/m<sup>2</sup> , respectively. Glucose, creatine kinase (CK), lactate, and myokines were measured before, after, 30, and 60 min after completing eight resistance exercises. Myokines were assayed using a multiplex myokine panel (Merck Millipore). CK was lower in PWS versus controls (62&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;16 vs.322&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;100 U/L, p &lt; .04). Peak lactate was 3.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.7 in PWS versus 7.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.7 mmol/Lin controls (p &lt; .001). The increase in interleukin-6 was similar in PWS and controls (41&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;16% and 35&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10%, respectively). Pre- and post-exercise levels of the six myokines assayed showed no consistent differences between the PWS and control participants. PWS young adults are capable of performing resistance/strength-building exercise. The lower CK and peak lactate levels in PWS may reflect decreased muscle mass in this population. Further studies are needed to determine optimal exercise regimens and assess the role of myokines incontributing to the metabolic phenotype of PWS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirsch</LastName><ForeName>Harry J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7499-4023</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multidisciplinary Prader-Willi Syndrome Clinic, Neuropediatric Unit, Department of Pediatrics, Shaare Zedek Medical Center, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gross-Tsur</LastName><ForeName>Varda</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multidisciplinary Prader-Willi Syndrome Clinic, Neuropediatric Unit, Department of Pediatrics, Shaare Zedek Medical Center, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Hebrew University School of Medicine, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabag</LastName><ForeName>Yanir</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Hebrew University School of Medicine, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nice</LastName><ForeName>Shachar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidi Rothberg Sport Medicine Center, Shaare Zedek Medical Center, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Genstil</LastName><ForeName>Larry</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multidisciplinary Prader-Willi Syndrome Clinic, Neuropediatric Unit, Department of Pediatrics, Shaare Zedek Medical Center, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benarroch</LastName><ForeName>Fortu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multidisciplinary Prader-Willi Syndrome Clinic, Neuropediatric Unit, Department of Pediatrics, Shaare Zedek Medical Center, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Hebrew University School of Medicine, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Herman Dana Division of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Hadassah-Hebrew University Medical Center, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Constantini</LastName><ForeName>Naama</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Hebrew University School of Medicine, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidi Rothberg Sport Medicine Center, Shaare Zedek Medical Center, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Med Genet A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101235741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1552-4825</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019208">Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7171WSG8A2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C579455">BDNF protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019208" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011218" MajorTopicYN="N">Prader-Willi Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain-derived neurotropic factor (BDNF)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interleukin-6 (IL-6)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lactate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31692257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.61391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Alsaif, M., Elliot, S. A., MacKenzie, M. L., Prado, C. M., Field, C. J., &amp; Haqq, A. M. (2017). Energy metabolism profile in individuals with Prader-Willi syndrome and implications for clinical management: A systematic review. Advances in Nutrition, 8, 905-915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Heart Association. (2018). Web site. Dallas, TX: American Heart Association Retrieved from http://www.americanheart.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blizzard LeBlanc, D. R., Rioux, B. V., Pelech, C., Mofatt, T. L., Kimber, D. E., Duhamel, T. A., &#x2026; Senachal, M. (2017). Exercise-induced irisin release as a determinant of the metabolic response to exercise training in obese youth: The EXIT trial. Physiological Reports, 5, e13539. https://doi.org/10.14814/phy2.13539</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bochukova, E. G., Lawler, K., Croizier, S., Keogh, J. M., Patel, N., Strohbehn, G., &#x2026; Farooqi, I. S. (2018). A transcriptomic signature of the hypothalamic response to fasting and BDNF deficiency in Prader-Willi syndrome. Cell Reports, 22, 3401-3408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostr&#xf6;m, P., Wu, J., Jedrychowski, M. P., Korde, A., Ye, L., Lo, J. C., &#x2026; Spiegelman, B. M. (2012). A PGC1-&#x3b1;-dependent myokine that drives brown-fat-like development of white fat and thermogenesis. Nature, 481, 463-468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briana, D. D., &amp; Malamitsi-Puchner, A. (2018). Developmental origins of adult health and disease: The metabolic role of BDNF from early life to adulthood. Metabolism, 81, 45-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briken, S., Rosenkranz, S. C., Keminer, O., Patra, S., Ketels, G., Heesen, C., &#x2026; Gold, S. M. (2016). Effects of exercise on irisin, BDNF and IL-6 serum levels in patients with progressive multiple sclerosis. Journal of Neuroimmunology, 299, 53-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, S., Thompson, W., Bailey, J., Johnson, K., Wood, L., Bean, M., Thompson, D. (1990). Blood lactate response to weightlifting in endurance and weight trained men. Journal of Applied Sport Science Research, 4, 122-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler, M. G., Theodoro, M. F., Bittel, D. C., &amp; Donnelly, J. E. (2007). Energy expenditure and physical activity in Prader-Willi syndrome: Comparison with obese subjects. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 143A, 449-459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadoudal, T., Bul&#xe9;on, M., Sengen&#xe8;s, C., Diene, G., Desneulin, F., Molinas, C., &#x2026; Valet, P. (2014). Impairment of adipose tissue in Prader-Willi syndrome rescued by growth hormone treatment. International Journal of Obesity, 38, 1234-1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassidy, S. B., &amp; Driscoll, D. J. (2009). Prader-Willi syndrome. European Journal of Human Genetics, 17(1), 3-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catoire, M., &amp; Kersten, S. (2015). The search for exercise factors in humans. The FASEB Journal, 29, 1615-1628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church, D. D., Hoffman, J. R., Mangine, G. T., Jajtner, A. R., Townsend, J. R., Beyer, K. S., &#x2026; Stout, J. R. (2016). Comparison of high-intensity vs. high-volume resistance training on the BDNF response to exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology, 121, 123-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cypess, A. M., Lehman, S., Williams, G., Tal, I., Rodman, D., Goldfine, A. B., &#x2026; Kahn, C. R. (2009). Identification and importance of brown adipose tissue in adult humans. The New England Journal of Medicine, 360, 1509-1517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duran, A. T., Gertz, E., Judelson, D. A., Haqq, A. M., Clark, S. J., Tsang, K. W., Rubin, D. (2015). Cytokine responses to acute intermittent aerobic exercise in children with Prader-Willi syndrome and nonsyndromic obesity. Pediatric Exercise Science, 27, 525-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiholzer, U., l'Allemand, D., van der Sluis, I., Steinert, H., Gasser, T., &amp; Ellis, K. (2000). Body composition abnormalities in children with Prader-Willi syndrome and long-term effects of growth hormone therapy. Hormone Research, 53(4), 200-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiholzer, U., Nordmann, Y., L'allemand, D., Schlumpf, M., Schmid, S., Kromeyer-Hauschild, K., &amp; Hauschild, K. (2003). Improving body composition and physical activity in Prader-Willi syndrome. The Journal of Pediatrics, 142(1), 73-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elena, G., Bruna, C., Benedetta, M., Stefania, D. C., &amp; Giuseppe, C. (2012). Prader-Willi syndrome: Clinical aspects. Journal of Obesity, 2012, 473941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giudice, J., &amp; Taylor, J. M. (2017). Muscle as a paracrine and endocrine organ. Current Opinion in Pharmacology, 34, 49-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstone, A. T. (2004). Prader-Willi syndrome: Advances in genetics, pathophysiology, and treatment. Trends in Endocrinology and Metabolism, 87, 927-937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grolla, E., Andrighetto, G., Parmigiano, P., Hladnik, U., Ferrari, G., Bernadelle, R., &#x2026; Dolcetta, D. (2011). Specfic treatment of Prader-Willi syndrome through cyclical rehabilitation programmes. Disability and Rehabilitation, 33, 1837-1847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross, I., Hirsch, H. J., Constantini, N., Nice, S., Pollak, Y., Genstil, L., &#x2026; Gross-Tsur, V. G. (2018). Physical activity and maximal oxygen uptake in adults with Prader-Willi syndrome. Eating and Weight Disorders, 23, 615-620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J. C., Muehlbauer, M. J., Cui, H. N., Newgard, C. B., &amp; Haqq, A. M. (2010). Lower brain-derived neurotrophic factor in patients with Prader-Willi syndrome compared to obese and lean control subjects. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism, 95, 3532-3536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haqq, A. M., Muehlbauer, M. J., Newgard, C. B., Grambow, S., &amp; Freemark, M. (2011). The metabolic phenotype of Prader-Willi syndrome (PWS) in childhood: Heightened insulin sensitivity relative to body mass index. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism, 96, E225-E232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch, H. J., Gross, I., Pollak, Y., Eldar-Geva, T., &amp; Gross-Tsur, V. (2015). Irisin and the metabolic phenotype of adults with Prader-Willi syndrome. PLoS One, 10, e0136864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;ybye, C. (2006). Inflammatory markers in adults with Prader-Willi syndrome before and during 12 months growth hormone treatment. Hormone Research, 66(1), 27-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huh, J. Y. (2018). The role of exercise-induced myokines in regulating metabolism. Archives of Pharmacal Research, 41, 14-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahgoub, M. O., D'Souza, C., Al Darmaki, R. S. M. H., Baniyas, M. M. Y. H., &amp; Adeghate, E. (2018). An update on the role of irisin in the regulation of endocrine and metabolic functions. Peptides, 104, 15-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, J. L., Lynn, C. H., Shuster, J., &amp; Driscoll, D. J. (2013). A reduced-energy intake, well-balanced diet improves weight control in children with Prader-Willi syndrome. Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics, 26, 2-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales, J. S., Valenzuela, P. L., Pareja-Galeano, H., Rinc&#xf3;n-Castanedo, C., Rubin, D. A., &amp; Lucia, A. (2019). Physical exercise and Prader-Willi syndrome: A systematic review. Clinical Endocrinology, 90, 649-661. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen.13953</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsso, C. E., Mackenzie, M., Alberga, A. S., Sharma, A. M., Richer, L., Rubin, D. A., &#x2026; Haqq, A. M. (2017). The use of magnetic resonance imaging to characterize abnormal body composition phenotypes in youth with Prader-Willi syndrome. Metabolism, 69, 67-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen, B. K. (2013). Muscle as a secretory organ. Comprehensive Physiology, 3, 1337-1362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin, D. A., Clark, S. J., Haqq, A. M., Castner, D. M., Ng, J., &amp; Judelson, D. A. (2017). Hormonal and metabolic responses to a single bout of resistance exercise in Prader-Willi syndrome. Hormone Research in Paediatrics, 87, 153-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui, L. (2017). Brown and Beige adipose tissues in health and disease. Comprehensive Physiology, 7, 1281-1306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnyder, S., &amp; Handschin, C. (2015). Skeletal muscle as an endocrine organ: PGC-1&#x3b1;, myokines and exercise. Bone, 80, 115-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields, N., Bennell, K. L., Radcliffe, J., &amp; Taylor, N. F. (2019). Is strength training feasible for young people with Prader-Willi syndrome? A phase 1 randomised controlled trial. Physiotherapy. pii: S0031-9406(19)30038-0. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physio.2019.01.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverthorn, K. H., &amp; Hornak, J. E. (1993). Beneficial effects of exercise on aerobic capacity and body composition in adults with Prader-Willi syndrome. American Journal of Mental Retardation, 97, 654-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son, J. S., Chae, S. A., Testroet, E. D., Du, M., &amp; Jun, H. P. (2018). Exercise-induced myokines: A brief review of controversial issues of this decade. Expert Review of Endocrinology and Metabolism, 13, 51-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegelman, B. M. (2013). Banting lecture 2012: Regulation of adipogenesis: Toward new therapeutics for metabolic disease. Diabetes, 62, 1774-1782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodoro, M. F., Talebizadeh, Z., &amp; Butler, M. G. (2006). Body composition and fatness patterns in Prader-Willi syndrome: Comparison with simple obesity. Obesity, 14, 1685-1690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya, Y., Ando, D., Takamatsu, K., &amp; Goto, K. (2015). Resistance exercise induces a greater irisin response than endurance exercise. Metabolism, 64, 1042-1050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Mil, E. G., Westerterp, K. R., Gerver, W. J., Van Marken Lichtenbelt, W. D., Kester, A. D., &amp; Saris, W. H. (2001). Body composition in Prader-Willi syndrome compared with nonsyndromal obesity: Relationship to physical activity and growth hormone function. The Journal of Pediatrics, 139(5), 708-714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitham, M., Parker, B. L., Friedrichsen, M., Hingst, J. R., Hjorth, M., Hughes, W. E., &#x2026; Febbraio, M. A. (2018). Extracellular vesicles provide a means for tissue crosstalk during exercise. Cell Metabolism, 27, 237-251.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>