<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34107512</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Creatine Supplementation and Resistance Training on Area and Density of Bone and Muscle in Older Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2388</StartPage><EndPage>2395</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2388-2395</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002722</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">To examine the efficacy of creatine (Cr) supplementation and any sex differences during supervised whole-body resistance training (RT) on properties of bone and muscle in older adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Seventy participants (39 men, 31 women; mean age &#xb1; standard deviation: 58 &#xb1; 6 yr) were randomized to supplement with Cr (0.1 g&#xb7;kg-1&#xb7;d-1) or placebo (Pl) during RT (3 d&#xb7;wk-1 for 1 yr). Bone geometry (radius and tibia) and muscle area and density (forearm and lower leg) were assessed using peripheral quantitative computed tomography.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with Pl, Cr increased or maintained total bone area in the distal tibia (Cr, &#x394; +17 &#xb1; 27 mm2; Pl, &#x394; -1 &#xb1; 22 mm2; P = 0.031) and tibial shaft (Cr, &#x394; 0 &#xb1; 9 mm2; Pl, &#x394; -5 &#xb1; 7 mm2; P = 0.032). Men on Cr increased trabecular (&#x394; +28 &#xb1; 31 mm2; P &lt; 0.001) and cortical bone areas in the tibia (&#x394; +4 &#xb1; 4 mm2; P &lt; 0.05), whereas men on Pl increased trabecular bone density (&#x394; +2 &#xb1; 2 mg&#xb7;cm-3; P &lt; 0.01). There were no bone changes in the radius (P &gt; 0.05). Cr increased lower leg muscle density (&#x394; +0.83 &#xb1; 1.15 mg&#xb7;cm-3; P = 0.016) compared with Pl (&#x394; -0.16 &#xb1; 1.56 mg&#xb7;cm-3), with no changes in the forearm muscle.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">One year of Cr supplementation and RT had some favorable effects on measures of bone area and muscle density in older adults.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Candow</LastName><ForeName>Darren G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Regina, Regina, SK, CANADA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chilibeck</LastName><ForeName>Philip D</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Kinesiology, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK, CANADA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gordon</LastName><ForeName>Julianne J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Kinesiology, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK, CANADA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kontulainen</LastName><ForeName>Saija</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Kinesiology, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK, CANADA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT01057680</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>MU72812GK0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003401">Creatine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000058" MajorTopicYN="N">Accidental Falls</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015519" MajorTopicYN="N">Bone Density</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016723" MajorTopicYN="N">Bone Remodeling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001842" MajorTopicYN="N">Bone and Bones</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003401" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014057" MajorTopicYN="N">Tomography, X-Ray Computed</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34107512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202111000-00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Frank-Wilson AW, Farthing JP, Chilibeck PD, et al. Lower leg muscle density is independently associated with fall status in community-dwelling older adults. Osteoporos Int . 2016;27(7):2231&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheu Y, Zmuda JM, Boudreau RM, et al. Bone strength measured by peripheral quantitative computed tomography and the risk of nonvertebral fractures: the osteoporotic fractures in men (MrOS) study. J Bone Miner Res . 2011;26(1):63&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Landeryou T, et al. Effects of creatine and resistance training on bone health in postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2015;47(8):1587&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Gordon JJ, et al. Effect of 12 months of creatine supplementation and whole-body resistance training on measures of bone, muscle and strength in older males. Nutr Health . 2021;27(2):151&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo DM, Tritto AC, da Silva LR, et al. Effects of long-term low-dose dietary creatine supplementation in older women. Exp Gerontol . 2015;70:97&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sales LP, Pinto AJ, Rodrigues SF, et al. Creatine supplementation (3 g/d) and bone health in older women: a 2-year, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci . 2020;75(5):931&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong AR, Kim SW. Effects of resistance exercise on bone health. Endocrinol Metab (Seoul) . 2018;33(4):435&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber I, ap Gwynn I, Alini M, et al. Stimulatory effects of creatine on metabolic activity, differentiation and mineralization of primary osteoblast-like cells in monolayer and micromass cell cultures. Eur Cell Mater . 2005;10:8&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Little JP, Chilibeck PD, et al. Low-dose creatine combined with protein during resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2008;40(9):1645&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornish SM, Candow DG, Jantz NT, et al. Conjugated linoleic acid combined with creatine monohydrate and whey protein supplementation during strength training. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2009;19(1):79&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, S&#xf6;derlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Lond) . 1992;83(3):367&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Chilibeck PD, et al. Effectiveness of creatine supplementation on aging muscle and bone: focus on falls prevention and inflammation. J Clin Med . 2019;8(4):488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Kaviani M, Candow DG, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Open Access J Sports Med . 2017;8:213&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Chrusch MJ, Chad KE, et al. Creatine monohydrate and resistance training increase bone mineral content and density in older men. J Nutr Health Aging . 2005;9(5):352&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D, et al. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomized trials. Ann Intern Med . 2010;152:726&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crockett K, Arnold CM, Farthing JP, et al. Bone strength and muscle properties in postmenopausal women with and without a recent distal radius fracture. Osteoporos Int . 2015;26(10):2461&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank-Wilson AW, Johnston JD, Olszynski WP, et al. Measurement of muscle and fat in postmenopausal women: precision of previously reported pQCT imaging methods. Bone . 2015;75:49&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duckham RL, Frank AW, Johnston JD, et al. Monitoring time interval for pQCT-derived bone out-comes in postmenopausal women. Osteoporos Int . 2013;24:1917&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontulainen SA, Johnston JD, Liu D, et al. Strength indices from pQCT imaging predict up to 85% of variance in bone failure properties at tibial epiphysis and diaphysis. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact . 2008;8(4):401&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang T, Cauley JA, Tylavsky F, et al. Computed tomographic measurements of thigh muscle cross-sectional area and attenuation coefficient predict hip fracture: the health, aging, and body composition study. J Bone Miner Res . 2010;25(3):513&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Manske SL, Kontulainen SA, et al. Tibial geometry is associated with failure load ex vivo: a MRI, pQCT and DXA study. Osteoporos Int . 2007;18(7):991&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gee AO, Israelite CL. Intramedullary nail fixation of tibial shaft fractures. Gowned and Gloved Orthopaedics: Introduction to Common Procedures . 2009;Ch 27:314&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonova E, Le TK, Burge R, et al. Tibia shaft fractures: costly burden of nonunions. BMC Musculoskelet Disord . 2013;14:42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Macedo AR, Alves CR, et al. Creatine supplementation and resistance training in vulnerable older women: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trial. Exp Gerontol . 2014;53:7&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk B, Feehan J, Lombardi G, et al. Muscle, bone, and fat crosstalk: the biological role of myokines, osteokines, and adipokines. Curr Osteoporos Rep . 2020;18(4):388&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uusi-Rasi K, Karinkanta S, Tokola K, et al. Bone mass and strength and fall-related fractures in older age. J Osteoporos . 2019;2019:5134690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duff WR, Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, et al. Effects of ibuprofen and resistance training on bone and muscle: a randomized controlled trial in older women. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2017;49(4):633&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawthon PM, Fox KM, Gandra SR, et al. Clustering of strength, physical function, muscle, and adiposity characteristics and risk of disability in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc . 2011;59:781&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2017;14:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Krentz JR, et al. Changes in Fat mass following creatine supplementation and resistance training in adults &#x2265;50 years of age: a meta-analysis. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol . 2019;4(3):62.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>