<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32796419</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Response of Muscle Damage Markers to an Accentuated Eccentric Training Protocol: Do Serum and Saliva Measurements Agree?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2132</StartPage><EndPage>2138</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2132-2138</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003777</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez, JM, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes, P, Cer&#xf3;n, JJ, Tvarijonaviciute, A, Llorente-Canterano, FJ, Mart&#xed;nez-Aranda, LM, and Garc&#xed;a-Ramos, A. Response of muscle damage markers to an accentuated eccentric training protocol: do serum and saliva measurements agree? J Strength Cond Res 36(8): 2132-2138, 2022-This study aimed (a) to examine the acute and delayed responses of 3 muscle damage biomarkers: creatine kinase (CK), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) to an accentuated eccentric training protocol in serum, and (b) to explore the changes of these biomarkers in saliva and compare them with serum. Sixteen resistance-trained university students (10 men [age = 26.6 &#xb1; 4.8 years, full squat one repetition maximum [1RM] = 103.4 &#xb1; 14.4 kg] and 6 women [age = 22.7 &#xb1; 1.4 years, full squat estimated 1RM = 68.3 &#xb1; 10.5 kg]) completed an accentuated eccentric strength training protocol with the full squat exercise consisting of 8 sets of 10 repetitions against the 120% estimated 1RM load with 5 minutes of interset rest. The activity of muscle damage biomarkers (CK, AST, and LDH) was measured in serum and saliva before training (Pre), 24 hours after training (Post24), and 96 hours after training (Post96). In serum, lower values of the 3 muscle damage markers were observed at Pre compared to Post24 and Post96, whereas no significant differences were observed between Post24 and Post96 for any analyte. In saliva, there was a significant increase in men at Post96 compared with Pre in CK. The correlations between the measurements in serum and saliva ranged from trivial to small ( r = -0.034 to 0.212). These results suggest that the measurement of muscle damage markers in serum and saliva do not provide the same information in the conditions of our study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>Jorge M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromove Research Group, Faculty of Sport, Catholic University of San Antonio (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Science, Universidad Europea de Canarias, Tenerife, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Studies, Rey Juan Carlos University, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cer&#xf3;n</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Laboratory of Clinical Analysis, University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tvarijonaviciute</LastName><ForeName>Asta</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Laboratory of Clinical Analysis, University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Llorente-Canterano</LastName><ForeName>Francisco J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Education, University of Sevilla, Sevilla, Spain; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Aranda</LastName><ForeName>Luis M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromove Research Group, Faculty of Sport, Catholic University of San Antonio (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Amador</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departament of Sport Sciences and Physical Conditioning, Faculty of Education, CIEDE, Catholic University of Most Holy Concepci&#xf3;n, Concepci&#xf3;n, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.1.1.27</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007770">L-Lactate Dehydrogenase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.3.2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003402">Creatine Kinase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003402" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine Kinase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007770" MajorTopicYN="N">L-Lactate Dehydrogenase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012463" MajorTopicYN="Y">Saliva</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202208000-00010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Askling C, Karlsson J, Thorstensson A. Hamstring injury occurrence in elite soccer players after preseason strength training with eccentric overload. Scand J Med Sci Sports 13: 244&#x2013;250, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Nevill AM. Statistical methods for assessing measurement error (reliability) in variables relevant to sports medicine. Sports Med 26: 217&#x2013;238, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barranco T, Tvarijonaviciute A, Tecles F, et al. Changes in CK, LDH and AST in saliva samples after an intense exercise&#x202f;: A pilot study. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 58: 910&#x2013;916, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaven CM, Gill ND, Cook CJ. Salivary testosterone and cortisol responses in professional rugby players after four resistance exercise protocols. J Strength Cond Res 22: 426&#x2013;432, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancaccio P, Lippi G, Maffulli N. Biochemical markers of muscular damage. Clin Chem Lab Med 48: 757&#x2013;767, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancaccio P, Maffulli N, Limongelli FM. Creatine kinase monitoring in sport medicine. Br Med Bull 81: 209&#x2013;230, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg J, Docherty D, Brandenburg JP. The effects of accentuated eccentric loading on strength, muscle hypertrophy, and neural adaptations in trained individuals J Strength Cond Res 16: 25&#x2013;32, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman D, Newton M, Sacco P, Nosaka K. Greater muscle damage induced by fast versus slow velocity eccentric exercise. Int J Sports Med 27: 591&#x2013;598, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Yang T-J, Huang M-J, et al. Damage and the repeated bout effect of arm, leg and trunk muscles induced by eccentric resistance exercises. Scand J Med Sci Sports 29: 725&#x2013;735, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Kearns AMYK, Rouzier P, Rubin R, Thompson PD. Serum creatine kinase levels and renal function measures in exertional muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc 38: 623&#x2013;627, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Stat Power Anal Behav Sci 2: 567, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Beaven CM, Kilduff LP. Three weeks of eccentric training combined with overspeed exercises enhances power and running speed performance gains in trained athletes. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1280&#x2013;1286, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deminice R. Blood and salivary oxidative stress biomarkers following an acute session of resistance exercise in humans. Int J Sports Med 31: 599&#x2013;603, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolezal BA, Potteiger JA, Jacobsen DJ, et al. Muscle damage and resting metabolic rate after acute resistance exercise with an eccentric overload. Med Sci Sports Exerc, 32: 1202&#x2013;1207, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J, Pearson S, Ross A, McGuigan M. Effects of accentuated eccentric loading on muscle properties, strength, power, and speed in resistance-trained rugby players. J Strength Cond Res 32: 2750&#x2013;2761, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM. Eccentric contractions require unique activation strategies by the nervous system. J Appl Physiol 81: 2339&#x2013;2346, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo JYY, Wan Y, Kostner K, et al. NT-ProBNP levels in saliva and its clinical relevance to heart failure. PLoS One 7: e48452, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friden J, Lieber RL. Eccentric exercise-induced injuries to contractile and cytoskeletal muscle fibre components. Acta Physiol Scand 171: 321&#x2013;326, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA, Stauber WT, Elorriaga A. Changes in human skeletal muscle ultrastructure and force production after acute resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol 78: 702&#x2013;708, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann U, Mester J. Training and overtraining markers in selected sport events. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 209&#x2013;215, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes LD, Sculthorpe N, Baker JS. Poor levels of agreement between serum and saliva testosterone measurement following exercise training in aging men. Aging Male 18: 67&#x2013;70, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK. Sex differences in human fatigability: Mechanisms and insight to physiological responses. Acta Physiol 210: 768&#x2013;789, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamurtas AZ, Fatouros IG, Buckenmeyer PJ, et al. Effects of plyometric exercise on muscle soreness and plasma creatine kinase levels and its comparison with eccentric and concentric exercise. J Strength Cond Res 14: 68&#x2013;74, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joonyoung K, Joohyung L. The relationship of creatine kinase variability with body composition and muscle damage markers following eccentric muscle contractions. J Exerc Nutr Biochem 19: 123&#x2013;129, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma JJ, de Knikker R, Wittink HM, Takken T. Eccentric overload training in patients with chronic achilles tendinopathy: A systematic review. Br J Sports Med 41: e3, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch A, Pereira R, Machado M. The creatine kinase response to resistance exercise. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 14: 68&#x2013;77, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan CP, Lovell DI, Gass GC. Creatine kinase and endocrine responses of elite players pre, during, and post rugby leage match play. J Strength Cond Res: 2908&#x2013;2919, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaii-Dizgah I, Jafari-Sabet M. Unstimulated whole saliva creatine phosphokinase in acute myocardial infarction. Oral Dis 17: 597&#x2013;600, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M. Concentric or eccentric training effect on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc, 34: 63&#x2013;69, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantoja PD, Alberton CL, Pilla C, Vendrusculo AP, Kruel LFM. Effect of resistive exercise on muscle damage in water and on land. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1051&#x2013;1054, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Acute and delayed response to resistance exercise leading or not leading to muscle failure. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 37: 630&#x2013;639, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Padial P, Morales-Artacho A, Feriche B. Load-velocity relationship in variations of the half-squat exercise: Influence of execution technique. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1024&#x2013;1031, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raeder C, Wiewelhove T, De Paula Simola R&#xc1;, et al. Assessment of fatigue and recovery in male and female athletes following six days of intensified strength training. J Strength Cond Res 30: 3412&#x2013;3427, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roig M, O'Brien K, Kirk G, et al. The effects of eccentric versus concentric resistance training on muscle strength and mass in healthy adults: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 43: 556&#x2013;568, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Squatting kinematics and kinetics and their application to exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res 24: 3497&#x2013;3506, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Vigotsky D, Franchi MV, Krieger JW. Hypertrophic effects of concentric vs. eccentric muscle actions: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2599&#x2013;2608, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard J, Hobson S, Barker M, et al. The effect of training with accentuated eccentric load counter-movement jumps on strength and power characteristics of high-performance volleyball players. Int J Sports Sci Coach 3: 355&#x2013;363, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skovdal Rathleff M, Thorborg K, Bandholm T. Concentric and eccentric time-under-tension during strengthening exercises: Validity and reliability of stretch-sensor recordings from an elastic exercise-band. PLoS One 8: e68172, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tvarijonaviciute A, Barranco T, Rubio M, et al. Measurement of creatine kinase and aspartate aminotransferase in saliva of dogs: A pilot study. BMC Vet Res 13: 168, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twist C, Eston R. The effects of exercise-induced muscle damage on maximal intensity intermittent exercise performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 94: 652&#x2013;658, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagle JP, Taber CB, Cunanan AJ, et al. Accentuated eccentric loading for training and performance: A review. Sports Med 47: 2473&#x2013;2495, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, Blazevich AJ, Haff GG, et al. Greater strength gains after training with accentuated eccentric than traditional isoinertial loads in already strength-trained men. Front Physiol 7: 1&#x2013;12, 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>