<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38018533</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-453X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Creatine Supplementation and Resistance Training in Patients With Breast Cancer (CaRTiC Study): Protocol for a Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>161</StartPage><EndPage>168</EndPage><MedlinePgn>161-168</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/COC.0000000000001070</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Creatine supplementation is an effective ergogenic nutrient for athletes, as well as for people starting a health or fitness program. Resistance training has previously been identified as an important method of increasing muscle mass and strength, especially in people with cancer to avoid sarcopenia. The potential of creatine supplementation for adaptations produced by resistance training in patients with cancer is still unknown. The primary aim of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of a supervised resistance training program intervention with and without creatine supplementation in patients with breast cancer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Is a multicentre, randomized, blind, placebo-controlled study. Patients will be randomly assigned to a control group and 2 experimental groups. The first training resistance group (RG) will perform resistance training, while the second experimental resistance-creatine group will perform the same resistance training as the RG and will also receive a 5&#xa0;g/d creatine supplementation during the intervention. RG participants will follow the same daily dosing protocol, but in their case, with dextrose/maltodextrin. Resistance training will be a 16-week supervised workout that will consist of a series of resistance exercises (leg press, knee extension, knee bends, chest press, sit-ups, back extensions, pull-ups, and shoulder press) that involve the largest muscle groups, performed 3 times a week on nonconsecutive days. Both the RG and the resistance-creatine group will receive a supplement of soluble protein powder (20 to 30&#xa0;g) daily.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This intervention will help to better understand the potential of nonpharmacological treatment for improving strength and well-being values in patients with breast cancer with and without creatine supplementation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinez Aguirre-Betolaza</LastName><ForeName>Aitor</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Education and Sport, University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cacicedo</LastName><ForeName>Jon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Group for Radiology and Physical Medicine in Oncology, Cruces University Hospital/Biocruces Bizkaia Health Research Institute, Barakaldo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casta&#xf1;eda-Babarro</LastName><ForeName>Arkaitz</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Education and Sport, University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8207754</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-3732</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>MU72812GK0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003401">Creatine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003401" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015337" MajorTopicYN="N">Multicenter Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38018533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/COC.0000000000001070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000421-202404000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Kaviani M, Candow DG, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. J Sports Med. 2017;8:213&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan E, Gualano B, Rawson ES. Beyond muscle: the effects of creatine supplementation on brain creatine, cognitive processing, and traumatic brain injury. Eur J Sports Sci. 2019;19:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Chilibeck PD, et al. Effectiveness of creatine supplementation on aging muscle and bone: focus on falls prevention and inflammation. J Clin Med. 2019;8:488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Kim CK, Carpentier A, et al. Studies on the safety of creatine supplementation. Amino Acids. 2011;40:1409&#x2013;1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ATS Committee on Proficiency Standards for Clinical Pulmonary Function laboratories ATS statement: guidelines for the six-minute walk test. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166:111&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Nowinski CJ. Measuring quality of life in chronic illness: the functional assessment of chronic illness therapy measurement system. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;83:S10&#x2013;S17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS, Kostek MA, Gordish-Dressman H, et al. ACE ID genotype and the muscle strength and size response to unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:1074&#x2013;1081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumien N, Shetty RA, Gonzales EB. Creatine, creatine kinase, and aging. Subcell Biochem. 2018;90:145&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro SML, Kehayias JJ. Sarcopenia and the analysis of body composition. Adv Nutr. 2014;5:260&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuchi N, Tsuchiya Y, Nakazato K, et al. Effects of the ACTN3 R577X genotype on the muscular strength and range of motion before and after eccentric contractions of the elbow flexors. Int J Sports Med. 2018;39:148&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morishita S Prevalence of sarcopenia in cancer patients: review and future directions. Int J Phys Med Rehabil 2016;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ. Strength training for young athletes. Hum Kinet. 2005;2:18&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Porter RR, Sui X, et al. The effect of resistance exercise on all-cause mortality in cancer survivors. Mayo Clin Proc. 2014;89:1108&#x2013;1115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielgo-Ayuso J, Calleja-Gonzalez J, Marqu&#xe9;s-Jim&#xe9;nez D, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on athletic performance in soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2019;11:757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos-Ferraz PL, Gualano B, das Neves W, et al. Exploratory studies of the potential anti-cancer effects of creatine. Amino Acids. 2016;48:1993&#x2013;2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patra S, Ghosh A, Roy SS, et al. A short review on creatine-creatine kinase system in relation to cancer and some experimental results on creatine as adjuvant in cancer therapy. Amino Acids. 2012;42:2319&#x2013;2330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Defoor JGM, Stevens A, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation as a potential adjuvant therapy to exercise training in cardiac patients: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2010;24:988&#x2013;999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Forst CV, Sayegh CE, et al. Molecular and genetic inflammation networks in major human diseases. Mol Biosyst. 2016;12:2318&#x2013;2341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson EA, Sheikhsaraf B, Boidin M, et al. Intra-individual differences in the effect of endurance versus resistance training on vascular function: a cross-over study. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31:1683&#x2013;1692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WJ, Campbell WW. Sarcopenia and age-related changes in body composition and functional capacity. J Nutr. 1993;123:465&#x2013;468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purcell S, Cherny SS, Sham PC. Genetic Power Calculator: design of linkage and association genetic mapping studies of complex traits. Bioinformatics. 2003;19:149&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith-Ryan AE, Cabre HE, Eckerson JM, et al. Creatine supplementation in women&#x2019;s health: a lifespan perspective. Nutrients. 2021;13:877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan L-J, Liu S-L, Lei S-F, et al. Molecular genetic studies of gene identification for sarcopenia. Hum Genet. 2012;131:1&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stares A, Bains M. The additive effects of creatine supplementation and exercise training in an aging population: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2020;43:99&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke H, Kim D-H, Meza CA, et al. The evolving applications of creatine supplementation: could creatine improve vascular health? Nutrients. 2020;12:2834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE, Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36). I Conceptual framework and item selection. Med Care. 1992;30:473&#x2013;483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brosnan ME, Brosnan JT. The role of dietary creatine. Amino Acids. 2016;48:1785&#x2013;1791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Li X, Sui C, et al. Incidence and risk factor analysis for sarcopenia in patients with cancer. Oncol Lett. 2016;11:1230&#x2013;1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares RJ, Cagnin S, Chemello F, et al. Involvement of microRNAs in the regulation of muscle wasting during catabolic conditions. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:21909&#x2013;21925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J-F, Tao Y, Li J, et al. microRNA-1 and microRNA-206 regulate skeletal muscle satellite cell proliferation and differentiation by repressing Pax7. J Cell Biol. 2010;190:867&#x2013;879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M, Zha F, Chen Y, et al. Handgrip strength-related factors affecting health outcomes in young adults: association with cardiorespiratory fitness. Biomed Res Int. 2021;2021:6645252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro PA, Carneiro J a O, Coqueiro RS, et al. &#x2018;Chair stand test&#x2019; as simple tool for sarcopenia screening in elderly women. J Nutr Health Aging. 2016;20:56&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM. The ACE ID genotype and muscle strength and size response to unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:1073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford TW, Kreider RB, Stout JR, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: creatine supplementation and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meza-Valderrama D, Marco E, D&#xe1;valos-Yerovi V, et al. sarcopenia, malnutrition, and cachexia: adapting definitions and terminology of nutritional disorders in older people with cancer. Nutrients. 2021;13:761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Eijnde BO, Derave W, et al. Creatine supplementation: exploring the role of the creatine kinase/phosphocreatine system in human muscle. Can J Appl Physiol. 2001:S79&#x2013;S102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, St&#xfc;bler D, Baier P, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on nutritional status, muscle function and quality of life in patients with colorectal cancer&#x2014;a double blind randomised controlled trial. Clin Nutr. 2006;25:596&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannone F, Montesanto A, Cione E, et al. Expression patterns of muscle-specific miR-133b and miR-206 correlate with nutritional status and sarcopenia. Nutrients. 2020;12:297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairman CM, Kendall KL, Newton RU, et al. Examining the effects of creatine supplementation in augmenting adaptations to resistance training in patients with prostate cancer undergoing androgen deprivation therapy: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2019;9:e030080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez-Romero J, Voisin S, Eynon N, et al. Mapping robust genetic variants associated with exercise responses. Int J Sports Med. 2021;42:3&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollis S, Campbell F. What is meant by intention to treat analysis? Survey of published randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 1999;319:670&#x2013;674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Li Y. Role of matrix metalloproteinases in skeletal muscle: migration, differentiation, regeneration and fibrosis. Cell Adhr Migr. 2009;3:337&#x2013;341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Stout JR. Creatine in health and disease. Nutrients. 2021;13:447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenech M, El-Sohemy A, Cahill L, et al. Nutrigenetics and nutrigenomics: viewpoints on the current status and applications in nutrition research and practice. J Nutrigenet Nutrigenomics. 2011;4:69&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi-Bajestani SMR, Mazurak VC, Baracos V. Computed tomography-defined muscle and fat wasting are associated with cancer clinical outcomes. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2016;54:2&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boidin M, Dawson EA, Thijssen DHJ, et al. VEGFA rs2010963 GG genotype is associated with superior adaptations to resistance versus endurance training in the same group of healthy, young men. Mol Genet Genomics. 2023;298:119&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilha CS, Marinello PC, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Evaluation of resistance training to improve muscular strength and body composition in cancer patients undergoing neoadjuvant and adjuvant therapy: a meta-analysis. J Cancer Surviv. 2017;11:339&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan E, Artioli GG, Pereira RMR, et al. Muscular atrophy and sarcopenia in the elderly: is there a role for creatine supplementation? Biomolecules. 2019;9:642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giallauria F, Cittadini A, Smart NA, et al. Resistance training and sarcopenia. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2016;84:738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2019&#x2013;2052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R, Heymsfield SB, Kehayias JJ, et al. Standardization of nomenclature of body composition in weight loss. Am J Clin Nutr. 1997;66:192&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner MJ, Coyle EF. Endurance exercise performance: the physiology of champions. J Physiol. 2008;586:35&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauretani F, Bandinelli S, Bartali B, et al. Axonal degeneration affects muscle density in older men and women. Neurobiol Aging. 2006;27:1145&#x2013;1154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall M, Trojian TH. Creatine supplementation. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2013;12:240&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones G, Trajanoska K, Santanasto AJ, et al. Genome-wide meta-analysis of muscle weakness identifies 15 susceptibility loci in older men and women. Nat Commun. 2021;12:654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CMM, Lieffers JR, McCargar LJ, et al. Prevalence and clinical implications of sarcopenic obesity in patients with solid tumours of the respiratory and gastrointestinal tracts: a population-based study. Lancet Oncol. 2008;9:629&#x2013;635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aaronson NK, Ahmedzai S, Bergman B, et al. The European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer QLQ-C30: a quality-of-life instrument for use in international clinical trials in oncology. J Natl Cancer Inst. 1993;85:365&#x2013;376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48:16&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang A, Yang C, Liu Y, et al. SOD2 in skeletal muscle: new insights from an inducible deletion model. Redox Biol. 2021;47:102135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto CL, Botelho PB, Pimentel GD, et al. Creatine supplementation and glycemic control: a systematic review. Amino Acids. 2016;48:2103&#x2013;2129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avgerinos KI, Spyrou N, Bougioukas KI, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on cognitive function of healthy individuals: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Exp Gerontol. 2018;108:166&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf8;nbro S, Dalgas U, Primdahl H, et al. Feasibility and efficacy of progressive resistance training and dietary supplements in radiotherapy treated head and neck cancer patients&#x2014;the DAHANCA 25A study. Acta Oncol. 2013;52:310&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ch&#xe1;idez YLB, Guadarrama RG, Hern&#xe1;ndez GA, et al. Construcci&#xf3;n y validaci&#xf3;n de un cuestionario para medir funci&#xf3;n gastrointestinal en adultos. Nutrici&#xf3;n Cl&#xed;nica y Diet&#xe9;tica Hospitalaria. 2020;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Williams AG, Jones DA, et al. The individual and combined influence of ACE and ACTN3 genotypes on muscle phenotypes before and after strength training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:642&#x2013;648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerland L, Baumann FT, Niels T. Resistance exercise for breast cancer patients? Evidence from the last decade. Breast Care (Basel). 2021;16:657&#x2013;663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butts J, Jacobs B, Silvis M. Creatine use in sports. Sports Health. 2018;10:31&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Roberts MD, et al. ISSN exercise &amp; sports nutrition review update: research &amp; recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15:38.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>