<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37639672</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sprint Resisted and Assisted Priming for Peak Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2354</StartPage><EndPage>2361</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2354-2361</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004557</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Krzysztof, K, Aleksander, M, Adam, Z, and Krzysztofik, M. Sprint resisted and assisted priming for peak performance. J Strength Cond Res 37(12): 2354-2361, 2023-This study aimed to investigate resisted and assisted sprint, or a combination of both, as a conditioning activity (CA) on creatine kinase activity, biceps femoris stiffness, postactivation performance enhancement (PAPE), and priming in a sprint. Ten female sprinters (age: 20.1 &#xb1; 2.3 years, body mass: 56.4 &#xb1; 4.2 kg, body height: 171 &#xb1; 5 cm, training experience: 5.6 &#xb1; 2 years) participated. Before the warm-up, blood samples were drawn to determine creatine kinase at baseline. After the warm-up, biceps femoris stiffness was determined, and consequently, 50-m sprint time (with 0- to 20-m and 20- to50-m split time evaluation) was assessed 5 minutes before (pre-CA) and in the seventh minute after the completion of each CA (4 sets of 40 m either: 10% body mass resisted [RST]; 105% maximum velocity assisted [AST] sprint; or 2 sets of each sprint as the CA [COMB]), as well as after 48 hours of recovery. Furthermore, another blood sample was taken 48 hours later, before the warm-up, to assess changes in creatine kinase activity. A significantly higher 20-m sprint time at post-CA ( p = 0.006; ES = 0.4) and post-48 ( p = 0.011; ES = 0.59) compared with pre-CA in the RST condition was found, whereas a significantly lower sprint time was reported in post-48 compared with post-CA ( p = 0.019; ES = 0.44) in the COMB condition. However, a significantly lower 30-m flying sprint time at post-CA ( p &lt; 0.001; ES = 0.28) and at post-48 ( p = 0.014; ES = 0.22) compared with pre-CA in the RST condition was revealed. Moreover, a significantly lower 30-m flying sprint time at post-48 compared with the pre-CA ( p = 0.007; ES = 0.7 and p = 0.003; ES = 0.77) and with the post-CA ( p = 0.019; ES = 0.61 and p = 0.009; ES = 0.68) in the AST condition and COMB was reported. Furthermore, a significantly lower 50-m sprint time at post-48 compared with pre-CA ( p = 0.015; ES = 0.51 and p = 0.011; ES = 0.64) and with post-CA ( p = 0.005; ES = 0.46 and p = 0.001; ES = 0.55) in the AST and COMB condition were found. The creatine kinase activity at post-48 during AST was significantly lower than during RST ( p = 0.028; ES = 0.73) and COMB ( p = 0.028; ES = 1.48). No significant changes were found for biceps femoris stiffness ( p = 0.085; &#x3b7; 2 = 0.199). The COMB and AST contributed to the improvement of the 50-m sprint time 48 hours after activation, which may be a good precompetition approach. However, during training sessions aiming to induce an acute PAPE effect and improve the 30-m flying sprint time, the best solution might be to use low-volume-resisted sprints.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kotu&#x142;a</LastName><ForeName>Krzysztof</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Sport Performance, The Jerzy Kukuczka Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Katowice, Poland; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matusi&#x144;ski</LastName><ForeName>Aleksander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Sport Performance, The Jerzy Kukuczka Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Katowice, Poland; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaj&#x105;c</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Sciences, The Jerzy Kukuczka Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krzysztofik</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2797-8431</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Sciences, The Jerzy Kukuczka Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.3.2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003402">Creatine Kinase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063996" MajorTopicYN="Y">Warm-Up Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003402" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine Kinase</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37639672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202312000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andonian P, Viallon M, Le Goff C, et al. Shear-wave elastography assessments of quadriceps stiffness changes prior to, during and after prolonged exercise: A longitudinal study during an extreme mountain ultra-marathon. PLoS One 11: e0161855, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D Applying the in-season periodization of strength and power training to football. Strength Cond J 20: 18&#x2013;27, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizzini M, Mannion AF. Reliability of a new, hand-held device for assessing skeletal muscle stiffness. Clin Biomech 18: 459&#x2013;461, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolger R, Lyons M, Harrison AJ, Kenny IC. Sprinting performance and resistance-based training interventions: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1146&#x2013;1156, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bomfim Lima J, Marin D, Barquilha G, et al. Acute effects of drop jump potentiation protocol on sprint and countermovement vertical jump performance. Hum Mov 12: 324&#x2013;330, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brink NJ, Constantinou D, Torres G. Postactivation performance enhancement (PAPE) of sprint acceleration performance. Eur J Sport Sci 22: 1411&#x2013;1417: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell MJ, Walters SJK, Machin D. Reliability and method comparison studies. In: Medical Statistics: A Textbook for the Health Sciences (5th ed.). Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley Blackwell, 2021. pp. 233&#x2013;264</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DA, Sabick MB, Pfeiffer RP, et al. Influence of towing force magnitude on the kinematics of supramaximal sprinting. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1162&#x2013;1168, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The t test for means. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Burlington: Elsevier Science, 2013. pp. 19&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Kilduff LP, Crewther BT, Beaven M, West DJ. Morning based strength training improves afternoon physical performance in rugby union players. J Sci Med Sport 17: 317&#x2013;321, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dechechi C, Lopes C, Galatti L, Ribeiro R. Post activation potentiation for lower limb with eccentric and concentric movements on sprinters. Int J Sports Sci 3: 1&#x2013;3, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dello Iacono A, Martone D, Padulo J. Acute effects of drop-jump protocols on explosive performances of elite handball players. J Strength Cond Res 30: 3122&#x2013;3133, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand LG, Battaglini CL, McMurray RG, Shields EW. Assessing explosive power production using the backward overhead shot throw and the effects of morning resistance exercise on afternoon performance. J Strength Cond Res 27: 101&#x2013;106, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esformes JI, Cameron N, Bampouras TM. Postactivation potentiation following different modes of exercise. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1911&#x2013;1916, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Garc&#xed;a J, Gir&#xe1;ldez-Costas V, Ruiz-Moreno C, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Hell&#xed;n J, Romero-Moraleda B. Delayed potentiation effects on neuromuscular performance after optimal load and high load resistance priming sessions using velocity loss. Eur J Sport Sci 21: 1617&#x2013;1627, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison PW, James LP, McGuigan MR, Jenkins DG, Kelly VG. Resistance priming to enhance neuromuscular performance in sport: Evidence, potential mechanisms and directions for future research. Sports Med 49: 1499&#x2013;1514, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugen T, Seiler S, Sandbakk &#xd8;, T&#xf8;nnessen E. The training and development of elite sprint performance: An integration of scientific and best practice literature. Sports Med Open 5: 44, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashihara A, Nagano Y, Ono T, Fukubayashi T. Differences in hamstring activation characteristics between the acceleration and maximum-speed phases of sprinting. J Sports Sci 36: 1313&#x2013;1318, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korhonen RK, Vain A, Vanninen E, Viir R, Jurvelin JS. Can mechanical myotonometry or electromyography be used for the prediction of intramuscular pressure? Physiol Meas 26: 951&#x2013;963, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen GO, van den Tillaar R, Ettema GJC. Velocity specificity in early-phase sprint training. J Strength Cond Res 20: 833&#x2013;837, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Trybulski R, Tr&#x105;bka B, et al. The impact of resistance exercise range of motion on the magnitude of upper-body post-activation performance enhancement. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 14: 123, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Wilk M. The effects of plyometric conditioning on post-activation bench press performance. J Hum Kinet 74: 99&#x2013;108, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Wilk M, Lockie RG, et al. Postactivation performance enhancement of concentric bench press throw after eccentric-only conditioning exercise. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2077&#x2013;2081, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason BRJ, Argus CK, Norcott B, Ball NB. Resistance training priming activity improves upper-body power output in rugby players: Implications for game day performance. J Strength Cond Res 31: 913&#x2013;920, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matusi&#x144;ski A, Go&#x142;as A, Zajac A, Maszczyk A. Acute effects of resisted and assisted locomotor activation on sprint performance. Biol Sport 39: 1049&#x2013;1054, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matusi&#x144;ski A, Pietraszewski P, Krzysztofik M, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A. The effects of resisted post-activation sprint performance enhancement in elite female sprinters. Front Physiol 12: 651659, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishioka T, Okada J. Influence of strength level on performance enhancement using resistance priming. J Strength Cond Res 36: 37&#x2013;46, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira LA, Boullosa D, Moura TBMA, et al. Post-activation performance enhancement in sprinters: Effects of hard versus sand surfaces. J Hum Kinet 82: 173&#x2013;180, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrakos G, Morin J-B, Egan B. Resisted sled sprint training to improve sprint performance: A systematic review. Sports Med 46: 381&#x2013;400, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell M, King A, Bracken RM, et al. A comparison of different modes of morning priming exercise on afternoon performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 763&#x2013;767, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez Saez de Villarreal E, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Izquierdo M. Optimal warm-up stimuli of muscle activation to enhance short and long-term acute jumping performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 100: 393&#x2013;401, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, de Villarreal ES, Haff GG. The temporal profile of postactivation potentiation is related to strength level. J Strength Cond Res 28: 706&#x2013;715, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, Haff GG. Factors modulating post-activation potentiation of jump, sprint, throw, and upper-body ballistic performances: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 231&#x2013;240, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siracusa J, Charlot K, Malgoyre A, et al. Resting muscle shear modulus measured with ultrasound shear-wave elastography as an alternative tool to assess muscle fatigue in humans. Front Physiol 10: 626, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Bishop D. Factors modulating post-activation potentiation and its effect on performance of subsequent explosive activities. Sports Med 39: 147&#x2013;166, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, Wojda&#x142;a G, Alexe DI, et al. Acute effects of different intensities during bench press exercise on the mechanical properties of triceps brachii long head. Appl Sci 12: 3197, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsimachidis C, Patikas D, Galazoulas C, Bassa E, Kotzamanidis C. The post-activation potentiation effect on sprint performance after combined resistance/sprint training in junior basketball players. J Sports Sci 31: 1117&#x2013;1124, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoukos A, Veligekas P, Brown LE, Terzis G, Bogdanis GC. Delayed effects of a low-volume, power-type resistance exercise session on explosive performance. J Strength Cond Res 32: 643&#x2013;650, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, De Vito G, Ditroilo M, Delahunt E. Effect of sex and fatigue on muscle stiffness and musculoarticular stiffness of the knee joint in a young active population. J Sports Sci 35: 1582&#x2013;1591, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, De Vito G, Ditroilo M, Delahunt E. Different effect of local and general fatigue on knee joint stiffness. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49: 173&#x2013;182, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu S, Lin L, Liang H, et al. Gender difference in effects of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation stretching on flexibility and stiffness of hamstring muscle. Front Physiol 13: 918176, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Z, Liao K, Zhang Y, et al. Optimal velocity loss threshold for inducing post activation potentiation in track and field athletes. Biol Sport 40: 603&#x2013;609, 2023.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>