<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34138821</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular Differences in Skeletal Muscle After 1 Week of Active vs. Passive Recovery From High-Volume Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2102</StartPage><EndPage>2113</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2102-2113</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004071</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vann, CG, Haun, CT, Osburn, SC, Romero, MA, Roberson, PA, Mumford, PW, Mobley, CB, Holmes, HM, Fox, CD, Young, KC, and Roberts, MD. Molecular differences in skeletal muscle after 1 week of active vs. passive recovery from high-volume resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 35(8): 2102-2113, 2021-Numerous studies have evaluated how deloading after resistance training (RT) affects strength and power outcomes. However, the molecular adaptations that occur after deload periods remain understudied. Trained, college-aged men (n = 30) performed 6 weeks of whole-body RT starting at 10 sets of 10 repetitions per exercise per week and finishing at 32 sets of 10 repetitions per exercise per week. After this period, subjects performed either active (AR; n = 16) or passive recovery (PR; n = 14) for 1 week where AR completed &#x223c;15% of the week 6 training volume and PR ceased training. Variables related to body composition and recovery examined before RT (PRE), after 6 weeks of RT (POST), and after the 1-week recovery period (DL). Vastus lateralis (VL) muscle biopsies and blood samples were collected at each timepoint, and various biochemical and histological assays were performed. Group &#xd7; time interactions (p &lt; 0.05) existed for skeletal muscle myosin heavy chain (MHC)-IIa mRNA (AR &gt; PR at POST and DL) and 20S proteasome activity (post-hoc tests revealed no significance in groups over time). Time effects (P &lt; 0.05) existed for total mood disturbance and serum creatine kinase and mechano growth factor mRNA (POST &gt; PRE &amp;D L), VL pressure to pain threshold and MHC-IIx mRNA (PRE&amp;DL &gt; POST), Atrogin-1 and MuRF-1 mRNA (PRE &lt; POST &lt; DL), MHC-I mRNA (PRE &lt; POST &amp; DL), myostatin mRNA (PRE &amp; POST &lt; DL), and mechanistic target of rapamycin (PRE &gt; POST &amp; DL). No interactions or time effects were observed for barbell squat velocity, various hormones, histological metrics, polyubiquitinated proteins, or phosphorylated/pan protein levels of 4E-BP1, p70S6k, and AMPK. One week of AR after a high-volume training block instigates marginal molecular differences in skeletal muscle relative to PR. From a practical standpoint, however, both paradigms elicited largely similar responses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vann</LastName><ForeName>Christopher G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haun</LastName><ForeName>Cody T</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, LaGrange College, Lagrange, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osburn</LastName><ForeName>Shelby C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romero</LastName><ForeName>Matthew A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Immunology and Molecular Genetics, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberson</LastName><ForeName>Paul A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular and Molecular Physiology, College of Medicine, The Pennsylvania State University, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mumford</LastName><ForeName>Petey W</ForeName><Initials>PW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, Missouri.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mobley</LastName><ForeName>C Brooks</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holmes</LastName><ForeName>Hudson M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fox</LastName><ForeName>Carlton D</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Kaelin C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine-Auburn Campus, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine-Auburn Campus, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34138821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202108000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baehr LM, Tunzi M, Bodine SC. Muscle hypertrophy is associated with increases in proteasome activity that is independent of MuRF1 and MAFbx expression. Front Physiol 5: 1&#x2013;8, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birzniece V, Khaw CH, Nelson AE, Meinhardt U, Ho KK. A critical evaluation of bioimpedance spectroscopy analysis in estimating body composition during GH treatment: Comparison with bromide dilution and dual X-ray absorptiometry. Eur J Endocrinol 172: 21&#x2013;28, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bompa TOH, Gregory G. Chapter 7: training cycles. In: Periodization: Theory and Methodology of Training. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2009. pp. 165&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Staples AW, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS One 5: e12033, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter AE, Jones TR, Lamprecht MR, et al. CellProfiler: Image analysis software for identifying and quantifying cell phenotypes. Genome Biol 7: 1&#x2013;7, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ch&#xe9;ry C, Ruf L. Reliability of the load-velocity relationship and validity of the PUSH to measure velocity in the deadlift. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2370&#x2013;2380, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grove JR, Prapavessis H. Preliminary evidence for the reliability and validity of an abbreviated Profile of Mood States. Int J Sport Psychol 23: 93&#x2013;109, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann H, Wirth K, Keiner M, et al. Short-term periodization models: Effects on strength and speed-strength performance. Sports Med 45: 1373&#x2013;1386, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Mumford PW, Roberson PA, et al. Molecular, neuromuscular, and recovery responses to light versus heavy resistance exercise in young men. Physiol Rep 5: e13457, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Mobley CB, et al. Effects of graded whey supplementation during extreme-volume resistance training. Front Nutr 5: 1&#x2013;16, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, et al. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol 10: 247, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby TJ, Erickson T, McBride JM. Model for progression of strength, power, and speed training. Strength Cond J 32: 86&#x2013;90, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Selby A, Rankin D, et al. Age-related differences in the dose-response relationship of muscle protein synthesis to resistance exercise in young and old men. J Physiol 587: 211&#x2013;217, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leger B, Cartoni R, Praz M, et al. Akt signalling through GSK-3beta, mTOR and Foxo1 is involved in human skeletal muscle hypertrophy and atrophy. J Physiol 576: 923&#x2013;933, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lockwood CM, Roberts MD, Dalbo VJ, et al. Effects of hydrolyzed whey versus other whey protein supplements on the physiological response to 8 weeks of resistance exercise in college-aged males. J Am Coll Nutr 36: 16&#x2013;27, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman M, Tallroth K, Kettunen JA, Marttinen MT. Reproducibility of dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry total and regional body composition measurements using different scanning positions and definitions of regions. Metabolism 58: 1663&#x2013;1668, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster DT, Gill N, Cronin J, McGuigan M. The development, retention and decay rates of strength and power in elite rugby union, rugby league and American football: A systematic review. Sports Med 43: 367&#x2013;384, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 113: 71&#x2013;77, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley CB, Haun CT, Roberson PA, et al. Effects of whey, soy or leucine supplementation with 12 weeks of resistance training on strength, body composition, and skeletal muscle and adipose tissue histological attributes in college-aged males. Nutrients 9: 1&#x2013;22, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon JR, Tobkin SE, Roberts MD, et al. Total body water estimations in healthy men and women using bioimpedance spectroscopy: A deuterium oxide comparison. Nutr Metab (Lond) 5: 1&#x2013;6, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Detraining: Loss of training-induced physiological and performance adaptations. Part I: Short term insufficient training stimulus. Sports Med 30: 79&#x2013;87, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murton AJ, Constantin D, Greenhaff PL. The involvement of the ubiquitin proteasome system in human skeletal muscle remodelling and atrophy. Biochim Biophys Acta 1782: 730&#x2013;743, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Yasuda T, Ishii N, Abe T. Comparison of muscle hypertrophy following 6-month of continuous and periodic strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 975&#x2013;985, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans JR, Carpentier A. Protein metabolism and physical training: Any need for amino acid supplementation?. Nutrire 41: 1&#x2013;17, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritchard HJ, Barnes MJ, Stewart RJC, Keogh JWL, McGuigan MR. Short-term training cessation as a method of tapering to improve maximal strength. J Strength Cond Res 32: 458&#x2013;465, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, et al. The effects of amino acid supplementation on muscular performance during resistance training overreaching. J Strength Cond Res 17: 250&#x2013;258, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberson PA, Romero MA, Osburn SC, et al. Skeletal muscle LINE-1 ORF1 mRNA is higher in older humans but decreases with endurance exercise and is negatively associated with higher physical activity. J Appl Physiol (1985) 127: 895&#x2013;904, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero MA, Mobley CB, Mumford PW, et al. Acute and chronic resistance training downregulates select LINE-1 retrotransposon activity markers in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 314: C379&#x2013;C388, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effects of resistance training frequency on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 1689&#x2013;1697, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, et al. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2909&#x2013;2918, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanetti RJ, Lamon S, Wallace M, et al. Regulation of ubiquitin proteasome pathway molecular markers in response to endurance and resistance exercise and training. Pflugers Arch 467: 1523&#x2013;1537, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock MS, Beck TW, DeFreitas JM, Dillon MA. Test-retest reliability of barbell velocity during the free-weight bench-press exercise. J Strength Cond Res 25: 171&#x2013;177, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, O'Bryant H, Garhammer J, McMillan J, Rozenek R. A theoretical model of strength training. NSCA J 4: 36&#x2013;39, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Stone M, Sands WA. Chapter 11: Psychological aspects of resistance training. In: Principles and Practice of Resistance Training. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2007. pp. 229&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams TD, Tolusso DV, Fedewa MV, Esco MR. Comparison of periodized and non-periodized resistance training on maximal strength: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2083&#x2013;2100, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Klemp A, Dolan C, et al. Novel resistance training-specific rating of perceived exertion scale measuring repetitions in reserve. J Strength Cond Res 30: 267&#x2013;275, 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>