<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34055154</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leucine Supplementation Does Not Improve Muscle Recovery from Resistance Exercise in Young Adults: A Randomized, Double-Blinded, Crossover Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>486</StartPage><EndPage>497</EndPage><MedlinePgn>486-497</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to investigate the effects of free leucine supplementation on muscle recovery from resistance exercise (RE) in young adults. Fourteen untrained subjects (23.9 &#xb1; 3.6 years old) underwent RE sessions (leg press and hack squat: three sets of 8-12 reps at 70% 1RM) supplemented with leucine (LEU: two daily doses of 3g) or a placebo (PLA), separated by a seven-day washout period. Following each occasion, participants were evaluated in three subsequent days (24h, 48h, and 72h) for muscle recovery via a repetition-to-failure test. The following markers were assessed: repetition performance, perceived exertion, lactate, creatine kinase, muscle soreness (DOMS), testosterone, and cortisol. No significant difference was observed between LEU and PLA conditions (<i>p</i> &gt; 0.05). Number of repetitions performed in the repetition-to-failure tests, perceived exertion, cortisol, and testosterone:cortisol ratio did not change over time (<i>p</i> &gt; 0.05). Creatine kinase increased immediately after exercise, at 24h, and 48h, and was attenuated at 72h post-exercise, while testosterone, lactate, and DOMS increased at 24h post-exercise (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05) and remained elevated up to 72h. All outcomes were similar between LEU and PLA. Results indicate that a 6g daily dose of free leucine supplementation does not improve muscle recovery following lower-limb RE in untrained young adults.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacinto</LastName><ForeName>Jeferson L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casonatto</LastName><ForeName>Juliano</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roveratti</LastName><ForeName>Mirela C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sena</LastName><ForeName>Bruna N S</ForeName><Initials>BNS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DA Silva</LastName><ForeName>Rubens A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>D&#xe9;partement des Sciences de la Sant&#xe9;, Programme de Physioth&#xe9;rapie de l'universit&#xe9; McGill offert en extension &#xe0; l'Universit&#xe9; du Qu&#xe9;bec &#xe0; Chicoutimi (UQAC), 555 boul. de l'Universit&#xe9;, ville du Saguenay, CANADA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguiar</LastName><ForeName>Andreo F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amino acids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BCAA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34055154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/QLQR5371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-14-2-486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College ACSM of Sports. Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College ACSM of Sports. Medicine joint position statement. Nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(3):543&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Grala AP, da Silva RA, Soares-Caldeira LF, Pacagnelli FL, Ribeiro AS, et al. Free leucine supplementation during an 8-week resistance training program does not increase muscle mass and strength in untrained young adult subjects. Amino Acids. 2017;49(7):1255&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28444456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Andrade IT, Gualano B, Hevia-Larra&#xed; V, Neves-Junior J, Cajueiro M, Jardim F, et al. Leucine supplementation has no further effect on training-induced muscle adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(8):1809&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32079916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony JC, Yoshizawa F, Anthony TG, Vary TC, Jefferson LS, Kimball SR. Leucine stimulates translation initiation skeletal muscle of postabsorptive rats via a rapamycin-sensitive pathway. J Nutr. 2000;130(10):2413&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11015466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Bandt JP. Leucine and mammalian target of rapamycin-dependent activation of muscle protein synthesis in aging. J Nutr. 2016;146(12):2616S&#x2013;2624S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27934653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Eliasson J, Karlssonr HKR, K&#xf6;hnke R. Branched-chain amino acids activate key enzymes in protein synthesis after physical exercise. J Nutr. 2006;136(1 Suppl):269S&#x2013;273S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgenvik M, Apr&#xf3; W, Blomstrand E. Intake of branched-chain amino acids influences the levels of MAFbx mRNA and MuRF-1 total protein in resting and exercising human muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;302(5):E510&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22127230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8;rsheim E, Bui QU, Tissier S, Kobayashi H, Ferrando AA, Wolfe RR. Effect of amino acid supplementation on muscle mass, strength, and physical function in elderly. Clin Nutr. 2008;27(8):189&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2430042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18294740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Breen L, Di Donato DM, Hector AJ, Mitchell CJ, Moore DR, et al. Leucine supplementation of a low-protein mixed macronutrient beverage enhances myofibrillar protein synthesis in young men: A double-blind, randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014;99(2):276&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24284442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Burd NA, Mitchell CJ, West DWD, Philp A, Marcotte GR, et al. Supplementation of a suboptimal protein dose with leucine or essential amino acids: Effects on myofibrillar protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in men. J Physiol. 2012;590(11):2751&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3424729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22451437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson D, Smith K, Babraj J, Leese G, Waddell T, Atherton P, et al. Anabolic signaling deficits underlie amino acid resistance of wasting, aging muscle. FASEB J. 2005;19(3):422&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardevet D, Sornet C, Bayle G, Prugnaud J, Pouyet C, Grizard J. Postprandial stimulation of muscle protein synthesis in old rats can be restored by a leucine-supplemented meal. J Nutr. 2002;132(1):95&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day ML, McGuigan MR, Brice G, Foster C. Monitoring exercise intensity during resistance training using the session RPE scale. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(2):353&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Drummond MJ, Pennings B, Fujita S, Glynn EL, Chinkes DL, et al. Leucine-enriched essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion following resistance exercise enhances mTOR signaling and protein synthesis in human muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;294(2):E392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2706121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18056791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Dreyer HC, Pennings B, Fry CS, Dhanani S, Dillon EL, et al. Skeletal muscle protein anabolic response to resistance exercise and essential amino acids is delayed with aging. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(5):1452&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2715298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18323467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med. 2018;48(3):499&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29022275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer BK, Woodard JL, White JP, Arguello EM, Haymes EM. Branched-chain amino acid supplementation and indicators of muscle damage after endurance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(6):595&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18156664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman SR, Witard OC, Philp A, Wallis GA, Baar K, Tipton KD. Branched-chain amino acid ingestion stimulates muscle myofibrillar protein synthesis following resistance exercise in humans. Front Physiol. 2017;8:390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5461297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28638350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson HK, Nilsson PA, Nilsson J, Chibalin AV, Zierath JR, Blomstrand E. Branched-chain amino acids increase p70S6k phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle after resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;287(1):E1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14998784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsanos CS, Kobayashi H, Sheffield-Moore M, Aarsland A, Wolfe RR. A high proportion of leucine is required for optimal stimulation of the rate of muscle protein synthesis by essential amino acids in the elderly. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291(2):E381&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16507602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby TJ, Triplett NT, Haines TL, Skinner JW, Fairbrother KR, McBride JM. Effect of leucine supplementation on indices of muscle damage following drop jumps and resistance exercise. Amino Acids. 2012;42(5):1987&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21562819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Verdijk L, Manders RJF, Gijsen AP, Gorselink M, Pijpers E, et al. Co-ingestion of protein and leucine stimulates muscle protein synthesis rates to the same extent in young and elderly lean men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;84(3):623&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Verdijk LB, Beelen M, Gorselink M, Kruseman AN, Wagenmakers AJM, et al. Co-ingestion of leucine with protein does not further augment post-exercise muscle protein synthesis rates in elderly men. Br J Nutr. 2008;99(3):571&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17697406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo AR, Silva-Batista C, Pedroso K, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Volume load rather than resting interval influences muscle hypertrophy during high-intensity resistance training. J Strength Cond Res Epub ahead of print. 2020 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luiking YC, Deutz NE, Memelink RG, Verlaan S, Wolfe RR. Postprandial muscle protein synthesis is higher after a high whey protein, leucine-enriched supplement than after a dairy-like product in healthy older people: A randomized controlled trial. Nutr J. 2014;13:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3909458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24450500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macnaughton LS, Wardle SL, Witard OC, McGlory C, Hamilton DL, Jeromson S, et al. The response of muscle protein synthesis following whole-body resistance exercise is greater following 40 g than 20 g of ingested whey protein. Physiol Rep. 2016;4(15):e12893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4985555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27511985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattacola CG, Perrin DH, Gansneder BM, Allen JD, Mickey CA. A comparison of visual analog and graphic rating scales for assessing pain following delayed onset muscle soreness. J Sport Rehabil. 1997;6(1):38&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, McGlory C, Phillips SM. Nutritional interventions to augment resistance training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Front Physiol. 2016;3(6):245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4558471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26388782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, McKellar SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Henselmans M, Helms E, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(6):376&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical issues relating to scientific discovery in exercise science. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Sacco P, Mawatari K. Effects of amino acid supplementation on muscle soreness and damage. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2006;16(6):620&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17342883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmond AD, Directo DJ, Elam ML, Juache G, Kreipke VC, Saralegui DE, et al. The effects of leucine-enriched branched-chain amino acid supplementation on recovery after high-intensity resistance exercise. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(8):1081&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31172828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters SJ, Van Helvoort A, Kegler D, Argil&#xe8;s JM, Luiking YC, Laviano A, et al. Dose-dependent effects of leucine supplementation on preservation of muscle mass in cancer cachectic mice. Oncol Rep. 2011;26(1):247&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21503587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ. A role for leucine in rejuvenating the anabolic effects of food in old rats. J Physiol. 2005;569(Pt 2):357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16210347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ. Should competitive bodybuilders ingest more protein than current evidence-based recommendations? Sports Med. 2019;49(10):1481&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31028659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson RJ, Goss FL, Rutkowski J, Lenz B, Dixon C, Timmer J, et al. Concurrent validation of the OMNI perceived exertion scale for resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(2):333&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12569225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roveratti MC, Jacinto JL, Oliveira DB, da Silva RA, Andraus RAC, de Oliveira EP, et al. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on muscle function during recovery from resistance exercise in young adults. Amino Acids. 2019;51(4):589&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30627787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp CPM, Pearson DR. Amino acid supplements and recovery from high-intensity resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(4):1125&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimomura Y, Inaguma A, Watanabe S, Yamamoto Y, Muramatsu Y, Bajotto G, et al. Branched-chain amino acid supplementation before squat exercise and delayed-onset muscle soreness. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20(3):236&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20601741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stark M, Lukaszuk J, Prawitz A, Salacinski A. Protein timing and its effects on muscular hypertrophy and strength in individuals engaged in weight-training. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3529694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23241341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock MS, Young JC, Golding LA, Kruskall LJ, Tandy RD, Conway-Klaassen JM, et al. The effects of adding leucine to pre and postexercise carbohydrate beverages on acute muscle recovery from resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(8):2211&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20634736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhoeven S, Vanschoonbeek K, Verdijk LB, Koopman R, Wodzig WKWH, Dendale P, et al. Long-term leucine supplementation does not increase muscle mass or strength in healthy elderly men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89(5):1468&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19321567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpi E, Kobayashi H, Sheffield-Moore M, Mittendorfer B, Wolfe RR. Essential amino acids are primarily responsible for the amino acid stimulation of muscle protein anabolism in healthy elderly adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2003;78(2):250&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12885705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldron M, Ralph C, Jeffries O, Tallent J, Theis N, Patterson SD. The effects of acute leucine or leucine&#x2013;glutamine co-ingestion on recovery from eccentrically biased exercise. Amino Acids. 2018;50(7):831&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29770871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waskiw-Ford M, Hannaian S, Duncan J, Kato H, Sawan SA, Locke M, et al. Leucine-enriched essential amino acids improve recovery from post-exercise muscle damage independent of increases in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis in young men. Nutrients. 2020;12(4):1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32290521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Hossain T, Hill DS, Phillips BE, Crossland H, Williams J, et al. Effects of leucine and its metabolite &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate on human skeletal muscle protein metabolism. J Physiol. 2013;591(11):2911&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23551944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe RR. Branched-chain amino acids and muscle protein synthesis in humans: Myth or reality? J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5568273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28852372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>