<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16284637</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-162X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Season>Jul-Sep</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of athletic training</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Athl Train</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of massage on delayed-onset muscle soreness, swelling, and recovery of muscle function.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>174</StartPage><EndPage>180</EndPage><MedlinePgn>174-80</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Delayed-onset muscle soreness (DOMS) describes muscle pain and tenderness that typically develop several hours postexercise and consist of predominantly eccentric muscle actions, especially if the exercise is unfamiliar. Although DOMS is likely a symptom of eccentric-exercise-induced muscle damage, it does not necessarily reflect muscle damage. Some prophylactic or therapeutic modalities may be effective only for alleviating DOMS, whereas others may enhance recovery of muscle function without affecting DOMS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To test the hypothesis that massage applied after eccentric exercise would effectively alleviate DOMS without affecting muscle function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used an arm-to-arm comparison model with 2 independent variables (control and massage) and 6 dependent variables (maximal isometric and isokinetic voluntary strength, range of motion, upper arm circumference, plasma creatine kinase activity, and muscle soreness). A 2-way repeated-measures analysis of variance and paired t tests were used to examine differences in changes of the dependent variable over time (before, immediately and 30 minutes after exercise, and 1, 2, 3, 4, 7, 10, and 14 days postexercise) between control and massage conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">University laboratory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS OR OTHER PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ten healthy subjects (5 men and 5 women) with no history of upper arm injury and no experience in resistance training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION(S)" NlmCategory="METHODS">Subjects performed 10 sets of 6 maximal isokinetic (90 degrees x s(-1)) eccentric actions of the elbow flexors with each arm on a dynamometer, separated by 2 weeks. One arm received 10 minutes of massage 3 hours after eccentric exercise; the contralateral arm received no treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURE(S)" NlmCategory="METHODS">Maximal voluntary isometric and isokinetic elbow flexor strength, range of motion, upper arm circumference, plasma creatine kinase activity, and muscle soreness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Delayed-onset muscle soreness was significantly less for the massage condition for peak soreness in extending the elbow joint and palpating the brachioradialis muscle (P &lt; .05). Soreness while flexing the elbow joint (P = .07) and palpating the brachialis muscle (P = .06) was also less with massage. Massage treatment had significant effects on plasma creatine kinase activity, with a significantly lower peak value at 4 days postexercise (P &lt; .05), and upper arm circumference, with a significantly smaller increase than the control at 3 and 4 days postexercise (P &lt; .05). However, no significant effects of massage on recovery of muscle strength and ROM were evident.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Massage was effective in alleviating DOMS by approximately 30% and reducing swelling, but it had no effects on muscle function.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zainuddin</LastName><ForeName>Zainal</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sacco</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nosaka</LastName><ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Athl Train</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9301647</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1062-6050</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Athl Train. 2005 Jul-Sep;40(3):186-90.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">16284639</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1250256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="sici">i1062-6050-40-3-174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB. Mechanisms of exercise-induced delayed onset muscular soreness: a brief review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1984;16:529&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6392811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Nosaka K, Braun B. Muscle function postexercise-induced muscle damage and rapid adaptation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24:512&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1569847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskula DR. Clinical implications of eccentric exercise in sports medicine. J Sport Rehabil. 1996;5:321&#x2013;329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulick DT, Kimura IF. Delayed-onset muscle soreness: what is it and how do we treat it? J Sport Rehabil. 1996;5:234&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M, Sacco P. Delayed-onset muscle soreness does not reflect the magnitude of eccentric-exercise&#x2013;induced muscle damage. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2002;12:337&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung K, Hume P, Maxwell L. Delayed-onset muscle soreness: treatment strategies and performance factors. Sports Med. 2003;33:145&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly DA, Sayers SP, McHugh MP. Treatment and prevention of delayed onset muscle soreness. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:197&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiidus PM. Manual massage and recovery of muscle function following exercise: a literature review. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1997;25:107&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9007768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernst E. Does post-exercise massage treatment reduce delayed-onset muscle soreness? A systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 1998;32:212&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9773168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiidus PM. Massage and ultrasound as therapeutic modalities in exercise-induced muscle damage. Can J Appl Physiol. 1999;24:267&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10364420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson A, Watt JM, Galloway SD. Effects of leg massage on recovery from high intensity cycling exercise. Br J Sports Med. 2004;38:173&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15039254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber MD, Servedio FJ, Woodall WR. The effects of three modalities on delayed onset muscle soreness. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1994;20:236&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7827630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LL, Keating MN, Holbert D. The effects of athletic massage on delayed onset muscle soreness, creatine kinase, and neutrophil count: a preliminary report. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1994;19:93&#x2013;99. et al.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8148868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr T, Nottle C, Nosaka K, Sacco P. The effects of therapeutic massage on delayed onset muscle soreness and muscle function following downhill walking. J Sci Med Sport. 2002;5:297&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12585613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilbert JE, Sforzo GA, Swensen T. The effects of massage on delayed onset muscle soreness. Br J Sports Med. 2003;37:72&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12547748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiidus PM, Shoemaker JK. Effleurage massage, muscle blood flow and long-term post-exercise strength recovery. Int J Sports Med. 1995;16:478&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8550258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodenburg JB, Steenbeek D, Schiereck P, Bar PR. Warm-up, stretching and massage diminish harmful effects of eccentric exercise. Int J Sports Med. 1994;15:414&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8002121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM. Variability in serum creatine kinase response after eccentric exercise of the elbow flexors. Int J Sports Med. 1996;17:120&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8833714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohnhaus EE, Adler R. Methodological problems in the measurements of pain: a comparison between the verbal rating scale and the visual analogue scale. Pain. 1975;1:379&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">800639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiidus PM. Estrogen and gender effects on muscle damage, inflammation, and oxidative stress. Can J Appl Physiol. 2000;25:274&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10953066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stupka N, Tarnopolsky MA, Yardley NJ, Phillips SM. Cellular adaptation to repeated eccentric-exercise&#x2013;induced muscle damage. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91:1669&#x2013;1678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11568149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stupka N, Lowther S, Chorneyko K, Bourgeois JM, Hogben C, Tarnopolsky MA. Gender differences in muscle inflammation after eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2000;89:2325&#x2013;2332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11090586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Hubal MJ. Are women less susceptible to exercise-induced muscle damage? Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2001;4:527&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11706288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stauber WT, Clarkson PM, Fritz VK, Evans WJ. Extracellular matrix disruption and pain after eccentric muscle action. J Appl Physiol. 1990;69:868&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2123179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LL. Acute inflammation: the underlying mechanism in delayed-onset muscle soreness. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1991;23:542&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2072832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannon JG, Orencole SF, Fielding RA. Acute phase response in exercise: interaction of age and vitamin E on neutrophils and muscle enzymes release. Am J Physiol. 1990;259:R1214&#x2013;1219. et al. (6 pt 2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2175569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>