<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30765926</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Endocrine responses following exhaustive strength exercise with and without the use of protein and protein-carbohydrate supplements.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>399</StartPage><EndPage>405</EndPage><MedlinePgn>399-405</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2018.75754</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this study was to determine the effect of carbohydrate-protein supplementation with whey protein (CHO-PROw) after resistance training, and casein protein (PROc) before bedtime on the concentration of growth hormone (GH), insulin (I) and insulin-like growth factor (IGF-1), as well as serum creatine kinase (CK) activity. Twelve strength trained male subjects (age: 25.8 &#xb1; 4.7 years; training experience 6.1 &#xb1; 0.79 years; body mass 75.9 &#xb1; 2.7 kg; body height 171.8 &#xb1; 13.3 cm) were recruited for the study. They were randomly divided into an experimental group (group E, n = 6) and a control group (group C, n = 6). All study participants completed full barbell squats with a constant external load of 90% one-repetition maximum (1RM) and a volume of 12 sets. In each set three repetitions were performed with 3 min rest periods after each set. Immediately after the exercise protocol, the subjects from the experimental group received a carbohydrate-protein complex (CHO-PROw) with a dose of 0.5 g/kg of body mass, while before bedtime they ingested a protein supplement (PROc) consisting of 90% casein protein with a dose of 0.3 g/kg of body weight The results indicate that a ignificant increase in GH concentration occurred in the experimental group between the pre-exercise level and after 24 h of recovery (p&lt;0.01), as well as between 1 h and 24 hours of recovery (p&lt;0.01). Significantly higher levels of GH were also found between the control group and the experimental group 24 hours after exercise (p&lt;0.01). The results showed significantly higher levels of IGF-1 in the experimental than in the control group after 24 hours of recovery (p&lt;0.05). In the case of insulin, no significant differences were observed when comparing levels before exercise, after exercise, after 1 hour of recovery and after 24 hours of recovery. The CHO-PROw and the PROc supplements did not reduce post-exercise muscle membrane damage as evidenced by serum CK activity. The intake of these supplements after high-intensity resistance exercise caused an increase in GH and IGF-1 concentration, which could stimulate muscle hypertrophy and inhibit proteolysis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilk</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Theory, Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michalczyk</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#x142;gorzata</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Theory, Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Go&#x142;a&#x15b;</LastName><ForeName>Artur</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Theory, Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krzysztofik</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Theory, Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maszczyk</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Theory, Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaj&#x105;c</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Theory, Academy of Physical Education in Katowice, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbohydrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supplementation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest toward publishing this article in Biology of Sport.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30765926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6358528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2018.75754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">75754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Uchida MC, Crewther BT, Ugrinowitsch C, Bacurau RF, Moriscot AS, Aoki MS. Hormonal responses to different resistance exercise schemes of similar total volume. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(7):2003&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther BT, Heke T, Keogh JW. The effects of training volume and competition on the salivary cortisol concentrations of Olympic weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(1):10&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21116196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Gomez AL, Kraemer WJ. Fasting and postprandial lipoprotein responses to a low-carbohydrate diet supplemented with n-3 fatty acids. J. of the Am. College of Nutr. 2000;19:383&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10872901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habito RC, Ball MJ. Postprandial changes in sex hormones after meals of different composition. Metabolism. 2001;50:505&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11319710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Charifi N, Denis C, Lexell J, Andersen JL, Schjerling P, Olsen S, Kjaer M. The behaviour of satellite cells in response to exercise: what have we learned from human studies? Pflugers Arch. 2005;451(2):319&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16091958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen S, Kvorning T, Kjaer M, Sj&#xf8;gaard G. The effect of short-term strength training on human skeletal muscle: the importance of physiologically elevated hormone levels. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2001;11(6):347&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaj&#x105;c A, Wilk M, Socha T, Maszczyk A, Chycki J. The effects of growth hormone and testosterone therapy on aerobic and anaerobic fitness, body composition and lipoprotein profile in middle aged men. Annals of Agricultural and Environmental Medicine. 2014;21(1):156&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24738516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, Cameron-Smith D. Is carbohydrate needed to further stimulate muscle protein synthesis/ hypertrophy following resistance exercise? J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10(1):42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3850644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24066806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AG, Ismail AN, Sharma A, Jones DA. Effects of resistance exercise volume and nutritional supplementation on anabolic and catabolic hormones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;86(4):315&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11990744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosse JD, Dixon BM. Dietary protein to maximize resistance training: a review and examination of protein spread and change theories. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012 Sep;9(1):42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3518828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22958314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak NM, Res PT, de Groot LC, Saris WH, van Loon LJ. Protein supplementation augments the adaptive response of skeletal muscle to resistance-type exercise training: a meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012;96(6):1454&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingstone C. Insulin-like growth factor-I (IGF-I) and clinical nutrition. Journal Clin Sci (Lond). 2013;125(6):265&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23721057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaj&#x105;c A, Porz&#x119;cki S, Maszczyk A, Czuba M, Michalczyk M, Zydek G. The effects of a ketogenic diet on exercise metabolism and physical performance in off-road cyclist. Nutrients. 2014;6:2493&#x2013;2508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med. 2005;35:339&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Gordon SE, Fleck SJ, Marchitelli LJ, Mello R, Dziados JE, Friedl E, Harman E, Maresh C, Fry AC. Endogenous anabolic hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise in males and females. Int. J. Sports Med. 1991;12(2):228&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1860749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Walrand S, Beelen M, Gijsen AP, Kies AK, Boirie Y, Saris WH, van Loon LJ. Dietary protein digestion and absorption rates and the subsequent postprandial muscle protein synthetic response do not differ between young and elderly men. J Nutr. 2009;139(9):1707&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tang JE, Moore DR. The role of milk- and soy-based protein in support of muscle protein synthesis and muscle protein accretion in young and elderly persons. J Am Coll Nutr. 2009;28(4):343&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20368372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Burke NC, Smith-Palmer T, Burke DG. Effect of whey and soy protein supplementation combined with resistance training in young adults. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2006;16(3):233&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16948480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb PJ, Williams AD, Hayes A. A creatine-protein-carbohydrate supplement enhances responses to resistance training. Journal Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(11):1960&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17986903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stark M, Lukaszuk J, Prawitz A, Salacinski A. Protein timing and its effects on muscular hypertrophy and strength in individuals engaged in weight-training. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3529694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23241341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Aragon A, W Krieger J. The effect of protein timing on muscle strength and hypertrophy: a meta-analysis J. Int. Soc. Sport Nutr. 2013;10:53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24299050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Hartman JW, Wilkinson SB. Dietary protein to support anabolism with resistance exercise in young men. J Am Coll Nutr. 2005;24(2):134S&#x2013;139S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15798080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Jonkers RA, Gleeson BG, Beelen M, Meijer K, Savelberg HH, Wodzig WK, Dendale P, van Loon LJ. Protein supplementation before and after exercise does not further augment skeletal muscle hypertrophy after resistance training in elderly men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89(2):608&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19106243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, Bush JA, Putukian M, Sebastianelli WJ. Hormonal responses to consecutive days of heavy-resistance exercise with or without nutritional supplementation. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85(4):1544&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9760352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Moore DR, Kujbida GW, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(3):987&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farnfield MM, Carey KA, Cameron-Smith D. Whey protein supplementation and resistance training to enhance muscle growth in young and older adults. Asia Pac J Clin Nutr. 2005;14:69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, Rahbek SK, Vendelbo MH, Matzon A, Hindhede J, Bejder A, Ringgard S, Vissing K. Whey protein hydrolysate augments tendon and muscle hypertrophy independent of resistance exercise contraction mode. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23647357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Tranchina CP, Rashti SL, Kang J, Faigenbaum AD. Effect of protein-supplement timing on strength, power, and body-composition changes in resistance-trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19(2):172&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Rasmussen CJ, Lancaster SL, Magu B, Smith P, Melton C, Greenwood M, Almada AL, Earnest CP, Kreider RB. The effects of protein and amino acid supplementation on performance and training adaptations during ten weeks of resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):643&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baty JJ, Hwang H, Ding Z, Bernard JR, Wang B, Kwon B, Ivy JL. The effect of a carbohydrate and protein supplement on resistance exercise performance, hormonal response, and muscle damage. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):321&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finaud J, Lac G, Filarie E. Oxidative stress. Relation with exercise and training. Sports Med. 2006;36(4):327&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16573358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coombes JS, McNaughton LR. Effects of branched-chain amino acid supplementation on serum creatine kinase and lactate dehydrogenase after prolonged exercise. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2000;40(3):240&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11125767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maszczyk A, Roczniok R, Czuba M, Zaj&#x105;c A, Wa&#x15b;kiewicz Z, Mikolajec K, Stanula A. Application of regression and neural models to predict competitive swimming performance. Perceptual &amp; Motor Skills. 2012;114(2):610&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22755464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormsbee MJ, Mandler WK, Thomas DD, Ward EG, Kinsey AW, Simonavice E, Panton LB, Kim JS. The effects of six weeks of supplementation with multi-ingredient performance supplements and resistance training on anabolic hormones, body composition, strength, and power in resistance-trained men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3542109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler RM, Byrne HK, Patterson JG, Ivy JL. Dietary supplements affect the anabolic hormones after weight-training exercise. J. of Appl. Physiol. 1994;76:839&#x2013;845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8175597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadi A, Gaeini AA, Kordi MR, Rahimi M, Rahnama N, Bambaeichi E. Effect of various ratios of carbohydrate-protein supplementation on resistance exercise-induced muscle damage. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2012;52(2):151&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22525650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockburn E, Hayes PR, French DN, Stevenson E, St Clair Gibson A. Acute milk-based protein-CHO supplementation attenuates exercise-induced muscle damage. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33(4):775&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18641722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher-Wellman K, Bell HK, Bloomer RJ. Oxidative stress and antioxidant defense mechanisms linked to exercise during cardiopulmonary and metabolic disorders. Journal Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2009;2(1):43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20046644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleiner RE, Hutchins AM, Johnston CS, Swan PD. Effects of an 8-week high-protein or high-carbohydrate diet in adults with hyperinsulinemia. Journal MedGenMed. 2006;8(4):39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1868379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17415320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SL, Maresh CM, Armstrong LE, Ebbeling CB, Lennon S, Rodriguez NR. Metabolic response to provision of mixed protein-carbohydrate supplementation during endurance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2002;12(4):384&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12500983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsheim E, Aarsland A, Wolfe RR. Effect of an amino acid, protein, and carbohydrate mixture on net muscle protein balance after resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2004;14(3):255&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15256687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Drummond MJ, Glynn EL, Fujita S, Chinkes DL, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Resistance exercise increases human skeletal muscle AS160/TBC1D4 phosphorylation in association with enhanced leg glucose uptake during postexercise recovery. J Appl Physiol. 2008;105(6):1967&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18845784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer RJ, Sforzo GA, Keller BA. Effects of meal form and composition on plasma testosterone, cortisol, and insulin following resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2000;10(4):415&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11099368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakravarthy MV, Fiorotto ML, Schwartz RJ, Booth FW. Long-term insulin-like growth factor-I expression in skeletal muscle attenuates the enhanced in vitro proliferation ability of the resident satellite cells in transgenic mice. Mech. Ageing Dev. 2001;122:1303&#x2013;1320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11438121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Shipp JR, Jiang J, Gower BA, Hunter GR, Goodman A, McLafferty CLJ, Urban RJ. Mechanical load increases muscle IGF-1 androgen receptor mRNA concentrations in humans. Am. J. Physiol. Endo nol. Metab. 2001;280:383&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11171591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller M, Breil FA, Lurman G, Klossner S, Fl&#xfc;ck M, Billeter R, D&#xe4;pp C, Hoppeler H. Different molecular and structural adaptations with eccentric and conventional strength training in elderly men and women. Journal Gerontology. 2011;57(6):528&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elias AN, Pandian MR, Wang L, Suarez E, James N, Wilson AF. Leptin and IGF-1 levels in unconditioned male volunteers after short-term exercise. Journal Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2000;25(5):453&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10818280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh MA, Ding W, Manfredi TJ, Solares GS, O&#x2019;Neill EF, Clements KM, Ryan ND, Kehayias JJ, Fielding RA, Evans WJ. Insulin-like growth factor I in skeletal muscle after weight-lifting exercise in frail elders. Am J Physiol. 1999;277:135&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10409137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter RC. Insulin-like growth factor (IGF), binding proteins: interactions with IGFs and intrinsic bioactivities. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2000;278:967&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10826997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony TG, Anthony JC, Lewitt MS, Donovan SM, Layman DK. Time course changes in IGFBP-1 after treadmill exercise and postexercise food intake in rats. Journal Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2001;280(4):650&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11254473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>