<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39903375</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Superset Versus Traditional Resistance Training Prescriptions: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis Exploring Acute and Chronic Effects on Mechanical, Metabolic, and Perceptual Variables.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>953</StartPage><EndPage>975</EndPage><MedlinePgn>953-975</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02176-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Supersets are a time-efficient resistance training (RT) method that involve the sequencing of two exercises with little or no rest between them. However, despite their common implementation during RT, a comprehensive and quantitative review is still lacking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">The primary aim of this systematic review and meta-analysis was to compare the acute and chronic effects of superset and traditional set prescriptions on mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual variables. We also aimed to conduct subgroup analyses to determine the effect of different types of supersets (agonist-antagonist, similar biomechanical, and alternate peripheral supersets).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A systematic literature search was conducted in PubMed, Web of Science, Embase, and EBSCO databases from inception to 10 February 2024. Studies written in English and meeting our inclusion criteria were included. Pooled meta-analysis and subgroup meta-analysis were performed using a random-effects model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Nineteen studies involving 313 participants were included. Although there was considerable variance in certain outcomes, our estimated effects suggested that, compared with traditional set prescription, supersets allow for (1) a similar total number of repetitions [standardized mean differences (SMD)&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.03; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.92] and volume load (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.05; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.86) with a shorter session duration and increased training efficiency (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.74; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01); (2) higher blood lactate concentration during (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.94; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03) and after (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.13; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) RT; (3) higher energy cost during RT (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.93; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04); (4) similar creatine kinase concentration after RT (SMD = 0.22; p = 0.36), surface electromyography (SMD = 0.01; p = 0.98), acute muscle swelling (SMD = -&#x2009;0.28; p = 0.36) and blood pressure (systolic blood pressure [SMD = 0.08; p = 0.71], diastolic blood pressure [SMD = -&#x2009;0.05; p = 0.85], and mean arterial pressure [SMD = -&#x2009;0.03; p = 0.88]); (5) higher rating of perceived exertion (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.77; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02) and similar perceived recovery (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.32; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.33); and (6) similar chronic adaptations in maximal strength (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.10; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.36), strength endurance (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.07; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.81), and muscle hypertrophy (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.05; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.87). The subgroup analysis revealed that utilizing agonist-antagonist supersets leads to a significant increase in the number of repetitions that are able to be completed compared with traditional sets (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.68; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01). Similar biomechanical supersets led to less volume load (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2009;-&#x2009;1.08; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) compared with traditional sets.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Supersets provide a time-efficient alternative to traditional RT, reducing session duration without compromising training volume, muscle activation, perceived recovery, or chronic adaptations in maximal strength, strength endurance, and muscle hypertrophy. Thus, supersets can be effectively implemented by athletes with busy schedules and RT enthusiasts whose main barrier to exercise is time. However, it should be noted that supersets generally induce higher internal loads, more severe muscle damage, and increased perceived exertion, potentially necessitating extended recovery times between sessions. Additionally, superset RT may have a similar potential to traditional RT in eliciting post-exercise hypotension. Regarding different types of supersets, agonist-antagonist supersets are more suitable for maintaining training volume, while similar biomechanical supersets concentrate stimulation on the same muscle group, compromising volume load.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROTOCOL REGISTRATION">The original protocol for this review was prospectively registered with the International Prospective Register of Systematic Reviews (PROSPERO) in December 2023 (CRD42023491533).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weakley</LastName><ForeName>Jonathon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carnegie Applied Rugby Research (CARR) Centre, Carnegie School of Sport, Leeds Beckett University, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hansen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Sichuan Agricultural University, Ya'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoqian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Amador</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0608-8755</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain. amagr@ugr.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Sciences and Physical Conditioning, Faculty of Education, Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de La Sant&#xed;sima Concepci&#xf3;n, Concepci&#xf3;n, Chile. amagr@ugr.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Funding: No external sources of funding were used to assist in the preparation of this article. Conflict of Interest: The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. Availability of Data and Material: The datasets generated and/or analyzed during the current review are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request. Author Contributions: XZ and&#xa0;HSL&#xa0;performed the meta-analysis and XZ wrote the first draft of the manuscript. All authors edited and revised the manuscript and approved the final version of the manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39903375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12011898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02176-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02176-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li H, Bi S, Luo Y, Cao Y, Zhang G. Auto-regulation method vs. fixed-loading method in maximum strength training for athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2021;12:651112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.651112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7994759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33776802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low-vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraska JM, Ramsey MW, Haff GG, Fethke N, Sands WA, Stone ME, et al. Relationship between strength characteristics and unweighted and weighted vertical jump height. Int J Sports physiol perform. 2009;4(4):461&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.4.4.461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20029097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisl&#xf8;ff U, Castagna C, Helgerud J, Jones R, Hoff J. Strong correlation of maximal squat strength with sprint performance and vertical jump height in elite soccer players. Br J Sports Med. 2004;38(3):285&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2002.002071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, Reyes A, Tran TT, de Villarreal ES, Haff GG. Increases in lower-body strength transfer positively to sprint performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2014;44(12):1693&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0227-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25059334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiteri T, Newton RU, Binetti M, Hart NH, Sheppard JM, Nimphius S. Mechanical determinants of faster change of direction and agility performance in female basketball athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(8):2205&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Falkel JE. Value of resistance training for the reduction of sports injuries. Sports Med. 1986;3(1):61&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-198603010-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3633121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11(4):209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e31825dabb8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kotob R, Ponzano M, Chaput J-P, Janssen I, Kho ME, Poitras VJ, et al. Resistance training and health in adults: an overview of systematic reviews. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2020;45(10):S165&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2020-0245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart PD, Buck DJ. The effect of resistance training on health-related quality of life in older adults: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Health Promotion Perspectives. 2019;9(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15171/hpp.2019.01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6377696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30788262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfield GS, Kenny GP, Alberga AS, Tulloch HE, Doucette S, Cameron JD, et al. Effects of aerobic or resistance training or both on health-related quality of life in youth with obesity: the HEARTY Trial. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42(4):361&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2016-0386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28177739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Feng S, Peng R, Li H. Using structural equation modeling to examine pathways between physical activity and sleep quality among Chinese TikTok users. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(9):5142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19095142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9105446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35564536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li H, Feng S, Su S. The effect of various training variables on developing muscle strength in velocity-based training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sports Med. 2023;44(12):857&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2095-8254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37196672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Castilla AP, Ramos AG, Van Hooren B, McGuigan MR, Helms ER. The acute and chronic effects of implementing velocity loss thresholds during resistance training: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and critical evaluation of the literature. Sports Med. 2023;53(1):177&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01754-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36178597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Van Hooren B, Ramos AG, Helms ER, McGuigan MR, Tufano JJ. The effects of set structure manipulation on chronic adaptations to resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51:1061&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01423-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Ramos AG, Helms ER, McGuigan MR, Tufano JJ. Acute effects of cluster and rest redistribution set structures on mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual fatigue during and after resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50:2209&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01344-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32901442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley JJ, Till K, Read DB, Leduc C, Roe GA, Phibbs PJ, et al. Jump training in rugby union players: barbell or hexagonal bar? J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(3):754&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald CJ, Lamont HS, Garner JC. A comparison of the effects of 6 weeks of traditional resistance training, plyometric training, and complex training on measures of strength and anthropometrics. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(2):422&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318220df79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22240547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivi&#xe8;re M, Louit L, Strokosch A, Seitz LB. Variable resistance training promotes greater strength and power adaptations than traditional resistance training in elite youth rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(4):947&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Vogt E, Johannsmeyer S, Forbes SC, Farthing JP. Strategic creatine supplementation and resistance training in healthy older adults. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2015;40(7):689&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2014-0498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25993883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen VM, Norum M, Schoenfeld BJ, Fimland MS. No time to lift? Designing time-efficient training programs for strength and hypertrophy: a narrative review. Sports Med. 2021;51(10):2079&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01490-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8449772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34125411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Camargo JBB, Zaroni RS, J&#xfa;nior ACT, De Oliveira TP, Trindade TB, Lopes CR, et al. Tri-set training system induces a high muscle swelling with short time commitment in resistance-trained subjects: a cross-over study. Int J Exerc Sci. 2022;15(3):561&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9022705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35516414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen V, Fimland MS, Iversen VM, Pedersen H, Balberg K, Gasvaer M, et al. A comparison of affective responses between time efficient and traditional resistance training. Front Psychol. 2022;13:912368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.912368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9243264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35783742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley KS, Flippin KJ, Blom LC, Bolin JE, Hoover DL, Judge LW. Practices, perceived benefits, and barriers to resistance training among women enrolled in college. Int J Exerc Sci. 2018;11(5):226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/ZRMT3507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5955292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoare E, Stavreski B, Jennings GL, Kingwell BA. Exploring motivation and barriers to physical activity among active and inactive Australian adults. Sports. 2017;5(3):47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports5030047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinney J, Millward H. Time and money: a new look at poverty and the barriers to physical activity in Canada. Soc Indic Res. 2010;99:341&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11205-010-9585-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Feng S, Li H. The effect of velocity loss on strength development and related training efficiency: a dose&#x2013;response meta&#x2013;analysis. Healthcare; 2023: MDPI; 2023. p. 337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9914552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36766912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Till K, Read D, Roe G, Darrall-Jones J, Phibbs P, et al. The effects of traditional, superset, and tri-set resistance training structures on perceived intensity and physiological responses. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(9):1877&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3680-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5556132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Orea GP, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Segarra-Carrillo D, Da Silva-Grigoletto ME, Belando-Pedreno N. Acute effect of upper-lower body super-set vs. traditional-set configurations on bar execution velocity and volume. Sports. 2022;10(7):110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports10070110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9323249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35878121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belo WR, Ovretveit K, de Salles BF, dos Santos LG, Ribeiro FM, Dias IB, et al. The effects of straight and alternating sets on volume load, training efficiency, and metabolic response in grapplers. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2020;60(5):713&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.20.10490-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32438787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley JJS, Till K, Read DB, Phibbs PJ, Roe G, Darrall-Jones J, et al. The effects of superset configuration on kinetic, kinematic, and perceived exertion in the barbell bench press. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(1):65&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28796130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Orea GP, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Ballester-Sanchez A, Da Silva-Grigoletto ME, Belando-Pedreno N. Upper-lower body super-sets vs. traditional sets for inducing chronic athletic performance improvements. PeerJ. 2023;11:e14636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.14636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9951798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36846453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace W, Ugrinowitsch C, Stefan M, Rauch J, Barakat C, Shields K, et al. Repeated bouts of advanced strength training techniques: effects on volume load, metabolic responses, and muscle activation in trained individuals. Sports. 2019;7(1):14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7010014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6359665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30621334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Int J Surg. 2021;88: 105906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2021.105906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Pham B, Lawson M, Klassen T. The inclusion of reports of randomised trials published in languages other than English in systematic reviews. Health Technol Assess. 2003;7(41):1&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3310/hta7410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14670218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison A, Polisena J, Husereau D, Moulton K, Clark M, Fiander M, et al. The effect of English-language restriction on systematic review-based meta-analyses: a systematic review of empirical studies. Int J Technol Assess Health Care. 2012;28(2):138&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0266462312000086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22559755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JR, Van Hooren B, Bishop C, Buckley JD, Willy RW, Fuller JT. A systematic review and meta-analysis of crossover studies comparing physiological, perceptual and performance measures between treadmill and overground running. Sports Med. 2019;49:763&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01087-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30847825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Fuller JT, Buckley JD, Miller JR, Sewell K, Rao G, et al. Is motorized treadmill running biomechanically comparable to overground running? A systematic review and meta-analysis of cross-over studies. Sports Med. 2020;50:785&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01237-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31802395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on dynamic muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47:1603&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0676-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Cooper H, Hedges L, Valentine J. Effect sizes for continuous data. The handbook of research synthesis and meta-analysis. 2009;2:221&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Wiley; 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbourne DR, Altman DG, Higgins JP, Curtin F, Worthington HV, Vail A. Meta-analyses involving cross-over trials: methodological issues. Int J Epidemiol. 2002;31(1):140&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/31.1.140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11914310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Leon S, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Perelman C, Sepulveda R, Rebolledo PA, Cuapio A, et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):16144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8352980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34373540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink J, Schoenfeld BJ, Sakamaki-Sunaga M, Nakazato K. Physiological responses to agonist&#x2013;antagonist superset resistance training. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2021;3:355&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42978-020-00092-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, Jones MT, White JB. A Comparison of compound set and traditional set resistance training in women: changes in muscle strength, endurance, quantity, and architecture. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2019;1:264&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42978-019-00030-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gahreman D, Moghadam MA, Hoseininejad E, Dehnou VV, Connor JD, Doma K, et al. Postactivation potentiation effect of two lower body resistance exercises on repeated jump performance measures. Biol Sport. 2020;37(2):105&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.93034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin-Pagan C, Blazevich AJ, Chung LH, Romero-Arenas S, Freitas TT, Alcaraz PE. Acute physiological responses to high-intensity resistance circuit training vs. traditional strength training in soccer players. Biology-Basel. 2020 Nov;9(11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7695212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33171830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carregaro RL, Gentil P, Brown LE, Pinto RS, Bottaro M. Effects of antagonist pre-load on knee extensor isokinetic muscle performance. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(3):271&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2010.529455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21170798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antunes L, Bezerra ED, Sakugawa RL, Dal Pupo J. Effect of cadence on volume and myoelectric activity during agonist-antagonist paired sets (supersets) in the lower body. Sports Biomech. 2018;17(4):502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29370715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentes CM, Costa PB, Corr&#xea;a Neto VG, Sim&#xe3;o R, Paz GA, Maia MF, et al. Hypotensive responses of reciprocal supersets versus traditional resistance training in apparently healthy men. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10(3):434&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/SIFA1254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5421986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28515839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelleher AR, Hackney KJ, Fairchild TJ, Keslacy S, Ploutz-Snyder LL. The metabolic costs of reciprocal supersets vs. traditional resistance exercise in young recreationally active adults. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(4):1043&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d3e993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz GA, Iglesias-Soler E, Willardson JM, Maia MD, Miranda H. Postexercise hypotension and heart rate variability responses subsequent to traditional, paired set, and superset resistance training methods. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(9):2433&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29239982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz GA, Robbins DW, De Oliveira CG, Bottaro M, Miranda H. Volume load and neuromuscular fatigue during an acute bout of agonist-antagonist paired-set vs. traditional-set training. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(10):2777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Realzola RA, Mang ZA, Millender DJ, Beam JR, Bellovary BN, Wells AD, et al. Metabolic profile of reciprocal supersets in young, recreationally active women and men. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(10):2709&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33927111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz GA, Maia MF, Salerno VP, Coburn J, Willardson JM, Miranda H. Neuromuscular responses for resistance training sessions adopting traditional, superset, paired set and circuit methods. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2019;59(12):1991&#x2013;2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31113178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz G, Maia M, Melibeu Bentes C, Figueiredo T, Salerno V, Sim&#xe3;o R, et al. Effect of agonist-antagonist paired set training vs. traditional set training on post-resistance exercise hypotension. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2014;17(6):13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48:137&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0788-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maia MF, Willardson JM, Paz GA, Miranda H. Effects of different rest intervals between antagonist paired sets on repetition performance and muscle activation. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(9):2529&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25148302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Monitoring training load to understand fatigue in athletes. Sports Med. 2014;44(2):139&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0253-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25200666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons R, Doma K, Sinclair W, Connor J, Leicht A. Acute effects of training loads on muscle damage markers and performance in semi-elite and elite athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51(10):2181&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01486-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34097298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Custodio R, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, S&#xe1;nchez-Moreno M, Pareja-Blanco F, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effect of different inter-repetition rest intervals across four load intensities on velocity loss and blood lactate concentration during full squat exercise. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(24):2856&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2018.1480052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29846142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Mirzaei B, Heidari N. Neuromuscular and metabolic responses to three different resistance exercise methods. Asian J Sports Med. 2014;5(1):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4009085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24868429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buitrago S, Wirtz N, Yue Z, Klein&#xf6;der H, Mester J. Mechanical load and physiological responses of four different resistance training methods in bench press exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(4):1091&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318260ec77</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22692106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa A, Coleman M, Haun C, Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ. Repetition performance, rating of perceived discomfort, and blood lactate responses to different rest interval lengths in single-joint and multijoint lower-body exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(7):1350&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37347940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Date AS, Simonson SR, Ransdell LB, Gao Y. Lactate response to different volume patterns of power clean. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(3):604&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825d9bd9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22648139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(9):1725&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213f880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saidi K, Abderrahman AB, Hackney AC, Bideau B, Zouita S, Granacher U, et al. Hematology, hormones, inflammation, and muscle damage in elite and professional soccer players: a systematic review with implications for exercise. Sports Med. 2021;51(12):2607&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01522-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manojlovi&#x107; V, Er&#x10d;ulj F. Using blood lactate concentration to predict muscle damage and jump performance response to maximal stretch-shortening cycle exercise. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2019;59(4):581&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29619805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senna GW, Dantas EHM, Scudese E, Brand&#xe3;o PP, Lira VA, Baffi M, et al. Higher muscle damage triggered by shorter inter-set rest periods in volume-equated resistance exercise. Front Physiol. 2022;13: 827847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.827847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8920480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35295573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisz A, Blazek D, Jebavy R, Kolinger D, Wilk M, Krzysztofik M, et al. Antagonist activation exercises elicit similar post-activation performance enhancement as agonist activities on throwing performance. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15(1):44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-023-00657-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10044369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36973790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda H, Maia MdF, Paz GA, Costa PB. Acute effects of antagonist static stretching in the inter-set rest period on repetition performance and muscle activation. Res Sports Med. 2015;23(1):37&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2014.975812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25630245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Fagard RH, Coeckelberghs E, Vanhees L. Impact of resistance training on blood pressure and other cardiovascular risk factors: a meta-analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Hypertension. 2011;58(5):950&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.111.177071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21896934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braith RW, Stewart KJ. Resistance exercise training: its role in the prevention of cardiovascular disease. Circulation. 2006;113(22):2642&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.105.584060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16754812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecchio RY, Brito LCd, Pe&#xe7;anha T, Forjaz CLdM. Post-exercise hypotension and its hemodynamic determinants depend on the calculation approach. J Human Hypertens. 2020;34(10):719&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41371-020-0297-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31965012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeno FP, Munhoz SV, Ramis TR, Leal-Menezes R, Fragoso EB, M&#xfc;ller DC, et al. Postexercise hypotension predicts the chronic effects of resistance training in middle-aged hypertensive individuals: a pilot study. Hypertens Res. 2021;44(5):598&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41440-020-00596-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33349650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly K, Yeung PK. Post-exercise hypotension: an alternative management strategy for hypertension and cardiovascular disease? J Clin Med. 2023;12(13):4456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12134456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10342491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37445491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudley C, Johnston R, Jones B, Till K, Westbrook H, Weakley J. Methods of monitoring internal and external loads and their relationships with physical qualities, injury, or illness in adolescent athletes: a systematic review and best-evidence synthesis. Sports Med. 2023;53(8):1559&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01844-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10356657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37071283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Lawrence MM, Utter AC, Triplett NT, Zwetsloot KA, McBride JM. Effect of inter-repetition rest on ratings of perceived exertion during multiple sets of the power clean. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:3141&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2300-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22215288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farah BQ, Lima AH, Lins-Filho OL, Souza DJ, Silva GQ, Robertson RJ, et al. Effects of rest interval length on rating of perceived exertion during a multiple-set resistance exercise. Percept Mot Skills. 2012;115(1):273&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2466/06.05.25.PMS.115.4.273-282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23033762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho IM, Luk JT, Ngo JK, Wong DP. Effects of different intraset rest durations on lifting performance and self-perceived exertion during bench press exercise. J Strength Condit Res. 2021;35(8):2114&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31045752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Condit Res. 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Trajano GS, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(6):1206&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of strength training and conditioning: Human kinetics; 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>