<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24149552</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1303-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sports science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle strength and damage following two modes of variable resistance training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>635</StartPage><EndPage>642</EndPage><MedlinePgn>635-42</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Nautilus Machine (NM) and Elastic Resistance (ER) have gained considerable popularity among athletes and recreational lifters seeking to increase muscle strength. However, there is controversy concerning the use of ER for increasing muscle hypertrophy and strength among healthy-trained individuals. The aim of the study was to compare the effect of repeated near maximal contractions by ER/NM on indicators of muscle damage including: maximal strength decrement (MVIC), rate of muscle soreness (DOMS), concentration of plasma creatine kinase (CK) and increased high muscle signal on T2 weighted images using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). Nine healthy male subjects completed two modalities of exercise (5 sets &#xd7; 10RM ER/NM) in a counterbalance cross-over study design with three weeks "wash-out" period between experiments. The MVIC was measured and DOMS rated and recorded for 4 consecutive days while blood samples were collected on day 1, 3, 5 and 7. Prior to and forty eight hours after completion of each mode of exercise, subjects underwent MRI scanning. The average of applied forces demonstrated significantly higher value for NM compared with ER (362 &#xb1; 34.2 N vs 266.73 &#xb1; 44.6 N respectively) throughout the 5 sets of dynamic exercise (all p &lt; 0.05). However, the indicators of muscle damage (T2 relaxation time, DOMS, MVIC and serum CK) exhibited a very similar response across both modes of training. Plasma CK increased significantly following both modes of training with the peak value on Day 3 (p &lt; 0.05). The time course of muscle soreness reached a significant level after both modes of exercise and showed a peak value on the 2(nd) day (p &lt; 0.05). The T2 relaxation time demonstrated a statistically significant increase following ER and NM compared with the pre-test value (p &lt; 0.05). The similarity of these responses following both the ER and NM exercise training session suggests that both modes of training provide a similar training stress; despite a considerably lower external force generation during ER. The importance of these findings is underlined by the fact that exercise-induced muscle damage has been shown to be the underlying mechanism of further muscle hypertrophy. Key pointsExercise induced muscle soreness increased levels of plasma CK, increased MRI T2 signal and prolonged strength loss indicate the moderate to intense nature of the training protocol.The similarity of these responses following both the Elastic Resistance and Nautilus Machine exercise training session suggests that both modes of training provide a similar training stress; despite a considerably lower external force generation during ER.The data in the present study suggest elastic training is a viable mode of resistance exercise that can provide a training stimulus greater than that employed in rehabilitation settings.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aboodarda</LastName><ForeName>Saied Jalal</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>George</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mokhtar</LastName><ForeName>Abdul Halim</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thompson</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1303-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elastic resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strain</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arendt-Nielsen L., Mills K. (1988) Muscle fibre conduction velocity, mean power frequency, mean EMG voltage and force during submaximal fatiguing contractions of human quadriceps. European Journal of Applied Physiology and Occupational Physiology 58, 20-25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3203668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C., Colli R., Bonomi R., Von Duvillard S.P., Viru A. (2000) Monitoring strength training: neuromuscular and hormonal profile. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 32, 202-208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne C., Eston R. (2002) The effect of exercise-induced muscle damage on isometric and dynamic knee extensor strength and vertical jump performance. Journal of Sports Science 20, 417-425</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12043831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne C., Twist C., Eston R. (2004) Neuromuscular Function after Exercise-Induced Muscle Damage: Theoretical and Applied Implications. Sports Medicine 34, 49-69</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrnes W.C., Clarkson P.M., White J.S., Hsieh S.S., Frykman P.N., Maughan R.J. (1985) Delayed onset muscle soreness following repeated bouts of downhill running. Journal of Applied Physiology 59, 710-715</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4055561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carolan B., Cafarelli E. (1992) Adaptations in coactivation after isometric resistance training. Journal of Applied Physiology 73(3), 911-917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1400055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson P., Hubal M. (2002) Exercise-induced muscle damage in humans. American Journal of Physical Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation 81(Suppl. 11), 52-69</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12409811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin J., McNair P., Marshall R. (2003) The effects of bungy weight training on muscle function and functional performance. Journal of Sports Sciences 21, 59-71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12587892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutlip R.G., Baker B.A., Hollander M., Ensey J. (2009) Injury and adaptive mechanisms in skeletal muscle. Journal of electromyography and kinesiology 19, 358-372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18768331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben W.E., Jensen R.L. (2002) Electromyographic and Kinetic Analysis of Traditional, Chain, and Elastic Band Squats. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research 16, 547-550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eston R., Byrne C., Twist C. (2003) Muscle function after exercise-induced muscle damage: Considerations for athletic performance in children and adults. Journal of Exercise Science and Fitness 1, 85-96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flann K., LaStayo P., McClain D., Hazel M., Lindstedt S. (2011) Muscle damage and muscle remodelling: no pain, no gain? Journal of Experimental Biology 15, 674-679</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21270317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley J.M., Jayaraman R.C., Prior B.M., Pivarnik J.M., Meyer R.A. (1999) MR measurements of muscle damage and adaptation after eccentric exercise Journal of Applied Physiology 87, 2311-2318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves J.E., Pollock M.L., Jones A.E., Colvin A.B., Leggett S.H. (1989) Specificity of limited range of motion variable resistance training. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 21, 84-89</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2927306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hintermeister RA, Bey MJ, Lange GW, Steadman JR, Dillman CJ. (1998) Quantification of Elastic Resistance Knee Rehabilitation Exercises. Journal of Orthopaedic and Sports Physical Therapy 28(1), 40-50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9653689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges G.N. (2006) The effect of movement strategy and elastic starting strain on shoulder resultant joint moment during elastic resistance exercise. Master Thesis. School of Medical Rehabilitation, Faculty of Medicine, University of Manitoba</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins J.T., Christopher D.I., Michelle A.S., Susan D.B. (1999) An Electromyographic Comparison of 4 Closed Chain Exercises. Journal of Athletic Training 34, 353-357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1323346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W.G. (2006) Estimating sample size for magnitude-based inferences. SportScience 10, 63-70
Available from URL:http://sportsci.org/resource/stats/ssdetermine.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hostler D., Schwirian C.I., Campos G., Toma K., Hagerman F.C., Staron R.S. (2001) Skeletal muscle adaptation in elastic resistance training young men and women. European Journal of Applied Physiology 86, 112-118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11822469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G., van Someren K.A. (2008) the prevention and treatment of exercise induce muscle damage. Sports Medicine 38, 483-503</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal M.J., Rubinstein S.R., Clarkson P.M. (2007) Mechanisms of variability in strength loss after muscle-lengthening actions. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 39, 461-468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17473772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes C.J., Hurd K., Jones A., Sprigle S. (1999) Resistance properties of Thera-Band&#xae; tubing during shoulder abduction exercise. Journal of Orthopaedic and Sports Physical Therapy 29, 413-420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10416181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israetel MA, McBride JM, Nuzzo JL, Skinner JW, Dayne AM. (2010) Kinetic and kinematic differences between squats performed with and without elastic bands. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 24(1), 190-194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19816219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;rvinen TAH, J&#xe4;rvinen TLN, K&#xe4;ri&#xe4;inen M, &#xc4;&#xe4;rimaa V, Vaittinen S, Kalimo H, J&#xe4;rvinen M. (2007) Muscle injuries: optimising recovery. Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Rheumatology 21, 317-331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17512485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi P.V., Tesch P.A. (1979) EMG frequency spectrum, muscle structure, and fatigue during dynamic contractions in men. European Journal of Applied Physiology and Occupational Physiology 42, 41-50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">499196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi P.V., Viitasalo J. (1977) Changes in motor unit activity and metabolism in human skeletal muscle during and after repeated eccentric and concentric contractions. Acta Physiology Scandinavia 100, 246-254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">888714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W., Gordon S., Fleck S., Marchitelli L., Mello R., Dziados J., Friedl K., Harman E., Maresh C., Fry A. (1991) Endogenous anabolic hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise in males and females. International Journal of Sports Medicine 12, 228-235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1860749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W.J., Duncan N.D., Volek J.S. (1998) Resistance training and elite athletes: adaptations and program considerations. Journal of Orthopedic and Sport Physical Therapy 28, 110-119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9699161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber R., Fraiden J. (1993) Muscle damage is not a function of muscle force but active muscle strain. Journal of Applied Physiology 74, 520-526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8458765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnamo V., Bottas R., Komi P. (2000) Force and EMG power spectrum during and after eccentric and concentric fatigue. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 10, 293-300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11018439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnamo V., Newton R.U., H&#xe4;kkinen K., Komi P.V., Davie A., McGuigan M., Triplett-McBride T. (2000 b) Neuromuscular responses to explosive and heavy resistance loading. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 10, 417-424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11102844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manning R.J., Graves J.E., Carpenter D.M., Leggett S.H., Pollock M.L. (1990) Constant vs variable resistance knee extension training. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 22, 397-401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2381309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCully K, Vandenborne K, DeMeirleir K, Posner J, Leigh JJ. (1992) Muscle metabolism in track athletes, using 31P magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Canadian Journal of Physiology and Pharmacology 70, 1353-1359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1490254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T., Muramatsu S., Muro M. (1988) Activity of motor units during concentric and eccentric contractions. American Journal of Physical Medicine 123, 214-224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3324772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newham D., McPhail G., Mills K., Edwards R. (1983) Ultrastructural changes after concentric and eccentric contractions of human muscle. Journal of the Neurological Sciences 61, 109-122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6631446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newsam C., Leese C., Fernandez-Silva J. (2005) Intratester reliability for determining an 8-repetition maximum for 3 shoulder exercises using elastic bands. Journal of Sport Rehabilitation 14, 35-47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page P., Lamberth J., Abadie B., Boling R., Collins R., Collins R. (1993) Posterior rotator cuff strengthening using Theraband&#xae; in a functional diagonal pattern in collegiate baseball pitchers. Journal of Athletic Training 28(4), 346-354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page P., Ellenbecker T. (2003) The Scientific and Clinical Application of Elastic Resistance. Human Kinetics</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwane J.A., Johnson S.R., Vandenakker C.B., Armstrong R.B. (1983) Delayed-onset muscular soreness and plasma CPK and LDH activities after downhill running. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 15, 51-56</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6843319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoneau G.G., Bereda S.M., Sobush D.C., Starsky A.J. (2001) Biomechanics of elastic resistance in therapeutic exercise programs. Journal of Orthopaedic and Sports Physical Therapy 31, 16-24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11204792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith L.L. (1991) Acute inflammation: the underlying mechanism in delayed onset muscle soreness? Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 23, 542-551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2072832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi H., Kuno S., Miyamoto T., Yoshioka H., Inaki M., Akima H., Katsuta S., Anno I., Itai Y. (1994) Changes in magnetic resonance images in human skeletal muscle after eccentric exercise. European Journal of Applied Physiology and Occupational Physiology 69, 408-13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7875137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee J.C., Bosch A.N., Lambert M.I. (2007) Metabolic consequences of exercise-induced muscle damage. Sports Medicine 37, 827-836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17887809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treiber F.A., Lott J., Duncan J., Slavens G., Davis H. (1998) Effects of theraband and lightweight dumbbell training on shoulder rotation torque and serve performance in college tennis players. The American Journal of Sports Medicine 26, 510-515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9689369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent W.J. (2005) Statistics in kinesiology. ThirdEdition, Human Kinetics; 147-151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace B.J., Winchester J.B., McGuigan M.R. (2006) Effects of elastic bands on force and power characteristics during the back squat exercise. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 20, 268-272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren G.L., Lowe D.A., Hayes D.A., Karwoski C.J., Prior B.M., Armstrong R.B. (1993) Excitation failure in eccentric contraction-induced injury of mouse soleus muscle. Journal of Physiology 468, 487-499</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1143838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8254518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>