<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29138605</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-1543</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Open access journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Open Access J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>213</StartPage><EndPage>226</EndPage><MedlinePgn>213-226</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/OAJSM.S123529</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The loss of muscle mass and strength with aging results in significant functional impairment. Creatine supplementation has been used in combination with resistance training as a strategy for increasing lean tissue mass and muscle strength in older adults, but results across studies are equivocal. We conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials of creatine supplementation during resistance training in older adults with lean tissue mass, chest press strength, and leg press strength as outcomes by searching PubMed and SPORTDiscus databases. Twenty-two studies were included in our meta-analysis with 721 participants (both men and women; with a mean age of 57-70 years across studies) randomized to creatine supplementation or placebo during resistance training 2-3 days/week for 7-52 weeks. Creatine supplementation resulted in greater increases in lean tissue mass (mean difference =1.37 kg [95% CI =0.97-1.76]; <i>p</i>&lt;0.00001), chest press strength (standardized mean difference [SMD] =0.35 [0.16-0.53]; <i>p</i>=0.0002), and leg press strength (SMD =0.24 [0.05-0.43]; <i>p</i>=0.01). A number of mechanisms exist by which creatine may increase lean tissue mass and muscular strength. These are included in a narrative review in the discussion section of this article. In summary, creatine supplementation increases lean tissue mass and upper and lower body muscular strength during resistance training of older adults, but potential mechanisms by which creatine exerts these positive effects have yet to be evaluated extensively.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chilibeck</LastName><ForeName>Philip D</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Kinesiology, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaviani</LastName><ForeName>Mojtaba</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nutrition and Dietetics, Acadia University, Wolfville, NS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Candow</LastName><ForeName>Darren G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology and Health Studies, University of Regina, Regina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zello</LastName><ForeName>Gordon A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Pharmacy and Nutrition, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Open Access J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101566036</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1179-1543</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">age</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bench press</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leg press</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OAJSM.S123529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">oajsm-8-213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, et al. Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: Report of the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People. Age Ageing. 2010;39(4):412&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, Vellas B, Evans WJ, et al. Sarcopenia: an undiagnosed condition in older adults. Current consensus definition: prevalence, etiology, and consequences. International working group on sarcopenia. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2011;12(4):249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3377163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Shepard DS, Katzmarzyk PT, Roubenoff R. The healthcare costs of sarcopenia in the United States. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004;52(1):80&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Little JP, Cornish SM, Pinkoski C, Chilibeck PD. Effect of nutritional interventions and resistance exercise on aging muscle mass and strength. Biogerontology. 2012;13(4):345&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22684187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on muscle accretion in the elderly. J Nutr Health Aging. 2007;11(2):185&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17435961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss M, Kaddurah-Daouk R. Creatine and creatinine metabolism. Physiol Rev. 2000;80(3):1107&#x2013;1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10893433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JF. Creatine: a review of its nutritional applications in sport. Nutrition. 1998;14(3):322&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9583381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrusch MJ, Chilibeck PD, Chad KE, Davison KS, Burke DG. Creatine supplementation combined with resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(12):2111&#x2013;2117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safdar A, Yardley NJ, Snow R, Melov S, Tarnopolsky MA. Global and targeted gene expression and protein content in skeletal muscle of young men following short-term creatine monohydrate supplementation. Physiol Genomics. 2008;32(2):219&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17957000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Forbes SC. Creatine supplementation and aging musculoskeletal health. Endocrine. 2014;45(3):354&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24190049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devries MC, Phillips SM. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in older adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(6):1194&#x2013;1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24576864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD. Differences in size, strength, and power of upper and lower body muscle groups in young and older men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2005;60(2):148&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15814855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindle RS, Metter EJ, Lynch NA, et al. Age and gender comparisons of muscle strength in 654 women and men aged 20-93 yr. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1997;83(5):1581&#x2013;1587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9375323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dangott B, Schultz E, Mozdziak PE. Dietary creatine monohydrate supplementation increases satellite cell mitotic activity during compensatory hypertrophy. Int J Sports Med. 2000;21(1):13&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadad AR, Moore RA, Carroll D, et al. Assessing the quality of reports of randomized clinical trials: is blinding necessary? Control Clin Trials. 1996;17(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8721797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 [updated March 2011] The Cochrane Collaboration; 2011.  Available from  http://handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo DM, Tritto AC, da Silva LR, et al. Effects of long-term low-dose dietary creatine supplementation in older women. Exp Gerontol. 2015;70:97&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26192975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson TJ, Lemmey AB, Jones JG, et al. Can creatine supplementation improve body composition and objective physical function in rheumatoid arthritis patients? A randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2016;68(6):729&#x2013;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26414681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans M, Guthrie N, Pezzullo J, Sanli T, Fielding RA, Bellamine A. Efficacy of a novel formulation of L-Carnitine, creatine, and leucine on lean body mass and functional muscle strength in healthy older adults: a randomized, double-blind placebo-controlled study. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2017;14:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5244582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28115977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG, Witten MS, Carter JM, Eliot KA, Knehans AW, Bemben DA. The effects of supplementation with creatine and protein on muscle strength following a traditional resistance training program in middle-aged and older men. J Nutr Health Aging. 2010;14(2):155&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20126965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliot KA, Knehans AW, Bemben DA, Witten MS, Carter J, Bemben MG. The effects of creatine and whey protein supplementation on body composition in men aged 48 to 72 years during resistance training. J Nutr Health Aging. 2008;12(3):208&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Janu&#xe1;rio RS, Junior RP, et al. Long-term creatine supplementation improves muscular performance during resistance training in older women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(4):987&#x2013;996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves CR, Merege Filho CA, Benatti FB, et al. Creatine supplementation associated or not with strength training upon emotional and cognitive measures in older women: a randomized double-blind study. PLoS One. 2013;8(10):e76301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24098469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermon S, Venembre P, Sachet C, Valour S, Dolisi C. Effects of creatine monohydrate ingestion in sedentary and weight-trained older adults. Acta Physiol Scand. 1998;164(2):147&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9805101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brose A, Parise G, Tarnopolsky MA. Creatine supplementation enhances isometric strength and body composition improvements following strength exercise training in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2003;58(1):11&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12560406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Little JP, Chilibeck PD, et al. Low-dose creatine combined with protein during resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(9):1645&#x2013;1652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18685526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Vogt E, Johannsmeyer S, Forbes SC, Farthing JP. Strategic creatine supplementation and resistance training in healthy older adults. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2015;40(7):689&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25993883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Landeryou T, Kaviani M, Paus-Jenssen L. Effects of creatine and resistance training on bone health in postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(8):1587&#x2013;1595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins J, Longhurst G, Roschel H, Gualano B. Resistance training and co-supplementation with creatine and protein in older subjects with frailty. J Frailty Aging. 2016;5(2):126&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27224505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke MB, Brabham B, Buford TW, et al. Creatine supplementation post-exercise does not enhance training-induced adaptations in middle to older aged males. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(6):1321&#x2013;1332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4019834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24633488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Defoor JG, Stevens A, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation as a potential adjuvant therapy to exercise training in cardiac patients: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2010;24(11):988&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20576665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deacon SJ, Vincent EE, Greenhaff PL, et al. Randomized controlled trial of dietary creatine as an adjunct therapy to physical training in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2008;178(3):233&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18420964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eijnde BO, Van Leemputte M, Goris M, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation and exercise training on fitness in men 55-75 yr old. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2003;95(2):818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, DE Salles Painneli V, Roschel H, et al. Creatine in type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(5):770&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20881878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Macedo AR, Alves CR, et al. Creatine supplementation and resistance training in vulnerable older women: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trial. Exp Gerontol. 2014;53:7&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24530883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Collins MA, Juncos JL. Resistance training with creatine monohydrate improves upper-body strength in patients with Parkinson disease: a randomized trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2007;21(2):107&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17312085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannsmeyer S, Candow DG, Brahms CM, Michel D, Zello GA. Effect of creatine supplementation and drop-set resistance training in untrained aging adults. Exp Gerontol. 2016;83:112&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27523919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves M, Jr, Gualano B, Roschel H, et al. Beneficial effect of creatine supplementation in knee osteoarthritis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(8):1538&#x2013;1543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto CL, Botelho PB, Carneiro JA, Mota JF. Impact of creatine supplementation in combination with resistance training on lean mass in the elderly. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2016;7(4):413&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4864174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27239423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky M, Zimmer A, Paikin J, et al. Creatine monohydrate and conjugated linoleic acid improve strength and body composition following resistance exercise in older adults. PLoS One. 2007;2(10):e991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1994592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17912368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villanueva MG, He J, Schroeder ET. Periodized resistance training with and without supplementation improve body composition and performance in older men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(5):891&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24458508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Bourgeois JM, Snow R, et al. Histological assessment of intermediate- and long-term creatine monohydrate supplementation in mice and rats. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2003;285(4):R762&#x2013;R769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12959920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taner B, Aysim O, Abdulkadir U. The effects of the recommended dose of creatine monohydrate on kidney function. NDT Plus. 2011;4(1):23&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4421632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25984094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorsteinsdottir B, Grande JP, Garovic VD. Acute renal failure in a young weight lifter taking multiple food supplements, including creatine monohydrate. J Ren Nutr. 2006;16(4):341&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17046619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves M, Jr, Gualano B, Roschel H, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation on measured glomerular filtration rate in postmenopausal women. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2011;36(3):419&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21574777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossouw JE, Anderson GL, Prentice RL, et al. Risks and benefits of estrogen plus progestin in healthy postmenopausal women: principal results From the Women&#x2019;s Health Initiative randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2002;288(3):321&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12117397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM, Price TB, Miles MP. Differential response of muscle phosphocreatine to creatine supplementation in young and old subjects. Acta Physiol Scand. 2002;174(1):57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11851597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SA, Montain SJ, Matott RP, Zientara GP, Jolesz FA, Fielding RA. Creatine supplementation and age influence muscle metabolism during exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1998;85(4):1349&#x2013;1356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9760327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solis MY, Artioli GG, Otaduy MCG, et al. Effect of age, diet and tissue type on PCr response to creatine supplementation. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2017;123(2):407&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28572496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotshalk LA, Volek JS, Staron RS, Denegar CR, Hagerman FC, Kraemer WJ. Creatine supplementation improves muscular performance in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(3):537&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotshalk LA, Kraemer WJ, Mendonca MA, et al. Creatine supplementation improves muscular performance in older women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102(2):223&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17943308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM. Acute creatine supplementation in older men. Int J Sports Med. 2000;21(1):71&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Sue Graves B, Cramer JT, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on the onset of neuromuscular fatigue threshold and muscle strength in elderly men and women (64&#x2013;86 years) J Nutr Health Aging. 2007;11(6):459&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17985060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobi JM, Rice CL, Curtin SV, Marsh GD. Neuromuscular properties and fatigue in older men following acute creatine supplementation. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;84(4):321&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11374116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Chilibeck PD, Parise G, Candow DG, Mahoney D, Tarnopolsky M. Effect of creatine and weight training on muscle creatine and performance in vegetarians. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(11):1946&#x2013;1955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14600563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg AM, Nilsson E, Werneman J, Bergstr&#xf6;m J, Hultman E. Muscle composition in relation to age and sex. Clin Sci (Lond) 1991;81(2):249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1716189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCully KK, Forciea MA, Hack LM, et al. Muscle metabolism in older subjects using 31P magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 1991;69(5):576&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1650649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCully KK, Fielding RA, Evans WJ, Leigh JS, Jr, Posner JD. Relationships between in vivo and in vitro measurements of metabolism in young and old human calf muscles. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1993;75(2):813&#x2013;819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf6;ller P, Bergstr&#xf6;m J, F&#xfc;rst P, Hellstr&#xf6;m K. Effect of aging on energy-rich phosphagens in human skeletal muscles. Clin Sci (Lond) 1980;58(6):553&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7428286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Paterson DH, McCreary CR, Marsh GD, Cunningham DA, Thompson RT. The effects of age on kinetics of oxygen uptake and phosphocreatine in humans during exercise. Exp Physiol. 1998;83(1):107&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9483424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent-Braun JA, Ng AV. Skeletal muscle oxidative capacity in young and older women and men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2000;89(3):1072&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conley KE, Jubrias SA, Esselman PC. Oxidative capacity and ageing in human muscle. J Physiol. 2000;526(1):203&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2269983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10878112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan HE, van der Graaf M, Klomp DW, Vlak MH, Padberg GW, Heerschap A. Intake of 13C-4 creatine enables simultaneous assessment of creatine and phosphocreatine pools in human skeletal muscle by 13C MR spectroscopy. Magn Reson Med. 2006;56(5):953&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17036281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen RG, Callahan DM, Foulis SA, Kent-Braun JA. Age-related changes in oxidative capacity differ between locomotory muscles and are associated with physical activity behavior. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2012;37(1):88&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22236246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J. Ageing and human muscle: observations from Sweden. Can J Appl Physiol. 1993;18(1):2&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8471991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi H, Kuno SY, Katsuta S, et al. Relationships between fiber composition and NMR measurements in human skeletal muscle. NMR Biomed. 1996;9(1):8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8842027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Rawson ES, Candow DG, Chilibeck PD. Creatine supplementation in the aging population: effects on skeletal muscle, bone and brain. Amino Acids. 2016;48(8):1793&#x2013;1805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27108136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Ward GR, Sale DG, Sutton JR. Biochemical adaptation of human skeletal muscle to heavy resistance training and immobilization. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol. 1977;43(4):700&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">908686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, Mihic S, MacLennan D, Yarasheski KE, Tarnopolsky MA. Effects of acute creatine monohydrate supplementation on leucine kinetics and mixed-muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2001;91(3):1041&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingwall JS, Morales MF, Stockdale FE. Creatine and the control of myosin synthesis in differentiating skeletal muscle. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1972;69(8):2250&#x2013;2253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC426911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4506094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingwall JS, Weiner CD, Morales MF, Davis E, Stockdale FE. Specificity of creatine in the control of muscle protein synthesis. J Cell Biol. 1974;62(1):145&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2109188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4407046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(10):1674&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis M, Poortmans JR, Francaux M, et al. No effect of creatine supplementation on human myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic protein synthesis after resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2003;285(5):E1089&#x2013;E1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12824083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanou N, Gailly P. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy and regeneration: interplay between the myogenic regulatory factors (MRFs) and insulin-like growth factors (IGFs) pathways. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2013;70(21):4117&#x2013;4130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11113627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23552962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis M, Van Beneden R, Dehoux M, Thissen JP, Francaux M. Creatine increases IGF-I and myogenic regulatory factor mRNA in C(2)C(12) cells. FEBS Lett. 2004;557(1&#x2013;3):243&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14741375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation and resistance-exercise training on muscle insulin-like growth factor in young adults. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18(4):389&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18708688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Op&#x2019;t Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, et al. Oral creatine supplementation facilitates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol. 2001;536(Pt 2):625&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene JM. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myogenic regulatory factor expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(6):923&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young JF, Bertram HC, Theil PK, et al. In vitro and in vivo studies of creatine monohydrate supplementation to Duroc and Landrace pigs. Meat Sci. 2007;76(2):342&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22064305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saremi A, Gharakhanloo R, Sharghi S, Gharaati MR, Larijani B, Omidfar K. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on serum myostatin and GASP-1. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2010;317(1&#x2013;2):25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20026378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagaard P, Kadi F, et al. Creatine supplementation augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol. 2006;573(Pt 2):525&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Charifi N, Denis C, Lexell J. Satellite cells and myonuclei in young and elderly women and men. Muscle Nerve. 2004;29(1):120&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14694507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Verdijk LB, Smeets JS, et al. The skeletal muscle satellite cell response to a single bout of resistance-type exercise is delayed with aging in men. Age (Dordr) 2014;36(4):9699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4150882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25108351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Theisen D, Bertrand L, Hespel P, Hue L, Francaux M. Creatine enhances differentiation of myogenic C2C12 cells by activating both p38 and Akt/PKB pathways. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2007;293(4):C1263&#x2013;C1271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17652429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Louis M, Theisen D, et al. Increased IGF mRNA in human skeletal muscle after creatine supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(5):731&#x2013;736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15870625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Atherton P, Patel R, et al. Effects of resistance exercise with and without creatine supplementation on gene expression and cell signaling in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2008;104(2):371&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18048590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Verdijk LB, Sakamoto K, Ely B, van Loon LJ, Musi N. Reduced AMPK-ACC and mTOR signaling in muscle from older men, and effect of resistance exercise. Mech Ageing Dev. 2012;133(11&#x2013;12):655&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23000302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sestili P, Martinelli C, Colombo E, et al. Creatine as an antioxidant. Amino Acids. 2011;40(5):1385&#x2013;1396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21404063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston AP, De Lisio M, Parise G. Resistance training, sarcopenia, and the mitochondrial theory of aging. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33(1):191&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18347672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sestili P, Martinelli C, Bravi G, et al. Creatine supplementation affords cytoprotection in oxidatively injured cultured mammalian cells via direct antioxidant activity. Free Radic Biol Med. 2006;40(5):837&#x2013;849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16520236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Koch AJ, Potteiger JA, et al. Carbohydrate supplementation attenuates muscle glycogen loss during acute bouts of resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2000;10(3):326&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10997956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>