<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41500363</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1541-6100</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle Recovery and Myofibrillar Protein Synthesis after Damaging Exercise with Recombinant Bovine &#x3b2;-Lactoglobulin, Dairy-Derived Whey or Carbohydrate Supplementation in Young Healthy Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101321</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101321</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.tjnut.2025.101321</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0022-3166(25)00827-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Supplementation with recombinant bovine &#x3b2;-lactoglobulin (rBLG), a precision-engineered mimetic of dairy-derived whey, supports similar resistance exercise (RE) training-induced muscle remodeling to whey protein (WHEY). However, the influence of rBLG on recovery indices and muscle protein synthesis rates after damaging exercise is unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the influence of rBLG supplementation on indices of muscle recovery and integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis (iMyoPS) over 72 h following damaging RE, compared with WHEY and a carbohydrate placebo.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In a randomized double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group design, 27 healthy adults consuming a controlled diet (&#x223c;0.9 g/kg body mass/d of protein) were supplemented thrice daily with 0.3 g/kg body mass of rBLG, WHEY, or isocaloric carbohydrate placebo for 3 d following an acute bout of damaging lower-body RE (8 &#xd7; 10 maximal, unilateral, eccentric knee extensions). Consumption of deuterated water combined with serial vastus lateralis muscle biopsies permitted the measurement of iMyoPS 72 h before (habitual) and after RE. Knee extensor maximum voluntary contraction (MVC), muscle soreness, and plasma concentrations of creatine kinase and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) were also assessed post-RE to characterize muscle recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">iMyoPS fractional synthetic rate (%/d) increased following damaging RE (P &lt; 0.001), with no significant differences between groups. Knee extensor MVC decreased, and subjective muscle soreness and plasma LDH concentrations increased following strenuous exercise (P &lt; 0.05 for all) with no significant differences between groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">At habitual dietary protein intakes &#x223c;0.9 g/kg body mass/d, further rBLG or WHEY supplementation did not influence muscle recovery or iMyoPS rates, suggesting that protein supplementation, at the intakes studied, may have limited efficacy as a tool to enhance muscle recovery and remodeling from damaging exercise.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 American Society for Nutrition. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rogers</LastName><ForeName>Lucy M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korzepa</LastName><ForeName>Marie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belfield</LastName><ForeName>Archie E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quinlan</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan I</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom; NIHR Birmingham Biomedical Research Centre, University Hospitals Birmingham, NHS Foundation Trust and University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallis</LastName><ForeName>Gareth A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Breen</LastName><ForeName>Leigh</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, United Kingdom; Diabetes Research Centre, College of Life Sciences, University of Leicester, Leicester, United Kingdom; Leicester Diabetes Centre, Leicester General Hospital, University Hospitals of Leicester NHS Trust, Leicester, United Kingdom. Electronic address: L.breen@leicester.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0404243</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3166</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dairy protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle protein synthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nonanimal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whey protein</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest LMR completed a PhD studentship in dietary proteins for human health, funded by The Hut Group Ltd. (Myprotein). GAW has received research funding from Volac International Ltd. LB has received research funding and/or honoraria for work related to dietary proteins in human health from Dairy UK, Volac International Ltd., The Hut Group Ltd. (Myprotein), Biomega Group, European Whey Processors Association, National Dairy Council and Danone Research &amp; Innovation. All other authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41500363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tjnut.2025.101321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0022-3166(25)00827-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>