<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27826394</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-000X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asian journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asian J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Exercise Order of Resistance Training on Strength Performance and Indices of Muscle Damage in Young Active Girls.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e30599</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e30599</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e30599</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Exercise order is one of the key variables in designing resistance training (RT) that may affect physiological and functional muscle characteristics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this research was to examine the effect of exercise order of RT on muscle strength, lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) and creatine kinase (CK) enzymes as indices of muscle damage in active young girls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">For this purpose, 24 active girls aged 20 - 30 years voluntarily participated in six weeks RT. The subjects were randomly assigned into three groups of large to small muscle group (SLM, n = 8), large to small group (LSM, n = 8) and control group (Co, n = 8). The RT performed in bench press, lat pull down, triceps with machine and biceps with barbell. Before and after RT, blood sample was collected to measure the level of LDH and CK enzymes activity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The result of analysis indicated that RT significantly increased the level of LDH enzymes in all three groups (P &lt; 0.05). In addition, the result showed that six weeks of RT did not cause any significant change in CK (P &gt; 0.05). However, there is no significant difference between SLM, LSM and control in CK and LDH after six weeks RT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Both RT methods cause the same improvement on muscle strength and performance. Also muscle damage indices did not show sensitivity to the exercise order. Therefore, resistance training may be designed regardless of effect of exercise order on muscle damage.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nazari</LastName><ForeName>Maydeye</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports Sciences, Taft Branch, Islamic Azad University, Taft, IR Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azarbayjani</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Ali</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Physical Education and Sports Science, Tehran Central Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, IR Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azizbeigi</LastName><ForeName>Kamal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports Sciences, Sanandaj Branch, Islamic Azad University, Sanandaj, IR Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Asian J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528850</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-000X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine Kinase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lactate Dehydrogenase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27826394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5097860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/asjsm.30599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ. Optimizing strength training: designing nonlinear periodization workouts. US: Human Kinetics; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellezza PA, Hall EE, Miller PC, Bixby WR. The influence of exercise order on blood lactate, perceptual, and affective responses. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(1):203&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias I, de Salles BF, Novaes J, Costa PB, Simao R. Influence of exercise order on maximum strength in untrained young men. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(1):65&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2008.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2008.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19243993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simao R, Leite RD, Speretta GF, Maior AS, de Salles BF, de Souza Junior TP, et al. Influence of upper-body exercise order on hormonal responses in trained men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2013;38(2):177&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2012-0040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2012-0040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23438229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simao R, Spineti J, de Salles BF, Oliveira LF, Matta T, Miranda F, et al. Influence of exercise order on maximum strength and muscle thickness in untrained men. J Sports Sci Med. 2010;9(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spineti J, de Salles BF, Rhea MR, Lavigne D, Matta T, Miranda F, et al. Influence of exercise order on maximum strength and muscle volume in nonlinear periodized resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(11):2962&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e2e19b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e2e19b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20938358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teague BN, Schwane JA. Effect of intermittent eccentric contractions on symptoms of muscle microinjury. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27(10):1378&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8531608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB. Mechanisms of exercise-induced delayed onset muscular soreness: a brief review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1984;16(6):529&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6392811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly AE, Clarkson PM, Maughan RJ. Exercise-induced muscle damage: effects of light exercise on damaged muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1992;64(4):350&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1592061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karamizrak SO, Ergen E, Tore IR, Akgun N. Changes in serum creatine kinase, lactate dehydrogenase and aldolase activities following supramaximal exercise in athletes. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1994;34(2):141&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7967583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stromme JH, Rustad P, Steensland H, Theodorsen L, Urdal P. Reference intervals for eight enzymes in blood of adult females and males measured in accordance with the International Federation of Clinical Chemistry reference system at 37 degrees C: part of the Nordic Reference Interval Project. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2004;64(4):371&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1080/00365510410002742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00365510410002742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15223701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves CP, Simao R, Miranda H, Ribeiro J, Soares J, Salles B, et al. Influence of exercise order on muscle damage during moderate-intensity resistance exercise and recovery. Res Sports Med. 2013;21(2):176&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1080/15438627.2012.738439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2012.738439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23541104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancaccio P, Limongelli FM, Maffulli N. Monitoring of serum enzymes in sport. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40(2):96&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2005.020719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2005.020719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2492050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16431993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva DP, Curty VM, Areas JM, Souza SC, Hackney AC, Machado M. Comparison of DeLorme with Oxford resistance training techniques: effects of training on muscle damage markers. Biol Sport. 2010;27(2):77&#x2013;81. doi: 10.5604/20831862.913066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/20831862.913066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Practical assessment of body-composition. Phys Sportsmed. 1985;13(5):76&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27463295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simao R, Farinatti Pde T, Polito MD, Maior AS, Fleck SJ. Influence of exercise order on the number of repetitions performed and perceived exertion during resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(1):152&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent HK, Morgan JW, Vincent KR. Obesity exacerbates oxidative stress levels after acute exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(5):772&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15126709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett WE. Exercise and sport science. USA: Lippincott Willams and Wilkins; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ, Evans WJ. Strength and power training: physiological mechanisms of adaptation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1996;24:363&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8744256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of strength training and conditioning/National Strength and Conditioning. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klapcinska B, Iskra J, Poprzecki S, Grzesiok K. The effects of sprint (300 m) running on plasma lactate, uric acid, creatine kinase and lactate dehydrogenase in competitive hurdlers and untrained men. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2001;41(3):306&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11533559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabo A, Romvari R, Bogner P, Febel H, Szendro Z. Metabolic changes induced by regular submaximal aerobic exercise in meat-type rabbits. Acta Vet Hung. 2003;51(4):503&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1556/AVet.51.2003.4.8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1556/AVet.51.2003.4.8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14680062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougios V. Reference intervals for serum creatine kinase in athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41(10):674&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2006.034041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2006.034041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17526622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiidus PM. Estrogen and gender effects on muscle damage, inflammation, and oxidative stress. Can J Appl Physiol. 2000;25(4):274&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10953066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>