<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34757466</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Social Media, Body Image and Resistance Training: Creating the Perfect 'Me' with Dietary Supplements, Anabolic Steroids and SARM's.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>81</StartPage><MedlinePgn>81</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">81</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-021-00371-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Few studies have assessed the use of dietary supplements, anabolic androgenic steroids (AAS) and selective androgen receptor modulators (SARM) in male gym users. The comparison of physical appearance with others on social media and the exposure to fitness-related content on social media (i.e., image-centric social media use) may have a profound role in using these compounds due to its role in creating negative body images in male gym users.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Provide contemporary data on the use of dietary supplements, AAS and SARM among young male gym users, and test the hypothesis that social media is associated with the use of dietary supplements, AAS and SARM, as a result of a&#xa0;negative body image.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this cross-sectional study, conducted in the Netherlands, male gym users (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;2269; 24&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6&#xa0;years) completed an online questionnaire including self-reported measures regarding resistance training participation, image-centric social media use, dietary supplement intake, and body image. The prevalence of AAS and SARM use was assessed with randomized response, a technique to ask sensitive questions indirectly.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of all participants, 83% used ergogenic dietary supplements (mainly protein and creatine), and an estimated 9 versus 2.7% had ever used AAS versus SARM. Image-centric social media use was positively associated with the use of dietary supplements (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;.26; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01) and AAS (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), but not SARM. Image-centric social media use was associated with a more dissatisfied body image (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;.34; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). Body image did not mediate the relationship between image-centric social media use and the use of doping compounds.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The use of dietary supplements in young male gym users is exorbitant, with the use of AAS and SARM being substantial. Image-centric social media use is positively associated with the use of dietary supplements and AAS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hilkens</LastName><ForeName>Luuk</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise, HAN University of Applied Sciences, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cruyff</LastName><ForeName>Maarten</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Methodology and Statistics, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woertman</LastName><ForeName>Liesbeth</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benjamins</LastName><ForeName>Jeroen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social, Health, and Organizational Psychology, Utrecht University, PO Box 80140, 3508 TC, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Psychology, Helmholtz Institute, Utrecht University, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evers</LastName><ForeName>Catharine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3942-0590</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social, Health, and Organizational Psychology, Utrecht University, PO Box 80140, 3508 TC, Utrecht, The Netherlands. c.evers@uu.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Androgenic&#x2013;anabolic steroids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body image</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary supplements</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gym users</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Image-centric social media use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARM&#x2019;s</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Selective androgen receptor modulators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social media</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Luuk Hilkens, Maarten Cruyff, Liesbeth Woertman, Jeroen Benjamins and Catharine Evers declare no conflicts of interest that might be relevant to the contents of this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34757466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8579410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-021-00371-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-021-00371-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gough C. Health &amp; Fitness Clubs-Statistics &amp; Facts;2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hover P, Eldert, P. van. Fitnessbranche in Nederland|2018: kerncijfers vraag- en aanbodzijde, factsheet 2019/1.;2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goston C. Intake of nutritional supplements among people exercising in gyms and influencing factors. Nutrition. 2010;26(6):604&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20004078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stubbe JH, Chorus AM, Frank LE, de Hon O, van der Heijden PG. Prevalence of use of performance enhancing drugs by fitness centre members. Drug Test Anal. 2014;6(5):434&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24019293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardenaar F, van den Dool R, Ceelen I, Witkamp R, Mensink M. Self-reported use and reasons among the general population for using sports nutrition products and dietary supplements. Sports (Basel) 2016;4(2):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooney R, Simonato P, Ruparelia R, Roman-Urrestarazu A, Martinotti G, Corazza O. The use of supplements and performance and image enhancing drugs in fitness settings: a exploratory cross-sectional investigation in the United Kingdom. Hum Psychopharmacol. 2017;32(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28657184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, McKellar SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Henselmans M, Helms E, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(6):376&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissen SL, Sharp RL. Effect of dietary supplements on lean mass and strength gains with resistance exercise: a meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol (Bethesda Md: 1985) 2003;94(2):651&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12433852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Ronde W, Smit DL. Anabolic androgenic steroid abuse in young males. Endocr Connect. 2020;9(4):R102&#x2013;R111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7219134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32229704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson AB, Evans NA. Anabolic androgenic steroids: a survey of 500 users. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(4):644&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, Storer TW, Berman N, Callegari C, Clevenger B, Phillips J, et al. The effects of supraphysiologic doses of testosterone on muscle size and strength in normal men. N Engl J Med. 1996;335(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8637535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit DL, de Ronde W. Outpatient clinic for users of anabolic androgenic steroids: an overview. Neth J Med. 2018;76(4):167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiblin I, Garmo H, Garle M, Holmberg L, Byberg L, Micha&#xeb;lsson K, et al. Anabolic steroids and cardiovascular risk: a national population-based cohort study. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2015;152:87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26005042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggish AL, Weiner RB, Kanayama G, Hudson JI, Lu MT, Hoffmann U, et al. Cardiovascular toxicity of illicit anabolic-androgenic steroid use. Circulation. 2017;135(21):1991&#x2013;2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5614517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28533317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, Hatfield DL, Hoffman JR, Kraemer WJ, Labotz M, Phillips SM, et al. Anabolic-Androgenic Steroid Use in Sports, Health, and Society. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(8):1778&#x2013;1794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan BP, Kanayama G, Pope HG., Jr Performance-enhancing drugs on the web: a growing public-health issue. Am J Addict. 2013;22(2):158&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23414502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Wagoner RM, Eichner A, Bhasin S, Deuster PA, Eichner D. Chemical composition and labeling of substances marketed as selective androgen receptor modulators and sold via the internet. JAMA. 2017;318(20):2004&#x2013;2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5820696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29183075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burmeister MA, Fincher TK. Recreational use of selective androgen receptor modulators. US Pharm. 2020;45(60):15&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machek SB, Cardaci TD, Wilburn DT, Willoughby DS. Considerations, possible contraindications, and potential mechanisms for deleterious effect in recreational and athletic use of selective androgen receptor modulators (SARMs) in lieu of anabolic androgenic steroids: a narrative review. Steroids. 2020;164:108753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagoe D, Pallesen S. Androgen abuse epidemiology. Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes. 2018;25(3):185&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29369917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagoe D, Molde H, Andreassen CS, Torsheim T, Pallesen S. The global epidemiology of anabolic-androgenic steroid use: a meta-analysis and meta-regression analysis. Ann Epidemiol. 2014;24(5):383&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24582699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Hon O, Kuipers H, van Bottenburg M. Prevalence of doping use in elite sports: a review of numbers and methods. Sports Med. 2015;45(1):57&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25169441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylow L. Three challenges of being a scientist in an age of misinformation. Wiley Online Library; 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33547635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland G, Tiggemann M. A systematic review of the impact of the use of social networking sites on body image and disordered eating outcomes. Body Image. 2016;17:100&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26995158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corazza O, Simonato P, Demetrovics Z, Mooney R, van de Ven K, Roman-Urrestarazu A, et al. The emergence of Exercise Addiction, Body Dysmorphic Disorder, and other image-related psychopathological correlates in fitness settings: A cross sectional study. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(4):e0213060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6447162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30943200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fardouly J, Vartanian LR. Social media and body image concerns: current research and future directions. Curr Opin Psychol 2016;9:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fardouly J, Diedrichs PC, Vartanian LR, Halliwell E. The mediating role of appearance comparisons in the relationship between media usage and self-objectification in young women. Psychol Women Q. 2015;39(4):447&#x2013;457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duplaga M. The use of fitness influencers' websites by young adult women: a cross-sectional study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(17).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7503997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope H, Pope HG, Phillips KA, Olivardia R. The Adonis complex: the secret crisis of male body obsession: Simon and Schuster; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavender JM, Brown TA, Murray SB. Men, muscles, and eating disorders: an overview of traditional and muscularity-oriented disordered eating. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2017;19(6):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5731454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28470486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray SB, Griffiths S, Mitchison D, Mond JM. The transition from thinness-oriented to muscularity-oriented disordered eating in adolescent males: a clinical observation. J Adolesc Health. 2017;60(3):353&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27989453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope HG, Khalsa JH, Bhasin S. Body image disorders and abuse of anabolic-androgenic steroids among men. JAMA. 2017;317(1):23&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27930760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauw D, Bilard J. Understanding appearance-enhancing drug use in sport using an enactive approach to body image. Front Psychol. 2017;8(2088).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5712587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman AL, Pope HG, Bhasin S. The health threat posed by the hidden epidemic of anabolic steroid use and body image disorders among young men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2019;104(4):1069&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30239802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fardouly J, Willburger BK, Vartanian LR. Instagram use and young women&#x2019;s body image concerns and self-objectification: testing mediational pathways. New Media Soc. 2018;20(4):1380&#x2013;1395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fardouly J, Vartanian LR. Negative comparisons about one's appearance mediate the relationship between Facebook usage and body image concerns. Body Image. 2015;12:82&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25462886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tylka TL, Bergeron D, Schwartz JP. Development and psychometric evaluation of the Male Body Attitudes Scale (MBAS) Body Image. 2005;2(2):161&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18089184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri A, Mukerjee R. Randomized response: theory and techniques. Abingdon-on-Thames: Routledge; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayc KUK. Asking sensitive questions indirectly. Biometrika. 1990;77(2):436&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lensvelt-Mulders GJ, Hox JJ, Van der Heijden PG, Maas CJ. Meta-analysis of randomized response research: thirty-five years of validation. Sociol Methods Res. 2005;33(3):319&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team RC . R: a language and environment for statistical computing. Vienna: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revelle W. psych: procedures for personality and psychological research. Evanston: Northwestern University; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheers NJ, Dayton CM. The covariate unrelated question randomized response model. In: Proceedings of the Social Statistics Section, American Statistical Association. 1982:407&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruano J, Teixeira VH. Prevalence of dietary supplement use by gym members in Portugal and associated factors. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2020;17(1):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7038552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreher M, Ehlert T, Simon P, Neuberger EWI. Boost me: prevalence and reasons for the use of stimulant containing pre workout supplements among fitness studio visitors in Mainz (Germany) Front Psychol. 2018;9:1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6056667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30065677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Camic CL, Harty PS. Common habits, adverse events, and opinions regarding pre-workout supplement use among regular consumers. Nutrients. 2019;11(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31014016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duiven E, van Loon LJ, Spruijt L, Koert W, de Hon OM. Undeclared doping substances are highly prevalent in commercial sports nutrition supplements. J Sports Sci Med. 2021;20(2):328&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8219275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon P, Striegel H, Aust F, Dietz K, Ulrich R. Doping in fitness sports: estimated number of unreported cases and individual probability of doping. Addiction. 2006;101(11):1640&#x2013;1644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit DL, Buijs MM, de Hon O, den Heijer M, de Ronde W. Positive and negative side effects of androgen abuse. The HAARLEM study: a one-year prospective cohort study in 100 men. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31(2):427&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindqvist Bagge AS, Ros&#xe9;n T, Fahlke C, Ehrnborg C, Eriksson BO, Moberg T, et al. Somatic effects of AAS abuse: a 30-years follow-up study of male former power sports athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(9):814&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28389219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwitz H, Andersen JT, Dalhoff KP. Health consequences of androgenic anabolic steroid use. J Intern Med. 2019;285(3):333&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30460728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope HG, Jr, Kanayama G, Athey A, Ryan E, Hudson JI, Baggish A. The lifetime prevalence of anabolic-androgenic steroid use and dependence in Americans: current best estimates. Am J Addict. 2014;23(4):371&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3961570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24112239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnecaze AK, O&#x2019;Connor T, Aloi JA. Characteristics and attitudes of men using anabolic androgenic steroids (AAS): a survey of 2385 men. Am J Mens Health. 2020;14(6):1557988320966536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33307930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yager Z, O&#x2019;Dea JA. Relationships between body image, nutritional supplement use, and attitudes towards doping in sport among adolescent boys: implications for prevention programs. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014;11(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3986904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24670105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association AP. Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders (DSM-5&#xae;). American Psychiatric Pub; 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24413388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosley PE. Bigorexia: bodybuilding and muscle dysmorphia. Eur Eat Disord Rev. 2009;17(3):191&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18759381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longobardi C, Prino LE, Fabris MA, Settanni M. Muscle dysmorphia and psychopathology: findings from an Italian sample of male bodybuilders. Psychiatry Res. 2017;256:231&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28646788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leiden I, Olfers M, van Wijk A, Rijnink R, Wolsink J, van Esseveldt J. Sterk spul: Aard, omvang en ernst van de dopinghandel in Nederland. 2020. https://bureaubeke.nl/publicaties/sterk-spul/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths S, Murray SB, Krug I, McLean SA. The contribution of social media to body dissatisfaction, eating disorder symptoms, and anabolic steroid use among sexual minority men. Cyberpsychol Behav Soc Netw. 2018;21(3):149&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5865626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29363993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frison E, Vandenbosch L, Eggermont S. Exposure to media predicts use of dietary supplements and anabolic-androgenic steroids among Flemish adolescent boys. Eur J Pediatr. 2013;172(10):1387&#x2013;1392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23748985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freberg K, Graham K, McGaughey K, Freberg LA. Who are the social media influencers? A study of public perceptions of personality. Public Relat Rev. 2011;37(1):90&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Veirman M, Cauberghe V, Hudders L. Marketing through Instagram influencers: the impact of number of followers and product divergence on brand attitude. Int J Adv. 2017;36(5):798&#x2013;828.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>