<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35813845</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on body composition: a GRADE-assessed systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>196</StartPage><EndPage>218</EndPage><MedlinePgn>196-218</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/15502783.2022.2079384</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Previous studies have suggested that beta-alanine supplementation may benefit exercise performance, but current evidence regarding its effects on body composition remains unclear. This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to investigate the effects of beta-alanine supplementation on body composition indices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Online databases, including PubMed/Medline, Scopus, Web of Science, and Embase, were searched up to April 2021 to retrieve randomized controlled trials (RCTs), which examined the effect of beta-alanine supplementation on body composition indices. Meta-analyses were carried out using a random-effects model. The I<sup>2</sup> index was used to assess the heterogeneity of RCTs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among the initial 1413 studies that were identified from electronic databases search, 20 studies involving 492 participants were eligible. Pooled effect size from 20 studies indicated that beta-alanine supplementation has no effect on body mass (WMD: -0.15 kg; 95% CI: -0.78 to 0.47; <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.631, I<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0%, <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.998), fat mass (FM) (WMD: -0.24 kg; 95% CI: -1.16 to 0.68; <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.612, I<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0%, <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.969), body fat percentage (BFP) (WMD: -0.06%; 95% CI: -0.53 to 0.40; <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.782, I<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0%, <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.936), and fat-free mass (FFM) (WMD: 0.05 kg; 95% CI: -0.71 to 0.82; <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.889, I<sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0%, <i>p</i> =&#xa0;0.912). Subgroup analyses based on exercise type (resistance training [RT], endurance training [ET], and combined training [CT]), study duration (&lt;8 and &#x2265;8&#xa0;weeks), and beta-alanine dosage (&lt;6 and &#x2265;6&#xa0;g/d) demonstrated similar results. Certainty of evidence across outcomes ranged from low to moderate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This meta-analysis study suggests that beta-alanine supplementation is unlikely to improve body composition indices regardless of supplementation dosage and its combination with exercise training. No studies have examined the effect of beta-alanine combined with both diet and exercise on body composition changes as the primary variable. Therefore, future studies examining the effect of the combination of beta-alanine supplementation with a hypocaloric diet and exercise programs are warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Informa UK Limited, trading as Taylor &amp; Francis Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashtary-Larky</LastName><ForeName>Damoon</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ahvaz Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Nutrition and Metabolic Diseases Research Center, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagheri</LastName><ForeName>Reza</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghanavati</LastName><ForeName>Matin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, National Nutrition and Food Technology Research Institute, Faculty of Nutrition Sciences and Food Technology, Teheran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asbaghi</LastName><ForeName>Omid</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Cancer Research Center, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Alexei</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Marymount University, Department of Health and Human Performance, Arlington, VA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stout</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6114-1649</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Central Florida, Institute of Exercise Physiology and Physical Therapy, School of Kinesiology and Physical Therapy, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suzuki</LastName><ForeName>Katsuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Waseda University, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Tokorozawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>11P2JDE17B</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015091">beta-Alanine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015091" MajorTopicYN="N">beta-Alanine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beta-alanine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Jeffrey R. Stout has conducted industry-sponsored research on creatine and other nutraceuticals over the past 25 years. Further, Jeffrey R. Stout has also received financial support for presenting the science of various nutraceuticals, like beta-alanine, at industry-sponsored scientific conferences</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35813845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9261744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2022.2079384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2079384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bagheri R, Moghadam BH, Candow DG, et al. Effects of Icelandic yogurt consumption and resistance training in healthy untrained older males. Br J Nutr. 2021;1&#x2013;26. DOI: 10.1017/S000711452100310X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S000711452100310X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34121642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deibert P, Solleder F, K&#xf6;nig D, et al. Soy protein based supplementation supports metabolic effects of resistance training in previously untrained middle aged males. Aging Male. 2011;14(4):273&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22066824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourabbas M, Bagheri R, Hooshmand Moghadam B, et al. Strategic ingestion of high-protein dairy milk during a resistance training program increases lean mass, strength, and power in trained young males. Nutrients. 2021;13(3):948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7999866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33804259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly RM, O&#x2019;Connell SL, Mundell NL, et al. Protein-enriched diet, with the use of lean red meat, combined with progressive resistance training enhances lean tissue mass and muscle strength and reduces circulating IL-6 concentrations in elderly women: a cluster randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014;99(4):899&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidari F, Asadi M, Mohammadi-Asl J, et al. Effect of weight-loss diet combined with taurine supplementation on body composition and some biochemical markers in obese women: a randomized clinical trial. Amino Acids. 2020;52(8):1115&#x2013;1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32696178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blancquaert L, Everaert I, Derave W.. Beta-alanine supplementation, muscle carnosine and exercise performance. Current Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2015;18(1):63&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25474013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quesnele JJ, Laframboise MA, Wong JJ, et al. The effects of beta-alanine supplementation on performance: a systematic review of the literature. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2014;24(1):14&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23918656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli GG, Gualano B, Smith A, et al. Role of beta-alanine supplementation on muscle carnosine and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(6):1162&#x2013;1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Graves BS, Smith AE, et al. The effect of beta-alanine supplementation on neuromuscular fatigue in elderly (55&#x2013;92 years): a double-blind randomized study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2008;5(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2585553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18992136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducker KJ, Dawson B, Wallman KE.. Effect of beta-alanine supplementation on 800-m running performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013;23(6):554&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23630039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AE, Walter AA, Graef JL, et al. Effects of &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation and high-intensity interval training on endurance performance and body composition in men; a double-blind trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2649036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19210788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern BD, Robinson TL. Effects of &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on performance and body composition in collegiate wrestlers and football players. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(7):1804&#x2013;1815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21659893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenn JM, Gray M, Stewart RW Jr., et al. Effects of 28-day beta-alanine supplementation on isokinetic exercise performance and body composition in female masters athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(1):200&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26110349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendrick IP, Harris RC, Kim HJ, et al. The effects of 10 weeks of resistance training combined with &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on whole body strength, force production, muscular endurance and body composition. Amino Acids. 2008;34(4):547&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18175046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6(7):e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al. The Cochrane collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Bmj. 2011;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Controlled Clin Trials. 1986;7(3):177&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, et al. Introduction to meta-analysis. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asbaghi O, Khosroshahi MZ, Kashkooli S, et al. Effect of calcium&#x2011;vitamin d co&#x2011;supplementation on insulin, insulin sensitivity, and glycemia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Horm Metab Res. 2019;51(5):288&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31071733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asbaghi O, Sadeghian M, Rahmani S, et al. The effect of green coffee extract supplementation on anthropometric measures in adults: a comprehensive systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Complement Ther Med. 2020;51:102424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32507437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hozo SP, Djulbegovic B, Hozo I. Estimating the mean and variance from the median, range, and the size of a sample. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2005;5(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1097734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15840177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, et al. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. Bmj. 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1539&#x2013;1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias A. Assessing the influence of a single study in the meta-analysis estimate. STATA Tech Bull. 1999;8(47).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, et al. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. Bmj. 1997;315(7109):629&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction&#x2014;GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology. 2011;64(4):383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon H, Oxman A, Vist G, et al. Rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations: GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2008;336:924&#x2013;926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2335261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shbib S, Rashidlamir A, Hakak Dokht E. The effects of plyometric training and &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on anaerobic power and serum level of carnosine in handball players. 2021;17(3):569&#x2013;576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impson-Davey GJK. Effects of supplementation with creatine monohydrate and beta-alanine, alone or combined, on repeated sprint performance and physiological parameters in amateur team and racket sport players. Kinesiology. 2020;52(1):115&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith CR, Harty PS, Stecker RA, et al. A pilot study to examine the impact of beta-alanine supplementation on anaerobic exercise performance in collegiate rugby athletes. Sports. 2019;7(11):231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6915363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31703346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshmand S, Halabchi F, Hashempour A, et al., Improving physical activity tolerance in sedentary overweight women under beta-alanine supplementation. Science &amp; Sports. 2019;34(3):e217&#x2013;e23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas MC, Cholewa J, Panissa V, et al. Short-time &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on the acute strength performance after high-intensity intermittent exercise in recreationally trained men. Sports. 2019;7(5):108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6571921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31075911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaques M, Glick D, Greco-Henderson D, et al. The effects of short term &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on performance in division iii male and female rowers. Journal of Exercise and Nutrition. 2(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askari F, Rahmaninia F. The effect of 8 weeks beta-alanine supplementation and resistance training on maximal-intensity exercise performance adaptations in young males. Physical education of students. 2019;23(1):4&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaffe D, Hewit J, Cholewa J, et al. Influence of sustained beta-alanine supplementation on body composition and physical performance in college-aged males seeking military commission. International Journal of Human Movement and Sports Sciences. 2018;6(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Fukuda DH, Hoffman JR, et al. Distinct Effects of Repeated-Sprint Training in Normobaric Hypoxia and &#x3b2;-Alanine Supplementation. Journal of the American College of Nutrition. 2019;38(2):149&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30277420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter AA, Smith AE, Kendall KL, et al. Six weeks of high-intensity interval training with and without beta-alanine supplementation for improving cardiovascular fitness in women. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2010;24(5):1199&#x2013;1207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross M, Bieri K, Hoppeler H, et al. Beta-alanine supplementation improves jumping power and affects severe-intensity performance in professional alpine skiers. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2014;24(6):665&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24901210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outlaw JJ, Smith-Ryan AE, Buckley AL, et al. Effects of &#x3b2;-alanine on body composition and performance measures in collegiate women. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(9):2627&#x2013;2637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25486294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale C, Hill CA, Ponte J, et al. &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation improves isometric endurance of the knee extensor muscles. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3420321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22697405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Landau G, Stout JR, et al. &#x3b2;-Alanine ingestion increases muscle carnosine content and combat specific performance in soldiers. Amino Acids. 2015;47(3):627&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4326648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25510839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Faigenbaum AD, et al. Short-duration &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation increases training volume and reduces subjective feelings of fatigue in college football players. Nutr Res. 2008;28(1):31&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kresta JY, Oliver JM, Jagim AR, et al. Effects of 28&#xa0;days of beta-alanine and creatine supplementation on muscle carnosine, body composition and exercise performance in recreationally active females. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014;11(1):55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25505854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huerta Ojeda &#xc1;, Tapia Cerda C, Poblete Salvatierra MF, et al. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on physical performance in aerobic-anaerobic transition zones: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2020;12(9):2490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32824885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale C, Saunders B, Harris RC. Effect of beta-alanine supplementation on muscle carnosine concentrations and exercise performance. Amino Acids. 2010;39(2):321&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20091069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutka TL, Lamboley CR, McKenna MJ, et al. Effects of carnosine on contractile apparatus Ca<sup>2</sup>&#x207a; sensitivity and sarcoplasmic reticulum Ca<sup>2</sup>&#x207a; release in human skeletal muscle fibers. J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(5):728&#x2013;736. Bethesda, Md: 1985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22174397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hipkiss AR, Michaelis J, Syrris P. Non-enzymatic glycosylation of the dipeptide L-carnosine, a potential anti-protein-cross-linking agent. FEBS Lett. 1995;371(1):81&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7664889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AE, Stout JR, Kendall KL, et al. Exercise-induced oxidative stress: the effects of &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation in women. Amino Acids. 2012;43(1):77&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22102056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KJ, Song HS, Yoon DH, et al. The effects of 10 weeks of &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on peak power, power drop, and lactate response in Korean national team boxers. J Exerc Rehabil. 2018;14(6):985&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30656159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Theisen D, Bertrand L, et al. Creatine enhances differentiation of myogenic C2C12 cells by activating both p38 and Akt/PKB pathways. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2007;293(4):C1263&#x2013;C71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17652429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on Yo&#x2013;Yo test performance: a meta-analysis. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;43:158&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Cramer JT, Zoeller RF, et al. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on the onset of neuromuscular fatigue and ventilatory threshold in women. Amino Acids. 2007;32(3):381&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17136505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Edge J, Kendrick IP, et al. The effect of very high interval training on the carnosine content and buffering capacity of V lateralis from humans. FASEB J. 2007;21(6):A944&#x2013;A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delextrat A, Targen N, Impson-Davey G, et al. Effects of supplementation with creatine monohydrate and beta-alanine, alone or combined, on repeated sprint performance and physiological parameters in amateur team and racket sport players. Kinesiology. 2020;52(1):115&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson RM, Saunders B, Ball G, et al. Effects of &#x3b2;-alanine supplementation on exercise performance: a meta-analysis. Amino Acids. 2012;43(1):25&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22270875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trexler ET, Smith-Ryan AE, Stout JR, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: beta-Alanine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2015;12(1):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4501114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26175657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Jones G, Hill CA, et al. The carnosine content of v lateralis in vegetarians and omnivores. FASEB J. 2007;21(6):A944&#x2013;A.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>