<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33651737</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Training, Supplementation, and Pharmacological Practices of Competitive Male Bodybuilders Across Training Phases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>963</StartPage><EndPage>970</EndPage><MedlinePgn>963-970</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003989</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hackett, DA. Training, supplementation, and pharmacological practices of competitive male bodybuilders across training phases. J Strength Cond Res 36(4): 963-970, 2022-Bodybuilding involves the pursuit of muscularity and leanness primarily through the use of progressive resistance training in combination with other practices such as manipulation of diet and use of ergogenic aids. This study aimed to compare the training practices and ergogenic aids used by competitive male bodybuilders across training phases. An online survey was completed by 235 competitive male bodybuilders with a median age of 26.0 (interquartile range 23.0-31.3) years. Results showed that most respondents performed split-routines (85.5%), 4-7 sessions per week (95.7%), trained major muscle groups twice a week (&gt;50%), and session duration being 60-90 minutes (55.7%). Off-season resistance training sessions mostly comprised of targeting 2-3 muscle groups (56%), 2-3 exercises per muscle group (60.4%), 3-4 sets per exercise (73.2%), 7-12 repetition maximum (RM) per set (71.6%), and 61-180 seconds recovery between sets and exercises (80.5%). At the precompetition phase (6 weeks before competition), there was a decrease in the number of muscle groups trained per session (p = 0.027) and a greater number of repetitions performed per set (p &lt; 0.001). A significant increase in the reported aerobic exercise volume was found during precompetition (&lt;0.001). Performance enhancing drugs were used by 53.6% of respondents who did not compete in natural bodybuilding competitions. Dietary supplements were used by 95.7% of respondents with the most common being creatine monohydrate (80.4%) and whey protein (65.8%). Findings suggest that competitive bodybuilders follow resistance training practices consistent with the broad muscular hypertrophy recommendations but a notable shift in practices occur in the weeks before competition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackett</LastName><ForeName>Daniel A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity, Lifestyle, Ageing and Wellbeing Faculty Research Group, School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>MU72812GK0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003401">Creatine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003401" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33651737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202204000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA. Are resistance training systems necessary to avoid a stagnation and maximize the gains muscle strength and hypertrophy? Sci Sports 35: 65.e1&#x2013;65.e16, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutcher SH. High-intensity intermittent exercise and fat loss. J Obes 2011: 868305, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell A, Simper T. Nutritional peak week and competition day strategies of competitive natural bodybuilders. Sports 6: 126, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell A, Simper T, Barker M. Nutritional strategies of high level natural bodybuilders during competition preparation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 15: 4, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell AJ, Simper T, Helms E. Nutritional strategies of British professional and amateur natural bodybuilders during competition preparation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 16: 35, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, et al. Do metabolites that are produced during resistance exercise enhance muscle hypertrophy? Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 2125&#x2013;2135, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, de Lira CAB, Paoli A, et al. Nutrition, pharmacological and training strategies adopted by six bodybuilders: Case report and critical review. Eur J Transl Myol 27: 6247, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fisher J, Steele J. A review of the acute effects and long-term adaptations of single- and multi-joint exercises during resistance training. Sports Med 47: 843&#x2013;855, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Schoenfeld BJ. Should resistance training programs aimed at muscular hypertrophy be periodized? A systematic review of periodized versus non-periodized approaches. Sci Sports 33: e97&#x2013;e104, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT. Program design for resistance training. In: Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. JM Sheppard and NT Triplett, eds. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2015. pp 458&#x2013;464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Aragon AA, Fitschen PJ. Evidence-based recommendations for natural bodybuilding contest preparation: Nutrition and supplementation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 11: 20, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kistler BM, Fitschen PJ, Ranadive SM, Fernhall B, Wilund KR. Case study: Natural bodybuilding contest preparation. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 24: 694&#x2013;700, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Wilk M, Wojda&#x142;a G, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A. Maximizing muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review of advanced resistance training techniques and methods. Int J Environ Res Public Health 16:4897, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Adhikari BK, Gao L, et al. Performance-enhancing drugs abuse caused cardiomyopathy and acute hepatic injury in a young bodybuilder. Am J Mens Health 12: 1700&#x2013;1704, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liokaftos D. Defining and defending drug-free bodybuilding: A current perspective from organisations and their key figures. Int J Drug Pol 60: 47&#x2013;55, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall K, Chamberlain K, Hodgetts D. Male bodybuilders on Instagram: Negotiating inclusive masculinities through hegemonic masculine bodies. J Gend Stud 29: 570&#x2013;589, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melhem AJ Jr, Ara&#xfa;jo AC, Figueiredo FNS, Figueiredo DLA. Acute myocardial infarction in a young bodybuilder: A case report and review of the literature. Am J Case Rep 21: e924796, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell L, Hackett D, Gifford J, Estermann F, O'Connor H. Do bodybuilders use evidence-based nutrition strategies to manipulate physique? Sports 5: 76, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell L, Slater G, Hackett D, Johnson N, O'Connor H. Physiological implications of preparing for a natural male bodybuilding competition. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 619&#x2013;629, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriarty N, Attar N. Clenbuterol-induced myocarditis: A case report. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med 7: 001662, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Farias Zuniga A, et al. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. J Physiol 597: 4601&#x2013;4613, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosley PE. Bigorexia: Bodybuilding and muscle dysmorphia. Eur Eat Disord Rev 17: 191&#x2013;198, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardue A, Trexler ET, Sprod LK. Case study: Unfavorable but transient physiological changes during contest preparation in a drug-free male bodybuilder. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 27: 550&#x2013;559, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope HG Jr, Wood RI, Rogol A, et al. Adverse health consequences of performance-enhancing drugs: An Endocrine Society Scientific Statement. Endocr Rev 35: 341&#x2013;375, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N, Alvar B, Evetovich T, et al. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards JR, Scheerlinck PH, Owen KP, Colby DK. Bodybuilding supplements leading to copper toxicity, encephalopathy, fulminant hepatic failure and rhabdomyolysis. Am J Emerg Med 38:2487.e1&#x2013;2487.e5, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts BM, Helms ER, Trexler ET, Fitschen PJ. Nutritional recommendations for physique athletes. J Hum Kinet 71: 79&#x2013;108, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson SL, Lambeth-Mansell A, Gillibrand G, Smith-Ryan A, Bannock L. A nutrition and conditioning intervention for natural bodybuilding contest preparation: Case study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 12: 20, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossow LM, Fukuda DH, Fahs CA, Loenneke JP, Stout JR. Natural bodybuilding competition preparation and recovery: A 12-month case study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 8: 582&#x2013;592, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger J. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low-vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2857&#x2013;2872, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The use of specialized training techniques to maximize muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J 33: 60&#x2013;65, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Is there a minimum intensity threshold for resistance training-induced hypertrophic adaptations? Sports Med 43: 1279&#x2013;1288, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 94&#x2013;103, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Haun C, Itagaki T, Helms ER. Calculating set-volume for the limb muscles with the performance of multi-joint exercises: Implications for resistance training prescription. Sports 7: 177, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effects of resistance training frequency on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 1689&#x2013;1697, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Tiryaki-Sonmez G. Influence of resistance training frequency on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1821&#x2013;1829, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spendlove J, Mitchell L, Gifford J, et al. Dietary intake of competitive bodybuilders. Sports Med 45: 1041&#x2013;1063, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele I, Pope H, Ip EJ, Barnett MJ, Kanayama G. Is competitive body-building pathological? Survey of 984 male strength trainers. BMJ Open Sport Exerc 6: e000708, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele IH, Pope HGJ, Kanayama G. Competitive bodybuilding: Fitness, pathology, or both? Harv Rev Psychiatry 27: 233&#x2013;240, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, Giessing J, Gentil P. Clarity in reporting terminology and definitions of set endpoints in resistance training. Muscle Nerve 56: 368&#x2013;374, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone M, Plisk S, Collins D. Training principles: Evaluation of modes and methods of resistance training&#x2014;a coaching perspective. Sports Biomech 1: 79&#x2013;103, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol 126: 30&#x2013;43, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, et al. Concurrent training: A meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2293&#x2013;2307, 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>