<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16284641</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-162X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Season>Jul-Sep</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of athletic training</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Athl Train</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of partial immobilization after eccentric exercise on recovery from muscle damage.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>197</StartPage><EndPage>202</EndPage><MedlinePgn>197-202</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Short-term strict immobilization of the arm using a cast enhances recovery of muscle function after eccentric exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine if placing one arm in a sling ("light" immobilization) for 4 days after eccentric exercise of the elbow flexor muscles would reduce muscle soreness and enhance recovery compared with the exercised but not immobilized contralateral arm.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Subjects performed 10 sets of 6 maximal isokinetic (90 degrees x s(-1)) eccentric actions of the elbow flexors of each arm on a Cybex dynamometer, separated by 2 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">University laboratory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS OR OTHER PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ten healthy subjects (5 men and 5 women) with no history of upper arm injury or resistance training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION(S)" NlmCategory="METHODS">One randomly assigned arm was placed in a sling for 4 days after the 30-minute postexercise measurement to secure the elbow joint at 90 degrees ; the contralateral arm received no treatment. The subject removed the sling when showering and sleeping and during postexercise measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURE(S)" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used an activity monitor to record upper arm activity before and after immobilization. We also compared changes in maximal isometric and isokinetic voluntary strength, range of motion, upper arm circumference, plasma creatine kinase activity, and muscle soreness during 7 days postexercise between arms with a 2-way, repeated-measures analysis of variance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eccentric exercise resulted in large losses in both isometric and isokinetic maximal voluntary contraction forces (approximately 40%), reduced range of motion (approximately 20%), increased arm circumference (approximately 10 mm), elevated plasma creatine kinase activity (approximately 2000 IU x L(-1)), and development of delayed-onset muscle soreness. No significant differences were noted between conditions for any measure except upper arm circumference, which increased significantly less for the immobilization than the control arm at 7 days postexercise (P &lt; .05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Light immobilization had no effect on enhancing recovery of muscle function and delayed-onset muscle soreness after eccentric-exercise-induced muscle damage.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zainuddin</LastName><ForeName>Zainal</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hope</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sacco</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nosaka</LastName><ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Athl Train</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9301647</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1062-6050</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1250263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="sici">i1062-6050-40-3-197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jarvinen MJ, Lehto MU. The effects of early mobilisation and immobilisation on the healing process following muscle injuries. Sports Med. 1993;15:78&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvinen TA, Kaariainen M, Jarvinen MJ, Kalimo H. Muscle strain injuries. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2000;12:155&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB. Initial events in exercise-induced muscular injury. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1990;22:429&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2205778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Nosaka K, Braun B. Muscle function after eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage and rapid adaptation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24:512&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1569847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Sayers SP. Etiology of exercise-induced muscle damage. Can J Appl Physiol. 1999;24:234&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10364418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrnes WC, Clarkson PM. Delayed onset muscle soreness and training. Clin Sports Med. 1986;5:605&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3521903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chleboun GS, Howell JN, Conatser RR, Giesey JJ. Relationship between muscle swelling and stiffness after eccentric exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30:529&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9565934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Clarkson PM, Lee J. Activity and immobilization after eccentric exercise, I: recovery of muscle function. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1587&#x2013;1592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10994909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Peters BT, Knight CA, Urso ML, Parkington J, Clarkson PM. Short term immobilization after eccentric exercise, part I: contractile properties. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:753&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12750584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Clarkson PM. Short term immobilization after eccentric exercise, part II: creatine kinase and myoglobin. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:762&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12750585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Clarkson PM, Lee J. Activity and immobilization after eccentric exercise, II: serum CK. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1593&#x2013;1597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10994910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell JN, Chleboun G, Conatser R. Muscle stiffness, strength loss, swelling and soreness following exercise-induced injury in humans. J Physiol. 1993;464:183&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1175380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8229798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Hubal MJ. Exercise-induced muscle damage in humans. Am Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;81:S52&#x2013;S69. (11 suppl)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12409811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM. Variability in serum creatine kinase response after eccentric exercise of the elbow flexors. Int J Sports Med. 1996;17:120&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8833714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M. Repeated eccentric exercise bouts do not exacerbate muscle damage and repair. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16:117&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zainuddin Z, Newton M, Sacco P, Nosaka K. Effects of massage on delayed-onset muscle soreness, swelling, and recovery of muscle function. J Athl Train. 2005;40:171&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1250256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metcalf BS, Curnow JSH, Evans C, Voss LD, Wilkin TJ. Technical reliability of the CSA activity monitor: the EarlyBird Study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:1533&#x2013;1537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12218751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehto MU, Duance VC, Restall D. Collagen and fibronectin in healing skeletal muscle injury: an immunohistological study of the effect of physical activity on the repair on injured gastrocnemius muscle in the rat. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1985;67:820&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3902851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasson S, Barnes W, Hunter M, Williams J. Therapeutic effect of high speed voluntary muscle contractions on muscle soreness and muscle performance. J Orthop Sports Physical Ther. 1989;10:499&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18796936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulick DT, Kimura IF, Sitler M, Paolone AM, Kelly JD., IV. Various treatment techniques on signs and symptoms of delayed onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train. 1996;31:145&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1318445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denegar CR, Perrin DH. Effect of transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation, cold, and a combination treatment on pain, decreased range of motion, and strength loss associated with delayed onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train. 1992;27:200&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isabell WK, Durrant E, Myrer W, Anderson S. The effects of ice massage, ice massage with exercise, and exercise on the prevention and treatment of delayed onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train. 1992;27:208&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxton JM, Donnelly AE. Light concentric exercise during recovery from exercise-induced muscle damage. Int J Sports Med. 1995;16:347&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7591383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung K, Hume PA, Maxwell L. Delayed onset muscle soreness: treatment strategies and performance factors. Sports Med. 2003;33:145&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM. Changes in indicators of inflammation after eccentric exercise of the elbow flexors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8871903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brondstrup P, Denmark V. Late edema after strenuous exercise. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1962:401&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13872805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>