<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32205914</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of a strength or hypertrophy training protocol, each performed using two different modes of resistance, on biomechanical, biochemical and anthropometric parameters.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>85</StartPage><EndPage>91</EndPage><MedlinePgn>85-91</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2020.92517</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The study aimed to analyse the effectiveness of two variants of 8-week strength training (hypertrophy, strength) with different modes of resistance. Healthy male subjects (n=75) were allocated to five groups of equal size: hypertrophy training with a variable cam (Hyp-Cam), hypertrophy training with disc plates (Hyp-Disc), maximal strength training with a variable cam (Str-Cam), maximal strength training with disc plates (Str-Disc), and a control group (CG). The Hyp-Cam and Str-Cam groups trained with a machine where the load was adjusted to the strength capabilities of the elbow flexors. The Hyp-Disc and Str-Disc groups trained on a separate machine in which a load was applied with disc plates. The CG did not train. All groups were assessed for changes and differences in one-repetition (1RM) lifts, isokinetic muscle torque, arm circumference and arm skinfold thickness, and plasma creatine kinase (CK) activity. Within the 8-week training period the 1RM increased (p&lt;.001) in all groups by over 20%, without significant between-group differences. Muscle torque increased significantly (p&lt;.001) only in the Hyp-Cam group (by 13.7%). Arm circumference at rest increased by 1.7 cm (p&lt;.001) and 1.1 cm (p&lt;.001) in the Hyp-Cam and Hyp-Disc groups, respectively, but not in the Str-Cam (0.3 cm; p&gt;.05) or Str-Disc (0.2 cm; p&gt;.05) group. Skinfold thickness of the biceps and triceps decreased more within the 8-week period in Str-Cam (by 1.1 and 2.1 cm; p&lt;.001 and p&lt;.001 respectively) and Str-Disc (0.7 and 1.5 cm; p&lt;.001 and p&lt;.01 respectively) than in Hyp-Cam (by 0.4 and 1.8 cm; p&gt;.05 and p&lt;.01 respectively) and Hyp-Disc groups (by 0.2 and 1.4 cm; p&gt;.05 and p&lt;.05 respectively). CK activity was significantly (p&lt;.05) elevated in each training group except Hyp-Cam (p&gt;.05). The 8-week hypertrophy training with a variable cam results in greater peak muscle torque improvement than in the other examined protocols, with an insignificant increase in training-induced muscle damage indices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2020.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staniszewski</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jozef Pilsudski University of Physical Education in Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mastalerz</LastName><ForeName>Andrzej</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jozef Pilsudski University of Physical Education in Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urbanik</LastName><ForeName>Czes&#x142;aw</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jozef Pilsudski University of Physical Education in Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine kinase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elbow flexors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Isokinetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle torque</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Variable cam</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7075227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.92517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">92517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen Keijo. Short vs. Long rest period between the sets in hypertrophic resistance training: influence on muscle strength, size, and hormonal adaptations in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(3):572&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. Evidence-based resistance training recommendations for muscular hypertrophy. Med Spor. 2013;17(4):217&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, Dudley GA, Dooly C, Feigenbaum MS, Fleck SJ, Franklin B, Fry AC, Hoffman JR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sport Exer. 2002;34(2):364&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, Lhester GM, Sellers J, Nooner JL, Schnaiter JA, Bond-Williams KE, Carter AS, Ross CL, et al. Longer interset rest periods enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(7):1805&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW, Wathen D. Resistance training. In: Baechle TR, Earle RW, editors. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2008. pp. 381&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judge LW, Burke JR. The effect of recovery time on strength performance following a high-intensity bench press workout in males and females. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5:184&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20625191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinkovi&#x107; M, Brati&#x107; M, Ignjatovi&#x107; A, Radovanovi&#x107; D. Effects of 8-week instability resistance training on maximal strength in inexperienced young individuals. Serb J Sports Sci. 2012;1(5):17&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehnert M, Stastny P, Sigmund M, Xaverova Z, Hubnerova B, Kostrzewa M. The effect of combined machine and body weight circuit training for women on muscle strength and body composition. J Phys Educ Sport. 2015;15(3):561&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manfredini Baroni B, Silveira Pinto R, Herzog W, Vaz MA. Eccentric resistance training of the knee extensor muscle: Training programs and neuromuscular adaptations. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2015;23(3):183&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Tiryaki-Sonmez G, Willardson JM, Fontana F. An electromyographic comparison of a modified version of the plank with a long lever and posterior tilt versus the traditional plank exercise. Sports Biomech. 2014;13(3):296&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25325773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya Y, Kikuchi N, Shirato M, Ochi E. Differences of activation pattern and damage in elbow flexor muscle after isokinetic eccentric contractions. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2015;23(3):169&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer JT, Beck TW, Housh TJ, Masseyc LL, Marekc SM, Danglemeierc S, et al. Acute effects of static stretching on characteristics of the isokinetic angle &#x2013; torque relationship, surface electromyography, and mechanomyography. J Sports Sci. 2007;25(6):687&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17454536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulig K, Andrews JG, Hay JG. Human strength curves. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1984;12:417&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6376139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP, Tetro DT. Changes in the relationship between joint angle and torque production associated with the repeated bout effect. J Sports Sci. 2003;21(11):927&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14626372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira LF, Matta TT, Alves DS, Garcia MAC, Vieira TMM. Effect of the shoulder position on the biceps brachii EMG in different dumbbell curls. J Sports Sci Med. 2009;8(1):24&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24150552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippou A, Maridaki M, Bogdanis GC. Angle-specific impairment of elbow flexors strength after isometric exercise at long muscle length. J Sports Sci. 2003;21(10):859&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14620029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigeon P, Yahia L, Feldman AG. Moment arms and lengths of human upper limb muscles as functions of joint angles. J Biomech. 1996;29(10):1365&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8884483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland J, Morris B. Variable-cam resistance training machines: Do they match the angle - torque relationship in humans? J Sports Sci. 2008;26(2):163&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17885926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasenoehrl T, Wessner B, Tschan H, Vidotto C, Crevenna R, Csapo R. Eccentric resistance training intensity may affect the severity of exercise induced muscle damage. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2017;57(9):1195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27167715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ide BN, Soares Nunes LA, Brenzikofer R, Macedo DV. Time course of muscle damage and inflammatory responses to resistance training with eccentric overload in trained individuals. Mediators Inflamm. 2013 Article ID 204942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3564279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23401642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Does blood flow restriction result in skeletal muscle damage? A critical review of available evidence. Scand J Med Sci Spor. 2014;24(6):e415&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24650102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado M, Pereira R, Sampaio-Jorge F, Knifis F, Hackney A. Creatine supplementation: effects on blood creatine kinase activity responses to resistance exercise and creatine kinase activity measurement. Braz J Pharm Sci. 2009;45(4):251&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabell L, Zebas C. Resistive torque validation of the nautilus multi-biceps machine. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13(1):20&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalleau G, Baron B, Bonazzi B, Leroyer P, Verstraete T, Verkindt C. The influence of variable resistance moment arm on knee extensor performance. J Sports Sci. 2010;28(6):657&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagen M, Lemke M, Kutsch H, Lahner M. Development of a functional anatomical subtalar pronator and supinator strength training machine. Technol Health Care. 2015;23(5):627&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26410123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staniszewski M, Urbanik C, Mastalerz A, Iwa&#x144;ska D, Madej A, Karczewska M. Comparison of changes in the load components for intense training on two machines: with a variable-cam and with a disc plate. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2017;57(6):782&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27054355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lochman TG, Roche AF, Martorell R. Anthropometric Standardization Reference Manual. Illinoi, USA: Human Kinetics Books; 1988. Hall JG, Allanson JE, Gripp KW, Slavotinek AM. Handbook of Physical Measurements. Oxford University Press 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Thornton JC, Kolesnik S, Pierson RN. Anthropometry in body composition: an overview. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2000;904:317&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campanholi Neto J, Cedin L, Dato CC, Rodrigues Bertucci D, De Andrade Perez SE, Baldissera V. A single session of testing for one repetition maximum (1RM) with eight exercises is trustworthy. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2015;18(3):74&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flores FJ, Sedano S, Redondo JC. Optimal load and power spectrum during snatch and clean: differences between international and national weightlifters. Int J Perform Anal Sport. 2017;17(4):521&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten B, Stevens L, Colpus M, Larumbe-Zabala E, Naclerio F. The effects of a sport-specific maximal strength and conditioning training on critical velocity, anaerobic running distance, and 5-km race performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(1):80&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25946163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Do Nascimento MA, Mayhew JL, Ritti-Dias RM, Avelar A, Okano AH, Cyrino ES. Reliability of 1RM test in detrained men with previous resistance training experience. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2014;22(2):137&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, van Loon L, Meijer K, Savelberg HM. One-repetition maximum strength test represents a valid means to assess leg strength in vivo in humans. J Sports Sci. 2009;27(1):59&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19031334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio FJ, Jim&#xe9;nez A, Alvar BA, Peterson MD. Assessing strength and power in resistance training. J Hum Sport Exerc. 2009;4(2):100&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyer B. A comparison of the effects of three strength training programs on women. J Appl Sports Sci Res. 1990;4(3):88&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driss T, Serrau V, Behm DG, Lesne-Chabran E, Le Pellec-Muller A, Vandewalle H. Isometric training with maximal co-contraction instruction does not increase co-activation during exercises against external resistances. J Sports Sci. 2014;32(1):60&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23876029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lemos Muller CH, Ramis TR, Ribeiro JL. Comparison of the effects of resistance training with and without vascular occlusion in increases of strength and hypertrophy: A review of the literature. Sports Med. 2015;11(4):2668&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Fukuda DH, Stout JR, Ratamess NA. Improving muscle strength and size: The importance of training volume, intensity, and status. Kinesiol. 2015;47(2):131&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Pain MG, Folland JP. Short-term training for explosive strength causes neural and mechanical adaptations. Exp Physiol. 2012;97(5):630&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22308164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowery RP, Joy JM, Loenneke JP, Souza EO, Machado M, Dudeck JE, Wilson I. Practical blood flow restriction training increases muscle hypertrophy during a periodized resistance training programme. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2014;34(4):317&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24188499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C. The development of skeletal muscle hypertrophy through resistance training: the role of muscle damage and muscle protein synthesis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(3):485&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29282529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>