<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34690286</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Eccentric Overload during Resistance Exercise: A Stimulus for Enhanced Satellite Cell Activation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>388</StartPage><EndPage>398</EndPage><MedlinePgn>388-398</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002818</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">This study aimed to assess if one bout of concentric/eccentric exercise with damaging eccentric overload (CON/ECC+) provides a sufficient stimulus to induce SC activation, proliferation, and differentiation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Biopsies from the vastus lateralis muscle of recreationally active men were obtained in the rested condition and again from the contralateral leg 7 d after exhaustive concentric/eccentric (CON/ECC) (n = 15) or CON/ECC+ (n = 15) leg extension exercise and in a nonexercising control group (CG) (n = 10). Total SC number (Pax7+), activated (Pax7+/MyoD+), and differentiating (myogenin+) SCs, fiber type distribution, and myofibers expressing neonatal myosin heavy chain (MHCneo) were determined immunohistochemically. Creatine kinase and myoglobin were measured in venous blood. Isokinetic strength tests were repeatedly conducted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Significant increases in creatine kinase and myoglobin (P = 0.001) indicated myofiber damage, whereas maximal strength was not impaired. Only after CON/ECC+, SC content (P = 0.019) and SC related to type II fibers (P = 0.011) were significantly increased. A significant increase in the proportion of activated SCs occurred after CON/ECC+ only (P = 0.003), the increase being significantly (P &lt; 0.05) different from the changes after CON/ECC and in CG. The number of differentiating SC and MHCneo remained unchanged.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Eccentric overload during leg extension exercise induced significant SC activation, increases in SC content and in SC number related to type II myofibers. However, there were no signs of increased SC differentiation or formation of new myofibers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wehrstein</LastName><ForeName>Michaela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Medical Clinic, University Hospital Heidelberg, GERMANY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xf6;ffel</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiberg</LastName><ForeName>Nadine</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Medical Clinic, University Hospital Heidelberg, GERMANY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gwechenberger</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Olympic Training Center Heidelberg, GERMANY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Betz</LastName><ForeName>Theresa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rittweg</LastName><ForeName>Mareike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Olympic Training Center Heidelberg, GERMANY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parstorfer</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pilz</LastName><ForeName>Maximilian</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Biometry and Informatics, University of Heidelberg, GERMANY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friedmann-Bette</LastName><ForeName>Birgit</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Medical Clinic, University Hospital Heidelberg, GERMANY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032496" MajorTopicYN="N">Satellite Cells, Skeletal Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34690286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202203000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dumont NA, Bentzinger CF, Sincennes MC, Rudnicki MA. Satellite cells and skeletal muscle regeneration. Compr Physiol . 2015;5(3):1027&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crameri RM, Langberg H, Magnusson P, et al. Changes in satellite cells in human skeletal muscle after a single bout of high intensity exercise. J Physiol . 2004;558(Pt 1):333&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Blanco CE, Sattler FR, Schroeder ET, Wiswell RA. Satellite cell numbers in young and older men 24 hours after eccentric exercise. Muscle Nerve . 2006;33(2):242&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, De Lisio M, Johnston AP, et al. Association of interleukin-6 signalling with the muscle stem cell response following muscle-lengthening contractions in humans. PLoS One . 2009;4(6):e6027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, Toth KG, Tarnopolsky MA, Parise G. Satellite cell number and cell cycle kinetics in response to acute myotrauma in humans: immunohistochemistry versus flow cytometry. J Physiol . 2010;588(Pt 17):3307&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, Nederveen JP, Fortino SA, et al. Brain-derived neurotrophic factor is associated with human muscle satellite cell differentiation in response to muscle-damaging exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2020;45(6):581&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen UR, Langberg H, Helmark IC, et al. Local NSAID infusion inhibits satellite cell proliferation in human skeletal muscle after eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2009;107(5):1600&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nederveen JP, Joanisse S, Snijders T, Thomas ACQ, Kumbhare D, Parise G. The influence of capillarization on satellite cell pool expansion and activation following exercise-induced muscle damage in healthy young men. J Physiol . 2018;596(6):1063&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly C, McKay B, Phillips S, Tarnopolsky M, Parise G. Hepatocyte growth factor (HGF) and the satellite cell response following muscle lengthening contractions in humans. Muscle Nerve . 2008;38(5):1434&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toth KG, McKay BR, De Lisio M, Little JP, Tarnopolsky MA, Parise G. IL-6 induced STAT3 signalling is associated with the proliferation of human muscle satellite cells following acute muscle damage. PLoS One . 2011;6(3):e17392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Nederveen JP, McKay BR, et al. Satellite cells in human skeletal muscle plasticity. Front Physiol . 2015;6:283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asfour HA, Allouh MZ, Said RS. Myogenic regulatory factors: the orchestrators of myogenesis after 30 years of discovery. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) . 2018;243(2):118&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl RD, Olson T, Welling T, Groscost L, Parcell AC. Satellite cell activity is differentially affected by contraction mode in human muscle following a work-matched bout of exercise. Front Physiol . 2014;5:485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crameri RM, Aagaard P, Qvortrup K, Langberg H, Olesen J, Kjaer M. Myofibre damage in human skeletal muscle: effects of electrical stimulation versus voluntary contraction. J Physiol . 2007;583(Pt 1):365&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey AL, Magnan M, Chazaud B, Kjaer M. Human skeletal muscle fibroblasts stimulate in vitro myogenesis and in vivo muscle regeneration. J Physiol . 2017;595(15):5115&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: training considerations. Sports Med . 2018;48(4):765&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagle JP, Taber CB, Cunanan AJ, et al. Accentuated eccentric loading for training and performance: a review. Sports Med . 2017;47(12):2473&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedmann-Bette B, Bauer T, Kinscherf R, et al. Effects of strength training with eccentric overload on muscle adaptation in male athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2010;108(4):821&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedmann-Bette B, Profit F, Gwechenberger T, et al. Strength training effects on muscular regeneration after ACL reconstruction. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2018;50(6):1152&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstr&#xf6;m J. Percutaneous needle biopsy of skeletal muscle in physiological and clinical research. Scand J Clin Lab Invest . 1975;35(7):609&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak NM, Snijders T, McKay BR, et al. Eccentric exercise increases satellite cell content in type II muscle fibers. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2013;45(2):230&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Reeves ND, Narici MV. Skeletal muscle remodeling in response to eccentric vs. concentric loading: morphological, molecular, and metabolic adaptations. Front Physiol . 2017;8:447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukada SI. The roles of muscle stem cells in muscle injury, atrophy and hypertrophy. J Biochem . 2018;163(5):353&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doguet V, Nosaka K, Plautard M, et al. Neuromuscular changes and damage after isoload versus isokinetic eccentric exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2016;48(12):2526&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Kearns AK, Rouzier P, Rubin R, Thompson PD. Serum creatine kinase levels and renal function measures in exertional muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2006;38(4):623&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl RD, Hubal MJ. Lengthening our perspective: morphological, cellular, and molecular responses to eccentric exercise. Muscle Nerve . 2014;49(2):155&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu JG, Malm C, Thornell LE. Eccentric contractions leading to DOMS do not cause loss of desmin nor fibre necrosis in human muscle. Histochem Cell Biol . 2002;118(1):29&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa A, Orosz Z, Apor P, et al. Impact of repeated bouts of eccentric exercise on sarcolemma disruption in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Hung . 2009;96(2):189&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren GL, Lowe DA, Armstrong RB. Measurement tools used in the study of eccentric contraction-induced injury. Sports Med . 1999;27(1):43&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey AL, Rasmussen LK, Kadi F, et al. Activation of satellite cells and the regeneration of human skeletal muscle are expedited by ingestion of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory medication. FASEB J . 2016;30(6):2266&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne C, Eston RG, Edwards RH. Characteristics of isometric and dynamic strength loss following eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2001;11(3):134&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mair J, Koller A, Artner-Dworzak E, et al. Effects of exercise on plasma myosin heavy chain fragments and MRI of skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1992;72(2):656&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, Nederveen JP, Snijders T, McKay BR, Parise G. Skeletal muscle regeneration, repair and remodelling in aging: the importance of muscle stem cells and vascularization. Gerontology . 2017;63(1):91&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishido M, Kami K, Masuhara M. Localization of MyoD, myogenin and cell cycle regulatory factors in hypertrophying rat skeletal muscles. Acta Physiol Scand . 2004;180(3):281&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyatt JP, Roy RR, Baldwin KM, Edgerton VR. Nerve activity-independent regulation of skeletal muscle atrophy: role of MyoD and myogenin in satellite cells and myonuclei. Am J Phys Cell Phys . 2003;285(5):C1161&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, McKay BR, Nederveen JP, et al. Satellite cell activity, without expansion, after nonhypertrophic stimuli. Am J Phys Regul Integr Comp Phys . 2015;309(9):R1101&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grounds MD. The need to more precisely define aspects of skeletal muscle regeneration. Int J Biochem Cell Biol . 2014;56:56&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Rossi AC, Smerdu V, Leinwand LA, Reggiani C. Developmental myosins: expression patterns and functional significance. Skelet Muscle . 2015;5:22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedmann B, Kinscherf R, Vorwald S, et al. Muscular adaptations to computer-guided strength training with eccentric overload. Acta Physiol Scand . 2004;182(1):77&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>English KL, Loehr JA, Lee SM, Smith SM. Early-phase musculoskeletal adaptations to different levels of eccentric resistance after 8 weeks of lower body training. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2014;114(11):2263&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L, Fluckey JD, Pozzo M, Tesch PA. Resistance training using eccentric overload induces early adaptations in skeletal muscle size. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2008;102(3):271&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellamy LM, Joanisse S, Grubb A, et al. The acute satellite cell response and skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance training. PLoS One . 2014;9(10):e109739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C, et al. Early- and later-phases satellite cell responses and myonuclear content with resistance training in young men. PLoS One . 2018;13(1):e0191039.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>