<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39074168</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effect of Creatine Supplementation on Resistance Training-Based Changes to Body Composition: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1813</StartPage><EndPage>1821</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1813-1821</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004862</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Desai, I, Wewege, MA, Jones, MD, Clifford, BK, Pandit, A, Kaakoush, NO, Simar, D, and Hagstrom, AD. The effect of creatine supplementation on resistance training-based changes to body composition: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 38(10): 1813-1821, 2024-The purpose of this review was to determine the added effect of creatine supplementation on changes in body composition with resistance training in adults younger than 50 years. The review protocol was preregistered on the Open Science Framework (osf.io/x48a6/). Our primary outcome was lean body mass (LBM); secondary outcomes were body fat percentage (%) and body fat mass (kg). We performed a random-effects meta-analysis in R using the metafor package. Subgroup analyses were conducted to examine the effects of training status and use of a carbohydrate drink with creatine. We conducted a meta-regression to examine the moderating effect of total training volume. Statistical significance was set at p &lt; 0.05. One thousand six hundred ninety-four records were screened, and 67 full-text articles were assessed for eligibility. Twelve studies were included in the meta-analysis. Fifty-two percentages of the studies had low risk, 41% some concerns, and 7% high risk of bias. Compared with resistance training (RT) alone, creatine supplementation increased LBM by 1.14 kg (95% CI 0.69 to 1.59), and reduced body fat percentage by -0.88% (95% CI -1.66 to -0.11) and body fat mass by -0.73 kg (95% CI -1.34 to -0.11). There were no differences between training status or carbohydrate subgroups. Training volume was not associated with effect size in all outcomes; 7 g or 0.3 g/kg of body mass of creatine per day is likely to increase LBM by 1 kg and reduce fat mass by 0.7 kg more than RT alone. Concurrent carbohydrate ingestion did not enhance the hypertrophy benefits of creatine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Imtiaz</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6972-4440</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wewege</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Pain IMPACT, Neuroscience Research Australia, Sydney, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Matthew D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Pain IMPACT, Neuroscience Research Australia, Sydney, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clifford</LastName><ForeName>Briana K</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandit</LastName><ForeName>Anurag</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaakoush</LastName><ForeName>Nadeem O</ForeName><Initials>NO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simar</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagstrom</LastName><ForeName>Amanda D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>MU72812GK0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003401">Creatine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003401" MajorTopicYN="Y">Creatine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39074168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202410000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andre TL, Gann JJ, McKinley-Barnard SK, Willoughby DS. Effects of five weeks of resistance training and relatively-dosed creatine monohydrate supplementation on body composition and muscle strength, and whole-body creatine metabolism in resistance-trained males. Int J Kinesiol Sports Sci 4: 27&#x2013;35, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Candow DG, Forbes SC, et al. Common questions and misconceptions about creatine supplementation: What does the scientific evidence really show? J Int Soc Sports Nutr 18: 13, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Hannibal NS III, Nindl BC, et al. Comparison of creatine ingestion and resistance training on energy expenditure and limb blood flow. Metabolism 50: 1429&#x2013;1434, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Automeris.ioa. Available at: https://automeris.io/WebPlotDigitizer . Accessed June 18. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito PJ, Cupeiro R, Ramos-Campo DJ, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias J. A systematic review with meta-analysis of the effect of resistance training on whole-body muscle growth in healthy adult males. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 1&#x2013;27, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton MJ, Spicher JM, McCormick S. Community-based survey exploring use of the dietary supplement creatine by adult non-athletes. Nutrients 13: 2529, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borga M, West J, Bell JD, et al. Advanced body composition assessment: From body mass index to body composition profiling. J Investig Med 66: 1&#x2013;9, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branch JD. Effect of creatine supplementation on body composition and performance: A meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 13: 198, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation and resistance-exercise training on muscle insulin-like growth factor in young adults. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 18: 389&#x2013;398, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Chilibeck PD, Parise G, et al. Effect of creatine and weight training on muscle creatine and performance in vegetarians. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 1946&#x2013;1955, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck P, Kaviani M, Candow D, Zello GA. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: A meta-analysis. Open Access J Sports Med 8: 213&#x2013;226, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifford B, Koizumi S, Wewege MA, et al. The effect of resistance training on body composition during and after cancer treatment: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 51: 2527&#x2013;2546, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb PJ, Williams AD, Stathis CG, Carey MF, Hayes A. Effects of whey isolate, creatine, and resistance training on muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc 39: 298&#x2013;307, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delpino FM, Figueiredo LM, Forbes SC, Candow DG, Santos HO. Influence of age, sex, and type of exercise on the efficacy of creatine supplementation on lean body mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Nutrition 103-104: 111791, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devries MC, Phillips SM. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in older adults-a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 1194&#x2013;1203, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson TB, Syrotuik DG. Effects of creatine monohydrate supplementation on body composition and strength indices in experienced resistance trained women. J Strength Cond Res 20: 939&#x2013;946, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Krentz JR, Roberts MD, Young KC. Changes in fat mass following creatine supplementation and resistance training in adults &#x2265;50 years of age: A meta-analysis. J Funct Morphol Kinesio 4: 62, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al.; American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green A, Hultman E, Macdonald I, Sewell DA, Greenhaff P. Carbohydrate ingestion augments skeletal muscle creatine accumulation during creatine supplementation in humans. Am J Phys 271: E821&#x2013;E826, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstrom AD, Marshall PW, Halaki M, Hackett DA. The effect of resistance training in women on dynamic strength and muscular hypertrophy: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med 50: 1075&#x2013;1093, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hangartner TN, Warner S, Braillon P, Jankowski L, Shepherd J. The official positions of the International Society for Clinical Densitometry: Acquisition of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry body composition and considerations regarding analysis and repeatability of measures. J Clin Densitom 16: 520&#x2013;536, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.3. Cochrane, 2022. Available at: www.training.cochrane.org/handbook . Accessed at February 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Kang J, et al. Effect of creatine and beta-alanine supplementation on performance and endocrine responses in strength/power athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 16: 430&#x2013;446, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Information VH. Covidence Systematic Review Software. Melbourne, Australia: Veritas Health Information, https://support.covidence.org/help/how-can-i-cite-covidence. (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Charifi N, Denis C, et al. The behaviour of satellite cells in response to exercise: What have we learned from human studies? Pflugers Arch 451: 319&#x2013;327, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB. Effects of creatine supplementation on performance and training adaptations. Mol Cell Biochem 244: 89&#x2013;94, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: Safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 14: 1&#x2013;18, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Wilborn CD, Taylor L, et al. ISSN exercise and sport nutrition review: Research and recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 15: 38, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie-Shalders K, Kelly JT, So D, Coffey VG, Byrne NM. The effect of exercise interventions on resting metabolic rate: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 38: 1635&#x2013;1649, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SR, Gordon AN, Cabre HE, Hackney AC, Smith-Ryan AE. A randomized controlled trial of changes in fluid distribution across menstrual phases with creatine supplementation. Nutrients 15: 429, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Creatine supplementation elicits greater muscle hypertrophy in upper than lower limbs and trunk in resistance-trained men. Nutr Health 23: 223&#x2013;229, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagaard P, Kadi F, et al. Creatine supplementation augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol 573: 525&#x2013;534, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Rev Esp Cardiol 74: 790&#x2013;799, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Stec MJ, Frederickson SJ, Miles MP. Low-dose creatine supplementation enhances fatigue resistance in the absence of weight gain. Nutrition 27: 451&#x2013;455, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Avelar A, Kassiano W, et al. Creatine supplementation does not influence the ratio between intracellular water and skeletal muscle mass in resistance-trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 11: 405&#x2013;411, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safdar A, Yardley NJ, Snow R, Melov S, Tarnopolsky MA. Global and targeted gene expression and protein content in skeletal muscle of young men following short-term creatine monohydrate supplementation. Physiol Genomics 32: 219&#x2013;228, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saremi A, Gharakhanloo R, Sharghi S, et al. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on serum myostatin and GASP-1. Mol Cell Endocrinol 317: 25&#x2013;30, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger J. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci 37: 1286&#x2013;1295, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Triplett NT: Program design for resistance training. In Haff GG, Triplett NT. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. (4th ed.). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2015. pp. 439&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiel F, Persson C, Furness J, et al. Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry positioning protocols in assessing body composition: A systematic review of the literature. J Sci Med Sport 21: 1038&#x2013;1044, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade SC, Dionne CE, Underwood M, et al. Consensus on exercise reporting template (CERT): Modified delphi study. Phys Ther 96: 1514&#x2013;1524, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith-Ryan AE, Cabre HE, Eckerson JM, Candow DG. Creatine supplementation in women's health: A lifespan perspective. Nutrients 13: 877, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ES, McKay AKA, Kuikman M, et al. Auditing the representation of female versus male athletes in sports science and sports medicine research: Evidence-based performance supplements. Nutrients 14: 953, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M, Schoch R, Cooke M, et al. The effects of creatine ethyl ester supplementation combined with heavy resistance training on body composition, muscle performance, and serum and muscle creatine levels. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 6: 6, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JACSJ, Page MJ, Elbers RG, et al. RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 366: I4898, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor L, Poole C, Pena E, et al. Effects of combined creatine plus fenugreek extract vs. creatine plus carbohydrate supplementation on resistance training adaptations. J Sports Sci Med 10: 254&#x2013;260, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vierck J, O'Reilly B, Hossner K, et al. Satellite cell regulation following myotrauma caused by resistance exercise. Cell Biol Int 24: 263&#x2013;272, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, et al. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 31: 1147&#x2013;1156, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Ratamess NA, Rubin MR, et al. The effects of creatine supplementation on muscular performance and body composition responses to short-term resistance training overreaching. Eur J Appl Physiol 91: 628&#x2013;637, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wewege MA, Desai I, Honey C, et al. The effect of resistance training in healthy adults on body fat percentage, fat mass and visceral fat: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 52: 287&#x2013;300, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 1674&#x2013;1681, 2001.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>