<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32598121</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rest Redistribution Does Not Alter Hormone Responses in Resistance-Trained Women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1867</StartPage><EndPage>1874</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1867-1874</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003617</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Merrigan, JJ, Tufano, JJ, Fields, JB, Oliver, JM, and Jones, MT. Rest redistribution does not alter hormone responses in resistance-trained women. J Strength Cond Res 34(7): 1867-1874, 2020-The purpose was to examine acute effects of rest redistribution (RR) on perceptual, metabolic, and hormonal responses during back squats. Twelve resistance-trained women (training age 5 &#xb1; 2 years; one repetition maximum [1-RM] per body mass, 1.6 &#xb1; 0.2) performed traditional (TS, 4 sets of 10 repetitions with 120 seconds interset rest) and RR sets (4 sets of two 5 repetition clusters with 30-second intraset rest and 90-second interset rest) in counterbalanced order, separated by 72 hours. Both conditions were performed at 70% 1RM with 360 seconds of total rest. Ratings of perceived exertion (RPE) were taken after each set. Blood was sampled at baseline, after each set, and at 5, 15, 30, and 60 minutes, as well as 24 and 48 hours after training. Alpha level was p &#x2264; 0.05. The RPE progressively increased throughout both conditions (p = 0.002) with a greater overall mean for TS (5.81 &#xb1; 0.14) than RR (4.71 &#xb1; 0.14; p = 0.003). Lactate increased above baseline and remained elevated through 15 minutes post in both conditions (4.00 &#xb1; 0.76; p = 0.001), with greater lactate levels for TS (6.33 &#xb1; 0.47) than RR (4.71 &#xb1; 0.53; p &lt; 0.001). Total testosterone was elevated after set 2 (0.125 &#xb1; 0.02; p = 0.011), but no other time point, while free testosterone remained unchanged. Growth hormone continually rose from baseline to set 3 and returned to baseline by 60 minutes post (20.58 &#xb1; 3.19). Cortisol and creatine kinase did not change over time. No condition &#xd7; time interactions existed for any hormone (p &gt; 0.05). Use of rest redistribution resulted in lower perceived effort and lactate responses. Yet, hormone responses during rest redistribution were no different from TS.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merrigan</LastName><ForeName>Justin J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frank Pettrone Center for Sports Performance, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology, George Mason University, Manassas, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tufano</LastName><ForeName>James J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, Charles University, Prague, Czech Republic; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fields</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frank Pettrone Center for Sports Performance, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology, George Mason University, Manassas, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliver</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Army West Point Athletics, United States Military Academy, West Point, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Margaret T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frank Pettrone Center for Sports Performance, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology, George Mason University, Manassas, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>12629-01-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019382">Human Growth Hormone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XMK78S47O</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013739">Testosterone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.3.2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003402">Creatine Kinase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WI4X0X7BPJ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006854">Hydrocortisone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003402" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine Kinase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019382" MajorTopicYN="N">Human Growth Hormone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006854" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrocortisone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="N">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="N">Rest</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013739" MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32598121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202007000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Walker S, Peltonen H, et al. Heterogeneity in resistance training-induced muscle strength and mass responses in men and women of different ages. Age (Dordr) 38: 10, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann G. Growth hormone heterogeneity: Genes, isohormones, variants, and binding proteins. Endocr Rev 12: 424&#x2013;449, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther B, Cronin J, Keogh J. Possible stimuli for strength and power adaptation. Sports Med 35: 967&#x2013;989, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day ML, McGuigan MR, Brice G, Foster C. Monitoring exercise intensity during resistance training using the session RPE scale. J Strength Cond Res 18: 796&#x2013;802, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esbj&#xf6;rnsson-Liljedahl M, Bodin K, Jansson E. Smaller muscle ATP reduction in women than in men by repeated bouts of sprint exercise. J Appl Physiol 93: 1075&#x2013;1083, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girman JC, Jones MT, Matthews TD, Wood RJ. Acute effects of a cluster-set protocol on hormonal, metabolic and performance measures in resistance-trained males. Eur J Sport Sci 14: 151&#x2013;159, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;dez J, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Capelo-Ram&#xed;rez F, et al. Mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual acute responses to different set configurations in full squat. J Strength Cond Res 2017. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Am&#xe9;zqueta I, Calbet JAL, et al. Energy metabolism during repeated sets of leg press exercise leading to failure or not. PLoS One 7: e40621, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 955&#x2013;963, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A. Acute hormonal responses to heavy resistance exercise in men and women at different ages. Int J Sports Med 16: 507&#x2013;513, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Lawrence MM, Utter AC, et al. Effect of inter-repetition rest on ratings of perceived exertion during multiple sets of the power clean. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 3141&#x2013;3147, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Volek JS, Selanne H, Mero AA. Protein ingestion prior to strength exercise affects blood hormones and metabolism. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 1990&#x2013;1997, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK. Sex differences in human fatigability: Mechanisms and insight to physiological responses. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 210: 768&#x2013;789, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hymer WC, Kennett MJ, Maji SK, et al. Bioactive growth hormone in humans: Controversies, complexities and concepts. Growth Horm IGF Res 50: 9&#x2013;22, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Carballeira E, S&#xe1;nchez-Otero T, et al. Acute effects of distribution of rest between repetitions. Int J Sports Med 33: 351&#x2013;358, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ. Endocrine responses to resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 20: S152&#x2013;S157, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Gordon SE, Fleck SJ, et al. Endogenous anabolic hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise in males and females. Int J Sports Med 12: 228&#x2013;235, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Hagerman FC, Fry AC, et al. The effects of short-term resistance training on endocrine function in men and women. Eur J Appl Occup Physiol 78: 69&#x2013;76, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med 35: 339&#x2013;361, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane AR, Duke JW, Hackney AC. Influence of dietary carbohydrate intake on the free testosterone: Cortisol ratio responses to short-term intensive exercise training. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 1125&#x2013;1131, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liening SH, Stanton SJ, Saini EK, Schultheiss OC. Salivary testosterone, cortisol, and progesterone: Two-week stability, interhormone correlations, and effects of time of day, menstrual cycle, and oral contraceptive use on steroid hormone levels. Physiol Behav 99: 8&#x2013;16, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnamo V, Pakarinen A, Komi PV, Kraemer WJ, Kkinen KH. Acute hormonal responses to submaximal and maximal heavy resistance and explosive exercises in men and women. J Strength Cond Res 19: 556&#x2013;571, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu SS, Lau CP, Tung YF, et al. Lactate and the effects of exercise on testosterone secretion: Evidence for the involvement of a cAMP-mediated mechanism. Med Sci Sports Exerc 29: 1048&#x2013;1054, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maresh C, Whittlesey M, Armstrong L, et al. Effect of hydration state on testosterone and cortisol responses to training-intensity exercise in collegiate runners. Int J Sports Med 27: 765&#x2013;770, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo X, Iglesias-Soler E, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Del-Olmo M. Effects of set configuration of resistance exercise on perceived exertion. Percept Mot Skills 119: 825&#x2013;837, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo X, Iglesias-Soler E, Kingsley JD. Perceived exertion is affected by the submaximal set configuration used in resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res 33: 426&#x2013;432, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Fleck SJ, Dickinson A, Kraemer WJ. Acute and chronic hormonal responses to resistance training designed to promote muscle hypertrophy. Can J Appl Physiol 24: 96&#x2013;107, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan J, Gallo S, Fields J, Jones M. Foot-to-foot bioelectrical impedance, air displacement plethysmography, and dual energy x-ray absorptiometry in resistance-trained men and women. Int J Exerc Sci 11: 1145&#x2013;1155, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, Tufano JJ, Oliver JM, et al. Reducing the loss of velocity and power in women athletes via rest redistribution. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 1: 1&#x2013;23, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, White JB, Hu YE, et al. Differences in elbow extensor muscle characteristics between resistance-trained men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 2359&#x2013;2366, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki M, McCarthy JJ, Fedele MJ, Esser KA. Early activation of mTORC1 signalling in response to mechanical overload is independent of phosphoinositide 3-kinase/Akt signalling. J Physiol 589: 1831&#x2013;1846, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morishita S, Yamauchi S, Fujisawa C, Domen K. Rating of perceived exertion for quantification of the intensity of resistance exercise. Int J Phys Med Rehabil 1: 1&#x2013;4, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Jagim AR, Sanchez AC, et al. Greater gains in strength and power with intraset rest intervals in hypertrophic training. J Strength Cond Res 27: 3116&#x2013;3131, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Kreutzer A, Jenke SC, et al. Acute response to cluster sets in trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 2383&#x2013;2393, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyreigne C, Bouix D, Fedou C, Mercier J. Effect of hydration on exercise-induced growth hormone response. Eur J Endocrinol 145: 445&#x2013;450, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podolin DA, Munger PA, Mazzeo RS. Plasma catecholamine and lactate response during graded exercise with varied glycogen conditions. J Appl Physiol 71: 1427&#x2013;1433, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, et al. Effects of heavy resistance exercise volume on post-exercise androgen receptor content in resistance-trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: S238, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res 18: 918&#x2013;920, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin MR, Kraemer WJ, Maresh CM, et al. High-affinity growth hormone binding protein and acute heavy resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 395&#x2013;403, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russ DW, Kent-Braun JA. Sex differences in human skeletal muscle fatigue are eliminated under ischemic conditions. J Appl Physiol 94: 2414&#x2013;2422, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada S, Okita K, Suga T, et al. Low-intensity exercise can increase muscle mass and strength proportionally to enhanced metabolic stress under ischemic conditions. J Appl Physiol 113: 199&#x2013;205, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo W, McGuigan MR, Newton MJ. The effects of circadian rhythmicity of salivary cortisol and testosterone on maximal isometric force, maximal dynamic force, and power output. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1538&#x2013;1545, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, et al. Maintenance of velocity and power with cluster sets during high-volume back squats. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 885&#x2013;892, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, et al. Different cluster sets result in similar metabolic, endocrine, and perceptual responses in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33: 346&#x2013;354, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingren JL, Kraemer WJ, Hatfield DL, et al. Effect of resistance exercise on muscle steroid receptor protein content in strength-trained men and women. Steroids 74: 1033&#x2013;1039, 2009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>