<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33306589</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance Training to Failure vs. Not to Failure: Acute and Delayed Markers of Mechanical, Neuromuscular, and Biochemical Fatigue.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>886</StartPage><EndPage>893</EndPage><MedlinePgn>886-893</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003921</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez, JM, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos, A, Colomer-Poveda, D, Tvarijonaviciute, A, Cer&#xf3;n, J, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes, P, and M&#xe1;rquez, G. Resistance training to failure vs. not to failure: acute and delayed markers of mechanical, neuromuscular, and biochemical fatigue. J Strength Cond Res 35(4): 886-893, 2021-This study aimed to compare acute and delayed markers of mechanical, neuromuscular, and biochemical fatigue between resistance training sessions leading to or not to failure. Twelve resistance-trained men completed 2 sessions that consisted of 6 sets of the full-squat exercise performed against the 10 repetitions maximum load. In a randomized order, in one session the sets were performed to failure and in the other session the sets were not performed to failure (5 repetitions per set). Mechanical fatigue was quantified through the recording of the mean velocity during all repetitions. The neuromuscular function of the knee extensors was assessed through a maximal voluntary contraction and the twitch interpolation technique before training, immediately after each set, and 1, 24, and 48 hours post-training. Serum creatine kinase (CK) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) were measured before training and 1, 24, and 48 hours post-training to infer muscle damage. Alpha was set at a level of 0.05. A higher velocity loss between sets was observed during the failure protocol (-21.7%) compared with the nonfailure protocol (-3.5%). The markers of peripheral fatigue were generally higher and long lasting for the failure protocol. However, the central fatigue assessed by the voluntary activation was comparable for both protocols and remained depressed up to 48 hours post-training. The concentrations of CK and AST were higher after the failure protocol revealing higher muscle damage compared with the nonfailure protocol. These results support the nonfailure protocol to reduce peripheral fatigue and muscle damage, whereas the central fatigue does not seem to be affected by the set configuration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez</LastName><ForeName>Jorge M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Science, European University of Canarias, Tenerife, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Catholic University of Murcia (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Amador</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Sciences and Physical Conditioning, Faculty of Education, Catholic University of the Most Holy Concepcion, Concepci&#xf3;n, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colomer-Poveda</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Catholic University of Murcia (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tvarijonaviciute</LastName><ForeName>Asta</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Medicine and Surgery, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Regional Campus of International Excellence "Campus Mare Nostrum," University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cer&#xf3;n</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Medicine and Surgery, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Regional Campus of International Excellence "Campus Mare Nostrum," University of Murcia, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Studies, Rey Juan Carlos University, Madrid, Spain; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xe1;rquez</LastName><ForeName>Gonzalo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Catholic University of Murcia (UCAM), Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, University of A Coru&#xf1;a, A Coru&#xf1;a, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011187" MajorTopicYN="N">Posture</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202104000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute hormonal and neuromuscular responses and recovery to forced vs. Maximum repetitions multiple resistance exercises. Int J Sports Med 24: 410&#x2013;418, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Eldridge MW, Lovering AT, et al. Arterial oxygenation influences central motor output and exercise performance via effects on peripheral locomotor muscle fatigue in humans. J Physiol 575: 937&#x2013;952, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aughey RJ, Murphy KT, Clark SA, et al. Muscle Na-K-ATPase activity and isoform adaptations to intense interval exercise and training in well-trained athletes. J Appl Physiol 103: 39&#x2013;47, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blain GM, Mangum TS, Sidhu SK, et al. Group III/IV muscle afferents limit the intramuscular metabolic perturbation during whole body exercise in humans. J Physiol 594: 5303&#x2013;5315, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyas S, Gu&#xe9;vel A. Neuromuscular fatigue in healthy muscle: Underlying factors and adaptation mechanisms. Ann Phys Rehabil Med 54: 88&#x2013;108, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Taylor JL, Gandevia SC. Recovery of central and peripheral neuromuscular fatigue after exercise. J Appl Physiol 122: 1068&#x2013;1076, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin ER, Allen DG. The contribution of pH-dependent mechanisms to fatigue at different intensities in mammalian single muscle fibres. J Physiol 512: 831&#x2013;840, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, Lindsell RP, et al. Training leading to repetition failure enhances bench press strength gains in elite junior athletes. J Strength Cond Res 19: 382&#x2013;388, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Irish CS, Roberts JC, Tarr JE, Jones DA. Fatigue is not a necessary stimulus for strength gains during resistance training. Br J Sports Med 36: 370&#x2013;373, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC. Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiol Rev 81: 1725&#x2013;1789, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Ba&#xf1;os-Pelegr&#xed;n E, et al. Mechanical and metabolic responses to traditional and cluster set configurations in the bench press exercise. J Strength Cond Res 34: 663&#x2013;670, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giandolini M, Horvais N, Rossi J, et al. Acute and delayed peripheral and central neuromuscular alterations induced by a short and intense downhill trail run. Scand J Med Sci Sports 26: 1321&#x2013;1333, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Manuel YGJ, Mora-Custodio R, Rodr&#xed;guez-rosell D. Velocity loss as a variable for monitoring resistance exercise. Int J Sports Med 38: 217&#x2013;225, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Sanchez-Medina L, et al. Short-term recovery following resistance exercise leading or not to failure. Int J Sports Med 37: 295&#x2013;304, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Casta&#xf1;o-Zambudio A, et al. Mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual acute responses to different set configurations in full squat. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1581&#x2013;1590, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Am&#xe9;zqueta I, Calbet JaL, et al. Energy metabolism during repeated sets of leg press exercise leading to failure or not. PLoS One 7: 1&#x2013;9, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Am&#xe9;zqueta I, Calbet JaL, et al. Blood ammonia and lactate as markers of muscle metabolites during leg press exercise. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2775&#x2013;2785, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Brandon R, Hunter AM. The response to, and recovery from maximum strength and power training in elite track and field athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 356&#x2013;362, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Iba&#xf1;ez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, et al. Differential effects of strength training leading to failure versus not to failure on hormonal responses, strength, and muscle power gains. J Appl Physiol 100: 1647&#x2013;1656, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, et al. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sport Exerc 34: 364&#x2013;380, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leppik JA, Aughey RJ, Medved I, et al. Prolonged exercise to fatigue in humans impairs skeletal muscle Na+-K+-ATPase activity, sarcoplasmic reticulum Ca2+ release, and Ca2+ uptake. J Appl Physiol 97: 1414&#x2013;1423, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacGregor LJ, Hunter AM. High-threshold motor unit firing reflects force recovery following a bout of damaging eccentric exercise. PLoS One 13: e0195051, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marquez G, Romero-arenas S, Mar C, et al. Peripheral and central fatigue after high intensity. Muscle and Nerve 56: 152&#x2013;159, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran-Navarro R, Perez CE, Mora-Rodriguez R, et al. Time course of recovery following resistance training leading or not to failure. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 2387&#x2013;2399, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Libardi CA. Is resistance training to muscular failure necessary? Front Physiol 7: 10, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Acute and delayed response to resistance exercise leading or not leading to muscle failure. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 37: 630&#x2013;639, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sport 27: 724&#x2013;735, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Castilla A, Piepoli A, Delgado-Garc&#xed;a G, Garrido-Blanca G, Garcia-Ramos A. Reliability and concurrent validity of seven commercially available devices for the assessment of movement velocity at different intensities during the bench press. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1258&#x2013;1265, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasartwuth O, Taylor JL, Gandevia SC. Maximal force, voluntary activation and muscle soreness after eccentric damage to human elbow flexor muscles. J Physiol 567: 337&#x2013;348, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rio-Rodriguez D, Iglesias-Soler E, del Olmo MF. Set configuration in resistance exercise: Muscle fatigue and cardiovascular effects. PLoS One 11: e0151163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson JA, Groeller H. Is repetition failure critical for the development of muscle hypertrophy and strength? Scand J Med Sci Sport 26: 375&#x2013;383, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Ogborn D, Krieger J. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schott J, McCully K, Rutherford OM. The role of metabolites in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 71: 337&#x2013;341, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souron R, Nosaka K, Jubeau M. Changes in central and peripheral neuromuscular fatigue indices after concentric versus eccentric contractions of the knee extensors. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 805&#x2013;816, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: Training considerations. Sports Med 48: 765&#x2013;785, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas K, Brownstein CG, Dent J, et al. Neuromuscular fatigue and recovery after heavy resistance, jump, and sprint training. Med Sci Sport Exerc 50: 2526&#x2013;2535, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd G, Gorman RB, Gandevia SC. Measurement and reproducibility of strength and voluntary activation of lower-limb muscles. Muscle Nerve 29: 834&#x2013;842, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerblad H, Duty S, Allen G. Intracellular calcium concentration during low-frequency fatigue in isolated single fibers of mouse skeletal muscle. Am Physiol Soc 75: 382&#x2013;388, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B-T, Yeung SS, Allen DG, Qin L, Yeung EW. Role of the calcium-calpain pathway in cytoskeletal damage after eccentric contractions. Biol Phys Act Youth J Appl Physiol 105: 352&#x2013;357, 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>