<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">29596867</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2019</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-6808</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neuroendocrinology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neuroendocrinol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The short-term stress response - Mother nature's mechanism for enhancing protection and performance under conditions of threat, challenge, and opportunity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>175</StartPage><EndPage>192</EndPage><MedlinePgn>175-192</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.yfrne.2018.03.004</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0091-3022(18)30029-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Our group has proposed that in contrast to chronic stress that can have harmful effects, the short-term (fight-or-flight) stress response (lasting for minutes to hours) is nature's fundamental survival mechanism that enhances protection and performance under conditions involving threat/challenge/opportunity. Short-term stress enhances innate/primary, adaptive/secondary, vaccine-induced, and anti-tumor immune responses, and post-surgical recovery. Mechanisms and mediators include stress hormones, dendritic cell, neutrophil, macrophage, and lymphocyte trafficking/function and local/systemic chemokine and cytokine production. Short-term stress may also enhance mental/cognitive and physical performance through effects on brain, musculo-skeletal, and cardiovascular function, reappraisal of threat/anxiety, and training-induced stress-optimization. Therefore, short-term stress psychology/physiology could be harnessed to enhance immuno-protection, as well as mental and physical performance. This review aims to provide a conceptual framework and targets for further investigation of mechanisms and conditions under which the protective/adaptive aspects of short-term stress/exercise can be optimized/harnessed, and for developing pharmacological/biobehavioral interventions to enhance health/healing, and mental/cognitive/physical performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2018 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhabhar</LastName><ForeName>Firdaus S</ForeName><Initials>FS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry &amp; Behavioral Sciences, Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center, Miller School of Medicine, University of Miami, Mail Stop M877, 1550 NW 10th Avenue, Miami, FL 33136-1000, United States. Electronic address: dhabhar@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AI048995</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AR046299</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 CA107498</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neuroendocrinol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7513292</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0091-3022</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056704" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive Immunity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007113" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunity, Innate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013315" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Psychological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amateur/elite athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Armed forces/special operations forces</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eustress/distress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infection/autoimmune disease/cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performers/entertainers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psycho-neuro-endocrine-immunology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress reduction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wound healing</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29596867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS957714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5964013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yfrne.2018.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0091-3022(18)30029-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McEwen BS. Protective and Damaging Effects of Stress Mediators. N Engl J Med. 1998;338:171&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9428819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ader R. Psychoneuroimmunology IV. Academic Press; San Diego: 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Enhancing versus suppressive effects of stress on immune function: implications for immunoprotection and immunopathology. NeuroImmunoModulation. 2009;16:300&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19571591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Malarkey WB, Neri E, McEwen BS. Stress-induced redistribution of immune cells - From barracks to boulevards to battlefields: A tale of three hormones. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2012;37:1345&#x2013;1368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22727761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padro CJ, Sanders VM. Neuroendocrine regulation of inflammation. Semin Immunol. 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4116469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24486056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Positive Effects of Stress. TED@Vancouver. 2012  http://talentsearch.ted.com/video/Firdaus-Dhabhar-The-positive-ef OR  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nsc83N-Q1q4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Miller AH, McEwen BS, Spencer RL. Effects of stress on immune cell distribution -- dynamics and hormonal mechanisms. J Immunology. 1995;154:5511&#x2013;5527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7730652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, McEwen BS. Bidirectional Effects Of Stress &amp; Glucocorticoid Hormones On Immune Function: Possible Explanations For Paradoxical Observations. In: Ader R, Felten DL, Cohen N, editors. Psychoneuroimmunology - Third Edition. Academic Press; San Diego: 2001. pp. 301&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, McEwen BS. Acute stress enhances while chronic stress suppresses immune function in vivo: A potential role for leukocyte trafficking. Brain Behavior &amp; Immunity. 1997;11:286&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9512816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Good Stress, Bad Stress, and Health, Invited Lecture at The Center for Compassion and Altruism Research and Education. Stanford University; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Effects of stress on immune function: the good, the bad, and the beautiful. Immunologic research. 2014;58:193&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24798553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein DS, McEwen B. Allostasis, homeostats, and the nature of stress. Stress. 2002;5:55&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12171767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwen BS. The end of stress as we know it. Dana Press; Washington, DC: 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapolsky RM. The influence of social hierarchy on primate health. Science. 2005;308:648&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jezova D, Jurankova E, Mosnarova A, Kriska M, Skultetyova I. Neuroendocrine response during stress with relation to gender differences. Acta Neurobiol Exp (Wars) 1996;56:779&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8917906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jong TR, Menon R, Bludau A, Grund T, Biermeier V, Klampfl SM, Jurek B, Bosch OJ, Hellhammer J, Neumann ID. Salivary oxytocin concentrations in response to running, sexual self-stimulation, breastfeeding and the TSST: The Regensburg Oxytocin Challenge (ROC) study. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2015;62:381&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26385109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steptoe A, Hamer M, Chida Y. The effects of acute psychological stress on circulating inflammatory factors in humans: a review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21:901&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17475444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puterman E, Epel ES, O&#x2019;Donovan A, Prather AA, Aschbacher K, Dhabhar FS. Anger Is Associated with Increased IL-6 Stress Reactivity in Women, But Only Among Those Low in Social Support. Int J Behav Med. 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4406249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24357433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschbacher K, Epel E, Wolkowitz OM, Prather AA, Puterman E, Dhabhar FS. Maintenance of a positive outlook during acute stress protects against pro-inflammatory reactivity and future depressive symptoms. Brain Behav Immun. 2012;26:346&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4030538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22119400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roseboom PH, Nanda SA, Bakshi VP, Trentani A, Newman SM, Kalin NH. Predator threat induces behavioral inhibition, pituitary-adrenal activation and changes in amygdala CRF-binding protein gene expression. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2007;32:44&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1847640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vendruscolo LF, Vendruscolo JC, Terenina-Rigaldie E, Raba F, Ramos A, Takahashi RN, Mormede P. Genetic influences on behavioral and neuroendocrine responses to predator-odor stress in rats. Neurosci Lett. 2006;409:89&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17052845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschbaum C, Pirke KM, Hellhammer DH. The &#x2018;Trier Social Stress Test&#x2019;--a tool for investigating psychobiological stress responses in a laboratory setting. Neuropsychobiology. 1993;28:76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8255414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley P, Kirschbaum C. Human hypothalamus-pituitary-adrenal axis responses to acute psychosocial stress in laboratory settings. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2010;35:91&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20109491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henze GI, Zankert S, Urschler DF, Hiltl TJ, Kudielka BM, Pruessner JC, Wust S. Testing the ecological validity of the Trier Social Stress Test: Association with real-life exam stress. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2017;75:52&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27771565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotwica G, Franczak A, Okrasa S, Koziorowski M, Kurowicka B. Effects of mating stimuli and oxytocin on plasma cortisol concentration in gilts. Reprod Biol. 2002;2:25&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14666160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronesi MC, Tosi U, Villani M, Govoni N, Faustini M, Kindahl H, Madej A, Carluccio A. Oxytocin, vasopressin, prostaglandin F(2alpha), luteinizing hormone, testosterone, estrone sulfate, and cortisol plasma concentrations after sexual stimulation in stallions. Theriogenology. 2010;73:460&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20022362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox CA, Fox B. A comparative study of coital physiology, with special reference to the sexual climax. J Reprod Fertil. 1971;24:319&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4926898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuner B, Glasper ER, Gould E. Sexual experience promotes adult neurogenesis in the hippocampus despite an initial elevation in stress hormones. PLoS One. 2010;5:e11597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2904381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20644737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Miller AH, Stein M, McEwen BS, Spencer RL. Diurnal and stress-induced changes in distribution of peripheral blood leukocyte subpopulations. Brain Behav Immun. 1994;8:66&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8003772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, McEwen BS. Stress-induced enhancement of antigen-specific cell-mediated immunity. J Immunology. 1996;156:2608&#x2013;2615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8786326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selye H. Stress without distress. Nal Penguin Inc; New York: 1974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, McEwen BS. Bidirectional effects of stress on immune function: Possible explanations for salubrious as well as harmful effects. In: Ader R, editor. Psychoneuroimmunology IV. Elsevier Academic Press; San Diego: 2007. pp. 723&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. A Hassle a Day May Keep the Pathogens Away: The Fight-Or-Flight Stress Response and the Augmentation of Immune Function. Integrative and comparative biology. 2009;49:215&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21665815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin M, Patterson T, Smith TL, Caldwell C, Brown SA, Gillin CJ, Grant I. Reduction of immune function in life stress and depression. Biol Psychiatry. 1990;27:22&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2297549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser R, Kiecolt-Glaser JK. Stress-induced immune dysfunction: implications for health. Nat Rev Immunol. 2005;5:243&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15738954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrousos GP, Kino T. Glucocorticoid action networks and complex psychiatric and/or somatic disorders. Stress. 2007;10:213&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17514590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Viswanathan K. Short-Term Stress Experienced At The Time Of Immunization Induces A Long-lasting Increase In Immunological Memory. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2005;289:R738&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15890793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton S, Spiegel D. Circadian disruption in cancer: a neuroendocrine-immune pathway from stress to disease? Brain Behav Immun. 2003;17:321&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12946654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saul AN, Oberyszyn TM, Daugherty C, Kusewitt D, Jones S, Jewell S, Malarkey WB, Lehman A, Lemeshow S, Dhabhar FS. Chronic stress and susceptibility to skin cancer. J Nat Cancer Institute. 2005;97:1760&#x2013;1767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3422720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunnar M, Quevedo K. The neurobiology of stress and development. Annu Rev Psychol. 2007;58:145&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16903808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, McEwen BS, Spencer RL. Stress response, adrenal steroid receptor levels, and corticosteroid-binding globulin levels -- a comparison between Sprague Dawley, Fischer 344, and Lewis rats. Brain Research. 1993;616:89&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8395308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternberg EM, Hill JM, Chrousos GP, Kamilaris T, Listwak SJ, Gold PW, Wilder RL. Inflammatory mediator-induced hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis activation is defective in streptococcal cell wall arthritis-susceptible Lewis rats. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1989;86:2374&#x2013;2378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC286915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2538840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, McEwen BS, Spencer RL. Adaptation to prolonged or repeated stress -- Comparison between rat strains showing intrinsic differences in reactivity to acute stress. Neuroendocrinology. 1997;65:360&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9158068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Miller AH, McEwen BS, Spencer RL. Differential activation of adrenal steroid receptors in neural and immune tissues of Sprague Dawley, Fischer 344, and Lewis rats. J Neuroimmunol. 1995;56:77&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7822484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Serrano M, Tonelli L, Listwak S, Sternberg E, Riley AL. Effects of cross fostering on open-field behavior, acoustic startle, lipopolysaccharide-induced corticosterone release, and body weight in Lewis and Fischer rats. Behav Genet. 2001;31:427&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11777171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab CL, Fan R, Zheng Q, Myers LP, Hebert P, Pruett SB. Modeling and predicting stress-induced immunosuppression in mice using blood parameters. Toxicol Sci. 2005;83:101&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15509669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benschop RJ, Rodriguez-Feuerhahn M, Schedlowski M. Catecholamine-induced leukocytosis: early observations, current research, and future directions. Brain, Behavior, &amp; Immunity. 1996;10:77&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8811932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schleimer RP, Claman HN, Oronsky A, editors. Anti-inflammatory steroid action: Basic and clinical aspects. Academic Press Inc; San Diego: 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopp JM, Miller GE, Myers HF, Fahey JL. Increased natural killer-cell mobilization and cytotoxicity during marital conflict. Brain Behav Immun. 2000;14:10&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10729214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segerstrom SC, Miller GE. Psychological stress and the human immune system: a meta-analytic study of 30 years of inquiry. Psychol Bull. 2004;130:601&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1361287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15250815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivier E, Malissen B. Innate and adaptive immunity: specificities and signaling hierarchies revisited. Nat Immunol. 2005;6:17&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15611777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamo SA. Bidirectional connections between the immune and the nervous system in insects. In: Beckage NE, editor. Insect Immunology. Academic Press; Amsterdam, Boston: 2008. p. 348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baines D, Downer RG. Octopamine enhances phagocytosis in cockroach hemocytes: involvement of inositol trisphosphate. Archives of Insect Biochemistry &amp; Physiology. 1994;26:249&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8068962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gaal LF, Mertens IL, De Block CE. Mechanisms linking obesity with cardiovascular disease. Nature. 2006;444:875&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantzer R, O&#x2019;Connor JC, Freund GG, Johnson RW, Kelley KW. From inflammation to sickness and depression: when the immune system subjugates the brain. Nature Reviews Neuroscience. 2008;9:46&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18073775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes MA. A review on the acute phase response in major depression. Rev Neurosci. 1993;4:407&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7506108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson E. Special regulatory T-cell review: Regulation of immune responses--examining the role of T cells. Immunology. 2008;123:13&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2433272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18154613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccirillo CA. Regulatory T cells in health and disease. Cytokine. 2008;43:395&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18722786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing K, Sakaguchi S. Regulatory T cells exert checks and balances on self tolerance and autoimmunity. Nat Immunol. 2010;11:7&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20016504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bluestone JA, Tang Q. How do CD4+CD25+ regulatory T cells control autoimmunity? Curr Opin Immunol. 2005;17:638&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16209918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finn OJ. Cancer Immunology. N Engl J Med. 2008;358:2704&#x2013;2715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18565863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson BM, McNeel DG. Monitoring regulatory immune responses in tumor immunotherapy clinical trials. Front Oncol. 2013;3:109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3644716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23653893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteside TL. Regulatory T cell subsets in human cancer: are they regulating for or against tumor progression? Cancer Immunol Immunother. 2014;63:67&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3888225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24213679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprent J, Tough DF. Lymphocyte life-span and memory. Science. 1994;265:1395&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8073282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickford GE, Srivastava AK, Slicher AM, Pang PKT. The stress response in the abundance of circulating leukocytes in the Killifish, Fundulus heteroclitus. I The cold-shock sequence and the effects of hypophysectomy. J Exp Zool. 1971;177:89&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5569241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilbo SD, Dhabhar FS, Viswanathan K, Saul A, Yellon SM, Nelson RJ. Short day lengths augment stress-induced leukocyte trafficking and stress-induced enhancement of skin immune function. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2002;99:4067&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC122649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11904451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MM. Changes in leukocyte counts associated with various stressors. J Reticuloendothelial Soc. 1969;8:457&#x2013;465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5388696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viswanathan K, Dhabhar FS. Stress-induced enhancement of leukocyte trafficking into sites of surgery or immune activation. PNAS, USA. 2005;102:5808&#x2013;5813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC556309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Miller AH, McEwen BS, Spencer RL. Stress-induced changes in blood leukocyte distribution -- role of adrenal steroid hormones. J Immunology. 1996;157:1638&#x2013;1644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8759750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinder CS, Mathew JP, Rinder HM, Tracey JB, Davis E, Smith BR. Lymphocyte and monocyte subset changes during cardiopulmonary bypass: effects of aging and gender [see comments] Journal of Laboratory &amp; Clinical Medicine. 1997;129:592&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9178725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toft P, Svendsen P, Tonnesen E, Rasmussen JW, Christensen NJ. Redistribution of lymphocytes after major surgical stress. Acta Anesthesiol Scand. 1993;37:245&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8517098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snow DH, Ricketts SW, Mason DK. Hematological responses to racing and training exercise in Thoroughbred horses, with particular reference to the leukocyte response. Equine Vet J. 1983;15:149&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6873048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrow-Tesch JL, McGlone JJ, Norman RL. Consequences of restraint stress on natural killer cell activity, behavior, and hormone levels in Rhesus Macaques (Macaca mulatta) Psychoneuroendocrinol. 1993;18:383&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8416048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert TB, Cohen S. Stress and immunity in humans: a meta-analytic review. Psychosom Med. 1993;55:364&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8416086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schedlowski M, Jacobs R, Stratman G, Richter S, H&#xe4;dike A, Tewes U, Wagner TOF, Schmidt RE. Changes of natural killer cells during acute psychological stress. J Clin Immunol. 1993;13:119&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8320310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills PJ, Ziegler MG, Rehman J, Maisel AS. Catecholamines, catecholamine receptors, cell adhesion molecules, and acute stressor-related changes in cellular immunity. Adv Pharmacol. 1998;42:587&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9327970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redwine L, Mills PJ, Sada M, Dimsdale J, Patterson T, Grant I. Differential immune cell chemotaxis responses to acute psychological stress in Alzheimer caregivers compared to non-caregiver controls. Psychosom Med. 2004;66:770&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch JA, Berntson GG, Cacioppo JT, Dhabhar FS, Marucha PT. Acute stress evokes selective mobilization of T cells that differ in chemokine receptor expression: A potential pathway linking immunologic reactivity to cardiovascular disease. Brain, Behavior and Immunity. 2003;17:251&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12831827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberger PH, Ickovics JR, Epel E, Nadler E, Jokl P, Fulkerson JP, Tillie JM, Dhabhar FS. Surgery stress induced immune cell redistribution profiles predict short- and long-term postsurgical recovery: A prospective study. Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery. 2009;91:2783&#x2013;2794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2780920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoagland H, Elmadjian F, Pincus G. Stressful psychomotor performance and adrenal cortical function as indicated by the lymphocyte reponse. J Clin Endocrinol. 1946;6:301&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21025123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fauci AS, Dale DC. The effect of in vivo hydrocortisone on subpopulations of human lymphocytes. J Clin Invest. 1974;53:240&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC301459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4808638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fauci AS, Dale DC. The effect of hydrocortisone on the kinetics of normal human lymphocytes. Blood. 1975;46:235&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1139040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson SL, Fox S, Abell KM. Catecholamine modulation of lymphocyte homing to lymphoid tissues. Brain, Behavior, &amp; Immunity. 1997;11:307&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9512817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benschop RJ, Oostveen FG, Heijnen CJ, Ballieux RE. Beta 2-adrenergic stimulation causes detachment of natural killer cells from cultured endothelium. Eur J Immunol. 1993;23:3242&#x2013;3247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8258340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redwine L, Snow S, Mills P, Irwin M. Acute psychological stress: effects on chemotaxis and cellular adhesion molecule expression. Psychosom Med. 2003;65:598&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12883110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills PJ, Meck JV, Waters WW, D&#x2019;Aunno D, Ziegler MG. Peripheral leukocyte subpopulations and catecholamine levels in astronauts as a function of mission duration. Psychosom Med. 2001;63:886&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11719626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, McEwen BS. Enhancing versus suppressive effects of stress hormones on skin immune function. PNAS, USA. 1999;96:1059&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC15350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9927693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Satoskar AR, Bluethmann H, David JR, McEwen BS. Stress-Induced Enhancement of Skin Immune Function: A Role For IFNg. PNAS, USA. 2000;97:2846&#x2013;2851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC16018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10706626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blecha F, Barry RA, Kelley KW. Stress-induced alterations in delayed-type hypersensitivity to SRBC and contact sensitivity to DNFB in mice. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med. 1982;169:239&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7063505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood PG, Karol MH, Kusnecov AW, Rabin BS. Enhancement of antigen-specific humoral and cell-mediated immunity by electric footshock stress in rats. Brain, Behav, Immun. 1993;7:121&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8347894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe CL, Lubach G, Ershler WB. Immunological consequences of maternal separation in infant primates. In: Lewis M, Worobey J, editors. Infant stress and coping. Jossey-Bass Inc; New York, NY: 1989. pp. 64&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2687728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saint-Mezard P, Chavagnac C, Bosset S, Ionescu M, Peyron E, Kaiserlian D, Nicolas JF, Berard F. Psychological stress exerts an adjuvant effect on skin dendritic cell functions in vivo. J Immunol. 2003;171(8):4073&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14530328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viswanathan K, Daugherty C, Dhabhar FS. Stress as an endogenous adjuvant: augmentation of the immunization phase of cell-mediated immunity. International Immunology. 2005;17:1059&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flint MS, Miller DB, Tinkle SS. Restraint-induced modulation of allergic and irritant contact dermatitis in male and female B6.129 mice. Brain Behav Immun. 2000;14:256&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11120595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flint MS, Valosen JM, Johnson EA, Miller DB, Tinkle SS. Restraint stress applied prior to chemical sensitization modulates the development of allergic contact dermatitis differently than restraint prior to challenge. J Neuroimmunol. 2001;113:72&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11137578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilbo SD, Hotchkiss AK, Chiavegatto S, Nelson RJ. Blunted stress responses in delayed type hypersensitivity in mice lacking the neuronal isoform of nitric oxide synthase. J Neuroimmunol. 2003;140:41&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12864970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kripke ML. Ultraviolet radiation and immunology: something new under the sun-- presidential address. Cancer Res. 1994;54:6102&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7954455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granstein RD, Matsui MS. UV radiation-induced immunosuppression and skin cancer. Cutis. 2004;74:4&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15603215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Saul AN, Daugherty C, Holmes TH, Bouley DM, Oberyszyn TM. Short-Term stress enhances cellular immunity and increases early resistance to squamous cell carcinoma. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity. 2010;24:127&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2788066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19765644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amkraut A, Solomon GF. Stress and murine sarcoma virus (Moloney)-induced tumors. Cancer Res. 1972;32:1428&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4337829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH. Exercise for secondary prevention of breast cancer: moving from evidence to changing clinical practice. Cancer prevention research (Philadelphia, Pa) 2011;4:476&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21464028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce JP, Stefanick ML, Flatt SW, Natarajan L, Sternfeld B, Madlensky L, Al-Delaimy WK, Thomson CA, Kealey S, Hajek R, Parker BA, Newman VA, Caan B, Rock CL. Greater survival after breast cancer in physically active women with high vegetable-fruit intake regardless of obesity. J Clin Oncol. 2007;25:2345&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2274898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17557947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speck RM, Courneya KS, Masse LC, Duval S, Schmitz KH. An update of controlled physical activity trials in cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cancer Surviv. 2010;4:87&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20052559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holick CN, Newcomb PA, Trentham-Dietz A, Titus-Ernstoff L, Bersch AJ, Stampfer MJ, Baron JA, Egan KM, Willett WC. Physical activity and survival after diagnosis of invasive breast cancer. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2008;17:379&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18250341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNeely ML, Campbell KL, Rowe BH, Klassen TP, Mackey JR, Courneya KS. Effects of exercise on breast cancer patients and survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. CMAJ. 2006;175:34&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1482759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16818906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betof AS, Dewhirst MW, Jones LW. Effects and potential mechanisms of exercise training on cancer progression: a translational perspective. Brain Behav Immun. 2013;30(Suppl):S75&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22610066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon GF, Merigan TC, Levine S. Variation in adrenal cortical hormones within physiologic ranges, stress and interferon production in mice. Riv Patol Nerv Ment. 1966;87:74&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4294391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nance DM, Sanders VM. Autonomic innervation and regulation of the immune system (1987&#x2013;2007) Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21:736&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1986730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17467231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders VM. The beta2-adrenergic receptor on T and B lymphocytes: do we understand it yet? Brain Behav Immun. 2012;26:195&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3243812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21855626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altemus M, Rao B, Dhabhar FS, Ding W, Granstein R. Stress-induced changes in skin barrier function in healthy women. J Investigative Dermatology. 2001;117:309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11511309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pace TW, Mletzko TC, Alagbe O, Musselman DL, Nemeroff CB, Miller AH, Heim CM. Increased stress-induced inflammatory responses in male patients with major depression and increased early life stress. Am J Psychiatry. 2006;163:1630&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16946190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prather AA, Puterman E, Epel ES, Dhabhar FS. Poor sleep quality potentiates stress-induced cytokine reactivity in postmenopausal women with high visceral abdominal adiposity. Brain, behavior, and immunity. 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3962521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capuron L, Miller AH. Immune system to brain signaling: neuropsychopharmacological implications. Pharmacol Ther. 2011;130:226&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M. Depression is an inflammatory disease,but cell-mediated immune activation is the key component of depression. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2011;35:664&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20599581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AH, Haroon E, Raison CL, Felger JC. Cytokine targets in the brain: impact on neurotransmitters and neurocircuits. Depress Anxiety. 2013;30:297&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreasson A, Arborelius L, Erlanson-Albertsson C, Lekander M. A putative role for cytokines in the impaired appetite in depression. Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21:147&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan N. Brain&#x2019;s firewall: blood-brain barrier actively regulates neuroimmune information flow. Brain Behav Immun. 2006;20:447&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16621441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan N. In-depth conversation: Spectrum and kinetics of neuroimmune afferent pathways. Brain Behav Immun. 2014 No of pages, 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6088807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24566385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besedovsky HO, Rey AD. Physiology of psychoneuroimmunology: a personal view. Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21:34&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17157762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schedlowski M, Engler H, Grigoleit JS. Endotoxin-induced experimental systemic inflammation in humans: a model to disentangle immune-to-brain communication. Brain Behav Immun. 2014;35:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24491305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Burke HM, Epel ES, Mellon SH, Rosser R, Reus VI, Wolkowitz OM. Low serum IL-10 concentrations and loss of regulatory association between IL-6 and IL-10 in adults with major depression. J Psychiatr Res. 2009;43:962&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19552919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pace TW, Hu F, Miller AH. Cytokine-effects on glucocorticoid receptor function: relevance to glucocorticoid resistance and the pathophysiology and treatment of major depression. Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21:9&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1820632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17070667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pace TW, Miller AH. Cytokines and glucocorticoid receptor signaling. Relevance to major depression. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2009;1179:86&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3399249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19906234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantzer R, O&#x2019;Connor JC, Lawson MA, Kelley KW. Inflammation-associated depression: from serotonin to kynurenine. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2011;36:426&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3053088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21041030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley KW, Dantzer R. Alcoholism and inflammation: neuroimmunology of behavioral and mood disorders. Brain Behav Immun. 2011;25(Suppl 1):S13&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4068736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altemus M, Cloitre M, Dhabhar FS. Cellular Immune Response in Adult Women with PTSD Related to Childhood Abuse. American Journal of Psychiatry. 2003;160:1705&#x2013;1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12944352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pace TW, Heim CM. A short review on the psychoneuroimmunology of posttraumatic stress disorder: from risk factors to medical comorbidities. Brain Behav Immun. 2011;25:6&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20934505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieck A, Grassi-Oliveira R, Hartmann do Prado C, Teixeira AL, Bauer ME. Neuroimmunoendocrine interactions in post-traumatic stress disorder: focus on long-term implications of childhood maltreatment. Neuroimmunomodulation. 2014;21:145&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24557048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredericks CA, Drabant EM, Edge MD, Tillie JM, Hallmayer J, Ramel W, Kuo JR, Mackey S, Gross JJ, Dhabhar FS. Healthy young women with serotonin transporter SS polymorphism show a pro-inflammatory bias under resting and stress conditions. Brain Behav Immun. 2009;24:350&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2826575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19883751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiegers GJ, Labeur MS, Stec IE, Klinkert WE, Holsboer F, Reul JM. Glucocorticoids accelerate anti-T cell receptor-induced T cell growth. J Immunol. 1995;155:1893&#x2013;1902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7636240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub RH, Bijlsma JW, Masi A, Cutolo M. Role of neuroendocrine and neuroimmune mechanisms in chronic inflammatory rheumatic diseases--the 10-year update. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2013;43:392&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23731531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub RH. Evolutionary medicine and chronic inflammatory state--known and new concepts in pathophysiology. J Mol Med (Berl) 2012;90:523&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3354326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22271169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub RH. Interaction of the endocrine system with inflammation: a function of energy and volume regulation. Arthritis Res Ther. 2014;16:203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3978663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24524669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juster RP, McEwen BS, Lupien SJ. Allostatic load biomarkers of chronic stress and impact on health and cognition. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2010;35:2&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danese A, McEwen BS. Adverse childhood experiences, allostasis, allostatic load, and age-related disease. Physiol Behav. 2012;106:29&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21888923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon GF. Emotions, stress, the central nervous system, and immunity. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1969;164:335&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5260533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitlic A, Lord JM, Phillips AC. Stress, ageing and their influence on functional, cellular and molecular aspects of the immune system. Age (Dordr) 2014:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4082590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24562499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster Marketon JI, Glaser R. Stress hormones and immune function. Cell Immunol. 2008;252:16&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagundes CP, Glaser R, Kiecolt-Glaser JK. Stressful early life experiences and immune dysregulation across the lifespan. Brain Behav Immun. 2013;27:8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3518756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22771426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders VM, Straub RH. Norepinephrine, The Beta-Adrenergic Receptor, and Immunity. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity. 2002;16:290&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12096881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin MR. Human psychoneuroimmunology: 20 Years of discovery. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity. 2008;22:129&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17911004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>APA. Stress In America, Stress In America. American Psychological Association; Washington, DC: 2007. pp. 1&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A, Vollmer-Conna U, Bennett B, Wakefield D, Hickie I, Lloyd A. The relationship between distress and the development of a primary immune response to a novel antigen. Brain Behav Immun. 2004;18:65&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14651948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sephton SE, Dhabhar FS, Keuroghlian AS, Giese-Davis J, McEwen BS, Ionan AC, Spiegel D. Depression, cortisol, and suppressed cell-mediated immunity in metastatic breast cancer. Brain Behav Immun. 2009;23:1148&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19643176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley KW, Greenfield RE, Evermann JF, Parish SM, Perryman LE. Delayed-type hypersensitivity, contact sensitivity, and PHA skin-test responses of heat- and cold-stressed calves. Am J Vet Res. 1982;43:775&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7091838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards EA, Dean LM. Effects of crowding of mice on humoral antibody formation and protection to lethal antigenic challenge. Psychosom Med. 1977;39:19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">322186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleshner M, Laudenslager ML, Simons L, Maier SF. Reduced serum antibodies associated with social defeat in rats. Physiol &amp; Behav. 1989;45:1183&#x2013;1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2813542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartrop R, Lazarus L, Luckhurst E, Kiloh LG, Penny R. Depressed lymphocyte function after bereavement. The Lancet. 1977;1:834&#x2013;836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">67339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiecolt-Glaser JK, Garner W, Speicher C, Penn GM, Holliday J, Glaser R. Psychosocial modifiers of immunocompetence in medical students. Psychosom Med. 1984;46:7&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6701256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng GJ, Morrow-Tesch JL, Beller DI, Levy EM, Black PH. Immunosuppression in mice induced by cold water stress. Brain, Behavior, &amp; Immunity. 1990;4:278&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2092864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regnier JA, Kelley KW. Heat- and cold-stress suppresses in vivo and in vitro cellular immune response of chickens. Am J Vet Res. 1981;42:294&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7258780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wistar R, Hildemann WH. Effect of stress on skin transplantation immunity in mice. Science. 1960;131:159&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13845426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonneau RH, Sheridan JF, Feng N, Glaser R. Stress-induced effects on cell-mediated innate and adaptive memory components of the murine immune response to herpes simplex virus infection. Brain, Behavior, Immunity. 1991;5:274&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1659472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DH, Zwilling BS. Activation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis differentially affects the anti-mycobacterial activity of macrophages from BCG-resistant and susceptible mice. J Neuroimmunol. 1994;53:181&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8071432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epel E, Blackburn EH, Lin J, Dhabhar FS, Adler NE, Morrow JD, Cawthon RM. Accelerated telomere shortening in response to life stress. PNAS. 2004;101:17312&#x2013;17315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC534658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epel ES, Merkin SS, Cawthon R, Blackburn EH, Adler NE, Pletcher MJ, Seeman TE. The rate of leukocyte telomere shortening predicts mortality from cardiovascular disease in elderly men. Aging (Albany NY) 2009;1:81&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2830080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackburn EH, Epel ES. Telomeres and adversity: Too toxic to ignore. Nature. 2012;490:169&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23060172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Miller GE, Rabin BS. Psychological stress and antibody response to immunization: a critical review of the human literature. Psychosom Med. 2001;63:7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11211068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser R, Rabin B, Chesney M, Cohen S, Natelson B. Stress-induced immunomodulation: implications for infectious diseases? [see comments] JAMA. 1999;281:2268&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10386538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marucha PT, Kiecolt-Glaser JK, Favagehi M. Mucosal wound healing is impaired by examination stress. Psychosomatic Medicine. 1998;60:362&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9625226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercado AM, Padgett DA, Sheridan JF, Marucha PT. Altered kinetics of IL-1 alpha, IL-1 beta, and KGF-1 gene expression in early wounds of restrained mice. Brain Behav Immun. 2002;16:150&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11908924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan JF, Padgett DA, Avitsur R, Marucha PT. Experimental models of stress and wound healing. World J Surg. 2004;28:327&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14961184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christian LM, Graham JE, Padgett DA, Glaser R, Kiecolt-Glaser JK. Stress and wound healing. Neuroimmunomodulation. 2006;13:337&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2792763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17709956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser R, Kiecolt-Glaser JK, Bonneau RH, Malarkey W, Kennedy S, Hughes J. Stress-induced modulation of the immune response to recombinant hepatitis B vaccine. Psychosom Med. 1991;54:22&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1553399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser R, Rice J, Speicher CE, Stout JC, Kiecolt-Glaser JK. Stress depresses interferon production by leukocytes concomitant with a decrease in natural killer cell activity. Behav Neurosci. 1986;100:675&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2430594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiecolt-Glaser JK, Glaser R. Chronic stress and mortality among older adults [editorial; comment] Jama. 1999;282:2259&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10605979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagundes CP, Glaser R, Johnson SL, Andridge RR, Yang EV, Di Gregorio MP, Chen M, Lambert DR, Jewell SD, Bechtel MA, Hearne DW, Herron JB, Kiecolt-Glaser JK. Basal Cell Carcinoma: Stressful Life Events and the Tumor Environment. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2012;69:618&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3890083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22664550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Doyle WJ, Skoner DP, Rabin BS, Gwaltney JM., Jr Social ties and susceptibility to the common cold [see comments] Jama. 1997;277:1940&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9200634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Frank E, Doyle WJ, Skoner DP, Rabin BS, Gwaltney JM., Jr Types of stressors that increase susceptibility to the common cold in healthy adults [see comments] Health Psychology. 1998;17:214&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9619470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Hamrick N, Rodriguez MS, Feldman PJ, Rabin BS, Manuck SB. Reactivity and vulnerability to stress-associated risk for upper respiratory illness. Psychosom Med. 2002;64:302&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11914447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Line S, Manuck SB, Rabin BS, Heise ER, Kaplan JR. Chronic social stress, social status, and susceptibility to upper respiratory infections in nonhuman primates [see comments] Psychosomatic Medicine. 1997;59:213&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9254393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas IG, Padgett DA, Sheridan JF, Marucha PT. Stress-induced susceptibility to bacterial infection during cutaneous wound healing. Brain Behav Immun. 2002;16:74&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozlog LA, Kiecolt-Glaser JK, Marucha PT, Sheridan JF, Glaser R. Stress and immunity: implications for viral disease and wound healing. J Periodontol. 1999;70:786&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10440641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoni MH, Lutgendorf SK, Cole SW, Dhabhar FS, Sephton SE, McDonald PG, Stefanek M, Sood AK. The influence of bio-behavioral factors on tumour biology: pathways and mechanisms. Nature Reviews Cancer. 2006;6:240&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3146042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16498446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chida Y, Hamer M, Wardle J, Steptoe A. Do stress-related psychosocial factors contribute to cancer incidence and survival? Nat Clin Pract Oncol. 2008;5:466&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18493231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sood AK, Lutgendorf SK. Stress influences on anoikis. Cancer prevention research (Philadelphia, Pa) 2011;4:481&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3074235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21464029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Eliyahu S, Yirmiya R, Liebeskind JC, Taylor AN, Gale RP. Stress increases metastatic spread of a mammary tumor in rats: evidence for mediation by the immune system. Brain, Behav, Immun. 1991;5:193&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1654166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaker PH, Han LY, Kamat AA, Arevalo JM, Takahashi R, Lu C, Jennings NB, Armaiz-Pena G, Bankson JA, Ravoori M, Merritt WM, Lin YG, Mangala LS, Kim TJ, Coleman RL, Landen CN, Li Y, Felix E, Sanguino AM, Newman RA, Lloyd M, Gershenson DM, Kundra V, Lopez-Berestein G, Lutgendorf SK, Cole SW, Sood AK. Chronic stress promotes tumor growth and angiogenesis in a mouse model of ovarian carcinoma. Nat Med. 2006;12:939&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levi B, Benish M, Goldfarb Y, Sorski L, Melamed R, Rosenne E, Ben-Eliyahu S. Continuous stress disrupts immunostimulatory effects of IL-12. Brain Behav Immun. 2011;25:727&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21277367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb Y, Sorski L, Benish M, Levi B, Melamed R, Ben-Eliyahu S. Improving postoperative immune status and resistance to cancer metastasis: a combined perioperative approach of immunostimulation and prevention of excessive surgical stress responses. Ann Surg. 2011;253:798&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21475023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS, Saul AN, Holmes TH, Daugherty C, Neri E, Tillie JM, Kusewitt DF, Oberyszyn TM. High anxiety is associated with higher chronic stress burden, lower protective immunity, and increased cancer progression. PLoS ONE. 2012;7 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0033069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0033069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3338811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22558071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine S, Saltzman A. Nonspecific stress prevents relapses of Experimental Allergic Encephalomyelitis in rats. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity. 1987;1:336&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3502584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers MP, Trentham DE, McCune WJ, Ginsberg BI, Rennke HG, Reich P, David JR. Effect of psychological stress on the induction of arthritis in rats. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatism. 1980;23:1337&#x2013;1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7192986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin AC, Warren DL, Wolny AC, Whitacre CC. Suppression of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis by restraint stress. J Neuroimmunology. 1993;44:103&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8496336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanski V, Hemschemeier SK, Schunke K, Hahnel A, Wolff C, Straub RH. Differential effect of severe and moderate social stress on blood immune and endocrine measures and susceptibility to collagen type II arthritis in male rats. Brain Behav Immun. 2013;29:156&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23295263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besedovsky HO, del Rey A. The cytokine-HPA axis feed-back circuit. Z Rheumatol. 2000;59(Suppl 2):II/26&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11155800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Rey A, Besedovsky HO. The cytokine-HPA axis circuit contributes to prevent or moderate autoimmune processes. Z Rheumatol. 2000;59:II/31&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11155801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub RH, Kalden JR. Stress of different types increases the proinflammatory load in rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Res Ther. 2009;11:114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19591636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Rey A, Wolff C, Wildmann J, Randolf A, Straub RH, Besedovsky HO. When immune-neuro-endocrine interactions are disrupted: experimentally induced arthritis as an example. Neuroimmunomodulation. 2010;17:165&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20134193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternberg EM. Neuroendocrine regulation of autoimmune/inflammatory disease. J Endocrinol. 2001;169:429&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11375112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackney AC. Exercise as a stressor to the human neuroendocrine system. Medicina (Kaunas) 2006;42:788&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17090977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK, Hoffman-Goetz L. Exercise and the immune system: regulation, integration, and adaptation. Physiol Rev. 2000;80:1055&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10893431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK. Special feature for the Olympics: effects of exercise on the immune system: exercise and cytokines. Immunol Cell Biol. 2000;78:532&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11050536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Gleeson M, Pyne DB, Nieman DC, Dhabhar FS, Shephard RJ, Oliver SJ, Bermon S, Kajeniene A. Position statement. Part two: Maintaining immune health. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2011;17:64&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21446353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winzer BM, Whiteman DC, Reeves MM, Paratz JD. Physical activity and cancer prevention: a systematic review of clinical trials. Cancer Causes Control. 2011;22:811&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21461921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM. The role of physical activity in breast cancer etiology. Semin Oncol. 2010;37:297&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20709211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM, Neilson HK, Lynch BM. State of the epidemiological evidence on physical activity and cancer prevention. European Journal of Cancer. 2010;46:2593&#x2013;2604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20843488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clague J, Bernstein L. Physical activity and cancer. Curr Oncol Rep. 2012;14:550&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22945451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M. Immune function in sport and exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103:693&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17303714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Whitham M. Exercising in environmental extremes: a greater threat to immune function? Sports Med. 2006;36:941&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17052132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods JA, Vieira VJ, Keylock KT. Exercise, inflammation, and innate immunity. Immunol Allergy Clin North Am. 2009;29:381&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19389588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips AC, Burns VE, Lord JM. Stress and exercise: Getting the balance right for aging immunity. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2007;35:35&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods JA, Lowder TW, Keylock KT. Can exercise training improve immune function in the aged? Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2002;959:117&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11976191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fondell E, Lagerros YT, Sundberg CJ, Lekander M, Balter O, Rothman KJ, Balter K. Physical activity, stress, and self-reported upper respiratory tract infection. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:272&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Psychological stress and immunoprotection versus immunopathology in the skin. Clin Dermatol. 2013;31:18&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Enhancing versus suppressive effects of stress on immune function -- The role of leukocyte trafficking and the kinetic and concentration conditions of exposure to stress hormones (New Investigator Award) Brain, Behavior, Immunity. 2002;16:785&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12480507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards KM, Burns VE, Reynolds T, Carroll D, Drayson M, Ring C. Acute stress exposure prior to influenza vaccination enhances antibody response in women. Brain Behav Immun. 2006;20:159&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16102936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards KM, Burns VE, Adkins AE, Carroll D, Drayson M, Ring C. Meningococcal A vaccination response is enhanced by acute stress in men. Psychosom Med. 2008;70:147&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18256346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards KM, Burns VE, Carroll D, Drayson M, Ring C. The acute stress-induced immunoenhancement hypothesis. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2007;35:150&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17620934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleyn CE, Schneider L, Saraceno R, Mantovani C, Richards HL, Fortune DG, Cumberbatch M, Dearman RJ, Terenghi G, Kimber I, Griffiths CE. The effects of acute social stress on epidermal Langerhans&#x2019; cell frequency and expression of cutaneous neuropeptides. J Invest Dermatol. 2008;128:1273&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17989731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths CE, Dearman RJ, Cumberbatch M, Kimber I. Cytokines and Langerhans cell mobilisation in mouse and man. Cytokine. 2005;32:67&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16153855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chida Y, Hamer M, Steptoe A. A bidirectional relationship between psychosocial factors and atopic disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychosom Med. 2008;70:102&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18158379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arndt J, Smith N, Tausk F. Stress and atopic dermatitis. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2008;8:312&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18606083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black PH, Garbutt LD. Stress, inflammation and cardiovascular disease. J Psychosom Res. 2002;52:1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11801260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkic KL, Landsbergis PA, Schnall PL, Baker D. Is job strain a major source of cardiovascular disease risk? Scand J Work Environ Health. 2004;30:85&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15127782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildebrand HC, Epstein J, Larjava H. The influence of psychological stress on periodontal disease. J West Soc Periodontol Periodontal Abstr. 2000;48:69&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11381953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright RJ, Rodriguez M, Cohen S. Review of psychosocial stress and asthma: an integrated biopsychosocial approach. Thorax. 1998;53:1066&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1745142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10195081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen E, Miller GE. Stress and inflammation in exacerbations of asthma. Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21:993&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17493786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al&#x2019;Abadie MS, Kent GG, Gawkrodger DJ. The relationship between stress and the onset and exacerbation of psoriasis and other skin conditions. Brit J Dermatol. 1994;130:199&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8123572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortune DG, Richards HL, Griffiths CE. Psychologic factors in psoriasis: consequences, mechanisms, and interventions. Dermatol Clin. 2005;23:681&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16112445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub RH, Dhabhar FS, Bijlsma JW, Cutolo M. How psychological stress via hormones and nerve fibers may exacerbate rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2005;52:16&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15641084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artemiadis AK, Anagnostouli MC, Alexopoulos EC. Stress as a Risk Factor for Multiple Sclerosis Onset or Relapse: A Systematic Review. Neuroepidemiology. 2011;36:109&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21335982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards KM, Burns VE, Allen LM, McPhee JS, Bosch JA, Carroll D, Drayson M, Ring C. Eccentric exercise as an adjuvant to influenza vaccination in humans. Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21:209&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16824730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamieson JP, Mendes WB, Blackstock E, Schmader T. Turning the knots in your stomach into bows: Reappraising arousal improves performance on the GRE. J Exp Soc Psychol. 2010;46:208&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20161454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Zein M, Wyart V, Grezes J. Anxiety dissociates the adaptive functions of sensory and motor response enhancements to social threats. Elife. 2015;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4868536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26712157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks AW. Get excited: reappraising pre-performance anxiety as excitement. J Exp Psychol Gen. 2014;143:1144&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24364682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamieson JP, Nock MK, Mendes WB. Mind over matter: reappraising arousal improves cardiovascular and cognitive responses to stress. J Exp Psychol Gen. 2012;141:417&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3410434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21942377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre CK, Roozendaal B. Adrenal Stress Hormones and Enhanced Memory for Emotionally Arousing Experiences. In: Bermudez-Rattoni F, editor. Neural Plasticity and Memory: From Genes to Brain Imaging. Boca Raton (FL): 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21204426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin MF, Pilgrim K, Lupien SJ. Modulatory effects of stress on reactivated emotional memories. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2010;35:1388&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20471179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal SK, Cahill L. Endogenous noradrenergic activation and memory for emotional material in men and women. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2009;34:1263&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19505766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal SK, Cotman CW, Cahill LF. Exercise-induced noradrenergic activation enhances memory consolidation in both normal aging and patients with amnestic mild cognitive impairment. J Alzheimers Dis. 2012;32:1011&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3951984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22914593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal SK, Simon R, McFarlin S, Alkire M, Desai A, Cahill LF. Glucocorticoids interact with noradrenergic activation at encoding to enhance long-term memory for emotional material in women. Neuroscience. 2014;277:267&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25010401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Stegeren AH, Wolf OT, Everaerd W, Scheltens P, Barkhof F, Rombouts SA. Endogenous cortisol level interacts with noradrenergic activation in the human amygdala. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2007;87:57&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16884932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taverniers J, Van Ruysseveldt J, Smeets T, von Grumbkow J. High-intensity stress elicits robust cortisol increases, and impairs working memory and visuo-spatial declarative memory in Special Forces candidates: A field experiment. Stress. 2010;13:323&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20536334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conrad CD, Lupien SJ, McEwen BS. Support for a bimodal role for type II adrenal steroid receptors in spatial memory. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 1999;72:39&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10371714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupien SJ, Wilkinson CW, Briere S, Menard C, Ng Ying Kin NM, Nair NP. The modulatory effects of corticosteroids on cognition: studies in young human populations. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2002;27:401&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11818174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther BT, Thomas AG, Stewart-Williams S, Kilduff LP, Cook CJ. Is salivary cortisol moderating the relationship between salivary testosterone and hand-grip strength in healthy men? Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17:188&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27562719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gullestad L, Hallen J, Medbo JI, Gronnerod O, Holme I, Sejersted OM. The effect of acute vs chronic treatment with beta-adrenoceptor blockade on exercise performance, haemodynamic and metabolic parameters in healthy men and women. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 1996;41:57&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8824694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KM, Kawada T, Ishihara K, Inoue K, Fushiki T. Increase in swimming endurance capacity of mice by capsaicin-induced adrenal catecholamine secretion. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 1997;61:1718&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9362118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Dawans B, Fischbacher U, Kirschbaum C, Fehr E, Heinrichs M. The social dimension of stress reactivity: acute stress increases prosocial behavior in humans. Psychol Sci. 2012;23:651&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22593119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amkraut AA, Solomon CF, Kraemer HC. Stress, early experience and adjuvant-induced arthritis in the rat. Psychosom Med. 1971;33:203&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5104622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackerman KD, Heyman R, Rabin BS, Anderson BP, Houck PR, Frank E, Baum A. Stressful life events precede exacerbations of multiple sclerosis. Psychosom Med. 2002;64:916&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12461197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg A, Chren MM, Sands LP, Matsui MS, Marenus KD, Feingold KR, Elias PM. Psychological stress perturbs epidermal permeability barrier homeostasis: implications for the pathogenesis of stress-associated skin disorders. Arch Dermatol. 2001;137:53&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11176661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Tyrrell DAJ, Smith AP. Psychological stress and susceptibility to the common cold. New Engl J Med. 1991;325:606&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1713648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandi C. Memory Impairments Associated with Stress and Aging. In: Bermudez-Rattoni F, editor. Neural Plasticity and Memory: From Genes to Brain Imaging. Boca Raton (FL): 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21204432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. Harnessing stress on the path to peace. TEDx Hayward. 2013  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u2QFJbE1EBs.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esch T, Stefano GB. Endogenous reward mechanisms and their importance in stress reduction, exercise and the brain. Arch Med Sci. 2010;6:447&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3282525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22371784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corah NL, Bissell GD, Illig SJ. Effect of perceived control on stress reduction in adult dental patients. J Dent Res. 1978;57:74&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">277503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin JA. Stress reduction through mindfulness meditation. Effects on psychological symptomatology, sense of control, and spiritual experiences. Psychother Psychosom. 1997;66:97&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9097338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin JM, Fuhrer R, Stansfeld SA, Marmot M. The importance of low control at work and home on depression and anxiety: do these effects vary by gender and social class? Soc Sci Med. 2002;54:783&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11999493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steptoe A, Kunz-Ebrecht S, Owen N, Feldman PJ, Rumley A, Lowe GD, Marmot M. Influence of socioeconomic status and job control on plasma fibrinogen responses to acute mental stress. Psychosom Med. 2003;65:137&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12554825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosma H, Stansfeld SA, Marmot MG. Job control, personal characteristics, and heart disease. J Occup Health Psychol. 1998;3:402&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9805284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garland EL, Hanley AW, Goldin PR, Gross JJ. Testing the mindfulness-to-meaning theory: Evidence for mindful positive emotion regulation from a reanalysis of longitudinal data. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0187727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5718463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29211754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SA. Mindfulness-based stress reduction: an intervention to enhance the effectiveness of nurses&#x2019; coping with work-related stress. Int J Nurs Knowl. 2014;25:119&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nejati S, Zahiroddin A, Afrookhteh G, Rahmani S, Hoveida S. Effect of Group Mindfulness-Based Stress-Reduction Program and Conscious Yoga on Lifestyle, Coping Strategies, and Systolic and Diastolic Blood Pressures in Patients with Hypertension. J Tehran Heart Cent. 2015;10:140&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4685370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26697087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacioppo JT, Cacioppo S, Capitanio JP, Cole SW. The neuroendocrinology of social isolation. Annu Rev Psychol. 2015;66:733&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5130104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25148851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmawardene M, Givens J, Wachholtz A, Makowski S, Tjia J. A systematic review and meta-analysis of meditative interventions for informal caregivers and health professionals. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2016;6:160&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4583788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25812579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma M, Rush SE. Mindfulness-based stress reduction as a stress management intervention for healthy individuals: a systematic review. J Evid Based Complementary Altern Med. 2014;19:271&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25053754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley KE, Park CL. How does yoga reduce stress? A systematic review of mechanisms of change and guide to future inquiry. Health Psychol Rev. 2015;9:379&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams DR, Sternthal MJ. Spirituality, religion and health: evidence and research directions. Med J Aust. 2007;186:S47&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17516883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandmire DA, Rankin NE, Gorham SR, Eggleston DT, French CA, Lodge EE, Kuns GC, Grimm DR. Psychological and autonomic effects of art making in college-aged students. Anxiety Stress Coping. 2016;29:561&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26222010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin L, Oepen R, Bauer K, Nottensteiner A, Mergheim K, Gruber H, Koch SC. Creative Arts Interventions for Stress Management and Prevention-A Systematic Review. Behav Sci (Basel) 2018;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5836011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornstad S, Patil GG, Raanaas RK. Nature contact and organizational support during office working hours: Benefits relating to stress reduction, subjective health complaints, and sick leave. Work. 2015;53:9&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26684700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>