<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36354748</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Influence of Different Training Load Magnitudes on Sleep Pattern, Perceived Recovery, and Stress Tolerance in Young Soccer Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>351</StartPage><EndPage>357</EndPage><MedlinePgn>351-357</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004235</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ferreira, ABdM, Ribeiro, BLL, Batista, EdS, Dantas, MP, and Mortatti, AL. The influence of different training load magnitudes on sleep pattern, perceived recovery, and stress tolerance in young soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 37(2): 351-357, 2023-The aim of this study was to analyze the influence of 3 weeks on sleep parameters, perceived recovery, and stress tolerance in young soccer players using different training load magnitudes. A total of 13 young male soccer athletes (15.9 &#xb1; 0.5 years; 68.7 &#xb1; 6.1 kg; 170 &#xb1; 7 cm) who performed 3 typical training weeks with different workloads were analyzed. The external training load (ETL) was verified by the PlayerLoad method, and the internal training load (ITL) was determined using the session rating of perceived exertion method. Sleep was monitored using a wrist-actigraphy monitor. Sleep variables, including total time in bed (TTB), total sleep time (TST), sleep latency (SL), wake after sleep onset (WASO), and sleep efficiency (SE), were evaluated across all nights of sleep. The recovery status was assessed with the perceived recovery status (PRS) scale, and the stress tolerance was monitored using the "daily analysis of life demands of athletes" questionnaire. There was an increase in sleep time during the week with the highest training load (week 2) (TTB: +35 minutes, TST: +46 minutes, SL: -5 minutes, SE: +3%). There was no difference in the PRS or in the stress tolerance during the evaluation weeks. A very large within-individual correlation was observed between ITL and ETL ( r = 0.78) and moderate within-individual correlation between ETL and TST ( r = 0.34), between ITL and TST ( r = 0.45), and between ITL and SE ( r = 0.359). These results showed that there was an increase in TST during a microcycle with intensified loads, without impairing bedtime and resulting in maintenance of the perceived recovery or stress tolerance values.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferreira</LastName><ForeName>Ayrton Bruno de Morais</ForeName><Initials>ABM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte-UFRN, Natal, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Bruno Laerte Lopes</ForeName><Initials>BLL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Batista</LastName><ForeName>Elias Dos Santos</ForeName><Initials>EDS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dantas</LastName><ForeName>Matheus Peixoto</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mortatti</LastName><ForeName>Arnaldo Luis</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6743-0070</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074361" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Latency</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094362" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Duration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36354748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202302000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anders T, Carskadon M, Dement W. Sleep and sleepiness in children and adolescents. Pediatr Clin North Am 27: 29&#x2013;43, 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besedovsky L, Lange T, Born J. Sleep and immune function. Eur J Physiol 463: 121&#x2013;137, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand S, Kalak N, Gerber M, et al. High self-perceived exercise exertion before bedtime is associated with greater objectively assessed sleep efficiency. Sleep Med 15: 1031&#x2013;1036, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RE, Basheer R, McKenna JT, Strecker RE, McCarley RW. Control of sleep and wakefulness. Physiol Rev 92: 1087&#x2013;1187, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pitts- burgh sleep quality Index: A new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res 28: 193&#x2013;213, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casamichana D, Castellano J, Calleja-Gonzalez J, San Roma&#xb4;n J, Castagna C. Relationship between indicators of training load in soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 27: 369&#x2013;374, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chennaoui M, Arnal PJ, Sauvet F, Le&#xb4;ger D. Sleep and exercise: A re- ciprocal issue? Sleep Med Rev 15: 59&#x2013;72, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleland I, Kikhia B, Nugent C, et al. Optimal placement of accelerometers for the detection of everyday activities. Sensors 13: 9183&#x2013;9200, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole RJ, Kripke DF, Gruen W, Mullaney DJ, Gillin JC. Automatic sleep/wake identification from wrist activity. Sleep 15: 461&#x2013;469, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa JA, Figueiredo P, Nakamura FY, Rebelo A, Brito J. Monitoring individual sleep and nocturnal heart rate variability indices: The impact of training and match schedule and load in high-level female soccer players. Front Physiol 12: 678462, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes HKM, Medeiros A, et al. Sleep and muscle recovery: Endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothe- sis. Med Hypotheses 77: 220&#x2013;222, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Dixon ZT, Clark MI. Accelerometer-based sleep behavior and activity levels in student athletes in comparison to student non-ath- letes. Sport Sci Health 13: 411&#x2013;418, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dworak M, Wiater A, Alfer D, et al. Increased slow wave sleep and reduced stage 2 sleep in children depending on exercise intensity. Sleep Med 9: 266&#x2013;272, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C. Monitoring training in athletes with reference to overtraining syndrome. Med Sci Sports Exerc 30: 1164&#x2013;1168, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res 15: 109&#x2013;115, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler PM, Paul DJ, Tomazoli G, et al. Evidence of sub-optimal sleep in adolescent Middle Eastern academy soccer players which is exacerbated by sleep intermission proximal to dawn. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 1110&#x2013;1118, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas CG, Aoki MS, Franciscon CA, et al. Psychophysiological responses to overloading and tapering phases in elite young soccer players. Pediatr Exerc Sci 26: 195&#x2013;202, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes RV, Moreira A, Lodo L, et al. Monitoring training loads, stress, immune-endocrine responses and performance in tennis players. Biol Sport 30: 173&#x2013;180, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta L, Morgan K, Gilchrist S. Does elite sport degrade sleep quality? A systematic review. Sports Med 47: 1317&#x2013;1333, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S, Martin DT, Gardner AS, Fallon K, Gulbin J. Persistent fatigue in a female sprint cyclist after a talent-transfer initiative. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 1: 65&#x2013;69, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirshkowitz M, Whiton K, Albert S, et al. National Sleep Foundation's sleep time duration recommendations: Methodology and results sum- mary. Sleep Health 1: 40&#x2013;43, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive sta- tistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3-13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ide K, Schmalbruch IK, Quistorff B, Horn A, Secher NH. Lactate, glucose and O2 uptake in human brain during recovery from maximal exercise. J Physiol 522: 159&#x2013;164, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and external training load: 15 years on training load: Internal and external load theoretical framework: The training process. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 270&#x2013;273, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M. Preventing overtraining in athletes in high-intensity sports and stress/recovery monitoring. Scand J Med Sci Sports 10: 95&#x2013;102, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killer SC, Svendsen IS, Jeukendrup AE, Gleeson M. Evidence of disturbed sleep and mood state in well-trained athletes during short-term intensified training with and without a high carbohydrate nutritional intervention. J Sports Sci 35: 1402&#x2013;1410, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;lling S, Steinacker JM, Endler S, et al. The longer the better: Sleep&#x2013;wake patterns during preparation of the World Rowing Junior Championships. Chronobiol Int 33: 73&#x2013;84, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalor BJ, Halson SL, Tran J, Kemp JG, Cormack SJ. A complex re- lationship: Sleep, external training load, and well-being in elite Australian footballers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 15: 777&#x2013;787, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Vincent GE, Duffield R, et al. Can sleep be used as an indicator of overreaching and overtraining in athletes? Front Physiol 9: 436, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latini S, Pedata F. Adenosine in the central nervous system: Release mecha- nisms and extracellular concentrations. J Neurochem 79: 463&#x2013;484, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent CM, Green JM, Bishop PA, et al. A practical approach to Mon- itoring recovery: Development of a perceived recovery status scale. J Strength Cond Res 25: 620&#x2013;628, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Glaister M, Pizzoferro K, Dawson J, Pedlar C. Sleep duration and quality in elite athletes measured using wristwatch actigraphy. J Sports Sci 30: 541&#x2013;545, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra RK. Sleep, recovery, and performance in sports. Neurol Clin 35: 547&#x2013;557, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino M, Li Y, Rueschman MN, et al. Measuring sleep: Accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity of wrist actigraphy compared to poly- somnography. Sleep 36: 1747&#x2013;1755, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marynowicz J, Kikut K, Lango M, Horna D, Andrzejewski M. Relationship between the Session-RPE and external measures of training load in youth soccer training. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2800&#x2013;2804, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Duclos M, Foster C, et al. Prevention, diagnosis, and treat- ment of the overtraining syndrome: Joint consensus statement of the Eu- ropean College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 186&#x2013;205, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira A, Cavazzoni PB. Monitoring training due Portuguese versions of Wisconsin upper respiratory symptom survey -21 and daily analysis of life demands in athletes. Rev da Educ F&#xb4;&#x131;sica/UEM 9: 109&#x2013;119, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ne&#xb4;de&#xb4;lec M, Halson S, Abaidia AE, Ahmaidi S, Dupont G. Stress, sleep and recovery in elite soccer: A critical review of the literature. Sports Med 45: 1387&#x2013;1400, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Alves A, Haghighi H, et al. Association between training load and well-being measures in young soccer players during a season. Int J Environ Res Public Health 18: 4451, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohayon M, Wickwire E, Hirshkowitz M, et al. National Sleep Founda- tion's sleep quality recommendations: First report. Sleep Health 3, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porkka-Heiskanen T, Alanko L, Kalinchuk A, Stenberg D. Adenosine and sleep. Sleep Med Rev 6: 321&#x2013;332, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robey E, Dawson B, Halson S, et al. Sleep quantity and quality in elite youth soccer players: A pilot study. Eur J Sport Sci 14: 410&#x2013;417, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushall BS. A tool for measuring stress tolerance in elite athletes. J Appl Sport Psychol 2: 51&#x2013;66, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saidi O, Dore&#xb4; E, Maso F, et al. Acute effect of an intensified exercise program on subsequent sleep, dietary intake, and performance in junior rugby players. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 2075&#x2013;2082, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlan AT, Wen N, Tucker PS, Dalbo VJ. The relationships between internal and external training load models during basketball training. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2397&#x2013;2405, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaal K, Le Meur Y, Louis J, et al. Whole-body cryostimulation limits overreaching in elite synchronized swimmers. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 1416&#x2013;1425, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schelling X, Torres L. Accelerometer load profiles for basketball-specific drills in elite players. J Sports Sci Med 15: 585&#x2013;591, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson NS, Gibbs EL, Matheson GO. Optimizing sleep to maximize performance: Implications and recommendations for elite athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 266&#x2013;274, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomsen DK, Yung Mehlsen M, Christensen S, Zachariae R. Rumination&#x2014;relationship with negative mood and sleep quality. Pers Individ Dif 34: 1293&#x2013;1301, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton HR, Delaney JA, Duthie GM, Dascombe BJ. Effects of pre- season training on the sleep characteristics of professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 176&#x2013;182, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Rosen P, Frohm A, Kottorp A, Fride&#xb4;n C, Heijne A. Too little sleep and an unhealthy diet could increase the risk of sustaining a new injury in adolescent elite athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 1364&#x2013;1371, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Gleeson M, Pyne DB, et al. Part two: Maintaining immune health. Exerc Immunol Rev 17: 64&#x2013;103, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson A, Brickson S. Impaired sleep mediates the negative effects of training load on subjective well-being in female youth athletes. Sport Heal A Multidiscip Approach 10: 244&#x2013;249, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitworth-Turner CM, Di Michele R, Muir I, Gregson W, Drust B. Training load and schedule are important determinants of sleep behaviours in youth-soccer players. Eur J Sport Sci 19: 576&#x2013;584, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youngstedt SD. Effects of exercise on sleep. Clin Sports Med 24: 355&#x2013;365, 2005.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>