<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30687419</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>65</Volume><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Maximizing the Functional Performance Outcomes of Patients Undergoing Rehabilitation by Maximizing Their Overall Health and Wellbeing.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>57</StartPage><EndPage>68</EndPage><MedlinePgn>57-68</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2018-0039</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To maximize the performance of an athlete, a team of experts work together to ensure each athlete achieves the maximal benefit from their prescribed exercise conditioning programs. In addition to the exercise specialists, the athlete's team frequently includes psychologists (who address performance anxiety, stress, and depression), counselors (who address smoking cessation, reduction or elimination of alcohol consumption if necessary, weight optimization, and optimal sleep), and nutritionists (who address optimal nutrition and body mass attributes). Such a collaborative approach has become standard practice for athletes aiming to excel in their sports. Despite unequivocal and compelling evidence, this paradigm has only weakly been transferred to the needs of patients participating in rehabilitation programs. These individuals, like the athlete, also need to achieve their highest level of functional performance and recovery for carrying out their activities of daily living, managing the needs of their families, and often returning to work. This article reviews the evidence-based literature and the implications of this multifaceted approach in rehabilitation programs. The augmented benefits to exercise training and conditioning (prescriptive activity/exercise and less sitting) along with their 'effect sizes' are described in the rehabilitation context, in conjunction with smoking cessation, reduced harmful alcohol consumption, optimal nutrition, optimal body mass, manageable stress, and optimal sleep. These factors can be viewed as physical performance enhancers both in individuals participating in rehabilitation whose aim is maximal performance and recovery and in athletes aiming for maximal performance in their sports. Thus, without targeted attention to these lifestyle factors, rehabilitation outcomes cannot be maximized. The evidence presented in this article has implications for health professionals including physical therapists and others who are practicing in rehabilitation settings and those working with individuals in need in the community.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dean</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disability and Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">International Classification of Function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthy lifestyle practices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical performance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30687419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6341960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2018-0039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2018-0039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abate M, Vanni D, Pantalone A, Salini V. Cigarette smoking and musculoskeletal disorders. Musc Lig Tend J. 2013;3(2):63&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3711704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23888288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams RM. Sleep deprivation. Obstet Gynecol Clin North Am. 2015;42(3):493&#x2013;506. doi: 10.1016/j.ogc.2015.05.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ogc.2015.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26333639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A clinical practice guideline for treating tobacco use and dependence: 2008 Update. A US public health service report. Am J Prev Med. 2008;35(2):158&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18617085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahluwalia IB, Mack KA, Murphy W, Mokdad AH, Bales VS. State-specific prevalence of selected chronic disease-related characteristics-Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System. MMWR Surveill Summ. 2001;52(2003)(8):1&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14532868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amor AJ, Serra-Mir M, Mart&#xed;nez-Gonz&#xe1;lez MA, Corella D, Salas-Salvad&#xf3; J, Fit&#xf3; M, Estruch R, Serra-Majem L, Ar&#xf3;s F, Babio N, Ros E, Ortega E; PREDIMED Investigators. Prediction of cardiovascular disease by the Framingham-REGICOR equation in the high-risk PREDIMED Cohort: Impact of the Mediterranean diet across different risk strata. J Am Heart Assoc. 2017;2017;13(6) doi: 10.1161/JAHA.116.004803. (3). pii: e004803. doi.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.116.004803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5524014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashe MC, Miller WC, Eng JJ, Noreau L. Older adults, chronic disease and leisure-time physical activity. Gerontology. 2009;55:64&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3167824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18566534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard CM, Courneya KS, Stein K. American Cancer Society's SCS-II. Cancer survivors' adherence to lifestyle behavior recommendations and associations with health-related quality of life: results from the American Cancer Society's SCS-II. J Clin Oncol. 2008;26(13):2198&#x2013;2204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18445845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buck D, Frosini F.  Clustering of unhealthy behaviours over time: implications for policy and practice. London, UK: The King&#x2019;s Fund; 2012. http://www.kingsfund.org.uk/sites/files/kf/field/field_publication_file/clustering-of-unhealthy-behaviours-over-time-aug-2012.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canada&#x2019;s Low Risk Alcohol Drinking Guidelines. http://www.ccsa.ca/Resource%20Library/2012-Canada-Low-Risk-Alcohol-Drinking-Guidelines-Brochure-en.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celis-Morales CA, Perez-Bravo F, Ibanez L, Salas C, Bailey MES, Gill JMR. Objective vs. self-reported physical activity and sedentary time: effects of measurement method on relationships with risk biomarkers. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(5):e36345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3348936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22590532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coren S. Sleep health and its assessment and management in physical therapy practice: the evidence. Physiother Theory Prac. 2009;25(5-6):442&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19842867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean E. Physical therapy in the 21st century (Part I): Toward practice informed by epidemiology and the crisis of lifestyle conditions. Physiother Theory Pract. 2009a;25:330&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19842862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean E. Physical therapy in the 21st century (Part II): Evidence-based practice within the context of evidence-informed practice. Physiother Theory Pract. 2009b;25:354&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19842863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean E, Gormsen Hansen R. Prescribing optimal nutrition and physical activity as &#x201c;first-line&#x201d; interventions for best practice management of chronic low-grade inflammation associated with osteoarthritis: Evidence synthesis. Arthritis. 2012;31:560634. doi: 10.1155/2012/560634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3546455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23346399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean E, S&#xf6;derlund A. What is the role of lifestyle behaviour change associated with non-communicable disease risk in managing musculoskeletal health conditions with special reference to chronic pain? BMC Musculoskel Disord. 2015;13:16&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1186/s12891-015-0545-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4397667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25888381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewing JA. Detecting alcoholism: The CAGE questionnaire. JAMA. 1984;252:1905&#x2013;1907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6471323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ES, Bergmann MM, Kr&#xf6;ger J, Schienkiewitz A, Weikert C, Boeing H. Healthy living is the best revenge. Arch Int Med. 2009;169:1355&#x2013;1362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19667296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennuso KP, Gangnon RE, Matthews CE, Thraen-Borowski KM, Colbert LH. Sedentary behavior, physical activity, and markers of health in older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(8):1493&#x2013;1500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5764165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23475142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagan KA, Chiuve SE, Stampfer MJ, Katz JN, Grodstein F. Greater adherence to the alternative healthy eating index is associated with lower incidence of physical function impairment in the Nurses' Health Study. J Nutr. 2016;146:1341&#x2013;1347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4926850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27170727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Positive Psychology. Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Harvard Medical School Press; Boston, MA: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Strength and Power Training. Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Harvard Medical School Press; Boston, MA;: 2013a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Improving Sleep. Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Harvard Medical School Press; Boston, MA;: 2013b.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Starting to Exercise. Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Harvard Medical School Press; Boston, MA;: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Healthy Eating. Harvard Medical School Special Health Report. Harvard Medical School Press; Boston, MA;: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henson J, Yates T, Biddle SJ, Edwardson CL, Khunti K, Wilmot EG, Gray LJ, Gorely T, Nimmo MA, Davies MJ. Associations of objectively measured sedentary behaviour and physical activity with markers of cardiometabolic health. Diabetologia. 2013;56(5):1012&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23456209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess AEM, Frohlich TC, Calio V. The heaviest-drinking countries in the world. https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/business/2014/05/17/heaviest-drinking-countries/9146227/ https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/business/2014/05/17/heaviest-drinking-countries/9146227/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein D, Jeejeebhoy K, Tremblay A, Kallio M, Rheaume C, Humphries S, Royall D, Brauer P, Heyland D, Dhaliwal R, Mutch DM. The CHANGE program. Exercise intervention in primary care. Can Fam Phys. 2017;63:546&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5507234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28701449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas JB, Robbins RS. Sleep for Success. Everything You Must Know About Sleep but Are Too Tired to Ask. Authorhouse: Bloomington, IN;; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArdle WD, Katch FI, Katch VL. Exercise Physiology (8th ed) Wolters Kluwer Health; Alphen aan den Rijn, The Netherlands;: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire LC, Strine TW, Okoro CA, Ahluwalia IB, Ford ES. Healthy lifestyle behaviors among older U.S. adults with and without disabilities, Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System, 2003. https://www.cdc.gov/pcd/issues/2007/jan/06_0029.htm Prev Chron Dis. 2007;4(1):A09.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1832137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17173717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice WE. Principles of Athletic Training: A Competency-Based Approach (14th ed) McGraw-Hill; New York, NY: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimmer JH, Vanderbom KA, Bandini LG, Drum CE, Luken K, Suarez-Balcazar Y, Graham ID. GRAIDs: a framework for closing the gap in the availability of health promotion programs and interventions for people with disabilities. Implement Sci. 2014;9(14):100. doi: 10.1186/s13012-014-0100-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-014-0100-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4148531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25123550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiri R, Viikari-Juntura E, Varonen H, Heli&#xf6;vaara M. Prevalence and determinants of lateral and medial epicondylitis: a population study. Am J Epidemiol. 2006;164(11):1065&#x2013;1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16968862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamatakis E, Hamer M, Mishra GD. Early adulthood television viewing and cardiometabolic risk profiles in early middle age: results from a population, prospective cohort study. Diabetologia. 2012;55(2):311&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22057195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strine TW, Okoro CA, Chapman DP, Balluz LS, Ford ES, Ajani UA, Mokdad AH. Health-related quality of life and health risk behaviors among smokers. Am J Prev Med. 2005;28(2):182&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15710274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15a;wi&#x105;tkiewicz G, Wieczorek &#x141; Allamani A. What influences changes in alcoholic beverage consumption over time? Poland in the light of the European Union Amphora study. Subst Use Misuse. 2014;49(12):1601&#x2013;1610. doi: 10.3109/10826084.2014.914376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10826084.2014.914376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai J, Ford ES, Li C, Zhao G, Pearson WS, Balluz LS. Multiple healthy behaviors and optimal self-rated health: findings from the 2007 Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System Survey. Prev Med. 2010;51(3-4):268&#x2013;274. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2010.07.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2010.07.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Health Consequences of Smoking&#x2014;50 Years of Progress: A Report of the Surgeon General. US Department of Health and Human Services, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Office on Smoking and Health. Rockville, MD: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24455788 . </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Surgeon General's Call to Action to Improve the Health and Wellness of Persons with Disabilities. Office of the Surgeon General (US); Office on Disability (US). Rockville (MD): Office of the Surgeon General (US) 2005. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK44667/pdf/Bookshelf_NBK44667.pdf https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK44667/pdf/Bookshelf_NBK44667.pdf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20669510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorp AA, Healy GN, Owen N, Salmon J, Ball K, Shaw JE, Zimmet PZ, Dunstan DW. Deleterious associations of sitting time and television viewing time with cardiometabolic risk biomarkers: Australian Diabetes, Obesity and Lifestyle (AusDiab) study 2004-2005. Diab Care. 2010;33(2):327&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19918003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagnild G. A review of the Resilience Scale. J Nurs Meas. 2009;17(2):105&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19711709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells M, Avers D, Brooks G. Resilience, physical performance measures, and self-perceived physical and mental health in older Catholic nuns. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2012;35(3):126&#x2013;131. doi: 10.1519/JPT.0b013e318237103f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0b013e318237103f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22107953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health. 2001. http://www.sustainable-design.ie/arch/ICIDH-2PFDec-2000.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global Strategy on Diet, Physical Activity, and Health. 2004. http://www.who.int/dietphysicalactivity/strategy/eb11344/strategy_english_web.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global Recommendations on Physical Activity for Health. Geneva: Switzerland; 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26180873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global Status Report on Alcohol and Health. Geneva: Switzerland; 2014. http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/112736/1/9789240692763_eng.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Professions Alliance. Health Improvement Card. 2014. http://www.ifpma.org/fileadmin/content/Publication/2011/ncd_Health-Improvement-Card_web-1.pdf Available from.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>