<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32132474</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30 Suppl 1</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Postconcussion Sleep Duration on Concussion Recovery in Collegiate Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S29</StartPage><EndPage>S35</EndPage><MedlinePgn>S29-S35</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000538</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To determine whether decreased sleep duration postconcussion influences days to asymptomatic and assessment of performance throughout recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">Prospective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING">Institutional Clinical Research Laboratory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS">Four hundred twenty-three collegiate athletes were diagnosed with concussion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS">Multidimensional concussion assessment battery was conducted at baseline, within 24 to 48 hours, daily [2-4 days postinjury (PI); symptoms only], once asymptomatic, and after return-to-play. The battery included the following: 22-item symptom checklist, Standardized Assessment of Concussion (SAC), Balance Error Scoring System (BESS), and computerized neurocognitive test [Immediate Post-Concussion Assessment and Cognitive Testing (ImPACT)].</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES">We subtracted baseline sleep duration from 24 to 48 hours postconcussion sleep duration and categorized athletes into the following groups: shorter sleep (&#x2264;-1 hour), no change (&gt;-1 hour, &lt;+1 hour), and longer sleep (&#x2265;+1 hour). A 1-way analysis of variance (ANOVA) was conducted to compare days to asymptomatic and separate mixed-model ANOVAs to compare total symptom scores, SAC total scores, BESS total error scores, and ImPACT composite scores between sleep categories across time points (&#x3b1; = 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Sleep groups did not differ in days to asymptomatic. The shorter sleep group had greater symptom severity than no sleep change and longer sleep groups at 24 to 48 hours (shorter: 39.1 &#xb1; 20.7; no change: 25.1 &#xb1; 18.4, P = 0.007; longer: 25.7 &#xb1; 21.8, P = 0.004), and at 2 to 4 days PI (shorter: 21.8 &#xb1; 21.8; no change: 10.5 &#xb1; 10.8, P = 0.013; longer: 11.9 &#xb1; 14.2, P = 0.007), but did not differ at other time points (ie, asymptomatic and return-to-play). Participants with shorter sleep exhibited slower ImPACT reaction times at 24 to 48 hours (shorter: 0.68 &#xb1; 0.14; no change: 0.61 &#xb1; 0.09, P = 0.016; and longer: 0.62 &#xb1; 0.12, P = 0.028) and asymptomatic time points (shorter: 0.62 &#xb1; 0.11; no change: 0.56 &#xb1; 0.05; P = 0.015).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Postinjury sleep declines may be associated with symptom severity and worsened reaction time during initial stages of recovery or may be the result of the concussion itself. Clinicians should be aware of alterations in sleep duration and manage appropriately to mitigate initial symptom burden postconcussion.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Nicole L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UGA Concussion Research Laboratory, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weber</LastName><ForeName>Michelle L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UGA Concussion Research Laboratory, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Broglio</LastName><ForeName>Steven P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NeuroTrauma Research Laboratory, University of Michigan Injury Center, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCrea</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurosurgery and Neurology, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McAllister</LastName><ForeName>Thomas W</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmidt</LastName><ForeName>Julianne D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UGA Concussion Research Laboratory, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>CARE Consortium Investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000704" MajorTopicYN="N">Analysis of Variance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001924" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Concussion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015601" MajorTopicYN="N">Injury Severity Score</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D038223" MajorTopicYN="N">Post-Concussion Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011930" MajorTopicYN="N">Reaction Time</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068958" MajorTopicYN="Y">Return to Sport</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057566" MajorTopicYN="N">Self Report</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012893" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Wake Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="N">Students</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014495" MajorTopicYN="N">Universities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32132474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-202003001-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Taylor DJ, McFatter RM. Cognitive performance after sleep deprivation: does personality make a difference? Pers Individ Dif. 2003;34:1179&#x2013;1193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center on Sleep Disorders Research. 2003 National Sleep Disorders Research Plan. Bethesda, MD: U.S. Dept. of Health and Human Services, National Institutes of Health, National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strine TW, Chapman DP. Associations of frequent sleep insufficiency with health-related quality of life and health behaviors. Sleep Med. 2005;6:23&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund HG, Reider BD, Whiting AB, et al. Sleep patterns and predictors of disturbed sleep in a large population of college students. J Adolesc Health. 2010;46:124&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broglio SP, Cantu RC, Gioia GA, et al. National athletic trainers' association position statement: management of sport concussion. J Athl Train. 2014;49:245&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon KG, Drezner JA, Gammons M, et al. American Medical Society for Sports Medicine position statement: concussion in sport. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47:15&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport-the 5th international conference on concussion in sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrier J. The role of sleep and circadian rhythms in health: a snapshot of key research interrogations. Pathol Biol. 2014;62:231&#x2013;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselin N, Lassonde M, Petit D, et al. Sleep following sport-related concussions. Sleep Med. 2009;10:35&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parcell DL, Ponsford JL, Rajaratnam SM, et al. Self-reported changes to nighttime sleep after traumatic brain injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2006;87:278&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sufrinko A, Pearce K, Johnson E, et al. The effect of preinjury sleep difficulties on neurocognitive impairment and symptoms after sport-related concussion. Am J Sport Med. 2015;43:830&#x2013;838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tham SW, Fales J, Palermo TM. Subjective and objective assessment of sleep in adolescents with mild traumatic brain injury. J Neurotrauma. 2015;32:847&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclos C, Dumont M, Wiseman-Hakes C, et al. Sleep and wake disturbances following traumatic brain injury. Pathol Biol. 2014;62:252&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamdar BB, Kaplan KA, Kezirian EJ, et al. The impact of extended sleep on daytime alertness, vigilance, and mood. Sleep Med. 2004;5:441&#x2013;448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Mah KE, Kezirian EJ, et al. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep. 2011;34:943&#x2013;950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broglio S, McCrea M, McAllister T, et al. A national study on the effects of concussion in collegiate athletes and us military service academy members: the NCAA-DoD concussion assessment, research and education (CARE) consortium structure and methods. Sports Med. 2017;47:1437&#x2013;1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuehl MD, Snyder AR, Erickson SE, et al. Impact of prior concussions on health-related quality of life in collegiate athletes. Clin J Sport Med. 2010;20:86&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggs LD. Sleep disturbances and learning disability (mental retardation). In: Morin CM, Espie CA, eds. The Oxford Handbodbook of Sleep and Sleep Disorders. New York, NY: Oxford University Press; 2012:787&#x2013;819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mick E, Biederman J, Jetton J, et al. Sleep disturbances associated with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: the impact of psychiatric comorbidity and pharmacotherapy. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2000;10:223&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnee EH, de Weert-van Oene GH, Wijdeveld TA, et al. Sleep disturbances are associated with reduced health-related quality of life in patients with substance use disorders. Am J Addict. 2015;24:515&#x2013;522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lufi D, Tzischinsky O, Hadar S. Delaying school starting time by one hour: some effects on attention levels in adolescents. J Clin Sleep Med. 2011;7:137&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrea M, Kelly JP, Randolph C, et al. Standardized assessment of concussion (SAC): on-site mental status evaluation of the athlete. J Head Trauma Rehab. 1998;13:27&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guskiewicz KM, Ross SE, Marshall SW. Postural stability and neuropsychological deficits after concussion in collegiate athletes. J Athl Train. 2001;36:263&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemann BL, Guskiewicz KM. Effects of mild head injury on postural stability as measured through clinical balance testing. J Athl Train. 2000;35:19&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schatz P, Pardini JE, Lovell MR, et al. Sensitivity and specificity of the impact test battery for concussion in athletes. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2006;21:91&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell MR, Collins MW, Iverson GL, et al. Recovery from mild concussion in high school athletes. J Neurosurg. 2003;98:296&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL, Brooks BL, Collins MW, et al. Tracking neuropsychological recovery following concussion in sport. Brain Inj. 2006;20:245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrea M, Barr WB, Guskiewicz K, et al. Standard regression-based methods for measuring recovery after sport-related concussion. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2005;11:58&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrea M, Guskiewicz KM, Marshall SW, et al. Acute effects and recovery time following concussion in collegiate football players: the NCAA concussion study. JAMA. 2003;290:2556&#x2013;2563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClure DJ, Zuckerman SL, Kutscher SJ, et al. Baseline neurocognitive testing in sports-related concussions: the importance of a prior night's sleep. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:472&#x2013;478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihalik JP, Lengas E, Register-Mihalik JK, et al. The effects of sleep quality and sleep quantity on concussion baseline assessment. Clin J Sport Med. 2013;23:343&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaffee MW, Winter WC, Jones CC, et al. Sleep disturbances in athletic concussion. Brain Inj. 2015;29:221&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg ND, Berkner PD, Atkins JE, et al. Relationship between short sleep duration and preseason concussion testing. Clin J Sport Med. 2016;26:226&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen-Zion M, Shabi A, Levy S, et al. Effects of partial sleep deprivation on information processing speed in adolescence. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2016;22:388&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL, Lovell MR, Collins MW. Interpreting change on impact following sport concussion. Clin Neuropsychol. 2003;17:460&#x2013;467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belenky G, Wesensten NJ, Thorne DR, et al. Patterns of performance degradation and restoration during sleep restriction and subsequent recovery: a sleep dose-response study. J Sleep Res. 2003;12:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien E, Hart C, Wing RR. Discrepancies between self-reported usual sleep duration and objective measures of total sleep time in treatment-seeking overweight and obese individuals. Behav Sleep Med. 2016;14:539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekleton JA, Parcell DL, Redman JR, et al. Sleep disturbance and melatonin levels following traumatic brain injury. Neurology. 2010;74:1732&#x2013;1738.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>