<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40845228</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does the Method Matter? Examining How Specific Educational Approaches Shape Sleep Education Outcomes in High-Level Adolescent Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1243</StartPage><EndPage>e1248</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e1243-e1248</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005195</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crosbie</LastName><ForeName>Flynn</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Sport, Expertise and Performance (EA 7370), French Institute of Sport (INSEP), Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasquier</LastName><ForeName>Florane</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nedelec</LastName><ForeName>Mathieu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40845228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aloulou A, Duforez F, L&#xe9;ger D, De Larochelambert Q, Nedelec M. The relationships between training load, type of sport, and sleep among high-level adolescent athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 890&#x2013;899, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GA, Veith S, Sampson JA, Whalan M, Fullagar HHK. Influence of training schedules on objective measures of sleep in adolescent academy football players. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2515&#x2013;2521, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep quality index: A new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res 28: 193&#x2013;213, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caia J, Scott TJ, Halson SL, Kelly VG. The influence of sleep hygiene education on sleep in professional rugby league athletes. Sleep Health 4: 364&#x2013;368, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coel RA, Pujalte GGA, Applewhite AI, et al. Sleep and the young athlete. Sports Health 15: 537&#x2013;546, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley SJ, Carskadon MA. Modifications to weekend recovery sleep delay circadian phase in older adolescents. Chronobiol Int 27: 1469&#x2013;1492, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci EL, Ryan RM. Cognitive evaluation theory. Intrinsic Motivation and Self-Determination in Human Behavior. Boston, MA: Springer US, 1985. pp. 43&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewald-Kaufmann JF, Oort FJ, Meijer AM. The effects of sleep extension on sleep and cognitive performance in adolescents with chronic sleep reduction: An experimental study. Sleep Med 14: 510&#x2013;517, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, et al. Sleep and athletic performance: The effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med 45: 161&#x2013;186, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardiner C, Weakley J, Burke LM, et al. The effect of caffeine on subsequent sleep: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev 69: 101764, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagenauer MH, Perryman JI, Lee TM, Carskadon MA. Adolescent changes in the homeostatic and circadian regulation of sleep. Dev Neurosci 31: 276&#x2013;284, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris A, Gundersen H, Andreassen PM, et al. A comparative study of sleep and mood between young elite athletes and age-matched controls. J Phys Act Health 14: 465&#x2013;473, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartley S, Royant-Parola S, Zayoud A, Gremy I, Matulonga B. Do both timing and duration of screen use affect sleep patterns in adolescents? PLoS One 17: e0276226, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirshkowitz M, Whiton K, Albert SM, et al. National Sleep Foundation's updated sleep duration recommendations: Final report. Sleep Health 1: 233&#x2013;243, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne JA, Ostberg O. A self-assessment questionnaire to determine morningness-eveningness in human circadian rhythms. Int J Chronobiol 4: 97&#x2013;110, 1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illingworth G, Sharman R, Harvey C-J, Foster RG, Espie CA. The Teensleep study: The effectiveness of a school-based sleep education programme at improving early adolescent sleep. Sleep Med X 2: 100011, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankowski KS. Social jet lag: Sleep-corrected formula. Chronobiol Int 34: 531&#x2013;535, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns MW. A new method for measuring daytime sleepiness: The Epworth Sleepiness Scale. Sleep 14: 540&#x2013;545, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanady JC, Drummond SPA, Mednick SC. Actigraphic assessment of a polysomnographic-recorded nap: A validation study. J Sleep Res 20: 214&#x2013;222, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: A practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol 4: 863, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo JC, Chee MW. Cognitive effects of multi-night adolescent sleep restriction: Current data and future possibilities. Curr Opin Behav Sci 33: 34&#x2013;41, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo JC, Ong JL, Leong RLF, Gooley JJ, Chee MWL. Cognitive performance, sleepiness, and mood in partially sleep deprived adolescents: The need for sleep study. Sleep 39: 687&#x2013;698, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Mah KE, Kezirian EJ, Dement WC. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep 34: 943&#x2013;950, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantua J, Spencer RMC. Exploring the nap paradox: Are mid-day sleep bouts a friend or foe? Sleep Med 37: 88&#x2013;97, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino M, Li Y, Rueschman MN, et al. Measuring sleep: Accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity of wrist actigraphy compared to polysomnography. Sleep 36: 1747&#x2013;1755, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matos MG, Gaspar T, Tom&#xe9; G, Paiva T. Sleep variability and fatigue in adolescents: Associations with school-related features. Int J Psychol 51: 323&#x2013;331, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski MD, Skaggs DL, Bishop GA, et al. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. J Pediatr Orthop 34: 129&#x2013;133, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minges KE, Redeker NS. Delayed school start times and adolescent sleep: A systematic review of the experimental evidence. Sleep Med Rev 28: 86&#x2013;95, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquier F, Pla R, Bosquet L, et al. The impact of multisession sleep-hygiene strategies on sleep parameters in elite swimmers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 18: 1304&#x2013;1312, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez O, Garza T, Hindera O, et al. Validated assessment tools for screen media use: A systematic review. PLoS One 18: e0283714, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rundo JV, Downey R. Polysomnography. In: Handbook of Clinical Neurology. Levin KH, Chauvel P, eds. Amsterdam, Netherlands: Elsevier, 2019. pp. 381&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A, Dahl RE, Shahar G, Rosenblat-Stein S. Sleep and the transition to adolescence: A longitudinal study. Sleep 32: 1602&#x2013;1609, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Schwerdt S, Roach GD. An individualized intervention increases sleep duration in professional athletes. J Strength Cond Res 35: 3407&#x2013;3413, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short MA, Booth SA, Omar O, Ostlundh L, Arora T. The relationship between sleep duration and mood in adolescents: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev 52: 101311, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiglic N, Viner RM. Effects of screentime on the health and well-being of children and adolescents: A systematic review of reviews. BMJ Open 9: e023191, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suppiah HT, Low CY, Chia M. Effects of sport-specific training intensity on sleep patterns and psychomotor performance in adolescent athletes. Pediatr Exerc Sci 28: 588&#x2013;595, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan E, Healey D, Gray AR, Galland BC. Sleep hygiene intervention for youth aged 10 to 18 years with problematic sleep: A before-after pilot study. BMC Pediatr 12: 189, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van de Water ATM, Holmes A, Hurley DA. Objective measurements of sleep for non-laboratory settings as alternatives to polysomnography&#x2014;A systematic review. J Sleep Res 20: 183&#x2013;200, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale KC, Owens R, Hopkins SR, Malhotra A. Sleep hygiene for optimizing recovery in athletes: Review and recommendations. Int J Sports Med 40: 535&#x2013;543, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheaton AG, Olsen EO, Miller GF, Croft JB. Sleep duration and injury-related risk behaviors among high school students&#x2014;United States, 2007-2013. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 65: 337&#x2013;341, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittmann M, Dinich J, Merrow M, Roenneberg T. Social jetlag: Misalignment of biological and social time. Chronobiol Int 23: 497&#x2013;509, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfson AR, Harkins E, Johnson M, Marco C. Effects of the Young Adolescent Sleep Smart Program on sleep hygiene practices, sleep health efficacy, and behavioral well-being. Sleep Health 1: 197&#x2013;204, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>