<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37077794</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of &#x3b1;-lactalbumin consumption on sleep quality and quantity in female rugby union athletes: a field-based study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>449</StartPage><EndPage>455</EndPage><MedlinePgn>449-455</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2023.116002</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This double-blind randomised placebo-controlled trial aimed to investigate the effects of &#x3b1;-lactalbumin consumption on sleep quality and quantity in female rugby union athletes during a competition season. Eighteen semi-professional female rugby union players (age 23.8 &#xb1; 5.2 y; mean &#xb1; SD) wore wrist actigraphy watches for four seven-day blocks corresponding to the pre-season, a home game, a bye week (i.e. no competition game scheduled) and an away game. Participants consumed either an &#x3b1;-lactalbumin (&#x3b1;-LAC), or placebo drink (PLA) every night two hours before bed for the duration of the season. Generalised linear mixed models were used to investigate the effects of the nutritional intervention on sleep variables (total sleep time, sleep efficiency (SE), sleep onset latency (SOL) and wake after sleep onset) over the duration of the season. There was a significant condition by period interaction effect on SOL (p = 0.01). While similar at baseline (23.3 &#xb1; 16.3 and 23.2 &#xb1; 18.9 min &#x3b1;-LAC and placebo respectively) and for the home game (22.4 &#xb1; 17.6 and 19.3 &#xb1; 14.9 min &#x3b1;-LAC and placebo respectively), SOL was reduced in the &#x3b1;-LAC group for the bye (11.6 &#xb1; 13.4 min) and away game (17.0 &#xb1; 11.5 min; p = 0.045). In comparison, SOL remained unchanged in the PLA group (bye 21.2 &#xb1; 17.3 and away 22.5 &#xb1; 18.5 min). Pre-sleep &#x3b1;-lactalbumin consumption improved SOL in a semi-professional female team-sport cohort. Thus, &#x3b1;-lactalbumin could be utilised by athletes to support sleep during a competitive season.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gratwicke</LastName><ForeName>Madeleine</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miles</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen H</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clark</LastName><ForeName>Brad</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pumpa</LastName><ForeName>Kate L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Team-sport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tryptophan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wrist Actigraphy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.116002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">116002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts A, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: the effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med. 2015; 45(2):161&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25315456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knufinke M, Nieuwenhuys A, Geurts SA, M&#xf8;st EI, Maase K, Moen MH, Coenen AM, Kompier MA. Train hard, sleep well? Perceived training load, sleep quantity and sleep stage distribution in elite level athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2018; 21(4):427&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28754605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, Roach GD, N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Gupta L, Leeder J, Fullagar HH, Coutts AJ, Edwards BJ. Sleep and the athlete: narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med. 2021; 55(7):356&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta L, Morgan K, Gilchrist S. Does elite sport degrade sleep quality? A systematic review. Sports Med. 2017; 47(7):1317&#x2013;1333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5488138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27900583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuomilehto H, Vuorinen V-P, Penttil&#xe4; E, Kivim&#xe4;ki M, Vuorenmaa M, Venoj&#xe4;rvi M, Airaksinen O, Pihlajam&#xe4;ki J. Sleep of professional athletes: underexploited potential to improve health and performance. J Sports Sci. 2017; 35(7):704&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27173843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caia J, Scott TJ, Halson SL, Kelly VG. The influence of sleep hygiene education on sleep in professional rugby league athletes. Sleep Health. 2018; 4(4):364&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30031530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles KH, Clark B, Fowler PM, Miller J, Pumpa KL. Sleep practices implemented by team sport coaches and sports science support staff: A potential avenue to improve athlete sleep? J Sci Med Sport. 2019; 22(7):748&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30685228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonarda G, Fedele E, Vitale E, Lucini D, Mirela V, Mirela IA. Healthy athlete&#x2019;s nutrition. Medicina Sportiva: Journal of Romanian Sports Medicine Society. 2018; 14(1):2967&#x2013;2985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahurkar A. Importance of balance diet &amp; nutrition for athletes performance. Indian J Appl Res. 2019; 9(11).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty R, Madigan S, Warrington G, Ellis J. Sleep and nutrition interactions: implications for athletes. Nutrients. 2019; 11(4):822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30979048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gratwicke M, Miles KH, Pyne DB, Pumpa KL, Clark B. Nutritional Interventions to Improve Sleep in Team-Sport Athletes: A Narrative Review. Nutrients. 2021; 13(5):1586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8150598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34068512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H-H, Tsai P-S, Fang S-C, Liu J-F. Effect of kiwifruit consumption on sleep quality in adults with sleep problems. Asia Pac J Clin Nutr. 2011; 20(2):169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21669584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, McHugh MP, Hill JA, Brouner J, Jewell AP, Van Someren KA, Shave RE, Howatson SA. Influence of tart cherry juice on indices of recovery following marathon running. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010; 20(6):843&#x2013;852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19883392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigeon WR, Carr M, Gorman C, Perlis ML. Effects of a tart cherry juice beverage on the sleep of older adults with insomnia: a pilot study. J Med Food. 2010; 13(3):579&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3133468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20438325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar-Navarro M, Baltazar-Martins G, Brito de Souza D, Mu&#xf1;oz-Guerra J, del Mar Plata M, Del Coso J. Gender differences in prevalence and patterns of dietary supplement use in elite athletes. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2020:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32809924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garthe I, and Ramsbottom R. Elite athletes, a rationale for the use of dietary supplements: a practical approach. PharmaNutrition. 2020:100234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott W, Brett A, Cockburn E, Clifford T. Presleep casein protein ingestion: acceleration of functional recovery in professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018; 14(3):385&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30204517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Abou Sawan S, Mazzulla M, Williamson E, Moore DR. Whey protein supplementation enhances whole body protein metabolism and performance recovery after resistance exercise: A double-blind crossover study. Nutrients. 2017; 9(7):735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28696380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, L&#xf6;nnerdal B, Fernstrom JD. Applications for &#x3b1;-lactalbumin in human nutrition. Nutr Rev. 2018; 76(6):444&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5934683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29617841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roz&#xe9; J-C, Barbarot, S, Butel, M-J, Kapel, N, Waligora-Dupriet, A-J, De Montgolfier, I, Leblanc, M, Godon, N, Soulaines, P, Darmaun, D. An &#x3b1;-lactalbumin-enriched and symbiotic-supplemented v. a standard infant formula: a multicentre, double-blind, randomised trial. Br J Nutr. 2012; 107(11):1616&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22079177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heine W, Radke M, Wutzke K-D. The significance of tryptophan in human nutrition. Amino Acids. 1995; 9(3):91&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24178836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong JN, Hackett DA, Chow C-M. Sleep quality and duration following evening intake of alpha-lactalbumin: a pilot study. Biol Rhythm Res. 2017; 48(4):507&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles K, Clark, B, Fowler, PM, Gratwicke, MJ, Martin, K, Welvaert, M, Miller, J, Pumpa, KL. &#x251;-lactalbumin Improves Sleep and Recovery Post Simulated Evening Competition in Female Athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34649262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld D. Statistical considerations for clinical trials and scientific experiments. 2015. 
[cited 2019 December]; Available from: http://hedwig.mgh.harvard.edu/sample_size/size.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss AR, Johnson NL, Berger NA, Redline S. Validity of activity-based devices to estimate sleep. J Clin Sleep Med. 2010; 6(4):336&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2919663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20726281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. The validity of activity monitors for measuring sleep in elite athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2016; 19(10):848&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26794719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, Dziedzic CE, Wood E, Oikawa SY, Phillips SM. Presleep &#x3b1;-Lactalbumin Consumption Does Not Improve Sleep Quality or Time-Trial Performance in Cyclists. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2020; 30(3):197&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oikawa SY, Macinnis MJ, Tripp TR, McGlory C, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Lactalbumin, Not Collagen, Augments Muscle Protein Synthesis with Aerobic Exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell S, and Driller MW. Sleep-hygiene education improves sleep indices in elite female athletes. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017; 10(4):522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Lastella M, Sharp AP. Individualized sleep education improves subjective and objective sleep indices in elite cricket athletes: A pilot study. J Sports Sci. 2019; 37(17):2021&#x2013;2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31076021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul MA, Gray G, MacLellan M, Pigeau RA. Sleep-inducing pharmaceuticals: a comparison of melatonin, zaleplon, zopiclone, and temazepam. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2004; 75(6):512&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15198277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Atkinson G, Budgett R. Effect of low-dose temazepam on physiological variables and performance tests following a westerly flight across five time zones. Int J Sports Med. 2001; 22(03):166&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11354518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor L, Chrismas BC, Dascombe B, Chamari K, Fowler PM. Sleep medication and athletic performance&#x2014;the evidence for practitioners and future research directions. Front Physiol. 2016; 7:83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4779957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27014084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Halson S, Roach GD. Sleep or swim? Early-morning training severely restricts the amount of sleep obtained by elite swimmers. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014; 14(sup1):S310&#x2013;S315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty R, Madigan SM, Nevill A, Warrington G, Ellis JG. The sleep and recovery practices of athletes. Nutrients. 2021; 13(4):1330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. The impact of training schedules on the sleep and fatigue of elite athletes. Chronobiol Int. 2014; 31(10):1160&#x2013;1168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus CR, Jonkman LM, Lammers JH, Deutz NE, Messer MH, Rigtering N. Evening intake of &#x3b1;-lactalbumin increases plasma tryptophan availability and improves morning alertness and brain measures of attention. Am J Clin Nutr. 2005; 81(5):1026&#x2013;1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus C, Olivier, B, Panhuysen, GEM, Van der Gugten, J, Alles, MS, Tuiten, A, Westenberg, HGM, Fekkes, D, Koppeschaar, HF, de Haan, EEHF. The bovine protein &#x3b1;-lactalbumin increases the plasma ratio of tryptophan to the other large neutral amino acids, and in vulnerable subjects raises brain serotonin activity, reduces cortisol concentration, and improves mood under stress. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000; 71(6):1536&#x2013;1544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10837296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokturk O, and Kanbay A, Tryptophan metabolism and sleep, in Tryptophan Metabolism: Implications for Biological Processes, Health and Disease, Engin A, Engin, Ayse Basak, Editor. 2015, Springer: Switzerland. p. 239&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silber B, and Schmitt J. Effects of tryptophan loading on human cognition, mood, and sleep. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2010; 34(3):387&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19715722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spoormaker VI, and van den Bout J. Depression and anxiety complaints; relations with sleep disturbances. Eur Psychiatry. 2005; 20(3):243&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15935423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>