<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33839107</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-821X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>103</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of physical medicine and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Toward Improving the Prediction of Functional Ambulation After Spinal Cord Injury Through the Inclusion of Limb Accelerations During Sleep and Personal Factors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>676</StartPage><EndPage>687.e6</EndPage><MedlinePgn>676-687.e6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.apmr.2021.02.029</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0003-9993(21)00297-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To determine if functional measures of ambulation can be accurately classified using clinical measures; demographics; personal, psychosocial, and environmental factors; and limb accelerations (LAs) obtained during sleep among individuals with chronic, motor incomplete spinal cord injury (SCI) in an effort to guide future, longitudinal predictions models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">Cross-sectional, 1-5 days of data collection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING">Community-based data collection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS">Adults with chronic (&gt;1 year), motor incomplete SCI (N=27).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES">Ambulatory ability based on the 10-m walk test (10MWT) or 6-minute walk test (6MWT) categorized as nonambulatory, household ambulator (0.01-0.44 m/s, 1-204 m), or community ambulator (&gt;0.44 m/s, &gt;204 m). A random forest model classified ambulatory ability using input features including clinical measures of strength, sensation, and spasticity; demographics; personal, psychosocial, and environmental factors including pain, environmental factors, health, social support, self-efficacy, resilience, and sleep quality; and LAs measured during sleep. Machine learning methods were used explicitly to avoid overfitting and minimize the possibility of biased results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The combination of LA, clinical, and demographic features resulted in the highest classification accuracies for both functional ambulation outcomes (10MWT=70.4%, 6MWT=81.5%). Adding LAs, personal, psychosocial, and environmental factors, or both increased the accuracy of classification compared with the clinical/demographic features alone. Clinical measures of strength and sensation (especially knee flexion strength), LA measures of movement smoothness, and presence of pain and comorbidities were among the most important features selected for the models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The addition of LA and personal, psychosocial, and environmental features increased functional ambulation classification accuracy in a population with incomplete SCI for whom improved prognosis for mobility outcomes is needed. These findings provide support for future longitudinal studies that use LA; personal, psychosocial, and environmental factors; and advanced analyses to improve clinical prediction rules for functional mobility outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 The American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rigot</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehab Neural Engineering Labs, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Human Engineering Research Laboratories, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Healthcare System, Pittsburgh, PA; Department of Bioengineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boninger</LastName><ForeName>Michael L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehab Neural Engineering Labs, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Human Engineering Research Laboratories, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Healthcare System, Pittsburgh, PA; Department of Bioengineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Rehabilitation Science and Technology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Engineering Research Laboratories, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Healthcare System, Pittsburgh, PA; Department of Bioengineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Rehabilitation Science and Technology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McKernan</LastName><ForeName>Gina</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Engineering Research Laboratories, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Healthcare System, Pittsburgh, PA; Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Field-Fote</LastName><ForeName>Edelle C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Crawford Research Institute, Shepherd Center, Atlanta, GA; Division of Physical Therapy, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA; Program in Applied Physiology, School of Biological Sciences, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Jeanne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, WA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hibbs</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Physical Therapy, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Worobey</LastName><ForeName>Lynn A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehab Neural Engineering Labs, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Human Engineering Research Laboratories, Veterans Affairs Pittsburgh Healthcare System, Pittsburgh, PA; Department of Bioengineering, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA; Physical Therapy, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA. Electronic address: law93@pitt.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>F30 HD096828</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 HD096134</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>TL1 TR001858</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985158R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0003-9993</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000054" MajorTopicYN="N">Acceleration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013119" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spinal Cord Injuries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016138" MajorTopicYN="Y">Walking</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Walking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wheelchair</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: None to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1694314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8596977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2021.02.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0003-9993(21)00297-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National Spinal Cord Injury Statistical Center. Annual Statistical Report for the Spinal Cord Injury Model Systems. Birmingham, Alabama; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Spinal Cord Injury Statistical Center. Facts and Figures at a Glance. Birmingham, Alabama: University of Alabama at Birmingham; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ditunno PL, Patrick M, Stineman M, Ditunno JF. Who wants to walk? Preferences for recovery after SCI: a longitudinal and cross-sectional study. Spinal Cord 2008;46(7):500&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18209742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson LA, Eng JJ, Hsieh JT, Wolfe DL. The health and life priorities of individuals with spinal cord injury: a systematic review. J Neurotrauma 2012;29(8):1548&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3501530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22320160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiremath SV, Hogaboom NS, Roscher MR, Worobey LA, Oyster ML, Boninger ML. Longitudinal Prediction of Quality-of-Life Scores and Locomotion in Individuals With Traumatic Spinal Cord Injury. Arch Phys Med Rehab 2017;98(12):2385&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28647550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggins MS, Kankipati P, Oyster ML, Cooper RA, Boninger ML. The relationship between quality of life and change in mobility 1 year postinjury in individuals with spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehab 2011;92(7):1027&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21704781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigot SK, Worobey L, Boninger ML. Gait Training in Acute Spinal Cord Injury Rehabilitation-Utilization and Outcomes Among Nonambulatory Individuals: Findings From the SCIRehab Project. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2018;99(8):1591&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29510092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hylin MJ, Kerr AL, Holden R. Understanding the Mechanisms of Recovery and/or Compensation following Injury. Neural Plast 2017;2017:7125057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5415868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28512585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbeau H, Nadeau S, Garneau C. Physical determinants, emerging concepts, and training approaches in gait of individuals with spinal cord injury. Journal of Neurotrauma 2006;23(3-4):571&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16629638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns AS, Marino RJ, Kalsi-Ryan S, Middleton JW, Tetreault LA, Dettori JR et al. Type and timing of rehabilitation following acute and subacute spinal cord injury: A systematic review. Global spine journal 2017;7(3 Suppl):175S&#x2013;94S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29164023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouad K, Tetzlaff W. Rehabilitative training and plasticity following spinal cord injury. Experimental Neurology 2012;235(1):91&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21333646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boggenpoel B, Madasa V, Jeftha T, Joseph C. Systematic scoping review protocol for clinical prediction rules (CPRs) in the management of patients with spinal cord injuries. BMJ Open 2019;9(1):e025076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30782748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tetreault L, Le D, C&#x229a; t&#xe9; P, Fehlings M. The Practical Application of Clinical Prediction Rules: A Commentary Using Case Examples in Surgical Patients with Degenerative Cervical Myelopathy. Global spine journal 2015;5(6):457&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4671907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26682095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks KE, Zhao Y, Fallah N, Rivers CS, Noonan VK, Plashkes T et al. A simplified clinical prediction rule for prognosticating independent walking after spinal cord injury: a prospective study from a Canadian multicenter spinal cord injury registry. Spine J 2017;17(10):1383&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28716636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Middendorp JJ, Hosman AJ, Donders AR, Pouw MH, Ditunno JF Jr., Curt A et al. A clinical prediction rule for ambulation outcomes after traumatic spinal cord injury: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet 2011;377(9770):1004&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malla R External validation study of a clinical prediction rule for ambulation outcomes after traumatic spinal cord injury [THESIS.MASTER]. Texas Medical Center Dissertations; (via ProQuest); 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Silfhout L, Peters AE, Graco M, Schembri R, Nunn AK, Berlowitz DJ. Validation of the Dutch clinical prediction rule for ambulation outcomes in an inpatient setting following traumatic spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord 2016;54(8):614&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26554272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturt R, Hill B, Holland A, New PW, Bevans C. Correction: Validation of a clinical prediction rule for ambulation outcome after non-traumatic spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord 2020;58(5):631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everhart J, Somers M, Hibbs R, Worobey L. Clinical Utility During Inpatient Rehabilitation of a Clinical Prediction Rule for Ambulation Prognosis Following Spinal Cord Injury. The Journal of Spinal Cord Medicine 2021:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10115000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33705271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel-Haber E, Zeilig G, Haber S, Worobey L, Kirshblum S. The effect of age and injury severity on clinical prediction rules for ambulation among individuals with spinal cord injury. The Spine Journal 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32502654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan P, Budhram B, Zhang Q, Rivers CS, Noonan VK, Plashkes T et al. Highlighting discrepancies in walking prediction accuracy for patients with traumatic spinal cord injury: an evaluation of validated prediction models using a Canadian Multicenter Spinal Cord Injury Registry. The Spine Journal 2019;19(4):703&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30179672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chay W, Kirshblum S. Predicting outcomes after spinal cord injury. Physical medicine and rehabilitation clinics of North America 2020;31(3):331&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32624098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharif S, Jazaib Ali MY. Outcome prediction in spinal cord injury: myth or reality. World neurosurgery 2020;140:574&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belliveau T, Jette AM, Seetharama S, Axt J, Rosenblum D, Larose D et al. Developing Artificial Neural Network Models to Predict Functioning One Year After Traumatic Spinal Cord Injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2016;97(10):1663&#x2013;8 e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27208647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVries Z, Hoda M, Rivers CS, Maher A, Wai E, Moravek D et al. Development of an unsupervised machine learning algorithm for the prognostication of walking ability in spinal cord injury patients. The Spine Journal 2020;20(2):213&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31525468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolliger M, Blight AR, Field-Fote EC, Musselman K, Rossignol S, Barth&#xe9;lemy D et al. Lower extremity outcome measures: considerations for clinical trials in spinal cord injury. Spinal cord 2018;56(7):628&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6131138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29700477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AB, Carnel CT, Ditunno JF, Read MS, Boninger ML, Schmeler MR et al. Outcome measures for gait and ambulation in the spinal cord injury population. J Spinal Cord Med 2008;31(5):487&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2607121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19086706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan O, Badhiwala JH, Wilson JRF, Jiang F, Martin AR, Fehlings MG. Predictive modeling of outcomes after traumatic and nontraumatic spinal cord injury using machine learning: review of current progress and future directions. Neurospine 2019;16(4):678&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31905456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter C, Muller R, Cieza A, Geyh S. Psychological resources in spinal cord injury: a systematic literature review. Spinal Cord 2012;50(3):188&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22124343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldron B, Benson C, O'Connell A, Byrne P, Dooley B, Burke T. Health locus of control and attributions of cause and blame in adjustment to spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord 2010;48(8):598&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20065982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevalier Z, Kennedy P, Sherlock O. Spinal cord injury, coping and psychological adjustment: a literature review. Spinal Cord 2009;47(11):778&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19506568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn SD, Smout RJ, DeJong G, Dijkers MP, Hsieh CH, Lammertse D et al. Association of various comorbidity measures with spinal cord injury rehabilitation outcomes. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2013;94(4 Suppl):S75&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23527775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian W, Hsieh CH, DeJong G, Backus D, Groah S, Ballard PH. Role of body weight in therapy participation and rehabilitation outcomes among individuals with traumatic spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2013;94(4 Suppl):S125&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23527768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grade Dvir Z. 4 in manual muscle testing: the problem with submaximal strength assessment. Clin Rehabil 1997;11(1):36&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9065358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW. Considerations and Practical Options for Measuring Muscle Strength: A Narrative Review. Biomed Res Int 2019;2019:8194537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30792998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hales M, Biros E, Reznik JE. Reliability and Validity of the Sensory Component of the International Standards for Neurological Classification of Spinal Cord Injury (ISNCSCI): A Systematic Review. Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil 2015;21(3):241&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4568087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26363591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholtes VA, Becher JG, Beelen A, Lankhorst GJ. Clinical assessment of spasticity in children with cerebral palsy: a critical review of available instruments. Dev Med Child Neurol 2006;48(1):64&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16359597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas BM, Bergstrom E, Jamous A, Bennie A. The inter rater reliability of the original and of the modified Ashworth scale for the assessment of spasticity in patients with spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord 1996;34(9):560&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8883191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baunsgaard CB, Nissen UV, Christensen KB, Biering-Sorensen F. Modified Ashworth scale and spasm frequency score in spinal cord injury: reliability and correlation. Spinal Cord 2016;54(9):702&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26857270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters RL, Adkins RH, Yakura JS, Sie I. Motor and sensory recovery following incomplete paraplegia. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 1994;75(1):67&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8291966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basso DM, Beattie MS, Bresnahan JC. Graded histological and locomotor outcomes after spinal cord contusion using the NYU weight-drop device versus transection. Exp Neurol 1996;139(2):244&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8654527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onifer SM, Smith GM, Fouad K. Plasticity after spinal cord injury: relevance to recovery and approaches to facilitate it. Neurotherapeutics 2011;8(2):283&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3101826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21384221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura S, Ozasa S, Nomura K, Yoshioka K, Endo F. Estimation of muscle strength from actigraph data in Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Pediatrics International 2014;56(5):748&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24689787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri R, Proserpio P, Rundo F, Lanza A, Sambusida K, Redaelli T et al. Neurophysiological correlates of sleep leg movements in acute spinal cord injury. Clin Neurophysiol 2015;126(2):333&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24947594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, Choi YC, Lee SH, Lee SB. Sleep-related periodic leg movements associated with spinal cord lesions. Movement Disorders 1996;11(6):719&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8914100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proserpio P, Lanza A, Sambusida K, Fratticci L, Frigerio P, Sommariva M et al. Sleep apnea and periodic leg movements in the first year after spinal cord injury. Sleep Medicine 2015;16(1):59&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25454844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall WV, Boggs N, Letton A. Changes in sleep and wake in response to different sleeping surfaces: a pilot study. Applied Ergonomics 2012;43(2):386&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21718964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giganti F, Ficca G, Gori S, Salzarulo P. Body movements during night sleep and their relationship with sleep stages are further modified in very old subjects. Brain Res Bull 2008;75(1):66&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18158097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oleson CV, Marino RJ, Leiby BE, Ditunno JF. Influence of Age Alone, and Age Combined With Pinprick, on Recovery of Walking Function in Motor Complete, Sensory Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2016;97(10):1635&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26898390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirshblum SC, Botticello AL, Dyson-Hudson TA, Byrne R, Marino RJ, Lammertse DP. Patterns of Sacral Sparing Components on Neurologic Recovery in Newly Injured Persons With Traumatic Spinal Cord Injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2016;97(10):1647&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26971670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ditunno JF Jr., Barbeau H, Dobkin BH, Elashoff R, Harkema S, Marino RJ et al. Validity of the walking scale for spinal cord injury and other domains of function in a multicenter clinical trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 2007;21(6):539&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4080923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW, Smith MB. Interrater reliability of a modified Ashworth scale of muscle spasticity. Phys Ther 1987;67(2):206&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3809245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirshblum S, Waring W 3rd. Updates for the International Standards for Neurological Classification of Spinal Cord Injury. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am 2014;25(3):505&#x2013;17, vii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25064785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Center for Health Statistics. NCHS Urban-Rural Classification Scheme for Counties. In: Services USDoHaH, editor. https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/data_access/urban_rural.htm; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Center for Health Statistics, Office of Analysis and Epidemiology. 2013 NCHS Urban&#x2013;Rural Classification Scheme for Counties. Hyattsville, MD: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botticello AL, Chen Y, Cao Y, Tulsky DS. Do communities matter after rehabilitation? The effect of socioeconomic and urban stratification on well-being after spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2011;92(3):464&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3668343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21353828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myaskovsky L, Gao S, Hausmann LRM, Bornemann KR, Burkitt KH, Switzer GE et al. How Are Race, Cultural, and Psychosocial Factors Associated With Outcomes in Veterans With Spinal Cord Injury? Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2017;98(9):1812&#x2013;20 e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6159211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleeland CS, Ryan K. The brief pain inventory. Pain Research Group; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widerstrom-Noga E, Biering-Sorensen F, Bryce T, Cardenas DD, Finnerup NB, Jensen MP et al. The international spinal cord injury pain basic data set. Spinal Cord 2008;46(12):818&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18521092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig Hospital. Craig Hospital Inventory of Environmental Factors, Version 3.0. Craig Hospital Research Department; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE Jr., Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36). I. Conceptual framework and item selection. Med Care 1992;30(6):473&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1593914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherbourne CD, Stewart AL. The MOS social support survey. Soc Sci Med 1991;32(6):705&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2035047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton JW, Tran Y, Lo C, Craig A. Reexamining the Validity and Dimensionality of the Moorong Self-Efficacy Scale: Improving Its Clinical Utility. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2016;97(12):2130&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27422349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollayeva T, Thurairajah P, Burton K, Mollayeva S, Shapiro CM, Colantonio A. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index as a screening tool for sleep dysfunction in clinical and non-clinical samples: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev 2016;25:52&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26163057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaVela SL, Burns SP, Goldstein B, Miskevics S, Smith B, Weaver FM. Dysfunctional sleep in persons with spinal cord injuries and disorders. Spinal Cord 2012;50(9):682&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22508535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenborn CA, Adams PF. Sleep Duration as a Correlate of Smoking, Alcohol Use, Leisure-Time Physical Inactivity, and Obesity Among Adults: United States, 2004-2006. NCHS Health &amp; Stats; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammell KW, Miller WC, Forwell SJ, Forman BE, Jacobsen BA. Fatigue and spinal cord injury: a qualitative analysis. Spinal Cord 2009;47(1):44&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18542089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn SH, Park HW, Lee BS, Moon HW, Jang SH, Sakong J et al. Gabapentin effect on neuropathic pain compared among patients with spinal cord injury and different durations of symptoms. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2003;28(4):341&#x2013;6; discussion 6-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12590206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usui A, Ishizuka Y, Obinata I, Okado T, Fukuzawa H, Kanba S. Validity of sleep log compared with actigraphic sleep-wake state II. Psychiatry and clinical neurosciences 1999;53(2):183&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10459683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victorson D, Tulsky DS, Kisala PA, Kalpakjian CZ, Weiland B, Choi SW. Measuring resilience after spinal cord injury: Development, validation and psychometric characteristics of the SCI-QOL Resilience item bank and short form. J Spinal Cord Med 2015;38(3):366&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4445027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton J, Tran Y, Craig A. Relationship between quality of life and self-efficacy in persons with spinal cord injuries. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2007;88(12):1643&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18047880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteneck G, Meade MA, Dijkers M, Tate DG, Bushnik T, Forchheimer MB. Environmental factors and their role in participation and life satisfaction after spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2004;85(11):1793&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15520974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteneck GG, Harrison-Felix CL, Mellick DC, Brooks CA, Charlifue SB, Gerhart KA. Quantifying environmental factors: a measure of physical, attitudinal, service, productivity, and policy barriers. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2004;85(8):1324&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15295760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post MWM, van Leeuwen CMC. Psychosocial issues in spinal cord injury: a review. Spinal Cord 2012;50(5):382&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22270190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy P, Lude P, Elfstr&#xf6;m ML, Smithson EF. Psychological contributions to functional independence: a longitudinal investigation of spinal cord injury rehabilitation. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2011;92(4):597&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21440705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migueles JH, Cadenas-Sanchez C, Ekelund U, Delisle Nystr&#xf6;m C, Mora-Gonzalez J, L&#xf6;f M et al. Accelerometer data collection and processing criteria to assess physical activity and other outcomes: A systematic review and practical considerations. Sports Med 2017;47(9):1821&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6231536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28303543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole RJ, Kripke DF, Gruen W, Mullaney DJ, Gillin JC. Automatic sleep/wake identification from wrist activity. Sleep 1992;15(5):461&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1455130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Masso X, Serra-Ano P, Garcia-Raffi LM, Sanchez-Perez EA, Lopez-Pascual J, Gonzalez LM. Validation of the use of Actigraph GT3X accelerometers to estimate energy expenditure in full time manual wheelchair users with spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord 2013;51(12):898&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23999111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warms CA, Belza BL. Actigraphy as a measure of physical activity for wheelchair users with spinal cord injury. Nurs Res 2004;53(2):136&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15084999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spivak E, Oksenberg A, Catz A. The feasibility of sleep assessment by actigraph in patients with tetraplegia. Spinal Cord 2007;45(12):765&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albaum E, Quinn E, Sedaghatkish S, Singh P, Watkins A, Musselman K et al. Accuracy of the Actigraph wGT3x-BT for step counting during inpatient spinal cord rehabilitation. Spinal Cord 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30737452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert MV, Azeze Y, Courtois M, Jayaraman A. In-lab versus at-home activity recognition in ambulatory subjects with incomplete spinal cord injury. J Neuroeng Rehabil 2017;14(1):10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5294819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28166824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannini A, Intille SS, Rosenberger M, Sabatini AM, Haskell W. Activity recognition using a single accelerometer placed at the wrist or ankle. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2013;45(11):2193&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3795931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23604069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore Ht, Leary E, Lee SY, Carrillo O, Stubbs R, Peppard P et al. Correction: Design and Validation of a Periodic Leg Movement Detector. PLoS One 2015;10(9):e0138205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4565674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26356080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sforza E, Johannes M, Claudio B. The PAM-RL ambulatory device for detection of periodic leg movements: a validation study. Sleep Medicine 2005;6(5):407&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16139771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayat A, Pomplun M, Tran DA. A Study on Human Activity Recognition Using Accelerometer Data from Smartphones. Procedia Computer Science 2014;34:450&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathie MJ, Coster ACF, Lovell NH, Celler BG. Accelerometry: providing an integrated, practical method for long-term, ambulatory monitoring of human movement. Physiological measurement 2004;25(2):R1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15132305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannini A, Sabatini AM. Machine learning methods for classifying human physical activity from on-body accelerometers. Sensors (Basel) 2010;10(2):1154&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3244008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22205862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sejdi&#x107; E, Lowry KA, Bellanca J, Redfern MS, Brach JS. A comprehensive assessment of gait accelerometry signals in time, frequency and time-frequency domains. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 2014;22(3):603&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23751971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hedel HJ, Dietz V. Walking during daily life can be validly and responsively assessed in subjects with a spinal cord injury. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 2009;23(2):117&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altenburger PA, Dierks TA, Miller KK, Combs SA, Van Puymbroeck M, Schmid AA. Examination of sustained gait speed during extended walking in individuals with chronic stroke. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2013;94(12):2471&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23816922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrest GF, Hutchinson K, Lorenz DJ, Buehner JJ, Vanhiel LR, Sisto SA et al. Are the 10 meter and 6 minute walk tests redundant in patients with spinal cord injury? Plos One 2014;9(5):e94108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4006773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24788068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hedel HJ, Emsci Study Group. Gait speed in relation to categories of functional ambulation after spinal cord injury. Neurorehabilitation and neural repair 2009;23(4):343&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19036717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altenburger PA, Dierks TA, Miller KK, Combs SA, Van Puymbroeck M, Schmid AA. Examination of sustained gait speed during extended walking in individuals with chronic stroke. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2013;94(12):2471&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23816922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulk GD, He Y, Boyne P, Dunning K. Predicting home and community walking activity poststroke. Stroke 2017;48(2):406&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, Michel V, Thirion B, Grisel O et al. Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python. the Journal of machine Learning research 2011;12:2825&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebedev AV, Westman E, Van Westen GJP, Kramberger MG, Lundervold A, Aarsland D et al. Random Forest ensembles for detection and prediction of Alzheimer's disease with a good between-cohort robustness. Neuroimage Clin 2014;6:115&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4215532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25379423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajjem A Mixed Effects Trees and Forests for Clustered Data. ProQuest LLC: University of Montreal; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawley GC, Talbot NL. On over-fitting in model selection and subsequent selection bias in performance evaluation. J Mach Learn Res 2010;11:2079&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varma S, Simon R. Bias in error estimation when using cross-validation for model selection. BMC Bioinformatics 2006;7:91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1397873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16504092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vabalas A, Gowen E, Poliakoff E, Casson AJ. Machine learning algorithm validation with a limited sample size. Plos One 2019;14(11):e0224365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6837442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31697686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossin M, Sulaiman M. A review on evaluation metrics for data classification evaluations. International Journal of Data Mining &amp; Knowledge Management Process 2015;5(2):1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause J, Carter RE, Brotherton S. Association of mode of locomotion and independence in locomotion with long-term outcomes after spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med 2009;32(3):237&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19810625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura S, Ozasa S, Nomura K, Yoshioka K, Endo F. Estimation of muscle strength from actigraph data in Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Pediatr Int 2014;56(5):748&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24689787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaspar R, Padula N, Freitas TB, de Oliveira JPJ, Torriani-Pasin C. Physical exercise for individuals with spinal cord injury: systematic review based on the international classification of functioning, disability, and health. J Sport Rehabil 2019;28(5):505&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Li J, Du L, Yang M, Yang D, Li J et al. Short-term effects of core stability training on the balance and ambulation function of individuals with chronic spinal cord injury: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Minerva Med 2019;110(3):216&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30809995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiPiro ND, Embry AE, Fritz SL, Middleton A, Krause JS, Gregory CM. Effects of aerobic exercise training on fitness and walking-related outcomes in ambulatory individuals with chronic incomplete spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord 2016;54(9):675&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4909592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26666508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin Ginis KA, Papathomas A, Perrier M-J, Smith B, Group S-SR. Psychosocial factors associated with physical activity in ambulatory and manual wheelchair users with spinal cord injury: a mixed-methods study. Disability and rehabilitation 2017;39(2):187&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26104107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chasens ER, Sereika SM, Weaver TE, Umlauf MG. Daytime sleepiness, exercise, and physical function in older adults. Journal of sleep research 2007;16(1):60&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17309764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman SE, Stone KL, Ancoli-Israel S, Blackwell T, Ewing SK, Boudreau R et al. Poor sleep is associated with poorer physical performance and greater functional limitations in older women. Sleep 2007;30(10):1317&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2266278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17969465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessi CA, Martin JL, Webber AP, Alam T, Littner MR, Harker JO et al. More daytime sleeping predicts less functional recovery among older people undergoing inpatient post-acute rehabilitation. Sleep 2008;31(9):1291&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2542969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18788654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beveridge C, Knutson K, Spampinato L, Flores A, Meltzer DO, Van Cauter E et al. Daytime Physical Activity and Sleep in Hospitalized Older Adults: Association with Demographic Characteristics and Disease Severity. J Am Geriatr Soc 2015;63(7):1391&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4752005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi Y Random forest for bioinformatics. In: Zhang C, Ma Y, editors. Ensemble Machine Learning. Boston, MA: Springer US; 2012. p 307&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>