<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39157027</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hormonal Contraceptive Influence on Baseline Vestibular/Ocular Symptomatology and Provocation for Concussion.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671241259735</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671241259735</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671241259735</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671241259735</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Hormonal contraceptives (HCs) and the menstrual cycle have been suggested to affect symptom severity and postconcussion recovery. Additionally, hormones have been a suggested rationale for sex differences between female and male athletes on concussion assessment. Researchers have yet to explore the effects of HC use on baseline symptomatology, including symptom reporting and provocation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To examine the influence of HC use on a baseline symptom reporting and vestibular/ocular provocation battery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cross-sectional study; Level of evidence, 3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 61 college-aged individuals (21 HC-using women, 21 non-HC-using women, 19 men) were administered a baseline symptom battery consisting of the Post-Concussion Symptom Scale (PCSS), Headache Impact Test-6 (HIT-6), Pediatric Vestibular Symptom Questionnaire (PVSQ), and Vestibular/Ocular Motor Screening (VOMS). The main outcome measures consisted of PCSS symptom reporting (total symptoms, symptom severity score, and symptom factors), HIT-6 and PVSQ total scores, and VOMS item (ie, saccades, convergence, or vestibular/ocular reflex) symptom provocation scores.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Significant differences were reported on HIT-6, with the highest headache reporting in the HC group (<i>P</i> = .026). On the PVSQ, the HC group also reported greater dizziness and unsteadiness symptoms than the non-HC group (<i>P</i> = .023). Similar findings existed on the PCSS, with the HC group reporting greater total symptoms (<i>P</i> &lt; .001), symptom severity (<i>P</i> &lt; .001), and vestibular-somatic (<i>P</i> = .024), cognitive-sensory (<i>P</i> = .004), sleep-arousal (<i>P</i> = .001), and affective (<i>P</i> &lt; .001) factors compared with the non-HC group. Smooth pursuit (ie, following finger smoothly with eyes) was the only VOMS items with differences between groups (<i>P</i> = .003), with the HC group having greater provocation compared with non-HC users (<i>P</i> = .020).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">HC use was associated with overall symptomatology and worse self-reported symptoms on vestibular-related inventories and concussion symptom scales and factors when compared with non-HC users and male controls. Additionally, HC users reported higher VOMS provocation scores on the smooth pursuit item than non-HC users and male controls.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moran</LastName><ForeName>Ryan N</ForeName><Initials>RN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Science, Athletic Training Research Laboratory, The University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guin</LastName><ForeName>J Russell</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family, Internal, and Rural Medicine, College of Community Health Sciences, The University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roehmer</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, Tennessee, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murray</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas G</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of Nevada, Reno, Nevada, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vestibular/Ocular Motor Screening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">female athlete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">head injuries/concussion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared that they have no conflicts of interest in the authorship and publication of this contribution. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto. Ethical approval for this study was waived by The University of Alabama (ref No. EX-19-CM-326).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39157027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11329980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671241259735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671241259735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allais G, Chiarle G, Sinigaglia S, et al. Treating migraine with contraceptives. Neurol Sci. 2017;38(suppl 1):85-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreen L, Nyberg S, Turkmen S, van Wingen G, Fernandez G, Backstrom T. Sex steroid induced negative mood may be explained by the paradoxical effect mediated by GABAA modulators. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2009;34(8):1121-1132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19272715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethea CL, Lu NZ, Gundlah C, Streicher JM. Diverse actions of ovarian steroids in the serotonin neural system. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2002;23(1):41-100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11906203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bretzin AC, Covassin T, Fox ME, et al. Sex differences in the clinical incidence of concussions, missed school days, and time loss in high school student-athletes: part 1. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(9):2263-2269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29879362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronnick MK, Okland I, Graugaard C, Bronnick KK. The effects of hormonal contraceptives on the brain: a systematic review of neuroimaging studies. Front Psychol. 2020;11:556577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7667464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33224053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christin-Maitre S. History of oral contraceptive drugs and their use worldwide. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;27(1):3-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23384741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook NE, Huang DS, Silverberg ND, et al. Baseline cognitive test performance and concussion-like symptoms among adolescent athletes with ADHD: examining differences based on medication use. Clin Neuropsychol. 2017;31(8):1341-1352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28429656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covassin T, Elbin RJ, III, Larson E, Kontos AP. Sex and age differences in depression and baseline sport-related concussion neurocognitive performance and symptoms. Clin J Sport Med. 2012;22(2):98-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22246342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covassin T, Swanik CB, Sachs M, et al. Sex differences in baseline neuropsychological function and concussion symptoms of collegiate athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40(11):923-927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16990442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbin RJ, Kontos AP, Kegel N, Johnson E, Burkhart S, Schatz P. Individual and combined effects of LD and ADHD on computerized neurocognitive concussion test performance: evidence for separate norms. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2013;28(5):476-484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23608188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farage MA, Osborn TW, MacLean AB. Cognitive, sensory, and emotional changes associated with the menstrual cycle: a review. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2008;278(4):299-307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18592262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher V, Kramer N, Abbott K, et al. The effects of sex differences and hormonal contraception on outcomes after collegiate sports-related concussion. J Neurotrauma. 2018;35(11):1242-1247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10331147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29336208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman Barr N. Managing adverse effects of hormonal contraceptives. Am Fam Physician. 2010;82(12):1499-1506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21166370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handa RJ, McGivern RF. Steroid hormones, receptors, and perceptual and cognitive sex differences in the visual system. Curr Eye Res. 2015;40(2):110-127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25153712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He B, Iovieno A, Etminan M, Kezouh A, Yeung SN. Effects of hormonal contraceptives on dry eye disease: a population-based study. Eye (Lond). 2022;36(3):634-638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8873413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33824509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzberg SD, Motu&#x2019;apuaka ML, Lambert W, Fu R, Brady J, Guise JM. The effect of menstrual cycle and contraceptives on ACL injuries and laxity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2017;5(7):2325967117718781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5524267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28795075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay JJM, Mangold KI, Lapointe A, et al. Hormonal contraceptives do not influence concussion recovery in collegiate athletes: data from the NCAA-DoD CARE Consortium. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023;55(8):1375-1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36897829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr ZY, Evenson KR, Rosamond WD, Mihalik JP, Guskiewicz KM, Marshall SW. Association between concussion and mental health in former collegiate athletes. Inj Epidemiol. 2014;1(1):28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5005582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27747661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos AP, Elbin RJ, Schatz P, et al. A revised factor structure for the Post-Concussion Symptom Scale: baseline and postconcussion factors. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(10):2375-2384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22904209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos AP, Sufrinko A, Sandel N, Emami K, Collins MW. Sport-related concussion clinical profiles: clinical characteristics, targeted treatments, and preliminary evidence. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2019;18(3):82-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30855306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosinski M, Bayliss MS, Bjorner JB, et al. A six-item short-form survey for measuring headache impact: the HIT-6. Qual Life Res. 2003;12(8):963-974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14651415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacGregor EA. Contraception and headache. Headache. 2013;53(2):247-276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23432442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza D, Harrison C, Taft A, et al. Current contraceptive management in Australian general practice: an analysis of BEACH data. Med J Aust. 2012;197(2):110-114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22794058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5th International Conference on Concussion in Sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):838-847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merritt VC, Bradson ML, Meyer JE, Arnett PA. Evaluating the test-retest reliability of symptom indices associated with the ImPACT Post-Concussion Symptom Scale (PCSS). J Clin Exp Neuropsychol. 2018;40(4):377-388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28728465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihalik JP, Ondrak KS, Guskiewicz KM, McMurray RG. The effects of menstrual cycle phase on clinical measures of concussion in healthy college-aged females. J Sci Med Sport. 2009;12(3):383-387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18771954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollayeva T, El-Khechen-Richandi G, Colantonio A. Sex &amp; gender considerations in concussion research. Concussion. 2018;3(1):CNC51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6094024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30202593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran RN, Broglio SP, Francioni KK, Sosnoff JJ. Exploring baseline concussion-assessment performance in adapted wheelchair sport athletes. J Athl Train. 2020;55(8):856-862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7462168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32607535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran RN, Covassin T, Elbin RJ. Sex differences on vestibular and ocular motor assessment in youth athletes. J Athl Train. 2019;54(4):445-448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6522088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31013113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran RN, Covassin T, Wallace J. Premorbid migraine history as a risk factor for vestibular and oculomotor baseline concussion assessment in pediatric athletes. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2019;23(4):465-470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30641840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran RN, Guin JR, Gardner J, Simer J. Baseline computerized neurocognitive testing and oculomotor measures are not altered by hormonal contraceptive use. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2023;38(6):922-928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran RN, Meek J, Allen J, Robinson J. Sex differences and normative data for the m-CTSIB and sensory integration on baseline concussion assessment in collegiate athletes. Brain Inj. 2020;34(1):20-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31542961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran RN, Murray NG, Esco MR, Dobbs W, McAllister-Deitrick J. Effects of exercise on symptoms, vestibular/ocular motor screening and postural stability in a college-aged sample. Concussion. 2020;5(2):CNC73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32509325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran RN, Wallace J, Murray NG, Covassin T. Effects of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder and learning disability on vestibular and ocular baseline concussion assessment in pediatric athletes. Appl Neuropsychol Child. 2021;10(3):276-282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31650856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mordecai KL, Rubin LH, Maki PM. Effects of menstrual cycle phase and oral contraceptive use on verbal memory. Horm Behav. 2008;54(2):286-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18455727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucha A, Collins MW, Elbin RJ, et al. A brief Vestibular/Ocular Motor Screening (VOMS) assessment to evaluate concussions: preliminary findings. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(10):2479-2486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4209316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25106780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson AK, Hansen KA. Menstrual migraines: diagnosis, evidence, and treatment. S D Med. 2021;74(12):570-575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35015948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Davis GA, Ahmed OH, et al. Introducing the Sport Concussion Office Assessment Tool 6 (SCOAT6). Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(11):648-650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37316211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlou M, Whitney S, Alkathiry AA, et al. The Pediatric Vestibular Symptom Questionnaire: a validation study. J Pediatr. 2016;168:171-177.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26522978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pletzer B, Kronbichler M, Aichhorn M, Bergmann J, Ladurner G, Kerschbaum HH. Menstrual cycle and hormonal contraceptive use modulate human brain structure. Brain Res. 2010;1348:55-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20550945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pletzer BA, Kerschbaum HH. 50 years of hormonal contraception&#x2014;time to find out, what it does to our brain. Front Neurosci. 2014;8:256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4139599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25191220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahr-Wagner L, Thillemann TM, Mehnert F, Pedersen AB, Lind M. Is the use of oral contraceptives associated with operatively treated anterior cruciate ligament injury? A case-control study from the Danish Knee Ligament Reconstruction Registry. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(12):2897-2905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25428957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schatz P, Robertshaw S. Comparing post-concussive neurocognitive test data to normative data presents risks for under-classifying &#x201c;above average&#x201d; athletes. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2014;29(7):625-632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25178629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt JD, Register-Mihalik JK, Mihalik JP, Kerr ZY, Guskiewicz KM. Identifying impairments after concussion: normative data versus individualized baselines. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(9):1621-1628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22525765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seifert T. The relationship of migraine and other headache disorders to concussion. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;158:119-126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shively CA, Bethea CL. Cognition, mood disorders, and sex hormones. ILAR J. 2004;45(2):189-199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15111738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ES, McKay AKA, Ackerman KE, et al. Methodology review: a protocol to audit the representation of female athletes in sports science and sports medicine research. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2022;32(2):114-127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35168200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sufrinko AM, Mucha A, Covassin T, et al. Sex differences in vestibular/ocular and neurocognitive outcomes after sport-related concussion. Clin J Sport Med. 2017;27(2):133-138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5203982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27379660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toffoletto S, Lanzenberger R, Gingnell M, Sundstrom-Poromaa I, Comasco E. Emotional and cognitive functional imaging of estrogen and progesterone effects in the female human brain: a systematic review. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;50:28-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Bergh O, Bogaerts K, Van Diest I. Symptom perception, awareness and interpretation. In: The International Encyclopedia of Social and Behavioral Science. Elsevier Ltd; 2015:866-872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace J, Worts P, Moran R, et al. Socioeconomic status and race as social determinants of health to be considered in clinical use of pre-season vestibular and oculomotor tests for concussion. J Clin Transl Res. 2020;6(4):168-178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren AM, Gurvich C, Worsley R, Kulkarni J. A systematic review of the impact of oral contraceptives on cognition. Contraception. 2014;90(2):111-116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24856205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wharton W, Hirshman E, Merritt P, Doyle L, Paris S, Gleason C. Oral contraceptives and androgenicity: influences on visuospatial task performance in younger individuals. Exp Clin Psychopharmacol. 2008;16(2):156-164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtys EM, Huston LJ, Boynton MD, Spindler KP, Lindenfeld TN. The effect of the menstrual cycle on anterior cruciate ligament injuries in women as determined by hormone levels. Am J Sports Med. 2002;30(2):182-188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11912085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wunderle K, Hoeger KM, Wasserman E, Bazarian JJ. Menstrual phase as predictor of outcome after mild traumatic brain injury in women. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2014;29(5):E1-E8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5237582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24220566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonkers KA, O&#x2019;Brien PM, Eriksson E. Premenstrual syndrome. Lancet. 2008;371(9619):1200-1210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>