<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41918016</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Associations between the athlete diet index and sleep quality in Iranian professional athletes: a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01563-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sleep quality is a key component of recovery in athletes, yet sleep disturbances are common in this population. Although dietary quality has been proposed as a lifestyle factor related to sleep, its association with sleep quality in professional athletes, when considered alongside other relevant factors, remains insufficiently understood. This study examined factors associated with sleep quality among Iranian professional athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This cross-sectional study included 340 professional athletes aged 18-29 years. Dietary quality was assessed using the Athlete Diet Index (ADI), sleep quality was evaluated using the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), and anthropometric characteristics were obtained using standard procedures. Multiple linear regression analysis was conducted to identify independent factors associated with the global PSQI score.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The Multiple linear regression model was statistically significant (adjusted R&#xb2; = 0.269, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Lower scores on the Specific Nutrients subscale (&#x3b2; = -0.238, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and the Core Nutrition subscale (&#x3b2; = -0.299, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) of the Athlete Diet Index were independently associated with poorer sleep quality. No significant associations were observed for body mass index, Dietary Habits, age, or sport type.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this cohort of Iranian professional athletes, dietary quality particularly core nutrition and specific nutrient intake was significantly associated with sleep quality. These findings highlight the potential importance of overall dietary quality in relation to sleep health and recovery among athletes. However, due to the cross-sectional design of the study, these associations should be interpreted with caution, and causal inferences cannot be drawn.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mansordehghan</LastName><ForeName>Maryam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Nutritional Sciences Department, School of Nutrition Sciences and Food Technology, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saber</LastName><ForeName>Amir</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, School of Nutritional Sciences and Food Technology, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran. Amir.saber@kums.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moludi</LastName><ForeName>Jalal</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, School of Nutritional Sciences and Food Technology, Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran. Jalal.moloudi@kums.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Djafarian</LastName><ForeName>Kurosh</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Nutrition, School of Nutritional Sciences and Dietetics, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yunesian</LastName><ForeName>Masud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Health Engineering, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garmaroudi</LastName><ForeName>Gholamreza</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Education &amp; Promotion, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athlete diet index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pittsburgh sleep quality index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep behaviors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sports nutrition</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences (IR.KUMS.REC.1402.636). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their participation in the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41918016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01563-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01563-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cirelli C, Tononi G. Is sleep essential? PLoS Biol. 2008;6(8):e216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes HKM, Medeiros A, Neto MM, Souza Hd, Tufik S, et al. Sleep and muscle recovery: endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothesis. Med Hypotheses. 2011;77(2):220&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirshkowitz M, Whiton K, Albert SM, Alessi C, Bruni O, DonCarlos L, et al. National sleep foundation&#x2019;s sleep time duration recommendations: methodology and results summary. Sleep Health. 2015;1(1):40&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belenky G, Wesensten NJ, Thorne DR, Thomas ML, Sing HC, Redmond DP, et al. Patterns of performance degradation and restoration during sleep restriction and subsequent recovery: A sleep dose-response study. J Sleep Res. 2003;12(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krueger JM, Majde JA, Rector DM. Cytokines in immune function and sleep regulation. Handb Clin Neurol. 2011;98:229&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel K, Tasali E, Penev P, Cauter EV. Brief communication: sleep curtailment in healthy young men is associated with decreased leptin levels, elevated Ghrelin levels, and increased hunger and appetite. Ann Intern Med. 2004;141(11):846&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dongen HP, Maislin G, Mullington JM, Dinges DF. The cumulative cost of additional wakefulness: dose-response effects on neurobehavioral functions and sleep physiology from chronic sleep restriction and total sleep deprivation. Sleep. 2003;26(2):117&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Glaister M, Pizzoferro K, Dawson J, Pedlar C. Sleep duration and quality in elite athletes measured using wristwatch actigraphy. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(6):541&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach GD, Halson SL, Sargent C. Sleep/wake behaviours of elite athletes from individual and team sports. Eur J Sport Sci. 2015;15(2):94&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Rosen P, Frohm A, Kottorp A, Frid&#xe9;n C, Heijne A. Too little sleep and an unhealthy diet could increase the risk of sustaining a new injury in adolescent elite athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(11):1364&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumortier J, Mariman A, Boone J, Delesie L, Tobback E, Vogelaers D, et al. Sleep, training load and performance in elite female gymnasts. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(2):151&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Julian R, Bartlett J, Meyer T. Impaired sleep and recovery after night matches in elite football players. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(14):1333&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Dawson B, Dupont G. Influence of night soccer matches on sleep in elite players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2019;33(1):174&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. The impact of training schedules on the sleep and fatigue of elite athletes. Chronobiol Int. 2014;31(10):1160&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler PM, Knez W, Crowcroft S, Mendham AE, Miller J, Sargent C, et al. Greater effect of East versus West travel on jet Lag, Sleep, and team sport performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(12):2548&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler P, Duffield R, Howle K, Waterson A, Vaile J. Effects of northbound long-haul international air travel on sleep quantity and subjective jet lag and wellness in professional Australian soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(5):648&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade A, Bevilacqua G, Casagrande P, Brandt R, Coimbra D. Sleep quality associated with mood in elite athletes. Physician Sportsmed. 2019;47(3):312&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts AJ, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: the effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45(2):161&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnar D, Bartel K, Kakoschke N, Lang C. Sleep interventions designed to improve athletic performance and recovery: a systematic review of current approaches. Sports Med. 2018;48:683&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao B, Dwivedi S, Milewski MD, Cruz AI Jr. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injury in adolescents: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7(3suppl):2325967119S00132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy J, Gladney C, Sullivan P. Exploring the relationship between sleep quality, sleep hygiene, and psychological distress in a sample of Canadian varsity athletes. J Clin Sport Psychol. 2021;16(3):220&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facer-Childs ER, Mascaro L, Hoffman D, Mansfield D, Drummond SP, Rajaratnam SM. Sleep as a major determinant for mental health outcomes in elite Australian football league (AFL) athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54(4):665&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knufinke M, Nieuwenhuys A, Maase K, Moen MH, Geurts SA, Coenen AM, et al. Effects of natural between-days variation in sleep on elite athletes&#x2019; psychomotor vigilance and sport-specific measures of performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2018;17(4):515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB. Energy balance and body composition in sports and exercise. J Sports Sci. 2004;22(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mountjoy M, Sundgot-Borgen J, Burke L, Ackerman KE, Blauwet C, Constantini N, et al. International olympic committee (IOC) consensus statement on relative energy deficiency in sport (RED-S): 2018 update. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28(4):316&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masaad AA, Yusuf AM, Shakir AZ, Khan MS, Khaleel S, Cheikh Ismail L, et al. Sleep quality and dietary inflammatory index among university students: a cross-sectional study. Sleep Breath. 2021;25:2221&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olga P, Emanuel F, Foster C, Cortis C, Fusco A. Eating Right, sleeping tight? A Cross-Sectional study on the Student-Athlete paradox for diet and sleep behaviors. Nutrients. 2025;17(18):2946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshikawa M, Uchida S, Hirano Y. A subjective assessment of the prevalence and factors associated with poor sleep quality amongst elite Japanese athletes. Sports medicine-open. 2018;4:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda J, Yoshizaki T, Yamamoto K, Yoshino M, Ota M, Kawahara T, et al. Association of frequency of milk or dairy product consumption with subjective sleep quality during training periods in Japanese elite athletes: A Cross-Sectional study. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo). 2019;65(2):177&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth MD, Jessup A, Turner-McGrievy G, Shivappa N, Hurley TG, H&#xe9;bert JR. Changes in dietary inflammatory potential predict changes in sleep quality metrics, but not sleep duration. Sleep. 2020;43(11):zsaa093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kase BE, Liu J, Wirth MD, Shivappa N, Hebert JR. Associations between dietary inflammatory index and sleep problems among adults in the united States, NHANES 2005&#x2013;2016. Sleep Health. 2021;7(2):273&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazyar H, Zare Javid A, Bavi Behbahani H, Shivappa N, Hebert JR, Khodaramhpour S, et al. The association between dietary inflammatory index with sleep quality and obesity amongst Iranian female students: A cross-sectional study. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;75(5):e14061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaput JP. Sleep patterns, diet quality and energy balance. Physiol Behav. 2014;134:86&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsereteli N, Vallat R, Fernandez-Tajes J, Delahanty LM, Ordovas JM, Drew DA, et al. Impact of insufficient sleep on dysregulated blood glucose control under standardised meal conditions. Diabetologia. 2022;65(2):356&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campanini MZ, Guallar-Castill&#xf3;n P, Rodr&#xed;guez-Artalejo F, Lopez-Garcia E. Mediterranean diet and changes in sleep duration and indicators of sleep quality in older adults. Sleep. 2017;40(3):zsw083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel NV, Zimberg IZ, Estadella D, Garcia MC, Padovani RC, Juzwiak CR. Effect of the intake of high or low glycemic index high carbohydrate-meals on athletes&#x2019; sleep quality in pre-game nights. An Acad Bras Cienc. 2019;91(01):e20180107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong JN, Hackett DA, Chow C-M. Sleep quality and duration following evening intake of alpha-lactalbumin: a pilot study. Biol Rhythm Res. 2017;48(4):507&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, Dziedzic CE, Wood E, Oikawa SY, Phillips SM. Presleep &#x3b1;-lactalbumin consumption does not improve sleep quality or time-trial performance in cyclists. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2020;30(3):197&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gratwicke M, Miles KH, Pyne DB, Pumpa KL, Clark B. Nutritional interventions to improve sleep in team-sport athletes: a narrative review. Nutrients. 2021;13(5):1586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts SSH, Teo W-P, Warmington SA. Effects of training and competition on the sleep of elite athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(8):513&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capling L, Gifford JA, Beck KL, Flood VM, Slater GJ, Denyer GS, et al. Development of an athlete diet index for rapid dietary assessment of athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019;29(6):643&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capling L, Gifford JA, Beck KL, Flood VM, Halar F, Slater GJ, et al. Relative validity and reliability of a novel diet quality assessment tool for athletes: the athlete diet index. Br J Nutr. 2021;126(2):307&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHMRC N. Australian dietary guidelines. National Health and Medical Research Council, National Resource Management Ministerial Council. 2013. https://www.nhmrc.gov.au/about-us/publications/australian-dietary-guidelines.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell B, Kreider RB, Ziegenfuss T, La Bounty P, Roberts M, Burke D, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: protein and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie K, Slater G, King N, Byrne N. The measurement and interpretation of dietary protein distribution during a rugby preseason. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2015;25(4):353&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falkenberg E, Aisbett B, Lastella M, Roberts S, Condo D. Nutrient intake, meal timing and sleep in elite male Australian football players. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(1):7&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands W, Cardinale M, McNeal J, Murray S, Sole C, Reed J, et al. Recommendations for measurement and management of an elite athlete. Sports. 2019;7(5):105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AK, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, Martin DT, Mujika I, Goosey-Tolfrey VL, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams JR. The declaration of Helsinki and public health. Bull World Health Organ. 2008;86:650&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF III, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad Gholi Mezerji N, Naseri P, Omraninezhad Z, Shayan Z. The reliability and validity of the Persian version of Pittsburgh sleep quality index in Iranian people. Avicenna J Neuro Psycho Physiol. 2017;4(3):95&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpi M. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: a brief review. Occup Med (Lond). 2025;75(1):14&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee PH, Macfarlane DJ, Lam TH, Stewart SM. Validity of the international physical activity questionnaire short form (IPAQ-SF): A systematic review. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Activity. 2011;8:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DT, Erdman KA, Burke LM. Position of the academy of nutrition and Dietetics, dietitians of Canada, and the American college of sports medicine: nutrition and athletic performance. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2016;116(3):501&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Condo D, Lastella M, Aisbett B, Stevens A, Roberts S. Sleep duration and quality are associated with nutrient intake in elite female athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25(4):345&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge M-P, Mikic A, Pietrolungo CE. Effects of diet on sleep quality. Adv Nutr. 2016;7(5):938&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva M-R, Paiva T. Risk factors for precompetitive sleep behavior in elite female athletes. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2018;59(4):708&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss K, Zhang Y, Kreutzer A, Graybeal AJ, Porter RR, Braun-Trocchio R, et al. The relationship between dietary intake and sleep quality in endurance athletes. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:810402.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>