<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41450133</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-509X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of head trauma rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Head Trauma Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Monitoring Adolescent Sport-Related Concussion Recovery Using Consumer-Grade Wearables: A Pilot Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HTR.0000000000001143</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate whether consumer-grade wearable devices (CGWDs) can detect physiological differences between adolescent athletes recovering from sport-related concussion (SRC) versus musculoskeletal (MSK) injury, and to examine whether wearable-derived physiological markers are associated with symptom burden during the acute post-injury phase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Outpatient sports medicine clinic at a pediatric academic medical center.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">High school student-athletes aged 14-18&#xa0;years were eligible if they presented within 10&#xa0;days of SRC or acute, nonsurgical MSK injury and had internet access and willingness to comply with study procedures. Thirty-eight participants were enrolled; four were excluded due to protocol deviations. The final analytic sample included 34 participants (SRC: n =&#xa0;17; MSK: n =&#xa0;17).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Prospective observational cohort study conducted from September 2021 to April 2022. All participants were issued a Fitbit Sense to passively monitor sleep, activity, and heart rate for up to 6&#xa0;weeks post-injury. No randomization or blinding occurred, as this was an observational study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">The primary outcome was group differences in CGWD-derived physiological metrics (sleep patterns and architecture, physical activity, heart rate) across 3 post-enrollment time intervals (Days 1-14, 15-28, 29-42). Secondary outcomes included correlations between physiological data and symptom burden based on the Post-Concussion Symptom Inventory, Second Edition (PCSI-2).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared to MSK peers, participants with SRC showed significantly more light sleep, more nocturnal wake time, and lower daily step counts during the first 4&#xa0;weeks post-injury (P &lt;.0038). No significant differences were observed in REM sleep, deep sleep, or heart rate. In SRC participants, greater nocturnal wake time and lower resting heart rate were modestly associated with higher cognitive symptom ratings; emotional symptoms were modestly associated with step counts. No adverse events occurred.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">CGWDs may capture recovery-specific physiological disruptions in adolescent SRC, particularly in sleep and physical activity. These findings support the potential for wearable technology to inform individualized, objective approaches to concussion monitoring in clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ransom</LastName><ForeName>Danielle M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Author Affiliations: Center for Behavioral Health, Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital, St. Petersburg, Florida (Dr Ransom); Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland (Dr Ransom); Center for Pediatric Data Science &amp; Analytic Methodology, Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital, St. Petersburg, Florida (Drs Tudor, Rehman, Ahumada); Department of Anesthesiology and Critical Care Medicine, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland (Drs Tudor, Rehman, Ahumada); Division of Sports Medicine, Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital, St. Petersburg, Florida (Drs Irani, Mularoni); Brain Injury Clinical Research Center, Kennedy Krieger Institute, Baltimore, Marlyland (Drs Suskauer, Svingos); Department of Physical Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland (Drs Suskauer, Svingos); and Department of Pediatrics, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland (Drs Suskauer, Mularoni).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tudor</LastName><ForeName>Brant H</ForeName><Initials>BH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Irani</LastName><ForeName>Sarah A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rehman</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suskauer</LastName><ForeName>Stacy J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svingos</LastName><ForeName>Adrian M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahumada</LastName><ForeName>Luis M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mularoni</LastName><ForeName>P Patrick</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Head Trauma Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8702552</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-9701</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feasibility studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate/physiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor activity/physiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiologic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery of function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep wake disorders/physiopathology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wearable electronic devices</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No conflicts of interest are declared. This work was supported in part by a research grant from the Kart 4 Kids Concussion Initiative through the Johns Hopkins All Children&#x2019;s Foundation.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41450133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HTR.0000000000001143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001199-990000000-00343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bryan M, Rowhani-Rahbar A, Comstock R, Rivara F. Sports- and recreation-related concussions in US youth. Pediatrics. 2016;138(1). doi:10.1542/peds.2015-4635</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2015-4635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echemendia RJ, Burma JS, Bruce JM, et al. Acute evaluation of sport-related concussion and implications for the Sport Concussion Assessment Tool (SCAT6) for adults, adolescents and children: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(11):722&#x2013;735. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2022-106661</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Davis GA, Ahmed OH, et al. Introducing the Sport Concussion Office Assessment Tool 6 (SCOAT6). Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(11):648&#x2013;650. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2023-106860</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Schneider KJ, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport: the 6th international conference on concussion in sport&#x2013;Amsterdam, October 2022. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(11):695&#x2013;711. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2023-106898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doroszkiewicz C, Gold D, Green R, Tartaglia MC, Ma J, Tator CH. Anxiety, depression, and quality of life: a long-term follow-up study of patients with persisting concussion symptoms. J Neurotrauma. 2021;38(4):493&#x2013;505. doi:10.1089/neu.2020.7313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2020.7313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassimatis M, Orr R, Fyffe A, Browne G. Association of sleep disturbance with neurocognition, symptom severity, and recovery in pediatric concussion: a 10-year retrospective analysis of a tertiary referral concussion clinic. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2023;38(3):231&#x2013;239. doi:10.1097/HTR.0000000000000804</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HTR.0000000000000804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neely LM, Smulligan KL, Wingerson MJ, et al. The association between sleep and physical activity with persisting postconcussion symptoms among adolescent athletes. PM R. 2023;15(9):1122&#x2013;1129. doi:10.1002/pmrj.12939</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis GA, Schneider KJ, Anderson V, et al. Pediatric sport-related concussion: recommendations from the amsterdam consensus statement 2023. Pediatrics. 2023;153(1):e2023063489. doi:10.1542/peds.2023-063489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2023-063489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabor JB, Brett BL, Nelson L, et al. Role of biomarkers and emerging technologies in defining and assessing neurobiological recovery after sport-related concussion: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(12):789&#x2013;797. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2022-106680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhagen E, Bolling C. Protecting the health of the @hlete: how online technology may aid our common goal to prevent injury and illness in sport. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(18):1174&#x2013;1178. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2014-094322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-094322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muniz-Pardos B, Angeloudis K, Guppy FM, et al. Wearable and telemedicine innovations for Olympic events and elite sport. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2021;61(8):1061&#x2013;1072. doi:10.23736/S0022-4707.21.12752-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.21.12752-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy F, Muniz-Pardos B, Angeloudis K, et al. Technology innovation and guardrails in elite sport: the future is now. Sports Med. 2023;53(Suppl 1):97&#x2013;113. doi:10.1007/s40279-023-01913-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01913-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi D, Roemer FW, Tol JL, et al. Emerging quantitative imaging techniques in sports medicine. Radiology. 2023;308(2):e221531. doi:10.1148/radiol.221531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.221531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte JP, Fernandes RJ, Silva G, et al. Lower limbs wearable sports garments for muscle recovery: an umbrella review. Healthcare (Basel). 2022;10(8):1552. doi:10.3390/healthcare10081552</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10081552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacey A, Whyte E, O&#x2019;Keeffe S, O&#x2019;Connor S, Moran K. A qualitative examination of the factors affecting the adoption of injury focused wearable technologies in recreational runners. PLoS One. 2022;17(7):e0265475. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0265475</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0265475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei RJ, Holder IG, Oumsang AS, Paris BA, Paris HL. Wearable activity trackers-advanced technology or advanced marketing? Eur J Appl Physiol. 2022;122(9):1975&#x2013;1990. doi:10.1007/s00421-022-04951-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-022-04951-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn J, Kidzinski L, Runge R, et al. Wearable sensors enable personalized predictions of clinical laboratory measurements. Nat Med. 2021;27(6):1105&#x2013;1112. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01339-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01339-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransom D, Tudor B, Irani S, et al. Feasibility of data collection via consumer-grade wearable devices in adolescent student athletes: prospective longitudinal cohort study. JMIR Form Res. 2025;9:e54630. doi:10.2196/54630</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/54630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan WP, Mannix R, Monuteaux MC, Stein CJ, Bachur RG. Early symptom burden predicts recovery after sport-related concussion. Neurology. 2014;83(24):2204&#x2013;2210. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000001073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan WP, O&#x2019;Brien MJ, Geminiani E, Mannix R. Initial symptom burden predicts duration of symptoms after concussion. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19(9):722&#x2013;725. doi:10.1016/j.jsams.2015.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.12.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook NE, Gaudet CE, Maxwell B, Zafonte R, Berkner PD, Iverson GL. Greater acute concussion symptoms are associated with longer recovery times in adolescents. J Child Neurol. 2022;37(12-14):970&#x2013;978. doi:10.1177/08830738221125986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738221125986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5th international conference on concussion in sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):838&#x2013;847. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2017-097699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PostConcussion symptom inventory TM 2 | PCSI-2 | PAR. Accessed June 5, 2025. https://www.parinc.com/products/PCSI-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putukian M, Purcell L, Schneider KJ, et al. Clinical recovery from concussion&#x2013;return to school and sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(12):798&#x2013;809. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2022-106682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumba-Brown A, Yeates KO, Sarmiento K. Centers for disease control and prevention guideline on the diagnosis and management of mild traumatic brain injury among children. JAMA Pediatr. 2018;172(11). doi:10.1001/jamapediatrics.2018.2853</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2018.2853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher M, Wiseman-Hakes C, Obeid J, DeMatteo C. Examining the trajectory and predictors of post-concussion sleep quality in children and adolescents. Brain Inj. 2022;36(2):166&#x2013;174. doi:10.1080/02699052.2022.2043439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02699052.2022.2043439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donahue CC, Smulligan KL, Wingerson MJ, et al. Feasibility of at-home sleep monitoring in adolescents with and without concussion. Nat Sci Sleep. 2024;16:2257&#x2013;2268. doi:10.2147/NSS.S497858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NSS.S497858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostyun RO, Milewski MD, Hafeez I. Sleep disturbance and neurocognitive function during the recovery from a sport-related concussion in adolescents. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(3):633&#x2013;640. doi:10.1177/0363546514560727</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546514560727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramley H, Henson A, Lewis MM, Kong L, Stetter C, Silvis M. Sleep disturbance following concussion is a risk factor for a prolonged recovery. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2017;56(14):1280&#x2013;1285. doi:10.1177/0009922816681603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0009922816681603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdaugh DL, Ono KE, Reisner A, Burns TG. Assessment of sleep quantity and sleep disturbances during recovery from sports-related concussion in youth athletes. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;99(5):960&#x2013;966. doi:10.1016/j.apmr.2018.01.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2018.01.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell DR, Oldham JR, Brilliant AN, Meehan WP. Trouble falling asleep after concussion is associated with higher symptom burden among children and adolescents. J Child Neurol. 2019;34(5):256&#x2013;261. doi:10.1177/0883073818824000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073818824000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tham SW, Aaron RV, Palermo TM. The role of sleep deficiency in the trajectory of postconcussive symptoms in adolescents. Brain Inj. 2019;33(11):1413&#x2013;1419. doi:10.1080/02699052.2019.1643921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02699052.2019.1643921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem GT, Slomine BS, Suskauer SJ. Sleep symptoms predict school attendance after pediatric concussion. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2020;59(6):580&#x2013;587. doi:10.1177/0009922820913960</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0009922820913960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaney NA, Trbovich A, Ernst N, Eagle SR, Collins MW, Kontos AP. Influence of sleep dysfunction on concussion assessment outcomes among adolescent athletes after concussion and healthy controls. Clin J Sport Med. 2021;31(6):481&#x2013;487. doi:10.1097/JSM.0000000000000860</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes C, Hunt K, Cox B, Raybon J, Lopez RM. Sleep dysfunction in adolescents with prolonged postconcussion symptoms: a reciprocal coupling of traumatic brain injury and sleep-related problems. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;31(6):809&#x2013;814. doi:10.1123/jsr.2021-0277</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2021-0277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy JJ, Burma JS, Toomey CM, et al. Rest and exercise early after sport-related concussion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(12):762&#x2013;770. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2022-106676</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magliato SN, Wingerson MJ, Seehusen CN, et al. Sleep problems after concussion are associated with poor balance and persistent postconcussion symptoms. J Child Neurol. 2023;38(3-4):198&#x2013;205. doi:10.1177/08830738231170721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738231170721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butterfield L, Zemek R, Borghese MM, et al. Nightly sleep duration and symptom burden over 1 month following pediatric concussion. JAMA Netw Open. 2025;8(6):e2516333. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2025.16333</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2025.16333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison L, Wilson S, Munaf&#xf2; MR. Pain-related and psychological symptoms in adolescents with musculoskeletal and sleep problems. Clin J Pain. 2016;32(3):246&#x2013;253. doi:10.1097/AJP.0000000000000252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AJP.0000000000000252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palermo TM, Wilson AC, Lewandowski AS, Toliver-Sokol M, Murray CB. Behavioral and psychosocial factors associated with insomnia in adolescents with chronic pain. Pain. 2011;152(1):89&#x2013;94. doi:10.1016/j.pain.2010.09.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pain.2010.09.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miutz LN, Burma JS, Lapointe AP, Newel KT, Emery CA, Smirl JD. Physical activity following sport-related concussion in adolescents: a systematic review. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2022;132(5):1250&#x2013;1266. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00691.2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00691.2021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledoux AA, Sicard V, Bijelic V, et al. Optimal volume of moderate-to-vigorous physical activity postconcussion in children and adolescents. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7(2):e2356458. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.56458</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.56458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purkayastha S, Williams B, Murphy M, Lyng S, Sabo T, Bell KR. Reduced heart rate variability and lower cerebral blood flow associated with poor cognition during recovery following concussion. Auton Neurosci. 2019;220:102548. doi:10.1016/j.autneu.2019.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2019.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbert LD, Kaelberer Z, Gleave E, et al. A systematic review of the relationship between traumatic brain injury and disruptions in heart rate variability. Appl Psychophysiol Biofeedback. 2024;49(4):523&#x2013;540. doi:10.1007/s10484-024-09663-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10484-024-09663-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffman CA, Kay JJM, Saba KM, et al. Predictive value of subacute heart rate variability for determining outcome following adolescent concussion. J Clin Med. 2021;10(1):161. doi:10.3390/jcm10010161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10010161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake TA, McKay CD, Meeuwisse WH, Emery CA. The impact of concussion on cardiac autonomic function: a systematic review. Brain Inj. 2016;30(2):132&#x2013;145. doi:10.3109/02699052.2015.1093659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02699052.2015.1093659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorne J, Hellewell SC, Cowen G, et al. Symptoms associated with exercise intolerance and resting heart rate following mild traumatic brain injury. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2024;39(5):E381&#x2013;E392. doi:10.1097/HTR.0000000000000928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HTR.0000000000000928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, Ades PA, Kligfield P, et al. Exercise standards for testing and training: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2013;128(8):873&#x2013;934. doi:10.1161/CIR.0b013e31829b5b44</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0b013e31829b5b44</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin K, Minamitani H, Onishi S, Yamazaki H, Lee M. Autonomic differences between athletes and nonathletes: spectral analysis approach. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29(11):1482&#x2013;1490. doi:10.1097/00005768-199711000-00015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199711000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia GL, Porto LGG, da Cruz CJG, Molina GE. Can resting heart rate explain the heart rate and parasympathetic responses during rest, exercise, and recovery? PLoS One. 2022;17(12):e0277848. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0277848</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0277848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon EM, Kamath MV, McCartney N, Fallen EL. Neural regulation of heart rate variability in endurance athletes and sedentary controls. Cardiovasc Res. 1992;26(7):713&#x2013;719. doi:10.1093/cvr/26.7.713</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/26.7.713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellenger CR, Fuller JT, Thomson RL, Davison K, Robertson EY, Buckley JD. Monitoring athletic training status through autonomic heart rate regulation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1461&#x2013;1486. doi:10.1007/s40279-016-0484-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0484-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin Harper LN, Nahman JC, Ahumada L, et al. Neurocognitive evaluation of adolescents recovering from sports-related concussion: a prospective cohort pilot study utilizing the national institutes of health toolbox cognition battery. Appl Neuropsychol Child. 2025:1&#x2013;10. doi:10.1080/21622965.2025.2507326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21622965.2025.2507326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinoy ED, Cuellar JA, Huwa KE, et al. Performance of seven consumer sleep-tracking devices compared with polysomnography. Sleep. 2020;44(5):zsaa291. doi:10.1093/sleep/zsaa291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/zsaa291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DJ, Sargent C, Roach GD. A validation of six wearable devices for estimating sleep, heart rate and heart rate variability in healthy adults. Sensors. 2022;22(16):6317. doi:10.3390/s22166317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22166317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schyvens AM, Van Oost NC, Aerts JM, et al. Accuracy of fitbit charge 4, garmin vivosmart 4, and WHOOP versus polysomnography: systematic review. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2024;12:e52192. doi:10.2196/52192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/52192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>