<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41369808</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Validating Subjective Ratings with Wearable Data for a Nuanced Understanding of Load-Recovery Status in Elite Endurance Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>154</StartPage><MedlinePgn>154</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">154</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-025-00958-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The emergence of wearable technology offers enhanced real-time health management, including sleep, recovery, and exercise optimization. Despite their potential to monitor load-recovery parameters in elite athletes, the selection, combination, and interpretation or reliance of metrics in relation to perceived impact remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study assessed data from three wearables measuring sleep, continuous glucose, and exercise, together with the Profile of Mood State (POMS) dimensions alongside subjective ratings via the Readiness Advisor application (RA app) (Silicon Valley Exercise Analytics, svexa, Menlo Park, California, USA) to evaluate their association and value in load-recovery monitoring.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty national team endurance athletes, competing at the highest international level, were monitored during one year of training, recovery, and competitions. Data collections were made with Global Positioning System (GPS) watches and heart rate monitors, &#x14c;ura rings (&#x14c;ura Health OY, Oulu, Finland), continuous glucose monitors, POMS questionnaires and subjective ratings in the RA app.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant correlations were found between each RA question and its counterpart in a linear mixed model (r values&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.39-0.81). However, time series analysis through autoregressive integrated moving average (ARIMA analysis) revealed individual variability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings indicate an influence of external aspects and advocate for a multifaceted approach to the assessment of load-recovery balance, well-being and performance. Moreover, personalized analyses proved more accurate than group averages, emphasizing the need for individualized monitoring. Integrating subjective and objective data appears essential for nuanced understanding of the athlete status, advancing high-performance monitoring and athletic health management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spetz</LastName><ForeName>Lina</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8314-7814</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Nutrition and Biomechanics, The Swedish School of Sport and Health Sciences, GIH, Stockholm, Sweden. lina.spetz@gih.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rogestedt</LastName><ForeName>Johan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Silicon Valley Exercise Analytics (svexa), Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nilsson</LastName><ForeName>Rickard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Silicon Valley Exercise Analytics (svexa), Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattsson</LastName><ForeName>C Mikael</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Silicon Valley Exercise Analytics (svexa), Menlo Park, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larsen</LastName><ForeName>Filip J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Nutrition and Biomechanics, The Swedish School of Sport and Health Sciences, GIH, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Silicon Valley Exercise Analytics (svexa), Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval and Consent to Participate: The study was approved by the Swedish Ethical Review Authority (DNR: 2021&#x2013;02498) and conducted in accordance with the ethical principles in the Declaration of Helsinki. Informed Consent: Informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their entry into the study. Consent for Publication: Consent for publication was included in the consent to participate prior to study entry. All data is presented anonymously, without identifying details of the participants. Competing Interests: The RA application, referenced in this publication, is a product of Silicon Valley Exercise Analytics (svexa), a company co-founded by authors F.J.L. and C.M.M. These authors, along with J.R. and R.N., are also shareholders in svexa. Additionally, L.S. has received funding from svexa, contributing to her PhD position. Although the final score provided in the RA app, the Readiness Score, is not part of the study analyses, the results provide valuable information to develop improved versions of the app and the potential inclusion of additional data parameters to refine athlete feedback.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41369808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12696214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00958-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-025-00958-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Daniore P, Nittas V, Haag C, Bernard J, Gonzenbach R, von Wyl V. From wearable sensor data to digital biomarker development: ten lessons learned and a framework proposal. Npj Digit Med. 2024;7:161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-024-01151-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11189504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38890529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekaran R, Katthula V, Moustakas E. Patterns of use and key predictors for the use of wearable health care devices by US adults: insights from a National survey. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22:e22443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/22443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7600024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33064083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR. Worldwide survey of fitness trends for 2020. ACSMS Health Fit J. 2019;23:10&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/FIT.0000000000000526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng K, Ryba T. The quantified athlete: associations of wearables for high school athletes. Adv Hum -Comput Interact. 2018;6317524. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seshadri DR, Li RT, Voos JE, Rowbottom JR, Alfes CM, Zorman CA, Drummond CK. Wearable sensors for monitoring the internal and external workload of the athlete. Npj Digit Med. 2019;2:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-019-0149-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31372506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seshadri DR, Li RT, Voos JE, Rowbottom JR, Alfes CM, Zorman CA, Drummond CK. Wearable sensors for monitoring the physiological and biochemical profile of the athlete. Npj Digit Med. 2019;2:72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-019-0150-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6646404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31341957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li RT, Kling SR, Salata MJ, Cupp SA, Sheehan J, Voos JE. Wearable performance devices in sports medicine. Sports Health. 2016;8:74&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738115616917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty C, Baldwin M, Keogh A, Caulfield B, Argent R. Keeping Pace with wearables: A living umbrella review of systematic reviews evaluating the accuracy of consumer wearable technologies in health measurement. Sports Med. 2024. 10.1007/s40279-024-02077-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02077-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11560992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39080098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phipps J, Passage B, Sel K, Martinez J, Saadat M, Koker T, Damaso N, Davis S, Palmer J, Claypool K, Kiley C, Pettigrew RI, Jafari R. Early adverse physiological event detection using commercial wearables: challenges and opportunities. NPJ Digit Med. 2024;7:136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-024-01129-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11116498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38783001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim J, Fleisch E, Barata F. Circadian rhythm analysis using wearable-based accelerometry as a digital biomarker of aging and healthspan. Npj Digit Med. 2024;7:146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-024-01111-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11150246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38834756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Amin O, Shihada B. Intelligent wearable systems: opportunities and challenges in health and sports. ACM Comput Surv. 2024;56(1&#x2013;190):42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celik Y, Godfrey A. Bringing it all together: wearable data fusion. Npj Digit Med. 2023;6:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-023-00897-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10435508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37591989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsoulakis E, Wang Q, Wu H, Shahriyari L, Fletcher R, Liu J, Achenie L, Liu H, Jackson P, Xiao Y, Syeda-Mahmood T, Tuli R, Deng J. Digital twins for health: a scoping review. Npj Digit Med. 2024;7:77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-024-01073-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10960047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38519626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hli&#x161; T, Fister I, Fister I Jr. Digital twins in sport: Concepts, taxonomies, challenges and practical potentials. Expert Syst Appl. 2024;258:125104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.125104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armeni P, Polat I, De Rossi LM, Diaferia L, Meregalli S, Gatti A. Digital twins in healthcare: is it the beginning of a new era of Evidence-Based medicine? A critical review. J Pers Med. 2022;12:1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jpm12081255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9410074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36013204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luka&#x10d; L, Fister I. Digital twin in sport: from an Idea to realization. Appl Sci. 2022;12:12741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app122412741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vall&#xe9;e A. Digital twin for healthcare systems. Front Digit Health. 2023;5:1253050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2023.1253050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10513171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37744683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naughton M, Salmon PM, Compton HR, McLean S. Challenges and opportunities of artificial intelligence implementation within sports science and sports medicine teams. Front Sports Act Living 2024;6 ;1332427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11144926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38832311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barricelli BR, Casiraghi E, Gliozzo J, Petrini A, Valtolina S. Human digital twin for fitness management. IEEE Access. 2020;8:26637&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2971576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attaran M, Celik BG. Digital twin: Benefits, use cases, challenges, and opportunities. Decis Anal J. 2023;6:100165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dajour.2023.100165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidari J, Beckmann J, Bertollo M, Brink M, Kallus KW, Robazza C, Kellmann M. Multidimensional monitoring of recovery status and implications for performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:2&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29543069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cintineo HP, Bello ML, Walker AJ, Chandler AJ, McFadden BA, Arent SM. Monitoring training, performance, biomarkers, and psychological state throughout a competitive season: a case study of a triathlete. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05414-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishica C, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Taskinen S, Hynynen E, Nummela A, Holmberg HC, Linnamo V. Associations between objective measures of performance-related characteristics and perceived stress in young cross-country skiers during pre-season training. J Sports Sci. 2024;1&#x2013;10. 10.1080/02640414.2024.2304499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38247021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson F, Rongen F, Cowburn I, Till K. A longitudinal mixed methods case study investigation of the Academic, Athletic, psychosocial and psychological impacts of being a sport school student athlete. Sports Med. 2024. 10.1007/s40279-024-02021-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02021-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11393160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38635007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Bridge MW, Meeusen R, Busschaert B, Gleeson M, Jones DA, Jeukendrup AE. Time course of performance changes and fatigue markers during intensified training in trained cyclists. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:947&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01164.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killer SC, Svendsen IS, Jeukendrup AE, Gleeson M. Evidence of disturbed sleep and mood state in well-trained athletes during short-term intensified training with and without a high carbohydrate nutritional intervention. J Sports Sci. 2017;35:1402&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1085589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26406911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods AL, Rice AJ, Garvican-Lewis LA, Wallett AM, Lundy B, Rogers MA, Welvaert M, Halson S, McKune A, Thompson KG. The effects of intensified training on resting metabolic rate (RMR), body composition and performance in trained cyclists. PLoS ONE. 2018;13:e0191644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0191644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29444097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flockhart M, Nilsson LC, Tais S, Ekblom B, Apr&#xf3; W, Larsen FJ. Excessive exercise training causes mitochondrial functional impairment and decreases glucose tolerance in healthy volunteers. Cell Metab. 2021;33:957&#x2013;e9706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2021.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33740420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and external training load: 15 years on. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:270&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourdon PC, Cardinale M, Murray A, Gastin P, Kellmann M, Varley MC, Gabbett TJ, Coutts AJ, Burgess DJ, Gregson W, Cable NT. Monitoring athlete training loads: consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(2&#x2013;161):2&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlin MJ, Wilkes D, Elliot CA, Lizamore CA, Kathiravel Y. Monitoring training loads and perceived stress in young elite university athletes. Front Physiol. 2019;10:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30761016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Main LC, Gastin PB. Monitoring the athlete training response: subjective self-reported measures Trump commonly used objective measures: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2015;50:281&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26423706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns L, Weissensteiner JR, Cohen M. Lifestyles and mindsets of Olympic, paralympic and world champions: is an integrated approach the key to elite performance? Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:818&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30352862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dohlsten J, Barker-Ruchti N, Lindgren E-C. Sustainable elite sport: Swedish athletes&#x2019; voices of sustainability in athletics. Qual Res Sport Exerc Health. 2021;13:727&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2159676X.2020.1778062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudo-Ortega A, Talsnes RK, Eid H, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Solli GS. Sex differences in Self-Reported Causes, Symptoms, and recovery strategies associated with underperformance in endurance athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;19:820&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2024-0131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38862109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts AJ, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: the effects of sleep loss on exercise Performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45:161&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0260-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25315456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nixdorf I, Frank R, Beckmann J. An explorative study on major stressors and its connection to depression and chronic stress among German elite athletes. Adv Phys Educ. 2015;05:255&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ape.2015.54030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne JOC, Haff G, Coutts G, Newton AJ, R. U., Nimphius S. The current state of subjective training load Monitoring&#x2014;a practical perspective and call to action. Sports Med - Open. 2018;4:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-018-0172-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6301906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30570718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne JOC, Coutts AJ, Newton RU, Haff GG. The current state of subjective training load monitoring: Follow-Up and future directions. Sports Med - Open. 2022;8:53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00433-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9012875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35426569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason AE, Hecht FM, Davis SK, Natale JL, Hartogensis W, Damaso N, Claypool KT, Dilchert S, Dasgupta S, Purawat S, Viswanath VK, Klein A, Chowdhary A, Fisher SM, Anglo C, Puldon KY, Veasna D, Prather JG, Pandya LS, Fox LM, Busch M, Giordano C, Mercado BK, Song J, Jaimes R, Baum BS, Telfer BA, Philipson CW, Collins PP, Rao AA, Wang EJ, Bandi RH, Choe BJ, Epel ES, Epstein SK, Krasnoff JB, Lee MB, Lee SW, Lopez GM, Mehta A, Melville LD, Moon TS, Mujica-Parodi LR, Noel KM, Orosco MA, Rideout JM, Robishaw JD, Rodriguez RM, Shah KH, Siegal JH, Gupta A, Altintas I, Smarr BL. Detection of COVID-19 using multimodal data from a wearable device: results from the first tempredict study. Sci Rep. 2022;12:3463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-07314-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35236896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altini M, Kinnunen H. The promise of sleep: A Multi-Sensor approach for accurate sleep stage detection using the Oura ring. Sensors. 2021;21:4302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21134302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8271886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34201861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum A. Freestyle libre glucose monitoring system. Clin Diabetes Publ Am Diabetes Assoc. 2018;36:203&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/cd17-0130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5898159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29686463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNair D. Manual for the profile of mood States. Educ Ind Test Serv. 1971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kentt&#xe4; G, Hassm&#xe9;n P, Raglin JS. Mood state monitoring of training and recovery in elite kayakers. Eur J Sport Sci. 2006;6:245&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461390601012652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie CJ, Terry PC, Lane AM. The profile of mood States and athletic performance: two meta-analyses. J Appl Sport Psychol. 2000;12:49&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10413200008404213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leunes A, Burger J. Profile of mood States research in sport and exercise psychology: Past, Present, and future. J Appl Sport Psychol. 2000;12:5&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10413200008404210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lochbaum M, Zanatta T, Kirschling D, May E. The profile of moods States and athletic performance: A Meta-Analysis of published studies. Eur J Investig Health Psychol Educ. 2021;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34542449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renger R. A review of the profile of mood States (POMS) in the prediction of athletic success. J Appl Sport Psychol. 1993;5:78&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10413209308411306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowley AJ, Landers DM, Kyllo LB, Etnier JL. Does the Iceberg Profile Discriminate between Successful and Less Successful Athletes? A Meta-Analysis. 1995. 10.1123/jsep.17.2.185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattsson CM, Larsen F. Pulstr&#xe4;ning. SISU idrottsb&#xf6;cker, Stockholm, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, Gottschall L, Hrovatin LA, Parker S, Doleshal P, Dodge C. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15:109&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H-G, Cheon E-J, Bai D-S, Lee YH, Koo B-H. Stress and heart rate variability: A Meta-Analysis and review of the literature. Psychiatry Investig. 2018;15:235&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30773/pi.2017.08.17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5900369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29486547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhshi B, Sultana N, Lin H, Fei D, Vallejo V, Gatanti A, Steenkamp DW, Murabito JM, McKeown NM, Walker ME, Spartano NL. Associations of diet composition and quality with continuous glucose monitor-derived glycemic metrics in a community-based cohort. Am J Clin Nutr. 2025;122:942&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajcnut.2025.07.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12495531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40749968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecksteden A, Kraushaar J, Scharhag-Rosenberger F, Theisen D, Senn S, Meyer T. Individual response to exercise training - a statistical perspective. J Appl Physiol Bethesda Md 1985. 2015;118:1450&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25663672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothschild JA, Stewart T, Kilding AE, Plews DJ. Predicting daily recovery during long-term endurance training using machine learning analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024. 10.1007/s00421-024-05530-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-024-05530-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11519101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38900201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Vincent GE, Duffield R, Roach GD, Halson SL, Heales LJ, Sargent C. Can sleep be used as an indicator of overreaching and overtraining in athletes? Front Physiol. 2018;9:436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.00436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5928142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiviniemi AM, Hautala AJ, Kinnunen H, Tulppo MP. Endurance training guided individually by daily heart rate variability measurements. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101:743&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0552-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17849143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montull L, Slap&#x161;inskait&#x117;-Dackevi&#x10d;ien&#x117; A, Kiely J, Hristovski R. Balagu&#xe9;, N. Integrative proposals of sports monitoring: subjective outperforms objective monitoring. Sports Med - Open. 2022;8:41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00432-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35348932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Halson SL, Mujika I. Overtraining syndrome symptoms and diagnosis in athletes: where is the research? A systematic review. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17:675&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35320774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellinger P. Functional overreaching in endurance athletes: A necessity or cause for concern? Sports Med. 2020;50:1059&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01269-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32064575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Jeukendrup AE. Does overtraining exist? An analysis of overreaching and overtraining research. Sports Med. 2004;34:967&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200434140-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15571428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinton PA, Hemingway BS, Saunders B, Gualano B, Dolan E. A statistical framework to interpret individual response to intervention: paving the way for personalized nutrition and exercise prescription. Front Nutr. 2018;5:41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2018.00041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5985399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29892599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB. New Horizons for the Methodology and Physiology of Training Periodization. Sports Med.2010 ;40(3):189&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20199119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achten J, Jeukendrup AE. Heart rate monitoring: applications and limitations. Sports Med. 2003;33:517&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200333070-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12762827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subar AF, Kipnis V, Troiano RP, Midthune D, Schoeller DA, Bingham S, Sharbaugh CO, Trabulsi J, Runswick S, Ballard-Barbash R, Sunshine J, Schatzkin A. Using intake biomarkers to evaluate the extent of dietary misreporting in a large sample of adults: the OPEN study. Am J Epidemiol. 2003;158:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwg092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12835280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, D&#xfc;king P, Leppich R, Holmberg H-C. Strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats associated with the application of artificial intelligence in connection with sport research, coaching, and optimization of athletic performance: a brief SWOT analysis. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1258562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2023.1258562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10618674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37920303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty C, Baldwin M, Lambe R, Altini M, Caulfield B. Privacy in consumer wearable technologies: a living systematic analysis of data policies across leading manufacturers. Npj Digit Med. 2025;8:363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-025-01757-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12167361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40517175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>