<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31469710</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Sleep Deprivation on Acute Skeletal Muscle Recovery after Exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>507</StartPage><EndPage>514</EndPage><MedlinePgn>507-514</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002137</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">Sleep is considered essential for muscle recovery, mainly due to its effect on hormone secretion. Total sleep deprivation or restriction is known to alter not only blood hormones but also cytokines that might be related to skeletal muscle recovery. This study aimed to evaluate whether total sleep deprivation after eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage (EEIMD) modifies the profiles of blood hormones and cytokines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In two separate conditions, with a crossover and randomized model, 10 men (age, 24.5 &#xb1; 2.9 yr; body mass index, 22.7 &#xb1; 2.3 kg&#xb7;m) performed a unilateral EEIMD protocol that comprised 240 eccentric contractions of the knee extensor muscles using an isokinetic dynamometer. In one condition, a "muscle damage" protocol was followed by 48 h of total sleep deprivation and 12 h of normal sleep (DEPRIVATION). In the other condition, the same muscle damage protocol was conducted, followed by three nights of regular sleep (SLEEP). Isometric muscle voluntary contraction tests and blood samples were collected serially throughout the protocol and analyzed for creatine kinase, free and total testosterone, IGF-1, cortisol, tumor necrosis factor-alpha, interleukin (IL)-1beta, IL-6, receptor antagonist of IL-1 and IL-10.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Muscle voluntary contraction and serum creatine kinase increased equally over the study period in both conditions. From the cytokines evaluated, only IL-6 increased in DEPRIVATION. No differences were detected in testosterone levels between conditions, but IGF-1, cortisol, and cortisol/total testosterone ratio were higher in DEPRIVATION.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Total sleep deprivation after EEIMD does not delay muscle strength recovery but modifies inflammatory and hormonal responses.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#xe1;ttilo</LastName><ForeName>Murilo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychobiology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antunes</LastName><ForeName>Hanna Karen Moreira</ForeName><Initials>HKM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, Santos, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galbes</LastName><ForeName>Nadine Marques Nunes</ForeName><Initials>NMN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Universidade de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xf4;nico-Neto</LastName><ForeName>Marcos</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychobiology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE S&#xe1; Souza</LastName><ForeName>Helton</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychobiology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dos Santos Quaresma</LastName><ForeName>Marcus Vin&#xed;cius L&#xfa;cio</ForeName><Initials>MVL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychobiology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Kil Sun</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugrinowitsch</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, Universidade de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tufik</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychobiology, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE Mello</LastName><ForeName>Marco T&#xfa;lio</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C508603">IL6R protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019947">Receptors, Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014409">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XMK78S47O</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013739">Testosterone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.3.2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003402">Creatine Kinase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WI4X0X7BPJ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006854">Hydrocortisone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003402" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine Kinase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006854" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrocortisone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007717" MajorTopicYN="N">Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019947" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Interleukin-6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012892" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Deprivation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013739" MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014409" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31469710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202002000-00028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hobson JA. Sleep is of the brain, by the brain and for the brain. Nature. 2005;437(7063):1254&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanHelder T, Symons JD, Radomski MW. Effects of sleep deprivation and exercise on glucose tolerance. Aviat Space Environ Med. 1993;64(6):487&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua EC, Shui G, Cazenave-Gassiot A, et al. Changes in plasma lipids during exposure to total sleep deprivation. Sleep. 2015;38(11):1683&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gangwisch JE. A review of evidence for the link between sleep duration and hypertension. Am J Hypertens. 2014;27(10):1235&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel K, Tasali E, Penev P, et al. Brief communication: sleep curtailment in healthy young men is associated with decreased leptin levels, elevated ghrelin levels, and increased hunger and appetite. Ann Intern Med. 2004;141(11):846&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penev PD. Sleep deprivation and energy metabolism: to sleep, perchance to eat? Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes. 2007;14(5):374&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leproult R, Van Cauter E. Role of sleep and sleep loss in hormonal release and metabolism. Endocr Dev. 2010;17:11&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos RV, Tufik S, De Mello MT. Exercise, sleep and cytokines: is there a relation? Sleep Med Rev. 2007;11(3):231&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanHelder T, Radomski MW. Sleep deprivation and the effect on exercise performance. Sports Med. 1989;7(4):235&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, et al. Sleep and athletic performance: the effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45(2):161&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes HK, Medeiros A, et al. Sleep and muscle recovery: endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothesis. Med Hypotheses. 2011;77(2):220&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes HK, Medeiros A, et al. Paradoxical sleep deprivation induces muscle atrophy. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45(3):431&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de S&#xe1; Souza H, Antunes HK, D&#xe1;ttilo M, et al. Leucine supplementation is anti-atrophic during paradoxical sleep deprivation in rats. Amino Acids. 2016;48(4):949&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf4;nico-Neto M, D&#xe1;ttilo M, Ribeiro DA, et al. REM sleep deprivation impairs muscle regeneration in rats. Growth Factors. 2017;35(1):12&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chase JD, Roberson PA, Saunders MJ, Hargens TA, Womack CJ, Luden ND. One night of sleep restriction following heavy exercise impairs 3-km cycling time-trial performance in the morning. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42(9):909&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rae DE, Chin T, Dikgomo K, et al. One night of partial sleep deprivation impairs recovery from a single exercise training session. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(4):699&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everson CA, Crowley WR. Reductions in circulating anabolic hormones induced by sustained sleep deprivation in rats. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;286(6):E1060&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaton LJ, Allan DA, Tarnopolsky MA, et al. Contraction-induced muscle damage is unaffected by vitamin E supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(5):798&#x2013;805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd ed. Hillsdale (NJ): Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; 1988. p. 567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proske U, Morgan DL. Muscle damage from eccentric exercise: mechanism, mechanical signs, adaptation and clinical applications. J Physiol. 2001;537(Pt 2):333&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frid&#xe9;n J, Lieber RL. Serum creatine kinase level is a poor predictor of muscle function after injury. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2001;11(2):126&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Nosaka K, Libardi CA, et al. Susceptibility to exercise-induced muscle damage: a cluster analysis with a large sample. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37(8):633&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Mikkelsen UR, Raastad T, et al. Leucocytes, cytokines and satellite cells: what role do they play in muscle damage and regeneration following eccentric exercise? Exerc Immunol Rev. 2012;18:42&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael DJ, Valle B, Cox J, Kalns JE, Fogt DL. Salivary biomarkers of physical fatigue as markers of sleep deprivation. J Clin Sleep Med. 2013;9(12):1325&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orze&#x142;-Gryglewska J. Consequences of sleep deprivation. Int J Occup Med Environ Health. 2010;23(1):95&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley MI, Kilduff LP, McEneny J, et al. Phosphatidylserine supplementation and recovery following downhill running. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(9):1617&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips T, Childs AC, Dreon DM, et al. A dietary supplement attenuates IL-6 and CRP after eccentric exercise in untrained males. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(12):2032&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toft AD, Jensen LB, Bruunsgaard H, et al. Cytokine response to eccentric exercise in young and elderly humans. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2002;283(1):C289&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross ML, Halson SL, Suzuki K, et al. Cytokine responses to carbohydrate ingestion during recovery from exercise-induced muscle injury. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2010;30(5):329&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Benestad HB, Str&#xf8;m-Gundersen I, et al. Delayed leukocytosis and cytokine response to high-force eccentric exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(11):1877&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, McFarlin B, Bois C. Interleukin-6 expression after repeated bouts of eccentric exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2003;24(1):15&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croisier JL, Camus G, Venneman I, et al. Effects of training on exercise-induced muscle damage and interleukin 6 production. Muscle Nerve. 1999;22(2):208&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shearer WT, Reuben JM, Mullington JM, et al. Soluble TNF-alpha receptor 1 and IL-6 plasma levels in humans subjected to the sleep deprivation model of spaceflight. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2001;107(1):165&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vgontzas AN, Papanicolaou DA, Bixler EO, et al. Circadian interleukin-6 secretion and quantity and depth of sleep. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1999;84(8):2603&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano AL, Baeza-Raja B, Perdiguero E, et al. Interleukin-6 is an essential regulator of satellite cell-mediated skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell Metab. 2008;7(1):33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narsale AA, Carson JA. Role of interleukin-6 in cachexia: therapeutic implications. Curr Opin Support Palliat Care. 2014;8(4):321&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luke A, Lazaro RM, Bergeron MF, et al. Sports-related injuries in youth athletes: is overscheduling a risk factor? Clin J Sport Med. 2011;21(4):307&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel K, Leproult R, Colecchia EF, et al. Adaptation of the 24-h growth hormone profile to a state of sleep debt. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2000;279(3):R874&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenberger G, Gronfier C, Chapotot F, et al. Effect of sleep deprivation on overall 24 h growth-hormone secretion. Lancet. 2000;356(9239):1408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauvet F, Drogou C, Bougard C, et al. Vascular response to 1 week of sleep restriction in healthy subjects. A metabolic response? Int J Cardiol. 2015;190:246&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med. 2005;35(4):339&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jauch-Chara K, Schmid SM, Hallschmid M, et al. Pituitary-gonadal and pituitary-thyroid axis hormone concentrations before and during a hypoglycemic clamp after sleep deprivation in healthy men. PLoS One. 2013;8(1):e54209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leproult R, Van Cauter E. Effect of 1 week of sleep restriction on testosterone levels in young healthy men. JAMA. 2011;305(21):2173&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Kujbida GW, Moore DR, et al. Resistance exercise-induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J Physiol. 2009;587(Pt 21):5239&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyon A, Balbo M, Morselli LL, et al. Adverse effects of two nights of sleep restriction on the hypothalamic&#x2013;pituitary&#x2013;adrenal axis in healthy men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014;99(8):2861&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel K, Leproult R, Van Cauter E. Impact of sleep debt on metabolic and endocrine function. Lancet. 1999;354(9188):1435&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leproult R, Copinschi G, Buxton O, et al. Sleep loss results in an elevation of cortisol levels the next evening. Sleep. 1997;20(10):865&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid SM, Hallschmid M, Jauch-Chara K, et al. Disturbed glucoregulatory response to food intake after moderate sleep restriction. Sleep. 2011;34(3):371&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willenberg HS, P&#xe4;th G, V&#xf6;geli TA, et al. Role of interleukin-6 in stress response in normal and tumorous adrenal cells and during chronic inflammation. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2002;966:304&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urhausen A, Gabriel H, Kindermann W. Blood hormones as markers of training stress and overtraining. Sports Med. 1995;20(4):251&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>