<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37316185</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-0480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rest and exercise early after sport-related concussion: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>762</StartPage><EndPage>770</EndPage><MedlinePgn>762-770</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106676</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To synthesise the evidence regarding the risks and benefits of physical activity (PA), prescribed aerobic exercise treatment, rest, cognitive activity and sleep during the first 14 days after sport-related concussion (SRC).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Meta-analysis was performed for PA/prescribed exercise interventions and a narrative synthesis for rest, cognitive activity and sleep. Risk of bias (ROB) was determined using the Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network and quality assessed using Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development and Evaluations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">MEDLINE, Embase, APA PsycInfo, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, CINAHL Plus and SPORTDiscus. Searches were conducted in October 2019 and updated in March 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA" NlmCategory="METHODS">Original research articles with sport-related mechanism of injury in &gt;50% of study sample and that evaluated how PA, prescribed exercise, rest, cognitive activity and/or sleep impact recovery following SRC. Reviews, conference proceedings, commentaries, editorials, case series, animal studies and articles published before 1 January 2001 were excluded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">46 studies were included and 34 had acceptable/low ROB. Prescribed exercise was assessed in 21 studies, PA in 15 studies (6 PA/exercise studies also assessed cognitive activity), 2 assessed cognitive activity only and 9 assessed sleep. In a meta-analysis of seven studies, PA and prescribed exercise improved recovery by a mean of -4.64 days (95% CI -6.69, -2.59). After SRC, early return to light PA (initial 2 days), prescribed aerobic exercise treatment (days 2-14) and reduced screen use (initial 2 days) safely facilitate recovery. Early prescribed aerobic exercise also reduces delayed recovery, and sleep disturbance is associated with slower recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Early PA, prescribed aerobic exercise and reduced screen time are beneficial following SRC. Strict physical rest until symptom resolution is not effective, and sleep disturbance impairs recovery after SRC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROSPERO REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">CRD42020158928.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2023. No commercial re-use. See rights and permissions. Published by BMJ.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leddy</LastName><ForeName>John J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0370-1289</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UBMD Department of Orthopaedics and Sports Medicine, SUNY Buffalo Jacobs School of Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, Buffalo, NY, USA leddy@buffalo.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burma</LastName><ForeName>Joel S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9756-5793</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toomey</LastName><ForeName>Clodagh M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Allied Health, Faculty of Education and Health Sciences, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayden</LastName><ForeName>Alix</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Libraries and Cultural Resources, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Gavin A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8293-4496</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babl</LastName><ForeName>Franz E</ForeName><Initials>FE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1107-2187</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Department, Royal Children's Hospital, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gagnon</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma Center and Pediatric Emergency Medicine, Montreal Children's Hospital- McGill University Health Center, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giza</LastName><ForeName>Christopher C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosurgery, UCLA Steve Tisch BrainSPORT Program, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics/Pediatric Neurology, UCLA Mattel Children's Hospital, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurowski</LastName><ForeName>Brad G</ForeName><Initials>BG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Pediatrics, Neurology and Rehabilitation Medicine, Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center and University of Cincinnati College of Medicine, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silverberg</LastName><ForeName>Noah D</ForeName><Initials>ND</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6378-148X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of British Columbia, Voncouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willer</LastName><ForeName>Barry</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, SUNY Buffalo Jacobs School of Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, Buffalo, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ronksley</LastName><ForeName>Paul E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Health Sciences, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5951-5899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Injury Prevention Research Centre, Faculty of Kinesiology; Hotchkiss Brain Institute, Alberta Children's Hospital Research Institute, Sport Medicine Centre, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0432520</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0306-3674</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="N">Rest</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Concussion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rest</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: JJL receives grant/research support from NIH, DoD and AMSSM. He is a member of the Scientific Advisory Boards for Neuronasal, Highmark Innovations and Quadrant Biosciences; has minority stock options in Highmark Innovations and 360 Concussion Care; is an expert consultant to NCAA; consults with NFL and NHL teams on athlete care but does not receive any compensation from these organisations. GAD is an honorary member of the AFL Concussion Scientific Committee and has attended meetings organised by sporting organisations including the NFL, NRL, IIHF and FIFA; however, he has not received any payment, research funding or other monies from these groups other than for travel costs. BW receives grant/research support from NIH, DoD and AMSSM. NDS receives clinical consulting fees from the National Hockey League and Major League Soccer. BGK receives grant support from NIH. IG receives funding from Fonds de la recherche du Qu&#xe9;bec&#x2013;Sant&#xe9;; Canadian Institutes of Health Research; Research Institute of the McGill University Health Center; School of Physical and Occupational Therapy, McGill University. CCG receives grant/research support from Hit-IQ (2022&#x2013;2023); NIH NINDS (R01 NS110757 2019&#x2013;2024); NINDS (U54 NS121688 2021&#x2013;2026); UCLA Brain Injury Research Center, UCLA Steve Tisch BrainSPORT Program, Easton Clinic for Brain Health; a clinical consultant (provides clinical care to athletes) for NBA, NFL-Neurological Care Program, NHL/NHLPA, Los Angeles Lakers; a member of the Advisory Boards (non-compensated) for Major League Soccer, National Basketball Association and US Soccer Federation, as well as Advisory Boards (stock shareholder) for Highmark Interactive; other financial or material support: book royalties&#x2014;Blackwell/Wiley Publishing: prioritised neurological differential diagnosis. KJS is a lead and coinvestigator on grants related to concussion and traumatic brain injury funded by several governments or other organisations (including but not limited to the Canadian Institutes of Health Research, Canadian Academy of Sport and Exercise Medicine, National Football League Scientific Advisory Board, Public Health Agency of Canada/Parachute Canada, Hotchkiss Brain Institute, Wellcome Trust, International Olympic Committee, Highmark Innovations, Mitacs Accelerate, University of Calgary), with funds paid to her institution and not to her personally. She is an associate professor and clinician scientist at the University of Calgary in the Sport Injury Prevention Research Centre and is a physiotherapy consultant, primarily working with patients with concussion and traumatic brain injuries. She is an associate editor of BJSM (unpaid) and has received travel and accommodation support for meetings where she has presented. She is coordinating the writing of the systematic reviews that will inform the 6th International Consensus on Concussion in Sport, for which she has received an educational grant to assist with the administrative costs associated with the writing of the reviews. She is a member of the Scientific Advisory Board for Eye Guide (share options), and member of the AFL Concussion Scientific Committee (unpaid position) and Brain Canada (unpaid position).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37316185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">57/12/762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>