<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40297077</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-061X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthroscopy, sports medicine, and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep Quality and Cognitive Skills Impact Neurocognitive Function and Reduce Sports-Related Injury Risk.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101077</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101077</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101077</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.asmr.2025.101077</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Injury prevention in sports is critically influenced by cognitive factors, particularly sleep quality and cognitive skills. Research has underscored the role of cognitive processes in injury risk and recovery, highlighting that inadequate sleep and poor cognitive functioning can significantly elevate injury susceptibility. Despite the well-documented benefits of adequate sleep and cognitive training in mitigating injury risk, access to sports psychology expertise is limited among athletes and health care providers. This work reviews the literature on the effectiveness of cognitive skills and sleep training in reducing sports-related injuries. Sleep affects musculoskeletal recovery, cognitive function, and immune response, which may further exacerbate injury risk. Neurobiological processes during sleep are crucial for muscle repair, cognitive function, and immune efficiency, all of which are integral to reducing the injury risk in athletes. Environmental factors such as travel schedules, training intensity, and competitive pressures disrupt sleep and increase the risk of injury. Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Insomnia has shown promise in addressing sleep disturbances by improving sleep habits and addressing cognitive distress related to sleep. In addition, cognitive skills training, including mental skills training and mindfulness, enhances perceptual awareness, decision making, and reaction times, potentially reducing injury incidence by improving cognitive and motor function. Evidence supports the pivotal role of sleep and cognitive skills in preventing sports injuries. Interventions like Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Insomnia and mental skills training can effectively address these factors, suggesting that integrating these approaches into athlete training programs could significantly enhance injury prevention strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Level V, expert opinion.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haskell</LastName><ForeName>Brett</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Women's Soccer League, Chicago, Illinois, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eiler</LastName><ForeName>Abigail</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Michigan School of Social Work, Ann Arbor, Michigan, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Essien</LastName><ForeName>Haven</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Michigan, School of Social Work, Ann Arbor, Michigan, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101765256</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-061X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>All authors (B.H., A.E., H.E.) declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40297077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12034071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmr.2025.101077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-061X(25)00003-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vorster A.P.A., Erlacher D., Birrer D., R&#xf6;thlin P. Sleep difficulties in Swiss elite athletes. Life. 2024;14:779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11204926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38929761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahdur K., Pruna R., Erasmus H., Pedret C. Does cognition play a role in injury prevention and return to play in the elite football player? A perspective from the field. Apunts Med Esport. 2018;53:125&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H.H., Skorski S., Duffield R., Hammes D., Coutts A.J., Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: The effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45:161&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25315456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha L.A., Costa J.A., Marques E.A., Brito J., Lastella M., Figueiredo P. The impact of sleep interventions on athletic performance: A systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2023;9:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10354314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCAA. NCAA Health and Wellness Study  2022-2023. Indianapolis, IN: NCAA. https://ncaaorg.s3.amazonaws.com/research/wellness/Dec2023RES_HW-MentalHealthRelease.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NCAA. NCAA GOALS Study  Indianapolis, IN: NCAA; 2020. 2019. https://ncaaorg.s3.amazonaws.com/research/goals/2020AWRES_GOALS2020con.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C.D., Kezirian E.J., Marcello B.M., Dement W.C. Poor sleep quality and insufficient sleep of a collegiate student-athlete population. Sleep Health. 2018;4:251&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29776619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox J.L., Scanlan A.T., Stanton R., Sargent C. Insufficient sleep in young athletes? Causes, consequences, and potential treatments. Sports Med. 2020;50:461&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31679145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts S.S.H., Teo W.P., Warmington S.A. Effects of training and competition on the sleep of elite athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:513&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30217831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh N.P., Halson S.L., Sargent C., et al. Sleep and the athlete: Narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:356&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlin M.J., Deuchrass R.W., Olsen P.D., et al. The effect of sleep quality and quantity on athlete's health and perceived training quality. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34568820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva A., Narciso F.V., Soalheiro I., et al. Poor sleep quality's association with soccer injuries: Preliminary data. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15:671&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang K., Ihm J. Sleep and injury risk. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2021;20:286&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34099605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charest J., Grandner M.A. Sleep and athletic performance: Impacts on physical performance, mental performance, injury risk and recovery, and mental health: An update. Sleep Med Clin. 2022;17:263&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35659079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski M.D., Skaggs D.L., Bishop G.A., et al. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. J&#xa0;Pediatr Orthop. 2014;34:129&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson N.F., Badr M.S., Belenky G., et al. Recommended amount of sleep for a healthy adult: A joint consensus statement of the American Academy of Sleep Medicine and Sleep Research Society. J&#xa0;Clin Sleep Med. 2015;11:591&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25979105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paruthi S., Brooks L.J., D'Ambrosio C., et al. Consensus statement of the American Academy of Sleep Medicine on the recommended amount of sleep for healthy children: Methodology and discussion. J&#xa0;Clin Sleep Med. 2016;12:1549&#x2013;1561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5078711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochoa-L&#xe1;car J., Singh M., Bird S.P., Charest J., Huyghe T., Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. How sleep affects recovery and performance in basketball: A systematic review. Brain Sci. 2022;12:1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9688068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36421894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekaran B., Fernandes S., Davis F. Science of sleep and sports performance&#x2014;a scoping review. Sci Sports. 2020;35:3&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kj&#xe6;r M., Doessing S., Mj&#xf8;sund Kp. The encyclopaedia of sports medicine: An IOC Medical Commission Publication, The Olympic textbook of medicine in sport. 1st ed. Vol 14. Wiley-Blackwell; Oxford, UK: 2009. Endocrine adaptations to training; p. 87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillard T. Detrimental effects of sleep deprivation on the regulatory mechanisms of postural balance: A comprehensive review. Front Hum Neurosci. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10133494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37124366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty R., Madigan S.M., Nevill A., Warrington G., Ellis J.G. The sleep and recovery practices of athletes. Nutrients. 2021;13:1330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8072992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel J.M. The REM sleep-memory consolidation hypothesis. Science. 2001;294:1058&#x2013;1063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8760621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11691984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith C.T., Aubrey J.B., Peters K.R. Different roles for REM and stage 2 sleep in motor learning: A proposed model. Psychol Belg. 2004;44:81&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemm W.R. Why does rem sleep occur? A wake-up hypothesis. Front Syst Neurosci. 2011;5:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3166790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21922003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killgore W.D., Balkin T.J., Wesensten N.J. Impaired decision making following 49 h of sleep deprivation. J&#xa0;Sleep Res. 2006;15:7&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16489997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grewal S., Theijse R.T., Dunlop G., et al. Exploring the impact of sleep on emotional and physical well-being in professional cricketers: A cohort study over an in-season training period. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11187254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38903388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook J.D., Charest J. Sleep and performance in professional athletes. Curr Sleep Med Rep. 2023;9:56&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9843114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36683842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossa K.R., Smith S.S., Allan A.C., Sullivan K.A. The effects of sleep restriction on executive inhibitory control and affect in young adults. J&#xa0;Adolesc Health. 2014;55:287&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24602612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besedovsky L., Lange T., Born J. Sleep and immune function. Pflugers Arch. 2012;463:121&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3256323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22071480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinali D., Esquifino A. Sleep and the immune system. Curr Immunol Rev. 2012;8:50&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S.L. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44:13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H., Banihashemi M., Saedmocheshi S., Prieto-Gonz&#xe1;lez P., Oliveira R. Overview of the impact of sleep monitoring on optimal performance, immune system function and injury risk reduction in athletes: A narrative review. Sci Prog. 2023;106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10666701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37990537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels C.H. Jet lag and travel fatigue: A comprehensive management plan for sport medicine physicians and high-performance support teams. Clin J Sport Med. 2012;22:268&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22450594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charest J., Grandner M.A. Sleep and athletic performance: Impacts on physical performance, mental performance, injury risk and recovery, and mental health. Sleep Med Clin. 2020;15:41&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9960533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32005349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti E., Carroll L.M. Psychology of performance. Curr Otorhinolaryngol Rep. 2023;11:381&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandner M. Elsevier Science; London: 2019. Sleep and health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin C.M., Espie C.A. Springer; New York, NY: 2003. Insomnia: A clinical guide to assessment and treatment.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bootzin R.R., Epstein D.R. Understanding and treating insomnia. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2011;7:435&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17716026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnet M.H., Arand D.L. Hyperarousal and insomnia: State of the science. Sleep Med Rev. 2010;14:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19640748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandner M., Athey A.B. Academic Press; London: 2024. Sleep and sport: physical performance, mental performance, injury prevention, and competitive advantage for athletes, coaches, and trainers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miglis M.G. Autonomic dysfunction in primary sleep disorders. Sleep Med. 2016;19:40&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27198946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink A.M., Bronas U.G., Calik M.W. Autonomic regulation during sleep and wakefulness: A review with implications for defining the pathophysiology of neurological disorders. Clin Auton Res. 2018;28:509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6542468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30155794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams J., Roth A., Vatthauer K., McCrae C.S. Cognitive behavioral treatment of insomnia. Chest. 2013;143:554&#x2013;565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4694188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23381322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin C.M., B&#xe9;langer L. In: Behavioral treatments for sleep disorders. Perlis M., Aloia M., Kuhn B., editors. Academic Press; London: 2011. Cognitive therapy for dysfunctional beliefs about sleep and insomnia; pp. 107&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes Dos Santos M., Uftring M., Stahl C.A., et al. Stress in academic and athletic performance in collegiate athletes: A narrative review of sources and monitoring strategies. Front Sports Act Living. 2020;2:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron K.G., Abbott S., Jao N., Manalo N., Mullen R. Orthosomnia: Are some patients taking the quantified self too far? J&#xa0;Clin Sleep Med. 2017;13:351&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5263088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27855740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edinger J.D., Arnedt J.T., Bertisch S.M., et al. Behavioral and psychological treatments for chronic insomnia disorder in adults: An American Academy of Sleep Medicine clinical practice guideline. J&#xa0;Clin Sleep Med. 2021;17:255&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33164742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrich A., Schlarb A.A. Let's talk about sleep: A systematic review of psychological interventions to improve sleep in college students. J&#xa0;Sleep Res. 2018;27:4&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28618185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M., Lovell G.P., Sargent C. Athletes' precompetitive sleep behaviour and its relationship with subsequent precompetitive mood and performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(suppl 1):S123&#x2013;S130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S., Buxton O.M., Andel R., Almeida D.M. Bidirectional associations of sleep with cognitive interference in employees' work days. Sleep Health. 2019;5:298&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11487484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30905693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H., Jung H.R., Kim J.B., Kim D.J. Autonomic dysfunction in sleep disorders: From neurobiological basis to potential therapeutic approaches. J&#xa0;Clin Neurol. 2022;18:140&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35274834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma M.P., Andrade C. Behavioral interventions for insomnia: Theory and practice. Indian J Psychiatry. 2012;54:359&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3554970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23372241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker J., Muench A., Perlis M.L., Vargas I. Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Insomnia (CBT-I): A primer. Klin Spec Psihol. 2022;11:123&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10002474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36908717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter L., Reindl R., Zauter S., Hillemacher T., Richter K. Effectiveness of an Online CBT-I Intervention and a face-to-face treatment for shift work sleep disorder: A comparison of sleep diary data. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16:3081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6747089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31450619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson N.S., Gibbs E.L., Matheson G.O. Optimizing sleep to maximize performance: Implications and recommendations for elite athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27:266&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27367265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann D.T., Williams A.M., Ward P., Janelle C.M. Perceptual-cognitive expertise in sport: A meta-analysis. J&#xa0;Sport Exerc Psychol. 2007;29:457&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17968048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams M., Wigmore T. Nicholas Brealey; London: 2021. The best: How elite athletes are made.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Wouw A. Advocating a holistic approach for sport injury prevention and rehabilitation. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:895&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37019604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grooms D.R., Onate J.A. Neuroscience application to noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injury prevention. Sports Health. 2016;8:149&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26608453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ericksen S., Dover G., DeMont R. Psychological interventions can reduce injury risk in athletes: A critically appraised topic. J&#xa0;Sport Rehabil. 2022;31:224&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34525450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams A.M., Ford P.R., Eccles D.W., Ward P. Perceptual-cognitive expertise in sport and its acquisition: Implications for applied cognitive psychology. Appl Cogn Psychol. 2011;25:432&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Corrado D., Guarnera M., Guerrera C.S., et al. Mental imagery skills in competitive young athletes and non-athletes. Front Psychol. 2020;11:633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7180224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumming J., Williams S.E. University of Oxford; Oxford, England: 2012. The role of imagery in performance.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank C., Land W.M., Popp C., Schack T. Mental representation and mental practice: experimental investigation on the functional links between motor memory and motor imagery. PLoS One. 2014;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3990621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24743576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faubert J., Sidebottom L. Perceptual-cognitive training of athletes. J&#xa0;Clin Sport Psychol. 2012;6:85&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanik C.B., Covassin T., Stearne D.J., Schatz P. The relationship between neurocognitive function and noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:943&#x2013;948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17369562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke J., Groneberg D.A. Neurocognitive function and musculoskeletal injury risk in sports: A systematic review. J&#xa0;Sci Med Sport. 2022;25:41&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34303619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson U., Ivarsson A. Psychosocial factors and sport injuries: Prediction, prevention and future research directions. Curr Opin Psychol. 2017;16:89&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28813363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivarsson A., Johnson U., Andersen M.B., Tranaeus U., Stenling A., Lindwall M. Psychosocial factors and sport injuries: Meta-analyses for prediction and prevention. Sports Med. 2017;47:353&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27406221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiche E., Lam K., Genoese F., Baez S. Integrating mindfulness to reduce injury rates in athletes: A critically appraised topic. Int J Athl Ther Training. 2023;28:291&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha A. Hachette UK; London: 2021. Peak mind: Find your focus, own your attention, invest 12 minutes a day.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feltz D.L., Ewing M.E. Psychological characteristics of elite young athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1987;19(5 suppl):S98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3316919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams A.M., Reilly T. Talent identification and development in soccer. J&#xa0;Sports Sci. 2000;18:657&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11043892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett T.J., Carius J., Mulvey M. Does improved decision-making ability reduce the physiological demands of game-based activities in field sport athletes? J&#xa0;Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:2027&#x2013;2035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vealey R.S. Conceptualization of sport-confidence and competitive orientation: preliminary investigation and instrument development. J&#xa0;Sport Exerc Psychol. 1986;8:221&#x2013;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yerkes R.M., Dodson J.D. The relation of strength of stimulus to rapidity of habit-formation. J&#xa0;Comp Neurol Psychol. 1908;18:459&#x2013;482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaccaro A., Piarulli A., Laurino M., et al. How breath-control can change your life: A systematic review on psycho-physiological correlates of slow breathing. Front Hum Neurosci. 2018;12:353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6137615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30245619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganguly A., Hulke S.M., Bharshanakar R., Parashar R., Wakode S. Effect of meditation on autonomic function in healthy individuals: A longitudinal study. J&#xa0;Family Med Prim Care. 2020;9:3944&#x2013;3948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7586536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33110791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker M.P. The role of sleep in cognition and emotion. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2009;1156:168&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19338508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett T.J., Jenkins D.G. Relationship between training load and injury in professional rugby league players. J&#xa0;Sci Med Sport. 2011;14:204&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21256078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>