<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28674597</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep-hygiene Education improves Sleep Indices in Elite Female Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>522</StartPage><EndPage>530</EndPage><MedlinePgn>522-530</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The importance of sleep in providing psychophysiological recovery in elite athletes is often overlooked. In other populations (eg shift workers and adolescent students), sleep hygiene education may serve to acutely improve sleep indices. However, this is yet to be examined in an elite athlete setting. Therefore, the aim of the current study was to evaluate the effect of a sleep hygiene education session on sleep indices in elite athletes. The study involved 26 elite female netball athletes performing one week of baseline sleep monitoring (PRE), followed by a sleep hygiene education session and a further week of sleep monitoring (POST) in a single group, pre- post design. The sleep hygiene education session focused on providing information on the importance of sleep for athletes and practical tips to improve sleep quality and quantity. Sleep monitoring was performed using wrist actigraphy to assess total sleep time (TST), sleep efficiency (SE%), total time in bed (TTB), sleep latency (SL), wake episodes per night (WE), sleep onset variance (SOV), wake variance (WV) wake episode duration (WED), sleep onset time (SOT), and wake time (WT). There was a significant improvement in TST (mean &#xb1; SD; 22.3 &#xb1; 39.9 minutes, p=0.01) PRE to POST sleep hygiene education session, the difference associated with a <i>small</i> effect (ES: 0.39). A significant improvement PRE to POST was found for WV (p=0.03), and for WED (p=0.03). There were no significant differences for SE%, SL, TTB, WE, SOV, SOT, WT. The current study reports that a sleep hygiene education session is effective in improving sleep quantity in elite female athletes in an acute setting.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Donnell</LastName><ForeName>Shannon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Waikato, Hamilton, NEW ZEALAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Driller</LastName><ForeName>Matthew W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Waikato, Hamilton, NEW ZEALAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">netball</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/DNOL2901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ancoli-Israel S, Cole R, Alessi C, Chambers M, Moorcroft W, Pollak C. The role of actigraphy in the study of sleep and circadian rhythms. Sleep. 2003;26(3):342&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12749557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batterham A, Hopkins W. Making meaningful inferences about magnitudes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2006;1(50):50&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Kuo H, Chueh K. Sleep hygiene education: efficacy on sleep quality in working women. J Nurs Res. 2010;18(4):283&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21139448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenne D. Sleep of athletes - problems and possible solutions. Biological Rhythm Research. 2009;40(1):45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis J, Dawson B, Heasman J, Rogalski B, Robey E. Sleep patterns and injury occurrence in elite Australian footballers. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19(2):113&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25770421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller M, McQuillan J, O&#x2019;Donnell S. Inter-device reliability of an automatic-scoring actigraph for measuring sleep in healthy adults. Sleep Sci. 2016;9(3):198&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5241607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28123660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eagles A, Mclellan C, Hing W, Carloss N, Lovell D. Changes in sleep quantity and efficiency in professional rugby union players during home based training and match-play. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2014 [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25369280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Duffield R, Skorski S, Coutts A, Julian R, Meyer T. Sleep and recovery in team sport: current sleep-related issues facing professional team-sport athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Performance. 2015;10:950&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25756787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebhart C, Erlacher D, Schredl M. Moderate exercise plus sleep education improves self-reported sleep quality, daytime mood, and vitality in adults with chronic sleep complaints: a waiting list-controlled trial. Sleep Disorders. 2011 article 809312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23471095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. Sleep and the elite athlete. Sports Sci Exchange. 2013;26(113):1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W. Spreadsheets for analysis of validity and reliability. Sports Sci. 2015;19:36&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff L, Halson S, Peiffer J. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important compeititons. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;18:13&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24629327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakinuma M, Takahashi M, Kato N, Aratake Y, Watanabe M, Ishikawa Y, Kojima R, Shibaoka M, Tanaka K. Effect of brief sleep hygiene education for workers of an information technology company. Ind Health. 2010;48:758&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20616458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacks P, Rotert M. Knowledge and practice of sleep hygiene techniques in insomniacs and good sleepers. Behav Res Ther. 1986;24(3):365&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3729908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach G, Halson S, Sargent C. Sleep/wake behaviours of elite athletes from individual and team sports. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;15(2):94&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24993935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Glaister M, Pizzoferro K, Dawson J, Pedlar C. Sleep duration and quality in elite athletes measured using wristwatch actigraphy. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(6):541&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22329779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C, Mah K, Kezirian E, Dement W. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep. 2011;34(7):943&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21731144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manber R, Bootzin R. Sleep and the menstrual cycle. Health Psychol. 1997;16(3):209&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9152698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastin D, Bryson J, Corwyn R. Assessment of sleep hygiene using the sleep hygiene index. J Behav Med. 2006;29(3):223&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16557353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCloughan L, Hanrahan S, Anderson R, Halson S. Progressive muscle relaxation (PMR), sleep, and recovery in elite performers. J Sci Med Sport. 2014;18:113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelec M, Halson S, Abaidia A, Ahmaidi S, Dupont G. Stress, sleep and recovery in elite soccer: a critical review of the literature. Sports Med. 2015;45:1387&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26206724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishinoue N, Takano T, Kaku A, Eto R, Kato N, Ono Y, Tanaka K. Effects of sleep hygiene education and behavioral therapy on sleep quality of white-collar workers: a randomized controlled trial. Industrial Health. 2012;50:123&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22293726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A. The role and validity of actigraphy in sleep medicine: an update. Sleep Med Rev. 2011;15:259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21237680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson N, Gibbs E, Matheson G. Optimizing sleep to maximize performance: implications and recommendations for elite athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;27(3):266&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27367265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa I, Araujo J, Azevedo C. The effect of a sleep hygiene education program on the sleep-wake cycle of Brazilian adolescent students. Sleep Biol Rhythms. 2007;5:251&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepanski E, Wyatt J. Use of sleep hygiene in the treatment of insomnia. Sleep Med Rev. 2003;7(3):215&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12927121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>