<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26933660</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2288-176X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does one night of partial sleep deprivation affect the evening performance during intermittent exercise in Taekwondo players?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>47</StartPage><EndPage>53</EndPage><MedlinePgn>47-53</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12965/jer.150256</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Athletes and coaches believe that adequate sleep is essential for peak performance. There is ample scientific evidence which support the conclusion that sleep loss seems to stress many physiological functions in humans. The aim of this study was to determine the effect of one night's sleep deprivation on intermittent exercise performance in the evening of the following day. Ten male Taekwondo players performed the Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test (YYIRT) in three sleep conditions (reference sleep night [RN], partial sleep deprivation at the beginning of night [PSDBN], partial sleep deprivation at the end of night [PSDEN]) in a counterbalanced order, allowing a recovery period &#x2265;36 hr in between them. Heart rate peak (HRpeak), plasma lactate concentrations (Lac) and rating of perceived exertion (RPE) were measured during the test. A significant effect of sleep restriction was observed on the total distance covered in YYIRT (P&lt;0.0005) and Lac (P&lt;0.01) in comparison with the RN. In addition, performance more decreased after PSDEN (P&lt;0.0005) than PSDBN (P&lt;0.05). Also, Lac decreased significantly only after PS-DEN (P&lt;0.05) compared with RN. However, there were no significant changes in HRpeak and RPE after the two types of partial sleep deprivation compared to RN. The present study indicates that short-term sleep restriction affect the intermittent performance, as well as the Lac levels of the Taekwondo players in the evening of the following day, without alteration of HRpeak and RPE.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mejri</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed Arbi</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimization", National Center of Medicine and Sciences in Sport (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia; Faculty of Science, Carthage University, Bizerte, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yousfi</LastName><ForeName>Narimen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimization", National Center of Medicine and Sciences in Sport (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia; High Institute of Sport and Physical Education, Ksar-Sa&#xef;d, Manouba University, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mhenni</LastName><ForeName>Thouraya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimization", National Center of Medicine and Sciences in Sport (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia; Faculty of Science, Carthage University, Bizerte, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tayech</LastName><ForeName>Amel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimization", National Center of Medicine and Sciences in Sport (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia; High Institute of Sport and Physical Education, Ksar-Sa&#xef;d, Manouba University, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammouda</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Ouest Nanterre La D&#xe9;fense, CeRSM (EA 2931), UFR STAPS, Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Driss</LastName><ForeName>Tarak</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Ouest Nanterre La D&#xe9;fense, CeRSM (EA 2931), UFR STAPS, Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaouachi</LastName><ForeName>Anis</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimization", National Center of Medicine and Sciences in Sport (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souissi</LastName><ForeName>Nizar</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimization", National Center of Medicine and Sciences in Sport (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia; National Observatory of Sport, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2288-176X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance intensive effort</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evening performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intermittent exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Taekwondo</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yo-Yo test</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26933660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4771153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.150256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jer-12-1-47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Azboy O, Kaygisiz Z. Effects of sleep deprivation on cardiorespiratory functions of the runners and volleyball players during rest and exercise. Acta Physiol Hung. 2009;96:29&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19264040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia FM, Krustrup P. The Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test: a useful tool for evaluation of physical performance in intermittent sports. Sports Med. 2008;38:37&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18081366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastuji H, Jouvet M. Int&#xe9;r&#xea;t de l&#x2019;agenda de sommeil pour l&#x2019;&#xe9;tude des troubles de la vigilance. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1985;60:299&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2579796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. The perception of physical performance. In: Shephard RJ, editor. Frontiers of fitness. Springfield (IL): CC Thomas; 1971. pp. 280&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14:377&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouhlel E, Jouinia A, Gmada N, Nefzi A, Ben Abdallah K, Tabka Z. Heart rate and blood lactate responses during Taekwondo training and competition. Sci Sports. 2006;21:285&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamari K, Padulo J. &#x2018;Aerobic&#x2019; and &#x2018;Anaerobic&#x2019; terms used in exercise physiology: a critical terminology reflection. Sport Med - Open. 2015;1:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5016084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27747843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HI. Effects of 30-h sleep loss on cardiorespiratory functions at rest and in exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1991;23:193&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1901933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Hammouda O, Aloui A, Souissi N. Effect of time-of-day on muscle fatigue: a review. J Nov Physiother. 2013;3:160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenne D. Sleep of athletes-problems and possible solutions. Biol Rhythm Res. 2009;40:45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman J, Radomski M, Hart L, Plyley M, Shephard RJ. Maximal aerobic exercise following prolonged sleep deprivation. Int J Sports Med. 1989;10:419&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2628360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammouda O, Chahed H, Chtourou H, Ferchichi S, Miled A, Souissi N. Morning-to-evening difference of biomarkers of muscle injury and antioxidant status in young trained soccer players. Biol Rhythm Res. 2012;43:431&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne JA, Ostberg O. A self-assessment questionnaire to determine morningness-eveningness in human circadian rhythms. Int J Chronobiol. 1976;4:97&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1027738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin M, McClintick J, Costlow C, Fortner M, White J, Gillin JC. Partial night sleep deprivation reduces natural killer and cellular immune responses in humans. FASEB J. 1996;10:643&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8621064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarraya M, Jarraya S, Chtourou H, Souissi N, Chamari K. The effect of partial sleep deprivation on the reaction time and the attentional capacities of the handball goalkeeper. Biol Rhythm Res. 2013;44:503&#x2013;510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff LE, Halson SL, Peiffer JJ. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important competitions. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;18:13&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24629327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Mohr M, Amstrup T, Rysgaard T, Johansen J, Steensberg A, Pedersen PK, Bangsbo J. The yo-yo intermittent recovery test: physiological response, reliability, and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:697&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12673156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin BJ, Chen HI. Sleep loss and the sympathoadrenal response to exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1984;16:56&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6423925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin BJ, Gaddis GM. Exercise after sleep deprivation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1981;13:220&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6792454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Hammouda O, Chaouachi A, Zouaouid K, Ben Rayanad MC, Souissi N. Effects of two types of partial sleep deprivation on hematological responses during intermittent exercise: a pilot study. Sci Sports. 2014a;29:266&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Hammouda O, Yousfi N, Haddad M, Souissi N. Sleep, sleep loss and performance in Taekwondo competition. In: Haddad M, editor. Performance optimization in Taekwondo: from laboratory to field. Heathrow (UK): OMICS International; 2014b. pp. 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Hammouda O, Yousfi N, Zouaoui K, Ben Rayana MC, Chaouachi A, Driss T, Souissi N. One night of partial sleep deprivation affect biomarkers of cardiac damage, but not cardiovascular and lipid profiles, in young athletes. Biol Rhythm Res. 2015;46:715&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Hammouda O, Zouaoui K, Chaouachi A, Chamari K, Ben Rayana MC, Souissi N. Effect of two types of partial sleep deprivation on Taekwondo players&#x2019; performance during intermittent exercise. Biol Rhythm Res. 2014c;45:17&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meney I, Waterhouse J, Atkinson G, Reilly T, Davenne D. The effect of one night&#x2019;s sleep deprivation on temperature, mood, and physical performance in subjects with different amounts of habitual physical activity. Chronobiol Int. 1998;15:349&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9706412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F, Bourdin H, Simon-Rigaud ML, Nguyen NU, Kantelip JP, Davenne D. Hormonal responses to exercise after partial sleep deprivation and after a hypnotic drug-induced sleep. J Sports Sci. 2001;19:89&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11217014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F, Simon-Rigaud ML, Davenne D, Renaud A, Garnier A, Kantelip JP, Magnin P. Effects of sleep disturbances on subsequent physical performance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1991;63:77&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1748108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver SJ, Costa RJ, Laing SJ, Bilzon JL, Walsh NP. One night of sleep deprivation decreases treadmill endurance performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:155&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omiya K, Akashi YJ, Yoneyama K, Osada N, Tanabe K, Miyake F. Heart-rate response to sympathetic nervous stimulation, exercise, and magnesium concentration in various sleep conditions. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19:127&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plyley MJ, Shephard RJ, Davis GM, Goode RC. Sleep deprivation and cardiorespiratory function. Influence of intermittent submaximal exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1987;56:338&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3569243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racinais S, Hue O, Blonc S, Le Gallais D. Effect of sleep deprivation on shuttle run score in middle-aged amateur athletes. Influence of initial score. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2004;44:246&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15756162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Edwards B. Altered sleep-wake cycles and physical performance in athletes. Physiol Behav. 2007;90:274&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17067642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricardo JS, Cartner L, Oliver SJ, Laing SJ, Walters R, Bilzon JL, Walsh NP. No effect of a 30-h period of sleep deprivation on leukocyte trafficking, neutrophil degranulation and saliva IgA responses to exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;105:499&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19018559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Chtourou H, Aloui A, Hammouda O, Dogui M, Chaouachi A, Chamari K. Effects of time-of-day and partial sleep deprivation on short-term maximal performances of judo competitors. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:2473&#x2013;2480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23974210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Souissi M, Souissi H, Chamari K, Tabka Z, Dogui M, Davenne D. Effect of time of day and partial sleep deprivation on short-term, high-power output. Chronobiol Int. 2008;25:1062&#x2013;1076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19005905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie L, Kang H, Xu Q, Chen MJ, Liao Y, Thiyagarajan M, O&#x2019;Donnell J, Christensen DJ, Nicholson C, Iliff JJ, Takano T, Deane R, Nedergaard M. Sleep drives metabolite clearance from the adult brain. Science. 2013;342:373&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3880190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24136970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>