<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40523229</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Twenty-Four-Hour Low Energy Availability Induced by Diet or Exercise Exhibits Divergent Influences on Sleep and Recovery Indices among Female and Male Cyclists.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2564</StartPage><EndPage>2576</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2564-2576</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003783</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine the effects of 24-h manipulations in energy availability (EA), through altering energy intake (EI) or exercise energy expenditure (EEE), on sleep characteristics and nocturnal heart rate variability (HRV).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty endurance athletes (10 females, 10 males) undertook five 24-h periods of EA manipulation, separated by 8 d, in a randomized Latin square design. Following 24 h of standardized high EA (45 kcal&#xb7;kg -1 FFM&#xb7;d -1 ), athletes then followed a diet providing low EA (15 kcal&#xb7;kg -1 FFM&#xb7;d -1 ) either with/without exercise (LEA EX/REST ), high EA (45 kcal&#xb7;kg -1 FFM&#xb7;d -1 ) with/without exercise (HEA EX/REST ), and excess EA (75 kcal&#xb7;kg -1 FFM&#xb7;d -1 ) without exercise (GEA). Sleep and overnight HRV were assessed using Somfit and Oura ring devices, respectively, pre- and post-EA manipulation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Total sleep duration was extended by 53-61 min following LEA EX versus non-exercise conditions: GEA ( P = 0.002), HEA REST ( P = 0.003), and LEA REST ( P = 0.020). Time in bed was also increased during LEA EX compared with GEA ( P = 0.006) and HEA REST ( P = 0.023), but without alterations to sleep efficiency between conditions ( P = 0.613). Sleep onset latency increased by 8 min following LEA REST compared with GEA ( P = 0.012), whereas there were no other alterations to objective/subjective sleep characteristics between conditions (all P &gt; 0.05). There was no difference in overnight HRV following the 24-h EA manipulation ( P &gt; 0.05). However, mean overnight HR was lower following LEA REST and HEA REST (-4 &#xb1; 3 and -2 &#xb1; 3 bpm), compared with LEA EX (+1 &#xb1; 3 bpm), HEA EX (0 &#xb1; 3 bpm), and GEA (0 &#xb1; 3 bpm, all P &lt; 0.01). There was no difference between sexes in the response to EA manipulation across all variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Twenty-four hours of exercise-induced LEA extended total sleep time, whereas diet-induced LEA reduced mean overnight HR. The responses to EA manipulations did not differ between sexes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Ella S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuikman</LastName><ForeName>Megan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rusell</LastName><ForeName>Suzanna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gardiner</LastName><ForeName>Carissa L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halson</LastName><ForeName>Shona L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stellingwerff</LastName><ForeName>Trent</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McKay</LastName><ForeName>Alannah K A</ForeName><Initials>AKA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burke</LastName><ForeName>Louise M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="Y">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002149" MajorTopicYN="Y">Energy Intake</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001642" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bicycling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ATHLETES</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HEART RATE VARIABILITY</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LEA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">REDS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SEX DIFFERENCES</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40523229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202511000-00022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB. Energy balance and body composition in sports and exercise. J Sports Sci . 2004;22(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB, Kiens B, Wright HH. Energy availability in athletes. J Sports Sci . 2011;29(Suppl 1):S7&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB. Energy balance and energy availability. Encyclopaedia Sports Med . 2013;19:72&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB, Thuma JR. Luteinizing hormone pulsatility is disrupted at a threshold of energy availability in regularly menstruating women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab . 2003;88(1):297&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihle R, Loucks AB. Dose&#x2013;response relationships between energy availability and bone turnover in young exercising women. J Bone Miner Res . 2004;19(8):1231&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks A, Verdun M, Heath E. Low energy availability, not stress of exercise, alters LH pulsatility in exercising women. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1998;84(1):37&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papageorgiou M, Elliott-Sale KJ, Parsons A, et al. Effects of reduced energy availability on bone metabolism in women and men. Bone . 2017;105:191&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koehler K, Hoerner NR, Gibbs JC, et al. Low energy availability in exercising men is associated with reduced leptin and insulin but not with changes in other metabolic hormones. J Sports Sci . 2016;34(20):1921&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB. The response of luteinizing hormone pulsatility to 5 days of low energy availability disappears by 14 years of gynecological age. J Clin Endocrinol Metab . 2006;91(8):3158&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mountjoy M, Ackerman K, Bailey D, et al. 2023 International Olympic Committee's (IOC) consensus statement on Relative Energy Deficiency in Sport (REDs). Br J Sports Med . 2023;57(17):1073&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellingwerff T. Case study: body composition periodization in an Olympic-level female middle-distance runner over a 9-year career. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2018;28(4):428&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Slater GJ, Matthews JJ, Langan-Evans C, Horswill CA. ACSM expert consensus statement on weight loss in weight-category sports. Curr Sports Med Rep . 2021;20(4):199&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, et al. Sleep and the athlete: narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med . 2021;55(7):356&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta L, Morgan K, Gilchrist S. Does elite sport degrade sleep quality? A systematic review. Sports Med . 2017;47(7):1317&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Glaister M, Pizzoferro K, Dawson J, Pedlar C. Sleep duration and quality in elite athletes measured using wristwatch actigraphy. J Sports Sci . 2012;30(6):541&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med . 2014;44(Suppl 1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drew M, Vlahovich N, Hughes D, et al. Prevalence of illness, poor mental health and sleep quality and low energy availability prior to the 2016 Summer Olympic Games. Br J Sports Med . 2018;52(1):47&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MR, Paiva T. Poor precompetitive sleep habits, nutrients&#x2019; deficiencies, inappropriate body composition and athletic performance in elite gymnasts. Eur J Sport Sci . 2016;16(6):726&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach GD, Halson SL, Sargent C. Sleep/wake behaviours of elite athletes from individual and team sports. Eur J Sport Sci . 2015;15(2):94&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Task Force of the European Society of Cardiology. Heart rate variability: standards of measurement, physiological interpretation, and clinical use. Circulation . 1996;93(5):1043&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altini M, Plews D. What is behind changes in resting heart rate and heart rate variability? A large-scale analysis of longitudinal measurements acquired in free-living. Sensors (Basel) . 2021;21(23):7932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Kilding AE, Buchheit M. Heart rate variability in elite triathletes, is variation in variability the key to effective training? A case comparison. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2012;112(11):3729&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trexler ET, Smith-Ryan AE, Norton LE. Metabolic adaptation to weight loss: implications for the athlete. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2014;11(1):7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langan-Evans C, Germaine M, Artukovic M, et al. The psychological and physiological consequences of low energy availability in a male combat sport athlete. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2020;53(4):673&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishibashi A, Kojima C, Tanabe Y, et al. Effect of low energy availability during three consecutive days of endurance training on iron metabolism in male long distance runners. Physiol Rep . 2020;8(12):e14494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelidi AM, Stefanakis K, Chou SH, et al. Relative Energy Deficiency in Sport (REDs): endocrine manifestations, pathophysiology and treatments. Endocr Rev . 2024;45(5):676&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saidi O, Souabni M, Del Sordo GC, et al. Association between low energy availability (LEA) and impaired sleep quality in young rugby players. Nutrients . 2024;16(5):609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Lundy B, Fahrenholtz IL, Melin AK. Pitfalls of conducting and interpreting estimates of energy availability in free-living athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2018;28(4):350&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M. Preventing overtraining in athletes in high-intensity sports and stress/recovery monitoring. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2010;20(Suppl 2):95&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichot V, Roche F, Gaspoz J-M, et al. Relation between heart rate variability and training load in middle-distance runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2000;32(10):1729&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry R, Grove J, Morton A, Zeroni P, Gaudieri S, Keast D. Psychological and immunological correlates of acute overtraining. Br J Sports Med . 1994;28(4):241&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e J, M&#xe4;estu J, Purge P, J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e T, S&#xf6;&#xf6;t T. Relations among heavy training stress, mood state, and performance for male junior rowers. Percept Mot Skills . 2002;95(2):520&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killer SC, Svendsen IS, Jeukendrup A, Gleeson M. Evidence of disturbed sleep and mood state in well-trained athletes during short-term intensified training with and without a high carbohydrate nutritional intervention. J Sports Sci . 2017;35(14):1402&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuuttila OP, Uusitalo A, Kokkonen VP, Weerarathna N, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H. Monitoring fatigue state with heart rate-based and subjective methods during intensified training in recreational runners. Eur J Sport Sci . 2024;24(7):857&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melin AK, Areta JL, Heikura IA, Stellingwerff T, Torstveit MK, Hackney AC. Direct and indirect impact of low energy availability on sports performance. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2024;34(1):e14327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaal K, Tafflet M, Nassif H, et al. Psychological balance in high level athletes: gender-based differences and sport-specific patterns. PLoS One . 2011;6(5):e19007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lok R, Qian J, Chellappa SL. Sex differences in sleep, circadian rhythms, and metabolism: implications for precision medicine. Sleep Med Rev . 2024;75:101926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mong JA, Cusmano DM. Sex differences in sleep: impact of biological sex and sex steroids. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci . 2016;371(1688):20150110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley J, Peake JM, Buchheit M. Cardiac parasympathetic reactivation following exercise: implications for training prescription. Sports Med . 2013;43(12):1259&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2022;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ES, Kuikman MA, Weakley J, et al. Effects of 24-hour diet- or exercise-induced energy availability manipulations on substrate utilization and performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2025;57(4):820&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe1;rquez G, Romero-Arenas S, Colomer-Poveda D. Mobile app review: &#x201c;HRV4Training&#x201d;. Training monitoring at your fingertip. Br J Sports Med . January 16, 2021. Available from: https://blogs.bmj.com/bjsm/2021/01/16/mobile-app-review-hrv4training-training-monitoring-at-your-fingertip/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svensson T, Madhawa K, Hoang N, Chung U-I, Svensson AK. Validity and reliability of the Oura Ring Generation 3 (Gen3) with Oura sleep staging algorithm 2.0 (OSSA 2.0) when compared to multi-night ambulatory polysomnography: a validation study of 96 participants and 421,045 epochs. Sleep Med . 2024;115:251&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao R, Azimi I, Sarhaddi F, et al. Accuracy assessment of oura ring nocturnal heart rate and heart rate variability in comparison with electrocardiography in time and frequency domains: comprehensive analysis. J Med Internet Res . 2022;24(1):e27487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne JA, &#xd6;stberg O. A self-assessment questionnaire to determine morningness&#x2013;eveningness in human circadian rhythms. Int J Chronobiol . 1976;4(2):97&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuikman MA, Smith ES, McKay AKA, et al. Impact of acute dietary and exercise manipulation on RMR measurements and DXA body composition estimates. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2025;57(2):285&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardiner CL, Weakley J, Burke LM, et al. Dose and timing effects of caffeine on subsequent sleep: a randomized clinical crossover trial. Sleep . 2025;48(4):zsae230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardiner C, Weakley J, Burke LM, et al. The effect of alcohol on subsequent sleep in healthy adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev . 2025;80:102030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup A, Wallis G. Measurement of substrate oxidation during exercise by means of gas exchange measurements. Int J Sports Med . 2005;26(Suppl 1):S28&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DJ, Sargent C, Roach GD. A validation of six wearable devices for estimating sleep, heart rate and heart rate variability in healthy adults. Sensors (Basel) . 2022;22(16):6317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon M, Goldin J, Kealy ES, et al. Performance investigation of Somfit sleep staging algorithm. Nat Sci Sleep . 2024;16:1027&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, et al. The REDCap consortium: building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform . 2019;95:103208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)&#x2014;a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform . 2009;42(2):377&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HRV4Training. Available from: https://link.edgepilot.com/s/cd0cbfb0/kwUpIOvH30WY5fQNl3CMxg?u=https://www.hrv4training.com/ . Accessed August 1, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Scott B, Altini M, Wood M, Kilding AE, Laursen PB. Comparison of heart-rate-variability recording with smartphone photoplethysmography, polar H7 chest strap, and electrocardiography. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2017;12(10):1324&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HRV4Training [Internet]. Available from: https://www.hrv4training.com/blog2/oura-ring-integration-read-sleep-data-whole-night-heart-rate-and-hrv-in-hrv4training .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vesterinen V, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Hynynen E, Mikkola J, Hokka L, Nummela A. Heart rate variability in prediction of individual adaptation to endurance training in recreational endurance runners. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2013;23(2):171&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell DC, Rogier M, Yzerbyt V, Bestgen Y. Statistical Methods in Human Sciences . New York: Wadsworth; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadegiani FA, Kater CE. Body composition, metabolism, sleep, psychological and eating patterns of overtraining syndrome: results of the EROS study (EROS-PROFILE). J Sports Sci . 2018;36(16):1902&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardue A, Trexler ET, Sprod LK. Case study: unfavorable but transient physiological changes during contest preparation in a drug-free male bodybuilder. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2017;27(6):550&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas C, Langan-Evans C, Germaine M, et al. Case report: effect of low energy availability and training load on sleep in a male combat sport athlete. Front Sports Act Living . 2023;4:981755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sateia MJ, Buysse DJ, Krystal AD, Neubauer DN, Heald JL. Clinical practice guideline for the pharmacologic treatment of chronic insomnia in adults: an American Academy of sleep medicine clinical practice guideline. J Clin Sleep Med . 2017;13(2):307&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillbanks L, Mountjoy M, Filbay SR. Lightweight rowers&#x2019; perspectives of living with Relative Energy Deficiency in Sport (RED-S). PLoS One . 2022;17(3):e0265268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berntson GG, Thomas Bigger Jr J, Eckberg DL, et al. Heart rate variability: origins, methods, and interpretive caveats. Psychophysiology . 1997;34(6):623&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt L, Regnard J, Desmarets M, et al. Fatigue shifts and scatters heart rate variability in elite endurance athletes. PLoS One . 2013;8(8):e71588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hynynen E, Uusitalo A, Konttinen N, Rusko H. Heart rate variability during night sleep and after awakening in overtrained athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2006;38(2):313&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzueta E, de Zambotti M, Javitz H, et al. Tracking sleep, temperature, heart rate, and daily symptoms across the menstrual cycle with the oura ring in healthy women. Int J Womens Health . 2022;14:491&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Johnston RD, Pearson M, Minahan C. Menstrual-cycle symptoms and sleep characteristics in elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2024;19(9):914&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke AC, Bruinvels G, Julian R, Inge P, Pedlar CR, Govus AD. Hormonal contraceptive use in football codes in Australia. Front Sports Act Living . 2021;3:634866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GA, Fullagar HH, Duffield R. Influence of menstrual phase and symptoms on sleep before and after matches for professional footballers. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2025;35(1):e70011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>