<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40920736</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Daily Use of a Broad-Spectrum Cannabidiol Supplement Produces Detectable Concentrations of Cannabinoids in Urine Prohibited by the World Anti-Doping Agency: An Effect Amplified by Exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>121</StartPage><EndPage>131</EndPage><MedlinePgn>121-131</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003842</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cannabidiol (CBD), a non-intoxicating phytocannabinoid, is used by athletes to enhance recovery and manage other conditions (e.g., poor sleep, anxiety). Although CBD is not prohibited by the World Anti-Doping Agency (WADA), other cannabinoids found in "broad-spectrum" CBD products (e.g., cannabigerol (CBG), cannabidivarin (CBDV)), remain prohibited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to determine whether 10-wk use of a broad-spectrum CBD product (150 mg&#xb7;day -1 (containing trace concentrations of CBG)) could lead to detectable concentrations of prohibited cannabinoids in urine and plasma. The influence of moderate-intensity exercise was also assessed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty-six healthy individuals (47% male) self-administered either a broad-spectrum CBD product ( n = 31, CBD) or a visually identical placebo ( n = 5, PLA) for 10 wk. After 10 wk, participants completed a fasted, 90-min bout of moderate-intensity exercise (55% V&#x307;O 2peak ). Blood and urine samples were collected at baseline (presupplementation) and pre- and postexercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No cannabinoids or metabolites were detected at baseline in either the PLA or CBD group. Following 10 wk of supplementation, urinary concentrations of CBD and its metabolites (6-OH-CBD, 7-COOH-CBD, 7-OH-CBD) were present. CBG and CBDV were also detected in 42% and 68% of preexercise samples, respectively. Urinary concentrations of 6-OH-CBD ( P = 0.006), 7-OH-CBD ( P = 0.009), CBD ( P = 0.043), CBG ( P = 0.0023), and CBDV ( P = 0.033) also increased from pre- to postexercise. CBG and CBDV were detected in 74% and 84% of postexercise samples, respectively. Concentrations of &#x2206; 9 -THC or its metabolites (11-OH-THC, 11-COOH-THC) were not present at any timepoint.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Daily use of a broad-spectrum CBD supplement resulted in detectable urinary concentrations of WADA-prohibited cannabinoids in urine. Exercise appeared to increase concentrations of these cannabinoids. Therefore, athletes should avoid consuming broad-spectrum CBD products, given the potential associated anti-doping risks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillham</LastName><ForeName>Scott H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1745-0118</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Sport and Exercise Sciences (RISES), Liverpool John Moores University, Byrom Street, Liverpool, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cole</LastName><ForeName>Paige L</ForeName><Initials>PL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Sport and Exercise Sciences (RISES), Liverpool John Moores University, Byrom Street, Liverpool, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owens</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Sport and Exercise Sciences (RISES), Liverpool John Moores University, Byrom Street, Liverpool, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chester</LastName><ForeName>Neil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Sport and Exercise Sciences (RISES), Liverpool John Moores University, Byrom Street, Liverpool, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bampouras</LastName><ForeName>Theodoros M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Sport and Exercise Sciences (RISES), Liverpool John Moores University, Byrom Street, Liverpool, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCartney</LastName><ForeName>Danielle</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gordon</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGregor</LastName><ForeName>Iain S</ForeName><Initials>IS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Close</LastName><ForeName>Graeme L</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Sport and Exercise Sciences (RISES), Liverpool John Moores University, Byrom Street, Liverpool, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>19GBJ60SN5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002185">Cannabidiol</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002186">Cannabinoids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cannabidiol</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000652" MajorTopicYN="N">urine</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Doping in Sports</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cannabinoids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000652" MajorTopicYN="N">urine</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ATHLETE SUPPLEMENTATION</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CANNABIDIVARIN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CANNABIGEROL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CANNABINOID DETECTION</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40920736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-00904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clarke RC, Merlin MD. Cannabis domestication, breeding history, present-day genetic diversity, and future prospects. Crit Rev Plant Sci . 2016;35(5&#x2013;6):293&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElSohly MA, Radwan MM, Gul W, Chandra S, Galal A. Phytochemistry of Cannabis sativa L. Prog Chem Org Nat Prod . 2017;103:1&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachnani R, Raup-Konsavage WM, Vrana KE. The pharmacological case for cannabigerol. J Pharmacol Exp Ther . 2021;376(2):204&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillham SH, Starke L, Welch L, et al. Does a broad-spectrum cannabidiol supplement improve performance in a 10-min cycle ergometer performance-test? Eur J Sport Sci . 2024;24(7):870&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinotti O, Sarill M. Differentiating full-spectrum hemp extracts from CBD isolates: implications for policy, safety and science. J Diet Suppl . 2020;17(5):517&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Carvajal R, Bruner L, Kaminski NE. The current understanding of the benefits, safety, and regulation of cannabidiol in consumer products. Food Chem Toxicol . 2021;157:112600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor IS, Cairns EA, Abelev S, et al. Access to cannabidiol without a prescription: a cross-country comparison and analysis. Int J Drug Policy . 2020;85:102935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper AM, Sparks SA, Hooks M, et al. High prevalence of cannabidiol use within male professional Rugby union and league players: a quest for pain relief and enhanced recovery. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2020;30(5):315&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney D, Benson MJ, Desbrow B, Irwin C, Suraev A, McGregor IS. Cannabidiol and sports performance: a narrative review of relevant evidence and recommendations for future research. Sports Med Open . 2020;6(1):27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Close GL, Gillham SH, Kasper AM. Cannabidiol (CBD) and the athlete: Claims, Evidence, Prevalence and Safety Concerns. 2021. Available from: https://www.gssiweb.org/sports-science-exchange/article/cannabidiol-(cbd)-and-the-athlete-claims-evidence-prevalence-and-safety-concerns . Accessed September 26, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurley BJ, Murphy TP, Gul W, Walker LA, ElSohly M. Content versus label claims in cannabidiol (CBD)-containing products obtained from commercial outlets in the state of Mississippi. J Diet Suppl . 2020;17(5):599&#x2013;607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson E, Kilgore M, Babalonis S. Cannabidiol (CBD) product contamination: quantitative analysis of &#x394;9-tetrahydrocannabinol (&#x394;9-THC) concentrations found in commercially available CBD products. Drug Alcohol Depend . 2022a;237:109522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liebling JP, Clarkson NJ, Gibbs BW, Yates AS, O'Sullivan SE. An analysis of over-the-counter cannabidiol products in the United Kingdom. Cannabis Cannabinoid Res . 2022;7(2):207&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson E, Kilgore M, Babalonis S. Label accuracy of unregulated cannabidiol (CBD) products: measured concentration vs label claim. J Cannabis Res . 2022b;4(1):28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SY, Sharan S, Woo S. Model-based analysis of cannabidiol dose&#x2013;exposure relationship and bioavailability. Pharmacotherapy . 2020;40(4):291&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreuz DS, Axelrod J. Delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol: localization in body fat. Science . 1973;179(4071):391&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson E, Nor&#xe9;n K, Sj&#xf6;vall J, Halldin MM. Determination of &#x394;1-tetrahydrocannabinol in human fat biopsies from marihuana users by gas chromatography&#x2013;mass spectrometry. Biomed Chromatogr . 1989;3(1):35&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunasekaran N, Long L, Dawson B, et al. Reintoxication: the release of fat-stored &#x394;9-tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) into blood is enhanced by food deprivation or ACTH exposure. Br J Pharmacol . 2009;158(5):1330&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A, Keats K, Rooney K, et al. Fasting and exercise increase plasma cannabinoid levels in THC pre-treated rats: an examination of behavioural consequences. Psychopharmacology (Berl) . 2014;231:3987&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A, Montebello ME, Norberg MM, et al. Exercise increases plasma THC concentrations in regular cannabis users. Drug Alcohol Depend . 2013;133(2):763&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CS, Jew CP, Lu HC. Lasting impacts of prenatal cannabis exposure and the role of endogenous cannabinoids in the developing brain. Future Neurol . 2011;6(4):459&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor L, Gidal B, Blakey G, Tayo B, Morrison G. A phase I, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, single ascending dose, multiple dose, and food effect trial of the safety, tolerability and pharmacokinetics of highly purified cannabidiol in healthy subjects. CNS Drugs . 2018;32(11):1053&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G, Ljunggren G, Ceci R. The increase of perceived exertion, aches and pain in the legs, heart rate and blood lactate during exercise on a bicycle ergometer. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1985;54(4):343&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochrane-Snyman KC, Cruz C, Morales J, Coles M. The effects of cannabidiol oil on noninvasive measures of muscle damage in men. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(7):1460&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney D, Irwin C, Bawa Z, et al. The effect of cannabidiol on subjective responses to endurance exercise: a randomised controlled trial. Sports Med Open . 2024;10(1):61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kevin RC, Allsop DJ, Lintzeris N, Dunlop AJ, Booth J, McGregor IS. Urinary cannabinoid levels during nabiximols (Sativex&#xae;)-medicated inpatient cannabis withdrawal. Forensic Toxicol . 2017a;35(1):33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kevin RC, Allsop DJ, Lintzeris N, Dunlop AJ, Booth J, McGregor IS. Urinary cannabinoid levels during nabiximols (Sativex&#xae;)-medicated inpatient cannabis withdrawal. Forensic Toxicol . 2017b;35(1):33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Haaf DS, Bongers CC, Hulshof HG, Eijsvogels TM, Hopman MT. The impact of protein supplementation on exercise-induced muscle damage, soreness and fatigue following prolonged walking exercise in vital older adults: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial. Nutrients . 2020;12(6):1806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grotenhermen F. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of cannabinoids. Clin Pharmacokinet . 2003;42:327&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odell MS, Frei MY, Gerostamoulos D, Chu M, Lubman DI. Residual cannabis levels in blood, urine and oral fluid following heavy cannabis use. Forensic Sci Int . 2015;249:173&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang R, Yamaori S, Takeda S, Yamamoto I, Watanabe K. Identification of cytochrome P450 enzymes responsible for metabolism of cannabidiol by human liver microsomes. Life Sci . 2011;89(5&#x2013;6):165&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin M, Cairns P, Conboy D, et al. Development and scale-up of 7-COOH CBD synthesis, a key cannabinoid metabolite. Org Process Res Dev . 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kevin RC, Allsop DJ, Lintzeris N, Dunlop AJ, Booth J, McGregor IS. Urinary cannabinoid levels during nabiximols (Sativex&#xae;)-medicated inpatient cannabis withdrawal. Forensic Toxicol . 2017;35:33&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zendulka O, Dovrtelov&#xe1; G, Noskov&#xe1; K, et al. Cannabinoids and cytochrome P450 interactions. Curr Drug Metab . 2016;17(3):206&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ujv&#xe1;ry I, Hanu&#x161; L. Human metabolites of cannabidiol: a review on their formation, biological activity, and relevance in therapy. Cannabis Cannabinoid Res . 2016;1(1):90&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolbold R, Klein K, Burk O, et al. Sex is a major determinant of CYP3A4 expression in human liver. Hepatology . 2003;38(4):978&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson GD. Pregnancy-induced changes in pharmacokinetics: a mechanistic-based approach. Clin Pharmacokinet . 2005;44(10):989&#x2013;1008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanger UM, Schwab M. Cytochrome P450 enzymes in drug metabolism: regulation of gene expression, enzyme activities, and impact of genetic variation. Pharmacol Ther . 2013;138(1):103&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolli AR, Hoeng J. Cannabidiol bioavailability is nonmonotonic with a long terminal elimination half-life: a pharmacokinetic modeling-based analysis. Cannabis Cannabinoid Res . 2025;10(1):81&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huestis MA. Human cannabinoid pharmacokinetics. Chem Biodivers . 2007;4(8):1770&#x2013;804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams NNB, Ewell TR, Abbotts KSS, et al. Comparison of five oral cannabidiol preparations in adult humans: pharmacokinetics, body composition, and heart rate variability. Pharmaceuticals . 2021;14(1):35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Hai A, Domb AJ, Hoffman A. Strategies for enhancing the oral bioavailability of cannabinoids. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol . 2022;18(5):313&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perucca E, Bialer M. Critical aspects affecting cannabidiol oral bioavailability and metabolic elimination, and related clinical implications. CNS Drugs . 2020;34:795&#x2013;800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbotts KSS, Ewell TR, Butterklee HM, et al. Cannabidiol and cannabidiol metabolites: pharmacokinetics, interaction with food, and influence on liver function. Nutrients . 2022;14(10):2152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira AF, Costa RR, Macedo RCO, Coconcelli L, Kruel LFM. Effects of aerobic exercise performed in fasted v. fed state on fat and carbohydrate metabolism in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Nutr . 2016;116(7):1153&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>