<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">29864109</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Total Sleep Deprivation and Recovery Sleep Affect the Diurnal Variation of Agility Performance: The Gender Differences.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>132</StartPage><EndPage>140</EndPage><MedlinePgn>132-140</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002614</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Romdhani, M, Hammouda, O, Smari, K, Chaabouni, Y, Mahdouani, K, Driss, T, and Souissi, N. Total sleep deprivation and recovery sleep affect the diurnal variation of agility performance: The gender differences. J Strength Cond Res 35(1): 132-140, 2021-This study aimed to investigate the effects of time-of-day, 24 and 36 hours of total sleep deprivation (TSD), and recovery sleep (RS) on repeated-agility performances. Twenty-two physical education students (11 male and 11 female students) completed 5 repeated modified agility T-test (RMAT) sessions (i.e., 2 after normal sleep night [NSN] [at 07:00 and 17:00 hours], 2 after TSD [at 07:00 hours, i.e., 24-hour TSD and at 17:00 hours, i.e., 36-hour TSD], and 1 after RS at 17:00 hours). The RMAT index decreased from the morning to the afternoon after NSN (p &lt; 0.05, d = 1.05; p &lt; 0.01, d = 0.73) and after TSD (p &lt; 0.001, d = 0.92; d = 1.08), respectively, for total time (TT) and peak time (PT). This finding indicates a diurnal variation in repeated agility, which persisted after TSD. However, the diurnal increase in PT was less marked in the female group after NSN (2.98 vs. 6.24%). Moreover, TT and PT increased, respectively, after 24-hour TSD (p &lt; 0.001; d = 0.84, d = 0.87) and 36-hour TSD (p &lt; 0.001, d = 1.12; p &lt; 0.01, d = 0.65). Female subjects' PT was less affected by 24-hour TSD (1.76 vs. 6.81%) compared with male subjects' PT. After 36-hour TSD, the amount of decrease was not different between groups, which increased the diurnal amplitude of PT only for male subjects. Total sleep deprivation suppressed the diurnal increase of PT and increased the diurnal amplitude of oral temperature only in women. Nevertheless, RS normalized the sleep-loss-induced performance disruption. Conclusively, sleep loss and RS differently affect repeated-agility performance of men and women during the day. Sleep extension postdeprivation could have potent restorative effect on repeated-agility performances, and female subjects could extract greater benefits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2018 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romdhani</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Observatory of Sports, Exercise Physiology Departement, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education Ksar-Said, Departement of Biology, Manouba University, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammouda</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Sport and Movement (CeRSM), UFP STAPS, University of Paris Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Molecular Bases of Human Pathology, UR12ES17, Faculty of Medicine of Sfax, Sfax University, Sfax, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smari</LastName><ForeName>Khawla</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education Ksar-Said, Departement of Biology, Manouba University, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Molecular Bases of Human Pathology, UR12ES17, Faculty of Medicine of Sfax, Sfax University, Sfax, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaabouni</LastName><ForeName>Yassine</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, CHU Ibn Jazzar, Kairouan, Tunisia ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Analysis, Treatment and Valorization of Pollutants of the Environment and Products (LATVEP), Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Monastir, Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahdouani</LastName><ForeName>Kacem</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, CHU Ibn Jazzar, Kairouan, Tunisia ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Analysis, Treatment and Valorization of Pollutants of the Environment and Products (LATVEP), Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Monastir, Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Driss</LastName><ForeName>Tarak</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Sport and Movement (CeRSM), UFP STAPS, University of Paris Nanterre, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souissi</LastName><ForeName>Nizar</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Observatory of Sports, Exercise Physiology Departement, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education Ksar-Said, Departement of Biology, Manouba University, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002940" MajorTopicYN="N">Circadian Rhythm</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012727" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sex Characteristics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012737" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012892" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Deprivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29864109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202101000-00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acheson A, Richards JB, de Wit H. Effects of sleep deprivation on impulsive behaviors in men and women. Physiol Behav 91: 579&#x2013;587, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen ML, Antunes IB, Silva A, Alvarenga TAF, Baracat EC, Tufik S. Effects of sleep loss on sleep architecture in Wistar rats: Gender-specific rebound sleep. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry 32: 975&#x2013;983, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armitage R, Smith C, Thompson S, Hoffmann R. Sex differences in slow-wave activity in response to sleep deprivation. Sleep (Rochester) 4: 33&#x2013;41, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bambaeichi E, Reilly T, Cable NT, Giacomoni M. Influence of time of day and partial sleep loss on muscle strength in eumenorrheic females. Ergonomics 48: 1499&#x2013;1511, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belenky G, Wesensten NJ, Thorne DR, Thomas ML, Sing HC, Redmond DP, Russo MB, Balkin TJ. Patterns of performance degradation and restoration during sleep restriction and subsequent recovery: A sleep dose-response study. J Sleep Res 12: 1&#x2013;12, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: A new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res 28: 193&#x2013;213, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai ZJ. A new function of rapid eye movement sleep: Improvement of muscular efficiency. Physiol Behav 144: 110&#x2013;115, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain SW, Dennison CF, Zeitzer JM, Guzik AM, Bir S, Khalsa S, Santhi N, Schoen MW, Czeisler C a, Duffy F. Sex differences in phase angle of entrainment and melatonin amplitude in humans. J Biol Rhythms 25: 288&#x2013;296, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Aloui A, Hammouda O, Chaouachi A, Chamari K, Souissi N. The effect of time-of-day and judo match on short-term maximal performances in judokas. Biol Rhythm Res 44: 797&#x2013;806, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Fakhfakh H, Fakhfakh H, Hammouda O, Souissi N. The effect of dynamic stretching on repeated sprints and jump performances after one night of partial sleep deprivation. Br J Sports Med 50: A49.1&#x2013;A49, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Hbiri R, Souissi N. The effect of dynamic stretching on short-term maximal performance and perceived exertion after a total sleep loss night in athletes. Acta Physiol 217: 131, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Souissi N. The effect of training at a specific time of day. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1984&#x2013;2005, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corsi-Cabrera M, S&#xe1;nchez Isabel A, Del-R&#x131;o-Portilla Y, Villanueva Y, P&#xe9;rez-Garci E. Effect of 38 h of total sleep deprivation on the waking EEG in women: Sex differences. Int J Psychophysiol 50: 213&#x2013;224, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dongen HPA, Maislin G, Mullington JM, Dinges DF. The cumulative cost of additional wakefulness: Dose-response effects on neurobehavioral functions and sleep physiology from chronic sleep restriction and total sleep deprivation. Sleep 26: 117&#x2013;126, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlen JC, Hesse S, Pinckney L, Paul KN. Sex chromosomes regulate nighttime sleep propensity during recovery from sleep loss in mice. PLoS One 8: 14&#x2013;19, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facer-Childs E, Brandstaetter R. The impact of circadian phenotype and time since awakening on diurnal performance in athletes. Curr Biol 25: 518&#x2013;522, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraut B, L&#xe9;ger D, Medkour T, Dubois A, Bayon V, Chennaoui M, Perrot S. Benefits of napping and an extended duration of recovery sleep on alertness and immune cells after acute sleep restriction. Brain Behav Immun 25: 16&#x2013;24, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraut B, Boudjeltia KZ, Vanhamme L, Kerkhofs M. Immune, inflammatory and cardiovascular consequences of sleep restriction and recovery. Sleep Med Rev 16: 137&#x2013;149, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraut B, L&#xe9;ger D, Medkour T, Dubois A, Bayon V, Chennaoui M, Perrot S. Napping reverses increased pain sensitivity due to sleep restriction. PLoS One 10: 1&#x2013;16, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzsimons M, Dawson B, Ward D, Wilkinson A. Cycling and running tests of repeated sprint ability. Aust J Sci Med Sport 25: 82&#x2013;87, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C. Monitoring training in athletes with reference to overtraining syndrome. Med Sci Sports Exerc 30: 1164&#x2013;1168, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts AJ, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: The effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med 45: 161&#x2013;186, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haj-Sassi R, Dardouri W, Gharbi Z, Chaouachi A, Mansour H, Rabhi A, Mahfoudhi M-E. Reliability and validity of a new repeated agility test as a measure of anaerobic and explosive power. J Strength Cond Res 25: 472&#x2013;480, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammouda, Chtourou H, Chahed H, Ferchichi S, Chaouachi A, Kallel C, Miled A, Chamari K, Souissi N. High intensity exercise affects diurnal variation of some biological markers in trained subjects. Int J Sports Med 33: 886&#x2013;891, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne J. Why REM sleep? Clues beyond the laboratory in a more challenging world. Biol Psychol 92: 152&#x2013;168, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne JA, Ostberg O. A self-assessment questionnaire to determine morningness-eveningness in human circadian rhythms. Int J Chronobiol 4: 97&#x2013;110, 1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda M, Ikeda-sagara M, Okada T. Brain oxidation is an initial process in sleep induction. Neuroscience 130: 1029&#x2013;1040, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin MR, Opp MR. Sleep-health: Reciprocal regulation of sleep and innate immunity. Neuropsychopharmacology 42: 1&#x2013;96, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarraya M, Jarraya S, Chtourou H, Souissi N. The impact of partial sleep deprivation on the diurnal variations of cognitive performance in trained subjects. Proced Soc Behav Sci 82: 392&#x2013;396, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamond N, Jay SM, Dorrian J, Ferguson SA, Jones C, Dawson D. The dynamics of neurobehavioural recovery following sleep loss. J Sleep Res 16: 33&#x2013;41, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen WMA, Lehto M, Karisola P, Lindholm H, Luukkonen R, Sallinen M, H&#xe4;rm&#xe4; M, Porkka-Heiskanen T, Alenius H. Sleep restriction increases the risk of developing cardiovascular diseases by augmenting proinflammatory responses through IL-17 and CRP. PLoS One 4: e4589, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier-Ewert HK, Ridker PM, Rifai N, Regan MM, Price NJ, Dinges DF, Mullington JM. Effect of sleep loss on C-reactive protein, an inflammatory marker of cardiovascular risk. J Am Coll Cardiol 43: 678&#x2013;683, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Hammouda O, Zouaoui K, Chaouachi A, Chamari K, Rayana MC Ben, Souissi N. Effect of two types of partial sleep deprivation on Taekwondo players' performance during intermittent exercise. Biol Rhythm Res 45: 1&#x2013;10, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mhenni T, Michalsik LB, Mejri MA, Yousfi N, Chaouachi A, Souissi N, Chamari K. Morning&#x2013;evening difference of team-handball-related short-term maximal physical performances in female team handball players. J Sports Sci 35: 912&#x2013;920, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mong JA, Cusmano DM. Sex differences in sleep: Impact of biological sex and sex steroids. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci 371: 20150110, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orze&#x142;-Gryglewska J. Consequences of sleep deprivation. Int J Occup Med Environ Health 23: 95&#x2013;114, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel M, Gomez S, Berg S, Almbladh P, Lindblad J, Petersen H, Magnusson M, Johansson R, Fransson PA. Effects of 24-h and 36-h sleep deprivation on human postural control and adaptation. Exp Brain Res 185: 165&#x2013;173, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pejovic S, Basta M, Vgontzas AN, Kritikou I, Shaffer ML, Tsaoussoglou M, Stiffler D, Stefanakis Z, Bixler EO, Chrousos GP. Effects of recovery sleep after one work week of mild sleep restriction on interleukin-6 and cortisol secretion and daytime sleepiness and performance. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 305: E890&#x2013;E896, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porkka-Heiskanen T, Strecker RE, Thakkar M, Bj&#xf8;rkum AA, Greene RW, McCarley RW. Adenosine: A mediator of the sleep-inducing effects of prolonged wakefulness. Science 276: 1265&#x2013;1268, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racinais S, Connes P, Bishop D, Blonc S, Hue O. Morning versus evening power output and repeated-sprint ability. Chronobiol Int 22: 1029&#x2013;1039, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Edwards B. Altered sleep-wake cycles and physical performance in athletes. Physiol Behav 90: 274&#x2013;284, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz J, Simon RD. Sleep extension improves serving accuracy: A study with college varsity tennis players. Physiol Behav 151: 541&#x2013;544, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro C, Bortz R, Mitchell D, Bartel P, Jooste P. Slow-wave sleep: A recovery period after exercise. Science 214: 1253&#x2013;1254, 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Young WB. Agility literature review: Classifications, training and testing. J Sports Sci 24: 919&#x2013;932, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Sesbo&#xfc;&#xe9; B, Gauthier A, Larue J, Davenne D. Effects of one night's sleep deprivation on anaerobic performance the following day. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 359&#x2013;366, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Souissi M, Souissi H, Chamari K, Tabka Z, Dogui M, Davenne D. Effect of time of day and partial sleep deprivation on short-term, high-power output. Chronobiol Int 25: 1062&#x2013;1076, 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>