<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32459411</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effect of Overreaching on Neuromuscular Performance and Wellness Responses in Australian Rules Football Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1530</StartPage><EndPage>1538</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1530-1538</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003603</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Campbell, PG, Stewart, IB, Sirotic, AC, and Minett, GM. Title: The effect of overreaching on neuromuscular performance and wellness responses in Australian rules football athletes. J Strength Cond Res 34(6): 1530-1538, 2020-This study seeks to evaluate the effect of periodized fluctuations in training load on wellness and psychological questionnaires, perceived exertion, performance, and neuromuscular measures in team-sport athletes. Thirteen amateur Australian rules football athletes completed 6 weeks of periodized training, consisting of 2-week normal training (NT), intensified training (IT), and taper training (TT). Training sessions were quantified using global positioning system devices, heart-rate, and session rating of perceived exertion (sRPE), with wellness (general soreness, sleep quality/quantity, readiness to train, fatigue, stress, mood, and motivation) questionnaires collected daily. Psychological (Recovery-Stress Questionnaire for Athletes) and physical performance (countermovement jump, cycle ergometer peak power, 30-m sprint, and 2-km time trial) markers were measured after each training period. Perceived (sRPE) and mechanical loading were higher for IT than NT, and IT than TT (p &lt; 0.03; d = 0.65-25.34). Cycle ergometer peak power, 30-m sprint, 2-km time trial, and countermovement jump height showed reductions in performance after IT compared to initial testing (p &lt; 0.02; d = 0.51-1.46), with subsequent increases in performance after TT (p &lt; 0.04; d = 0.66-2.27). Average wellness was higher during NT compared to IT (p = 0.005; d = 1.11). Readiness to train did not significantly differ from NT to IT or TT (p &lt; 0.55; d = &lt;0.59); however, readiness to train did improve during TT after the IT (p = 0.01; d = 1.05). The disturbances in performance, perceptual, and mood states may indicate a state of functional overreaching. The findings suggest that an averaged wellness score may be useful in potentially identifying overreaching. However, despite the popularity of wellness in monitoring systems, these measures overall demonstrated a limited capacity to differentiate between periodized fluctuations in load.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Patrick G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Kelvin Grove, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Biomedical Innovation, Queensland University of Technology, Kelvin Grove, Queensland, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stewart</LastName><ForeName>Ian B</ForeName><Initials>IB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Kelvin Grove, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Biomedical Innovation, Queensland University of Technology, Kelvin Grove, Queensland, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sirotic</LastName><ForeName>Anita C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catapult Sports, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minett</LastName><ForeName>Geoffrey M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Queensland University of Technology, Kelvin Grove, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health and Biomedical Innovation, Queensland University of Technology, Kelvin Grove, Queensland, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000339" MajorTopicYN="N">Affect</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="N">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006304" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009042" MajorTopicYN="N">Motivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064797" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Conditioning, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202006000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbott W, Brownlee TE, Harper LD, Naughton RJ, Clifford T. The independent effects of match location, match result and the quality of opposition on subjective wellbeing in under 23 soccer players: A case study. Res Sports Med 26: 262&#x2013;275, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen G, Gandevia S, McKenzie D. Reliability of measurements of muscle strength and voluntary activation using twitch interpolation. Muscle Nerve 18: 593&#x2013;600, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourdon PC, Cardinale M, Murray A, et al. Monitoring athlete training loads: Consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: S2161&#x2013;S2170, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Racinais S, Bilsborough J, et al. Monitoring fitness, fatigue and running performance during a pre-season training camp in elite football players. J Sci Med Sport 16: 550&#x2013;555, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell PG, Stewart IB, Sirotic AC, Minett GM. Does exercise intensity affect wellness scores in a dose-like fashion? Eur J Sport Sci 2020. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mez&#xea;ncio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 397&#x2013;402, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The t test for means. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: L. Lawrence Earlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 25&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormack SJ, Newton RU, McGuigan MR, Doyle TL. Reliability of measures obtained during single and repeated countermovement jumps. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 3: 131, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts A, Wallace L, Slattery K. Monitoring changes in performance, physiology, biochemistry, and psychology during overreaching and recovery in triathletes. Int J Sports Med 28: 125&#x2013;134, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ, Reaburn P, Piva TJ, Rowsell GJ. Monitoring for overreaching in rugby league players. Eur J Appl Physiol 99: 313&#x2013;324, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C. Monitoring training in athletes with reference to overtraining syndrome. Med Sci Sports Exerc 30: 1164&#x2013;1168, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo TF, Cormack SJ, Gabbett TJ, Lorenzen CH. Pre-training perceived wellness impacts training output in Australian football players. J Sports Sci 34: 1445&#x2013;1451, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo TF, Cormack SJ, Gabbett TJ, Lorenzen CH. Self-reported wellness profiles of professional Australian football players during the competition phase of the season. J Strength Cond Res 31: 495&#x2013;502, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastin PB, Meyer D, Robinson D. Perceptions of wellness to monitor adaptive responses to training and competition in elite Australian football. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2518&#x2013;2526, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govus AD, Coutts A, Duffield R, Murray A, Fullagar H. Relationship between pretraining subjective wellness measures, player load, and rating-of-perceived-exertion training load in American college football. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 13: 95&#x2013;101, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grove JR, Main LC, Sharp L. Stressors, recovery processes, and manifestations of training distress in dance. J Dance Med Sci 17: 70&#x2013;78, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H Aile L, Agher GA Jr, Ael M, J Robertson R. Perceived exertion scaling procedures. In: Perceived Exertion Laboratory Manual. New York, NY: Springer, 2016. p. 45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Monitoring training load to understand fatigue in athletes. Sports Med 44: 139&#x2013;147, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper SL, MacKinnon LT. Monitoring overtraining in athletes. Sports Med 20: 321&#x2013;327, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaspers A, Brink MS, Probst SG, Frencken WG, Helsen WF. Relationships between training load indicators and training outcomes in professional soccer. Sports Med 47: 533&#x2013;544, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M, Kallus KW. Recovery-stress Questionnaire for Athletes: User Manual. (Vol. 1). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M, Klaus-Dietrich G. Changes in stress and recovery in elite rowers during preparation for the Olympic Games. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 676&#x2013;683, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kentt&#xe4; G, Hassm&#xe9;n P. Overtraining and recovery. Sports Med 26: 1&#x2013;16, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;lling S, Hitzschke B, Holst T, et al. Validity of the acute recovery and stress scale: Training monitoring of the German junior national field hockey team. Int J Sports Sci Coach 10: 529&#x2013;542, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone S, Hughes B, Roe M, Collins K, Buchheit M. Monitoring player fitness, fatigue status and running performance during an in-season training camp in elite Gaelic football. Sci Med Football 1: 229&#x2013;236, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone S, Owen A, Newton M, et al. Wellbeing perception and the impact on external training output among elite soccer players. J Sci Med Sport 21: 29&#x2013;34, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin DT, Andersen MB, Gates W. Using profile of mood states (POMS) to monitor high-intensity training in cyclists: Group versus case studies. Sport Psychol 14: 138&#x2013;156, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 5: 367&#x2013;383, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNair D. Manual Profile of Mood States. San Diego, CA: Educational &amp; Industrial Testing Service, 1971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Duclos M, Foster C, et al. Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: Joint consensus statement of the European College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 186&#x2013;205, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe4;ssi A, Ferrauti A, Meyer T, Pfeiffer M, Kellmann M. Psychological tools used for monitoring training responses of athletes. Perform Enhance Health 4: 125&#x2013;133, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M, Sacco P. Delayed-onset muscle soreness does not reflect the magnitude of eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Scand J Med Sci Sports 12: 337&#x2013;346, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piacentini MF, Witard OC, Tonoli C, et al. Intensive training affects mood with no effect on brain-derived neurotrophic factor. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 11: 824&#x2013;830, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe G, Darrall-Jones J, Till K, et al. Between-days reliability and sensitivity of common fatigue measures in rugby players. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 11: 581&#x2013;586, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossignol PL, Gabbett TJ, Comerford D, Stanton WR. Repeated-sprint ability and team selection in Australian Football League players. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 9: 161&#x2013;165, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan S, Coutts AJ, Hocking J, Kempton T. Factors affecting match running performance in professional Australian football. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 12: 1199&#x2013;1204, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Kellmann M, Main LC, Gastin PB. Athlete self-report measures in research and practice: Considerations for the discerning reader and fastidious practitioner. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 12: S2127&#x2013;S2135, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Main LC, Gastin PB. Monitoring the athlete training response: Subjective self-reported measures trump commonly used objective measures: A systematic review. Br J Sports Med 50: 281&#x2013;291, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor K, Chapman D, Cronin J, Newton M, Gill N. Fatigue monitoring in high performance sport: A survey of current trends. J Aust Strength Cond 20: 12&#x2013;23, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe RT, Atkinson G, Drust B, Gregson W. Monitoring fatigue status in elite team-sport athletes: Implications for practice. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 12: S227&#x2013;S234, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe RT, Strudwick AJ, Buchheit M, et al. Monitoring fatigue during the in-season competitive phase in elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 10: 958&#x2013;964, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren GL, Lowe DA, Armstrong RB. Measurement tools used in the study of eccentric contraction-induced injury. Sports Med 27: 43&#x2013;59, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weaving D, Jones B, Marshall P, Till K, Abt G. Multiple measures are needed to quantify training loads in professional rugby league. Int J Sports Med 38: 735&#x2013;740, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehbe G, Gabbett T, Dwyer D, McLellan C, Coad S. Monitoring neuromuscular fatigue in team-sport athletes using a cycle-ergometer test. Int J Sports Physiol Perf 10: 292&#x2013;297, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellman AD, Coad SC, Flynn PJ, Climstein M, McLellan CP. Movement demands and perceived wellness associated with preseason training camp in NCAA Division I college football players. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2704&#x2013;2718, 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>