<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37809566</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2405-8440</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Heliyon</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Heliyon</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Narrative review: The role of circadian rhythm on sports performance, hormonal regulation, immune system function, and injury prevention in athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e19636</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e19636</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e19636</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e19636</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study was a narrative review of the importance of circadian rhythm (CR), describes the underlying mechanisms of CR in sports performance, emphasizes the reciprocal link between CR, endocrine homeostasis and sex differences, and the unique role of the circadian clock in immune system function and coordination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">As a narrative review study, a comprehensive search was conducted in PubMed, Scopus, and Web of Science (core collection) databases using the keywords "circadian rhythm", "sports performance", "hormonal regulation", "immune system", and "injury prevention". Inclusion criteria were studies published in English and peer-reviewed journals until July 2023. Studies that examined the role of CR in sports performance, hormonal status, immune system function, and injury prevention in athletes were selected for review.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">CR is followed by almost all physiological and biochemical activities in the human body. In humans, the superchiasmatic nucleus controls many daily biorhythms under solar time, including the sleep-wake cycle. A body of literature indicates that the peak performance of essential indicators of sports performance is primarily in the afternoon hours, and the evening of actions occurs roughly at the peak of core body temperature. Recent studies have demonstrated that the time of day that exercise is performed affects the achievement of good physical performance. This review also shows various biomarkers of cellular damage in weariness and the underlying mechanisms of diurnal fluctuations. According to the clock, CR can be synchronized with photonic and non-photonic stimuli (i.e., temperature, physical activity, and food intake), and feeding patterns and diet changes can affect CR and redox markers. It also emphasizes the reciprocal links between CR and endocrine homeostasis, the specific role of the circadian clock in coordinating immune system function, and the relationship between circadian clocks and sex differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The interaction between insufficient sleep and time of day on performance has been established in this study because it is crucial to balance training, recovery, and sleep duration to attain optimal sports performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nobari</LastName><ForeName>Hadi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Extremadura, 10003, C&#xe1;ceres, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Educational Sciences and Psychology, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Ardabil, 56199-11367, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azarian</LastName><ForeName>Somayeh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Educational Sciences and Psychology, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Ardabil, 56199-11367, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saedmocheshi</LastName><ForeName>Saber</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, 66177-15175, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vald&#xe9;s-Badilla</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity Sciences, Faculty of Education Sciences, Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica del Maule, Talca, 3530000, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Coach Career, School of Education, Universidad Vi&#xf1;a del Mar, Vi&#xf1;a del Mar, 2520000, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a Calvo</LastName><ForeName>Tom&#xe1;s</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Extremadura, 10003, C&#xe1;ceres, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Heliyon</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672560</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-8440</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Circadian rhythm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hormonal homeostasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37809566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10558889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e19636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-8440(23)06844-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Refinetti R. Integration of biological clocks and rhythms. Compr. Physiol. 2011;2(2):1213&#x2013;1239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G., et al. Diurnal variation in cycling performance: influence of warm-up. J. Sports Sci. 2005;23(3):321&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15966350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redlin U., Mrosovsky N. Exercise and human circadian rhythms: what we know and what we need to know. Chronobiol. Int. 1997;14(2):221&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9095380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T. Human circadian rhythms and exercise. Crit. Rev. Biomed. Eng. 1990;18(3):165&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2286092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T., et al. Diurnal variation in temperature, mental and physical performance, and tasks specifically related to football (soccer) Chronobiol. Int. 2007;24(3):507&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17612948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessot N., et al. The influence of circadian rhythm on muscle activity and efficient force production during cycling at different pedal rates. J. Electromyogr. Kinesiol. 2007;17(2):176&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16563800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline C.E., et al. Circadian variation in swim performance. J. Appl. Physiol. 2007;102(2):641&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastings M.H., Herzog E.D. Clock genes, oscillators, and cellular networks in the suprachiasmatic nuclei. J. Biol. Rhythm. 2004;19(5):400&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15534320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buijs R., et al. Circadian and seasonal rhythms-the biological clock tunes the organs of the body: timing by hormones and the autonomic nervous system. J. Endocrinol. 2003;177(1):17&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12697033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guignard M.M., et al. Circadian rhythms in plasma levels of cortisol, dehydroepiandrosterone, &#x3b4;4-androstenedione, testosterone and dihydrotestosterone of healthy young men. Eur. J. Endocrinol. 1980;94(4):536&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6449126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes L.D., Bickerstaff G.F., Baker J.S. Interactions of cortisol, testosterone, and resistance training: influence of circadian rhythms. Chronobiol. Int. 2010;27(4):675&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20560706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard T., et al. Time-of-day effects in maximal anaerobic leg exercise. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 1997;77(1&#x2013;2):133&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9459533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irandoust K., et al. Effect of time-of-day-exercise in group settings on level of mood and depression of former elite male athletes. Int. J. Environ. Res. Publ. Health. 2019;16(19):3541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6801561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31546685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClean C., Davison G.W. Circadian clocks, redox homeostasis, and exercise: time to connect the dots? Antioxidants. 2022;11(2):256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8868136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35204138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D., et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann. Intern. Med. 2009;151(4):264&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala V., et al. Influence of circadian rhythms on sports performance. Chronobiol. Int. 2021;38(11):1522&#x2013;1536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34060402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cajochen C., Kr&#xe4;uchi K., Wirz&#x2010;Justice A. Role of melatonin in the regulation of human circadian rhythms and sleep. J. Neuroendocrinol. 2003;15(4):432&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12622846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamura H., Yamaguchi S., Yagita K. Molecular machinery of the circadian clock in mammals. Cell Tissue Res. 2002;309(1):47&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrier J., Monk T.H. Circadian rhythms of performance: new trends. Chronobiol. Int. 2000;17(6):719&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11128289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wever R.A. Springer Science &amp; Business Media; 2013. The Circadian System of Man: Results of Experiments under Temporal Isolation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellastella G., et al. Endocrine rhythms and sport: it is time to take time into account. J. Endocrinol. Invest. 2019;42(10):1137&#x2013;1147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30924095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantermann T F.S., Halle M., Schlangen L., Roenneberg T., Schmidt-Trucks&#xe4;ss A. The stimulating effect of bright light on physical performance depends on internal time. PLoS One. 2012;7(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3394763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22808224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serin Y., Tek N.A. Effect of circadian rhythm on metabolic processes and the regulation of energy balance. Ann. Nutr. Metabol. 2019;74(4):322&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31013492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabzevari Rad R., Mahmoodzadeh Hosseini H., Shirvani H. Circadian rhythm effect on military physical fitness and field training: a narrative review. Sport Sci. Health. 2021;17(1):43&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo W., Newton M.J., McGuigan M.R. Circadian rhythms in exercise performance: implications for hormonal and muscular adaptation. J. Sports Sci. Med. 2011;10(4):600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoyama S., Shibata S. Time-of-day-dependent physiological responses to meal and exercise. Front. Nutr. 2020;7:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7059348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32181258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H., Souissi N. The effect of training at a specific time of day: a review. J. Strength Condit Res. 2012;26(7):1984&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22531613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winget C.M., DeRoshia C.W., Holley D.C. Circadian rhythms and athletic performance. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 1985:498&#x2013;516. (pmid:3906341)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3906341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starkie R.L., et al. Effect of temperature on muscle metabolism during submaximal exercise in humans. Exp. Physiol. 1999;84(4):775&#x2013;784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10481233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smolensky M., Lamberg L. first ed. Henry Holt and Co.; New York: 2000. The Body Clock Guide to Better Health: How to Use Your Body's Natural Clock to Fight Illness and Achieve Maximum Health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata S., Tahara Y. Circadian rhythm and exercise. The Journal of Physical Fitness and Sports Medicine. 2014;3(1):65&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G., Speirs L. Diurnal variation in tennis service. Percept. Mot. Skills. 1998;86(3_suppl):1335&#x2013;1338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9700810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racinais S., et al. Time of day influences the environmental effects on muscle force and contractility. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2005;37(2):256&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15692321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huguet G., Touitou Y., Reinberg A. Diurnal changes in sport performance of 9-to 11-year-old school children. Chronobiol. Int. 1995;12(5):351&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qasrawi S.O., Pandi-Perumal S.R., BaHammam A.S. The effect of intermittent fasting during Ramadan on sleep, sleepiness, cognitive function, and circadian rhythm. Sleep Breath. 2017;21:577&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28190167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukelia B., Sabba A., Fogarty M. The effect of zeitgeber (Fasting and Exercise) on phase advance blood glucose circadian rhythms in endurance athletes. Int. J. Soc. Sci. Humanit. 2019;2(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleitman N. Biological rhythms and cycles. Physiol. Rev. 1949;29(1):1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18118978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baehr E.K., Revelle W., Eastman C.I. Individual differences in the phase and amplitude of the human circadian temperature rhythm: with an emphasis on morningness&#x2013;eveningness. J. Sleep Res. 2000;9(2):117&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10849238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grisham S.C. Diurnal variations in responses to exercise of ((MORNING types and ((EVENING types. J. Sports Med. 1988;28:213&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3230901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chelminski I., et al. Horne and Ostberg questionnaire: a score distribution in a large sample of young adults. Pers. Indiv. Differ. 1997;23(4):647&#x2013;652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youngstedt S.D., O'Connor P.J. The influence of air travel on athletic performance. Sports Med. 1999;28(3):197&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10541442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha-Hikim I., et al. Testosterone-induced increase in muscle size in healthy young men is associated with muscle fiber hypertrophy. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2002;283(1):E154&#x2013;E164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12067856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrando A.A., et al. Testosterone injection stimulates net protein synthesis but not tissue amino acid transport. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9815007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvorning T., et al. Suppression of endogenous testosterone production attenuates the response to strength training: a randomized, placebo-controlled, and blinded intervention study. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2006;291(6):E1325&#x2013;E1332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16868226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calbet J.L., et al. Salivary steroid changes and physical performance in highly trained cyclists. Int. J. Sports Med. 1993;14(3):111&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8509237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tafet G.E., et al. Correlation between cortisol level and serotonin uptake in patients with chronic stress and depression. Cognit. Affect Behav. Neurosci. 2001;1(4):388&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12467090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka R.M. Mechanisms of muscle fatigue: central factors and task dependency. J. Electromyogr. Kinesiol. 1995;5(3):141&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20719645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdez P. Homeostatic and circadian regulation of cognitive performance. Biol. Rhythm. Res. 2019;50(1):85&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaut A., et al. Maximal voluntary eccentric, isometric and concentric torque recovery following a concentric isokinetic exercise. Int. J. Sports Med. 2003;24(1):51&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12582952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquet B., et al. Muscle fatigue during concentric and eccentric contractions. Muscle Nerve: Official Journal of the American Association of Electrodiagnostic Medicine. 2000;23(11):1727&#x2013;1735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11054752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas A., et al. Effect of circadian rhythm of neuromuscular properties on muscle fatigue during concentric and eccentric isokinetic actions. Isokinet. Exerc. Sci. 2007;15(2):117&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xf8;llestad N.K. Measurement of human muscle fatigue. J. Neurosci. Methods. 1997;74(2):219&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9219890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borisenkov M., et al. Diurnal changes in the total antioxidant activity of human saliva. Hum. Physiol. 2007;33(3):375&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17619627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardona F. Periodic dip of lipidperoxidation in humans: a redox signal to synchronize peripheral circadian clocks? Med. Hypotheses. 2004;63(5):841&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15488658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benot S., et al. Physiological levels of melatonin contribute to the antioxidant capacity of human serum. J. Pineal Res. 1999;27(1):59&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10451025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan D.-X., et al. The pineal hormone melatonin inhibits DNA-adduct formation induced by the chemical carcinogen safrole in vivo. Cancer Lett. 1993;70(1&#x2013;2):65&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8330303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammouda O., et al. High intensity exercise affects diurnal variation of some biological markers in trained subjects. Int. J. Sports Med. 2012;33(11):886&#x2013;891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22791622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes M.R., et al. Chronobiological effects on exercise performance and selected physiological responses. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 1998;77(3):249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9535586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalton B., McNaughton L., Davoren B. Circadian rhythms have no effect on cycling performance. Int. J. Sports Med. 1997;18(7):538&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9414078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammouda O., et al. Diurnal variations of plasma homocysteine, total antioxidant status, and biological markers of muscle injury during repeated sprint: effect on performance and muscle fatigue&#x2014;a pilot study. Chronobiol. Int. 2011;28(10):958&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22080741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N., et al. Effect of time of day on aerobic contribution to the 30&#x2010;s Wingate test performance. Chronobiol. Int. 2007;24(4):739&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17701684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammouda O C.H., Chaouachi A., Chahed H., Bellimem H., Chamari K., Souissi N. Time-of-day effects on biochemical responses to soccer-specific endurance in elite Tunisian football players. J. Sports Sci. 2013;31(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23311995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J., et al. Changes in sleep, mood and subjective and objective responses to physical performance during the daytime in Ramadan. Biol. Rhythm. Res. 2009;40(5):367&#x2013;383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsyth J., Reilly T. Circadian rhythms in blood lactate concentration during incremental ergometer rowing. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2004;92(1):69&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14991328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinges D.F., et al. Cumulative sleepiness, mood disturbance, and psychomotor vigilance performance decrements during a week of sleep restricted to 4&#x2013;5 hours per night. Sleep. 1997;20(4):267&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9231952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pejovic S., et al. Effects of recovery sleep after one work week of mild sleep restriction on interleukin-6 and cortisol secretion and daytime sleepiness and performance. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2013;305(7):E890&#x2013;E896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3798707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23941878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S.L., Jeukendrup A.E. Does overtraining exist? Sports Med. 2004;34(14):967&#x2013;981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15571428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R., et al. Prevention, diagnosis and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: joint consensus statement of the European college of sport science (ECSS) and the American college of sports medicine (ACSM) Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2013;13(1):1&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadegiani F.A., Kater C.E. Hormonal aspects of overtraining syndrome: a systematic review. BMC Sports Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation. 2017;9(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5541747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28785411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chase J.D., et al. One night of sleep restriction following heavy exercise impairs 3-km cycling time-trial performance in the morning. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metabol. 2017;42(9):909&#x2013;915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robson-Ansley P.J., Gleeson M., Ansley L. Fatigue management in the preparation of Olympic athletes. J. Sports Sci. 2009;27(13):1409&#x2013;1420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19221925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S.L. Nutrition, sleep and recovery. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2008;8(2):119&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besedovsky L., Lange T., Born J. Sleep and immune function. Pflueg. Arch. Eur. J. Physiol. 2012;463(1):121&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3256323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22071480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;kerstedt T., Kecklund G., Axelsson J. Impaired sleep after bedtime stress and worries. Biol. Psychol. 2007;76(3):170&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17884278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen H., et al. Stress vulnerability and the effects of moderate daily stress on sleep polysomnography and subjective sleepiness. J. Sleep Res. 2013;22(1):50&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22835074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meerlo P., Sgoifo A., Suchecki D. Restricted and disrupted sleep: effects on autonomic function, neuroendocrine stress systems and stress responsivity. Sleep Med. Rev. 2008;12(3):197&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18222099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C., Louis J., Aubry A., Bonnet G., Duffield R., Le Muer, and Y. Evidence of disturbed sleep patterns and increased illness in functionally overreached endurance athletes. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2014;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24091995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C., et al. The impact of training schedules on the sleep and fatigue of elite athletes. Chronobiol. Int. 2014;31(10):1160&#x2013;1168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roach G.D., et al. The sleep of elite athletes at sea level and high altitude: a comparison of sea-level natives and high-altitude natives (ISA3600) Br. J. Sports Med. 2013;47(Suppl 1):i114&#x2013;i120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3903309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24282197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M., et al. Sleep/wake behaviour of endurance cyclists before and during competition. J. Sports Sci. 2015;33(3):293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25105558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C., Roach G.D. Sleep duration is reduced in elite athletes following night-time competition. Chronobiol. Int. 2016;33(6):667&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27097227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd A.S., Toth A.T., Stanford F.C. Racial disparities in obesity treatment. Current obesity reports. 2018;7(2):130&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6066592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29616469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruscalupi D.G.a.G. Circadian rhythms and hormonal homeostasis: pathophysiological implications. Biology Bulletin of the Russian Academy of Sciences. 2017;6:10. doi: 10.3390/biology6010010. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology6010010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5372003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28165421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel S.A., et al. Circadian clocks govern calorie restriction&#x2014;mediated life span extension through BMAL1&#x2010;and IGF&#x2010;1&#x2010;dependent mechanisms. Faseb. J. 2016;30(4):1634&#x2013;1642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4799504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26700733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrowsky R., et al. Effects of diurnal sleep on secretion of cortisol, luteinizing hormone, and growth hormone in man. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 1994;78(3):683&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8126142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weibel L., M F., Spiegel K., Gronfier C., Brandenberger G. Growth hormone secretion in night workers. Chronobiol. Int. 1997;14(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9042551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holl R.W., et al. Thirty-second sampling of plasma growth hormone in man: correlation with sleep stages. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 1991;72(4):854&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2005213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cauter E., et al. A quantitative estimation of growth hormone secretion in normal man: reproducibility and relation to sleep and time of day. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 1992;74(6):1441&#x2013;1450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1592892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Liempt S., et al. Decreased nocturnal growth hormone secretion and sleep fragmentation in combat-related posttraumatic stress disorder; potential predictors of impaired memory consolidation. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2011;36(9):1361&#x2013;1369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21489700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verrillo E., et al. Effects of replacement therapy on sleep architecture in children with growth hormone deficiency. Sleep Med. 2012;13(5):496&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22437138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain S.W., et al. Sex differences in phase angle of entrainment and melatonin amplitude in humans. J. Biol. Rhythm. 2010;25(4):288&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20679498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooley J.J., et al. Exposure to room light before bedtime suppresses melatonin onset and shortens melatonin duration in humans. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2011;96(3):E463&#x2013;E472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3047226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Teclemariam-Mesbah, G.J.T.H., F. Postema, J. Wortel, and R. M. Buijs, Anatomical demonstration of the suprachiasmatic nucleus-pineal pathway<i>.</i> Comparative Neurology, 199. 406(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10096604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharkey K.M., Fogg L.F., Eastman C.I. Effects of melatonin administration on daytime sleep after simulated night shift work. J. Sleep Res. 2001;10(3):181&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3679650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11696071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aeschbach D., et al. Use of transdermal melatonin delivery to improve sleep maintenance during daytime. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 2009;86(4):378&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2909186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19606092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Den Heuvel C.J., Reid K.J., Dawson D. Effect of atenolol on nocturnal sleep and temperature in young men: reversal by pharmacological doses of melatonin. Physiol. Behav. 1997;61(6):795&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9177549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheer F., et al. Reduced sleep efficiency in cervical spinal cord injury; association with abolished night time melatonin secretion. Spinal Cord. 2006;44(2):78&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2882209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16130027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyatt J.K., et al. Sleep-facilitating effect of exogenous melatonin in healthy young men and women is circadian-phase dependent. Sleep. 2006;29(5):609&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16774150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess H.J., et al. Human phase response curves to three days of daily melatonin: 0.5 mg versus 3.0 mg. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2010;95(7):3325&#x2013;3331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20410229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sack R.L., et al. Entrainment of free-running circadian rhythms by melatonin in blind people. N. Engl. J. Med. 2000;343(15):1070&#x2013;1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11027741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan J.S., Czeisler C. Persistence of the circadian thyrotropin rhythm under constant conditions and after light-induced shifts of circadian phase. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 1994;79(2):508&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8045970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehr T.A., et al. Conservation of photoperiod-responsive mechanisms in humans. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 1993;265(4):R846&#x2013;R857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8238456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goichot B., et al. Nocturnal plasma thyrotropin variations are related to slow&#x2010;wave sleep. J. Sleep Res. 1992;1(3):186&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10607049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronfier C., et al. Temporal link between plasma thyrotropin levels and electroencephalographic activity in man. Neurosci. Lett. 1995;200(2):97&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8614572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehr T., Aeschbach D., Duncan W., Jr. Evidence for a biological dawn and dusk in the human circadian timing system. J. Physiol. 2001;535(Pt 3):937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11559786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheer F.A., et al. Adverse metabolic and cardiovascular consequences of circadian misalignment. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2009;106(11):4453&#x2013;4458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windle R., et al. Ultradian rhythm of basal corticosterone release in the female rat: dynamic interaction with the response to acute stress. Endocrinology. 1998;139(2):443&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9449609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young E.A., Abelson J., Lightman S.L. Cortisol pulsatility and its role in stress regulation and health. Front. Neuroendocrinol. 2004;25(2):69&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buijs R.M., et al. Anatomical and functional demonstration of a multisynaptic suprachiasmatic nucleus adrenal (cortex) pathway. Eur. J. Neurosci. 1999;11(5):1535&#x2013;1544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10215906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiger A. Sleep and the hypothalamo&#x2013;pituitary&#x2013;adrenocortical system. Sleep Med. Rev. 2002;6(2):125&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esler W.P., et al. Small-molecule ghrelin receptor antagonists improve glucose tolerance, suppress appetite, and promote weight loss. Endocrinology. 2007;148(11):5175&#x2013;5185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17656463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement K., et al. A mutation in the human leptin receptor gene causes obesity and pituitary dysfunction. Nature. 1998;392(6674):398&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9537324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluge M., et al. Ghrelin increases slow wave sleep and stage 2 sleep and decreases stage 1 sleep and REM sleep in elderly men but does not affect sleep in elderly women. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2010;35(2):297&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19647945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzaja A., et al. Sleep enhances nocturnal plasma ghrelin levels in healthy subjects. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2004;286(6):E963&#x2013;E967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14871884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuessler P., et al. Nocturnal ghrelin levels&#x2013;relationship to sleep EEG, the levels of growth hormone, ACTH and cortisol&#x2013;and gender differences. J. Sleep Res. 2005;14(4):329&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16364133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea S.A., et al. Independent circadian and sleep/wake regulation of adipokines and glucose in humans. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2005;90(5):2537&#x2013;2544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15687326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghani S., Mehri S., Hosseinzadeh H. The effects of Crataegus pinnatifida (Chinese hawthorn) on metabolic syndrome: a review. Iranian journal of basic medical sciences. 2019;22(5):460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6556496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31217924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastings M.H., Maywood E.S., Brancaccio M. Generation of circadian rhythms in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2018;19(8):453&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi J.S. Transcriptional architecture of the mammalian circadian clock. Nat. Rev. Genet. 2017;18(3):164&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5501165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27990019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westwood M.L., et al. The evolutionary ecology of circadian rhythms in infection. Nature ecology &amp; evolution. 2019;3(4):552&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7614806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30886375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man K., Loudon A., Chawla A. Immunity around the clock. Science. 2016;354(6315):999&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5247264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27885005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheiermann C., Kunisaki Y., Frenette P.S. Circadian control of the immune system. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2013;13(3):190&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4090048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23391992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacheco-Bernal I., Becerril-P&#xe9;rez F., Aguilar-Arnal L. Circadian rhythms in the three-dimensional genome: implications of chromatin interactions for cyclic transcription. Clin. Epigenet. 2019;11(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6521413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31092281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haus E., Smolensky M.H. Biologic rhythms in the immune system. Chronobiol. Int. 1999;16(5):581&#x2013;622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitrov S., et al. Cortisol and epinephrine control opposing circadian rhythms in T cell subsets. Blood, the Journal of the American Society of Hematology. 2009;113(21):5134&#x2013;5143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2686184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19293427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheiermann C., et al. Adrenergic nerves govern circadian leukocyte recruitment to tissues. Immunity. 2012;37(2):290&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3428436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22863835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley J.A., et al. Integrative biology of exercise. Cell. 2014;159(4):738&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25417152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas J.M., et al. Circadian rhythm phase shifts caused by timed exercise vary with chronotype. JCI insight. 2020;5(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y., et al. Circadian rhythm gene expression and daily melatonin levels vary in athletes and sedentary males. Biol. Rhythm. Res. 2018;49(2):237&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinert D., Gubin D. The impact of physical activity on the circadian system: benefits for health, performance and Wellbeing. Appl. Sci. 2022;12(18):9220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J., et al. The circadian rhythm of core temperature: origin and some implications for exercise performance. Chronobiol. Int. 2005;22(2):207&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16021839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezagouri S., et al. Physiological and molecular dissection of daily variance in exercise capacity. Cell Metabol. 2019;30(1):78&#x2013;91. e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31006590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G., Reilly T. Circadian variation in sports performance. Sports Med. 1996;21(4):292&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8726347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A., et al. Relationship between biomarkers of muscle damage and redox status in response to a weightlifting training session: effect of time-of-day. Acta Physiol. Hung. 2016;103(2):243&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28639862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A C.H., Trabelsi K., Padulo J., Turki M., El Abed K., Hoekelmann A., Hakim A. Temporal specificity of training: intra-day effects on biochemical responses and Olympic weightlifting performances. J. Sports Sci. 2015;33(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25117722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H., et al. Diurnal variations in physical performances related to football in young soccer players. Asian J. Sports Med. 2012;3(3):139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23012632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H., et al. Diurnal variation of short-term repetitive maximal performance and psychological variables in elite judo athletes. Front. Physiol. 2018;9:1499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6212582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30416454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A., et al. Acute and delayed responses of C-reactive protein, malondialdehyde and antioxidant markers after resistance training session in elite weightlifters: effect of time of day. Chronobiol. Int. 2015;32(9):1211&#x2013;1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26453313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henst R.H., et al. A chronotype comparison of South African and Dutch marathon runners: the role of scheduled race start times and effects on performance. Chronobiol. Int. 2015;32(6):858&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26102236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Cagno A., et al. Time of day&#x2013;effects on motor coordination and reactive strength in elite athletes and untrained adolescents. J. Sports Sci. Med. 2013;12(1):182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copenhaver E.A., Diamond A.B. The value of sleep on athletic performance, injury, and recovery in the young athlete. Pediatr. Ann. 2017;46(3):e106&#x2013;e111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28287684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddick&#x2010;Collins L., et al. The Big Breakfast Study: chrono&#x2010;nutrition influence on energy expenditure and bodyweight. Nutr. Bull. 2018;43(2):174&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5969247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29861661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddick&#x2010;Collins L.C., Morgan P.J., Johnstone A.M. Mealtime: a circadian disruptor and determinant of energy balance? J. Neuroendocrinol. 2020;32(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32662577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickel L., Sung H.-K. Feeding rhythms and the circadian regulation of metabolism. Front. Nutr. 2020;7:39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32363197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahara Y., Shibata S. Chrono-biology, chrono-pharmacology, and chrono-nutrition. J. Pharmacol. Sci. 2014;124(3):320&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24572815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saper C.B., Scammell T.E., Lu J. Hypothalamic regulation of sleep and circadian rhythms. Nature. 2005;437(7063):1257&#x2013;1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16251950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S.L. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silber B., Schmitt J. Effects of tryptophan loading on human cognition, mood, and sleep. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2010;34(3):387&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19715722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afaghi A., O'Connor H., Chow C.M. High-glycemic-index carbohydrate meals shorten sleep onset. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2007;85(2):426&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17284739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peuhkuri K., Sihvola N., Korpela R. Diet promotes sleep duration and quality. Nutr. Res. (N.Y.) 2012;32(5):309&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22652369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golem D.L., et al. An integrative review of sleep for nutrition professionals. Adv. Nutr. 2014;5(6):742&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4224209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25398735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ord&#xf3;&#xf1;ez F.M., et al. Sleep improvement in athletes: use of nutritional supplements. Am. J. Sports Med. 2017;34:93&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandner M.A., et al. Sleep symptoms associated with intake of specific dietary nutrients. J. Sleep Res. 2014;23(1):22&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3866235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23992533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter J., Horne J. Bed-time food supplements and sleep: effects of different carbohydrate levels. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1981;51(4):426&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6164541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H.-H., et al. Effect of kiwifruit consumption on sleep quality in adults with sleep problems. Asia Pac. J. Clin. Nutr. 2011;20(2):169&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21669584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valtonen M., et al. Effect of melatonin-rich night-time milk on sleep and activity in elderly institutionalized subjects. Nord. J. Psychiatr. 2005;59(3):217&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido M., et al. Jerte Valley cherry-enriched diets improve nocturnal rest and increase 6-sulfatoxymelatonin and total antioxidant capacity in the urine of middle-aged and elderly humans. Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biomedical Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2010;65(9):909&#x2013;914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20547498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G., et al. Effect of tart cherry juice (Prunus cerasus) on melatonin levels and enhanced sleep quality. Eur. J. Nutr. 2012;51(8):909&#x2013;916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22038497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas D.T.E., K A., Burke L.M. American college of sports medicine joint position Statement.Nutrition and athletic performance. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2016;48</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Close G.L., et al. New strategies in sport nutrition to increase exercise performance. Free Radical Biol. Med. 2016;98:144&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26855422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup A.E. Periodized nutrition for athletes. Sports Med. 2017;47(1):51&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5371625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roehrs T., Roth T. Sleep, sleepiness, and alcohol use. Alcohol Res. Health. 2001;25(2):101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6707127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11584549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardo-Mendon&#xe7;a R.C., et al. The benefits of four weeks of melatonin treatment on circadian patterns in resistance-trained athletes. Chronobiol. Int. 2015;32(8):1125&#x2013;1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheikh M., et al. Melatonin ingestion after exhaustive late-evening exercise improves sleep quality and quantity, and short-term performances in teenage athletes. Chronobiol. Int. 2018;35(9):1281&#x2013;1293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29846091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G., et al. Are there hangover-effects on physical performance when melatonin is ingested by athletes before nocturnal sleep? Int. J. Sports Med. 2001;22(3):232&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11354528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghattassi K., et al. Morning melatonin ingestion and diurnal variation of short-term maximal performances in soccer players. Acta Physiol. Hung. 2016;103(1):94&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27030631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson C., et al. Protein source tryptophan versus pharmaceutical grade tryptophan as an efficacious treatment for chronic insomnia. Nutr. Neurosci. 2005;8(2):121&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16053244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rondanelli M., et al. The effect of melatonin, magnesium, and zinc on primary insomnia in long&#x2010;term care facility residents in Italy: a double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled clinical trial. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2011;59(1):82&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21226679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires M.L.N., et al. Acute effects of low doses of melatonin on the sleep of young healthy subjects. J. Pineal Res. 2001;31(4):326&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11703562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus C.R., et al. Evening intake of &#x3b1;-lactalbumin increases plasma tryptophan availability and improves morning alertness and brain measures of attention. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2005;81(5):1026&#x2013;1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Flores M., et al. Effects of melatonin on sports performance: a systematic review. Journal of Exercise Physiology Online. 2018;21(5)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meoli A.L., et al. Oral nonprescription treatment for insomnia: an evaluation of products with limited evidence. J. Clin. Sleep Med. 2005;1(2):173&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17561634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A., Chtourou H., Souissi N. Effect of time-of-day on biochemical markers in response to physical exercise. J. Strength Condit Res. 2017;31(1):272&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27191691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joubert L.M., Manore M.M. Exercise, nutrition, and homocysteine. Int. J. Sport Nutr. Exerc. Metabol. 2006;16(4):341&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17136938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazyar Y., et al. An Animal Model Of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease. 2015. Effect of endurance exercise training and gallic acid on tumor necrosis factor-?</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanabrocki E., et al. Ten-year-replicated circadian profiles for 36 physiological, serological and urinary variables in healthy men. Chronobiol. Int. 1988;5(3):237&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3219757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera-Coll A., Fuentes-Arderiu X., D&#xed;ez-Noguera A. Circadian rhythms of serum concentrations of 12 enzymes of clinical interest. Chronobiol. Int. 1993;10(3):190&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8100488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri M.A., et al. One night of partial sleep deprivation affects biomarkers of cardiac damage, but not cardiovascular and lipid profiles, in young athletes. Biol. Rhythm. Res. 2015;46(5):715&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knutson K.L., et al. The metabolic consequences of sleep deprivation. Sleep Med. Rev. 2007;11(3):163&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1991337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17442599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neill J.S., Reddy A.B. Circadian clocks in human red blood cells. Nature. 2011;469(7331):498&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3040566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21270888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedelmalek S., et al. Effects of partial sleep deprivation on proinflammatory cytokines, growth hormone, and steroid hormone concentrations during repeated brief sprint interval exercise. Chronobiol. Int. 2013;30(4):502&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rae D.E., et al. One night of partial sleep deprivation impairs recovery from a single exercise training session. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2017;117(4):699&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28247026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzoubi K.H., et al. The combined effect of sleep deprivation and Western diet on spatial learning and memory: role of BDNF and oxidative stress. J. Mol. Neurosci. 2013;50(1):124&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22956188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savic-Radojevic A., et al. Effect of hyperglycemia and hyperinsulinemia on glutathione peroxidase activity in non-obese women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Hormones (Basel) 2015;14(1):101&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25402379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smolensky M.H., Dalonzo G.E. Medical chronobiology concepts and appications. Am, Rev, Respir. 1993:147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8494195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melhim A.F. Investigation of circadian rhythms in peak power and mean power of female physical education students. Int. J. Sports Med. 1993;14(6):303&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8407059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borb&#xe9;ly A.A., et al. The two&#x2010;process model of sleep regulation: a reappraisal. J. Sleep Res. 2016;25(2):131&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26762182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borb&#xe9;ly A.A. A two process model of sleep regulation. Hum. Neurobiol. 1982;1(3):195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7185792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czeisler C.A., et al. Stability, precision, and near-24-hour period of the human circadian pacemaker. Science. 1999;284(5423):2177&#x2013;2181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10381883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin M.R., Olmstead R., Carroll J.E. Sleep disturbance, sleep duration, and inflammation: a systematic review and meta-analysis of cohort studies and experimental sleep deprivation. Biol. Psychiatr. 2016;80(1):40&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26140821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank M.G. The mystery of sleep function: current perspectives and future directions. Rev. Neurosci. 2006;17(4):375&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17139839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin M.R. Why sleep is important for health: a psychoneuroimmunology perspective. Annu. Rev. Psychol. 2015;66:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4961463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25061767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuomilehto H., et al. Sleep of professional athletes: underexploited potential to improve health and performance. J. Sports Sci. 2017;35(7):704&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27173843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlacher D., et al. Sleep habits in German athletes before important competitions or games. J. Sports Sci. 2011;29(8):859&#x2013;866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21506041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski M.D., et al. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. J. Pediatr. Orthop. 2014;34(2):129&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Rosen P., et al. Too little sleep and an unhealthy diet could increase the risk of sustaining a new injury in adolescent elite athletes. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 2017;27(11):1364&#x2013;1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27539373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meney I., et al. The effect of one night's sleep deprivation on temperature, mood, and physical performance in subjects with different amounts of habitual physical activity. Chronobiol. Int. 1998;15(4):349&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9706412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Zwart B.C., et al. After-effects of night work on physical performance capacity and sleep quality in relation to age. Int. Arch. Occup. Environ. Health. 1993;65(4):259&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8144237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin B.J. Effect of sleep deprivation on tolerance of prolonged exercise. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 1981;47(4):345&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7199438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N., et al. Effects of one night's sleep deprivation on anaerobic performance the following day. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2003;89(3):359&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12736846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N., et al. Effect of time of day and partial sleep deprivation on short&#x2010;term, high&#x2010;power output. Chronobiol. Int. 2008;25(6):1062&#x2013;1076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19005905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougard C., Davenne D. Effects of sleep deprivation and time-of-day on selected physical abilities in off-road motorcycle riders. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2012;112(1):59&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21479811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F., et al. Effects of a selective sleep deprivation on subsequent anaerobic performance. Int. J. Sports Med. 1996;17(2):115&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8833713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodgers C., et al. Sleep deprivation: effects on work capacity, self-paced walking, contractile properties and perceived exertion. Sleep. 1995;18(1):30&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7761740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T., Piercy M. The effect of partial sleep deprivation on weight-lifting performance. Ergonomics. 1994;37(1):107&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8112265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J., et al. The role of a short post-lunch nap in improving cognitive, motor, and sprint performance in participants with partial sleep deprivation. J. Sports Sci. 2007;25(14):1557&#x2013;1566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T., Atkinson G., Waterhouse J.M. Oxford University Press; 1997. Biological Rhythms and Exercise.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C.D., et al. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep. 2011;34(7):943&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21731144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumert P.A., et al. The acute effects of twenty-four hours of sleep loss on the performance of nationalcaliber male collegiate weightlifters. J. Strength Condit Res. 2007;21(4):1146&#x2013;1154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athey A.B., Ross M.J. 2019. Sleep and Health Among Collegiate Student Athletes.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31472156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C.D., et al. Poor sleep quality and insufficient sleep of a collegiate student-athlete population. Sleep health. 2018;4(3):251&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29776619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz J., Simon R.D., Jr. Sleep extension improves serving accuracy: a study with college varsity tennis players. Physiol. Behav. 2015;151:541&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26325012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Services, U.D.o.H.a.H. Sleep health objectives. Mar. 2015;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemola S., et al. Adolescents' electronic media use at night, sleep disturbance, and depressive symptoms in the smartphone age. J. Youth Adolesc. 2015;44(2):405&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25204836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimputkar S., et al. Prospects for LED lighting. Nat. Photonics. 2009;3(4):180&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gringras P., et al. Bigger, brighter, bluer-better? Current light-emitting devices&#x2013;adverse sleep properties and preventative strategies. Front. Public Health. 2015;3:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4602096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26528465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cajochen C., et al. Evening exposure to a light-emitting diodes (LED)-backlit computer screen affects circadian physiology and cognitive performance. J. Appl. Physiol. 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munch M., et al. Wavelength-dependent effects of evening light exposure on sleep architecture and sleep EEG power density in men. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2006;290(5):R1421&#x2013;R1428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16439671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannibal J., et al. Melanopsin expressing human retinal ganglion cells: subtypes, distribution, and intraretinal connectivity. J. Comp. Neurol. 2017;525(8):1934&#x2013;1961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28160289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern S., et al. Glucose metabolic changes in the prefrontal cortex are associated with HPA axis response to a psychosocial stressor. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2008;33(4):517&#x2013;529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2601562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18337016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt C., et al. Light exposure via a head&#x2010;mounted device suppresses melatonin and improves vigilant attention without affecting cortisol and comfort. PsyCh J. 2018;7(4):163&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29943899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leproult R., et al. Transition from dim to bright light in the morning induces an immediate elevation of cortisol levels. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2001;86(1):151&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11231993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang A.-M., et al. Evening use of light-emitting eReaders negatively affects sleep, circadian timing, and next-morning alertness. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2015;112(4):1232&#x2013;1237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4313820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25535358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knufinke M., et al. Restricting short-wavelength light in the evening to improve sleep in recreational athletes&#x2013;A pilot study. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2019;19(6):728&#x2013;735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30427265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards B.J., Lindsay K., Waterhouse J. Effect of time of day on the accuracy and consistency of the badminton serve. Ergonomics. 2005;48(11&#x2013;14):1488&#x2013;1498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16338715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T., Down A. Perceptual and Motor Skills; 1986. Circadian Variation in the Standing Broad Jump.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier A., et al. Diurnal rhythm of the muscular performance of elbow flexors during isometric contractions. Chronobiol. Int. 1996;13(2):135&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8877122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier A., et al. Orcadian rhythm in the torque developed by elbow flexors during isometric contraction effect of sampling schedules. Chronobiol. Int. 1997;14(3):287&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9167889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier A., et al. Time of day effects on isometric and isokinetic torque developed during elbow flexion in humans. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2001;84(3):249&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11320645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N., et al. Circadian rhythms in two types of anaerobic cycle leg exercise: force-velocity and 30-s Wingate tests. Int. J. Sports Med. 2004;25(1):14&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14750007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T., Down A. Investigation of circadian rhythms in anaerobic power and capacity of the legs. J. Sports Med. Phys. Fit. 1992;32(4):343&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1293415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javierre C., et al. Influence of sleep and meal schedules on performance peaks in competitive sprinters. Int. J. Sports Med. 1996;17(6):404&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8884413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilcher J.J., Huffcutt A.I. Effects of sleep deprivation on performance: a meta-analysis. Sleep. 1996;19(4):318&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8776790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul K.N., Turek F.W., Kryger M.H. Influence of sex on sleep regulatory mechanisms. J. Wom. Health. 2008;17(7):1201&#x2013;1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18710368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thordstein M.L.N., et al. Sex differences in electrocortical activity in human neonates. Neuroreport. 2006;17(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16837847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menna-Barreto L., et al. The sleep/wake cycle in 4-to 14-month old children: general aspects and sex differences. Brazilian Journal of Medical and Biological Research= Revista Brasileira de Pesquisas Medicas e Biologicas. 1989;22(1):103&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2758163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy E., et al. Gender-related physiologic differences in human neonates and the greater vulnerability of males to developmental brain disorders. J. Gender-Specific Med. (JGSM): JGSM: the official journal of the Partnership for Women's Health at Columbia. 2001;4(1):41&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11324239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roenneberg T., et al. A marker for the end of adolescence. Curr. Biol. 2004;14(24):R1038&#x2013;R1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15620633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagenauer M.H., Lee T.M. The neuroendocrine control of the circadian system: adolescent chronotype. Front. Neuroendocrinol. 2012;33(3):211&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4762453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22634481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A., et al. Sleep and the transition to adolescence: a longitudinal study. Sleep. 2009;32(12):1602&#x2013;1609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20041596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manber R., Baker F., Gress J. Sex differences in sleep and sleep disorders: a focus on women's sleep. Int J Sleep Disorders. 2006;1(1):7&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Wing Y.-K. Sex differences in insomnia: a meta-analysis. Sleep. 2006;29(1):85&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16453985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse D.J., et al. EEG spectral analysis in primary insomnia: NREM period effects and sex differences. Sleep. 2008;31(12):1673&#x2013;1682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2603490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19090323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mong J.A., et al. Sleep, rhythms, and the endocrine brain: influence of sex and gonadal hormones. J. Neurosci. 2011;31(45):16107&#x2013;16116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3249406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22072663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armitage R. Sex differences in slow-wave activity in response to sleep deprivation. Sleep Res. Online. 2001;4:33&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dijk D.J., Beersma D.G., Bloem G.M. Sex differences in the sleep EEG of young adults: visual scoring and spectral analysis. Sleep. 1989;12(6):500&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2595173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlers C., Kupfer D. Slow&#x2010;wave sleep: do young adult men and women age differently? J. Sleep Res. 1997;6(3):211&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9358400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul K.N., et al. Diurnal sex differences in the sleep-wake cycle of mice are dependent on gonadal function. Sleep. 2006;29(9):1211&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17040009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid K.J. Assessment of circadian rhythms. Neurol. Clin. 2019;37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6857846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31256786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touati S., et al. Exercise training protects against atherosclerotic risk factors through vascular NADPH oxidase, extracellular signal&#x2010;regulated kinase 1/2 and stress&#x2010;activated protein kinase/c&#x2010;J un N&#x2010;terminal kinase downregulation in obese rats. Clin. Exp. Pharmacol. Physiol. 2015;42(2):179&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25399833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezanipour M., et al. The effect of weight reduction on antioxidant enzymes and their association with dietary intake of vitamins A, C and E. Arquivos Brasileiros Endocrinol. Metabol. 2014;58:744&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25372584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougoulia M., Triantos A., Koliakos G. Plasma interleukin-6 levels, glutathione peroxidase and isoprostane in obese women before and after weight loss. Association with cardiovascular risk factors. Hormones-Athens- 2006;5(3):192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wycherley T., et al. Effect of caloric restriction with and without exercise training on oxidative stress and endothelial function in obese subjects with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes. Metabol. 2008;10(11):1062&#x2013;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18435772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer R.J., et al. Postprandial oxidative stress in response to dextrose and lipid meals of differing size. Lipids Health Dis. 2010;9(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2915990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Fiskum G., Schubert D. Generation of reactive oxygen species by the mitochondrial electron transport chain. J. Neurochem. 2002;80(5):780&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11948241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer R.J., et al. A 21 day Daniel Fast improves selected biomarkers of antioxidant status and oxidative stress in men and women. Nutr. Metab. 2011;8(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3068072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21414232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy C.G., et al. High-fat feeding, but not strenuous exercise, increases blood oxidative stress in trained men. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metabol. 2013;38(0):33&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23368826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg E.L., et al. Lifespan&#x2010;extending caloric restriction or m TOR inhibition impair adaptive immunity of old mice by distinct mechanisms. Aging Cell. 2015;14(1):130&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4326902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25424641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jov&#xe9; M., et al. Caloric restriction reveals a metabolomic and lipidomic signature in liver of male mice. Aging Cell. 2014;13(5):828&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4331741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25052291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohal R.S., Forster M.J. Caloric restriction and the aging process: a critique. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 2014;73:366&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4111977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24941891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noakes T.D. Low-carbohydrate and high-fat intake can manage obesity and associated conditions: occasional survey. S. Afr. Med. J. 2013;103(11):826&#x2013;830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24148165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremsdorf R.A., et al. Effects of a high-protein diet on regulation of phosphorus homeostasis. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2013;98(3):1207&#x2013;1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3590482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23393178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mennen L.I., et al. Consumption of foods rich in flavonoids is related to a decreased cardiovascular risk in apparently healthy French women. J. Nutr. 2004;134(4):923&#x2013;926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15051848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urquiaga I., Leighton F. Plant polyphenol antioxidants and oxidative stress. Biol. Res. 2000;33(2):55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15693271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R.H. Health benefits of fruit and vegetables are from additive and synergistic combinations of phytochemicals. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2003;78(3):517S&#x2013;520S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12936943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y., et al. Cruciferous vegetable intake is inversely correlated with circulating levels of proinflammatory markers in women. J. Acad. Nutr. Diet. 2014;114(5):700&#x2013;708. e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4063312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24630682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feskanich D., et al. Prospective study of fruit and vegetable consumption and risk of lung cancer among men and women. J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 2000;92(22):1812&#x2013;1823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11078758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>