<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36287181</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Long-Haul Travel on Recovery and Performance in Elite Athletes: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3234</StartPage><EndPage>3245</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3234-3245</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004021</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rossiter, A, Warrington, GD, and Comyns, TM. Effects of long-haul travel on recovery and performance in elite athletes: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 36(11): 3234-3245, 2022-Elite athletes are often required to travel long-haul (LH) across numerous time zones for training or competition. However, the extent to which LH travel affects elite athlete performance remains largely unknown. The purpose of this systematic literature review was to critically evaluate available evidence on the effects of LH travel on elite athlete psychometric, physiological, sleep, and performance markers. Electronic database searches of PubMed, SPORTDiscus, Scopus, and Web of Science were conducted in accordance with Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines. Studies were eligible for inclusion if subjects were identified as elite athletes who embarked on a LH flight (&gt;6 hours) and used an outcome measurement of recovery or performance after the flight. Studies that were retrospective, used light therapy or pharmacological interventions were not included. Of 2,719 records assessed, 14 studies comprising a total of 197 athletes from 6 sports met the inclusion criteria. There was an increase in perceived jet lag and disturbance to various physiological markers after LH travel; however, there was minimal disturbance in other psychometric markers. Sleep was not negatively affected by LH travel. Of 10 studies that assessed performance, 3 found decrements in indirect markers of performance. Elite athletes perceived themselves to be jet lagged and experienced disturbance to various physiological mechanisms after LH travel; however, the effect on performance was inconclusive. Future research would benefit from higher quality studies with improved control measures, larger sample sizes from a wider variety of sports, and use of ecologically valid measures of circadian rhythm and athletic performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rossiter</LastName><ForeName>Antonia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Ireland Institute, National Sports Campus, Abbotstown, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warrington</LastName><ForeName>Giles D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Human Performance Research Group, Health Research Institute, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Comyns</LastName><ForeName>Thomas M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Human Performance Research Group, Health Research Institute, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020179" MajorTopicYN="Y">Jet Lag Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014195" MajorTopicYN="N">Travel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36287181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202211000-00034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arendt J. Managing jet lag: Some of the problems and possible new solutions. Sleep Med Rev 13: 249&#x2013;256, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendt J, Marks V. Physiological changes underlying jet lag. BMJ 284: 144&#x2013;146, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Batterham AM, Dowdall N, Thompson A, van Drongelen A. From animal cage to aircraft cabin: An overview of evidence translation in jet lag research. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 2459&#x2013;2468, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bin YS, Postnova S, Cistulli PA. What works for jetlag? A systematic review of non-pharmacological interventions. Sleep Med Rev 43: 47&#x2013;59, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broatch JR, Bishop DJ, Zadow EK, Halson S. Effects of sports compression socks on performance, physiological, and hematological alterations after long-haul air travel in elite female volleyballers. J Strength Cond Res 33: 492&#x2013;501, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Cholley Y, Lambert P. Psychometric and physiological responses to a preseason competitive camp in the heat with a 6-hour time difference in elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 176&#x2013;181, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullock N, Cox AJ, Martin DT, Marino FE. Resting salivary and plasma cortisol in elite athletes following long-haul travel from Australia to Canada. J Sci Med Sport 12: 300&#x2013;302, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullock N, Martin DT, Ross A, Rosemond D, Marino FE. Effect of long haul travel on maximal sprint performance and diurnal variations in elite skeleton athletes. Br J Sports Med 41: 569&#x2013;573, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman DW, Bullock N, Ross A, Rosemond D, Martin DT. Detrimental effects of west to east transmeridian flight on jump performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1663&#x2013;1669, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currell K, Jeukendrup AE. Validity, reliability and sensitivity of measures of sporting performance. Sports Med 38: 297&#x2013;316, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dranitsin OV. The effect on heart rate variability of acclimatization to a humid, hot environment after a transition across five time zones in elite junior rowers. Eur J Sport Sci 8: 251&#x2013;258, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastman CI, Burgess HJ. How to travel the World without jet lag. Sleep Med Clin 4: 241&#x2013;255, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everett KLA, Chapman DW, Mitchell JA, Ball N. Effects of westbound trans-meridian travel on countermovement jump performance in international-level rowers. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1961&#x2013;1965, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes-Robertson S, Dudley E, Vadgama P, Cook C, Drawer S, Kilduff L. Circadian disruption and remedial interventions: Effects and interventions for jet lag for athletic peak performance. Sports Med 42: 185&#x2013;208, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster RG. Sleep, circadian rhythms and health. Interf Focus 10: 20190098, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler P, Duffield R, Howle K, et al. Effects of northbound long-haul international air travel on sleep quantity and subjective jet lag and wellness in professional Australian soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 648&#x2013;654, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler P, Duffield R, Vaile J. Effects of simulated domestic and international air travel on sleep, performance, and recovery for team sports. Scand J Med Sci Sports 25: 441&#x2013;451, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, Duffield R, Skorski S, et al. Sleep, travel, and recovery responses of national footballers during and after long-haul international air travel. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 86&#x2013;95, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, Skorski S, Duffield R, et al. Sleep and athletic performance: The effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med 45: 161&#x2013;186, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta L, Morgan K, Gilchrist S. Does elite sport degrade sleep quality? A systematic review. Sports Med 47: 1317&#x2013;1333, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastings M, O'Neill JS, Maywood ES. Circadian clocks: Regulators of endocrine and metabolic rhythms. J Endocrinol 195: 187&#x2013;198, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herxheimer A, Petrie KJ. Melatonin for the prevention and treatment of jet lag. Cochrane Database Syst Rev (2): CD001520, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill DW, Hill CM, Fields KL, Smith JC. Effects of jet lag on factors related to sport performance. Can J Appl Physiol 18: 91&#x2013;103, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M. Preventing overtraining in athletes in high-intensity sports and stress/recovery monitoring. Scand J Med Sci Sports 20: 95&#x2013;102, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;lling S, Treff G, Winkert K, et al. The effect of westward travel across five time zones on sleep and subjective jet-lag ratings in athletes before and during the 2015's World Rowing Junior Championships. J Sports Sci 35: 2240&#x2013;2248, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach GD, Sargent C. Travel fatigue and sleep/wake behaviors of professional soccer players during international competition. Sleep Health 5: 141&#x2013;147, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leatherwood WE, Dragoo JL. Effect of airline travel on performance: A review of the literature. Br J Sports Med 47: 561&#x2013;567, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemmer BB, Kern R II, Nold G, Lohrer H. Jet lag in athletes after eastward and westward time-zone transition. Chronobiol Int 19: 743&#x2013;764, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loat CER, Rhodes EC, Buchanan JM. Jet-lag and human performance. Sports Med 8: 226&#x2013;238, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLoS Med 6:e1000097, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor PJ, Morgan WP. Athletic performance following rapid traversal of multiple time zones A review. Sports Med 10: 20&#x2013;30, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor PJ, Youngstedt SD, Buxton OM, Breus MD. Air travel and performance in sports. In: Federation Internationale de Medecine du Sport, Position Statement, 2004. Available at: http://www.fims.org/knowledge/position-statements/ . Accessed April 14, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S, Hogenesch JB, Kay SA. Circadian rhythms from flies to human. Nature 417: 329&#x2013;335, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn M, Sinclair J, Atkins S. Differences in the high speed match-play characteristics of rugby league players before, during and after a period of tramseridian transition. Int J Perf Anal 15: 1065&#x2013;1076, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raysmith BP, Drew MK. Performance success or failure is influenced by weeks lost to injury and illness in elite Australian track and field athletes: A 5-year prospective study. J Sci Med Sport 19: 778&#x2013;783, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T. How can travelling athletes deal with jet-lag? Kinesiology 41: 128&#x2013;135, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T. The body clock and athletic performance. Biol Rhythm Res 40: 37&#x2013;44, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Atkinson G, Budgett R, Effect BR. Effect of low-dose temazepam on physiological variables and performance tests following a westerly flight across five time zones. Int J Sports Med 22: 166&#x2013;174, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Atkinson G, Waterhouse J. Travel fatigue and jet-lag. J Sports Sci 15: 365&#x2013;369, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Edwards B. Altered sleep-wake cycles and physical performance in athletes. Physiol Behav 90: 274&#x2013;284, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Waterhouse J. Sports performance: Is there evidence that the body clock plays a role? Eur J Appl Physiol 106: 321&#x2013;332, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Waterhouse J, Burke LM, Alonso JM. Nutrition for travel. J Sports Sci 25: 125&#x2013;134, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roach GD, Matthews R, Naweed A, Kontou TG, Sargent C. Flat-out napping: The quantity and quality of sleep obtained in a seat during the daytime increase as the angle of recline of the seat increases. Chronobiol Int 35: 872&#x2013;883, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roach GD, Sargent C. Interventions to minimize jet lag after westward and eastward flight. Front Physiol 10:927, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts SSH, Teo W-PP, Warmington SA. Effects of training and competition on the sleep of elite athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 53: 513&#x2013;522, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sack RL. The pathophysiology of jet lag. Trav Med Infect Dis 7: 102&#x2013;110, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels CH. Jet lag and travel fatigue: A comprehensive management plan for sport medicine physicians and high-performance support teams. Clin J Sport Med 22: 268&#x2013;273, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands WA, Mcneal JR, Stone MH. Plaudits and pitfalls in studying elite athletes. Percept Mot Skills 100: 22&#x2013;24, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwellnus MP, Derman WE, Jordaan E, et al. Elite athletes travelling to international destinations &gt;5 time zone differences from their home country have a 2-3-fold increased risk of illness. Br J Sports Med 46: 816&#x2013;821, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons E, McGrane O, Wedmore I. Jet lag modification. Curr Sports Med Rep 14: 123&#x2013;128, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soligard T, Schwellnus M, Alonso JM, et al. How much is too much? (Part 1) International Olympic Committee consensus statement on load in sport and risk of injury. Br J Sports Med 50: 1030&#x2013;1041, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer RL, Chun LE, Hartsock MJ, Woodruff ER. Glucocorticoid hormones are both a major circadian signal and major stress signal: How this shared signal contributes to a dynamic relationship between the circadian and stress systems. Front Neuroendocrinol 49: 52&#x2013;71, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svendsen IS, Taylor IM, Tonnessen E, Bahr R, Gleeson M. Training-related and competition-related risk factors for respiratory tract and gastrointestinal infections in elite cross-country skiers. Br J Sports Med 50: 809&#x2013;815, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton HR, Miller J, Taylor L, et al. Impact of short- compared to long-haul international travel on the sleep and wellbeing of national wheelchair basketball athletes. J Sports Sci 36: 1476&#x2013;1484, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpy MJ. Classification of sleep disorders. Neurotherapeutics 9: 687&#x2013;701, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Edwards B, Nevill A, et al. Do subjective symptoms predict our perception of jet-lag? Ergonomics 43: 1514&#x2013;1527, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Edwards B, Nevill A, et al. Identifying some determinants of &#x201c;jet lag&#x201d; and its symptoms: A study of athletes and other travellers. Br J Sports Med 36: 54&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Reilly T, Atkinson G, Edwards B. Jet lag: Trends and coping strategies. Lancet 369: 1117&#x2013;1129, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Reilly T, Atkinson G. Jet lag. Lancet 350: 1611&#x2013;1616, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Reilly T, Edwards B. The stress of travel. J Sports Sci 22: 946&#x2013;966, 2004.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>