<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34711770</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Monitoring Effects of Sleep Extension and Restriction on Endurance Performance Using Heart Rate Indices.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3381</StartPage><EndPage>3389</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3381-3389</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004157</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Roberts, SSH, Aisbett, B, Teo, W-P, and Warmington, S. Monitoring effects of sleep extension and restriction on endurance performance using heart rate indices. J Strength Cond Res 36(12): 3381-3389, 2022-Heart rate (HR) indices are useful for monitoring athlete fatigue or "readiness to perform." This study examined whether HR indices are sensitive to changes in readiness following sleep restriction (SR) and sleep extension (SE). Nine athletes completed a crossover study with 3 conditions: SR, normal sleep (NS), and SE. Each condition required completion of an endurance time trial (TT) on 4 consecutive days (D1-D4). Athletes slept habitually before D1; however, time in bed was reduced by 30% (SR), remained normal (NS), or extended by 30% (SE), on subsequent nights (D1-D3). Daily resting HR and HR variability were recorded. The maximal rate of HR increase and HR recovery was determined from a constant-load test before TTs. Exercise intensity ratios incorporating mean HR, mean power (W), and perceived exertion (RPE) were recorded at steady state during constant-load tests (W:HR SS ) and during TTs (W:HR TT , RPE:HR TT ). Compared with D4 of NS, RPE:HR TT was lower on D4 of SE ( p = 0.008)-when TT performances were faster. Compared with D1 of SR, RPE:HR TT was higher on D3 and D4 of SR ( p &lt; 0.02). Moderate correlations were found between percentage changes in W:HR TT and changes in TT finishing time in SR ( r = -0.67, p = 0.049) and SE ( r = -0.69, p = 0.038) conditions. Intensity ratios incorporating mean HR seem sensitive to effects of sleep duration on athlete readiness to perform. When interpreting intensity ratios, practitioners should consider potential effects of prior sleep duration to determine whether sleep-promoting interventions are required (e.g., SE).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Spencer S H</ForeName><Initials>SSH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, Deakin University, Geelong, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aisbett</LastName><ForeName>Brad</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, Deakin University, Geelong, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teo</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Peng</ForeName><Initials>WP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, Deakin University, Geelong, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education and Sports Science Academic Group, National Institute of Education, Nanyang University, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warmington</LastName><ForeName>Stuart</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition, Deakin University, Geelong, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34711770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202212000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beaver WL, Wasserman K, Whipp BJ. A new method for detecting anaerobic threshold by gas exchange. J Appl Physiol 60: 2020&#x2013;2027, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellenger CR, Thomson RL, Howe PR, Karavirta L, Buckley JD. Monitoring athletic training status using the maximal rate of heart rate increase. J Sci Med Sport 19: 590&#x2013;595, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Psychophysical scaling with applications in physical work and the perception of exertion. Scand J Work Environ Health 16: 55&#x2013;58, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc 14: 377&#x2013;381, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brink M, Visscher C, Coutts A, Lemmink K. Changes in perceived stress and recovery in overreached young elite soccer players. Scand J Med Sci Sports 22: 285&#x2013;292, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Monitoring training status with HR measures: Do all roads lead to Rome? Front Physiol 5: 1&#x2013;19, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: A new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res 28: 193&#x2013;213, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dancey CP, Reidy J. Correlational analysis: Pearson's r (Chapter 6). In: Statistics Without Maths for Psychology (4th ed.). Essex, United Kingdom: Pearson Education, 2007. p. 176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Zambotti M, Trinder J, Silvani A, Colrain IM, Baker FC. Dynamic coupling between the central and autonomic nervous systems during sleep: A review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 90: 84&#x2013;103, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dettoni JL, Consolim-Colombo FM, Drager LF, et al. Cardiovascular effects of partial sleep deprivation in healthy volunteers. J Appl Physiol 113: 232&#x2013;236, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flatt AA, Hornikel B, Esco MR. Heart rate variability and psychometric responses to overload and tapering in collegiate sprint-swimmers. J Sci Med Sport 20: 606&#x2013;610, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grazzi G, Alfieri N, Borsetto C, et al. The power output/heart rate relationship in cycling: Test standardization and repeatability. Med Sci Sports Exerc 31: 1478&#x2013;1483, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep monitoring in athletes: Motivation, methods, miscalculations and why it matters. Sports Med 49: 1487&#x2013;1497, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin MR, Ziegler M. Sleep deprivation potentiates activation of cardiovascular and catecholamine responses in abstinent alcoholics. Hypertension 45: 252&#x2013;257, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup AE, Craig NP, Hawley JA. The bioenergetics of world class cycling. J Sci Med Sport 3: 414&#x2013;433, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliano LM, Griffiths RR. A critical review of caffeine withdrawal: Empirical validation of symptoms and signs, incidence, severity, and associated features. Psychopharmacology 176: 1&#x2013;29, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;lling S, Steinacker JM, Endler S, et al. The longer the better: Sleep&#x2013;wake patterns during preparation of the world rowing junior championships. Chronobiol Int 33: 73&#x2013;84, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroshus E, Wagner J, Wyrick D, et al. Wake up call for collegiate athlete sleep: Narrative review and consensus recommendations from the NCAA interassociation task force on sleep and wellness. Br J Sports Med 53: 731&#x2013;736, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lusardi P, Mugellini A, Preti P, et al. Effects of a restricted sleep regimen on ambulatory blood pressure monitoring in normotensive subjects. Am J Hypertens 9: 503&#x2013;505, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lusardi P, Zoppi A, Preti P, et al. Effects of insufficient sleep on blood pressure in hypertensive patients: A 24-h study. Am J Hypertens 12: 63&#x2013;68, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier-Ewert HK, Ridker PM, Rifai N, et al. Effect of sleep loss on C-reactive protein, an inflammatory marker of cardiovascular risk. J Am Coll Cardiol 43: 678&#x2013;683, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Hammouda O, Chaouachi A, et al. Effects of two types of partial sleep deprivation on hematological responses during intermittent exercise: A pilot study. Sci Sport 29: 266&#x2013;274, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles KH, Clark B, Fowler PM, Miller J, Pumpa KL. Sleep practices implemented by team sport coaches and sports science support staff: A potential avenue to improve athlete sleep? J Sci Med Sport 22: 748&#x2013;752, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Kilding AE, Buchheit M. Heart rate variability in elite triathletes, is variation in variability the key to effective training? A case comparison. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 3729&#x2013;3741, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts SS, Teo W-P, Aisbett B, Warmington SA. Effects of total sleep deprivation on endurance cycling performance and heart rate indices used for monitoring athlete readiness. J Sports Sci 37: 2691&#x2013;2701, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts SS, Teo W-P, Aisbett B, Warmington SA. Extended sleep maintains endurance performance better than normal or restricted sleep. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 2516&#x2013;2523, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders D, Heijboer M, Hesselink MKC, Myers T, Akubat I. Analysing a cycling grand tour: Can we monitor fatigue with intensity or load ratios? J Sports Sci 36: 1385&#x2013;1391, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. The validity of activity monitors for measuring sleep in elite athletes. J Sci Med Sport 19: 848&#x2013;853, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt L, Regnard J, Desmarets M, et al. Fatigue shifts and scatters heart rate variability in elite endurance athletes. PLoS One 8: e71588, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonelli G, Mantua J, Gad M, et al. Sleep extension reduces pain sensitivity. Sleep Med 54: 172&#x2013;176, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel K, Leproult R, L'Hermite-Bal&#xe9;riaux M, et al. Leptin levels are dependent on sleep duration: Relationships with sympathovagal balance, carbohydrate Regulation, cortisol, and thyrotropin. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 89: 5762&#x2013;5771, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielberger CD, Gorsuch R. State-Trait Anxiety Inventory for Adults: Manual and Sample: Manual, Instrument and Scoring Guide. Palo Alto, CA: Consulting Psychologists Press, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takase B, Akima T, Satomura K, et al. Effects of chronic sleep deprivation on autonomic activity by examining heart rate variability, plasma catecholamine, and intracellular magnesium levels. Biomed Pharmacother 58(Suppl 1): S35&#x2013;S39, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tochikubo O, Ikeda A, Miyajima E, Ishii M. Effects of insufficient sleep on blood pressure monitored by a new multibiomedical recorder. Hypertension 27: 1318&#x2013;1324, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trounson KM, Roberts S, Balloch A, Warmington SA. Light exercise heart rate on&#x2010;kinetics: A comparison of data fitted with sigmoidal and exponential functions and the impact of fitness and exercise intensity. Physiol Rep 5: e13312, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandewalle G, Middleton B, Rajaratnam SM, et al. Robust circadian rhythm in heart rate and its variability: Influence of exogenous melatonin and photoperiod. J Sleep Res 16: 148&#x2013;155, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White DW, Raven PB. Autonomic neural control of heart rate during dynamic exercise: Revisited. J Physiol 592: 2491&#x2013;2500, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>