<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35173360</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of alterations in whole-body cryotherapy (WBC) exposure on post-match recovery markers in elite Premier League soccer players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>31</StartPage><EndPage>36</EndPage><MedlinePgn>31-36</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2021.102931</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The use of whole-body cryotherapy (WBC) as a recovery intervention is prevalent amongst elite soccer players. However, there is a distinct lack of data available around chronic WBC use and post-match recovery markers in elite soccer. The aim of this study was to investigate the impact of different levels of WBC exposure on subjective and objective measures of post-match recovery in elite soccer players during a chronic exposure period. Sixteen male senior professional outfield soccer players participated in this study over two seasons. K means cluster analysis was used to classify low (-114 &#xb1; 2&#xb0;C for 133 &#xb1; 2 s), medium (-121 &#xb1; 1&#xb0;C for 173 &#xb1; 2 s) and high (-133 &#xb1; 1&#xb0;C for 181 &#xb1; 2 s) cryotherapy exposure indexes (CEI). Salivary markers (immunoglobulin A (IgA) and alpha amylase (AA)) and subjective wellness scores (perceived fatigue, sleep quality, general muscle soreness and stress) were collected post-match across both seasons. Training load (session-RPE) was collected and used as a covariate to control for the load amongst groups. No differences were seen in perceived measures of wellness and salivary AA. Significantly lower IgA concentrations were observed in the medium CEI group (255 &#xb1; 32 &#xb5;g&#x2219;ml<sup>-1</sup>) compared to the low (328 &#xb1; 38 &#xb5;g&#x2219;ml<sup>-1</sup>) and high (306 &#xb1; 32 &#xb5;g&#x2219;ml<sup>-1</sup>) groups. Therefore, increasing the level of chronic WBC exposure appears to have no additional benefit on subjective recovery and alpha amylase response post-match. However, there appears to be an optimal chronic WBC dose with regards to IgA response.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malone</LastName><ForeName>James J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Liverpool Hope University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hodges</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Science and Medicine Department, Bournemouth Football Club, Bournemouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Craig</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Science and Medicine Department, Bournemouth Football Club, Bournemouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinclair</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Page</LastName><ForeName>Richard M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Physical Activity, Edge Hill University, Ormskirk, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allan</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Central Lancashire, Preston, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Load</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Match</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Salivary</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35173360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8805367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.102931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">102931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J. The physiology of soccer--with special reference to intense intermittent exercise. Acta Physiol Scand Suppl. 1994;619:1&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8059610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley PS, Sheldon W, Wooster B, Olsen P, Boanas P, Krustrup P. High-intensity running in English FA Premier League soccer matches. J Sports Sci. 2009;27(2):159&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes C, Archer D, Hogg B, Bush M, Bradley P. The Evolution of Physical and Technical Performance Parameters in the English Premier League. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(13):1095&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25009969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomfield J, Polman R, O&#x2019;Donoghue P. Physical demands of different positions in FA Premier League soccer. J Sport Sci Med. 2007;6(1):63&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3778701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, &#xd8;rtenblad N, Nielsen J, Nybo L, Gunnarsson TP, Iaia FM, et al. Maximal voluntary contraction force, SR function and glycogen resynthesis during the first 72 h after a high-level competitive soccer game. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:2987&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21448723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelec M, McCall A, Carling C, Legall F, Berthoin S, Dupont G. The influence of soccer playing actions on the recovery kinetics after a soccer match. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(6):1517&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24172722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ascens&#xe3;o A, Leite M, Rebelo AN, Magalh&#xe4;es S, Magalh&#xe4;es J. Effects of cold water immersion on the recovery of physical performance and muscle damage following a one-off soccer match. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(3):217&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21170794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownstein C, Dent J, Parker P, Hicks K, Howatson G, Goodall S, et al. Etiology and recovery of neuromuscular fatigue following competitive soccer match-play. Front Physiol. 2017;8:831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29118716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, McCall A, Carling C, Legall F, Berthoin S, Dupont G. Recovery in Soccer: part ii-recovery. Sport Med. 2013;43(1):9&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23315753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banfi G, Lombardi G, Colombini A, Melegati G. Whole-body cryotherapy in athletes. Sport Med. 2010;40(6):509&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20524715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banfi G, Melegati G. Effect on sport hemolysis of cold water leg immersion in athletes after training sessions. Lab Hematol. 2008;14(2):15&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18599431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wozniak A, Wozniak B, Drewa G, Mila-Kierzenkowska C, Rakowski A. The effect of whole-body cryostimulation on lysosomal enzyme activity in kayakers during training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100(2):137&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17458576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonda B, Sarabon N. Effects of whole-body cryotherapy on recovery after hamstring damaging exercise: A crossover study. Scand J Med Sci Sport. 2013;23(5):e270&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23614691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis J, Theurot D, Filliard JR, Volondat M, Dugu&#xe9; B, Dupuy O. The use of wholebody cryotherapy: timeand doseresponse investigation on circulating blood catecholamines and heart rate variability. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120:1733&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7340648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32474683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selfe J, Alexander J, Costello JT, May K, Garratt N, Atkins S, et al. The effect of three different (-135oC) whole body cryotherapy exposure durations on elite rugby league players. PLoS One. 2014;9(1):e86420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24489726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonda B, De Nardi M, Sarabon N. Effects of whole-body cryotherapy duration on thermal and cardio-vascular response. J Therm Biol. 2014;42:52&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24802149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerlund T, Smolander J, Uusitalo-Koskinen A, Mikkelsson M. The blood pressure responses to an acute and long-term whole-body cryotherapy (-110&#xb0;C) in men and women. J Therm Biol. 2004;29(6):285&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banfi G, Melegati G, Barassi A, Dogliotti G, Melzi d&#x2019;Eril G, Dugu&#xe9; B, et al. Effects of whole-body cryotherapy on serum mediators of inflammation and serum muscle enzymes in athletes. J Therm Biol. 2009;34(2):55&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper S, Mackinnon L, Howard A, Gordon R, Bachmann A. Markers for monitoring overtraining and recovery. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27:106&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7898325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug J a, Franklin J, Gottschall L, Hrovatin L a, Parker S, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15(1):109&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duda RO, Hart PE, Stork DG. Pattern Classification. 2000. pp. 13&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field A. Discovering statistics using IBM SPSS statistics. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgans R, Orme P, Anderson L, Drust B, Morton JP. An Intensive Winter Fixture Schedule Induces a Transient Fall in Salivary IgA in English Premier League Soccer Players. Res Sport Med. 2014;22(4):346&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25295473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M. Mucosal immunity and respiratory illness in elite athletes. Int J Sports Med. 2000;21(Sup. 1):33&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10893023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira A, Arsati F, Cury P, Franciscon C, de Oliveira P, de Araujo V. Salivary immunoglobulin a response to a match in top-level brazilian soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(7):1968&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19704379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>