<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40493649</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep Duration and Sleep Quality as Season-Long Predictors of Ratings of Perceived Exertion and Psychological Well-Being in Female Soccer Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>973</StartPage><EndPage>981</EndPage><MedlinePgn>973-981</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005166</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Long, JW, Gonzalez, M, Farrell, J, Carmargo, ME, and Cheever, K. Sleep duration and sleep quality as season-long predictors of ratings of perceived exertion and psychological well-being in female soccer athletes. J Strength Cond Res 39(9): 973-981, 2025-Sleep's effect on physiologic and psychological well-being has been examined through cross-sectional studies, but research is limited on the longitudinal impact sleep has on well-being in collegiate athletes. Thus, the purpose of this study was to explore daily fluctuations in subjective measures of psychological wellness and physiologic stress (soreness, rating of perceived exertion [RPE]) across a competitive soccer season, and the extent to which sleep duration and quality modify daily measures of wellness. Twenty female collegiate soccer players underwent daily measures of psychological well-being (mental stress, mental fatigue, anxiety, and depression), physical stress (active time, total distance, GPS load, soreness, and RPE), and sleep (duration and quality) across a 120-day competitive season. Generalized linear mixed-effects models with a zero-inflation component were used to examine the effects of sleep duration and quality on measures of physiologic and psychological stress. Sleep duration was a predictor of RPE and anxiety, and there was an interaction between sleep duration and the day of the soccer season affecting RPE, anxiety, and soreness ( p &lt; 0.05). Sleep quality was a predictor of anxiety, mental stress, and RPE ( p &lt; 0.05). Significant interactions were observed between sleep quality and the day of the soccer season affecting soreness, anxiety, mental fatigue, and mental stress (all p &lt; 0.05). Findings suggest sleep duration and sleep quality are protective of measures of psychological well-being, with increasingly protective effects across a competitive soccer season. These findings have utility in helping to maximize both student athlete performance and wellness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>John William</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutritional Sciences, Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology Department, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Science Program, University of Texas at San Antonio Health Science Center at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farrell</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Suffix>3rd</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, Texas State University, San Marcos, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carmargo</LastName><ForeName>Maria Elena</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Introduction &amp; Strategies Department, Univeristy of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheever</LastName><ForeName>Kelly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology Department, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Science Program, University of Texas at San Antonio Health Science Center at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Research Interest Group, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Quality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013315" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Psychological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005222" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092862" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological Well-Being</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000094362" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep Duration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acclimatization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40493649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202509000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aloulou A, Duforez F, L&#xe9;ger D, De Larochelambert Q, Nedelec M. The relationships between training load, type of sport, and sleep among high-level adolescent athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 890&#x2013;899, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astridge D, Sommerville A, Verheul M, Turner AP. Training and academic demands are associated with sleep quality in high-performance &#x201c;dual career&#x201d; student swimmers. Eur J Sport Sci 21: 1675&#x2013;1683, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauer AA, Athey AB, Ross MJ, Grandner MA. Sleep and health among collegiate student athletes. Chest 156: 1234&#x2013;1245, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks ME, Kristensen K, Benthem KV, et al. glmmTMB balances speed and flexibility among packages for zero-inflated generalized linear mixed modeling. R J 9: 378&#x2013;400, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Mendes B, Bredt S, et al. Perceived training load, muscle soreness, stress, fatigue, and sleep quality in professional basketball: A full season study. J Hum Kinet 67: 199&#x2013;207, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Mendes B, Palao JM, et al. Seasonal player wellness and its longitudinal association with internal training load: Study in elite volleyball. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 59: 345&#x2013;351, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drew MK, Finch CF. The relationship between training load and injury, illness and soreness: A systematic and literature review. Sports Med 46: 861&#x2013;883, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duignan CM, Slevin PJ, Caulfield BM, Blake C. Mobile athlete self-report measures and the complexities of implementation. J Sports Sci Med 18: 405&#x2013;412, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duignan C, Doherty C, Caulfield B, Blake C. Single-item self-report measures of team-sport athlete wellbeing and their relationship with training load: A systematic review. J Athl Train 55: 944&#x2013;953, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eime RM, Young JA, Harvey JT, Charity MJ, Payne WR. A systematic review of the psychological and social benefits of participation in sport for adults: Informing development of a conceptual model of health through sport. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Activ 10: 1&#x2013;21, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govus AD, Coutts A, Duffield R, Murray A, Fullagar H. Relationship between pretraining subjective wellness measures, player load, and rating-of-perceived-exertion training load in American college football. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 95&#x2013;101, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad M, Chaouachi A, Wong delP, et al. Influence of fatigue, stress, muscle soreness and sleep on perceived exertion during submaximal effort. Physiol Behav 119: 185&#x2013;189, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlin MJ, Wilkes D, Elliot CA, Lizamore CA, Kathiravel Y. Monitoring training loads and perceived stress in young elite university athletes. Front Physiol 10: 1&#x2013;12, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsouna H, Boukhris O, Abdessalem R, et al. Effect of different nap opportunity durations on short-term maximal performance, attention, feelings, muscle soreness, fatigue, stress and sleep. Physiol Behav 211: 1&#x2013;5, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Rampinini E, Coutts AJ, Sassi A, Marcora SM. Use of RPE-based training load in soccer. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 1042&#x2013;1047, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones BJ, Kaur S, Miller M, Spencer RMC. Mindfulness-based stress reduction benefits psychological well-being, sleep quality, and athletic performance in female collegiate rowers. Front Psychol 11: 1&#x2013;10, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo JH, Hwang S, Abu H, Gallo JJ. An innovative model of depression care delivery: Peer mentors in collaboration with a mental health professional to relieve depression in older adults. Am J Geriatr Psychiatr 24: 407&#x2013;416, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kegelaers J, Wylleman P, Defruyt S, et al. The mental health of student-athletes: A systematic scoping review. Int Rev Sport Exer Psychol 17: 848&#x2013;881, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koikawa N, Shimada S, Suda S, Murata A, Kasai T. Sex differences in subjective sleep quality, sleepiness, and health-related quality of life among collegiate soccer players. Sleep Biol Rhythm 14: 377&#x2013;386, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroshus E, Wagner J, Wyrick D, et al. Wake up call for collegiate athlete sleep: Narrative review and consensus recommendations from the NCAA interassociation task force on sleep and wellness. Br J Sports Med 53: 731&#x2013;736, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leduc C, Tee J, Weakley J, Ramirez C, Jones B. The quality, quantity, and intraindividual variability of sleep among students and student-athletes. Sports Health 12: 43&#x2013;50, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long JW, Brown D, Farrell J, Gonzalez M, Cheever K. Relationship between workload, psychological state and recovery in male soccer athletes. Int J Sports Med 45: 829&#x2013;836, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;decke D, Ben-Shachar M, Patil I, Waggoner P, Makowski D. performance: An R package for assessment, comparison and testing of statistical models. J Open Source Softw 6: 1&#x2013;8, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Kezirian EJ, Marcello BM, Dement WC. Poor sleep quality and insufficient sleep of a collegiate student-athlete population. Sleep Health 4: 251&#x2013;257, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski MD, Skaggs DL, Bishop GA, et al. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. J Pediatr Orthop 34: 129&#x2013;133, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Collegiate Athletic Association NCAA Student-Athlete Well-Being Study. Indianapolis, IN: NCAA, 2022. pp. 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon JE, Docherty CL. Current health-related quality of life in former National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I collision athletes compared with contact and limited-contact athletes. J Athl Train 51: 205&#x2013;212, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starr LR, Davila J. Temporal patterns of anxious and depressed mood in generalized anxiety disorder: A daily diary study. Behav Res Ther 50: 131&#x2013;141, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutcliffe JH, Greenberger PA. Identifying psychological difficulties in college athletes. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract 8: 2216&#x2013;2219, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team RC. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. Vienna, Austria: Foundation for Statistical Computing, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson A, Brickson S. Impaired sleep mediates the negative effects of training load on subjective well-being in female youth athletes. Sports Health 10: 244&#x2013;249, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. ggplot2. Wiley interdisciplinary reviews: computational statistics. New York: Springer-Verlag, 2011. pp. 180&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xanthopoulos MS, Benton T, Lewis J, Case JA, Master CL. Mental health in the young athlete. Curr Psychiatry Rep 22: 1&#x2013;15, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Peek-Asa C, Corlette JD, et al. Prevalence of and risk factors associated with symptoms of depression in competitive collegiate student athletes. Clin J Sport Med 17: 481&#x2013;487, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>