<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33708170</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Examining Criteria for Defining Persistent Post-concussion Symptoms in Children and Adolescents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>614648</StartPage><MedlinePgn>614648</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">614648</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2021.614648</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Researchers operationalize persistent post-concussion symptoms in children and adolescents using varied definitions. Many pre-existing conditions, personal characteristics, and current health issues can affect symptom endorsement rates in the absence of, or in combination with, a recent concussion, and the use of varied definitions can lead to differences in conclusions about persistent symptoms and recovery across studies. This study examined how endorsement rates varied by 14 different operational definitions of persistent post-concussion symptoms for uninjured boys and girls with and without pre-existing or current health problems. This cross-sectional study included a large sample (age range: 11-18) of girls (<i>n</i> = 21,923) and boys (<i>n</i> = 26,556) without a recent concussion who completed the Post-Concussion Symptom Scale at preseason baseline. Endorsements rates varied substantially by definition, health history, and current health issues. The most lenient definition (i.e., a single mild symptom) was endorsed by most participants (54.5% of boys/65.3% of girls). A large portion of participants with pre-existing mental health problems (42.7% of boys/51.5% of girls), current moderate psychological distress (70.9% of boys/72.4% of girls), and insufficient sleep prior to testing (33.4% of boys/47.6% of girls) endorsed symptoms consistent with mild ICD-10 postconcussional syndrome; whereas participants with no current or prior health problems rarely met this definition (1.6% of boys/1.6% of girls). The results illustrate the tremendous variability in the case definitions of persistent symptoms and the importance of harmonizing definitions across future studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Iverson, Karr, Maxwell, Zafonte, Berkner and Cook.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iverson</LastName><ForeName>Grant L</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MassGeneral Hospital for Children Sports Concussion Program, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital, Charlestown, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spaulding Research Institute, Charlestown, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karr</LastName><ForeName>Justin E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maxwell</LastName><ForeName>Bruce</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Colby College, Waterville, ME, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zafonte</LastName><ForeName>Ross</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital, Charlestown, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Home Base, A Red Sox Foundation and Massachusetts General Hospital Program, Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berkner</LastName><ForeName>Paul D</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Osteopathic Medicine, University of New England, Biddeford, ME, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cook</LastName><ForeName>Nathan E</ForeName><Initials>NE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MassGeneral Hospital for Children Sports Concussion Program, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spaulding Rehabilitation Hospital, Charlestown, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain trauma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mild traumatic brain injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcome research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postconcussional syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symptoms</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>GI has been reimbursed by the government, professional scientific bodies, and commercial organizations for discussing or presenting research relating to MTBI and sport-related concussion at meetings, scientific conferences, and symposiums. He has a clinical practice in forensic neuropsychology, including expert testimony, involving individuals who have sustained mild TBIs (including athletes). He has received honorariums for serving on research panels that provide scientific peer review of programs. He is a co-investigator, collaborator, or consultant on grants relating to mild TBI funded by the federal government and other organizations. He has received research support from test publishing companies in the past, including ImPACT&#xae; Applications Systems, Psychological Assessment Resources, and CNS Vital Signs. He has received research support from the Harvard Integrated Program to Protect and Improve the Health of NFLPA Members, and a grant from the National Football League. He serves as a scientific advisor for BioDirection, Inc, Sway Medical, Inc., and Highmark, Inc. RZ has received salary support from the Harvard Integrated Program to Protect and Improve the Health of National Football League Players Association Members. He serves on the Scientific Advisory Board of Myomo, Oxeia Pharma, and ElMInda. The authors declare that this study received funding from the National Football League and ImPACT&#xae; Applications, Inc. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33708170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7940348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.614648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvor&#xe1;k J, Aubry M, Bailes J, Broglio S, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5 th international conference on concussion in sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. (2017) 51:838. 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis GA, Anderson V, Babl FE, Gioia GA, Giza CC, Meehan W, et al. What is the difference in concussion management in children as compared with adults? A systematic review. Br J Sports Med. (2017) 51:949. 10.1136/bjsports-2016-097415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28455361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson LD, Guskiewicz KM, Barr WB, Hammeke TA, Randolph C, Ahn KW, et al. Age differences in recovery after sport-related concussion: a comparison of high school and collegiate athletes. J Athl Train. (2016) 51:142&#x2013;52. 10.4085/1062-6050-51.4.04</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-51.4.04</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4852320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26974186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyer GL, Schaffer CE, Rose SC, Young JA, McNally KA, Fischer AN. Specific factors influence postconcussion symptom duration among youth referred to a sports concussion clinic. J Pediatr. (2016) 174:33&#x2013;8.e2. 10.1016/j.jpeds.2016.03.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2016.03.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27056449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrisman SP, Rivara FP, Schiff MA, Zhou C, Comstock RD. Risk factors for concussive symptoms 1 week or longer in high school athletes. Brain Inj. (2013) 27:1&#x2013;9. 10.3109/02699052.2012.722251</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02699052.2012.722251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23252433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkwood MW, Crossland MM, Howell DR, Wilson JC, Peterson RL. A longitudinal investigation of symptom recovery following concussion in youth soccer. J Pediatr. (2020) 220:207&#x2013;13.e2. 10.1016/j.jpeds.2020.01.068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2020.01.068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32147217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castile L, Collins CL, McIlvain NM, Comstock RD. The epidemiology of new versus recurrent sports concussions among high school athletes, 2005-2010. Br J Sports Med. (2012) 46:603&#x2013;10. 10.1136/bjsports-2011-090115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2011-090115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22144000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg MA, Andrea J, Meehan W, Mannix R. Time interval between concussions and symptom duration. Pediatrics. (2013) 132:8&#x2013;17. 10.1542/peds.2013-0432</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2013-0432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23753087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemek R, Barrowman N, Freedman SB, Gravel J, Gagnon I, McGahern C, et al. Clinical risk score for persistent postconcussion symptoms among children with acute concussion in the ED. JAMA. (2016) 315:1014&#x2013;25. 10.1001/jama.2016.1203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2016.1203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26954410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis MJ, Cordingley DM, Vis S, Reimer KM, Leiter J, Russell K. Clinical predictors of vestibulo-ocular dysfunction in pediatric sports-related concussion. J Neurosurg Pediatr. (2017) 19:38&#x2013;45. 10.3171/2016.7.PEDS16310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2016.7.PEDS16310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27689244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JH, Gill C, Kuhn EN, Rocque BG, Menendez JY, O'Neill JA, et al. Predictors of delayed recovery following pediatric sports-related concussion: a case-control study. J Neurosurg Pediatr. (2016) 17:491. 10.3171/2015.8.PEDS14332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2015.8.PEDS14332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5476956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26684762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fehr SD, Nelson LD, Scharer KR, Traudt EA, Veenstra JM, Tarima SS, et al. Risk factors for prolonged symptoms of mild traumatic brain injury: a pediatric sports concussion clinic cohort. Clin J Sport Med. (2019) 29:11&#x2013;7. 10.1097/JSM.0000000000000494</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29084034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corwin DJ, Zonfrillo MR, Master CL, Arbogast KB, Grady MF, Robinson RL, et al. Characteristics of prolonged concussion recovery in a pediatric subspecialty referral population. J Pediatr. (2014) 165:1207. 10.1016/j.jpeds.2014.08.034</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2014.08.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4253594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25262302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlanger D, Kaushik T, Cantu R, Barth JT, Broshek DK, Freeman JR, et al. Symptom-based assessment of the severity of a concussion. J Neurosurg. (2003) 98:477&#x2013;84. 10.3171/jns.2003.98.3.0477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/jns.2003.98.3.0477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12650417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson S, Nigrovic LE, O'Brien M, Meehan WP, 3rd. The effect of recommending cognitive rest on recovery from sport-related concussion. Brain Inj. (2013) 27:839&#x2013;42. 10.3109/02699052.2013.775494</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02699052.2013.775494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23758286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan WP, 3rd, Mannix R, Monuteaux MC, Stein CJ, Bachur RG. Early symptom burden predicts recovery after sport-related concussion. Neurology. (2014) 83:2204&#x2013;10. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000001073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4277671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25381296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan WP, 3rd, Mannix RC, Stracciolini A, Elbin RJ, Collins MW. Symptom severity predicts prolonged recovery after sport-related concussion, but age and amnesia do not. J Pediatr. (2013) 163:721&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.jpeds.2013.03.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2013.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3732501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23628374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker JG, Leddy JJ, Darling SR, Rieger BP, Mashtare TL, Sharma T, et al. Factors associated with problems for adolescents returning to the classroom after sport-related concussion. Clin Pediatr. (2015) 54:961&#x2013;8. 10.1177/0009922815588820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0009922815588820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26084537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terwilliger VK, Pratson L, Vaughan CG, Gioia GA. Additional post-concussion impact exposure may affect recovery in adolescent athletes. J Neurotrauma. (2016) 33:761&#x2013;5. 10.1089/neu.2015.4082</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2015.4082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4840822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26421452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow KM. Postconcussion syndrome: a review. J Child Neurol. (2016) 31:57&#x2013;67. 10.1177/0883073814543305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073814543305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25330797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis GA. Neurological outcomes. In: Kirkwood MW, Yeates KO, editors. Mild Traumatic Brain Injury in Children and Adolescents: From Basic Science to Clinical Management. New York, NY: The Guilford Press; (2012). p. 99&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization . WH. The ICD-10 Classification of Mental and Behavioural Disorders: Clinical Descriptions and Diagnostic Guidelines. Geneva: World Health Organization; (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL, Silverberg ND, Mannix R, Maxwell BA, Atkins JE, Zafonte R, et al. Factors associated with concussion-like symptom reporting in high school athletes. JAMA Pediatr. (2015) 169:1132&#x2013;40. 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2015.2374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2015.2374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5333772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26457403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook NE, Sapigao RG, Silverberg ND, Maxwell BA, Zafonte R, Berkner PD, et al. Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder mimics the post-concussion syndrome in adolescents. Front Pediatr. (2020) 8:2. 10.3389/fped.2020.00002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2020.00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7014960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32117823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasundaram AP, Athens J, Schneiders AG, McCrory P, Sullivan SJ. Psychological and lifestyle factors that influence the serial reporting of postconcussion-like symptoms in a non-concussed population. PM R. (2017) 9:866&#x2013;73. 10.1016/j.pmrj.2017.01.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmrj.2017.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28167303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg ND, Berkner PD, Atkins JE, Zafonte R, Iverson GL. Relationship between short sleep duration and preseason concussion testing. Clin J Sport Med. (2016) 26:226&#x2013;31. 10.1097/JSM.0000000000000241</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26247549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riegler KE, Guty ET, Thomas GA, Arnett PA. Sleep deprived or concussed? the acute impact of self-reported insufficient sleep in college athletes. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. (2021) 27:35&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32641197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polich G, Iaccarino MA, Kaptchuk TJ, Morales-Quezada L, Zafonte R. Nocebo effects in concussion: is all that is told beneficial? Am J Phys Med Rehabil. (2020) 99:71&#x2013;80. 10.1097/PHM.0000000000001290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000001290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31393270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtowicz M, Iverson GL, Silverberg ND, Mannix R, Zafonte R, Maxwell B, et al. Consistency of self-reported concussion history in adolescent athletes. J Neurotrauma. (2017) 34:322&#x2013;7. 10.1089/neu.2016.4412</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2016.4412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5335743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27349296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook NE, Kelshaw PM, Caswell SV, Iverson GL. Children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder perform differently on pediatric concussion assessment. J Pediatr. (2019) 214:168&#x2013;74.e1. 10.1016/j.jpeds.2019.07.048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2019.07.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31477384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>