<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40845312</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Establishing Comprehensive Normative Values of Objective Sleep Quantity and Quality in Collegiate Athletes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005220</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vatne, E, Vatne, M, Cencer, D, Kraemer, WJ, Saenz, C, Stone, J, Merrigan, J, Pulvermacher, K, Robinson, B, Dial, M, Jones, P, Montalbano, A, Carpenter, T, and Hagen, J. Establishing comprehensive normative values of objective sleep quantity and quality in collegiate athletes. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-Collegiate athletes frequently experience insufficient sleep, adversely affecting physical performance and recovery. Historically, sleep studies primarily relied on subjective data and small sample sizes with most subjects being male athletes, which limits generalizability. Modern wearables enable more robust, objective analysis. Our objective was to leverage wearables to establish normative values for sleep quantity and quality in National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I athletes and investigate sex and sport-specific differences. Retrospective analysis was conducted on 37,672 sleep records from 397 NCAA Division I male and female athletes across 22 sports. Subjects wore a validated wearable device, Oura Ring, nightly for objective sleep tracking. Key metrics included total sleep time (TST), time in bed, sleep efficiency (SE), sleep onset latency (SOL), resting heart rate, and heart rate variability (HRV). Descriptive statistics and Wilcoxon rank-sum tests (p &lt; 0.05) were used to analyze differences by sex and sport. Average TST across athletes was 6.97 &#xb1; 1.27 hours. Female athletes achieved significantly higher TST (p &lt; 0.001, effect size (ES) = 0.23), SE (p &lt; 0.001, ES = 0.29), and HRV (p &lt; 0.001, ES = 0.09) than male athletes, while exhibiting shorter SOL (p &lt; 0.001, ES = -0.09). Eight teams averaged &lt;7 hours of TST per night. Findings underscore the need for tailored sleep interventions in collegiate athletes, particularly in male athletes. Strategies include education, monitoring, and scheduling adjustments to enhance recovery and performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vatne</LastName><ForeName>Emaly</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0395-2798</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Collaborative, Office of Research, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Athletics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vatne</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Collaborative, Office of Research, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Athletics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cencer</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Athletics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kraemer</LastName><ForeName>William J</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Collaborative, Office of Research, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Athletics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saenz</LastName><ForeName>Catherine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stone</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Athletics, University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merrigan</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Collaborative, Office of Research, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pulvermacher</LastName><ForeName>Kyle</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Athletics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robinson</LastName><ForeName>Bradley</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Collaborative, Office of Research, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dial</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Collaborative, Office of Research, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Athletics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montalbano</LastName><ForeName>Alexandria</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carpenter</LastName><ForeName>Tyler</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Athletics, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagen</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2829-1191</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Collaborative, Office of Research, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrated Systems Engineering, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>N/A</GrantID><Agency>Harry T. Mangurian, Jr. Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athlete monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40845312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Altini M. How data can capture recovery: The case for heart rate variability. In: Individualizing Training Procedures With Wearable Technology. D&#xfc;king P, Sperlich B, eds. Cham, Switzerland: Springer International Publishing, 2024. pp. 7&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altini M, Kinnunen H. The promise of sleep: A multi-sensor approach for accurate sleep stage detection using the Oura ring. Sensors (Basel) 21: 4302&#x2013;4323, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzueta E, de Zambotti M, Javitz H, et al. Tracking sleep, temperature, heart rate, and daily symptoms across the menstrual cycle with the Oura ring in healthy women. Int J Womens Health 14: 491&#x2013;503, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker FC, Driver HS. Self-reported sleep across the menstrual cycle in young, healthy women. J Psychosom Res 56: 239&#x2013;243, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Madsen EE, Clubb J, Emmonds S, Krustrup P. Monitoring readiness to train and perform in female football: Current evidence and recommendations for practitioners. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 19: 223&#x2013;231, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin CL, Curtis RM, Huggins RA, et al. Sleep dysfunction and mood in collegiate soccer athletes. Sports Health 12: 234&#x2013;240, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolin DJ. Sleep deprivation and its contribution to mood and performance deterioration in college athletes. Curr Sports Med Rep 18: 305&#x2013;310, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown AMC, Gervais NJ. Role of ovarian hormones in the modulation of sleep in females across the adult lifespan. Endocrinology 161: 1&#x2013;15, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brychta RJ, R&#xf6;gnvaldsd&#xf3;ttir V, Gu&#xf0;mundsd&#xf3;ttir SL, et al. Longitudinal change in adolescent bedtimes measured by self-report and actigraphy. J Meas Phys Behav 2: 282&#x2013;287, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Monitoring training status with HR measures: Do all roads lead to Rome? Front Physiol 5: 73&#x2013;92, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao R, Azimi I, Sarhaddi F, et al. Accuracy assessment of Oura ring nocturnal heart rate and heart rate variability in comparison with electrocardiography in time and frequency domains: Comprehensive analysis. J Med Internet Res 24: 1&#x2013;16, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter JR, Gervais BM, Adomeit JL, Greenlund IM. Subjective and objective sleep differ in male and female collegiate athletes. Sleep Health 6: 623&#x2013;628, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinoy ED, Cuellar JA, Jameson JT, Markwald RR. Performance of four commercial wearable sleep-tracking devices tested under unrestricted conditions at home in healthy young adults. Nat Sci Sleep 14: 493&#x2013;516, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craven J, McCartney D, Desbrow B, et al. Effects of acute sleep loss on physical performance: A systematic and meta-analytical review. Sports Med 52: 2669&#x2013;2690, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Zambotti M, Goldstein C, Cook J, et al. State of the science and recommendations for using wearable technology in sleep and circadian research. Sleep 47: 1&#x2013;31, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Dunican IC, Omond SET, et al. Pyjamas, polysomnography and professional athletes: The role of sleep tracking technology in sport. Sports 11: 14&#x2013;31, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driver HS, Dijk DJ, Werth E, Biedermann K, Borb&#xe9;ly AA. Sleep and the sleep electroencephalogram across the menstrual cycle in young healthy women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 81: 728&#x2013;735, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott-Sale KJ, Minahan CL, de Jonge XAKJ, et al. Methodological considerations for studies in sport and exercise science with women as participants: A working guide for standards of practice for research on women. Sports Med 51: 843&#x2013;861, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, Duffield R, Skorski S, Coutts AJ, Julian R, Meyer T. Sleep and recovery in team sport: Current sleep-related issues facing professional team-sport athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 950&#x2013;957, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, Vincent GE, McCullough M, Halson S, Fowler P. Sleep and sport performance. J Clin Neurophysiol 40: 408&#x2013;416, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girschik J, Fritschi L, Heyworth J, Waters F. Validation of self-reported sleep against actigraphy. J Epidemiol 22: 462&#x2013;468, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JT, Donohoe B, Hatamiya N, et al. Baseline sleep characteristics in NCAA Division I collegiate athletes. Clin J Sport Med 34: 370&#x2013;375, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouin J, Wenzel K, Deschenes S, Dang-Vu T. Heart rate variability predicts sleep efficiency. Sleep Med 14: 142, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Johnston RD, Pearson M, Minahan C. Menstrual-cycle symptoms and sleep characteristics in elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 19: 914&#x2013;920, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirshkowitz M, Whiton K, Albert SM, et al. National Sleep Foundation's updated sleep duration recommendations: Final report. Sleep Health 1: 233&#x2013;243, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrozanova M, Kl&#xf6;ckner CA, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Pallesen S, Moen F. Sex differences in sleep and influence of the menstrual cycle on women&#x2019;s sleep in junior endurance athletes. PLoS One 16: 1&#x2013;18, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knufinke M, Nieuwenhuys A, Geurts SAE, Coenen AML, Kompier MAJ. Self-reported sleep quantity, quality and sleep hygiene in elite athletes. J Sleep Res 27: 78&#x2013;85, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koikawa N, Takami Y, Kawasaki Y, et al. Changes in the objective measures of sleep between the initial nights of menses and the nights during the midfollicular phase of the menstrual cycle in collegiate female athletes. J Clin Sleep Med 16: 1745&#x2013;1751, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroshus E, Wagner J, Wyrick D, et al. Wake up call for collegiate athlete sleep: Narrative review and consensus recommendations from the NCAA Interassociation Task Force on Sleep and Wellness. Br J Sports Med 53: 731&#x2013;736, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Glaister M, Pizzoferro K, Dawson J, Pedlar C. Sleep duration and quality in elite athletes measured using wristwatch actigraphy. J Sports Sci 30: 541&#x2013;545, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes Dos Santos M, Uftring M, Stahl CA, et al. Stress in academic and athletic performance in collegiate athletes: A narrative review of sources and monitoring strategies. Front Sports Act Living 2: 42&#x2013;52, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Kezirian EJ, Marcello BM, Dement WC. Poor sleep quality and insufficient sleep of a collegiate student-athlete population. Sleep Health 4: 251&#x2013;257, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Mah KE, Kezirian EJ, Dement WC. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep 34: 943&#x2013;950, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles KH, Clark B, Fowler PM, Miller J, Pumpa KL. What are the sleep characteristics of elite female athletes? A systematic review with meta-analysis. Biol Sport 39: 751&#x2013;763, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DJ, Sargent C, Roach GD. A validation of six wearable devices for estimating sleep, heart rate and heart rate variability in healthy adults. Sensors (Basel) 22: 6317&#x2013;6334, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray A, Fullagar H, Turner AP, Sproule J. Recovery practices in Division 1 collegiate athletes in North America. Phys Ther Sport 32: 67&#x2013;73, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell S, Beaven CM, Driller MW. From pillow to podium: A review on understanding sleep for elite athletes. Nat Sci Sleep 10: 243&#x2013;253, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohayon M, Wickwire EM, Hirshkowitz M, et al. National Sleep Foundation's sleep quality recommendations: First report. Sleep Health 3: 6&#x2013;19, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Stanley J, Kilding AE, Buchheit M. Training adaptation and heart rate variability in elite endurance athletes: Opening the door to effective monitoring. Sports Med 43: 773&#x2013;781, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed BG, Carr BR. The normal menstrual cycle and the control of ovulation. In: The Follicular Phase. Feingold KR, Anawalt B, Blackman MR, et al, eds. South Dartmouth, MA: MDText.com, Inc., 2000. p. 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rugvedh P, Gundreddy P, Wandile B. The menstrual cycle&#x2019;s influence on sleep duration and cardiovascular health: A comprehensive review. Cureus 15: 1&#x2013;11, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shechter A, Varin F, Boivin DB. Circadian variation of sleep during the follicular and luteal phases of the menstrual cycle. Sleep 33: 647&#x2013;656, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone JD, Rentz LE, Forsey J, et al. Evaluations of commercial sleep technologies for objective monitoring during routine sleeping conditions. Nat Sci Sleep 12: 821&#x2013;842, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone JD, Ulman HK, Tran K, et al. Assessing the accuracy of popular commercial technologies that measure resting heart rate and heart rate variability. Front Sports Act Living 3: 585870&#x2013;585886, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Reen E, Kiesner J. Individual differences in self-reported difficulty sleeping across the menstrual cycle. Arch Womens Ment Health 19: 599&#x2013;608, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlahoyiannis A, Sakkas GK, Manconi M, Aphamis G, Giannaki CD. A critical review on sleep assessment methodologies in athletic populations: Factors to be considered. Sleep Med 74: 211&#x2013;223, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, et al. Sleep and the athlete: Narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med 55: 356&#x2013;368, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>