<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40176188</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of time of day and menstrual cycle on physical performance and psychological responses in elite female Tunisian volleyball players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>67</StartPage><MedlinePgn>67</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">67</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01117-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The influence of circadian rhythms and menstrual cycle phases on athletic performance and psychological responses is critical for optimizing training and competition strategies for female athletes. This study aimed to investigate the effects of time of day and menstrual cycle phases on the physical performance and psychological responses of elite female Tunisian volleyball players.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirteen elite female volleyball players were assessed during three different phases of their menstrual cycle (menstrual, follicular, and luteal) and at two different times of day (morning and evening). Physical performance was evaluated using the Modified Agility Test (MAT), Reactive Agility Test (RAT), and Repeated Sprint Ability (RSA) Test. Psychological responses were measured using the Profile of Mood States (POMS), Hooper's Questionnaire, Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index, Epworth Sleepiness Scale, Vis-Morgen Questionnaire, and Spiegel Questionnaire.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant effects of menstrual cycle, time of day, and competition on physical performance, cognitive function, mood, and sleep parameters were found. Physical performance, including the Countermovement Jump (CMJ), the Modified Agility T-test (MAT) and the Reactive Agility test (RAT), was higher in the afternoon than in the morning across all menstrual phases (CMJ: p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.836; MAT: p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.777; RAT: p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.859). After the competition, performance decreased significantly, especially in the follicular and luteal phases. As measured by the Stroop test, cognitive function showed significant diurnal effects (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.910), with pre-competition performance being better in the afternoon. Mood disturbances (POMS) increased after the competition, especially in the morning and during the luteal phase (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.961). Sleep parameters were significantly influenced by time and menstrual cycle, with higher fatigue (Hooper score: p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.754) and poorer sleep quality (PSQI: p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, &#x3b7;&#xb2; = 0.627) in the morning, especially after the competition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results suggest that aligning high-intensity training and competitions with afternoon circadian peaks may enhance physical and cognitive performance in elite female athletes. Recovery strategies and workload adjustments should account for menstrual phases, particularly reducing morning demands during the luteal phase to mitigate fatigue and mood disruptions. Integrating circadian timing with menstrual cycle monitoring offers a practical, evidence-based approach to optimize athlete readiness and resilience.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seddik</LastName><ForeName>Meher</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit "Physical Activity, Sport and Health" (UR18JS01), National Observatory of Sports, Tunis, 1003, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, Manouba, 2010, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouzourraa</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed Mansour</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human and Social Sciences, High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, 7100, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ceylan</LastName><ForeName>Halil &#x130;brahim</ForeName><Initials>H&#x130;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education of Sports Teaching Department, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Ataturk University, Erzurum, T&#xfc;rkiye. halil.ibrahimceylan60@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamaidi</LastName><ForeName>Jaouher</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human and Social Sciences, High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, 7100, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghouili</LastName><ForeName>Hatem</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human and Social Sciences, High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, 7100, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chtourou</LastName><ForeName>Hamdi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Sfax, University of Sfax, Sfax, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guelmami</LastName><ForeName>Noomen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human and Social Sciences, High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, 7100, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Dergaa</LastName><ForeName>Ismail</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit "Physical Activity, Sport and Health" (UR18JS01), National Observatory of Sports, Tunis, 1003, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, Manouba, 2010, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Muntean</LastName><ForeName>Raul Ioan</ForeName><Initials>RI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Law and Social Sciences, University "1 Decembrie 1918" of Alba Iulia, Alba Iulia, Romania. muntean.raul@uab.ro.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Souissi</LastName><ForeName>Nizar</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit "Physical Activity, Sport and Health" (UR18JS01), National Observatory of Sports, Tunis, 1003, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, Manouba, 2010, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Circadian rhythm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mood states</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sprint ability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Human ethics and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki guidelines and was approved by the Research Ethics Committee of the ISSEP Sfax prior to the start of the study. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants after a thorough explanation of the study&#x2019;s objectives, procedures, benefits, and potential risks. Informed consent: Participants gave written informed consent to participate in the present study and to its publication. Consent for publication: Not Applicable. In preparing this paper, the authors used ChatGPT model 4 on November 11, 2024, to revise some passages of the manuscript, to double-check for any grammar mistakes or improve academic English only [93, 94]. After using this tool, the authors have reviewed and edited the content as necessary and take full responsibility for the content of the publication. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40176188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11963659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01117-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01117-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Palao JM, Ure&#xf1;a A, Moreno MP, Ortega-Toro E. Effect of changes in the net height, court size, and serve limitations on technical-tactical, physical, and psychological aspects of U-14 female volleyball matches. Front Psychol. 2024;14:1341297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10806054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38268810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hank M, Cabell L, Zahalka F, Mi&#x159;&#xe1;tsk&#x1ef3; P, Cabrnoch B, Mala L, et al. Differences in external load among indoor and beach volleyball players during elite matches. PeerJ. 2024;11:e16736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10768657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38188147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim FA, Postma DB, Haider F, Luz S, van Beijnum BJF, Reidsma D. Enhancing volleyball training: empowering athletes and coaches through advanced sensing and analysis. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1326807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11058639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38689871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vavassori R, Moreno Arroyo MP, Espa AU. Training load and players&#x2019; readiness monitoring methods in volleyball: A systematic review. Kinesiology. 2024;56(1):61&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rada L, Amzar EL, Niculescu II. Methodical Contributions Regarding the Improvement of Physical Training in U16 Female Volleyball Players. Bulletin of the Transilvania University of Bra&#x15f;ov Series IX: Sciences of Human Kinetics [Internet]. 2024 [cited 2024 Jul 24]; Available from: https://webbut.unitbv.ro/index.php/Series_IX/article/view/7691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebelo A, Pereira JR, Cunha P, Coelho-e-Silva MJ, Valente-dos-Santos J. Training stress, neuromuscular fatigue and well-being in volleyball: a systematic review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024;16(1):17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10788005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38218879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima R, Gracinda A, Silva B, Silva AF, Pereira J, Silva RM, et al. Week-to-week variations of internal and external intensity measures in professional women volleyball players. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2024;19(1):294&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harber V. The female athlete perspective [Internet]., Edmonton A. 2010 [cited 2024 Jul 24]. Available from: https://volleyvekst.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/the20female20athlete20perspective.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihalainen JK, Mikkonen RS, Ackerman KE, Heikura IA, Mj&#xf8;sund K, Valtonen M et al. Beyond Menstrual Dysfunction: Does Altered Endocrine Function Caused by Problematic Low Energy Availability Impair Health and Sports Performance in Female Athletes? Sports Med [Internet]. 2024 Jul 12 [cited 2024 Jul 24]; Available from: https://link.springer.com/10.1007/s40279-024-02065-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11393114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38995599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward E, Akam L, Hunter D, Mastana S. Role of the menstrual cycle on performance and injury risk: a survey of female professional rugby players in the united Kingdom. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2024;21(2):150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10888092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38397641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiemle-Gabbay LR, Valentin S, Martin D, Forrest LJ. Menstrual cycle and hormonal contraceptive symptom severity and frequency in athletic females. Women in Sport and Physical Activity Journal [Internet]. 2024 [cited 2024 Jul 24];32(S1). Available from: https://journals.humankinetics.com/view/journals/wspaj/32/S1/article-wspaj.2023-0086.xml.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamed-Hamed D, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mu&#xf1;oz A, Cuevas-Cervera M, Perez-Montilla JJ, Aguilar-Nu&#xf1;ez D, Aguilar-Garc&#xed;a M, et al. Effects of the menstrual cycle on the performance of female football players. A systematic review. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1359953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11033481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38651042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones BP, L&#x2019;Heveder A, Bishop C, Kasaven L, Saso S, Davies S, et al. Menstrual cycles and the impact upon performance in elite British track and field athletes: a longitudinal study. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1296189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10912517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38445211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juillard E, Douchet T, Paizis C, Babault N. Impact of the menstrual cycle on physical performance and subjective ratings in elite academy women soccer players. Sports. 2024;12(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10820559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38251290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niering M, Wolf-Belala N, Seifert J, Tovar O, Coldewey J, Kuranda J, et al. The influence of menstrual cycle phases on maximal strength performance in healthy female adults: A systematic review with Meta-Analysis. Sports. 2024;12(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38251305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyward O, Elliott-Sale KJ, Roe G, Emmonds S, Hornby K, Stokes KA, et al. Oral contraceptive use in premiership and championship women&#x2019;s rugby union: perceived symptomology, management strategies, and performance and wellness effects. Sci Med Footb. 2024;8(2):95&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laske H, Konjer M, Meier HE. Menstruation and training&#x2013; A quantitative study of (non-)communication about the menstrual cycle in German sports clubs. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2022;174795412211430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taim BC, Lye J, Suppiah HT, Chan TW, Chia M, Clarke A. Menstrual cycle characteristics, perceived impact on performance, and barriers to communication: perspectives of high-performance adolescent athletes in Singapore. Scandinavian Med Sci Sports. 2024;34(1):e14488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37682006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabre HE, Ladan AN, Moore SR, Joniak KE, Blue MN, Pietrosimone BG, et al. Effects of hormonal contraception and the menstrual cycle on fatigability and recovery from an anaerobic exercise test. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2024;38(7):1256&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12704363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38598545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Assis Arantes F, Moreira OC, da Costa BDD, Valente JS, Marins JCB, de Oliveira CEP. Menstrual cycle and strength levels in women: a pilot study. Cuad De Educaci&#xf3;n Y Desarrollo. 2024;16(5):e4197&#x2013;4197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ES, Weakley J, McKay AKA, McCormick R, Tee N, Kuikman MA et al. Minimal influence of the menstrual cycle or hormonal contraceptives on performance in female rugby league athletes. European Journal of Sport Science. 2024;ejsc.12151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11295101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38877892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fomin SK, Pivovarova VI, Voronova VI. Changes in the special working capacity and mental stability of well-trained woman skiers at various phases of the biological cycle. Sports Med Train Rehabilitation. 1989;1(2):89&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebrun CM. Effect of the different phases of the menstrual cycle and oral contraceptives on athletic performance. Sports Med. 1993;16(6):400&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8303141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampoukos A, Peckham EA, James R, Nevill ME. Effect of menstrual cycle phase on sprinting performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(4):659&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20198384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Romdhani M, Fessi MS, Ben Saad H, Varma A, Ben Salem A, Gadhavi B, Chaabane M, Souissi N, Hammouda O. Does lunar cycle affect biological parameters in young healthy men? Chronobiol Int. 2021;38(6):933&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33779457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi A, Dergaa I, Chtourou H, Ben Saad H. The effect of daytime ingestion of melatonin on thyroid hormones responses to acute submaximal exercise in healthy active males: A pilot study. Am J Men&#x2019;s Health. 2022;16(1):15579883211070383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8785310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35060417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi A, Farjallah MA, Gaied Chortane O, Dergaa I, Mejri MA, Gaamouri N, Souissi N, Chamari K, Weiss K, Ben Saad H, Ghram A. The effects of daytime melatonin ingestion on arousal and vigilance vanish after sub-maximal exercise: a pilot study. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2022;26(17).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Varma A, Musa S, Chaabane M, Salem AB, Fessi MS. Diurnal variation: does it affect short-term maximal performance and biological parameters in Police officers. Int J Sport Stud Hlth. 2020;3(2):e111424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Fessi MS, Chaabane M, Souissi N, Hammouda O. The effects of lunar cycle on the diurnal variations of short-term maximal performance, mood State, and perceived exertion. Chronobiol Int. 2019;36(9):1249&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31368366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Marshall S. Circadian rhythms in power output on a swim bench. J Swim Res. 1991;7(2):11&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Sesbo&#xfc;&#xe9; B, Gauthier A, Larue J, Davenne D. Effects of one night&#x2019;s sleep deprivation on anaerobic performance the following day. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89(3):359&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12736846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buijs RM, Tinoco ECS, Alvarado GH, Escobar C. The circadian system: from clocks to physiology. Handb Clin Neurol. 2021;179:233&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34225965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala V, Mart&#xed;nez-Bebia M, Latorre JA, Gimenez-Blasi N, Jimenez-Casquet MJ, Conde-Pipo J, et al. Influence of circadian rhythms on sports performance. Chronobiol Int. 2021;38(11):1522&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34060402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Engel FA, Fakhfakh H, Fakhfakh H, Hammouda O, Ammar A, et al. Diurnal variation of short-term repetitive maximal performance and psychological variables in elite judo athletes. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6212582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30416454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facer-Childs ER, Boiling S, Balanos GM. The effects of time of day and chronotype on cognitive and physical performance in healthy volunteers. Sports Med - Open. 2018;4(1):47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6200828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30357501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Souissi N. The effect of training at a specific time of day: a review. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2012;26(7):1984&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22531613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horta TA, Bara Filho MG, Coimbra DR, Miranda R, Werneck FZ. Training load, physical performance, biochemical markers, and psychological stress during a short preparatory period in Brazilian elite male volleyball players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2019;33(12):3392&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29239985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guelmami N, Ben Ezzeddine L, Hatem G, Trabelsi O, Ben Saad H, Glenn JM, El Omri A, Chalghaf N, Taheri M, Bouassida A, Ben Aissa M. The ethical compass: Establishing ethical guidelines for research practices in sports medicine and exercise science. Int J Sport Stud Health. 2024;7(2):31&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF III, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns MW. A new method for measuring daytime sleepiness: the Epworth sleepiness scale. Sleep. 1991;14(6):540&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1798888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincivero DM, Bachmeier B, Coelho AJ. The effects of joint angle and reliability on knee proprioception. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(10):1708&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Dizdar D, Jukic I, Cardinale M. Reliability and factorial validity of squat and countermovement jump tests. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2004;18(3):551&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauole K, Madole K, Garhammer J, Lacourse M, Rozenek R. Reliability and validity of the T-test as a measure of agility, leg power, and leg speed in college-aged men and women. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2000;14(4):443&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassi RH, Dardouri W, Yahmed MH, Gmada N, Mahfoudhi ME, Gharbi Z. Relative and absolute reliability of a modified agility T-test and its relationship with vertical jump and straight sprint. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2009;23(6):1644&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrow D, Young W, Bruce L. The development of a test of reactive agility for Netball: a new methodology. J Sci Med Sport. 2005;8(1):52&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15887901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroop JR. Studies of interference in serial verbal reactions. J Exp Psychol. 1935;18(6):643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarraya M, Jarraya S, Chtourou H, Souissi N, Chamari K. The effect of partial sleep deprivation on the reaction time and the attentional capacities of the handball goalkeeper. Biol Rhythm Res. 2013;44(3):503&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Droppleman LF, McNair DM. An experimental analog of public speaking. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1971;36(1):91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5100697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cayrou S, Dickes P, Gauvain-Piquard A, Dolbeault S, Callahan S, Roge B. Validation de La traduction Fran&#xe7;aise du POMS (Profile of mood States). Psychologie Et Psychom&#xe9;trie. 2000;21(4):5&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel R. Schlafst&#xf6;rungen Im alter [Sleep disorders in the aged]. Internist (Berl). 1984;25(9):552&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6386736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14(5):377&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: a practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol. 2013;4:863. 10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3840331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster RG, Roenneberg T. Human responses to the geophysical daily, annual and lunar cycles. Curr Biol. 2008;18(17):R784&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18786384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adan A, Archer SN, Hidalgo MP, Di Milia L, Natale V, Randler C. Circadian typology: A comprehensive review. Chronobiol Int. 2012;29(9):1153&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23004349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blatter K, Cajochen C. Circadian rhythms in cognitive performance: methodological constraints, protocols, theoretical underpinnings. Physiol Behav. 2007;90(2&#x2013;3):196&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17055007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A, Chtourou H, Souissi N. Effect of time-of-day on biochemical markers in response to physical exercise. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2017;31(1):272&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27191691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammouda O, Chtourou H, Chaouachi A, Chahed H, Bellimem H, Chamari K, et al. Time-of-day effects on biochemical responses to soccer-specific endurance in elite Tunisian football players. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(9):963&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23311995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirizio GG, Nunes RSM, Vargas DA, Foster C, Vieira E. Time-of-day effects on short-duration maximal exercise performance. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):9485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32528038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Liang J, Wang K, Zhang T, Liu S, Luo J. Mood status response to physical activity and its influence on performance: are chronotype and exercise timing affect? Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(4):2822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9956388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36833520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veale DMWDC. Exercise and mental health. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1987;76(2):113&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2890264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender AM, Lambing KA. A practical guide to improve sleep and performance in athletes. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2023;17479541231201105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brager AJ, Gordon JA III, Rouska A, Moore BA, Mysliwiec V. Circadian advantages in elite athletes. In: Sleep and Sport [Internet]. Elsevier; 2024 [cited 2024 Jul 27]. pp. 205&#x2013;24. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780128229699000122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miletin MS, Hanly PJ. Measurement properties of the Epworth sleepiness scale. Sleep Med. 2003;4(3):195&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghiasvand P, Irandoust K. Moving for better sleep: A narrative review of exercise and sleep quality. Int J Sport Stud Health. 2024;7(3):25&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantini NW, Dubnov G, Lebrun CM. The menstrual cycle and sport performance. Clin Sports Med. 2005;24(2):e51&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15892917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julian R, Hecksteden A, Fullagar HH, Meyer T. The effects of menstrual cycle phase on physical performance in female soccer players. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(3):e0173951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5348024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meigni&#xe9; A, Duclos M, Carling C, Orhant E, Provost P, Toussaint JF, et al. The effects of menstrual cycle phase on elite athlete performance: a critical and systematic review. Front Physiol. 2021;12:654585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8170151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34093223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikstr&#xf6;m-Fris&#xe9;n L, Boraxbekk CJ, Henriksson-Larsen K. Effects on power, strength and lean body mass of menstrual/oral contraceptive cycle based resistance training. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2017;57(1&#x2013;2):43&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26558833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein C, Behringer M. Mechanisms underlying menstrual cycle effects on exercise performance: A scoping review. Women Sport Phys Activity J. 2023;31(2):129&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado RCR, Silveira R, Kilpatrick MW, Pires FO, Asano RY. The effect of menstrual cycle and exercise intensity on psychological and physiological responses in healthy eumenorrheic women. Physiol Behav. 2021;232:113290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Secher N, Snell P, Williams C. Physiology of sports: an overview. Physiol Sports. 1990;465&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks KM, McNulty K, Ansdell P. The Effect of the Menstrual Cycle on Exercise and Sports Performance. In: Hackney AC, editor. Sex Hormones, Exercise and Women [Internet]. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2023 [cited 2024 Jul 27]. pp. 245&#x2013;57. Available from: https://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-3-031-21881-1_11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung E, Han A, Hinrichs T, Vorgerd M, Manchado C, Platen P. Effects of follicular versus luteal phase-based strength training in young women. SpringerPlus. 2014;3(1):668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4236309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25485203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankovich RJ, Lebrun CM. Menstrual cycle, contraception, and performance. Clin Sports Med. 2000;19(2):251&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10740758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jonge J. Effects of the menstrual cycle on exercise performance. Sports Med. 2003;33(11):833&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12959622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smekal G, Von Duvillard SP, Frigo P, Tegelhofer T, Pokan R, Hofmann P, et al. Menstrual cycle: no effect on exercise cardiorespiratory variables or blood lactate concentration. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(7):1098&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17596777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackney AC. Influence of oestrogen on muscle glycogen utilization during exercise. Acta Physiol Scand. 1999;167(3):273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10606830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebrun CM, McKENZIE DC, PRIOR JC, TAUNTON JE. Effects of menstrual cycle phase on athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27(3):437&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7752873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montain SJ, Coyle EF. Influence of graded dehydration on hyperthermia and cardiovascular drift during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1992;73(4):1340&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1447078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pivarnik JM, Marichal CJ, Spillman T, Morrow JR. Menstrual cycle phase affects temperature regulation during endurance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1992;72(2):543&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1559930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieczorek K, Targonskaya A, Maslowski K. Reproductive hormones and female mental wellbeing. Women. 2023;3(3):432&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forst C. Burnout and Overtraining in Division 1 Female Soccer Athletes. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi C, Amato A, Alesi M, Alioto A, Proia P. Hormonal and psychological influences on performance anxiety in adolescent female volleyball players: a multi-approach study. PeerJ. 2024;12:e16617. 10.7717/peerj.16617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.16617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10883150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe4;ckstr&#xf6;m T, Andersson A, Andre&#xe9; L, Birzniece V, Bixo M, Bj&#xf6;rn I, et al. Pathogenesis in menstrual Cycle-Linked CNS disorders. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2003;1007(1):42&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14993039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstr&#xf6;m Poromaa I, Gingnell M. Menstrual cycle influence on cognitive function and emotion processing&#x2014;from a reproductive perspective. Front NeuroSci. 2014;8:380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25505380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toffoletto S, Lanzenberger R, Gingnell M, Sundstr&#xf6;m-Poromaa I, Comasco E. Emotional and cognitive functional imaging of Estrogen and progesterone effects in the female human brain: a systematic review. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2014;50:28&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNulty KL, Elliott-Sale KJ, Dolan E, Swinton PA, Ansdell P, Goodall S, et al. The effects of menstrual cycle phase on exercise performance in eumenorrheic women: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(10):1813&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frid&#xe9;n C. Neuromuscular performance and balance during the menstrual cycle and the influence of premenstrual symptoms [Internet]. Institutionen f&#xf6;r kvinnors och barns h&#xe4;lsa/Department of Women&#x2019;s and&#x2026;; 2004 [cited 2024 Jul 27]. Available from: https://openarchive.ki.se/xmlui/handle/10616/38957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sims ST, Heather AK. Myths and methodologies: reducing scientific design ambiguity in studies comparing sexes and/or menstrual cycle phases. Exp Physiol. 2018;103(10):1309&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Stefanyshyn DJ, Ramage B, Hart DA, Ronsky JL. Alterations in knee joint laxity during the menstrual cycle in healthy women leads to increases in joint loads during selected athletic movements. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37(6):1169&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker FC, Siboza F, Fuller A. Temperature regulation in women: effects of the menstrual cycle. Temperature. 2020;7(3):226&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#x10d;m&#xe1;rov&#xe1; B, Kr&#x10d;m&#xe1;r M, Schwarzov&#xe1; M, Chlebo P, Chlebov&#xe1; Z, &#x17d;idek R, et al. The effects of 12-week progressive strength training on strength, functional capacity, metabolic biomarkers, and serum hormone concentrations in healthy older women: morning versus evening training. Chronobiol Int. 2018;35(11):1490&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Saad HB, Glenn JM, Aissa MB, Taheri M, Swed S, Guelmami N, Chamari K. A thorough examination of ChatGPT-3.5 potential applications in medical writing: A preliminary study. Medicine. 2024;103(40):e39757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11460921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39465713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Fekih-Romdhane F, Glenn JM, Saifeddin Fessi M, Chamari K, Dhahbi W, Zghibi M, Bragazzi NL, Ben Aissa M, Guelmami N, El Omri A. Moving beyond the stigma: Understanding and overcoming the resistance to the acceptance and adoption of artificial intelligence chatbots. New Asian J Med. 2023;1(2):29&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>