<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41668951</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>43</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of daytime napping on psychophysiological measures in physically active individuals and athletes: A systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression, with assessment of the certainty of evidence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>149</StartPage><EndPage>163</EndPage><MedlinePgn>149-163</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2026.153310</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To synthesise the impacts of napping following normal sleep (NS) or deprived sleep on psychophysiological measures in physically active individuals and athletes. This systematic review and metaanalysis utilized nine databases, including Web of Science, PubMed/MEDLINE, Scopus, SPORTDiscus, Embase, ProQuest Central, Cochrane Library, PsycInfo, and SciElo, to evaluate the effects of napping in physically active individuals and athletes, focusing on psychophysiological measures. The risk of bias in the included studies was assessed using the Cochrane Collaboration's RoB 2.0 tool, while the certainty of evidence (CoE) was evaluated using the GRADE (Grading of Recommendations, Assessment, Development, and Evaluations) approach. In the 35 studies, 489 participants (athletes or physically active) were studied. Following NS, napping significantly reduced total mood score (standardized mean difference (SMD)=0.61), fatigue (SMD=0.91), rating of perceived exertion (RPE) both during (SMD=1.62) and immediately after exercise (SMD=1.11). Additionally, napping significantly improved perceived recovery (SMD=1.66). There were no significant effects of napping on sleepiness (SMD=1.09), muscle soreness (SMD=1.57), heart rate during exercise (SMD=0.62), and temperature (SMD=0.66). Similarly, following sleep deprivation, there were no significant effects of napping on sleepiness (SMD=1.03) and fatigue (SMD=0.79). The CoE was rated as moderate for RPE during and after exercise following NS, while it was low to very low for the remaining outcomes. Napping has been found to positively impact only fatigue, mood states, perceived exertion, and recovery following NS in physically active individuals and athletes. The low-to-very low CoE requires cautious interpretation, highlighting the need for further napping studies implementing robust methodologies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Institute of Sport &#x2013; National Research Instutite.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boukhris</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Performance, and Nutrition Research Group, School of Allied Health, Human Services, and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SIESTA Research Group, School of Allied Health, Human Services and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trabelsi</LastName><ForeName>Khaled</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research laboratory, Education, Motricity, Sport and Health (EM2S), LR15JS01, High Institute of Sport and Physical Education, University of Sfax, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement Sciences and Sports Training, School of Sport Science, The University of Jordan, Amman-Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suppiah</LastName><ForeName>Haresh</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Performance, and Nutrition Research Group, School of Allied Health, Human Services, and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SIESTA Research Group, School of Allied Health, Human Services and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jahrami</LastName><ForeName>Haitham</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Ministry of Health, Manama, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, College of Medicine and Medical Sciences, Arabian Gulf University, Manama, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Driller</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport, Performance, and Nutrition Research Group, School of Allied Health, Human Services, and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SIESTA Research Group, School of Allied Health, Human Services and Sport, La Trobe University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nap</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sport</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41668951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12884900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2026.153310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cunha LA, Costa JA, Marques EA, Brito J, Lastella M, Figueiredo P. The Impact of Sleep Interventions on Athletic Performance: A Systematic Review. Sports Med-Open. 2023; 9(1):58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10354314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, Roach GD, N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Gupta L, et al. Sleep and the athlete: Narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med. 2021; 55(7):356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP. Sleep, Recovery, and Athletic Performance: A Brief Review and Recommendations. Strength Cond J. 2013; 35(5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandt R, Bevilacqua GG, Andrade A. Perceived Sleep Quality, Mood States, and Their Relationship With Performance Among Brazilian Elite Athletes During a Competitive Period. J Strength Cond Res. 2017; 31(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28328717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sura&#x142;a O, Malczewska-Lenczowska J, Sitkowski D, Witek K, S&#x142;omi&#x144;ski P, Certa M, et al. Effect of training load on sleep parameters and biochemical fatigue markers in elite swimmers. Biol Sport. 2023; 40(4):1229&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10588581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37867745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romyn G, Lastella M, Miller DJ, Versey NG, Roach GD, Sargent C. Daytime naps can be used to supplement night-time sleep in athletes. Chronobiol Int. 2018; 35(6):865&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30024323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botonis PG, Koutouvakis N, Toubekis AG. The impact of daytime napping on athletic performance &#x2013; A narrative review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021; 31(12):2164&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Halson SL, Vitale JA, Memon AR, Vincent GE. To Nap or Not to Nap? A Systematic Review Evaluating Napping Behavior in Athletes and the Impact on Various Measures of Athletic Performance. Nat Sci Sleep. 2021; 13(null):841&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8238550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34194254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Trabelsi K, Suppiah H, Ammar A, Clark CCT, Jahrami H, et al. The Impact of Daytime Napping Following Normal Night-Time Sleep on Physical Performance: A Systematic Review, Meta-analysis and Metaregression. Sports Med. 2024; 54(2):323&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37700141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Abdessalem R, Hsouna H, Glenn JM, et al. A 90 min Daytime Nap Opportunity Is Better Than 40 min for Cognitive and Physical Performance. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020; 17(13).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7369743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32605240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Trabelsi K, Hill DW, Hsouna H, Abdessalem R, Ammar A, et al. Physiological response and physical performance after 40 min and 90 min daytime nap opportunities. Res Sports Med. 2023; 31(6):881&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35611984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesas AE, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez de Arenas-Arroyo S, Martinez-Vizcaino V, Garrido-Miguel M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rodr&#xed;guez R, Bizzozero-Peroni B, et al. Is daytime napping an effective strategy to improve sport-related cognitive and physical performance and reduce fatigue? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med. 2023; 57(7):417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36690376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souabni M, Hammouda O, Romdhani M, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Driss T. Benefits of Daytime Napping Opportunity on Physical and Cognitive Performances in Physically Active Participants: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2021; 51(10):2115&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34043185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirohi P, Khan MH, Sharma S, Nuhmani S, Al Muslem WH, Abualait T. A systematic review of effects of daytime napping strategies on sports performance in physically active individuals with and without partial-sleep deprivation. PeerJ. 2022; 10:e14460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9744144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36518294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade A, Bevilacqua GG, Coimbra DR, Pereira FS, Brandt R. Sleep Quality, Mood and Performance: A Study of Elite Brazilian Volleyball Athletes. J Sports Sci Med. 2016; 15:601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5131213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27928205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoeber J. The dual nature of perfectionism in sports: relationships with emotion, motivation, and performance. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2011; 4(2):128&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Hsouna H, Abdessalem R, Altmann S, et al. Performance, muscle damage, and inflammatory responses to repeated high-intensity exercise following a 40-min nap. Res Sports Med. 2023; 31(4):398&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34665981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Atkinson G, Edwards B, Reilly T. The role of a short post-lunch nap in improving cognitive, motor, and sprint performance in participants with partial sleep deprivation. J Sports Sci. 2007; 25(14):1557&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brotherton EJ, Moseley SE, Langan-Evans C, Pullinger SA, Robertson CM, Burniston JG, et al. Effects of two nights partial sleep deprivation on an evening submaximal weightlifting performance; are 1 h powernaps useful on the day of competition? Chronobiol Int. 2019; 36(3):407&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30626222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell S, Beaven CM, Driller M. The Influence of Match-Day Napping in Elite Female Netball Athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018; 13(9):1143&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29543074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanabe K, Nakazato K, Noi S. Effects of prophylactic naps on physical fitness/exercise ability and executive function in healthy young trained males. Biol Rhythm Res. 2020; 51(3):421&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suppiah HT, Low CY, Choong G, Chia M. Effects of a Short Daytime Nap on Shooting and Sprint Performance in High-Level Adolescent Athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019; 14(1):76&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29893599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajjimaporn A, Ramyarangsi P, Siripornpanich V. Effects of a 20-min Nap after Sleep Deprivation on Brain Activity and Soccer Performance. Int J Sports Med. 2020; 41(14):1009&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32629506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musahl V, Karlsson J, Hirschmann MT, Ayeni OR, Marx RG, Koh JL, et al. Basic Methods Handbook for Clinical Orthopaedic Research. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2019. 1&#x2013;570 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagger M. Meta-analysis. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2022; 15(1):120&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Moher D, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021; 372:n160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, B&#xfc;ttner F, Andrade R, Weir A, Ashe MC, Holden S, et al. Implementing the 27 PRISMA 2020 Statement items for systematic reviews in the sport and exercise medicine, musculoskeletal rehabilitation and sports science fields: the PERSiST (implementing Prisma in Exercise, Rehabilitation, Sport medicine and SporTs science) guidance. Br J Sports Med. 2022; 56(4):175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34625401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rico-Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Pino-Ortega J, Clemente F, Los Arcos A. Guidelines for performing systematic reviews in sports science. Biol Sport. 2022; 39(2):463&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019; 366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, Kunz R, Falck-Ytter Y, Alonso-Coello P, et al. GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2008; 336(7650):924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2335261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W, Cheung MWL. Outlier and influence diagnostics for metaanalysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010; 1(2):112&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26061377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Controlled Clin Trials. 1986; 7(3):177&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assink M, Wibbelink CJ. Fitting three-level meta-analytic models in R: A step-by-step tutorial. Quant Meth Psych. 2016; 12:154&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung MWL. A Guide to Conducting a Meta-Analysis with Non-Independent Effect Sizes. Neuropsychol Rev. 2019; 29(4):387&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31446547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale,NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochran WG. The combination of estimates from different experiments. Biometrics. 1954; 10:101&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003; 327(7414):557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens JP. Outliers and influential data points in regression analysis. US: American Psychological Association; 1984. p. 334&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguinis H, Gottfredson RK, Wright TA. Best-practice recommendations for estimating interaction effects using meta-analysis. J Organ Behav. 2011; 32(8):1033&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begg CB, Mazumdar M. Operating characteristics of a rank correlation test for publication bias. Biometrics. 1994:1088&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7786990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Castilla B, Declercq L, Jamshidi L, Beretvas SN, Onghena P, Van den Noortgate W. Detecting Selection Bias in Meta-Analyses with Multiple Outcomes: A Simulation Study. J Exp Educ. 2021; 89(1):125&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32808180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kmet LM, Cook LS, Lee RC. Standard quality assessment criteria for evaluating primary research papers from a variety of fields. HTA Initiat. 2004; 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit E, Mougin F, Bourdin H, Tio G, Haffen E. A 20-min nap in athletes changes subsequent sleep architecture but does not alter physical performances after normal sleep or 5-h phase-advance conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014; 114(2):305&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24276580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelka M, K&#xf6;lling S, Ferrauti A, Meyer T, Pfeiffer M, Kellmann M. Acute effects of psychological relaxation techniques between two physical tasks. J Sports Sci. 2017; 35(3):216&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26999625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchfield AW, Lewis-Jones TM, Wignall JR, Roberts JB, Oliver SJ. The influence of an afternoon nap on the endurance performance of trained runners. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018; 18(9):1177&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29851569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammouda O, Romdhani M, Chaabouni Y, Mahdouani K, Driss T, Souissi N. Diurnal napping after partial sleep deprivation affected hematological and biochemical responses during repeated sprint. Bio Rhythm Res. 2018; 49(6):927&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdessalem R, Boukhris O, Hsouna H, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Taheri M, et al. Effect of napping opportunity at different times of day on vigilance and shuttle run performance. Chronobiol Int. 2019; 36(10):1334&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31368367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Abdessalem R, Ammar A, Hsouna H, Trabelsi K, Engel FA, et al. Nap Opportunity During the Daytime Affects Performance and Perceived Exertion in 5-m Shuttle Run Test. Front Physiol. 2019; 10:779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6596336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31281263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Abdessalem R, Hsouna H, Glenn JM, et al. A 90 min Daytime Nap Opportunity Is Better Than 40 min for Cognitive and Physical Performance. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020; 17(13).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7369743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32605240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Zghal F, Trabelsi K, Suppiah H, Ammar A, Jahrami H, et al. The impact of a 40-min nap on neuromuscular fatigue profile and recovery following the 5-m shuttle run test. J Sleep Res. 2024; 33(1):e14052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37803885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daaloul H, Souissi N, Davenne D. Effects of Napping on Alertness, Cognitive, and Physical Outcomes of Karate Athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019; 51(2):338&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30239491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsouna H, Boukhris O, Hill DW, Abdessalem R, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, et al. A daytime 40-min nap opportunity after a simulated late evening soccer match reduces the perception of fatigue and improves 5-m shuttle run performance. Res Sports Med. 2022; 30(5):502&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33998848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsouna H, Boukhris O, Abdessalem R, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Shephard RJ, et al. Effect of different nap opportunity durations on short-term maximal performance, attention, feelings, muscle soreness, fatigue, stress and sleep. Physiol Behav. 2019; 211:112673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31491444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Dergaa I, Moussa-Chamari I, Souissi N, Chaabouni Y, Mahdouani K, et al. The effect of post-lunch napping on mood, reaction time, and antioxidant defense during repeated sprint exercice. Biol Sport. 2021; 38(4):629&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Souissi N, Dergaa I, Moussa-Chamari I, Abene O, Chtourou H, et al. The Effect of Experimental Recuperative and Appetitive Post-lunch Nap Opportunities, With or Without Caffeine, on Mood and Reaction Time in Highly Trained Athletes. Front Psychol. 2021; 12:720493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8473839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34589026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Souissi N, Dergaa I, Moussa-Chamari I, Chaabouni Y, Mahdouani K, et al. The effect of caffeine, nap opportunity and their combination on biomarkers of muscle damage and antioxidant defence during repeated sprint exercise. Biol Sport. 2022; 39(4):1033&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9536395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Souissi N, Moussa-Chamari I, Chaabouni Y, Mahdouani K, Sahnoun Z, et al. Caffeine Use or Napping to Enhance Repeated Sprint Performance After Partial Sleep Deprivation: Why Not Both? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021; 16(5):711&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Souissi N, Chaabouni Y, Mahdouani K, Driss T, Chamari K, et al. Improved Physical Performance and Decreased Muscular and Oxidative Damage With Postlunch Napping After Partial Sleep Deprivation in Athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020; 15(6):874&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32023544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi M, Souissi Y, Bayoudh A, Knechtle B, Nikolaidis PT, Chtourou H. Effects of a 30 min nap opportunity on cognitive and short-duration highintensity performances and mood states after a partial sleep deprivation night. J Sports Sci. 2020; 38(22):2553&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32734824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A, Boukhris O, Hsouna H, Dhia IB, Trabelsi K, Gujar TA, et al. The effect of a daytime 60-min nap opportunity on postural control in highly active individuals. Biol Sport. 2021; 38(4):683&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida M, Yamamoto K, Murata Y, Ichinose A, Shioda K. Exploring the Effect of Long Naps on Handball Performance and Heart Rate Variability. Sports Med Int Open. 2021; 5(3):E73&#x2013;E80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8443333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34541302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida M, Okano S, Ichinose A, Suyama S, Youn S. Daytime Napping Benefits Passing Performance and Scanning Activity in Elite Soccer Players. J Sports Sci Med. 2023; 22:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9982537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36876185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souabni M, Hammouda O, Souabni MJ, Romdhani M, Driss T. 40-min nap opportunity attenuates heart rate and perceived exertion and improves physical specific abilities in elite basketball players. Res Sports Med. 2023; 31(6):859&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souabni M, Hammouda O, Souabni MJ, Romdhani M, Souissi W, Ammar A, et al. Nap improved game-related technical performance and physiological response during small-sided basketball game in professional players. Biol Sport. 2023; 40(2):389&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10108772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentouati E, Romdhani M, Abid R, Khemila S, Garbarino S, Souissi N. The combined effects of napping and self-selected motivation music during warming up on cognitive and physical performance of karate athletes. Front Physiol. 2023; 14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10372344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37520834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teece AR, Beaven CM, Argus CK, Gill N, Driller MW. Daytime naps improve afternoon power and perceptual measures in elite rugby union athletes-a randomized cross-over trial. Sleep. 2023; 46(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10710987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37155971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willmer F, Reuter C, Pramsohler S, Faulhaber M, Burkhardt A, Netzer N. The Effects of Napping on Wakefulness and Endurance Performance in Athletes: A Randomized Crossover Study. Life (Basel, Switzerland). 2023; 13(6).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10301598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37374196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurto&#x11f;lu A, Eken &#xd6;, Engin A, &#xc7;ar B, Nobari H. The impact of strategic napping on peak expiratory flow and respiratory function in young elite athletes. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024; 16:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10854142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38336766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher C, Green CE, Kenny ML, Evans JR, McCullagh GDW, Pullinger SA, et al. Is implementing a post-lunch nap beneficial on evening performance, following two nights partial sleep restriction? Chronobiol Int. 2023(9):1169&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37722387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholls AR, Polman RCJ. Coping in sport: A systematic review. J Sports Sci. 2007; 25(1):11&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17127578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papatsimpa C, Schlangen LJM, Smolders KCHJ, Linnartz JPMG, de Kort YAW. The interindividual variability of sleep timing and circadian phase in humans is influenced by daytime and evening light conditions. Sci Rep. 2021; 11(1):13709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8249410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34211005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montaruli A, Castelli L, Mul&#xe8; A, Scurati R, Esposito F, Galasso L, et al. Biological Rhythm and Chronotype: New Perspectives in Health. Biomolecules. 2021; 11(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8063933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33804974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell SS, Murphy PJ, Stauble TN. Effects of a Nap on Nighttime Sleep and Waking Function in Older Subjects. J Am Ger Soc. 2005; 53(1):48&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15667375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spineli LM, Pandis N. Problems and pitfalls in subgroup analysis and meta-regression. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 2020; 158(6):901&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>