<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31403575</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Well-Being Indices and Recovery State on the Technical and Physiological Aspects of Play During Small-Sided Games.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2802</StartPage><EndPage>2809</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2802-2809</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003228</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Selmi, O, Gon&#xe7;alves, B, Levitt, DE, Ouergui, I, Sampaio, J, and Bouassida, A. Influence of well-being indices and recovery state on the technical and physiological aspects of play during small-sided games. J Strength Cond Res 35(10): 2802-2809, 2021-Soccer players performing at high level are frequently exposed to periods of intense training, which can induce substantial stress and fatigue. These high-intensity stimuli likely lead to a lower state of well-being and poor recovery and, consequently, may affect players' performance. This study aimed to assess the influence of well-being indices (i.e., self-ratings of sleep, stress, fatigue, and delayed onset muscle soreness [DOMS]) and the total quality of recovery (TQR) on technical and physiological measures during soccer small-sided games (SSGs). Twenty male professional soccer players (age: 25.1 &#xb1; 1.0 years) performed four 25-minute SSG sessions. Well-being indices were collected before each SSG-session. Heart rate was continuously measured throughout each session, and the ratings of perceived exertion and blood lactate concentration were collected after each SSG. A hierarchical cluster analysis was performed across variables and cases to identify associations between variables and variability in players' responses between sessions. No significant correlations were found between well-being indices, TQR and physiological parameters. Total quality recovery was positively correlated with successful pass % (r = 0.27) and interceptions (r = 0.25) and negatively correlated with lost balls (r = -0.25). Fatigue and DOMS were negatively correlated with tackles (r = -0.29, r = -0.28, respectively), successful pass % (r = -0.58, r = -0.55, respectively) and interceptions (r = -0.25, r = -0.27, respectively), and positively correlated with lost balls (r = 0.32, r = 0.28, respectively). Results provide an alternative and complementary method to understand training responses and can be an objective tool to help create subgroups in training for optimizing performance. This study demonstrates the efficacy and utility of using simple well-being and recovery measures to help coaches monitor athlete readiness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Selmi</LastName><ForeName>Okba</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Sportive Performance and Physical Rehabilitation, High Institute of Sports and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, Faculty of Sciences of Bizerte, University of Carthage, Zarzouna-Bizerte, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gon&#xe7;alves</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center in Sports Sciences, Health Sciences and Human Development, CIDESD, University of Tr&#xe1;s-os-Montes and Alto Douro, UTAD, Vila Real, Portugal; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ouergui</LastName><ForeName>Ibrahim</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Sportive Performance and Physical Rehabilitation, High Institute of Sports and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levitt</LastName><ForeName>Danielle E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotion and Recreation, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sampaio</LastName><ForeName>Jaime</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center in Sports Sciences, Health Sciences and Human Development, CIDESD, University of Tr&#xe1;s-os-Montes and Alto Douro, UTAD, Vila Real, Portugal; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouassida</LastName><ForeName>Anissa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Sportive Performance and Physical Rehabilitation, High Institute of Sports and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31403575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202110000-00021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abade EA, Gon&#xe7;alves BV, Silva AM, et al. Classifying young soccer players by training performances. Percept Mot Skills 119: 971&#x2013;984, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brink MS, Nederhof E, Visscher C, Schmikli SL, Lemmink KA. Monitoring load, recovery, and performance in young elite soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 24: 597&#x2013;603, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casamichana D, Castellano J, Dellal A. Influence of different training regimes on physical and physiological demands during small-sided soccer games: Continuous vs. intermittent format. J Strength Cond Res 27: 690&#x2013;697, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellano J, Casamichana D, Dellal A. Influence of game format and number of players on heart rate responses and physical demands in small-sided soccer games. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1295&#x2013;1303, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamari K, Haddad M, Wong del P, Dellal A, Chaouachi A. Injury rates in professional soccer players during Ramadan. J Sports Sci 30(Suppl 1): S93&#x2013;S102, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutinho D, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Travassos B, et al. Mental fatigue and spatial references impair soccer players' physical and tactical performances. Front Psychol 8: 1645, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutinho D, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Wong DP, et al. Exploring the effects of mental and muscular fatigue in soccer players' performance. Hum Mov Sci 58: 287&#x2013;296, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ, Reaburn P. Monitoring changes in rugby league players' perceived stress and recovery during intensified training. Percept Mot Skills 106: 904&#x2013;916, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva CD, Impellizzeri FM, Natali AJ, et al. Exercise intensity and technical demands of small-sided games in young Brazilian soccer players: Effect of number of players, maturation, and reliability. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2746&#x2013;2751, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellal A, Chamari K, Pintus A, et al. Heart rate responses during small-sided games and short intermittent running training in elite soccer players: A comparative study. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1449&#x2013;1457, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellal A, Owen A, Wong DP, et al. Technical and physical demands of small vs. large sided games in relation to playing position in elite soccer. Hum Mov Sci 31: 957&#x2013;969, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elloumi M, Makni E, Moalla W, et al. Monitoring training load and fatigue in rugby sevens players. Asian J Sports Med 3: 175&#x2013;184, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanchini M, Azzalin A, Castagna C, et al. Effect of bout duration on exercise intensity and technical performance of small-sided games in soccer. J Strength Cond Res 25: 453&#x2013;458, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraz R, van den Tillaar R, Marques MC. The effect of fatigue on kicking velocity in soccer players. J Hum Kinet 35: 97&#x2013;107, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fessi MS, Nouira S, Dellal A, et al. Changes of the psychophysical state and feeling of wellness of professional soccer players during pre-season and in-season periods. Res Sports Med 24: 375&#x2013;386, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folgado H, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Sampaio J. Positional synchronization affects physical and physiological responses to preseason in professional football (soccer). Res Sports Med 26: 51&#x2013;63, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res 15: 109&#x2013;115, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas VH, Nakamura FY, Miloski B, Samulski D, Bara-Filho MG. Sensitivity of physiological and psychological markers to training load intensification in volleyball players. J Sports Sci Med 13: 571&#x2013;579, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo TF, Cormack SJ, Gabbett TJ, Lorenzen CH. Pre-training perceived wellness impacts training output in Australian football players. J Sports Sci 34: 1445&#x2013;1451, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves B, Esteves P, Folgado H, et al. Effects of pitch area-restrictions on tactical behavior, physical, and physiological performances in soccer large-sided games. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2398&#x2013;2408, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves B, Marcelino R, Torres-Ronda L, Torrents C, Sampaio J. Effects of emphasising opposition and cooperation on collective movement behaviour during football small-sided games. J Sports Sci 34: 1346&#x2013;1354, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad M, Chaouachi A, Wong del P, et al. Influence of fatigue, stress, muscle soreness and sleep on perceived exertion during submaximal effort. Physiol Behav 119: 185&#x2013;189, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Haas S, Dawson B, Impellizzeri M, Coutts J. Physiology of small-sided games training in football: A systematic review. Sports Med 41: 199&#x2013;220, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Haas SV, Coutts AJ, Rowsell GJ, Dawson BT. Generic versus small-sided game training in soccer. Int J Sports Med 30: 636&#x2013;642, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper SL, Mackinnon LT. Monitoring overtraining in athletes: Recommendations. Sports Med 20: 321&#x2013;327, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sport Exer 41: 3&#x2013;12, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katis A, Kellis E. Effects of small-sided games on physical conditioning and performance in young soccer players. J Sports Sci Med 8: 374&#x2013;380, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly DM, Drust B. The effect of pitch dimensions on heart rate responses and technical demands of small-sided soccer games in elite players. J Sci Med Sport 12: 475&#x2013;479, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kentt&#xe4; G, Hassm&#xe9;n P. Overtraining and recovery: A conceptual model. Sports Med 26: 1&#x2013;16, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;kl&#xfc; Y. A comparison of physiological responses to various intermittent and continuous small-sided games in young soccer players. J Hum Kinet 31: 89&#x2013;96, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moalla W, Fessi MS, Farhat F, et al. Relationship between daily training load and psychometric status of professional soccer players. Res Sports Med 24: 387&#x2013;394, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Krustrup P, Bangsbo J. Match performance of high-standard soccer players with special reference to development of fatigue. J Sports Sci 21: 519&#x2013;528, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, McCall A, Carling C, et al. Recovery in soccer: Part I&#x2014;Post-match fatigue and time course of recovery. Sports Med 42: 997&#x2013;1015, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelec M, McCall A, Carling C, et al. The influence of soccer playing actions on the recovery kinetics after a soccer match. J Strength Cond Res 28: 1517&#x2013;1523, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osiecki R, Rubio G, Coelho RL, et al. The total quality recovery scale (TQR) as a proxy for determining athletes' recovery state after a professional soccer match. J Exerc Physiol 18: 27&#x2013;32, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AL, Wong DP, McKenna M, Dellal A. Heart rate responses and technical comparison between small- vs. large-sided games in elite professional soccer. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2104&#x2013;2110, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AL, Wong DP, Paul D, Dellal A. Effects of a periodized small-sided game training intervention on physical performance in elite professional soccer. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2748&#x2013;2754, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platt D, Maxwell A, Horn R, Williams M, Reilly T. Physiological and technical analysis of 3 v 3 and 5 v 5 youth football matches. Insight FACA 4: 23&#x2013;25, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selmi O, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Ouergui I, Sampaio J, Bouassida A. Influence of well-being variables and recovery state in physical enjoyment of professional soccer players during small-sided games. Res Sports Med 26: 199&#x2013;210, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selmi O, Haddad M, Majed L, et al. Soccer training: High-intensity interval training is mood disturbing while small sided games ensure mood balance. J Sport Med Phys Fitness 58:1163&#x2013;1170, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selmi O, Marzouki H, Ouergui I, BenKhalifa W, Bouassida A. Influence of intense training cycle and psychometric status on technical and physiological aspects performed during the small-sided games in soccer players. Res Sports Med 26: 401&#x2013;412, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MR, Coutts AJ, Merlini M, et al. Mental fatigue impairs soccer-specific physical and technical performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 267&#x2013;276, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe RT, Strudwick AJ, Buchheit M, et al. Monitoring fatigue during the in-season competitive phase in elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 10: 958&#x2013;964, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, Gon&#xe7;alves B, Marcelino R, et al. Heart rate, time-motion, and body impacts when changing the number of teammates and opponents in soccer small-sided games. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2723&#x2013;2730, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaz L, Figueira B, Gon&#xe7;alves B. Classifying youth rugby union players by training performances. Int J Perform Anal Sport 15: 159&#x2013;171, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>