<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37062892</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>601</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exogenous ketosis elevates circulating erythropoietin and stimulates muscular angiogenesis during endurance training overload.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2345</StartPage><EndPage>2358</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2345-2358</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP284346</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>De novo capillarization is a primary muscular adaptation to endurance exercise training and is crucial to improving performance. Excess training load, however, impedes such beneficial adaptations, yet we recently demonstrated that such downregulation may be counteracted by ketone ester ingestion (KE) post-exercise. Therefore, we investigated whether KE could increase pro-angiogenic factors and thereby stimulate muscular angiogenesis during a 3-week endurance training-overload period involving 10 training sessions/week in healthy, male volunteers. Subjects received either 25&#xa0;g of a ketone ester (KE, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;9) or a control drink (CON, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;9) immediately after each training session and before sleep. In KE, but not in CON, the training intervention increased the number of capillary contacts and the capillary-to-fibre perimeter exchange index by 44% and 42%, respectively. Furthermore, KE also substantially increased vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and endothelial nitric oxide synthase (eNOS) expression both at the protein and at the mRNA level. Serum erythropoietin concentration was concomitantly increased by 26%. Conversely, in CON the training intervention increased only the protein content of eNOS. These data indicate that intermittent exogenous ketosis during endurance overload training stimulates muscular angiogenesis. This likely resulted from a direct stimulation of muscle angiogenesis, which may be at least partly due to stimulation of erythropoietin secretion and elevated VEGF activity, and/or an inhibition of the suppressive effect of overload training on the normal angiogenic response to training. This study provides novel evidence to support the potential of exogenous ketosis to benefit endurance training-induced muscular adaptation. KEY POINTS: Increased capillarization is a primary muscular adaptation to endurance exercise training. However, excess training load may impede such response. We previously observed that intermittent exogenous ketosis by post-exercise and pre-sleep ketone ester ingestion (KE) counteracted physiological dysregulations induced by endurance overload training. Therefore, we investigated whether KE could increase pro-angiogenic factors thereby stimulating muscular angiogenesis during a 3-week endurance training overload period. We show that the overload training period in the presence, but not in the absence, of KE markedly increased muscle capillarization (+40%). This increase was accompanied by higher circulating erythropoietin concentration and stimulation of the pro-angiogenic factors vascular endothelial growth factor and endothelial nitric oxide synthase in skeletal muscle. Collectively, our data indicate that intermittent exogenous ketosis may evolve as a potent nutritional strategy to facilitate recovery from strenuous endurance exercise, thereby stimulating beneficial muscular adaptations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poff&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Chiel</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8085-3075</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Research Group, Department of Movement Sciences, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robberechts</LastName><ForeName>Ruben</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5715-994X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Research Group, Department of Movement Sciences, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Thienen</LastName><ForeName>Ruud</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Research Group, Department of Movement Sciences, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hespel</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1283-2229</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement Sciences, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D042461">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.14.13.39</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D052250">Nitric Oxide Synthase Type III</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>11096-26-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004921">Erythropoietin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007659">Ketones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004952">Esters</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2023 Sep;601(18):3991-3992. doi: 10.1113/JP285257.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37566813</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endurance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042461" MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052250" MajorTopicYN="N">Nitric Oxide Synthase Type III</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018919" MajorTopicYN="N">Neovascularization, Physiologic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Erythropoietin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007659" MajorTopicYN="N">Ketones</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007662" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ketosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004952" MajorTopicYN="N">Esters</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EPO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VEGF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angiogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ketone</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37062892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP284346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Andersen, A. B., Graae, J., Bejder, J., Bonne, T. C., S&#xf8; S., Debertin, M., Eibye, K., Hostrup, M., &amp; Nordsborg, N. B. (2023). Microdoses of recombinant human erythropoietin enhance time trial performance in trained males and females. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 55(2), 311-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, P., &amp; Henriksson, J. (1977). Capillary supply of the quadriceps femoris muscle of man: Adaptive response to exercise. The Journal of Physiology, 270(3), 677-690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubry, A., Hausswirth, C., Louis, J., Coutts, A. J., &amp; Meur, Y. L. E. (2014). Functional overreaching: The key to peak performance during the taper? Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 46(9), 1769-1777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartlett, J. D., Joo, C. H., Jeong, T. S., Louhelainen, J., Cochran, A. J., Gibala, M. J., Gregson, W., Close, G. L., Drust, B., &amp; Morton, J. P. (2012). Matched work high-intensity interval and continuous running induce similar increases in PGC-1&#x3b1; mRNA, AMPK, p38, and p53 phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle. Journal of Applied Physiology, 112(7), 1135-1143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellinger, P. M., Sabapathy, S., Craven, J., Arnold, B., &amp; Minahan, C. (2019). Overreaching attenuates training-induced improvements in muscle oxidative capacity. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(1), 77-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonen, A. (2001). The expression of lactate transporters (MCT1 and MCT4) in heart and muscle. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 86(1), 6-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth, F. W., &amp; Thomason, D. B. (1991). Molecular and cellular adaptation of muscle in response to exercise: Perspectives of various models. Physiological Reviews, 71(2), 541-585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen, E. C., Johnson, E. C., Wagner, H., Tseng, H. M., Sung, L. A., &amp; Wagner, P. D. (1996). Angiogenic growth factor mRNA responses in muscle to a single bout of exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology, 81(1), 355-361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, A., Huang, G. X., Bonkowski, M. S., Longchamp, A., Li, C., Schultz, M. B., Kim, L.-J., Osborne, B., Joshi, S., Lu, Y., Trevi&#xf1;o-Villarreal, J. H., Kang, M.-J., Hung, T.-T., Lee, B., Williams, E. O., Igarashi, M., Mitchell, J. R., Wu, L. E., Turner, N., &#x2026; Sinclair, D. A. (2018). Impairment of an endothelial NAD+-H2S signaling network is a reversible cause of vascular aging. Cell, 173(1), 74-89.e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaver, H., Nogueira, L., Wagner, P. D., Hogan, M. C., Metzger, D., &amp; Breen, E. C. (2014). Skeletal myofiber VEGF is essential for the exercise training response in adult mice. American Journal of Physiology. Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 306(8), R586-R595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elamin, M., Ruskin, D. N., Masino, S. A., &amp; Sacchetti, P. (2017). Ketone-based metabolic therapy: Is increased nad+ a primary mechanism? Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 10, 377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans, E., Walhin, J.-P., Hengist, A., Betts, J. A., Dearlove, D. J., &amp; Gonzalez, J. T. (2023). Ketone monoester ingestion increases post-exercise serum erythropoietin 2 concentrations in healthy men. American Journal of Physiology. Endocrinology and Metabolism 324(1), E56-E61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraresso, R. L. P., Buscariolli De Oliveira, R., MacEdo, D. V., Alessandro Soares Nunes, L., Brenzikofer, R., Damas, D., &amp; Hohl, R. (2012). Interaction between overtraining and the interindividual variability may (not) trigger muscle oxidative stress and cardiomyocyte apoptosis in rats. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2012, 935483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Caballero, M., Zecchin, A., Souffreau, J., Truong, A.-C. K., Teuwen, L.-A., Vermaelen, W., Mart&#xed;n-P&#xe9;rez, R., de Zeeuw, P., Bouch&#xe9;, A., Vinckier, S., Cornelissen, I., Eelen, G., Ghesqui&#xe8;re, B., Mazzone, M., Dewerchin, M., &amp; Carmeliet, P. (2019). Role and therapeutic potential of dietary ketone bodies in lymph vessel growth. Nature Metabolism, 1(7), 666-675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gliemann, L., Gunnarsson, T. P., Hellsten, Y., &amp; Bangsbo, J. (2015). 10-20-30 training increases performance and lowers blood pressure and VEGF in runners. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports, 25(5), e479-e489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorski, T., &amp; De Bock, K. (2019). Metabolic regulation of exercise-induced angiogenesis. Vascular Biology, 1(1), H1-H8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenwald, A. C., Licht, T., Kumar, S., Oladipupo, S. S., Iyer, S., Grunewald, M., &amp; Keshet, E. (2019). VEGF expands erythropoiesis via hypoxia-independent induction of erythropoietin in noncanonical perivascular stromal cells. Journal of Experimental Medicine, 216(1), 215-230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hepple, R. T. (1997). A new measurement of tissue capillarity: The capillary-to-fibre perimeter exchange index. Canadian Journal of Applied Physiology, 22(1), 11-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoier, B., &amp; Hellsten, Y. (2014). Exercise-induced capillary growth in human skeletal muscle and the dynamics of VEGF. Microcirculation, 21(4), 301-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoier, B., Passos, M., Bangsbo, J., &amp; Hellsten, Y. (2013). Intense intermittent exercise provides weak stimulus for vascular endothelial growth factor secretion and capillary growth in skeletal muscle. Experimental Physiology, 98(2), 585-597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudlicka, O., Brown, M., &amp; Egginton, S. (1992). Angiogenesis in skeletal and cardiac muscle. Physiological Reviews, 72(2), 369-417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isales, C. M., Min, L., &amp; Hoffman, W. H. (1999). Acetoacetate and &#x3b2;-hydroxybutyrate differentially regulate endothelin-1 and vascular endothelial growth factor in mouse brain microvascular endothelial cells. Journal of Diabetes and Its Complications, 13(2), 91-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen, L., Pilegaard, H., Neufer, P. D., &amp; Hellsten, Y. (2004). Effect of acute exercise and exercise training on VEGF splice variants in human skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology. Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 287(2), R397-R402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, Y., Suzuki, N., Yamamoto, M., Gassmann, M., &amp; Noguchi, C. T. (2012). Endogenous erythropoietin signaling facilitates skeletal muscle repair and recovery following pharmacologically induced damage. FASEB Journal, 26(7), 2847-2858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim&#xe1;kov&#xe1;, P., Sol&#xe1;r, P., Sol&#xe1;rov&#xe1;, Z., Komel, R., &amp; Debeljak, N. (2017). Erythropoietin and its angiogenic activity. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 18(7), 19-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kissane, R. W., &amp; Egginton, S. (2019). Exercise-mediated angiogenesis. Current Research in Physiology, 10, 193-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens, D. (2013). Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: A practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Frontiers in Psychology, 4, 863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamon, S., &amp; Russell, A. P. (2013). The role and regulation of erythropoietin (EPO) and its receptor in skeletal muscle: How much do we really know? Frontiers in Psychology, 4, 176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Christensen, P. M., Hellsten, Y., &amp; Gliemann, L. (2022). Effects of exercise training intensity and duration on skeletal muscle capillarization in healthy subjects: A Meta-analysis. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 54(10), 1714-1728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby, C., Robach, P., Boushel, R., Thomsen, J. J., Rasmussen, P., Koskolou, M., &amp; Calbet, J. A. L. (2008). Does recombinant human Epo increase exercise capacity by means other than augmenting oxygen transport? Journal of Applied Physiology, 105(2), 581-587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen, R., Duclos, M., Foster, C., Fry, A., Gleeson, M., Nieman, D., Raglin, J., Rietjens, G., Steinacker, J., &amp; Urhausen, A. (2013). Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: Joint consensus statement of the European College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 45(1), 186-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, E. A., Martin, N. R. W., Bailey, S. J., &amp; Ferguson, R. A. (2018). Critical power is positively related to skeletal muscle capillarity and type i muscle fibers in endurance-trained individuals. Journal of Applied Physiology, 125(3), 737-745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murias, J. M., Kowalchuk, J. M., Ritchie, D., Hepple, R. T., Doherty, T. J., &amp; Paterson, D. H. (2011). Adaptations in capillarization and citrate synthase activity in response to endurance training in older and young men. Journals of Gerontology - Series A Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences, 66A(9), 957-964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachbauer, W., Boesch, S., Reindl, M., Eigentler, A., Hufler, K., Poewe, W., L&#xf6;scher, W., &amp; Wanschitz, J. (2012). Skeletal muscle involvement in friedreich ataxia and potential effects of recombinant human erythropoietin administration on muscle regeneration and neovascularization. Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology, 71(8), 708-715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano, M., Satoh, K., Fukumoto, Y., Ito, Y., Kagaya, Y., Ishii, N., Sugamura, K., &amp; Shimokawa, H. (2007). Important role of erythropoietin receptor to promote VEGF expression and angiogenesis in peripheral ischemia in mice. Circulation Research, 100(5), 662-669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olfert, I. M., Howlett, R. A., Wagner, P. D., &amp; Breen, E. C. (2010). Myocyte vascular endothelial growth factor is required for exercise-induced skeletal muscle angiogenesis. American Journal of Physiology. Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 299(4), R1059-R1067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poff&#xe9;, C., Ramaekers, M., Van Thienen, R., &amp; Hespel, P. (2019). Ketone ester supplementation blunts overreaching symptoms during endurance training overload. The Journal of Physiology, 597(12), 3009-3027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, W., &amp; Prommer, N. (2010). Impact of alterations in total hemoglobin mass on VO2max. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 38(2), 68-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;korjanc, D., Jaschinski, F., Heine, G., &amp; Pette, D. (1998). Sequential increases in capillarization and mitochondrial enzymes in low-frequency-stimulated rabbit muscle. American Journal of Physiology. Cell Physiology, 274(3), C810-C818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soejima, E., Ohki, T., Kurita, Y., Yuan, X., Tanaka, K., Kakino, S., Hara, K., Nakayama, H., Tajiri, Y., &amp; Yamada, K. (2018). Protective effect of 3-hydroxybutyrate against endoplasmic reticulum stress-associated vascular endothelial cell damage induced by low glucose exposure. PLoS ONE, 13(3), 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suresh, S., Rajvanshi, P. K., &amp; Noguchi, C. T. (2020). The many facets of erythropoietin physiologic and metabolic response. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 1-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters, R. E., Rotevatn, S., Li, P., Annex, B. H., &amp; Yan, Z. (2004). Voluntary running induces fiber type-specific angiogenesis in mouse skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology. Cell Physiology, 287(5), C1342-C1348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weis, E., Puchalska, P., Nelson, A. B., Taylor, J., Moll, I., Hasan, S. S., Dewenter, M., Hagenm&#xfc;ller, M., Fleming, T., Poschet, G., Hotz-Wagenblatt, A., Backs, J., Crawford, P. A., &amp; Fischer, A. (2022). Ketone body oxidation increases cardiac endothelial cell proliferation. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 14(4), 1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winder, W. W., Baldwin, K. M., &amp; Holloszy, J. O. (1974). Enzymes involved in ketone utilization in different types of muscle: Adaptation to exercise. European Journal of Biochemistry, 47(3), 461-467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X., Miao, D., Liu, Z., Liu, K., Zhang, B., Li, J., Li, Y., &amp; Qi, J. (2020). &#x3b2;-hydroxybutyrate antagonizes aortic endothelial injury by promoting generation of VEGF in diabetic rats. Tissue &amp; Cell, 64, 101345.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>