<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39431780</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4040</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurosurgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurosurgery</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Initial Symptom Severity and Recovery of Sport-Related Concussion in Team Versus Individual Sport Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1261</StartPage><EndPage>1271</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1261-1271</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1227/neu.0000000000003225</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Recovery after sport-related concussion is variable, and potential differences between team vs individual sport athletes are not fully understood. In a cohort of athletes with concussions, we sought to compare these groups across (1) symptom severity score, (2) individual symptom cluster scores, and (3) recovery metrics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective, cohort study of 13 to 23-year-old athletes treated at a regional sport concussion center between November 2017 and April 2022 was conducted. Athletes were categorized into team vs individual sport athletes, with additional classification of individual sports based on strong vs minimal team elements (ie, the degree of interdependence displayed by athletes). The primary outcomes were symptom severity score, measured by either the Sport Concussion Assessment Tool-5th Edition or the Immediate Post-Concussion Assessment and Cognitive Testing, and physical, cognitive, emotional, and sleep symptom cluster scores. Secondary outcomes were recovery metrics, including time to return-to-learn, symptom resolution, and return-to-play.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 1051 athletes, 954 (90.8%) were in team sports and 97 (9.2%) in individual sports. In multivariable linear regression, individual sport athletes had higher emotional symptom severity compared with team sport athletes (&#x3b2; = 0.09 [0.01, 0.17], P = .034) when adjusting for sex, attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder, psychological disorders, time to clinic, on-field evaluation, and Immediate Post-Concussion Assessment and Cognitive Testing vs Sport Concussion Assessment Tool-5 th Edition scale. There were no significant differences in return-to-learn ( P = .104), symptom resolution ( P = .941), or return-to-play ( P = .279) on univariate regressions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In the current single-center, pilot study of athletes with a sport-related concussion, individual sport athletes exhibited more emotional symptoms than team sport athletes. These preliminary data lend early support that individual sport athletes may be more at risk of emotional symptoms than team sport athletes after a sport-related concussion. Clinicians may use these findings to identify athletes who may be particularly vulnerable to emotional symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Congress of Neurological Surgeons 2024. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Connor C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>James H. Quillen College of Medicine, East Tennessee State University, Johnson City , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dugan</LastName><ForeName>John E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Medicine, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Memphis , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jo</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Vanderbilt University, Nashville , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Kristen L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jonzzon</LastName><ForeName>Soren</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Terry</LastName><ForeName>Douglas P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yengo-Kahn</LastName><ForeName>Aaron M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Neurosurgery, University of Utah School of Medicine, Salt Lake City , Utah , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuckerman</LastName><ForeName>Scott L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2951-2942</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville , Tennessee , USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurosurgery</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7802914</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-396X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Concussion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="Y">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068958" MajorTopicYN="N">Return to Sport</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009483" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emotional symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Initial symptom severity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prolonged recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Return-to-learn</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Return-to-play</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Symptom resolution</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39431780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/neu.0000000000003225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006123-202506000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Schneider KJ, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport: the 6th International Conference on Concussion in Sport&#x2013;Amsterdam, October 2022. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(11):695-711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5th international conference on concussion in sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):838-847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllister TW, Broglio SP, Katz BP, et al. Characteristics and outcomes of athletes with Slow recovery from sports-related concussion: a CARE consortium study. Neurology. 2023;100(14):e1510-e1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker JG, Leddy JJ, Darling SR, Shucard J, Makdissi M, Willer BS. Gender differences in recovery from sports-related concussion in adolescents. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2016;55(8):771-775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang AR, Wallace J, Grusky AZ, et al. Investigation of factors contributing to racial differences in sport-related concussion outcomes. World Neurosurg. 2023;173:e755-e765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeithan L, Hibshman N, Yengo-Kahn AM, Solomon GS, Zuckerman SL. Sport-related concussion: evaluation, treatment, and future directions. Med Sci. 2019;7(3):44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Master CL, Corwin DJ, Fedonni D, et al. Dose-response effect of mental health diagnoses on concussion recovery in children and adolescents. Sports Health. 2024;16(2):254-268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeckell AS, Brett BL, Totten DJ, Solomon GS. Team versus individual sport participation as a modifying factor in the development of post-concussion syndrome after first concussion: a pilot study. Appl Neuropsychol Child. 2019;8(3):199-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang EX, Hwang CE, Nguyen JN, Segovia NA, Abrams GD, Kussman A. Factors associated with a prolonged time to return to play after a concussion. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(6):1695-1701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Ierssel J, Pennock KF, Sampson M, Zemek R, Caron JG. Which psychosocial factors are associated with return to sport following concussion? A systematic review. J Sport Health Sci. 2022;11(4):438-449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuckerman SL, Yengo-Kahn AM, Brett BL, Kuhn AW, Wolfson DI, Kerr ZY. Benefits of team sport participation versus concerns of chronic traumatic encephalopathy: prioritizing the health of our youth. Concussion. 2020;5(2):CNC75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan K, Cuff S, LaBella CR, et al. Organized sports for children, preadolescents, and adolescents. Pediatrics. 2019;143(6):e20190997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guddal MH, Stensland S&#xd8;, Sm&#xe5;stuen MC, Johnsen MB, Zwart J, Storheim K. Physical activity and sport participation among adolescents: associations with mental health in different age groups. Results from the Young-HUNT study: a cross-sectional survey. BMJ Open. 2019;9(9):e028555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann MD, Barnes JD, Tremblay MS, Guerrero MD. Associations between organized sport participation and mental health difficulties: data from over 11,000 US children and adolescents. PLoS One. 2022;17(6):e0268583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pluhar E, McCracken C, Griffith KL, Christino MA, Sugimoto D, Meehan WP 3rd. Team sport athletes may be less likely to suffer anxiety or depression than individual sport athletes. J Sports Sci Med. 2019;18(3):490-496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuckerman SL, Brett BL, Jeckell AS, Yengo-Kahn AM, Solomon GS. Prognostic factors in pediatric sport-related concussion. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2018;18(12):104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL, Gardner AJ, Terry DP, et al. Predictors of clinical recovery from concussion: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(12):941-948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCauley SR, Wilde EA, Miller ER, et al. Preinjury resilience and mood as predictors of early outcome following mild traumatic brain injury. J Neurotrauma. 2013;30(8):642-652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharr JR, Lough NL, Terencio MA. Health and sociodemographic differences between individual and team sport participants. Sports. 2019;7(6):150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans MB, Eys MA, Bruner MW. Seeing the &#x201c;we&#x201d; in &#x201c;me&#x201d; sports: the need to consider individual sport team environments. Can Psychol. 2012;53(4):301-308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans B, Eys M, Wolf S. Exploring the nature of interpersonal influence in elite individual sport teams. J Appl Sport Psychol. 2013;25(4):448-462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson M, Hague C, Evans MB, Martin LJ. Do participant reporting practices in youth sport research adequately represent the diversity of sport contexts? Psychol Sport Exerc. 2019;45:101559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)&#x2014;a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42(2):377-381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, et al. The REDCap consortium: Building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform. 2019;95:103208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayers LB, Redick TS. Clinical utility of ImPACT assessment for postconcussion return-to-play counseling: psychometric issues. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol. 2012;34(3):235-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echemendia RJ, Meeuwisse W, McCrory P, et al. The Sport Concussion Assessment Tool 5th Edition (SCAT5): background and rationale. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):848-850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos AP, Elbin RJ, Schatz P, et al. A revised factor structure for the post-concussion symptom scale: baseline and postconcussion factors. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(10):2375-2384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merritt VC, Meyer JE, Arnett PA. A novel approach to classifying postconcussion symptoms: the application of a new framework to the Post-Concussion Symptom Scale. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol. 2015;37(7):764-775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawid MY, Williams KL, Jo J, et al. Acute psychological symptom profiles in high school football players following sport-related concussion. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2024;33(2):118-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang AR, Davis PJ, Williams KL, et al. Use of acute cognitive symptom cluster to predict return-to-learn duration following a sport-related concussion. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2022;30(4):378-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams K, Zeoli T, Allen JH, et al. Risk of two sport-related concussions in the same year: is the second concussion worse? Clin J Sport Med. 2024;34(1):38-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishay AE, Williams KL, Jo J, Fitch S, Terry DP, Zuckerman SL. Does recovery after sport-related concussion vary by time point in a season? A multi-sport investigation. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2024;33(3):268-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo J, Williams KL, Hill TM, et al. Return-to-learn after sport-related concussion: does school level matter? J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2023;32(2):125-132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bursac Z, Gauss CH, Williams DK, Hosmer DW. Purposeful selection of variables in logistic regression. Source Code Biol Med. 2008;3(1):17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedard C, Hanna S, Cairney J. A longitudinal study of sport participation and perceived social competence in youth. J Adolesc Health. 2020;66(3):352-359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eime RM, Young JA, Harvey JT, Charity MJ, Payne WR. A systematic review of the psychological and social benefits of participation in sport for children and adolescents: informing development of a conceptual model of health through sport. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Activity. 2013;10(1):98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabiston CM, Jewett R, Ashdown-Franks G, et al. Number of years of team and individual sport participation during adolescence and depressive symptoms in early adulthood. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2016;38(1):105-110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nixdorf I, Frank R, Beckmann J. Comparison of athletes' proneness to depressive symptoms in individual and team sports: research on psychological mediators in junior elite athletes. Front Psychol. 2016;7:893.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>