<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37398966</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A post-exercise infrared sauna session improves recovery of neuromuscular performance and muscle soreness after resistance exercise training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>681</StartPage><EndPage>689</EndPage><MedlinePgn>681-689</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2023.119289</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this study was to investigate effects of a single infrared sauna (IRS) session on post-exercise recovery of neuromuscular performance, autonomic nervous system function, subjective sleep quality, and muscle soreness. Male basketball players (n = 16) performed two trials consisting of a complex resistance exercise protocol (maximal strength with plyometrics), followed by either 20 min passive recovery (PAS) or IRS (temperature 43 &#xb1; 5&#xb0;C), in a randomized crossover design, with trials separated by one week. Recovery of neuromuscular performance was assessed using 20 m maximal sprint, maximal countermovement-jump (CMJ), and isometric leg press tests, performed 14 hours after exercise. Heart rate (HR), heart rate variability (HRV), sleep diary, muscle soreness, and indirect muscle damage markers were measured pre and post exercise. The decrease in CMJ performance from pre- to post-exercise was attenuated after IRS compared to PAS (p &lt; 0.01). The IRS session resulted in higher HR and lower root mean square of successive differences between normal heartbeats (RMSSD), and high and low frequency power, compared to PAS (p &lt; 0.002). Post-exercise night-time HR and HRV did not differ following IRS vs. PAS. Muscle soreness was less severe, and perceived recovery was higher after IRS compared to PAS (p &lt; 0.01). Post-exercise IRS attenuated the drop in explosive performance and decreased subjective muscle soreness after resistance training, which may enhance mood, readiness, and physical performance of an athlete. A single IRS session had no detrimental effects on recovery of the autonomic nervous system.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahokas</LastName><ForeName>Essi K</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Research Center, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ihalainen</LastName><ForeName>Johanna K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Research Center, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanstock</LastName><ForeName>Helen G</ForeName><Initials>HG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Swedish Winter Sports Research Centre, Department of Health Sciences, Mid Sweden University, &#xd6;stersund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Savolainen</LastName><ForeName>Eero</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Research Center, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen</LastName><ForeName>Heikki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Research Center, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infrared radiation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery methods</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sauna</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10286597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.119289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">119289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vatansever F, Hamblin MR. Far infrared radiation (FIR): Its biological effects and medical applications. Photonics Lasers Med. 2012; 1(4):255&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3699878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23833705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beever R. Clinical Review Far-infrared saunas for treatment of cardiovascular risk factors Summary of published evidence. Can Fam Physician. 2009; 55:691&#x2013;696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19602651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero A, Tornberg J, M&#xe4;ntykoski M, Puurtinen R. Effects of far-infrared sauna bathing on recovery from strength and endurance training sessions in men. SpringerPlus. 2015; 4(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4493260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26180741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Louis J, Bieuzen F, Pournot H, Fournier J, Filliard J-R, Brisswalter J. Effects of Whole-Body Cryotherapy vs. Far-Infrared vs. Passive Modalities on Recovery from Exercise-Induced Muscle Damage in Highly-Trained Runners. PloS One. 2011; 6(12):e27749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3233540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22163272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng-De Lin, Chien-Chung Huang, Ching-Hung Chen, Tak-Wah Wong, Ming-Shing Young. Far-infrared rays penetrate deeper into mammary tissue and induce a higher skin blood flow in comparison to infrared irradiation. In: The Second Asian and Pacific Rim Symposium on Biophotonics. 2004. p. 107&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nopanen PVA, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Mero AA. Effects of Far Infrared Heat on Recovery in Power Athletes. J Athl Enhanc. 2015; 4(4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Li S, Zhang Y, Chen Y, Yan F, Han L, Ma Y. Heat and cold therapy reduce pain in patients with delayed onset muscle soreness: A systematic review and meta-analysis of 32 randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther Sport. 2021; 48:177&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33493991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hautala A, Tulppo MP, M&#xe4;kikallio TH, Laukkanen R, Nissil&#xe4; S, Huikuri HV. Changes in cardiac autonomic regulation after prolonged maximal exercise. Clin Physiol. 2001; 21(2):238&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11318832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James DVB, Barnes AJ, Lopes P, Wood DM. Heart rate variability: Response following a single bout of interval training. Int J Sports Med. 2002; 23(4):247&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12015624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marciniak RA, Wahl CA, Ebersole KT. Autonomic Nervous System Response to Far-Infrared Sauna Exposure in Firefighters. Ann Work Expo Health. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda A, Koga Y, Hattanmaru M, Minagoe S, Tei C. The Effects of Repeated Thermal Therapy for Patients with Chronic Pain. Psychother Psychosom. 2005; 74(5):288&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16088266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelec M, McCall A, Carling C, Legall F, Berthoin S, Dupont G. Recovery in Soccer. Sports Med Auckl. 2012; 42(12):997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23046224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioakimidis P, Gerodimos V, Kellis E, Alexandris N, Kellis S. Combined effects of age and maturation on maximum isometric leg press strength in young basketball players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2004; 44(4):389&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15758851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogd&#xe1;ny T, Szemerszky R, K&#xf6;teles F. Validation of the Firstbeat TeamBelt and BodyGuard2 systems. Magyar Sporttudom&#xe1;nyi Szemle. 2016; 17:5&#x2013;12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarvainen MP, Niskanen J-P, Lipponen JA, Ranta-aho PO, Karjalainen PA. Kubios HRV &#x2013; Heart rate variability analysis software. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2014; 113(1):210&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24054542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DC, Thorner MO, Fisher RA, Woodman JP, Goble HL, Besser EM. Effects of hormonal treatment on plasma unbound androgen levels in hirsute women. Acta Endocrinol. 1975; 199(0):224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dill DB, Costill DL. Calculation of percentage changes in volumes of blood, plasma, and red cells in dehydration. J Appl Physiol. 1974; 37(2):247&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4850854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rissanen J, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Laukkanen J, Kraemer W, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute Neuromuscular and Hormonal Responses to Different Exercise Loadings Followed by a Sauna. J Strength Cond Res. 2020; 34(2):313&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31490429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skorski S, Schimpchen J, Pfeiffer M, Ferrauti A, Kellmann M, Meyer T. Effects of postexercise sauna bathing on recovery of swim performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020; 15(7):934&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31869820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahmane R, Djordjevi&#x10d; S, &#x160;imuni&#x10d; B, Valen&#x10d;i&#x10d; V. Spatial fiber type distribution in normal human muscle: Histochemical and tensiomyographical evaluation. J Biomech. 2005; 38(12):2451&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16214493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Gissane C, Van Someren K, Gregson W, Howatson G. Cold water immersion and recovery from strenuous exercise: a meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2012; 46(4):233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira A, Siqueira AF, Ferreira-Junior JB, do Carmo J, Durigan JLQ, Blazevich A, Bottaro M. The Effect of Water Temperature during Cold-Water Immersion on Recovery from Exercise-Induced Muscle Damage. Int J Sports Med. 2016; 37(12):937&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27557407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delecluse C. Influence of strength training on sprint running performance Current findings and implications for training. Sports Med Auckl. 1997; 24(3):147&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9327528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, Maresh CM, VanHeest JL, Sharman MJ, Rubin MR, French DN, Vescovi JD, Silvestre R, Hatfield DL, Fleck SJ, Deschenes MR. Androgen receptor content following heavy resistance exercise in men. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2005; 93(1):35&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15748830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingren JL, Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, Anderson JM, Volek JS, Maresh CM. Testosterone Physiology in Resistance Exercise and Training: The Up-Stream Regulatory Elements. Sports Med. 2010; 40(12):1037&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21058750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatfield DL, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, Nindl BC, Caldwell LK, Vingren JL, Newton RU, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Lee EC, Maresh CM, Hymer WC. Hormonal stress responses of growth hormone and insulin-like growth factor-I in highly resistance trained women and men. Growth Horm IGF Res. 2021; 59:101407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34118743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes RFH, Dittrich N, Duffield R, Serpa MC, Coelho TM, Martins DF, Guglielmo LGA. Effects of Far-Infrared Emitting Ceramic Material Clothing on Recovery after Maximal Eccentric Exercise. J Hum Kinet. 2019; 70(1):135&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6942487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31915483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinke F, Bakenecker P, Hahn D. Influence of platinum harmonized textile on neuromuscular, systemic and subjective recovery. PLoS One. 2017; 12(10):e0186162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5638408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29023563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins T, Greene D, Baker M. Effects of Cold Water Immersion and Contrast Water Therapy for Recovery From Team Sport: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017; 31(5):1443&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27398915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>