<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35859645</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Sleep-Related Symptoms on Recovery From a Sport-Related Concussion.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671221105256</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671221105256</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671221105256</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671221105256</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sleep issues are commonly reported in athletes after a sport-related concussion (SRC). Further studies are needed to evaluate screening methods for sleep disturbances and the risk of persisting symptoms after an SRC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate the association between the Sport Concussion Assessment Tool 5 (SCAT5) symptoms of trouble falling asleep, fatigue (or low energy), and drowsiness and the risk of persisting symptoms (&#x2265;28 days to recovery) in adolescent athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cohort study; Level of evidence, 3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 519 athletes aged 13 to 18 years reported any sleep-related symptoms with an SRC, scored as none (0), mild (1-2), moderate (3-4), or severe (5-6), at their initial office visit (median, 5.4 days after an SRC). Scores were correlated with the risk of persisting symptoms. A composite "sleep cluster" score (range, 0-18) was calculated by summing the SCAT5 component items for trouble falling asleep, fatigue, and drowsiness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results indicated that, compared with athletes who reported that they did not have each symptom, (1) athletes who reported mild, moderate, or severe trouble falling asleep were 3.0, 4.6, and 6.7 times more likely to have persisting symptoms, respectively; (2) athletes reporting mild, moderate, or severe fatigue (or low energy) were 2.6, 4.8, and 7.6 times more likely to have persisting symptoms, respectively; and (3) athletes reporting mild, moderate, or severe drowsiness were 1.9, 4.6, and 6.8 times more likely to have persisting symptoms, respectively (<i>P</i> &lt; .001 for all). For every 1-point increase in the sleep cluster score, there was a 1.2-fold increased risk of persisting symptoms and an additional 2.4 days of recovery required (<i>P</i> &lt; .001 for both).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Athletes who reported mild, moderate, or severe sleep-related symptoms on the SCAT5 were at a proportionally increased risk of persisting symptoms at the initial office visit.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DuPrey</LastName><ForeName>Kevin M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Crozer Health, Springfield, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Char</LastName><ForeName>Amber S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Crozer Health, Springfield, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loose</LastName><ForeName>Sean R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Crozer Health, Springfield, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suffredini</LastName><ForeName>Michael V</ForeName><Initials>MV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Crozer Health, Springfield, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walpole</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Crozer Health, Springfield, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cronholm</LastName><ForeName>Peter F</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Community Health, Center for Public Health Initiatives, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leonard Davis Institute of Health Economics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical assessment/grading scales</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">head injuries/concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric sports medicine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: K.M.D. has received consulting fees from HydroCision. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35859645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9290123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671221105256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671221105256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baldwin GT, Breiding MJ, Comstock RD. Epidemiology of sports concussion in the United States. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;158:63&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake AL, McVicar CL, Retino M, Hall EE, Ketcham CJ. Concussion history influences sleep disturbances, symptoms, and quality of life in collegiate student-athletes. Sleep Health. 2019;5(1):72&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramley H, Henson A, Lewis MM, Kong L, Stetter C, Silvis M. Sleep disturbance following concussion is a risk factor for a prolonged recovery. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 2017;56(14):1280&#x2013;1285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramley H, Hong J, Zacko C, Royer C, Silvis M. Mild traumatic brain injury and post-concussion syndrome: treatment and related sequela for persistent symptomatic disease. Sports Med Arthrosc Rev. 2016;24(3):123&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27482778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryan MA, Rowhani-Rahbar A, Comstock RD, Rivara F; Seattle Sports Concussion Research Collaborative. Sports- and recreation-related concussions in US youth. Pediatrics. 2016;138(1):e20154635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27325635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung JS, Zynda AJ, Didehbani N, et al. Association between sleep quality and recovery following sport-related concussion in pediatrics. J Child Neurol. 2019;34(11):639&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31113274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corwin DJ, Zonfrillo MR, Master CL, et al. Characteristics of prolonged concussion recovery in a pediatric subspecialty referral population. J Pediatr. 2014;165(6):1207&#x2013;1215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4253594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25262302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuPrey KM, Webner D, Lyons A, Kucuk CH, Ellis JT, Cronholm PF. Convergence insufficiency identifies athletes at risk of prolonged recovery from sport-related concussion. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(10):2388&#x2013;2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echemendia RJ, Meeuwisse W, McCrory P, et al. The Sport Concussion Assessment Tool 5th edition (SCAT5): background and rationale. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):848&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg MA, Andrea J, Meehan W, Mannix R. Time interval between concussions and symptom duration. Pediatrics. 2013;132(1):8&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23753087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guty E, Arnett P. Post-concussion symptom factors and neuropsychological outcomes in collegiate athletes. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2018;24(7):684&#x2013;692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29925450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon KG, Drezner JA, Gammons M, et al. American Medical Society for Sports Medicine position statement: concussion in sport. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(1):15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman NL, Weber ML, Broglio SP, et al. Influence of postconcussion sleep duration on concussion recovery in collegiate athletes. Clin J Sport Med. 2020;30( suppl 1):S29&#x2013;S35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32132474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL, Gardner AJ, Terry DP, et al. Predictors of clinical recovery from concussion: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(12):941&#x2013;948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28566342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacotte-Simancas A, Fucich EA, Stielper ZF, Molina PE. Traumatic brain injury and the misuse of alcohol, opioids, and cannabis. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2021;157:195&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33648670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos AP, Jorgensen-Wagers K, Trbovich AM, et al. Association of time since injury to the first clinic visit with recovery following concussion. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(4):435&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6990755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31904763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostyun RO, Milewski MD, Hafeez I. Sleep disturbance and neurocognitive function during the recovery from a sport-related concussion in adolescents. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(3):633&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25520301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langdon S, K&#xf6;nigs M, Adang EAMC, Goedhart E, Oosterlaan J. Subtypes of sport-related concussion: a systematic review and meta-cluster analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(10):1829&#x2013;1842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32720230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langlois JA, Rutland-Brown W, Wald MM. The epidemiology and impact of traumatic brain injury: a brief overview. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2006;21(5):375&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16983222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig R, D&#x2019;Silva L, Vaduvathiriyan P, Rippee MA, Siengsukon C. Sleep disturbances in the acute stage of concussion are associated with poorer long-term recovery: a systematic review. PM R. 2020;12(5):500&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31876086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvo&#x159;&#xe1;k J, et al. Consensus Statement on Concussion in Sport: the 5th International Conference on Concussion in Sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):838&#x2013;847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse AM, Kothare SV. Sleep disorders and concussion. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;158:127&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdaugh DL, Ono KE, Reisner A, Burns TG. Assessment of sleep quantity and sleep disturbances during recovery from sports-related concussion in youth athletes. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;99(5):960&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29425698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyegbile TO, Dougherty A, Tanveer S, Zecavati N, Delasobera BE. High sleep disturbance and longer concussion duration in repeat concussions. Behav Sleep Med. 2020;18(2):241&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30784317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paniccia M, Verweel L, Thomas SG, et al. Heart rate variability following youth concussion: how do autonomic regulation and concussion symptoms differ over time postinjury? BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2018;4(1):e000355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6173244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30305921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raikes AC, Schaefer SY. Sleep quantity and quality during acute concussion: a pilot study. Sleep. 2016;39(12):2141&#x2013;2147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5103802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27748242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Root JM, Zuckerbraun NS, Wang L, et al. History of somatization is associated with prolonged recovery from concussion. J Pediatr. 2016;174:39&#x2013;44.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4925238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27059916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosner B. Fundamentals of Biostatistics. 7th ed. Boston: Brooks/Cole; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandsmark DK, Elliott JE, Lim MM. Sleep-wake disturbances after traumatic brain injury: synthesis of human and animal studies. Sleep. 2017;40(5):zsx044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6251652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28329120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone S, Lee B, Garrison JC, Blueitt D, Creed K. Sex differences in time to return-to-play progression after sport-related concussion. Sports Health. 2017;9(1):41&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5315255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27697890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theadom A, Cropley M, Parmar P, et al. Sleep difficulties one year following mild traumatic brain injury in a population-based study. Sleep Med. 2015;16(8):926&#x2013;932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26138280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas RE, Alves J, Vaska MM, Magalh&#xe3;es R. SCAT2 and SCAT3 scores at baseline and after sports-related mild brain injury/concussion: qualitative synthesis with weighted means. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2016;2(1):e000095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5125422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27900167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>