<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28874926</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1933-6586</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical acupuncture</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Acupunct</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>CranioSacral Therapy and Visceral Manipulation: A New Treatment Intervention for Concussion Recovery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>239</StartPage><EndPage>248</EndPage><MedlinePgn>239-248</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1089/acu.2017.1222</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background:</b> Military service members and veterans face health issues related to traumatic brain injury (TBI), especially during combat, use of heavy equipment, and exposures to environmental hazards and explosives. There were 400,000 TBIs reported in deployed U.S. troops in 2012. Athletes are also subject to TBI. Studies have indicated that some manual therapies could be helpful for treating patients who have post-concussive syndrome. <b>Objective:</b> This case series report describes the effects of CranioSacral Therapy (CST), Visceral Manipulation (VM), and Neural Manipulation (NM) modalities for treating patients who have post-concussion syndrome. The goal of this study was to evaluate these effects on immobility, pain intensity, quality of life, sleep disorders, and cognition in these patients. <b>Materials and Methods:</b> This single-blinded case series was conducted at the Upledger Institute, in West Palm Beach, FL. The patients were 11 male retired professional football players from the National Football League and the Canadian Football League who had been medically diagnosed with post-concussion syndrome. Each participant received a morning and afternoon 2-hour session of these three specific manual therapies, which were capable of accessing and addressing the structural, vascular, and neurologic tissues of the cranium and brain-as well addressing far-reaching ramifications throughout the body following trauma. The main outcome measures were scores on the: Impact Neurocognitive Test; Dynavision<sup>tm</sup> Test; Short Form-36 Quality of Life Survey, Headache Impact Test, Dizziness Handicap Inventory; a numeric pain rating scale; orthopedic range of motion tests (ROM); and vestibular testing. Hours of sleep were also checked. These outcome measures were registered at baseline, after treatment, and after a 3-month follow up. <b>Results:</b> Statistically significant differences were seen with a decrease in overall pain rating scale scores (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0448), and cervicogenic pain levels decreased (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0486). There were statistically significant increases in Dynavision Average Reaction Time (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0332), Memory Test (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0156) scores, and cervical ROM scores (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0377). Hours of sleep averaged 2 hours on the first day of treatment and increased to 4.0 hours at the end of treatment and were continuing to increase, as noted at a 3-month evaluation. <b>Conclusions:</b> Ten sessions of specific CST/VM/NM therapy resulted in statistically greater improvements in pain intensity, ROM, memory, cognition, and sleep in concussed patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wetzler</LastName><ForeName>Gail</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research, Barral Institute, West Palm Beach, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wetzler Integrative Physical Therapy, Denver, CO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roland</LastName><ForeName>Melinda</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research, Upledger Institute, West Palm Beach, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integral Therapies, San Diego, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fryer-Dietz</LastName><ForeName>Sally</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research, Upledger Institute, West Palm Beach, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Concussion Therapy, Dallas, TX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dettmann-Ahern</LastName><ForeName>Dee</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research, Barral Institute, West Palm Beach, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dee Ahern Physical Therapy, Stuart, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Acupunct</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100899009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1933-6586</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CranioSacral Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Manipulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Visceral Manipulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">traumatic brain injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No financial conflicts exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28874926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5580370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/acu.2017.1222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1089/acu.2017.1222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>MedlinePlus. Traumatic Brain Injury. Online document at: www.medlineplus.gov/traumaticbraininjury.html Accessed February6, 2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snell FI, Halter MJ. A signature wound of war: Mild traumatic brain injury. J Psychosoc Nurs Ment Health Serv. 2010;48(2):22&#x2013;28</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20166653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallakuri S, Desai A, Feng K, et al. Neuronal injury and glial changes are hallmarks of open field blast exposure in swine frontal lobe. PLoS One. 2017;12(1):e0169239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5249202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28107370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL. Chronic traumatic encephalopathy and risk of suicide in former athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(2):162&#x2013;165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24178363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webner D, Iverson GL. Suicide in professional American football players in the past 95 years. Brain Inj. 2016;30(13&#x2013;14):1718&#x2013;1721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27996330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amen D, Newberg A, Thatcher R, Jim Y, Wu J, Keator D, Willeumier K. Impact of playing American professional football on long-term brain function. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2011;23(1):98&#x2013;106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21304145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giza C, Kutcher J, Ashwal S, et al. Summary of evidence-based guideline update: Evaluation and management of concussion in sports. Report of the Guideline Development Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2013;80(24):2250&#x2013;2257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23508730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries E.
Beyond Rest: Physical Therapists and Concussion Management. PT in Motion, March
2017:22&#x2013;27. Online document at: www.apta.org/PTinMotion/2017/3/Feature/BeyondRest/ Accessed June5, 2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upledger JE, Vredevoogd J. Introduction to the CranioSacral concept. In: CranioSacral Therapy. Seattle, WA: Eastland Press; 1983:5&#x2013;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanveer T.
Introduction and a few key words. In: Brain Stars, <i>1st</i>
<i>ed</i>
West Palm Beach, FL: Upledger Productions; 2015:1&#x2013;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedergaard M, Rodriguiz J, Verkhratsky A. Glial calcium and diseases of the nervous system. Cell Calcium. 2010;47(2):140&#x2013;149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20045186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barral JP, Mercier P. Basic Concepts. In: Visceral Manipulation. Seattle: Eastland Press; 1988:1&#x2013;20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barral JP, Croibier A.
Some preliminary thoughts. In: Manual Therapy for the Cranial Nerves, <i>1st</i>
<i>ed</i>
London: Churchill Livingstone; 2008:1&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse WH, Aubry M, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport: The 4th International Conference on Concussion in Sport held in Zurich, November 2012. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(5):250&#x2013;258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23479479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grady MF, Master CL, Gioia GA. Concussion pathophysiology: Rationale for physical and cognitive rest. Pediatr Ann. 2012;41(9):377&#x2013;382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22953984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z, Iliff J, Yang L, et al. &#x201c;Hit &amp; Run&#x201d; model of closed-skull traumatic brain injury (TBI) reveals complex pattern of post-traumatic AQP4 dysregulation. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2013;33(6):834&#x2013;845</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3677112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23443171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro-Sanchez AM, Mataran-Penarrocha GA, Sanchez-Labraca N, et al. A randomized controlled trial investigating the effects of CranioSacral therapy on pain and heart rate variability in fibromyalgia patients. Clin Rehabil. 2011;25(1):25&#x2013;35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood SD. The craniosacral mechanism and the temporomandibular joint. J Am Osteopath Assoc. 1986;86(8):512&#x2013;519</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3759521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnadottir TS, Sigurdardottir AK. Is CranioSacral therapy effective for migraine? Tested with HIT-6 Questionnaire. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2013;19(1):11&#x2013;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23337558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nourbakhsh MR, Fearon FJ. The effect of oscillating-energy manual therapy on lateral epicondylitis: A randomized, placebo-control, double-blinded study. J Hand Ther. 2008;21(1):4&#x2013;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18215746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerdner LA, Hart LK, Zimmerman MB. Craniosacral still point technique: Exploring its effects in individuals with dementia. J Gerontol Nurs. 2008;34(3):36&#x2013;45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18350746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raviv G, Shefi S, Nizani D, Achiron A. Effect of CranioSacral therapy on lower urinary tract signs and symptoms in multiple sclerosis. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2009;15(2):72&#x2013;75</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19341983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro-Sanchez AM, Lara-Palomo IC, Mataran-Penarrocha GA, Saavedra-Hernandez M, Perez-Marmol JM, Aguilar-Ferrandiz ME. Benefits of CranioSacral therapy in patients with chronic low back pain: A randomized controlled trial. J Altern Complement Med. 2016;22(8):650&#x2013;657</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller H, Lauche R, Cramer H, et al. CranioSacral therapy for the treatment of chronic neck pain: A randomized sham-controlled trial. Clin J Pain. 2016;32(5):441&#x2013;449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4894825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26340656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Kolk B. Body-Brain Connections. In: The Body Keeps the Score: Brain, Mind, and Body in the Healing of Trauma. New York: Penguin Books; 2014:62&#x2013;64</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse WH, Johnston K, et al. Consensus Statement on Concussion in Sport: The 3rd International Conference on Concussion in Sport Held in Zurich, November 2008. J Athl Train. 2009;44(4):434&#x2013;448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19593427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>