<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34145161</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-509X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2022 May-Jun 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of head trauma rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Head Trauma Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Should We Lose Sleep Over Sleep Disturbances After Sports-Related Concussion? A Scoping Review of the Literature.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>E206</StartPage><EndPage>E219</EndPage><MedlinePgn>E206-E219</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HTR.0000000000000701</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">A single, severe traumatic brain injury can result in chronic sleep disturbances that can persist several years after the incident. In contrast, it is unclear whether there are sleep disturbances after a sports-related concussion (SRC). Considering growing evidence of links between sleep disturbance and neurodegeneration, this review examined the potential links between diagnosed SRCs and sleep disturbances to provide guidance for future studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The scoping review undertook a systematic search of key online databases (Scopus, MEDLINE, SportDiscus, and Web of Science) using predetermined search terms for any articles that examined sleep after concussion. A screening criterion using agreed inclusion and exclusion criteria was utilized to ensure inclusion of relevant articles.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">This scoping review is guided by the PRSIMA Scoping Review report.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Ten studies met the inclusion criteria, reporting on 896 adults who had experienced an SRC. Comparison with 1327 non-SRC adults occurred in 8 studies. Nine studies subjectively examined sleep, of which all but one study reported sleep disturbances after an SRC. Three studies objectively measured sleep, with 2 studies indicating large coefficients of variation of sleep duration, suggesting a range of sleep responses after an SRC. The only study to examine overnight polysomnography showed no differences in sleep metrics between those with and without an SRC. No studies examined interventions to improve sleep outcomes in people with concussion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This scoping review indicates preliminary evidence of sleep disturbances following an SRC. The heterogeneity of methodology used in the included studies makes consensus on the results difficult. Given the mediating role of sleep in neurodegenerative disorders, further research is needed to identify physiological correlates and pathological mechanisms of sleep disturbances in SRC-related neurodegeneration and whether interventions for sleep problems improve recovery from concussion and reduce the risk of SRC-related neurodegeneration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stevens</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adelaide Institute for Sleep Health, College of Medicine and Public Health, Flinders University, Bedford Park, South Australia, Australia (Drs Stevens, Appleton, Prof Adams and Ms Bickley); Centre for Nutrition and Gastrointestinal Diseases, South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia (Dr Stevens); School of Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Jordan, Amman, Jordan (Prof Alghwiri); School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia (Dr Rogers); Department of Neurosurgery, Northshore University Health System, Evanston, Illinois (Dr Plummer); Translational Neuropathology Laboratory, Adelaide Medical School, The University of Adelaide, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia (Dr Plummer); Section Sports Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Pretoria, Pretoria, South Africa (Drs Grant and Holtzhausen); Department of Psychiatry, Alfred Health, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia (Dr Alvaro); Wakefield Sports and Exercise Medicine Clinic, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia (Dr Kennett); Respiratory and Sleep Service, Southern Adelaide Local Health Network, Bedford Park, South Australia, Australia (Prof Adams); and Sports Medicine Department, Aspetar Orthopaedic and Sports Medicine Hospital, Doha, Qatar (Dr Holtzhausen).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alghwiri</LastName><ForeName>Alia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Appleton</LastName><ForeName>Sarah L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rogers</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plummer</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grant</LastName><ForeName>Catharina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bickley</LastName><ForeName>Kelsey</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alvaro</LastName><ForeName>Pasquale K</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kennett</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adams</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holtzhausen</LastName><ForeName>Louis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Head Trauma Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8702552</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-9701</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Concussion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012893" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Wake Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34145161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HTR.0000000000000701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001199-202205000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse WH, Echemendia RJ, Iverson GL, Dvo&#x159;&#xe1;k J, Kutcher JS. What is the lowest threshold to make a diagnosis of concussion? Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(5):268&#x2013;271. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2013-092247</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshvar DH, Nowinski CJ, McKee AC, Cantu RC. The epidemiology of sport-related concussion. Clin Sports Med. 2011;30(1):1&#x2013;17, vii. doi:10.1016/j.csm.2010.08.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruhe A, G&#xe4;nsslen A, Klein W. The incidence of concussion in professional and collegiate ice hockey: are we making progress? A systematic review of the literature. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(2):102&#x2013;106. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2012-091609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casson IR, Viano DC, Powell JW, Pellman EJ. Twelve years of national football league concussion data. Sports Health. 2010;2(6):471&#x2013;483. doi:10.1177/1941738110383963</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savage J, Hooke C, Orchard J, Parkinson R. The incidence of concussion in a professional Australian Rugby League team, 1998-2012. J Sports Med (Hindawi Publ Corp). 2013;2013:304576. doi:10.1155/2013/304576</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafferty J, Ranson C, Oatley G, et al. On average, a professional rugby union player is more likely than not to sustain a concussion after 25 matches. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(15):969&#x2013;973. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2017-098417</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Collegiate Athletic Association. Self-Reported Concussion Among NCAA Student-Athletes [press release]. National Collegiate Athletic Association; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Pelt KL, Allred D, Cameron KL, et al. A cohort study to identify and evaluate concussion risk factors across multiple injury settings: findings from the CARE Consortium. Inj Epidemiol. 2019;6(1):1. doi:10.1186/s40621-018-0178-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asken BM, McCrea MA, Clugston JR, Snyder AR, Houck ZM, Bauer RM. &#x201c;Playing Through It&#x201d;: delayed reporting and removal from athletic activity after concussion predicts prolonged recovery. J Athl Train. 2016;51(4):329&#x2013;335. doi:10.4085/1062-6050-51.5.02</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meaney DF, Smith DH. Biomechanics of concussion. Clin Sports Med. 2011;30(1):19&#x2013;31, vii. doi:10.1016/j.csm.2010.08.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigler ED, Maxwell WL. Neuropathology of mild traumatic brain injury: relationship to neuroimaging findings. Brain Imaging Behav. 2012;6(2):108&#x2013;136. doi:10.1007/s11682-011-9145-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dettwiler A, Murugavel M, Putukian M, Cubon V, Furtado J, Osherson D. Persistent differences in patterns of brain activation after sports-related concussion: a longitudinal functional magnetic resonance imaging study. J Neurotrauma. 2014;31(2):180&#x2013;188. doi:10.1089/neu.2013.2983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon KG, Clugston JR, Dec K, et al. American Medical Society for Sports Medicine position statement on concussion in sport. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(4):213&#x2013;225. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2018-100338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choe MC, Giza CC. Diagnosis and management of acute concussion. Semin Neurol. 2015;35(1):29&#x2013;41. doi:10.1055/s-0035-1544243</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavett BE, Stern RA, McKee AC. Chronic traumatic encephalopathy: a potential late effect of sport-related concussive and subconcussive head trauma. Clin Sports Med. 2011;30(1):179&#x2013;188, xi. doi:10.1016/j.csm.2010.09.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKee AC, Stein TD, Nowinski CJ, et al. The spectrum of disease in chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Brain. 2013;136(pt 1):43&#x2013;64. doi:10.1093/brain/aws307</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein TD, Montenigro PH, Alvarez VE, et al. Beta-amyloid deposition in chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Acta Neuropathol. 2015;130(1):21&#x2013;34. doi:10.1007/s00401-015-1435-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson A. Concussion, dementia and CTE: are we getting it very wrong? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(6):462&#x2013;464. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2016-315510</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holth JK, Fritschi SK, Wang C, et al. The sleep-wake cycle regulates brain interstitial fluid tau in mice and CSF tau in humans. Science. 2019;363(6429):880&#x2013;884. doi:10.1126/science.aav2546</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtzman DM. Effects of disrupted sleep on abeta and tau pathology and effects of abeta and tau pathology on sleep: a vicious cycle? Alzheimers Dement. 2015;11(7):P165&#x2013;P166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju YS, Ooms SJ, Sutphen C, et al. Slow wave sleep disruption increases cerebrospinal fluid amyloid-&#x3b2; levels. Brain. 2017;140(8):2104&#x2013;2111. doi:10.1093/brain/awx148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott SM, Videnovic A. Chronic sleep disturbance and neural injury: links to neurodegenerative disease. Nat Sci Sleep. 2016;8:55&#x2013;61. doi:10.2147/NSS.S78947</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamim SA, Warriach ZI, Tariq MA, Rana KF, Malik BH. Insomnia: risk factor for neurodegenerative diseases. Cureus. 2019;11(10):e6004. doi:10.7759/cureus.6004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen JE, Veasey SC. Impact of sleep disturbances on neurodegeneration: insight from studies in animal models. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;139:104820. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2020.104820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lajoie AC, Lafontaine AL, Kimoff RJ, Kaminska M. Obstructive sleep apnea in neurodegenerative disorders: current evidence in support of benefit from sleep apnea treatment. J Clin Med. 2020;9(2):297. doi:10.3390/jcm9020297</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuzu&#xe1;rregui JRP, Bickart K, Kutscher SJ. A review of sleep disturbances following traumatic brain injury. Sleep Sci Pract. 2018;2(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gioia GA, Collins M, Isquith PK. Improving identification and diagnosis of mild traumatic brain injury with evidence: psychometric support for the acute concussion evaluation. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2008;23(4):230&#x2013;242. doi:10.1097/01.HTR.0000327255.38881.ca</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall S, Bayley M, McCullagh S, Velikonja D, Berrigan L. Clinical practice guidelines for mild traumatic brain injury and persistent symptoms. Can Fam Physician. 2012;58(3):257&#x2013;267, e128&#x2013;e140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;473. doi:10.7326/M18-0850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O'Brien KK. Scoping studies: advancing the methodology. Implement Sci. 2010;5:69. doi:10.1186/1748-5908-5-69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun HL, Levac D, O'Brien KK, et al. Scoping reviews: time for clarity in definition, methods, and reporting. J Clin Epidemiol. 2014;67(12):1291&#x2013;1294. doi:10.1016/j.jclinepi.2014.03.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Peters MDJ, Stern C, Tufanaru C, McArthur A, Aromataris E. Systematic review or scoping review? Guidance for authors when choosing between a systematic or scoping review approach. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):143. doi:10.1186/s12874-018-0611-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuula L, Gradisar M, Martinm&#xe4;ki K, et al. Using big data to explore worldwide trends in objective sleep in the transition to adulthood. Sleep Med. 2019;62:69&#x2013;76. doi:10.1016/j.sleep.2019.07.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vela-Bueno A, Fernandez-Mendoza J, Olavarrieta-Bernardino S. Sleep patterns in the transition from adolescence to young adulthood. Sleep Med Clin. 2009;4(1):77&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213. doi:10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvo&#x159;&#xe1;k J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5(th) International Conference on Concussion in Sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):838&#x2013;847. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2017-097699</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino M, Li Y, Rueschman MN, et al. Measuring sleep: accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity of wrist actigraphy compared to polysomnography. Sleep. 2013;36(11):1747&#x2013;1755. doi:10.5665/sleep.3142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake AL, McVicar CL, Retino M, Hall EE, Ketcham CJ. Concussion history influences sleep disturbances, symptoms, and quality of life in collegiate student-athletes. Sleep Health. 2019;5(1):72&#x2013;77. doi:10.1016/j.sleh.2018.10.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchill NW, Hutchison MG, Graham SJ, Schweizer TA. Symptom correlates of cerebral blood flow following acute concussion. Neuroimage Clin. 2017;16:234&#x2013;239. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2017.07.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis-Hayes C, Gossett JD, Levine WN, et al. Sex-specific outcomes and predictors of concussion recovery. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2017;25(12):818&#x2013;828. doi:10.5435/JAAOS-D-17-00276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselin N, Lassonde M, Petit D, et al. Sleep following sport-related concussions. Sleep Med. 2009;10(1):35&#x2013;46. doi:10.1016/j.sleep.2007.11.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouttebarge V, Aoki H, Lambert M, Stewart W, Kerkhoffs G. A history of concussions is associated with symptoms of common mental disorders in former male professional athletes across a range of sports. Phys Sportsmed. 2017;45(4):443&#x2013;449. doi:10.1080/00913847.2017.1376572</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman NL, Weber ML, Broglio SP, et al. Influence of postconcussion sleep duration on concussion recovery in collegiate athletes. Clin J Sport Med. 2020;30(suppl 1):S29&#x2013;S35. doi:10.1097/JSM.0000000000000538</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman NL, O'Connor PJ, Schmidt MD, Lynall RC, Schmidt JD. Differences in sleep between concussed and nonconcussed college students: a matched case-control study. Sleep. 2019;42(2). doi:10.1093/sleep/zsy222</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchison MG, Mainwaring L, Senthinathan A, Churchill N, Thomas S, Richards D. Psychological and physiological markers of stress in concussed athletes across recovery milestones. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2017;32(3):E38&#x2013;E48. doi:10.1097/HTR.0000000000000252</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raikes AC, Schaefer SY. Sleep quantity and quality during acute concussion: a pilot study. Sleep. 2016;39(12):2141&#x2013;2147. doi:10.5665/sleep.6314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vagnozzi R, Signoretti S, Tavazzi B, et al. Temporal window of metabolic brain vulnerability to concussion: a pilot 1 H-magnetic resonance spectroscopic study in concussed athletes&#x2014;part III. Neurosurgery. 2008;62(6):1286&#x2013;1295; discussion 1295&#x2013;1296. doi:10.1227/01.neu.0000333300.34189.74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broglio SP, McCrea M, McAllister T, et al. A national study on the effects of concussion in collegiate athletes and US Military Service Academy members: the NCAA-DoD Concussion Assessment, Research and Education (CARE) Consortium structure and methods. Sports Med. 2017;47(7):1437&#x2013;1451. doi:10.1007/s40279-017-0707-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney N, Ghajar J, Jagoda A, et al. Concussion guidelines step 1: systematic review of prevalent indicators. Neurosurgery. 2014;75(suppl 1):S3&#x2013;S15. doi:10.1227/NEU.0000000000000433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm L, Cassidy JD, Carroll LJ, Borg J; Neurotrauma Task Force on Mild Traumatic Brain Injury of the WHO Collaborating Centre. Summary of the WHO Collaborating Centre for Neurotrauma Task Force on Mild Traumatic Brain Injury. J Rehabil Med. 2005;37(3):137&#x2013;141. doi:10.1080/16501970510027321</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King NS, Crawford S, Wenden FJ, Moss NE, Wade DT. The Rivermead Post Concussion Symptoms Questionnaire: a measure of symptoms commonly experienced after head injury and its reliability. J Neurol. 1995;242(9):587&#x2013;592. doi:10.1007/BF00868811</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain JL, Ahmad P, Reinish LW, Kayumov L, Hossain NK, Shapiro CM. Subjective fatigue and subjective sleepiness: two independent consequences of sleep disorders? J Sleep Res. 2005;14(3):245&#x2013;253. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2869.2005.00466.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessen NA, Munk ASF, Lundgaard I, Nedergaard M. The glymphatic system: a beginner's guide. Neurochem Res. 2015;40(12):2583&#x2013;2599. doi:10.1007/s11064-015-1581-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parcell DL, Ponsford JL, Redman JR, Rajaratnam SM. Poor sleep quality and changes in objectively recorded sleep after traumatic brain injury: a preliminary study. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2008;89(5):843&#x2013;850. doi:10.1016/j.apmr.2007.09.057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiseman-Hakes C, Duclos C, Blais H, et al. Sleep in the acute phase of severe traumatic brain injury: a snapshot of polysomnography. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2016;30(8):713&#x2013;721. doi:10.1177/1545968315619697</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KA, Hicks G, Nino-Murcia G. Validity and reliability of a scale to assess fatigue. Psychiatry Res. 1991;36(3):291&#x2013;298. doi:10.1016/0165-1781(91)90027-m</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makley MJ, Gerber D, Newman JK, et al. Optimized Sleep After Brain Injury (OSABI): a pilot study of a sleep hygiene intervention for individuals with moderate to severe traumatic brain injury. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2020;34(2):111&#x2013;121. doi:10.1177/1545968319895478</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morawska MM, Buchele F, Moreira CG, Imbach LL, Noain D, Baumann CR. Sleep modulation alleviates axonal damage and cognitive decline after rodent traumatic brain injury. J Neurosci. 2016;36(12):3422&#x2013;3429. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3274-15.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff LE, Halson SL, Peiffer JJ. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important competitions. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;18(1):13&#x2013;18. doi:10.1016/j.jsams.2014.02.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekhtiari S, Yusuf I, AlMakadma Y, MacDonald A, Leroux T, Khan M. Opioid use in athletes: a systematic review. Sports Health. 2020;12(6):534&#x2013;539. doi:10.1177/1941738120933542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta L, Morgan K, Gilchrist S. Does elite sport degrade sleep quality? A systematic review. Sports Med. 2017;47(7):1317&#x2013;1333. doi:10.1007/s40279-016-0650-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raikes AC, Athey A, Alfonso-Miller P, Killgore WDS, Grandner MA. Insomnia and daytime sleepiness: risk factors for sports-related concussion. Sleep Med. 2019;58:66&#x2013;74. doi:10.1016/j.sleep.2019.03.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori C, Mercuri NB, Izzi F, et al. Obstructive sleep apnea is associated with early but possibly modifiable Alzheimer's disease biomarkers changes. Sleep. 2017;40(5). doi:10.1093/sleep/zsx011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooms S, Overeem S, Besse K, Rikkert MO, Verbeek M, Claassen JA. Effect of 1 night of total sleep deprivation on cerebrospinal fluid &#x3b2;-amyloid 42 in healthy middle-aged men: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71(8):971&#x2013;977. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.1173</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mander BA, Marks SM, Vogel JW, et al. &#x3b2;-Amyloid disrupts human NREM slow waves and related hippocampus-dependent memory consolidation. Nat Neurosci. 2015;18(7):1051&#x2013;1057. doi:10.1038/nn.4035</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrell TR, Abramson R, Barth JT, et al. Genetic polymorphisms associated with the risk of concussion in 1056 college athletes: a multicentre prospective cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(3):192&#x2013;198. doi:10.1136/bjsports-2016-097419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasilevskaya A, Taghdiri F, Burke C, et al. Interaction of APOE4 alleles and PET tau imaging in former contact sport athletes. Neuroimage Clin. 2020;26:102212. doi:10.1016/j.nicl.2020.102212</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Zhao N, Fu Y, et al. ApoE4 accelerates early seeding of amyloid pathology. Neuron. 2017;96(5):1024&#x2013;1032.e3. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2017.11.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baugh CM, Stamm JM, Riley DO, et al. Chronic traumatic encephalopathy: neurodegeneration following repetitive concussive and subconcussive brain trauma. Brain Imaging Behav. 2012;6(2):244&#x2013;254. doi:10.1007/s11682-012-9164-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CC, Lung FW. The role of PGC-1 and Apo&#x25b;4 in insomnia. Psychiatr Genet. 2012;22(2):82&#x2013;87. doi:10.1097/YPG.0b013e32834dc438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb DJ, DeStefano AL, Foley DJ, et al. APOE epsilon4 is associated with obstructive sleep apnea/hypopnea: the Sleep Heart Health Study. Neurology. 2004;63(4):664&#x2013;668. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000134671.99649.32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drogos LL, Gill SJ, Tyndall AV, et al. Evidence of association between sleep quality and APOE &#x25b;4 in healthy older adults: a pilot study. Neurology. 2016;87(17):1836&#x2013;1842. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000003255</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collie A, Maruff P, Makdissi M, McCrory P, McStephen M, Darby D. CogSport: reliability and correlation with conventional cognitive tests used in postconcussion medical evaluations. Clin J Sport Med. 2003;13(1):28&#x2013;32. doi:10.1097/00042752-200301000-00006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibarra S. Immediate postconcussion assessment and cognitive testing. In: Kreutzer JS, DeLuca J, Caplan B, eds. Encyclopedia of Clinical Neuropsychology. Springer; 2011:1297&#x2013;1299.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>