<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37043600</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute Performance, Daily Well-Being, and Hormone Responses to Water Immersion After Resistance Exercise in Junior International and Subelite Male Volleyball Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1643</StartPage><EndPage>1653</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1643-1653</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004428</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Horgan, BG, Tee, N, West, NP, Drinkwater, EJ, Halson, SL, Colomer, CME, Fonda, CJ, Tatham, J, Chapman, DW, and Haff, GG. Acute performance, daily well-being and hormone responses to water immersion after resistance exercise in junior international and subelite male volleyball athletes. J Strength Cond Res 37(8): 1643-1653, 2023-Athletes use postexercise hydrotherapy strategies to improve recovery and competition performance and to enhance adaptative responses to training. Using a randomized cross-over design, the acute effects of 3 postresistance exercise water immersion strategies on perceived recovery, neuromuscular performance, and hormone concentrations in junior international and subelite male volleyball athletes ( n = 18) were investigated. After resistance exercise, subjects randomly completed either 15-minute passive control (CON), contrast water therapy (CWT), cold (CWI), or hot water immersion (HWI) interventions. A treatment effect occurred after HWI; reducing perceptions of fatigue (HWI &gt; CWT: p = 0.05, g = 0.43); improved sleep quality, compared with CON ( p &lt; 0.001, g = 1.15), CWI ( p = 0.017, g = 0.70), and CWT ( p = 0.018, g = 0.51); as well as increasing testosterone concentration (HWI &gt; CWT: p = 0.038, g = 0.24). There were trivial to small ( p &lt; 0.001-0.039, g = 0.02-0.34) improvements (treatment effect) in jump performance (i.e., squat jump and countermovement jump) after all water immersion strategies, as compared with CON, with high variability in the individual responses. There were no significant differences (interaction effect, p &gt; 0.05) observed between the water immersion intervention strategies and CON in performance ( p = 0.153-0.99), hormone ( p = 0.207-0.938), nor perceptual ( p = 0.368-0.955) measures. To optimize recovery and performance responses, e.g., during an in-season competition phase, postresistance exercise HWI may assist with providing small-to-large improvements for up to 38 hours in perceived recovery (i.e., increased sleep quality and reduced fatigue) and increases in circulating testosterone concentration. Practitioners should consider individual athlete neuromuscular performance responses when prescribing postexercise hydrotherapy. These findings apply to athletes who aim to improve their recovery status, where postresistance exercise HWI optimizes sleep quality and next-day perceptions of fatigue.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horgan</LastName><ForeName>Barry G</ForeName><Initials>BG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6436-8950</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brumbies Rugby, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tee</LastName><ForeName>Nicolin</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1130-9516</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Catholic University, Watson, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>West</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas P</ForeName><Initials>NP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5482-4182</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical Science and Menzies Health Institute QLD, Griffith University, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drinkwater</LastName><ForeName>Eric J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9594-9360</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Research, School of Exercise &amp; Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halson</LastName><ForeName>Shona L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1047-3878</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Catholic University, McAuley at Banyo, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colomer</LastName><ForeName>Carmen M E</ForeName><Initials>CME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fonda</LastName><ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3896-5399</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tatham</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Volleyball Australia, Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chapman</LastName><ForeName>Dale W</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3393-1261</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Australian Institute of Sport, Bruce, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Curtin University, Perth, Western Australia, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haff</LastName><ForeName>G Gregory</ForeName><Initials>GG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0676-7750</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Directorate of Psychology and Sport, University of Salford, Salford, Greater Manchester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XMK78S47O</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013739">Testosterone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054798" MajorTopicYN="Y">Volleyball</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007101" MajorTopicYN="N">Immersion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013739" MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003080" MajorTopicYN="N">Cold Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37043600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202308000-00014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al Haddad H, Parouty J, Buchheit M. Effect of daily cold water immersion on heart rate variability and subjective ratings of well-being in highly trained swimmers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 7: 33&#x2013;38, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argus CK, Broatch JR, Petersen AC, et al. Cold-water immersion and contrast water therapy: No improvement of short-term recovery after resistance training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: 886&#x2013;892, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobba RK, Odem JL, Doll DC, Perry MC. Skin metastases in non-small cell lung cancer. Am J Med Sci 344: 59&#x2013;62, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. The Borg CR10 scale. In: Borg's Perceived Exertion and Pain Scales. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 1998. pp. 39&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broatch JR, Petersen A, Bishop DJ. The influence of post-exercise cold-water immersion on adaptive responses to exercise: A review of the literature. Sports Med 48: 1369&#x2013;1387, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke DH. Effect of immersion in hot and cold water upon recovery of muscular strength following fatiguing isometric exercise. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 44: 565&#x2013;568, 1963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Dos' Santos T, Beckham GK, et al. Standardization and methodological considerations for the isometric midthigh pull. Strength Cond J 41: 57&#x2013;79, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C. The development of skeletal muscle hypertrophy through resistance training: The role of muscle damage and muscle protein synthesis. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 485&#x2013;500, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Freitas VH, Ramos SP, Bara-Filho MG, et al. Effect of cold water immersion performed on successive days on physical performance, muscle damage, and inflammatory, hormonal, and oxidative stress markers in volleyball players. J Strength Cond Res 33: 502&#x2013;513, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Hatfield DL, Sherman A, Lee EC, Kraemer WJ. Cold-water immersion blunts and delays increases in circulating testosterone and cytokines post-resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 1901&#x2013;1907, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, Roberts LA, Markworth JF, et al. Impact of resistance exercise on ribosome biogenesis is acutely regulated by post-exercise recovery strategies. Physiol Rep 4: e12670, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Broatch JR, Trewin AJ, et al. Cold water immersion attenuates anabolic signaling and skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy, but not strength gain, following whole-body resistance training. J Appl Physiol 127: 1403&#x2013;1418, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabrielsen A, Johansen LB, Norsk P. Central cardiovascular pressures during graded water immersion in humans. J Appl Physiol (1985) 75: 581&#x2013;585, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasso D, Lanteri P, Di Bernardo C, et al. Salivary steroid hormone response to whole-body cryotherapy in elite rugby players. J Biol Regul Homeost Agents 28: 291&#x2013;300, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray SR, De Vito G, Nimmo MA, Farina D, Ferguson RA. Skeletal muscle ATP turnover and muscle fiber conduction velocity are elevated at higher muscle temperatures during maximal power output development in humans. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 290: R376&#x2013;R382, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy S, Brady C, Kotani Y, et al. The effect of altering body posture and barbell position on the between-session reliability of force-time curve characteristics in the isometric mid-thigh pull. Sports (Basel) 6: 162, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guppy SN, Kotani Y, Brady CJ, et al. The reliability and magnitude of time-dependent force-time characteristics during the isometric midthigh pull are affected by both testing protocol and analysis choices. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1191&#x2013;1199, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Carlock JM, Hartman MJ, et al. Force-time curve characteristics of dynamic and isometric muscle actions of elite women Olympic weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res 19: 741&#x2013;748, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton LC. Resistant normality check and outlier identification. Stata Tech Bull 1: 1&#x2013;28, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding EC, Franks NP, Wisden W. The temperature dependence of sleep. Front Neurosci 13: 336, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV. Distribution theory for Glass's estimator of effect size and related estimators. J Educ Stat 6: 107&#x2013;128, 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins TR, Greene DA, Baker MK. Effects of cold water immersion and contrast water therapy for recovery from team sport: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1443&#x2013;1460, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horgan BG, Drew MK, Halson SL, et al. Impaired recovery is associated with increased injury and illness: A retrospective study of 536 female netball athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports 31: 691&#x2013;701, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horgan BG, West NP, Tee N, et al. Acute inflammatory, anthropometric, and perceptual (muscle soreness) effects of postresistance exercise water immersion in junior international and subelite male volleyball athletes. J Strength Cond Res 36: 3473&#x2013;3484, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes S, Warmenhoven J, Haff GG, Chapman DW, Nimphius S. Countermovement jump and squat jump force-time curve analysis in control and fatigue conditions. J Strength Cond Res 36: 2752&#x2013;2761, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichiba T, Suzuki M, Aritake-Okada S, Uchiyama M. Periocular skin warming promotes body heat loss and sleep onset: A randomized placebo-controlled study. Sci Rep 10: 20325, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihsan M, Watson G, Abbiss CR. What are the physiological mechanisms for post-exercise cold water immersion in the recovery from prolonged endurance and intermittent exercise? Sports Med 46: 1095&#x2013;1109, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeacocke NA, Burke LM. Methods to standardize dietary intake before performance testing. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 20: 87&#x2013;103, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, Nindl BC. Recovery responses of testosterone, growth hormone, and IGF-1 after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 122: 549&#x2013;558, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraska JM, Ramsey MW, Haff GG, et al. Relationship between strength characteristics and unweighted and weighted vertical jump height. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 4: 461&#x2013;473, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CE, McArdle A, Griffiths RD. The role of hormones, cytokines and heat shock proteins during age-related muscle loss. Clin Nutr 26: 524&#x2013;534, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorm H, Roberts LA, Coombes JS, Peake JM. Turning up the heat: An evaluation of the evidence for heating to promote exercise recovery, muscle rehabilitation and adaptation. Sports Med 48: 1311&#x2013;1328, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan MR, Foster C. A new approach to monitoring resistance training. Strength Cond J 26: 42&#x2013;47, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 5: 367&#x2013;383, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, Stone JD, Hornsby WG, Hagen JA. Identifying reliable and relatable force&#x2013;time metrics in athletes&#x2014;considerations for the isometric mid-thigh pull and countermovement jump. Sports (Basel) 9: 4, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methenitis S, Stergiou I, Antonopoulou S, Nomikos T. Can exercise-induced muscle damage be a good model for the investigation of the anti-inflammatory properties of diet in humans? Biomedicines 9: 36, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minett GM, Costello JT. Specificity and context in post-exercise recovery: It is not a one-size-fits-all approach. Front Physiol 6: 130, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake JM, Roberts LA, Figueiredo VC, et al. The effects of cold water immersion and active recovery on inflammation and cell stress responses in human skeletal muscle after resistance exercise. J Physiol 595: 695&#x2013;711, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Rojas FJ, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A. Assessment of unloaded and loaded squat jump performance with a force platform: Which jump starting threshold provides more reliable outcomes? J Biomech 92: 19&#x2013;28, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pointon M, Duffield R, Cannon J, Marino FE. Cold application for neuromuscular recovery following intense lower-body exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 2977&#x2013;2986, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pournot H, Bieuzen F, Duffield R, et al. Short term effects of various water immersions on recovery from exhaustive intermittent exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 1287&#x2013;1295, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymann RJEM, Swaab DF, Van Someren EJW. Cutaneous warming promotes sleep onset. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 288: R1589&#x2013;R1597, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LA, Nosaka K, Coombes JS, Peake JM. Cold water immersion enhances recovery of submaximal muscle function after resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 307: R998&#x2013;R1008, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LA, Raastad T, Markworth JF, et al. Post-exercise cold water immersion attenuates acute anabolic signalling and long-term adaptations in muscle to strength training. J Physiol 593: 4285&#x2013;4301, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues P, Trajano GS, Wharton L, Minett GM. Effects of passive heating intervention on muscle hypertrophy and neuromuscular function: A preliminary systematic review with meta-analysis. J Therm Biol 93: 102684, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schimpchen J, Wagner M, Ferrauti A, et al. Can cold water immersion enhance recovery in elite Olympic weightlifters? An individualized perspective. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1569&#x2013;1576, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Chapman D, Taylor K-L. An evaluation of a strength qualities assessment method for the lower body. J Aust Strength Cond 19: 4&#x2013;10, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva VSd, Vieira MFS. International Society for the Advancement of Kinanthropometry (ISAK) global: International accreditation scheme of the competent anthropometrist. Rev Bras Cineantropom Desempenho Hum 22: 1&#x2013;6, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens JM, Halson S, Miller J, Slater GJ, Askew CD. Cold-water immersion for athletic recovery: One size does not fit all. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: 2&#x2013;9, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale RS, Kyrolainen H, Gagnon SS, et al. Active and passive recovery influence responses of luteinizing hormone and testosterone to a fatiguing strength loading. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 123&#x2013;131, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares F, Simoes M, Matos B, Smith TB, Driller M. The acute and longer-term effects of cold water immersion in highly-trained volleyball athletes during an intense training block. Front Sports Act Living 2: 568420, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor K, Cronin JB, Gill N, Chapman DW, Sheppard JM. Warm-up affects diurnal variation in power output. Int J Sports Med 32: 185&#x2013;189, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timoteo TF, Seixas MB, Almeida Falci MF, et al. Impact of consecutive games on workload, state of recovery and well-being of professional volleyball players. J Exerc Physiol Online 20: 130&#x2013;140, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AN, Comfort P, McMahon J, et al. Developing powerful athletes, Part 1: Mechanical underpinnings. Strength Cond J 42: 30&#x2013;39, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaile J, Halson S, Gill N, Dawson B. Effect of hydrotherapy on the signs and symptoms of delayed onset muscle soreness. Eur J Appl Physiol 102: 447&#x2013;455, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versey NG, Halson SL, Dawson BT. Water immersion recovery for athletes: Effect on exercise performance and practical recommendations. Sports Med 43: 1101&#x2013;1130, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viitasalo JT, Niemel&#xe4; K, Kaappola R, et al. Warm underwater water-jet massage improves recovery from intense physical exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 71: 431&#x2013;438, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AJ, Sawka MN, Epstein Y, Decristofano B, Pandolf KB. Cooling different body surfaces during upper and lower body exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 63: 1218&#x2013;1223, 1987.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>