<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31864419</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>International Society of Sports Nutrition Position Stand: Probiotics.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>62</StartPage><MedlinePgn>62</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">62</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12970-019-0329-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Position statement: The International Society of Sports Nutrition (ISSN) provides an objective and critical review of the mechanisms and use of probiotic supplementation to optimize the health, performance, and recovery of athletes. Based on the current available literature, the conclusions of the ISSN are as follows: 1)Probiotics are live microorganisms that, when administered in adequate amounts, confer a health benefit on the host (FAO/WHO).2)Probiotic administration has been linked to a multitude of health benefits, with gut and immune health being the most researched applications.3)Despite the existence of shared, core mechanisms for probiotic function, health benefits of probiotics are strain- and dose-dependent.4)Athletes have varying gut microbiota compositions that appear to reflect the activity level of the host in comparison to sedentary people, with the differences linked primarily to the volume of exercise and amount of protein consumption. Whether differences in gut microbiota composition affect probiotic efficacy is unknown.5)The main function of the gut is to digest food and absorb nutrients. In athletic populations, certain probiotics strains can increase absorption of key nutrients such as amino acids from protein, and affect the pharmacology and physiological properties of multiple food components.6)Immune depression in athletes worsens with excessive training load, psychological stress, disturbed sleep, and environmental extremes, all of which can contribute to an increased risk of respiratory tract infections. In certain situations, including exposure to crowds, foreign travel and poor hygiene at home, and training or competition venues, athletes' exposure to pathogens may be elevated leading to increased rates of infections. Approximately 70% of the immune system is located in the gut and probiotic supplementation has been shown to promote a healthy immune response. In an athletic population, specific probiotic strains can reduce the number of episodes, severity and duration of upper respiratory tract infections.7)Intense, prolonged exercise, especially in the heat, has been shown to increase gut permeability which potentially can result in systemic toxemia. Specific probiotic strains can improve the integrity of the gut-barrier function in athletes.8)Administration of selected anti-inflammatory probiotic strains have been linked to improved recovery from muscle-damaging exercise.9)The minimal effective dose and method of administration (potency per serving, single vs. split dose, delivery form) of a specific probiotic strain depends on validation studies for this particular strain. Products that contain probiotics must include the genus, species, and strain of each live microorganism on its label as well as the total estimated quantity of each probiotic strain at the end of the product's shelf life, as measured by colony forming units (CFU) or live cells.10)Preclinical and early human research has shown potential probiotic benefits relevant to an athletic population that include improved body composition and lean body mass, normalizing age-related declines in testosterone levels, reductions in cortisol levels indicating improved responses to a physical or mental stressor, reduction of exercise-induced lactate, and increased neurotransmitter synthesis, cognition and mood. However, these potential benefits require validation in more rigorous human studies and in an athletic population.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J&#xe4;ger</LastName><ForeName>Ralf</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7345-9635</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Increnovo LLC, Milwaukee, WI, USA. ralf.jaeger@increnovo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohr</LastName><ForeName>Alex E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Health Solutions, Arizona State University, Phoenix, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carpenter</LastName><ForeName>Katie C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Isagenix International LLC, Gilbert, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerksick</LastName><ForeName>Chad M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Performance Nutrition Laboratory, School of Health Sciences, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purpura</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Increnovo LLC, Milwaukee, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moussa</LastName><ForeName>Adel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of M&#xfc;nster, Department of Physics Education, M&#xfc;nster, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Townsend</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Nutrition Science Graduate Program, Lipscomb University, Nashville, TN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lamprecht</LastName><ForeName>Manfred</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Otto Loewi Research Center, Medical University of Graz, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>West</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas P</ForeName><Initials>NP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical Science and Menzies Health Institute of QLD, Griffith Health, Griffith University, Southport, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Black</LastName><ForeName>Katherine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Nutrition, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gleeson</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pyne</LastName><ForeName>David B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, 2617, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wells</LastName><ForeName>Shawn D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>WGI, Lewisville, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arent</LastName><ForeName>Shawn M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UofSC Sport Science Lab, Department of Exercise Science, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith-Ryan</LastName><ForeName>Abbie E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Exercise and Sport Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreider</LastName><ForeName>Richard B</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sport Nutrition Lab, Human Clinical Research Facility, Department of Health &amp; Kinesiology, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Bill I</ForeName><Initials>BI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance &amp; Physique Enhancement Laboratory, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bannock</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Performance Nutrition, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scheiman</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fitbiomics, Inc, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wissent</LastName><ForeName>Craig J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jamieson Wellness Inc, Windsor, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pane</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bioloab Research, Novara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalman</LastName><ForeName>Douglas S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scientific Affairs. Nutrasource Diagnostics, Inc. Guelph, Guelph, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pugh</LastName><ForeName>Jamie N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Tom Reilly Building, Byrom St Campus, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ter Haar</LastName><ForeName>Jessica A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Probiotic Association, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antonio</LastName><ForeName>Jose</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Sport Science, Nova Southeastern University, Davie, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019936" MajorTopicYN="Y">Probiotics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012955" MajorTopicYN="N">Societies, Medical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064132" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports Nutritional Sciences</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gut-muscle-Axis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microbiome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microbiota</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sport performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>AM, ASR, KB, LB, and SDW declare no competing interests. RJ has received grants to evaluate the efficacy and safety of probiotics, serves on scientific advisory boards, and has served as an expert witness, legal and scientific consultant. AEM and KCC are employed by Isagenix, a company selling branded probiotics products. CMK has previously received external funding to conduct research studies involving nutritional supplements and is currently conducting studies involving prebiotics and probiotics. MP has received grants to evaluate the efficacy and safety of probiotics, and has served as a scientific consultant. JRT reports no conflicts of interest regarding the material or paper presented. JRT has previously received grants to evaluate the efficacy of various nutritional supplements including probiotics. ML conducts industry sponsored studies and serves as a scientific consultant to the Juice Plus+ Company. MG reports no conflicts of interest regarding the material or paper presented. MG has previously received external funding to conduct research studies involving nutritional supplements including probiotics. DBP reports no conflicts of interest regarding the material or paper presented, and has received grants to evaluate the effectiveness of probiotic supplementation in athletes. BIC serves on the scientific advisory board of Dymatize (Post Holdings). SMA reports no conflicts of interest related to the material presented in this paper. He has conducted industry sponsored studies at the universities he has been affiliated with and has occasionally served as an expert witness and scientific consultant. RBK reports no conflicts of interest related to the material presented in this paper. He has conducted industry sponsored studies at the universities he has been affiliated with and occasionally serves as a scientific and legal consultant related to exercise and nutrition intervention studies. CJW is employed by Jamieson Labs, a company selling branded probiotics products. MPa is employed by Biolab research Srl, performing research &amp; development activities for Probiotical SpA, a leading probiotic supplier. DSK works for a Contract Research Organization (Nutrasource) that has received funding from the probiotic industry for clinical trials and serves on the Scientific Advisory Board for Dymatize (Post Holdings). JS is a co-founder of FitBiomics, a company identifying, researching and commercializing new probiotic strains. JAT is employed by the International Probiotic Association and further consults within the probiotic and microbiome industries. JA is the CEO of the International Society of Sports Nutrition.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31864419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6925426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-019-0329-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12970-019-0329-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hill C, Guarner F, Reid G, Gibson GR, Merenstein DJ, Pot B, Morelli L, Canani RB, Flint HJ, Salminen S, et al. Expert consensus document. The international scientific Association for Probiotics and Prebiotics consensus statement on the scope and appropriate use of the term probiotic. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2014;11:506&#x2013;514. doi: 10.1038/nrgastro.2014.66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrgastro.2014.66</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson GR, Hutkins R, Sanders ME, Prescott SL, Reimer RA, Salminen SJ, Scott K, Stanton C, Swanson KS, Cani PD, et al. Expert consensus document: the international scientific Association for Probiotics and Prebiotics (ISAPP) consensus statement on the definition and scope of prebiotics. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;14:491&#x2013;502. doi: 10.1038/nrgastro.2017.75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrgastro.2017.75</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28611480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vrese Michael, Schrezenmeir J. Food Biotechnology. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Berlin Heidelberg; 2008. Probiotics, Prebiotics, and Synbiotics; pp. 1&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar-toala J, Garcia-Perez R, Garcia H, Mata-Haro V, Gonzalez-Cordova A, Vallego-Cordoba B, Hernandez-Mendoza A. Postbiotics: An evolving term within the functional foods field. Trends Food Sci Technol. 2018;75:105&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1016/j.tifs.2018.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2018.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, Larson-Meyer DE, Peeling P, Phillips SM, Rawson ES, Walsh NP, Garthe I, Geyer H, et al. IOC consensus statement: dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:439&#x2013;455. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2018-099027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29540367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland I, Capurso L, Collins K, Cummings J, Delzenne N, Goulet O, Guarner F, Marteau P, Meier R. Current level of consensus on probiotic science--report of an expert meeting--London, 23 November 2009. Gut Microbes. 2010;1:436&#x2013;439. doi: 10.4161/gmic.1.6.13610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/gmic.1.6.13610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21637035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metchnikoff E. The prolongated of life; optimistic studies. New York: G.P. Putnam&#x2019;s Son; 1908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duranti S, Ferrario C, van Sinderen D, Ventura M, Turroni F. Obesity and microbiota: an example of an intricate relationship. Genes Nutr. 2017;12:18. doi: 10.1186/s12263-017-0566-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12263-017-0566-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5473000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28638490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staley JT. Biodiversity: are microbial species threatened? Curr Opin Biotechnol. 1997;8:340&#x2013;345. doi: 10.1016/S0958-1669(97)80014-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0958-1669(97)80014-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9206017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyne DB, West NP, Cox AJ, Cripps AW. Probiotics supplementation for athletes - clinical and physiological effects. Eur J Sport Sci. 2015;15:63&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2014.971879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2014.971879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25339255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello EK, Lauber CL, Hamady M, Fierer N, Gordon JI, Knight R. Bacterial community variation in human body habitats across space and time. Science. 1694;2009:326. doi: 10.1126/science.1177486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1177486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3602444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19892944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffy LC, Raiten DJ, Hubbard VS, Starke-Reed P. Progress and challenges in developing metabolic footprints from diet in human gut microbial cometabolism. J Nutr. 2015;145:1123S&#x2013;1130S. doi: 10.3945/jn.114.194936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.114.194936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4410496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25833886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yatsunenko T, Rey FE, Manary MJ, Trehan I, Dominguez-Bello MG, Contreras M, Magris M, Hidalgo G, Baldassano RN, Anokhin AP, et al. Human gut microbiome viewed across age and geography. Nature. 2012;486:222&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1038/nature11053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature11053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3376388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22699611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Mihindukulasuriya KA, Gao H, La Rosa PS, Wylie KM, Martin JC, Kota K, Shannon WD, Mitreva M, Sodergren E, et al. Exploration of bacterial community classes in major human habitats. Genome Biol. 2014;15:R66. doi: 10.1186/gb-2014-15-5-r66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/gb-2014-15-5-r66</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4073010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24887286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bressa C, Bailen-Andrino M, Perez-Santiago J, Gonzalez-Soltero R, Perez M, Montalvo-Lominchar MG, Mate-Munoz JL, Dominguez R, Moreno D, Larrosa M. Differences in gut microbiota profile between women with active lifestyle and sedentary women. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0171352. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0171352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0171352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5302835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28187199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke SF, Murphy EF, O'Sullivan O, Lucey AJ, Humphreys M, Hogan A, Hayes P, O'Reilly M, Jeffery IB, Wood-Martin R, et al. Exercise and associated dietary extremes impact on gut microbial diversity. Gut. 1913;2014:63. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2013-306541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2013-306541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25021423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen LM, Bautista EJ, Nguyen H, Hanson BM, Chen L, Lek SH, Sodergren E, Weinstock GM. Community characteristics of the gut microbiomes of competitive cyclists. Microbiome. 2017;5:98. doi: 10.1186/s40168-017-0320-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-017-0320-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28797298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morkl S, Lackner S, Muller W, Gorkiewicz G, Kashofer K, Oberascher A, Painold A, Holl A, Holzer P, Meinitzer A, et al. Gut microbiota and body composition in anorexia nervosa inpatients in comparison to athletes, overweight, obese, and normal weight controls. Int J Eat Disord. 2017;50:1421&#x2013;1431. doi: 10.1002/eat.22801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.22801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton W, Penney NC, Cronin O, Garcia-Perez I, Molloy MG, Holmes E, Shanahan F, Cotter PD, O'Sullivan O. The microbiome of professional athletes differs from that of more sedentary subjects in composition and particularly at the functional metabolic level. Gut. 2018;67:625&#x2013;633. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2016-313627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2016-313627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28360096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estaki M, Pither J, Baumeister P, Little JP, Gill SK, Ghosh S, Ahmadi-Vand Z, Marsden KR, Gibson DL. Cardiorespiratory fitness as a predictor of intestinal microbial diversity and distinct metagenomic functions. Microbiome. 2016;4:42. doi: 10.1186/s40168-016-0189-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40168-016-0189-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4976518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27502158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerda B, Perez M, Perez-Santiago JD, Tornero-Aguilera JF, Gonzalez-Soltero R, Larrosa M. Gut microbiota modification: another piece in the puzzle of the benefits of physical exercise in health? Front Physiol. 2016;7:51. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2016.00051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2016.00051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4757670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26924990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JJ, Eum SY, Rampersaud E, Daunert S, Abreu MT, Toborek M. Exercise attenuates PCB-induced changes in the mouse gut microbiome. Environ Health Perspect. 2013;121:725&#x2013;730. doi: 10.1289/ehp.1306534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/ehp.1306534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3672930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23632211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans CC, LePard KJ, Kwak JW, Stancukas MC, Laskowski S, Dougherty J, Moulton L, Glawe A, Wang Y, Leone V, et al. Exercise prevents weight gain and alters the gut microbiota in a mouse model of high fat diet-induced obesity. PLoS One. 2014;9:e92193. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0092193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0092193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3966766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24670791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petriz BA, Castro AP, Almeida JA, Gomes CP, Fernandes GR, Kruger RH, Pereira RW, Franco OL. Exercise induction of gut microbiota modifications in obese, non-obese and hypertensive rats. BMC Genomics. 2014;15:511. doi: 10.1186/1471-2164-15-511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-15-511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4082611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24952588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queipo-Ortuno MI, Seoane LM, Murri M, Pardo M, Gomez-Zumaquero JM, Cardona F, Casanueva F, Tinahones FJ. Gut microbiota composition in male rat models under different nutritional status and physical activity and its association with serum leptin and ghrelin levels. PLoS One. 2013;8:e65465. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0065465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0065465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3665787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23724144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell SC, Wisniewski PJ, Noji M, McGuinness LR, Haggblom MM, Lightfoot SA, Joseph LB, Kerkhof LJ. The effect of diet and exercise on intestinal integrity and microbial diversity in mice. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0150502. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0150502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0150502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4783017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26954359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook MD, Martin SA, Williams C, Whitlock K, Wallig MA, Pence BD, Woods JA. Forced treadmill exercise training exacerbates inflammation and causes mortality while voluntary wheel training is protective in a mouse model of colitis. Brain Behav Immun. 2013;33:46&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2013.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2013.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23707215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen JM, Mailing LJ, Niemiro GM, Moore R, Cook MD, White BA, Holscher HD, Woods JA. Exercise alters gut microbiota composition and function in lean and obese humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50:747&#x2013;757. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29166320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto M, Inoue R, Tsukahara T, Ushida K, Chiji H, Matsubara N, Hara H. Voluntary running exercise alters microbiota composition and increases n-butyrate concentration in the rat cecum. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2008;72:572&#x2013;576. doi: 10.1271/bbb.70474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1271/bbb.70474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18256465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheiman J, Luber JM, Chavkin TA, MacDonald T, Tung A, Pham LD, Wibowo MC, Wurth RC, Punthambaker S, Tierney BT, et al. Meta-omics analysis of elite athletes identifies a performance-enhancing microbe that functions via lactate metabolism. Nat Med. 2019;25:1104&#x2013;1109. doi: 10.1038/s41591-019-0485-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-019-0485-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31235964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin O, O'Sullivan O, Barton W, Cotter PD, Molloy MG, Shanahan F. Gut microbiota: implications for sports and exercise medicine. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:700&#x2013;701. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-097225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28077354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David LA, Maurice CF, Carmody RN, Gootenberg DB, Button JE, Wolfe BE, Ling AV, Devlin AS, Varma Y, Fischbach MA, et al. Diet rapidly and reproducibly alters the human gut microbiome. Nature. 2014;505:559&#x2013;563. doi: 10.1038/nature12820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature12820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3957428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu GD, Chen J, Hoffmann C, Bittinger K, Chen YY, Keilbaugh SA, Bewtra M, Knights D, Walters WA, Knight R, et al. Linking long-term dietary patterns with gut microbial enterotypes. Science. 2011;334:105&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1126/science.1208344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1208344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3368382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21885731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheflin AM, Melby CL, Carbonero F, Weir TL. Linking dietary patterns with gut microbial composition and function. Gut Microbes. 2017;8:113&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1080/19490976.2016.1270809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19490976.2016.1270809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5390824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27960648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-P&#xe9;rez Diego, Bressa Carlo, Bail&#xe9;n Mar&#xed;a, Hamed-Bousdar Safa, Naclerio Fernando, Carmona Manuel, P&#xe9;rez Margarita, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Soltero Roc&#xed;o, Montalvo-Lominchar Maria, Caraba&#xf1;a Claudia, Larrosa Mar. Effect of a Protein Supplement on the Gut Microbiota of Endurance Athletes: A Randomized, Controlled, Double-Blind Pilot Study. Nutrients. 2018;10(3):337. doi: 10.3390/nu10030337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10030337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5872755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29534465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M. Immune function in sport and exercise. J App Physiol (1985) 2007;103:693&#x2013;699. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00008.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00008.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17303714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tap J, Furet JP, Bensaada M, Philippe C, Roth H, Rabot S, Lakhdari O, Lombard V, Henrissat B, Corthier G, et al. Gut microbiota richness promotes its stability upon increased dietary fibre intake in healthy adults. Environ Microbiol. 2015;17:4954&#x2013;4964. doi: 10.1111/1462-2920.13006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1462-2920.13006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26235304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramp T, Broad E, Martin D, Meyer BJ. Effects of preexercise carbohydrate ingestion on mountain bike performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1602;2004:36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15354044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caesar R, Tremaroli V, Kovatcheva-Datchary P, Cani PD, Backhed F. Crosstalk between gut microbiota and dietary lipids aggravates WAT inflammation through TLR signaling. Cell Metab. 2015;22:658&#x2013;668. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2015.07.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2015.07.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4598654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26321659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Miles MP, Larson-Meyer DE. Dietary supplements for health, adaptation, and recovery in athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28:188&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira EP, Burini RC, Jeukendrup A. Gastrointestinal complaints during exercise: prevalence, etiology, and nutritional recommendations. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):S79&#x2013;S85. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0153-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0153-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger Ralf, Purpura Martin, Stone Jason, Turner Stephanie, Anzalone Anthony, Eimerbrink Micah, Pane Marco, Amoruso Angela, Rowlands David, Oliver Jonathan. Probiotic Streptococcus thermophilus FP4 and Bifidobacterium breve BR03 Supplementation Attenuates Performance and Range-of-Motion Decrements Following Muscle Damaging Exercise. Nutrients. 2016;8(10):642. doi: 10.3390/nu8100642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu8100642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5084029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27754427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger Ralf, Shields Kevin A., Lowery Ryan P., De Souza Eduardo O., Partl Jeremy M., Hollmer Chase, Purpura Martin, Wilson Jacob M. ProbioticBacillus coagulansGBI-30, 6086 reduces exercise-induced muscle damage and increases recovery. PeerJ. 2016;4:e2276. doi: 10.7717/peerj.2276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.2276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4963221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27547577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salarkia N, Ghadamli L, Zaeri F, Sabaghian Rad L. Effects of probiotic yogurt on performance, respiratory and digestive systems of young adult female endurance swimmers: a randomized controlled trial. Med J Islam Repub Iran. 2013;27:141&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3917487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehzadeh K. The effects of probiotic yogurt drink on lipid profile, CRP, and record changes in aerobic athletes. Life Sci. 2015;9:32&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shing CM, Peake JM, Lim CL, Briskey D, Walsh NP, Fortes MB, Ahuja KD, Vitetta L. Effects of probiotics supplementation on gastrointestinal permeability, inflammation and exercise performance in the heat. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:93&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1007/s00421-013-2748-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-013-2748-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24150782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klaenhammer TR, Kleerebezem M, Kopp MV, Rescigno M. The impact of probiotics and prebiotics on the immune system. Nat Rev Immunol. 2012;12:728&#x2013;734. doi: 10.1038/nri3312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nri3312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23007572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang LX, Chang B, Zhang WL, Wu XM, Li XH, Jiang M. Remission induction and maintenance effect of probiotics on ulcerative colitis: a meta-analysis. World J Gastroenterol. 1908;2010:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng SC, Hart AL, Kamm MA, Stagg AJ, Knight SC. Mechanisms of action of probiotics: recent advances. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2009;15:300&#x2013;310. doi: 10.1002/ibd.20602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ibd.20602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plaza-Diaz J, Gomez-Llorente C, Fontana L, Gil A. Modulation of immunity and inflammatory gene expression in the gut, in inflammatory diseases of the gut and in the liver by probiotics. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:15632&#x2013;15649. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v20.i42.15632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v20.i42.15632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25400447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miettinen M, Vuopio-Varkila J, Varkila K. Production of human tumor necrosis factor alpha, interleukin-6, and interleukin-10 is induced by lactic acid bacteria. Infect Immun. 1996;64:5403&#x2013;5405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC174537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8945595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazemian V, Shadnoush M, Manaheji H, Zaringhalam J. Probiotics and inflammatory pain: a literature review study. Middle East J Rehab Health. 2016;3:e36087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clancy RL, Gleeson M, Cox A, Callister R, Dorrington M, D'Este C, Pang G, Pyne D, Fricker P, Henriksson A. Reversal in fatigued athletes of a defect in interferon gamma secretion after administration of Lactobacillus acidophilus. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40:351&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2005.024364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2005.024364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2577537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16556792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira A, Kekkonen R, Korpela R, Delgado L, Haahtela T. Allergy in marathon runners and effect of Lactobacillus GG supplementation on allergic inflammatory markers. Respir Med. 2007;101:1123&#x2013;1131. doi: 10.1016/j.rmed.2006.11.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2006.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17196811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kekkonen RA, Vasankari TJ, Vuorimaa T, Haahtela T, Julkunen I, Korpela R. The effect of probiotics on respiratory infections and gastrointestinal symptoms during training in marathon runners. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17:352&#x2013;363. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.17.4.352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.17.4.352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17962710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiollier E, Chennaoui M, Gomez-Merino D, Drogou C, Filaire E, Guezennec CY. Effect of a probiotics supplementation on respiratory infections and immune and hormonal parameters during intense military training. Mil Med. 2007;172:1006&#x2013;1011. doi: 10.7205/milmed.172.9.1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7205/milmed.172.9.1006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17937368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox AJ, Pyne DB, Saunders PU, Fricker PA. Oral administration of the probiotic Lactobacillus fermentum VRI-003 and mucosal immunity in endurance athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2010;44:222&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2007.044628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2007.044628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18272539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martarelli D, Verdenelli MC, Scuri S, Cocchioni M, Silvi S, Cecchini C, Pompei P. Effect of a probiotic intake on oxidant and antioxidant parameters in plasma of athletes during intense exercise training. Curr Microbiol. 1689;2011:62. doi: 10.1007/s00284-011-9915-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00284-011-9915-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21400082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M, Bishop NC, Stensel DJ, Lindley MR, Mastana SS, Nimmo MA. The anti-inflammatory effects of exercise: mechanisms and implications for the prevention and treatment of disease. Nat Rev Immunol. 2011;11:607&#x2013;615. doi: 10.1038/nri3041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nri3041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21818123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M, Bishop NC, Oliveira M, Tauler P. Daily probiotic's (Lactobacillus casei Shirota) reduction of infection incidence in athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2011;21:55&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.21.1.55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.21.1.55</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21411836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West NP, Pyne DB, Cripps AW, Hopkins WG, Eskesen DC, Jairath A, Christophersen CT, Conlon MA, Fricker PA. Lactobacillus fermentum (PCC(R)) supplementation and gastrointestinal and respiratory-tract illness symptoms: a randomised control trial in athletes. Nutr J. 2011;10:30. doi: 10.1186/1475-2891-10-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2891-10-30</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3083335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21477383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe4;lim&#xe4;ki I., Vuorimaa T., Ahotupa M., Kekkonen R., Korpela R., Vasankari T. Decreased Training Volume and Increased Carbohydrate Intake Increases Oxidized LDL Levels. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2012;33(04):291&#x2013;296. doi: 10.1055/s-0031-1291223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0031-1291223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22377944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamprecht M, Bogner S, Schippinger G, Steinbauer K, Fankhauser F, Hallstroem S, Schuetz B, Greilberger JF. Probiotic supplementation affects markers of intestinal barrier, oxidation, and inflammation in trained men; a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9:45. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-9-45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-9-45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3465223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M, Bishop N, Oliveira M, McCauley T, Tauler P, Muhamad AS. Respiratory infection risk in athletes: association with antigen-stimulated IL-10 production and salivary IgA secretion. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2012;22:410&#x2013;417. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01272.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01272.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grobbelaar et al. The influence of probiotic supplementation on selected athletic performance-related blood markers in men. African Journal for Physical, Health Education, Recreation and Dance. 2012;18(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West NP, Pyne DB, Cripps AW, Christophersen CT, Conlon MA, Fricker PA. Gut balance, a synbiotic supplement, increases fecal Lactobacillus paracasei but has little effect on immunity in healthy physically active individuals. Gut Microbes. 2012;3:221&#x2013;227. doi: 10.4161/gmic.19579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/gmic.19579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3427214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22572834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sashihara T, Nagata M, Mori T, Ikegami S, Gotoh M, Okubo K, Uchida M, Itoh H. Effects of Lactobacillus gasseri OLL2809 and alpha-lactalbumin on university-student athletes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2013;38:1228&#x2013;1235. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2012-0490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2012-0490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24195623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West NP, Horn PL, Pyne DB, Gebski VJ, Lahtinen SJ, Fricker PA, Cripps AW. Probiotic supplementation for respiratory and gastrointestinal illness symptoms in healthy physically active individuals. Clin Nutr. 2014;33:581&#x2013;587. doi: 10.1016/j.clnu.2013.10.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2013.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24268677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haywood BA, Black KE, Baker D, McGarvey J, Healey P, Brown RC. Probiotic supplementation reduces the duration and incidence of infections but not severity in elite rugby union players. J Sci Med Sport. 2014;17:356&#x2013;360. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2013.08.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2013.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24045086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghaee M, Khosravi N, Hanachi P, Kordi MR, Aghaee R. Effect of probiotic supplement on immune response in male athletes. Qom Univ Med Sci. 2014;7:27&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georges J, Lowery R, Yaman G, Kerio C, Ormes J, McCleary S, Sharp M, Shields K, Rauch J, Silva J, et al. The effects of probiotic supplementation on lean body mass, strength, power, and health indicators in resistance trained males: a pilot study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014;11:P38. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-11-S1-P38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-11-S1-P38</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narimani-Rad et al. Indian Journal of Fundamental and Applied Life Sciences (Online) An Open Access, Online International Journal Available at www.cibtech.org/sp.ed/jls/2014/03/jls.htm. 2014;4(S3):231&#x2013;5. ISSN: 2231&#x2013;6345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhamad A, Gleeson M. Effects of a 14-strain probiotics supplement on salivary antimicrobial proteins at rest and in reponse to an acute bout of prolonged exercise. Int J Sports Sci. 2014;4:60&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien KV, Stewart LK, Forney LA, Aryana KJ, Prinyawiwatkul W, Boeneke CA. The effects of postexercise consumption of a kefir beverage on performance and recovery during intensive endurance training. J Dairy Sci. 2015;98:7446&#x2013;7449. doi: 10.3168/jds.2015-9392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2015-9392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26298752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill SK, Teixeira AM, Rosado F, Cox M, Costa RJ. High-dose probiotic supplementation containing Lactobacillus casei for 7 days does not enhance salivary antimicrobial protein responses to exertional heat stress compared with placebo. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2016;26:150&#x2013;160. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26479711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill SK, Allerton DM, Ansley-Robson P, Hemmings K, Cox M, Costa RJ. Does short-term high dose probiotic supplementation containing Lactobacillus casei attenuate exertional-heat stress induced Endotoxaemia and Cytokinaemia? Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2016;26:268&#x2013;275. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2015-0186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26568577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts Justin, Suckling Craig, Peedle Georgia, Murphy Joseph, Dawkins Tony, Roberts Michael. An Exploratory Investigation of Endotoxin Levels in Novice Long Distance Triathletes, and the Effects of a Multi-Strain Probiotic/Prebiotic, Antioxidant Intervention. Nutrients. 2016;8(11):733. doi: 10.3390/nu8110733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu8110733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5133117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27869661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser Barbara, Geiger Daniela, Schauer Markus, Gostner Johanna, Gatterer Hannes, Burtscher Martin, Fuchs Dietmar. Probiotic Supplements Beneficially Affect Tryptophan&#x2013;Kynurenine Metabolism and Reduce the Incidence of Upper Respiratory Tract Infections in Trained Athletes: A Randomized, Double-Blinded, Placebo-Controlled Trial. Nutrients. 2016;8(11):752. doi: 10.3390/nu8110752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu8110752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5133134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27886064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michalickova D, Minic R, Dikic N, Andjelkovic M, Kostic-Vucicevic M, Stojmenovic T, Nikolic I, Djordjevic B. Lactobacillus helveticus Lafti L10 supplementation reduces respiratory infection duration in a cohort of elite athletes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41:782&#x2013;789. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2015-0541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2015-0541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27363733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M, Bishop NC, Struszczak L. Effects of Lactobacillus casei Shirota ingestion on common cold infection and herpes virus antibodies in endurance athletes: a placebo-controlled, randomized trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:1555&#x2013;1563. doi: 10.1007/s00421-016-3415-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3415-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4943997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27294502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall H, Chrismas BCR, Suckling CA, Roberts JD, Foster J, Taylor L. Chronic probiotic supplementation with or without glutamine does not influence the eHsp72 response to a multi-day ultra-endurance exercise event. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42:876&#x2013;883. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2017-0131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2017-0131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28460195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan Connery J., Axelrod Christopher L., Paul Deborah, Hull Michaela, Kirwan John P. Effects Of A Novel Probiotic On Exercise-Induced Gut Permeability and Microbiota in Endurance Athletes. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise. 2018;50:840. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000538764.55259.9c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000538764.55259.9c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend Jeremy, Bender David, Vantrease William, Sapp Philip, Toy Ann, Woods Clint, Johnson Kent. Effects of Probiotic (Bacillus subtilis DE111) Supplementation on Immune Function, Hormonal Status, and Physical Performance in Division I Baseball Players. Sports. 2018;6(3):70. doi: 10.3390/sports6030070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports6030070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6162611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30049931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Leaf A, Carson C, Ellerbroek A, Axelrod C, Silver T, Burgess V, Peacock C. The effects of probiotic supplementation in active men and women. J Exerc Nutr. 2018;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang WC, Hsu YJ, Li H, Kan NW, Chen YM, Lin JS, Hsu TK, Tsai TY, Chiu YS, Huang CC. Effect of Lactobacillus Plantarum TWK10 on improving endurance performance in humans. Chin J Phys. 2018;61:163&#x2013;170. doi: 10.4077/CJP.2018.BAH587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4077/CJP.2018.BAH587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29962176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbuhn Aaron, Reynolds Shelby, Campbell Clark, Bradford Luke, Deckert Jake, Kreutzer Andreas, Fry Andrew. Effects of Probiotic (Bifidobacterium longum 35624) Supplementation on Exercise Performance, Immune Modulation, and Cognitive Outlook in Division I Female Swimmers. Sports. 2018;6(4):116. doi: 10.3390/sports6040116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports6040116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30308984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Wen-Ching, Wei Chen-Chan, Huang Chi-Chang, Chen Wen-Lin, Huang Hui-Yu. The Beneficial Effects of Lactobacillus plantarum PS128 on High-Intensity, Exercise-Induced Oxidative Stress, Inflammation, and Performance in Triathletes. Nutrients. 2019;11(2):353. doi: 10.3390/nu11020353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11020353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6412901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30736479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh Jamie N., Sparks Andy S., Doran Dominic A., Fleming Simon C., Langan-Evans Carl, Kirk Ben, Fearn Robert, Morton James P., Close Graeme L. Four weeks of probiotic supplementation reduces GI symptoms during a marathon race. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2019;119(7):1491&#x2013;1501. doi: 10.1007/s00421-019-04136-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-019-04136-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6570661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30982100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pumpa Kate L., McKune Andrew J., Harnett Joanna. A novel role of probiotics in improving host defence of elite rugby union athlete: A double blind randomised controlled trial. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport. 2019;22(8):876&#x2013;881. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2019.03.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31006545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaisberg Mauro, Paix&#xe3;o Vitoria, Almeida Ewin, Santos Juliana, Foster Roberta, Rossi Marcelo, Pithon-Curi Tania, Gorj&#xe3;o Renata, Momesso Cesar, Andrade Mar&#xed;lia, Araujo Jos&#xe9;, Garcia Maur&#xed;cio, Cohen Moises, Perez Elizabeth, Santos-Dias Alana, Vieira Rodolfo, Bachi Andr&#xe9;. Daily Intake of Fermented Milk Containing Lactobacillus casei Shirota (Lcs) Modulates Systemic and Upper Airways Immune/Inflammatory Responses in Marathon Runners. Nutrients. 2019;11(7):1678. doi: 10.3390/nu11071678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11071678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6682935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31336570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R. Exercise, nutrition and the brain. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):S47&#x2013;S56. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0150-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0150-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YM, Wei L, Chiu YS, Hsu YJ, Tsai TY, Wang MF, Huang CC. Lactobacillus plantarum TWK10 supplementation improves exercise performance and increases muscle mass in mice. Nutrients. 2016;8:205. doi: 10.3390/nu8040205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu8040205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4848674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27070637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Shao C, Liu L, Guo X, Xu Y, Lu X. Optimization, partial characterization and antioxidant activity of an exopolysaccharide from Lactobacillus plantarum KX041. Int J Biol Macromol. 2017;103:1173&#x2013;1184. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2017.05.118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2017.05.118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28551435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storelli G, Defaye A, Erkosar B, Hols P, Royet J, Leulier F. Lactobacillus plantarum promotes Drosophila systemic growth by modulating hormonal signals through TOR-dependent nutrient sensing. Cell Metab. 2011;14:403&#x2013;414. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2011.07.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2011.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21907145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer M, Makki K, Storelli G, Machuca-Gayet I, Srutkova D, Hermanova P, Martino ME, Balmand S, Hudcovic T, Heddi A, et al. Lactobacillus plantarum strain maintains growth of infant mice during chronic undernutrition. Science. 2016;351:854&#x2013;857. doi: 10.1126/science.aad8588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aad8588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26912894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minevich J, Olson M, Mannion J, Boublik J, McPerson J, Lowery R, Shields K, Sharp M, De Souza E, Wilson J, et al. Digestive enzymes reduce quality difference between plant and animal proteins: a double-blind crossover study (abstract) J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2015;12:P26. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-12-S1-P26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-12-S1-P26</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Gu Q. Effect of probiotic on growth performance and digestive enzyme activity of arbor acres broilers. Res Vet Sci. 2010;89:163&#x2013;167. doi: 10.1016/j.rvsc.2010.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rvsc.2010.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20350733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimmel M, Keller D, Farmer S, Warrino DE. A controlled clinical trial to evaluate the effect of GanedenBC(30) on immunological markers. Methods Find Exp Clin Pharmacol. 2010;32:129&#x2013;132. doi: 10.1358/mf.2010.32.2.1423881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1358/mf.2010.32.2.1423881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20401350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maathuis AJ, Keller D, Farmer S. Survival and metabolic activity of the GanedenBC30 strain of Bacillus coagulans in a dynamic in vitro model of the stomach and small intestine. Benefic Microbes. 2010;1:31&#x2013;36. doi: 10.3920/BM2009.0009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2009.0009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21831748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemenak M, Dolinsek J, Langerholc T, Di Gioia D, Micetic-Turk D. Administration of Bifidobacterium breve decreases the production of TNF-alpha in children with celiac disease. Dig Dis Sci. 2015;60:3386&#x2013;3392. doi: 10.1007/s10620-015-3769-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-015-3769-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26134988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicola S, Mogna L, Allesina S, Barba M, Deidda F, Lorenzini P, Raiteri E, Strozzi G, Mogna G. Interaction between probiotics and human immune cells. The prospective anti-inflammatory activity of Bifidobacterium breve BRO3. Agro Food Ind Hi-Tech. 2010;21:9&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saggioro A. Probiotics in the treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2004;38:S104&#x2013;S106. doi: 10.1097/01.mcg.0000129271.98814.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.mcg.0000129271.98814.e2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15220671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toohey JC, Townsend JR, Johnson SB, Toy AM, Vantrease WC, Bender D, Crimi CC, Stowers KL, Ruiz MD, VanDusseldorp TA, et al. Effects of probiotic (Bacillus subtilis) supplementation during offseason resistance training in female division I athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2018. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33105368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekkes MC, Weenen TC, Brummer RJ, Claassen E. The development of probiotic treatment in obesity: a review. Benefic Microbes. 2014;5:19&#x2013;28. doi: 10.3920/BM2012.0069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2012.0069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23886977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minami J, Kondo S, Yanagisawa N, Odamaki T, Xiao JZ, Abe F, Nakajima S, Hamamoto Y, Saitoh S, Shimoda T. Oral administration of Bifidobacterium breve B-3 modifies metabolic functions in adults with obese tendencies in a randomised controlled trial. J Nutr Sci. 2015;4:e17. doi: 10.1017/jns.2015.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/jns.2015.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4463018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26090097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo S, Xiao JZ, Satoh T, Odamaki T, Takahashi S, Sugahara H, Yaeshima T, Iwatsuki K, Kamei A, Abe K. Antiobesity effects of Bifidobacterium breve strain B-3 supplementation in a mouse model with high-fat diet-induced obesity. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 1656;2010:74. doi: 10.1271/bbb.100267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1271/bbb.100267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20699581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardin BJ, Campbell KS, Smith JD, Arbogast S, Smith J, Moylan JS, Reid MB. TNF-alpha acts via TNFR1 and muscle-derived oxidants to depress myofibrillar force in murine skeletal muscle. J App Physiol (1985) 2008;104:694&#x2013;699. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00898.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00898.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18187611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang CH, Frost RA, Nairn AC, MacLean DA, Vary TC. TNF-alpha impairs heart and skeletal muscle protein synthesis by altering translation initiation. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2002;282:E336&#x2013;E347. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00366.2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00366.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11788365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Main LC, Dawson B, Heel K, Grove JR, Landers GJ, Goodman C. Relationship between inflammatory cytokines and self-report measures of training overload. Res Sports Med (Print) 2010;18:127&#x2013;139. doi: 10.1080/15438621003627133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438621003627133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen NB, Bryrup T, Allin KH, Nielsen T, Hansen TH, Pedersen O. Alterations in fecal microbiota composition by probiotic supplementation in healthy adults: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Genome Med. 2016;8:52. doi: 10.1186/s13073-016-0300-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13073-016-0300-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4862129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27159972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarland LV. Use of probiotics to correct dysbiosis of normal microbiota following disease or disruptive events: a systematic review. BMJ Open. 2014;4:e005047. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2014-005047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2014-005047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4156804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnbaugh PJ, Hamady M, Yatsunenko T, Cantarel BL, Duncan A, Ley RE, Sogin ML, Jones WJ, Roe BA, Affourtit JP, et al. A core gut microbiome in obese and lean twins. Nature. 2009;457:480&#x2013;484. doi: 10.1038/nature07540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature07540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2677729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19043404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donmez N, Kisadere I, Balaban C, Kadiralieva N. Effects of traditional homemade koumiss on some hematological and biochemical characteristics in sedentary men exposed to exercise. Biotech Histochem. 2014;89:558&#x2013;563. doi: 10.3109/10520295.2014.915428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10520295.2014.915428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24893332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lollo PC, Cruz AG, Morato PN, Moura CS, Carvalho-Silva LB, Oliveira CA, Faria JA, Amaya-Farfan J. Probiotic cheese attenuates exercise-induced immune suppression in Wistar rats. J Dairy Sci. 2012;95:3549&#x2013;3558. doi: 10.3168/jds.2011-5124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2011-5124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22720913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells JM, Rossi O, Meijerink M, van Baarlen P. Epithelial crosstalk at the microbiota-mucosal interface. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108(Suppl 1):4607&#x2013;4614. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1000092107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1000092107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3063605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20826446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwellnus M, Soligard T, Alonso JM, Bahr R, Clarsen B, Dijkstra HP, Gabbett TJ, Gleeson M, Hagglund M, Hutchinson MR, et al. How much is too much? (part 2) International Olympic Committee consensus statement on load in sport and risk of illness. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1043&#x2013;1052. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5013087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geuking MB, McCoy KD, Macpherson AJ. Metabolites from intestinal microbes shape Treg. Cell Res. 2013;23:1339&#x2013;1340. doi: 10.1038/cr.2013.125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cr.2013.125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3847568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24018374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiramatsu Y, Hosono A, Konno T, Nakanishi Y, Muto M, Suyama A, Hachimura S, Sato R, Takahashi K, Kaminogawa S. Orally administered Bifidobacterium triggers immune responses following capture by CD11c(+) cells in Peyer's patches and cecal patches. Cytotechnology. 2011;63:307&#x2013;317. doi: 10.1007/s10616-011-9349-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10616-011-9349-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21461945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shephard RJ. Special feature for the Olympics: effects of exercise on the immune system: overview of the epidemiology of exercise immunology. Immunol Cell Biol. 2000;78:485&#x2013;495. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1711.2000.t01-1-.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1711.2000.t01-1-.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11050531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakravarti A. The CD4/CD8 ratio: message in a bottle? Nat Med. 1995;1:1240&#x2013;1241. doi: 10.1038/nm1295-1240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm1295-1240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7489396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders M, Merenstein D, Merrifield C, Hutkins R. Probiotics for Human Use. Nutr Bull. 2019;43:212&#x2013;225. doi: 10.1111/nbu.12334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nbu.12334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azad MAK, Sarker M, Wan D. Immunomodulatory effects of probiotics on cytokine profiles. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:8063647. doi: 10.1155/2018/8063647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/8063647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30426014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;u&#x161;kovi&#x107; J, Kos B, Novak J, Pavunc A, Habjani&#x10d; K, Mato&#x107; S. Antimicrobial activity - the most important property of probiotic and starter lactic acid bacteria. Food Technol Biotechnol. 2010;48:296&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobson A, Cotter PD, Ross RP, Hill C. Bacteriocin production: a probiotic trait? Appl Environ Microbiol. 2012;78:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1128/AEM.05576-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.05576-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22038602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotter PD, Hill C, Ross RP. Bacteriocins: developing innate immunity for food. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2005;3:777&#x2013;788. doi: 10.1038/nrmicro1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrmicro1273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16205711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wosinska Laura, Cotter Paul D., O&#x2019;Sullivan Orla, Guinane Caitriona. The Potential Impact of Probiotics on the Gut Microbiome of Athletes. Nutrients. 2019;11(10):2270. doi: 10.3390/nu11102270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11102270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31546638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehrer NJ, van Kemenade M, Meester W, Brouns F, Saris WH. Gastrointestinal complaints in relation to dietary intake in triathletes. Int J Sport Nutr. 1992;2:48&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1123/ijsn.2.1.48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsn.2.1.48</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1338583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Wijck K, Lenaerts K, Grootjans J, Wijnands KA, Poeze M, van Loon LJ, Dejong CH, Buurman WA. Physiology and pathophysiology of splanchnic hypoperfusion and intestinal injury during exercise: strategies for evaluation and prevention. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2012;303:G155&#x2013;G168. doi: 10.1152/ajpgi.00066.2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpgi.00066.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22517770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Wijck K, Lenaerts K, van Loon LJ, Peters WH, Buurman WA, Dejong CH. Exercise-induced splanchnic hypoperfusion results in gut dysfunction in healthy men. PLoS One. 2011;6:e22366. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0022366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0022366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3141050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21811592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup AE, Jentjens RL, Moseley L. Nutritional considerations in triathlon. Sports Med. 2005;35:163&#x2013;181. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200535020-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535020-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15707379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup AE. Training the gut for athletes. Sports Med. 2017;47:101&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0690-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0690-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5371619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan, C.J.; Axelrod, C.; Paul, D.; Hull, M.; Kirwan, J.P. Effects of a novel probiotic on exercise-induced gut permeability and microbiota in endurance athletes (abstract). In proceedings of American College of Sports Medicine, Minneapolis, MN.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasano A. Zonulin and its regulation of intestinal barrier function: the biological door to inflammation, autoimmunity, and cancer. Physiol Rev. 2011;91:151&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00003.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00003.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21248165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira EP, Burini RC. Food-dependent, exercise-induced gastrointestinal distress. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2011;8:12. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-8-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-8-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3190328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21955383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groschwitz KR, Hogan SP. Intestinal barrier function: molecular regulation and disease pathogenesis. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2009;124:3&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2009.05.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2009.05.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4266989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19560575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonier B, Patrick C, Ajjikuttira P, Scott FW. Intestinal immune regulation as a potential diet-modifiable feature of gut inflammation and autoimmunity. Int Rev Immunol. 2009;28:414&#x2013;445. doi: 10.3109/08830180903208329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/08830180903208329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19954357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup AE, Vet-Joop K, Sturk A, Stegen JH, Senden J, Saris WH, Wagenmakers AJ. Relationship between gastro-intestinal complaints and endotoxaemia, cytokine release and the acute-phase reaction during and after a long-distance triathlon in highly trained men. Clin Sci (Lond) 2000;98:47&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1042/cs0980047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0980047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10600658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid G. Probiotics: definition, scope and mechanisms of action. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2016;30:17&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/j.bpg.2015.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpg.2015.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27048893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langa S, Martin-Cabrejas I, Montiel R, Landete JM, Medina M, Arques JL. Short communication: combined antimicrobial activity of reuterin and diacetyl against foodborne pathogens. J Dairy Sci. 2014;97:6116&#x2013;6121. doi: 10.3168/jds.2014-8306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2014-8306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25087026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velraeds MM, van de Belt-Gritter B, van der Mei HC, Reid G, Busscher HJ. Interference in initial adhesion of uropathogenic bacteria and yeasts to silicone rubber by a Lactobacillus acidophilus biosurfactant. J Med Microbiol. 1998;47:1081&#x2013;1085. doi: 10.1099/00222615-47-12-1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/00222615-47-12-1081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9856644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermudez-Brito M, Plaza-Diaz J, Munoz-Quezada S, Gomez-Llorente C, Gil A. Probiotic mechanisms of action. Ann Nutr Metab. 2012;61:160&#x2013;174. doi: 10.1159/000342079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000342079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23037511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohland CL, Macnaughton WK. Probiotic bacteria and intestinal epithelial barrier function. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2010;298:G807&#x2013;G819. doi: 10.1152/ajpgi.00243.2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpgi.00243.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20299599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper LV, Stappenbeck TS, Hong CV, Gordon JI. Angiogenins: a new class of microbicidal proteins involved in innate immunity. Nat Immunol. 2003;4:269&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1038/ni888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ni888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12548285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper LV, Wong MH, Thelin A, Hansson L, Falk PG, Gordon JI. Molecular analysis of commensal host-microbial relationships in the intestine. Science. 2001;291:881&#x2013;884. doi: 10.1126/science.291.5505.881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.291.5505.881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11157169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson RC, Cookson AL, McNabb WC, Park Z, McCann MJ, Kelly WJ, Roy NC. Lactobacillus plantarum MB452 enhances the function of the intestinal barrier by increasing the expression levels of genes involved in tight junction formation. BMC Microbiol. 2010;10:316. doi: 10.1186/1471-2180-10-316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2180-10-316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3004893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21143932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mack DR, Ahrne S, Hyde L, Wei S, Hollingsworth MA. Extracellular MUC3 mucin secretion follows adherence of Lactobacillus strains to intestinal epithelial cells in vitro. Gut. 2003;52:827&#x2013;833. doi: 10.1136/gut.52.6.827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gut.52.6.827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1773687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12740338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattar AF, Teitelbaum DH, Drongowski RA, Yongyi F, Harmon CM, Coran AG. Probiotics up-regulate MUC-2 mucin gene expression in a Caco-2 cell-culture model. Pediatr Surg Int. 2002;18:586&#x2013;590. doi: 10.1007/s00383-002-0855-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00383-002-0855-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12471471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuhl M, Schneider S, Lanphere K, Conn C, Dokladny K, Moseley P. Exercise regulation of intestinal tight junction proteins. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:980&#x2013;986. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2012-091585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn MG, McFarlin BK. Toll-like receptor 4: link to the anti-inflammatory effects of exercise? Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2006;34:176&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1249/01.jes.0000240027.22749.14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.jes.0000240027.22749.14</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17031256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuempfle KJ, Valentino T, Hew-Butler T, Hecht FM, Hoffman MD. Nausea is associated with endotoxemia during a 161-km ultramarathon. J Sports Sci. 1662;2016:34. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2015.1130238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1130238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26707127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munford RS. Sensing gram-negative bacterial lipopolysaccharides: a human disease determinant? Infect Immun. 2008;76:454&#x2013;465. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00939-07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.00939-07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2223455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18086818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mach N, Fuster-Botella D. Endurnace exercise and gut microbiota: a review. J Sport Health Sci. 2017;6:179&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/j.jshs.2016.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2016.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6188999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lescheid D. Probiotics as regulators of inflammation: a review. Functional Foods in Health and Disease. 2014;4:299&#x2013;311. doi: 10.31989/ffhd.v4i7.2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31989/ffhd.v4i7.2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnini C, Saeed R, Bamias G, Arseneau KO, Pizarro TT, Cominelli F. Probiotics promote gut health through stimulation of epithelial innate immunity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107:454&#x2013;459. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0910307107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0910307107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2806692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20018654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karczewski J, Troost FJ, Konings I, Dekker J, Kleerebezem M, Brummer RJ, Wells JM. Regulation of human epithelial tight junction proteins by Lactobacillus plantarum in vivo and protective effects on the epithelial barrier. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2010;298:G851&#x2013;G859. doi: 10.1152/ajpgi.00327.2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpgi.00327.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20224007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cario E, Gerken G, Podolsky DK. Toll-like receptor 2 controls mucosal inflammation by regulating epithelial barrier function. Gastroenterology. 2007;132:1359&#x2013;1374. doi: 10.1053/j.gastro.2007.02.056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2007.02.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17408640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdigon G, Maldonado Galdeano C, Valdez JC, Medici M. Interaction of lactic acid bacteria with the gut immune system. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2002;56(Suppl 4):S21&#x2013;S26. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12556943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffrin EJ, Brassart D, Servin AL, Rochat F, Donnet-Hughes A. Immune modulation of blood leukocytes in humans by lactic acid bacteria: criteria for strain selection. Am J Clin Nutr. 1997;66:515S&#x2013;520S. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/66.2.515S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/66.2.515S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9250141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano J, Yoshida T, Sugiyama T, Koide N, Mori I, Yokochi T. The effect of Lactobacillus rhamnosus on enterohemorrhagic Escherichia coli infection of human intestinal cells in vitro. Microbiol Immunol. 2003;47:405&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1111/j.1348-0421.2003.tb03377.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1348-0421.2003.tb03377.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12906100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YS, Ho SB. Intestinal goblet cells and mucins in health and disease: recent insights and progress. Curr Gastroenterol Rep. 2010;12:319&#x2013;330. doi: 10.1007/s11894-010-0131-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11894-010-0131-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20703838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayabe T, Satchell DP, Wilson CL, Parks WC, Selsted ME, Ouellette AJ. Secretion of microbicidal alpha-defensins by intestinal Paneth cells in response to bacteria. Nat Immunol. 2000;1:113&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1038/77783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/77783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11248802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostaff MJ, Stange EF, Wehkamp J. Antimicrobial peptides and gut microbiota in homeostasis and pathology. EMBO Mol Med. 2013;5:1465&#x2013;1483. doi: 10.1002/emmm.201201773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/emmm.201201773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24039130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furrie E, Macfarlane S, Kennedy A, Cummings JH, Walsh SV, O'Neil DA, Macfarlane GT. Synbiotic therapy (Bifidobacterium longum/Synergy 1) initiates resolution of inflammation in patients with active ulcerative colitis: a randomised controlled pilot trial. Gut. 2005;54:242&#x2013;249. doi: 10.1136/gut.2004.044834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gut.2004.044834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1774839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15647189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Servin AL. Antagonistic activities of lactobacilli and bifidobacteria against microbial pathogens. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2004;28:405&#x2013;440. doi: 10.1016/j.femsre.2004.01.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.femsre.2004.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15374659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenoll E, Casinos B, Bataller E, Astals P, Echevarria J, Iglesias JR, Balbarie P, Ramon D, Genoves S. Novel probiotic Bifidobacterium bifidum CECT 7366 strain active against the pathogenic bacterium helicobacter pylori. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2011;77:1335&#x2013;1343. doi: 10.1128/AEM.01820-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.01820-10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3067243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21169430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu H, Kang S, Ha S, Cho K, Park SM, Han KH, Kang SK, Lee H, Han SH, Yun CH, et al. Lactobacillus acidophilus expressing recombinant K99 adhesive fimbriae has an inhibitory effect on adhesion of enterotoxigenic Escherichia coli. Microbiol Immunol. 2005;49:941&#x2013;948. doi: 10.1111/j.1348-0421.2005.tb03687.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1348-0421.2005.tb03687.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16301804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz JA, Chenoll E, Casinos B, Bataller E, Ramon D, Genoves S, Montava R, Ribes JM, Buesa J, Fabrega J, et al. Novel probiotic Bifidobacterium longum subsp. infantis CECT 7210 strain active against rotavirus infections. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2011;77:8775&#x2013;8783. doi: 10.1128/AEM.05548-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.05548-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3233071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22003027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sgouras D, Maragkoudakis P, Petraki K, Martinez-Gonzalez B, Eriotou E, Michopoulos S, Kalantzopoulos G, Tsakalidou E, Mentis A. In vitro and in vivo inhibition of helicobacter pylori by Lactobacillus casei strain Shirota. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2004;70:518&#x2013;526. doi: 10.1128/AEM.70.1.518-526.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.70.1.518-526.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC321236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14711683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todoriki K, Mukai T, Sato S, Toba T. Inhibition of adhesion of food-borne pathogens to Caco-2 cells by Lactobacillus strains. J Appl Microbiol. 2001;91:154&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2672.2001.01371.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2672.2001.01371.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11442725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai CC, Lin PP, Hsieh YM. Three Lactobacillus strains from healthy infant stool inhibit enterotoxigenic Escherichia coli grown in vitro. Anaerobe. 2008;14:61&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1016/j.anaerobe.2007.11.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anaerobe.2007.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18182312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura S, Kuda T, An C, Kanno T, Takahashi H, Kimura B. Inhibitory effects of Leuconostoc mesenteroides 1RM3 isolated from narezushi, a fermented fish with rice, on listeria monocytogenes infection to Caco-2 cells and a/J mice. Anaerobe. 2012;18:19&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/j.anaerobe.2011.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anaerobe.2011.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22193553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffrin EJ, Blum S. Interactions between the microbiota and the intestinal mucosa. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2002;56(Suppl 3):S60&#x2013;S64. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12142966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara S, Hashiba H, Hirota T, Forstner JF. Inhibition of the binding of enterotoxigenic Escherichia coli Pb176 to human intestinal epithelial cell line HCT-8 by an extracellular protein fraction containing BIF of Bifidobacterium longum SBT2928: suggestive evidence of blocking of the binding receptor gangliotetraosylceramide on the cell surface. Int J Food Microbiol. 2001;67:97&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1016/S0168-1605(01)00432-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0168-1605(01)00432-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11482574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeser JR, Granato D, Rouvet M, Servin A, Teneberg S, Karlsson KA. Lactobacillus johnsonii La1 shares carbohydrate-binding specificities with several enteropathogenic bacteria. Glycobiology. 2000;10:1193&#x2013;1199. doi: 10.1093/glycob/10.11.1193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/glycob/10.11.1193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11087711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukai T, Asasaka T, Sato E, Mori K, Matsumoto M, Ohori H. Inhibition of binding of helicobacter pylori to the glycolipid receptors by probiotic Lactobacillus reuteri. FEMS Immunol Med Microbiol. 2002;32:105&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1111/j.1574-695X.2002.tb00541.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1574-695X.2002.tb00541.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11821231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coconnier MH, Bernet MF, Chauviere G, Servin AL. Adhering heat-killed human Lactobacillus acidophilus, strain LB, inhibits the process of pathogenicity of diarrhoeagenic bacteria in cultured human intestinal cells. J Diarrhoeal Dis Res. 1993;11:235&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8188996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinov SR, Kuipers EJ, Peppelenbosch MP. Functional genomic analyses of the gut microbiota for CRC screening. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2013;10:741&#x2013;745. doi: 10.1038/nrgastro.2013.178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrgastro.2013.178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24042452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberg TS, Steele JL, Ingham SC, Smeianov VV, Briczinski EP, Abdalla A, Broadbent JR. Intrinsic and inducible resistance to hydrogen peroxide in Bifidobacterium species. J Ind Microbiol Biotechnol. 1947;2011:38. doi: 10.1007/s10295-011-0983-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10295-011-0983-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21626209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsilingiri K, Rescigno M. Postbiotics: what else? Benefic Microbes. 2013;4:101&#x2013;107. doi: 10.3920/BM2012.0046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2012.0046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23271068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma M, Shukla G. Metabiotics: one step ahead of probiotics; an insight into mechanisms involved in Anticancerous effect in colorectal Cancer. Front Microbiol. 1940;2016:7. doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2016.01940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2016.01940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5133260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27994577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenderov BA. Metabiotics: novel idea or natural development of probiotic conception. Microb Ecol Health Dis. 2013;24. 10.3402/mehd.v24i0.20399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3747726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23990841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canfora EE, Jocken JW, Blaak EE. Short-chain fatty acids in control of body weight and insulin sensitivity. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2015;11:577&#x2013;591. doi: 10.1038/nrendo.2015.128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrendo.2015.128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26260141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura I, Ozawa K, Inoue D, Imamura T, Kimura K, Maeda T, Terasawa K, Kashihara D, Hirano K, Tani T, et al. The gut microbiota suppresses insulin-mediated fat accumulation via the short-chain fatty acid receptor GPR43. Nat Commun. 1829;2013:4. doi: 10.1038/ncomms2852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms2852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3674247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23652017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Besten G, van Eunen K, Groen AK, Venema K, Reijngoud DJ, Bakker BM. The role of short-chain fatty acids in the interplay between diet, gut microbiota, and host energy metabolism. J Lipid Res. 2013;54:2325&#x2013;2340. doi: 10.1194/jlr.R036012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1194/jlr.R036012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3735932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23821742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kullisaar T, Zilmer M, Mikelsaar M, Vihalemm T, Annuk H, Kairane C, Kilk A. Two antioxidative lactobacilli strains as promising probiotics. Int J Food Microbiol. 2002;72:215&#x2013;224. doi: 10.1016/S0168-1605(01)00674-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0168-1605(01)00674-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11845820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin MY, Chang FJ. Antioxidative effect of intestinal bacteria Bifidobacterium longum ATCC 15708 and Lactobacillus acidophilus ATCC 4356. Dig Dis Sci. 1617;2000:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11007114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saide JA, Gilliland SE. Antioxidative activity of lactobacilli measured by oxygen radical absorbance capacity. J Dairy Sci. 2005;88:1352&#x2013;1357. doi: 10.3168/jds.S0022-0302(05)72801-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.S0022-0302(05)72801-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15778302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coqueiro AY, de Oliveira Garcia AB, Rogero MM, Tirapegui J. Probiotic supplementation in sports and physical exercise: does it present any ergogenic effect? Nutr Health. 2017;23:239&#x2013;249. doi: 10.1177/0260106017721000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0260106017721000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari V, Hendijani F. Effects of probiotic supplementation in patients with type 2 diabetes: systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutr Rev. 2016;74:774&#x2013;784. doi: 10.1093/nutrit/nuw039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nutrit/nuw039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27864537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan Y, Sun J, He J, Chen F, Chen R, Chen H. Effect of probiotics on glycemic control: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized, Controlled Trials. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0132121. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0132121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0132121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4498615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26161741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alakomi HL, Skytta E, Saarela M, Mattila-Sandholm T, Latva-Kala K, Helander IM. Lactic acid permeabilizes gram-negative bacteria by disrupting the outer membrane. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2001;2000:66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10788373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Keersmaecker SC, Verhoeven TL, Desair J, Marchal K, Vanderleyden J, Nagy I. Strong antimicrobial activity of Lactobacillus rhamnosus GG against Salmonella typhimurium is due to accumulation of lactic acid. FEMS Microbiol Lett. 2006;259:89&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1111/j.1574-6968.2006.00250.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6968.2006.00250.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16684107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makras L, Triantafyllou V, Fayol-Messaoudi D, Adriany T, Zoumpopoulou G, Tsakalidou E, Servin A, De Vuyst L. Kinetic analysis of the antibacterial activity of probiotic lactobacilli towards Salmonella enterica serovar typhimurium reveals a role for lactic acid and other inhibitory compounds. Res Microbiol. 2006;157:241&#x2013;247. doi: 10.1016/j.resmic.2005.09.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resmic.2005.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16266797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell JB, Diez-Gonzalez F. The effects of fermentation acids on bacterial growth. Adv Microb Physiol. 1998;39:205&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1016/S0065-2911(08)60017-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-2911(08)60017-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9328648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macouzet M, Lee BH, Robert N. Production of conjugated linoleic acid by probiotic Lactobacillus acidophilus La-5. J Appl Microbiol. 1886;2009:106. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2672.2009.04164.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.2009.04164.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Shea EF, Cotter PD, Stanton C, Ross RP, Hill C. Production of bioactive substances by intestinal bacteria as a basis for explaining probiotic mechanisms: bacteriocins and conjugated linoleic acid. Int J Food Microbiol. 2012;152:189&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2011.05.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2011.05.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21742394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K, Paek K, Lee HY, Park JH, Lee Y. Antiobesity effect of trans-10,cis-12-conjugated linoleic acid-producing Lactobacillus plantarum PL62 on diet-induced obese mice. J Appl Microbiol. 2007;103:1140&#x2013;1146. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2672.2007.03336.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.2007.03336.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17897219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC, Henson DA, Austin MD, Sha W. Upper respiratory tract infection is reduced in physically fit and active adults. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:987&#x2013;992. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2010.077875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2010.077875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21041243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M, Bishop NC. URI in athletes: are mucosal immunity and cytokine responses key risk factors? Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2013;41:148&#x2013;153. doi: 10.1097/JES.0b013e3182956ead.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JES.0b013e3182956ead</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23792489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP. Recommendations to maintain immune health in athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18:820&#x2013;831. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2018.1449895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1449895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29637836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Gleeson M, Shephard RJ, Gleeson M, Woods JA, Bishop NC, Fleshner M, Green C, Pedersen BK, Hoffman-Goetz L, et al. Position statement. Part one: Immune function and exercise. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2011;17:6&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21446352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Llorente C, Munoz S, Gil A. Role of toll-like receptors in the development of immunotolerance mediated by probiotics. Proc Nutr Soc. 2010;69:381&#x2013;389. doi: 10.1017/S0029665110001527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0029665110001527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20416121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebeer S, Vanderleyden J, De Keersmaecker SC. Host interactions of probiotic bacterial surface molecules: comparison with commensals and pathogens. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2010;8:171&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1038/nrmicro2297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrmicro2297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20157338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermon S, Petriz B, Kajeniene A, Prestes J, Castell L, Franco OL. The microbiota: an exercise immunology perspective. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2015;21:70&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25825908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster GI, Halson SL, Khan Q, Drysdale P, Wallace F, Jeukendrup AE, Drayson MT, Gleeson M. Effects of acute exhaustive exercise and chronic exercise training on type 1 and type 2 T lymphocytes. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2004;10:91&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15633589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin SA, Pence BD, Woods JA. Exercise and respiratory tract viral infections. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2009;37:157&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1097/JES.0b013e3181b7b57b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JES.0b013e3181b7b57b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2803113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19955864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jager R, Purpura M, Farmer S, Cash HA, Keller D. Probiotic Bacillus coagulans GBI-30, 6086 improves protein absorption and utilization. Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins. 2018;10:611&#x2013;615. doi: 10.1007/s12602-017-9354-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12602-017-9354-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6208742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29196920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller D, Van Dinter R, Cash H, Farmer S, Venema K. Bacillus coagulans GBI-30, 6086 increases plant protein digestion in a dynamic, computer-controlled in vitro model of the small intestine (TIM-1) Benefic Microbes. 2017;8:491&#x2013;496. doi: 10.3920/BM2016.0196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2016.0196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28504581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley JD, Thomson RL, Coates AM, Howe PR, DeNichilo MO, Rowney MK. Supplementation with a whey protein hydrolysate enhances recovery of muscle force-generating capacity following eccentric exercise. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13:178&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2008.06.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2008.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18768358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton D, Williams C, Brown A. Impact of consuming a milk drink containing a probiotic on mood and cognition. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2007;61:355&#x2013;361. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17151594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Simone Claudio. The Unregulated Probiotic Market. Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology. 2019;17(5):809&#x2013;817. doi: 10.1016/j.cgh.2018.01.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2018.01.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29378309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Gastroenterology Organisation. Global Guidelines: Probiotics and Prebiotics. World Gastroentereology Oganisation. Milwaukee; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders ME, Akkermans LM, Haller D, Hammerman C, Heimbach J, Hormannsperger G, Huys G, Levy DD, Lutgendorff F, Mack D, et al. Safety assessment of probiotics for human use. Gut Microbes. 2010;1:164&#x2013;185. doi: 10.4161/gmic.1.3.12127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/gmic.1.3.12127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21327023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marteau P. Safety aspects of probiotic products. Naringsforskning. 2001;45:22&#x2013;24. doi: 10.3402/fnr.v45i0.1785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3402/fnr.v45i0.1785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesaro C, Tiso A, Del Prete A, Cariello R, Tuccillo C, Cotticelli G, Del Vecchio Blanco C, Loguercio C. Gut microbiota and probiotics in chronic liver diseases. Dig Liver Dis. 2011;43:431&#x2013;438. doi: 10.1016/j.dld.2010.10.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dld.2010.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21163715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besselink MG, van Santvoort HC, Buskens E, Boermeester MA, van Goor H, Timmerman HM, Nieuwenhuijs VB, Bollen TL, van Ramshorst B, Witteman BJ, et al. Probiotic prophylaxis in predicted severe acute pancreatitis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2008;371:651&#x2013;659. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(08)60207-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(08)60207-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders ME, Merenstein DJ, Ouwehand AC, Reid G, Salminen S, Cabana MD, Paraskevakos G, Leyer G. Probiotic use in at-risk populations. J Am Pharm Assoc (2003) 2016;56:680&#x2013;686. doi: 10.1016/j.japh.2016.07.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.japh.2016.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27836128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallabhaneni S, Walker TA, Lockhart SR, Ng D, Chiller T, Melchreit R, Brandt ME, Smith RM. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, see https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/preview/mmwrhtml/mm6406a6.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA. New Dietary Ingredients Notification Process. Washington; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didari T, Solki S, Mozaffari S, Nikfar S, Abdollahi M. A systematic review of the safety of probiotics. Expert Opin Drug Saf. 2014;13:227&#x2013;239. doi: 10.1517/14740338.2014.872627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/14740338.2014.872627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24405164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle RJ, Robins-Browne RM, Tang ML. Probiotic use in clinical practice: what are the risks? Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;83:1256&#x2013;1264. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/83.6.1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/83.6.1256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16762934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapiovaara L, Lehtoranta L, Poussa T, Makivuokko H, Korpela R, Pitkaranta A. Absence of adverse events in healthy individuals using probiotics--analysis of six randomised studies by one study group. Benefic Microbes. 2016;7:161&#x2013;169. doi: 10.3920/BM2015.0096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2015.0096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen CN, Nielsen S, Kaestel P, Brockmann E, Bennedsen M, Christensen HR, Eskesen DC, Jacobsen BL, Michaelsen KF. Dose-response study of probiotic bacteria Bifidobacterium animalis subsp lactis BB-12 and Lactobacillus paracasei subsp paracasei CRL-341 in healthy young adults. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2006;60:1284&#x2013;1293. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16721394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford Alexander C, Quigley Eamonn M M, Lacy Brian E, Lembo Anthony J, Saito Yuri A, Schiller Lawrence R, Soffer Edy E, Spiegel Brennan M R, Moayyedi Paul. Efficacy of Prebiotics, Probiotics, and Synbiotics in Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Chronic Idiopathic Constipation: Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. American Journal of Gastroenterology. 2014;109(10):1547&#x2013;1561. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2014.202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ajg.2014.202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25070051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro Ros&#xe1;rio, Azevedo Isabel. Chronic Inflammation in Obesity and the Metabolic Syndrome. Mediators of Inflammation. 2010;2010:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1155/2010/289645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2010/289645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2913796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20706689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations and World Health Organization . Joint FAO/WHO working group report on drafting guidelines fro the evaluation of probiotics in food. 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada. Natural Health Products Ingredients Database: Probiotics. Availabe online: http://webprod.hc-sc.gc.ca/nhpid-bdipsn/atReq.do?atid=probio&amp;lang=eng (accessed on Oct 23).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorzela L, Ardestani SK, McFarland LV, Vohra S. Is there a role for modified probiotics as beneficial microbes: a systematic review of the literature. Benefic Microbes. 2017;8:739&#x2013;754. doi: 10.3920/BM2017.0032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2017.0032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28884589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada. Licensed Natural Health Products Database. 2019. . Availabe online: https://health-products.canada.ca/lnhpd-bdpsnh/index-eng.jsp (accessed on Oct 23).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora M, Baldi A. Regulatory categories of probiotics across the globe: a review representing existing and recommended categorization. Indian J Med Microbiol. 2015;33(Suppl):2&#x2013;10. doi: 10.4103/0255-0857.150868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0255-0857.150868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25657150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amagase H. Current marketplace for probiotics: a Japanese perspective. Clin Infect Dis. 2008;46(Suppl 2):S73&#x2013;S75. doi: 10.1086/523338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/523338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18181727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Food Standards Agency. Qualified Presumption of Safety. Available from: http://www.efsa.europa.eu/en/topics/topic/qualified-presumption-safety-qps. Access date: 10 Aug 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolacek S, Hojsak I, Berni Canani R, Guarino A, Indrio F, Orel R, Pot B, Shamir R, Szajewska H, Vandenplas Y, et al. Commercial probiotic products: a call for improved quality control. A position paper by the ESPGHAN working Group for Probiotics and Prebiotics. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2017;65:117&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1097/MPG.0000000000001603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0000000000001603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28644359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIH. Probiotics: In Depth. https://nccih.nih.gov/health/probiotics/introduction.htm. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giordano-Schaefer, J.; Ruthsatz, M.; Schneider, H. Overcoming distinctive regulatory barriers for the development of medical foods. Availabe online: https://www.raps.org/regulatory-focus%E2%84%A2/news-articles/2017/10/overcoming-distinctive-regulatory-barriers-for-the-development-of-medical-foods (Accessed on Oct 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kullen MJ, Amann MM, O'Shaughnessy MJ, O'Sullivan DJ, Busta FF, Brady LJ. Differentiation of ingested and endogenous bifidobacteria by DNA fingerprinting demonstrates the survival of an unmodified strain in the gastrointestinal tract of humans. J Nutr. 1997;127:89&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1093/jn/127.1.89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/127.1.89</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9040550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poutahidis T, Springer A, Levkovich T, Qi P, Varian BJ, Lakritz JR, Ibrahim YM, Chatzigiagkos A, Alm EJ, Erdman SE. Probiotic microbes sustain youthful serum testosterone levels and testicular size in aging mice. PLoS One. 2014;9:e84877. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0084877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0084877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24392159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyte M. Probiotics function mechanistically as delivery vehicles for neuroactive compounds: microbial endocrinology in the design and use of probiotics. Bioessays. 2011;33:574&#x2013;581. doi: 10.1002/bies.201100024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bies.201100024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21732396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bravo JA, Forsythe P, Chew MV, Escaravage E, Savignac HM, Dinan TG, Bienenstock J, Cryan JF. Ingestion of Lactobacillus strain regulates emotional behavior and central GABA receptor expression in a mouse via the vagus nerve. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:16050&#x2013;16055. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1102999108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1102999108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3179073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21876150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenbergen L, Sellaro R, van Hemert S, Bosch JA, Colzato LS. A randomized controlled trial to test the effect of multispecies probiotics on cognitive reactivity to sad mood. Brain Behav Immun. 2015;48:258&#x2013;264. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2015.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2015.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25862297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Yun JM, Kim MK, Kwon O, Cho B. Lactobacillus gasseri BNR17 supplementation reduces the visceral fat accumulation and waist circumference in obese adults: a randomized, double-blind, Placebo-Controlled Trial. J Med Food. 2018;21:454&#x2013;461. doi: 10.1089/jmf.2017.3937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jmf.2017.3937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29688793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez M, Darimont C, Drapeau V, Emady-Azar S, Lepage M, Rezzonico E, Ngom-Bru C, Berger B, Philippe L, Ammon-Zuffrey C, et al. Effect of Lactobacillus rhamnosus CGMCC1.3724 supplementation on weight loss and maintenance in obese men and women. Br J Nutr. 2014;111:1507&#x2013;1519. doi: 10.1017/S0007114513003875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114513003875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24299712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauchard GC, Gangloff P, Vouriot A, Mallie JP, Perrin PP. Effects of exercise-induced fatigue with and without hydration on static postural control in adult human subjects. Int J Neurosci. 2002;112:1191&#x2013;1206. doi: 10.1080/00207450290026157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00207450290026157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12587522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green H, Halestrap A, Mockett C, O'Toole D, Grant S, Ouyang J. Increases in muscle MCT are associated with reductions in muscle lactate after a single exercise session in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2002;282:E154&#x2013;E160. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.2002.282.1.E154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.2002.282.1.E154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11739096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson RM, Saunders B, Ball G, Harris RC, Sale C. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on exercise performance: a meta-analysis. Amino Acids. 2012;43:25&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1007/s00726-011-1200-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-011-1200-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22270875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks SP, Storey KB. A quantitative evaluation of the effect of enzyme complexes on the glycolytic rate in vivo: mathematical modeling of the glycolytic complex. J Theor Biol. 1991;149:361&#x2013;375. doi: 10.1016/S0022-5193(05)80311-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-5193(05)80311-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2062101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan SH, Louis P, Flint HJ. Lactate-utilizing bacteria, isolated from human feces, that produce butyrate as a major fermentation product. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2004;70:5810&#x2013;5817. doi: 10.1128/AEM.70.10.5810-5817.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.70.10.5810-5817.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC522113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15466518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu Yi-Ju, Huang Wen-Ching, Lin Jin-Seng, Chen Yi-Ming, Ho Shang-Tse, Huang Chi-Chang, Tung Yu-Tang. Kefir Supplementation Modifies Gut Microbiota Composition, Reduces Physical Fatigue, and Improves Exercise Performance in Mice. Nutrients. 2018;10(7):862. doi: 10.3390/nu10070862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10070862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6073576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29973525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ANVISA-Ministry of Health . Technical Regulation of Bioeactive and Probiotic Substances Isolated with Allegations of Functional or Health Properties. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministerio della Salute . Linee guida su probiotici e prebioticic. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Asmakh M, Stukenborg JB, Reda A, Anuar F, Strand ML, Hedin L, Pettersson S, Soder O. The gut microbiota and developmental programming of the testis in mice. PLoS One. 2014;9:e103809. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0103809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0103809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4132106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25118984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada N, Hanaoka R, Horiuchi H, Kitakaze T, Mitani T, Inui H, Yamaji R. Castration influences intestinal microflora and induces abdominal obesity in high-fat diet-fed mice. Sci Rep. 2016;6:23001. doi: 10.1038/srep23001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep23001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26961573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim HA, Zhu Y, Wu C, Lu C, Ezekwe MO, Liao SF, Huang K. Selenium-enriched probiotics improves murine male fertility compromised by high fat diet. Biol Trace Elem Res. 2012;147:251&#x2013;260. doi: 10.1007/s12011-011-9308-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12011-011-9308-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22207218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Yang W, Hostetler A, Schultz N, Suckow MA, Stewart KL, Kim DD, Kim HS. Characterization of the anti-inflammatory Lactobacillus reuteri BM36301 and its probiotic benefits on aged mice. BMC Microbiol. 2016;16:69. doi: 10.1186/s12866-016-0686-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12866-016-0686-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4837529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27095067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMullen MH, Hamilton-Reeves JM, Bonorden MJ, Wangen KE, Phipps WR, Feirtag JM, Kurzer MS. Consumption of Lactobacillus acidophilus and Bifidobacterium longum does not alter phytoestrogen metabolism and plasma hormones in men: a pilot study. J Altern Complement Med. 2006;12:887&#x2013;894. doi: 10.1089/acm.2006.12.887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/acm.2006.12.887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17109580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maretti C, Cavallini G. The association of a probiotic with a prebiotic (Flortec, Bracco) to improve the quality/quantity of spermatozoa in infertile patients with idiopathic oligoasthenoteratospermia: a pilot study. Andrology. 2017;5:439&#x2013;444. doi: 10.1111/andr.12336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/andr.12336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28245352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremellen K. Gut endotoxin leading to a decline IN gonadal function (GELDING) - a novel theory for the development of late onset hypogonadism in obese men. Basic Clin Androl. 2016;26:7. doi: 10.1186/s12610-016-0034-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12610-016-0034-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4918028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27340554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremellen K, McPhee N, Pearce K. Metabolic endotoxaemia related inflammation is associated with hypogonadism in overweight men. Basic Clin Androl. 2017;27:5. doi: 10.1186/s12610-017-0049-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12610-017-0049-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5341351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28286655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremellen K, McPhee N, Pearce K, Benson S, Schedlowski M, Engler H. Endotoxin-initiated inflammation reduces testosterone production in men of reproductive age. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2018;314:E206&#x2013;E213. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00279.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00279.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5899218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29183872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lorenzo Antonino, Noce Annalisa, Moriconi Eleonora, Rampello Tiziana, Marrone Giulia, Di Daniele Nicola, Rovella Valentina. MOSH Syndrome (Male Obesity Secondary Hypogonadism): Clinical Assessment and Possible Therapeutic Approaches. Nutrients. 2018;10(4):474. doi: 10.3390/nu10040474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10040474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5946259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29649106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piqu&#xe9; N&#xfa;ria, Berlanga Mercedes, Mi&#xf1;ana-Galbis David. Health Benefits of Heat-Killed (Tyndallized) Probiotics: An Overview. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 2019;20(10):2534. doi: 10.3390/ijms20102534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20102534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6566317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31126033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komano Y, Shimada K, Naito H, Fukao K, Ishihara Y, Fujii T, Kokubo T, Daida H. Efficacy of heat-killed Lactococcus lactis JCM 5805 on immunity and fatigue during consecutive high intensity exercise in male athletes: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blinded trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15:39. doi: 10.1186/s12970-018-0244-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-018-0244-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30071871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalman D, Hewlings S. Inactivated probiotic Bacillus coagulans GBI-30 demonstrates Immunosupportive properties in healthy adults following stressful exercise. J Probiotics and Health. 2018;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taverniti V, Guglielmetti S. The immunomodulatory properties of probiotic microorganisms beyond their viability (ghost probiotics: proposal of paraprobiotic concept) Genes Nutr. 2011;6:261&#x2013;274. doi: 10.1007/s12263-011-0218-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12263-011-0218-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3145061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21499799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshpande Girish, Athalye-Jape Gayatri, Patole Sanjay. Para-probiotics for Preterm Neonates&#x2014;The Next Frontier. Nutrients. 2018;10(7):871. doi: 10.3390/nu10070871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10070871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6073938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29976885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugahara H, Yao R, Odamaki T, Xiao JZ. Differences between live and heat-killed bifidobacteria in the regulation of immune function and the intestinal environment. Benefic Microbes. 2017;8:463&#x2013;472. doi: 10.3920/BM2016.0158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2016.0158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28441886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burta Ovidiu, Iacobescu Claudia, Mateescu Radu Bogdan, Nicolaie Tudor, Tiuca Nicoleta, Pop Corina Silvia. Efficacy and safety of APT036 versus simethicone in the treatment of functional bloating: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, parallel group, clinical study. Translational Gastroenterology and Hepatology. 2018;3:72&#x2013;72. doi: 10.21037/tgh.2018.09.11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/tgh.2018.09.11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6256934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30511026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenplas Y, Bacarea A, Marusteri M, Bacarea V, Constantin M, Manolache M. Efficacy and safety of APT198K for the treatment of infantile colic: a pilot study. J Comp Eff Res. 2017;6:137&#x2013;144. doi: 10.2217/cer-2016-0059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cer-2016-0059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28114795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirose Y, Yamamoto Y, Yoshikai Y, Murosaki S. Oral intake of heat-killed Lactobacillus plantarum L-137 decreases the incidence of upper respiratory tract infection in healthy subjects with high levels of psychological stress. J Nutr Sci. 2013;2:e39. doi: 10.1017/jns.2013.35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/jns.2013.35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4153334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25191589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arimori Yojiro, Nakamura Risa, Hirose Yoshitaka, Murosaki Shinji, Yamamoto Yoshihiro, Shidara Osamu, Ichikawa Hiroshi, Yoshikai Yasunobu. Daily intake of heat-killedLactobacillus plantarumL-137 enhances type I interferon production in healthy humans and pigs. Immunopharmacology and Immunotoxicology. 2012;34(6):937&#x2013;943. doi: 10.3109/08923973.2012.672425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/08923973.2012.672425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22468623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada Daisuke, Kuwano Yuki, Tanaka Hiroki, Hara Susumu, Uchiyama Yoshihide, Sugawara Tomonori, Fujiwara Shigeru, Rokutan Kazuhito, Nishida Kensei. Daily intake of Lactobacillus gasseri CP2305 relieves fatigue and stress-related symptoms in male university Ekiden runners: A double-blind, randomized, and placebo-controlled clinical trial. Journal of Functional Foods. 2019;57:465&#x2013;476. doi: 10.1016/j.jff.2019.04.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2019.04.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida K, Sawadab D, Kuwanoa Y, Tanakaa H, Sugawarab T, Aokib Y, Fujiwarab S, Rokutana K. Daily administration of paraprobiotic Lactobacillus gasseri CP2305 ameliorates chronic stress-associated symptoms in Japanese medical students. J Funct Foods. 2017;36:112&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1016/j.jff.2017.06.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2017.06.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrich MJ. Depression is the leading cause of disability around the world. JAMA. 2017;317:1517. doi: 10.1001/jama.2017.3826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.3826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28418490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes M, Kubera M, Leunis JC, Berk M, Geffard M, Bosmans E. In depression, bacterial translocation may drive inflammatory responses, oxidative and nitrosative stress (O&amp;NS), and autoimmune responses directed against O&amp;NS-damaged neoepitopes. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2013;127:344&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0447.2012.01908.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0447.2012.01908.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22900942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke G, Grenham S, Scully P, Fitzgerald P, Moloney RD, Shanahan F, Dinan TG, Cryan JF. The microbiome-gut-brain axis during early life regulates the hippocampal serotonergic system in a sex-dependent manner. Mol Psychiatry. 2013;18:666&#x2013;673. doi: 10.1038/mp.2012.77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2012.77</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22688187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitetta L, Bambling M, Alford H. The gastrointestinal tract microbiome, probiotics, and mood. Inflammopharmacology. 2014;22:333&#x2013;339. doi: 10.1007/s10787-014-0216-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10787-014-0216-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25266952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao AV, Bested AC, Beaulne TM, Katzman MA, Iorio C, Berardi JM, Logan AC. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot study of a probiotic in emotional symptoms of chronic fatigue syndrome. Gut Pathog. 2009;1:6. doi: 10.1186/1757-4749-1-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1757-4749-1-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2664325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19338686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messaoudi M, Lalonde R, Violle N, Javelot H, Desor D, Nejdi A, Bisson JF, Rougeot C, Pichelin M, Cazaubiel M, et al. Assessment of psychotropic-like properties of a probiotic formulation (Lactobacillus helveticus R0052 and Bifidobacterium longum R0175) in rats and human subjects. Br J Nutr. 2011;105:755&#x2013;764. doi: 10.1017/S0007114510004319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114510004319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20974015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marotta A, Sarno E, Del Casale A, Pane M, Mogna L, Amoruso A, Felis GE, Fiorio M. Effects of probiotics on cognitive reactivity, mood, and sleep quality. Front Psychiatry. 2019;10:164. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30971965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark A, Mach N. Exercise-induced stress behavior, gut-microbiota-brain axis and diet: a systematic review for athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2016;13:43. doi: 10.1186/s12970-016-0155-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-016-0155-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5121944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27924137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S, Liu W, Wang J, Shi J, Sun Y, Wang W, Ning G, Liu R, Hong J. Akkermansia muciniphila improves metabolic profiles by reducing inflammation in chow diet-fed mice. J Mol Endocrinol. 2017;58:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1530/JME-16-0054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/JME-16-0054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27821438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warber JP, Patton JF, Tharion WJ, Zeisel SH, Mello RP, Kemnitz CP, Lieberman HR. The effects of choline supplementation on physical performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2000;10:170&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.10.2.170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.10.2.170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10861337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin FP, Wang Y, Sprenger N, Holmes E, Lindon JC, Kochhar S, Nicholson JK. Effects of probiotic Lactobacillus paracasei treatment on the host gut tissue metabolic profiles probed via magic-angle-spinning NMR spectroscopy. J Proteome Res. 2007;6:1471&#x2013;1481. doi: 10.1021/pr060596a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/pr060596a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17316039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Klipfell E, Bennett BJ, Koeth R, Levison BS, Dugar B, Feldstein AE, Britt EB, Fu X, Chung YM, et al. Gut flora metabolism of phosphatidylcholine promotes cardiovascular disease. Nature. 2011;472:57&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1038/nature09922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature09922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3086762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21475195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutagy NE, Neilson AP, Osterberg KL, Smithson AT, Englund TR, Davy BM, Hulver MW, Davy KP. Probiotic supplementation and trimethylamine-N-oxide production following a high-fat diet. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2015;23:2357&#x2013;2363. doi: 10.1002/oby.21212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.21212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26465927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges NA, Stenvinkel P, Bergman P, Qureshi AR, Lindholm B, Moraes C, Stockler-Pinto MB, Mafra D. Effects of probiotic supplementation on trimethylamine-N-oxide plasma levels in hemodialysis patients: a pilot study. Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins. 2018. 10.1007/s12602-018-9411-1, 10.1007/s12602-018-9411-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29651635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tompkins TA, Mainville I, Arcand Y. The impact of meals on a probiotic during transit through a model of the human upper gastrointestinal tract. Benefic Microbes. 2011;2:295&#x2013;303. doi: 10.3920/BM2011.0022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/BM2011.0022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22146689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He CS, Tsai ML, Ko MH, Chang CK, Fang SH. Relationships among salivary immunoglobulin a, lactoferrin and cortisol in basketball players during a basketball season. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110:989&#x2013;995. doi: 10.1007/s00421-010-1574-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1574-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20668874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li TL, Lin HC, Ko MH, Chang CK, Fang SH. Effects of prolonged intensive training on the resting levels of salivary immunoglobulin a and cortisol in adolescent volleyball players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2012;52:569&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22976746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai ML, Li TL, Chou LW, Chang CK, Huang SY, Fang SH. Resting salivary levels of IgA and cortisol are significantly affected during intensive resistance training periods in elite male weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:2202&#x2013;2208. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823a4246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823a4246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21997453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ait-Belgnaoui A, Durand H, Cartier C, Chaumaz G, Eutamene H, Ferrier L, Houdeau E, Fioramonti J, Bueno L, Theodorou V. Prevention of gut leakiness by a probiotic treatment leads to attenuated HPA response to an acute psychological stress in rats. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2012;37:1885&#x2013;1895. doi: 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2012.03.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2012.03.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22541937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles SR, Nelson EA, Palombo EA. Investigating the role of perceived stress on bacterial flora activity and salivary cortisol secretion: a possible mechanism underlying susceptibility to illness. Biol Psychol. 2008;77:132&#x2013;137. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsycho.2007.09.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsycho.2007.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18023961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson H, Tullberg C, Ahrne S, Hamberg K, Lazou Ahren I, Molin G, Sonesson M, Hakansson A. Oral Administration of Lactobacillus plantarum 299v reduces cortisol levels in human saliva during examination induced stress: a randomized, Double-Blind Controlled Trial. Int J Microbiol. 2016;2016:8469018. doi: 10.1155/2016/8469018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/8469018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28101105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato-Kataoka A, Nishida K, Takada M, Kawai M, Kikuchi-Hayakawa H, Suda K, Ishikawa H, Gondo Y, Shimizu K, Matsuki T, et al. Fermented Milk containing Lactobacillus casei strain Shirota preserves the diversity of the gut microbiota and relieves abdominal dysfunction in healthy medical students exposed to academic stress. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2016;82:3649&#x2013;3658. doi: 10.1128/AEM.04134-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.04134-15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4959178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27208120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada M, Nishida K, Kataoka-Kato A, Gondo Y, Ishikawa H, Suda K, Kawai M, Hoshi R, Watanabe O, Igarashi T, et al. Probiotic Lactobacillus casei strain Shirota relieves stress-associated symptoms by modulating the gut-brain interaction in human and animal models. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2016;28:1027&#x2013;1036. doi: 10.1111/nmo.12804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.12804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26896291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly JR, Allen AP, Temko A, Hutch W, Kennedy PJ, Farid N, Murphy E, Boylan G, Bienenstock J, Cryan JF, et al. Lost in translation? The potential psychobiotic Lactobacillus rhamnosus (JB-1) fails to modulate stress or cognitive performance in healthy male subjects. Brain Behav Immun. 2017;61:50&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2016.11.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2016.11.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27865949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis DJ, Ilardi SS, Punt SEW. The anxiolytic effect of probiotics: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the clinical and preclinical literature. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0199041. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0199041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0199041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6010276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29924822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desbrow B, McCormack J, Burke LM, Cox GR, Fallon K, Hislop M, Logan R, Marino N, Sawyer SM, Shaw G, et al. Sports dietitians Australia position statement: sports nutrition for the adolescent athlete. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2014;24:570&#x2013;584. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2014-0031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2014-0031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw MT, Leggat PA, Chatterjee S. Travelling to India for the Delhi XIX commonwealth games 2010. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2010;8:129&#x2013;138. doi: 10.1016/j.tmaid.2010.04.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tmaid.2010.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>