<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40845297</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Relationship Between External and Internal Load, Sleep, and Wellness During an Off-Season Phase in Women's Collegiate NCAA Division I Lacrosse Athletes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005235</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sutton, PJ, Cintineo, HP, Mumford, PW, and Sunderland, KL. The relationship between external and internal load, sleep, and wellness during an off-season phase in women's collegiate NCAA Division I lacrosse athletes. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-The purpose of this study was to investigate the bidirectional associations between workload, recovery, sleep, and wellness during the off-season in collegiate women's lacrosse athletes. Data from 20 athletes were evaluated throughout 2 weeks of off-season. Workload was determined by Edwards Training Impulse (eTRIMP), total distance (TD), high-speed running distance (HSR), and session rating of perceived exertion-derived internal training load (sRPE-TL). Resting heart rate and heart rate variability were measured during a 10-minute period upon waking each morning. A Consensus Sleep Diary and Modified Hooper wellness questionnaires were completed within 60 minutes of waking to determine sleep efficiency (SE), sleep onset latency, wake after sleep onset (WASO), total sleep time, and wellness scores. Repeated-measures correlations determined the bidirectional relationships between workload and measures of sleep and wellness (&#x3b1; = 0.05). Total distance, eTRIMP, and sRPE-TL inversely correlated with the following night's SE (r = -0.204, -0.218, and -0.172, respectively) and SE positively correlated with same-day TD (r = 0.222) and eTRIMP (r = 0.199). This relationship was attributable to WASO, with both TD (r = 0.187) and eTRIMP (r = 0.179) having positive correlations with WASO. A positive correlation with session duration was observed for TD (r = 0.811), eTRIMP (r = 0.914), HSR (r = 0.417), and sRPE-TL (r = 0.168). Significant associations between workload, sleep, and wellness outcomes were found, with WASO and session duration emerging as key factors. Although we observed associations between workload, subjective wellness, sleep outcomes, the small-to-moderate relationship strengths suggest other contributing factors. Practitioners should prioritize sleep hygiene education to help athletes mitigate potential sleep disruptions caused by training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sutton</LastName><ForeName>Paige J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, College of Science, Technology, and Health, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, Missouri; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cintineo</LastName><ForeName>Harry P</ForeName><Initials>HP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, College of Science, Technology, and Health, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, Missouri; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mumford</LastName><ForeName>Petey W</ForeName><Initials>PW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, College of Science, Technology, and Health, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, Missouri; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, College of Osteopathic Medicine, Pacific Northwest University of Health Sciences, Yakima, Washington.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sunderland</LastName><ForeName>Kyle L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, College of Science, Technology, and Health, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, Missouri; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athlete monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training load</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40845297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achten J, Jeukendrup AE. Heart rate monitoring: Applications and limitations. Sports Med 33: 517&#x2013;538, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aloulou A, Duforez F, L&#xe9;ger D, De Larochelambert Q, Nedelec M. The relationships between training load, type of sport, and sleep among high-level adolescent athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 890&#x2013;899, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astorino TA, Tam PA, Rietschel JC, Johnson SM, Freedman TP. Changes in physical fitness parameters during a competitive field hockey season. J Strength Cond Res 18: 850&#x2013;854, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakdash JZ, Marusich LR. Repeated measures correlation. Front Psychol 8: 456, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadegiani FA, Kater CE. Body composition, metabolism, sleep, psychological and eating patterns of overtraining syndrome: Results of the eros study (eros-profile). J Sports Sci 36: 1902&#x2013;1910, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney CE, Buysse DJ, Ancoli-Israel S, et al. The consensus sleep diary: Standardizing prospective sleep self-monitoring. Sleep 35: 287&#x2013;302, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauvineau M, Pasquier F, Poirier C, et al. Higher training loads affect sleep in endurance runners: Can a high-heat-capacity mattress topper mitigate negative effects? J Sports Sci 41: 1605&#x2013;1616, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copenhaver EA, Diamond AB. The value of sleep on athletic performance, injury, and recovery in the young athlete. Pediatr Ann 46: e106&#x2013;e111, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crouch AK, Jiroutek MR, Snarr RL, Bunn JA. Relationship between pre-training wellness scores and internal and external training loads in a Division I women's lacrosse team. J Sports Sci 39: 1070&#x2013;1076, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devine NF, Hegedus EJ, Nguyen AD, Ford KR, Taylor JB. External match load in women's collegiate lacrosse. J Strength Cond Res 36: 503&#x2013;507, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Mah CD, Halson SL. Development of the athlete sleep behavior questionnaire: A tool for identifying maladaptive sleep practices in elite athletes. Sleep Sci 11: 37&#x2013;44, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumortier J, Mariman A, Boone J, et al. Sleep, training load and performance in elite female gymnasts. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 151&#x2013;161, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards S. High performance training and racing. The Heart Rate Monitor Book. Sacramento, CA: Feet Fleet Press, 1993. pp. 113&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagundes LHS, Noce F, Albuquerque MR, de Andrade AGP, Teoldo da Costa V. Can motivation and overtraining predict burnout in professional soccer athletes in different periods of the season? Int J Sport Exerc Psychol 19: 279&#x2013;294, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields JB, Lameira DM, Short JL, et al. Relationship between external load and self-reported wellness measures across a men's collegiate soccer preseason. J Strength Cond Res 35: 1182&#x2013;1186, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res 15: 109&#x2013;115, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frimpong E, Mograss M, Zvionow T, Dang-Vu TT. The effects of evening high-intensity exercise on sleep in healthy adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev 60: 101535, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts AJ, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: The effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med 45: 161&#x2013;186, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo TF, Cormack SJ, Gabbett TJ, Lorenzen CH. Pre-training perceived wellness impacts training output in Australian football players. J Sports Sci 34: 1445&#x2013;1451, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Nutrition, sleep and recovery. Eur J Sport Sci 8: 119&#x2013;126, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlet MD, Frick MD, Bunn JA. High-speed running density in collegiate women's lacrosse. Res Sports Med 29: 386&#x2013;394, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauer R, Tessitore A, Knaus R, Tschan H. Lacrosse athletes load and recovery monitoring: Comparison between objective and subjective methods. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 3329, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Louis J, Aubry A, Bonnet G, Duffield R, LE Meur Y. Evidence of disturbed sleep and increased illness in overreached endurance athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 1036&#x2013;1045, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper SL, Mackinnon LT, Howard A, Gordon RD, Bachmann AW. Markers for monitoring overtraining and recovery. Med Sci Sports Exerc 27: 106&#x2013;112, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrozanova M, Kl&#xf6;ckner CA, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Pallesen S, Moen F. Sex differences in sleep and influence of the menstrual cycle on women's sleep in junior endurance athletes. PLoS One 16: e0253376, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff LE, Halson SL, Peiffer JJ. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important competitions. J Sci Med Sport 18: 13&#x2013;18, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krystal AD, Edinger JD. Measuring sleep quality. Sleep Med 9: S10&#x2013;S17, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumahara H, Ohta C, Nabeshima E, Nakayama A, Mine S, Yamato T. Dietary intake and energy expenditure during two different phases of athletic training in female collegiate lacrosse players. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1547&#x2013;1554, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund HG, Reider BD, Whiting AB, Prichard JR. Sleep patterns and predictors of disturbed sleep in a large population of college students. J Adolesc Health 46: 124&#x2013;132, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maich KHG, Lachowski AM, Carney CE. Psychometric properties of the consensus sleep diary in those with insomnia disorder. Behav Sleep Med 16: 117&#x2013;134, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchelli G, Humphries H, Bunn JA. An analysis of wellness responses in female lacrosse athletes throughout their menstrual cycles. Exerc Sport Mov 3: e00049, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 5: 367&#x2013;383, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Duclos M, Foster C, et al. Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: Joint consensus statement of the European College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 186&#x2013;205, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moalla W, Fessi MS, Farhat F, Nouira S, Wong DP, Dupont G. Relationship between daily training load and psychometric status of professional soccer players. Res Sports Med 24: 387&#x2013;394, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy CJ, Saavedra JM, &#xd3;lafsson D, Krist&#xf3;fersd&#xf3;ttir KH, Arnard&#xf3;ttir ES, Kristj&#xe1;nsd&#xf3;ttir H. The training times of athletes could play a role in clinical sleep problems due to their associations with sleep difficulty scores. Sleep Health 10: 449&#x2013;454, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson KL, Davis JE, Corbett CF. Sleep quality: An evolutionary concept analysis. Nurs Forum 57: 144&#x2013;151, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Alves AR, Haghighi H, et al. Association between training load and well-being measures in young soccer players during a season. Int J Environ Res Publ Health 18: 4451, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Marroyo JA, Blanco P, Foster C, Villa JG, Carballo-Leyenda B. Expanding knowledge about the effect of measurement time on session rating of perceived exertion. J Strength Cond Res 27: 230&#x2013;233, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saidi O, Souabni M, Del Sordo GC, et al. Association between low energy availability (lea) and impaired sleep quality in young rugby players. Nutrients 16: 609, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. How much sleep does an elite athlete need? Int J Sports Physiol Perform 16: 1746&#x2013;1757, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Main LC, Gastin PB. Monitoring the athlete training response: Subjective self-reported measures trump commonly used objective measures: A systematic review. Br J Sports Med 50: 281&#x2013;291, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soligard T, Schwellnus M, Alonso JM, et al. How much is too much? (part 1) International Olympic Committee consensus statement on load in sport and risk of injury. Br J Sports Med 50: 1030&#x2013;1041, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stutz J, Eiholzer R, Spengler CM. Effects of evening exercise on sleep in healthy participants: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 49: 269&#x2013;287, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale JA, Bonato M, Galasso L, et al. Sleep quality and high intensity interval training at two different times of day: A crossover study on the influence of the chronotype in male collegiate soccer players. Chronobiol Int 34: 260&#x2013;268, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall SP, Mattacola CG, Swanik CB, Levenstein S. Sleep efficiency and overreaching in swimmers. J Sport Rehabil 12: 1&#x2013;12, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AM. Sleep and athletic performance. Curr Sports Med Rep 16: 413&#x2013;418, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellman AD, Coad SC, Flynn PJ, Siam TK, McLellan CP. Perceived wellness associated with practice and competition in National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I football players. J Strength Cond Res 33: 112&#x2013;124, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson SG, Baker J. Exploring the relationship between sleep and expertise in endurance sport athletes. Int J Sport Exerc Psychol 19: 866&#x2013;881, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar U, Hamid N, Ahsan J. Sleep patterns and efficiency among students in a medical school. J Med Sci 26: 221&#x2013;224, 2018.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>