<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33201030</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-509X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2021 Mar-Apr 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of head trauma rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Head Trauma Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Within-Subjects Comparison of Clinical Outcomes for Patients' First and Second Concussions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>114</StartPage><EndPage>119</EndPage><MedlinePgn>114-119</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HTR.0000000000000612</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To examine the difference between an individual's first and second concussion using a comprehensive, multidomain assessment including symptoms, neurocognitive, vestibular, ocular, and individual demographic and medical history risk factors associated with protracted recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING">Concussion Specialty Clinic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS">Seventy-three patients (aged 13-21 years; 57% female) diagnosed with 2 separate concussions (380.5 &#xb1; 278.7 days between injuries) from August 2016 to August 2018.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">Retrospective within-subjects cohort study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN MEASURES">ImPACT, PCSS, and Vestibular-Ocular Motor Screen (VOMS) at each visit. Patients were divided into "normal" (&#x2264;30 days) and "protracted" recovery (&gt;30 days) for &#x3c7;2 analyses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There were no differences between the first and second injuries in recovery time, VOMS, visual and verbal memory, or reaction time. Visual motor speed scores were higher at the second injury time point and reported sleep symptoms were higher at the first injury time point. In addition, participants reported to the clinic on average 3 days earlier for an evaluation for their second injury. Results from &#x3c7;2 analyses indicated that female sex predicted protracted recovery (&gt;30 days) from concussion at the first injury time point (OR = 4.1; 95% CI, 1.5-11.6; P = .006).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The findings provide preliminary evidence that there is no clinical difference between patients' first and second concussions when both injuries were treated through a concussion specialty clinic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>French</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Drs French, Jennings, Collins, and Kontos); and Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Drs Eagle and Kontos).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jennings</LastName><ForeName>Sabrina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eagle</LastName><ForeName>Shawn R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collins</LastName><ForeName>Michael W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kontos</LastName><ForeName>Anthony P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Head Trauma Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8702552</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-9701</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Concussion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011930" MajorTopicYN="N">Reaction Time</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33201030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HTR.0000000000000612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001199-202103000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Harmon KG, Clugston JR, Dec K, et al. American Medical Society for Sports Medicine position statement on concussion in sport. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(4):213&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrea M, Guskiewicz KM, Marshall SW, et al. Acute effects and recovery time following concussion in collegiate football players: the NCAA Concussion Study. JAMA. 2003;290(19):2556&#x2013;2563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DJ, Coxe K, Li H, et al. Length of recovery from sports-related concussions in pediatric patients treated at concussion clinics. Clin J Sport Med. 2018;28(1):56&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refakis CA, Turner CD, Cahill PJ. Sports-related concussion in children and adolescents. Clin Spine Surg. 2017;30(5):191&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covassin T, Moran R, Wilhelm K. Concussion symptoms and neurocognitive performance of high school and college athletes who incur multiple concussions. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(12):2885&#x2013;2889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schatz P, Moser RS, Covassin T, Karpf R. Early indicators of enduring symptoms in high school athletes with multiple previous concussions. Neurosurgery. 2011;68(6):1562&#x2013;1567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belanger HG, Spiegel E, Vanderploeg RD. Neuropsychological performance following a history of multiple self-reported concussions: a meta-analysis. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2010;16(2):262&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macciocchi SN, Barth JT, Littlefield L, Cantu RC. Multiple concussions and neuropsychological functioning in collegiate football players. J Athl Train. 2001;36(3):303&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ImPACT Applications, Inc. Immediate Post-Concussion Assessment Testing (ImPACT&#xae;) Test. Technical Manual. Pittsburgh, PA: ImPACT Applications; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barr WB, McCrea M. Sensitivity and specificity of standardized neurocognitive testing immediately following sports concussion. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2001;7(06):693&#x2013;702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schatz P, Pardini JE, Lovell MR, Collins MW, Podell K. Sensitivity and specificity of the ImPACT Test Battery for concussion in athletes. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2006;21(1):91&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucha A, Collins MW, Elbin R, et al. A brief Vestibular/Ocular Motor Screening (VOMS) assessment to evaluate concussions preliminary findings. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(10):2479&#x2013;2486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell MR, Iverson GL, Collins MW, et al. Measurement of symptoms following sports-related concussion: reliability and normative data for the postconcussion scale. Appl Neuropsychol. 2006;13(3):166&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos AP, Elbin R, Schatz P, et al. A revised factor structure for the postconcussion symptom scale baseline and postconcussion factors. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(10):2375&#x2013;2384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson GL, Gardner AJ, Terry DP, et al. Predictors of clinical recovery from concussion: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(12):941&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos AP, Jorgensen-Wagers K, Trbovich AM, et al. Association of time since injury to the first clinic visit with recovery following concussion. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(4):435&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker JG, Leddy JJ, Darling SR, Shucard J, Makdissi M, Willer BS. Gender differences in recovery from sports-related concussion in adolescents. Clin Pediatr. 2016;55(8):771&#x2013;775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollayeva T, El-Khechen-Richandi G, Colantonio A. Sex &amp; gender considerations in concussion research. Concussion. 2018;3(1):CNC51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iverson G, Brooks B, Lovell M, Collins M. No cumulative effects for one or two previous concussions. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40(1):72&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser RS, Schatz P. Enduring effects of concussion in youth athletes. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2002;17(1):91&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins MW, Kontos AP, Reynolds E, Murawski CD, Fu FH. A comprehensive, targeted approach to the clinical care of athletes following sport-related concussion. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22(2):235&#x2013;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos A, Sufrinko A, Sandel N, Emami K, Collins M. Sport-related concussion clinical profiles: clinical characteristics, targeted treatments, and preliminary evidence. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2019;18(3):82&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry LC, Elbin R, Collins MW, Marchetti G, Kontos AP. Examining recovery trajectories after sport-related concussion with a multimodal clinical assessment approach. Neurosurgery. 2015;78(2):232&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauman S, Ray M, Joseph PP. Gender differences in clinical presentation and recovery of sports related concussion. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(11):A35.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>