<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41824225</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Monitoring Training Effects in Athletes: A Multidimensional Framework for Decision-Making.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-026-02417-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Athlete monitoring is widely used to support training and recovery decisions in elite sport, yet practitioners often face challenges related to data quality, feasibility, and the interpretation of short-term readiness signals within longer-term training adaptation. This narrative review synthesizes conceptual and applied developments in athlete monitoring through the lens of 'training effects', encompassing positive adaptation, maintenance, or maladaptation arising from training, competition, and contextual stressors. We distinguish assessment as isolated or periodic measurement from monitoring as repeated, systematic data collection used to track change over time. Building on contemporary conceptual models, readiness is positioned as an operational proxy for training effects that can inform day-to-day decision making when interpreted longitudinally and within context. We integrate the Minimal, Adequate, and Accurate framework to support tool selection that is economical in resource use, sufficient to meet clearly defined objectives, and grounded in valid and reliable measurement. Tools and metrics are organized according to the primary construct they inform: training load, athlete state and training response. We summarize practical considerations across neuromuscular, subjective, physiological, biochemical, and sleep-related indicators, emphasizing interpretive scope, measurement variability, and implementation constraints. To operationalize individualized monitoring, we outline pragmatic approaches using athlete-specific baselines and distribution-based thresholds (e.g., standard deviation intervals, minimum detectable change), alongside decision-making considerations related to Type I and Type II errors. Overall, this framework aims to reconcile scientific rigor with real-world feasibility, supporting practitioner decision making while acknowledging that monitoring should function as a decision-support process rather than a stand-alone determinant of performance outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rebelo</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2441-9167</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CIDEFES, Research Center in Sport, Physical Education, and Exercise and Health, Lus&#xf3;fona University, Lisbon, Portugal. andre94rebelo@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Centre for Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), University of Porto, Rua Dr. Pl&#xe1;cido Costa, 91, 4200-450, Porto, Portugal. andre94rebelo@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>COD, Center of Sports Optimization, Sporting Clube de Portugal, Lisbon, Portugal. andre94rebelo@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1505-1287</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Technology, London Sport Institute, Middlesex University, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thorpe</LastName><ForeName>Robin T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Red Bull Performance Centre, 2700 Pennsylvania Ave, Santa Monica, CA, 90404, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Anthony N</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5121-432X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Technology, London Sport Institute, Middlesex University, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabbett</LastName><ForeName>Tim J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9950-5505</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gabbett Performance Solutions, Brisbane, QLD, 4011, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: TJB works as a consultant to several high&#x2011;performance organizations, including sporting teams, artistic, industry, military and higher&#x2011;education institutions. These roles are independent of the current article. All other authors declare they have no conflicts of interest relevant to the content of this article. Author Contributions: AR conceived and designed the narrative review, led the literature identification and synthesis, developed the conceptual framework, and drafted the manuscript. CB contributed to methodological and statistical interpretation, provided applied practitioner perspectives, and critically revised the manuscript. RTT contributed to the conceptual development of monitoring and readiness constructs, with particular input into Sect.&#xa0;2, provided high-performance sport applications, and critically revised the manuscript. ANT contributed to the conceptual and theoretical development of fatigue, readiness and monitoring constructs, supported the interpretation of training effects, and critically revised the manuscript. TJG contributed to the conceptual framing of training load, adaptation, and athlete monitoring, supported the integration of applied models and decision-making frameworks, and critically revised the manuscript. All authors reviewed and approved the final version of the manuscript and agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work. Ethics Approval: Not applicable. Consent to Participate: Not applicable. Availability of Data and Material: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41824225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-026-02417-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-026-02417-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hill J. Sport in history: an introduction. London: Bloomsbury Publishing; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soligard T, Schwellnus M, Alonso J-M, Bahr R, Clarsen B, Dijkstra HP, et al. How much is too much? (Part 1) International Olympic Committee consensus statement on load in sport and risk of injury. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(17):1030&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-096581 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Nassis GP, Oetter E, Pretorius J, Johnston N, Medina D, et al. The athlete monitoring cycle: a practical guide to interpreting and applying training monitoring data. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(20):1451. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-097298 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28646100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schelling X, Fern&#xe1;ndez J, Ward P, Fern&#xe1;ndez J, Robertson S. Decision support system applications for scheduling in professional team sport. The team&#x2019;s perspective. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3:678489. https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2021.678489 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.678489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34151262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8213205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Halson S, Burke LM, Balagu&#xe9; G, Farrow D. An integrated, multifactorial approach to periodization for optimal performance in individual and team sports. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(5):538&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0093 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I. Intense training: the key to optimal performance before and during the taper. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 2):24&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01189.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01189.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20840559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Monitoring training load to understand fatigue in athletes. Sports Med. 2014;44(2):139&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-014-0253-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0253-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffries AC, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ, Wallace L, McCall A, Impellizzeri FM. Development of a revised conceptual framework of physical training for use in research and practice. Sports Med. 2022;52(4):709&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-021-01551-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01551-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Madsen EE, Clubb J, Emmonds S, Krustrup P. Monitoring readiness to train and perform in female football: current evidence and recommendations for practitioners. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;19(3):223&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2023-0405 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2023-0405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38307011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe RT, Atkinson G, Drust B, Gregson W. Monitoring fatigue status in elite team-sport athletes: implications for practice. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(Suppl 2):S227&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2016-0434 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28095065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebelo A, Pereira JR, Martinho DV, Amorim G, Lima R, Valente-Dos-Santos J. Training load, neuromuscular fatigue, and well-being of elite male volleyball athletes during an in-season mesocycle. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023;18(4):354&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2022-0279 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2022-0279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36754058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Oetter E. From tissue to system: what constitutes an appropriate response to loading? Sports Med. 2025;55(1):17&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-024-02126-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02126-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39527327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Jeukendrup AE. Does overtraining exist? An analysis of overreaching and overtraining research. Sports Med. 2004;34(14):967&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200434140-00003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200434140-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15571428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamble P, Chia L, Allen S. The illogic of being data-driven: reasserting control and restoring balance in our relationship with data and technology in football. Sci Med Footb. 2020;4(4):338&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1080/24733938.2020.1854842 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2020.1854842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ash GI, Stults-Kolehmainen M, Busa MA, Gaffey AE, Angeloudis K, Muniz-Pardos B, et al. Establishing a global standard for wearable devices in sport and exercise medicine: perspectives from academic and industry stakeholders. Sports Med. 2021;51(11):2237&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-021-01543-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01543-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34468950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8666971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Pyne DB. Optimal support for elite sprinters using a minimal, adequate, and accurate approach. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2025;20(2):321&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2024-0227 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2024-0227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39265975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Main LC, Gastin PB. Monitoring the athlete training response: subjective self-reported measures trump commonly used objective measures: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(5):281&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2015-094758 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26423706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boullosa D, Claudino JG, Fernandez-Fernandez J, Bok D, Loturco I, Stults-Kolehmainen M, et al. The fine-tuning approach for training monitoring. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023;18(12):1374&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2023-0154 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2023-0154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37689401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boullosa D, Casado A, Claudino JG, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Rav&#xe9; G, Casta&#xf1;o-Zambudio A, et al. Do you play or do you train? Insights from individual sports for training load and injury risk management in team sports based on individualization. Front Physiol. 2020;11:995. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2020.00995 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32973548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7472986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ. Working fast and working slow: the benefits of embedding research in high performance sport. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(1):1&#x2013;2. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2015-0781 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26752203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffries AC, Wallace L, Coutts AJ, McLaren SJ, McCall A, Impellizzeri FM. Athlete-reported outcome measures for monitoring training responses: a systematic review of risk of bias and measurement property quality according to the COSMIN guidelines. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15(9):1203&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2020-0386 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32957081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borszcz FK, Vieira MT, Tramontin AF, Visentainer LH, Costa VP. Is functional overreaching or acute fatigue the key to the effects of concentrated block training in running? J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(12):3485&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000004231 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000004231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36417360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB. New horizons for the methodology and physiology of training periodization. Sports Med. 2010;40(3):189&#x2013;206. https://doi.org/10.2165/11319770-000000000-00000 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11319770-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20199119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Rav&#xe9; JM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mohino F, Rodrigo-Carranza V, Pyne DB. Reverse periodization for improving sports performance: a systematic review. Sports Med - Open. 2022;8(1):56. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-022-00445-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00445-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35445953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9023617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Hornsby WG, Haff GG, Fry AC, Suarez DG, Liu J, et al. Periodization and block periodization in sports: emphasis on strength-power training&#x2014;a provocative and challenging narrative. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(8):2351&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000004050 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000004050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34132223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guthrie B, Jagim AR, Jones MT. Ready or not, here I come: a scoping review of methods used to assess player readiness via indicators of neuromuscular function in football code athletes. Strength Cond J. 2023;45(1):93&#x2013;110. https://doi.org/10.1519/ssc.0000000000000735 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Duclos M, Foster C, Fry A, Gleeson M, Nieman D, et al. Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: joint consensus statement of the European College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(1):186&#x2013;205. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e318279a10a .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318279a10a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Rumpf MC, Hertzog M, Castagna C, Farooq A, Girard O, et al. Acute and residual soccer match-related fatigue: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(3):539&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-017-0798-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0798-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29098658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry RW, Morton AR, Keast D. Overtraining in athletes. An update. Sports Med. 1991;12(1):32&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-199112010-00004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199112010-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1925188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tornero-Aguilera JF, Jimenez-Morcillo J, Rubio-Zarapuz A, Clemente-Su&#xe1;rez VJ. Central and peripheral fatigue in physical exercise explained: a narrative review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19073909 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19073909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36429449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9690799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. The training-injury prevention paradox: should athletes be training smarter and harder? Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(5):273&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2015-095788 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4789704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwellnus M, Soligard T, Alonso JM, Bahr R, Clarsen B, Dijkstra HP, et al. How much is too much? (Part 2) International Olympic Committee consensus statement on load in sport and risk of illness. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(17):1043&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-096572 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5013087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourdon PC, Cardinale M, Murray A, Gastin P, Kellmann M, Varley MC, et al. Monitoring athlete training loads: consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12:161&#x2013;70. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2017-0208 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, McCall A, Impellizzeri FM, Favero T, Coutts AJ. The translation of sport science research to the field: a current opinion and overview on the perceptions of practitioners, researchers and coaches. Sports Med. 2019;49(12):1817&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01139-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01139-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31214978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akenhead R, Nassis GP. Training load and player monitoring in high-level football: current practice and perceptions. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(5):587&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2015-0331 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26456711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmerman WP, Abbiss CR, Lawler NG, Stanley M, Raynor AJ. Athlete monitoring perspectives of sports coaches and support staff: a scoping review. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2024;19(4):1813&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1177/17479541241247131 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17479541241247131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Menasp&#xe0; P, Coutts AJ, Kalkhoven J, Menasp&#xe0; MJ. Training load and its role in injury prevention, Part I: back to the future. J Athl Train. 2020;55(9):885&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.4085/1062-6050-500-19 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-500-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7534945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and external training load: 15 years on. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(2):270&#x2013;3. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0935 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Mann B, Banyard H, McLaren S, Scott T, Garcia-Ramos A. Velocity-based training: from theory to application. Strength Cond J. 2021;43(2):31&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.1519/ssc.0000000000000560 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Muscle fatigue: what, why and how it influences muscle function. J Physiol. 2008;586(1):11&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2007.139477 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2007.139477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17702815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulbulian R, Heaney JH, Leake CN, Sucec AA, Sjoholm NT. The effect of sleep deprivation and exercise load on isokinetic leg strength and endurance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1996;73(3&#x2013;4):273&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1007/bf02425487 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf02425487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8781857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss EP, Racette SB, Villareal DT, Fontana L, Steger-May K, Schechtman KB, et al. Lower extremity muscle size and strength and aerobic capacity decrease with caloric restriction but not with exercise-induced weight loss. J Appl Physiol. 2007;102(2):634&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00853.2006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00853.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JB, Bryant KR, Johnstone B, Ivey PA, Sayers SP. Effect of physical and academic stress on illness and injury in Division 1 college football players. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(1):20&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000001055 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26049791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moura RE, Bezerra da Silva RF, Gomes LMS, Ramos da Silva JL, Henrique RDS, Sousa FAB, et al. Monitoring bar velocity to quantify fatigue in resistance training. Int J Sports Med. 2024;45(8):624&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-2316-7966 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2316-7966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38684188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appleby BB, Banyard H, Cormack SJ, Newton RU. Validity and reliability of methods to determine barbell displacement in heavy back squats: implications for velocity-based training. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(11):3118&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000002803 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33105362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peart DJ, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Shaw MP. Use of mobile applications to collect data in sport, health, and exercise science: a narrative review. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(4):1167&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000002344 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29176384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum D, Barbosa TM. Brief review: effects of isometric strength training on strength and dynamic performance. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40(6):363&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-0863-4539 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0863-4539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30943568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, Stone JD, Hornsby WG, Hagen JA. Identifying reliable and relatable force-time metrics in athletes&#x2014;considerations for the isometric mid-thigh pull and countermovement jump. Sports (Basel). 2020. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports9010004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports9010004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33396304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7824153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Witt JK, English KL, Crowell JB, Kalogera KL, Guilliams ME, Nieschwitz BE, et al. Isometric midthigh pull reliability and relationship to deadlift one repetition maximum. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(2):528&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000001605 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27548797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mez&#xea;ncio B, McMaster DT, McGuigan M, Tricoli V, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: a meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(4):397&#x2013;402. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2016.08.011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2016.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27663764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Turner A, Jordan M, Harry J, Loturco I, Lake J, et al. A framework to guide practitioners for selecting metrics during the countermovement and drop jump tests. Strength Cond J. 2022;44(4):95&#x2013;103. https://doi.org/10.1519/ssc.0000000000000677 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Turner A, Jarvis P, Chavda S, Read P. Considerations for selecting field-based strength and power fitness tests to measure asymmetries. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(9):2635&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000002023 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28644195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gathercole R, Sporer B, Stellingwerff T, Sleivert G. Alternative countermovement-jump analysis to quantify acute neuromuscular fatigue. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(1):84&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2013-0413 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2013-0413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Jordan M, Torres-Ronda L, Loturco I, Harry J, Virgile A, et al. Selecting metrics that matter: comparing the use of the countermovement jump for performance profiling, neuromuscular fatigue monitoring, and injury rehabilitation testing. Strength Cond J. 2023;45(5):545&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1519/ssc.0000000000000772 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehbe G, Gabett TJ, Dwyer D, McLellan C, Coad S. Monitoring neuromuscular fatigue in team-sport athletes using a cycle-ergometer test. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(3):292&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2014-0217 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2014-0217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25115142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehbe GM, Gabbett TJ, Hartwig TB, McLellan CP. Reliability of a cycle ergometer peak power test in running-based team sport athletes: a technical report. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(7):2050&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000000814 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000000814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallus W, Kellmann M. The recovery-stress questionnaires: user manual. London: Pearson; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushall BS. A tool for measuring stress tolerance in elite athletes. J Appl Sport Psychol. 1990;2(1):51&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1080/10413209008406420 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10413209008406420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Kellmann M, Main LC, Gastin PB. Athlete self-report measures in research and practice: considerations for the discerning reader and fastidious practitioner. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(Suppl 2):S2127&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2016-0395 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27834546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas M, Vacher P, Martinent G, Mourot L. Monitoring stress and recovery states: structural and external stages of the short version of the RESTQ sport in elite swimmers before championships. J Sport Health Sci. 2019;8(1):77&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jshs.2016.03.007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2016.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30719387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo TF, Cormack SJ, Gabbett TJ, Lorenzen CH. Pre-training perceived wellness impacts training output in Australian football players. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(15):1445&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2015.1119295 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1119295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26637525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung K, Hume P, Maxwell L. Delayed onset muscle soreness: treatment strategies and performance factors. Sports Med. 2003;33(2):145&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200333020-00005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200333020-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper SL, Mackinnon LT. Monitoring overtraining in athletes. Recommendations. Sports Med. 1995;20(5):321&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-199520050-00003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199520050-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8571005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarsen B, Bahr R, Myklebust G, Andersson SH, Docking SI, Drew M, et al. Improved reporting of overuse injuries and health problems in sport: an update of the Oslo Sport Trauma Research Center questionnaires. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(7):390. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2019-101337 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32060142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duignan C, Doherty C, Caulfield B, Blake C. Single-item self-report measures of team-sport athlete wellbeing and their relationship with training load: a systematic review. J Athl Train. 2020;55(9):944&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.4085/1062-6050-0528.19 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-0528.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7534939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coventry M, Timler A, Mosler AB, Russell K, Travers M, Mitchell OL, et al. &#x2018;I lied a little bit.&#x2019; A qualitative study exploring the perspectives of elite Australian athletes on self-reported data. Phys Ther Sport. 2023;60:91&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ptsp.2023.01.009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2023.01.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36738670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall A, Wolfberg A, Ivarsson A, Dupont G, Larocque A, Bilsborough J. A qualitative study of 11 world-class team-sport athletes&#x2019; experiences answering subjective questionnaires: a key ingredient for &#x201c;visible&#x201d; health and performance monitoring? Sports Med. 2023;53(5):1085&#x2013;100. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-023-01814-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01814-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36763237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10115681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan H, Hassm&#xe9;n P, Rosic N, Stevens CJ. Training monitoring methods used in the field by coaches and practitioners: A systematic review. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2020;15(3):439&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1177/1747954120913172 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747954120913172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rios M, Pyne DB. Integrative physiological strategies for monitoring demands in functional fitness. Sports Basel. 2025. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports13110381 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports13110381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41295764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12656209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Monitoring training status with HR measures: do all roads lead to Rome? Front Physiol. 2014;5:73. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2014.00073 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2014.00073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24578692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3936188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatisson J, Oswald V, Lalonde F. Influence diagram of physiological and environmental factors affecting heart rate variability: an extended literature overview. Heart Int. 2016;11(1):e32&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.5301/heartint.5000232 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5301/heartint.5000232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27924215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5056628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saboul D, Pialoux V, Hautier C. The impact of breathing on HRV measurements: implications for the longitudinal follow-up of athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. 2013;13(5):534&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2013.767947 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2013.767947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24050471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Le Meur Y, Hausswirth C, Kilding AE, Buchheit M. Monitoring training with heart rate-variability: how much compliance is needed for valid assessment? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(5):783&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2013-0455 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2013-0455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24334285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulin BT, J. GT, DJR, Jenkins DG. Sub-maximal heart rate is associated with changes in high-intensity intermittent running ability in professional rugby league players. Sci Med Footb. 2019;3(1):50&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1080/24733938.2018.1475748</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulin BT, Gabbett TJ, Pickworth NJ, Johnston RD, Jenkins DG. Relationships among PlayerLoad, high-intensity intermittent running ability, and injury risk in professional Rugby League players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15(3):423&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2019-0139 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31569073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shushan T, Lovell R, Buchheit M, Scott TJ, Barrett S, Norris D, et al. Submaximal fitness test in team sports: a systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise heart rate measurement properties. Sports Medicine - Open. 2023;9(1):21. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-023-00564-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00564-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36964427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10039193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougios V. Reference intervals for serum creatine kinase in athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41(10):674&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsm.2006.034041 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2006.034041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17526622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2465154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EC, Fragala MS, Kavouras SA, Queen RM, Pryor JL, Casa DJ. Biomarkers in sports and exercise: tracking health, performance, and recovery in athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(10):2920&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000002122 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28737585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5640004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichel T, Bo&#xdf;lau TK, Palmowski J, Eder K, Ringseis R, Mooren FC, et al. Reliability and suitability of physiological exercise response and recovery markers. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):11924. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-69280-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-69280-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7368084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller N, Behringer M, Reichel T, Wahl P, Simon P, Kr&#xfc;ger K, et al. Blood-based biomarkers for managing workload in athletes: considerations and recommendations for evidence-based use of established biomarkers. Sports Med. 2023;53(7):1315&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-023-01836-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01836-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37204619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10197055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, Stanton R, Sargent C, Wintour SA, Scanlan AT. The association between training load and performance in team sports: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48(12):2743&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-018-0982-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0982-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30225537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard JL, Murray-Kolb LE, Rosales FJ, Solomons NW, Angelilli ML. Interpretation of serum ferritin concentrations as indicators of total-body iron stores in survey populations: the role of biomarkers for the acute phase response. Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;84(6):1498&#x2013;505. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/84.6.1498 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/84.6.1498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17158435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urhausen A, Gabriel H, Kindermann W. Blood hormones as markers of training stress and overtraining. Sports Med. 1995;20(4):251&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-199520040-00004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199520040-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8584849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vervoorn C, Quist AM, Vermulst LJ, Erich WB, de Vries WR, Thijssen JH. The behaviour of the plasma free testosterone/cortisol ratio during a season of elite rowing training. Int J Sports Med. 1991;12(3):257&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-2007-1024677 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1024677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1889932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):S13-23. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-014-0147-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0147-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4008810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF 3rd, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213. https://doi.org/10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender AM, Lawson D, Werthner P, Samuels CH. The clinical validation of the Athlete Sleep Screening Questionnaire: an instrument to identify athletes that need further sleep assessment. Sports Med - Open. 2018;4(1):23. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-018-0140-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-018-0140-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29869021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5986689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Johnston RD, Appaneal RN, Rogers MA, Toohey LA, Drew MK, et al. Sleep quality in elite athletes: normative values, reliability and understanding contributors to poor sleep. Sports Med. 2022;52(2):417&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-021-01555-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01555-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller KL, Juliff L, Gore CJ, Peiffer JJ, Halson SL. Software thresholds alter the bias of actigraphy for monitoring sleep in team-sport athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(8):756&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2016.11.021 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2016.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28189461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quante M, Kaplan ER, Rueschman M, Cailler M, Buxton OM, Redline S. Practical considerations in using accelerometers to assess physical activity, sedentary behaviour, and sleep. Sleep Health. 2015;1(4):275&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sleh.2015.09.002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleh.2015.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep monitoring in athletes: motivation, methods, miscalculations and why it matters. Sports Med. 2019;49(10):1487&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01119-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01119-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31093921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harry JR, Hurwitz J, Agnew C, Bishop C. Statistical tests for sports science practitioners: identifying performance gains in individual athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(5):e264&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000004727 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000004727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38662890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Nevill AM. Statistical methods for assessing measurement error (reliability) in variables relevant to sports medicine. Sports Med. 1998;26(4):217&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-199826040-00002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199826040-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9820922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner A. But did my athlete improve? Assessing performance changes when N = 1. Prof Strength Cond. 2022;63:27&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Batterham AM. Error Rates, Decisive Outcomes and Publication Bias with Several Inferential Methods. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1563&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-016-0517-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0517-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26971328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G. Does size matter for sports performance researchers? J Sports Sci. 2003;21(2):73&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1080/0264041031000071038 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0264041031000071038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12630786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copay AG, Subach BR, Glassman SD, Polly DW Jr, Schuler TC. Understanding the minimum clinically important difference: a review of concepts and methods. Spine J. 2007;7(5):541&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.spinee.2007.01.008 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spinee.2007.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17448732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe RT, Strudwick AJ, Buchheit M, Atkinson G, Drust B, Gregson W. Monitoring fatigue during the in-season competitive phase in elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(8):958&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2015-0004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25710257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leduc C, Weaving D. Invisible monitoring for athlete health and performance: a call for a better conceptualization and practical recommendations. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2025;20(6):880&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2024-0292 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2024-0292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39855186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWeese BH, Hamilton DK, Huls S, Peterson BJ, Rath T, Althoff A. Clarifying high performance and the role, responsibilities, and requisite attributes of the high-performance director in American professional sport. Strength Cond J. 2023;45(4):429&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1519/ssc.0000000000000763 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Hader K. Data everywhere, insight nowhere: a practical quadrant-based model for monitoring training load vs. response in elite football. Sport Perf Sci Rep. 2025;1(258):1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>