<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35526065</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Salzburg 10/7 HIIT shock cycle study: the effects of a 7-day high-intensity interval training shock microcycle with or without additional low-intensity training on endurance performance, well-being, stress and recovery in endurance trained athletes-study protocol of a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>84</StartPage><MedlinePgn>84</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">84</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-022-00456-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Performing multiple high-intensity interval training (HIIT) sessions in a compressed period of time (approximately 7-14&#xa0;days) is called a HIIT shock microcycle (SM) and promises a rapid increase in endurance performance. However, the efficacy of HIIT-SM, as well as knowledge about optimal training volumes during a SM in the endurance-trained population have not been adequately investigated. This study aims to examine the effects of two different types of HIIT-SM (with or without additional low-intensity training (LIT)) compared to a control group (CG) on key endurance performance variables. Moreover, participants are closely monitored for stress, fatigue, recovery, and sleep before, during and after the intervention using innovative biomarkers, questionnaires, and wearable devices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a study protocol of a randomized controlled trial that includes the results of a pilot participant. Thirty-six endurance trained athletes will be recruited and randomly assigned to either a HIIT-SM (HSM) group, HIIT-SM with additional LIT (HSM&#x2009;+&#x2009;LIT) group or a CG. All participants will be monitored before (9&#xa0;days), during (7&#xa0;days), and after (14&#xa0;days) a 7-day intervention, for a total of 30&#xa0;days. Participants in both intervention groups will complete 10 HIIT sessions over 7 consecutive days, with an additional 30&#xa0;min of LIT in the HSM&#x2009;+&#x2009;LIT group. HIIT sessions consist of aerobic HIIT, i.e., 5&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;4&#xa0;min at 90-95% of maximal heart rate interspersed by recovery periods of 2.5&#xa0;min. To determine the effects of the intervention, physiological exercise testing, and a 5 km time trial will be conducted before and after the intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The feasibility study indicates good adherence and performance improvement of the pilot participant. Load monitoring tools, i.e., biomarkers and questionnaires showed increased values during the intervention period, indicating sensitive variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study will be the first to examine the effects of different total training volumes of HIIT-SM, especially the combination of LIT and HIIT in the HSM&#x2009;+&#x2009;LIT group. In addition, different assessments to monitor the athletes' load during such an exhaustive training period will allow the identification of load monitoring tools such as innovative biomarkers, questionnaires, and wearable technology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">clinicaltrials.gov, NCT05067426. Registered 05 October 2021-Retrospectively registered, https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05067426 . Protocol Version Issue date: 1 Dec 2021. Original protocol. Authors: TLS, NH.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>St&#xf6;ggl</LastName><ForeName>Thomas Leonhard</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Red Bull Athlete Performance Center, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Blumkaitis</LastName><ForeName>Julia C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strepp</LastName><ForeName>Tilmann</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sareban</LastName><ForeName>Mahdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Institute of Sports Medicine, Prevention and Rehabilitation and Research Institute of Molecular Sports Medicine and Rehabilitation, Paracelsus Medical University, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simon</LastName><ForeName>Perikles</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Rehabilitation and Disease Prevention, Johannes Gutenberg University of Mainz, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neuberger</LastName><ForeName>Elmo W I</ForeName><Initials>EWI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Rehabilitation and Disease Prevention, Johannes Gutenberg University of Mainz, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finkenzeller</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Natalia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, University of Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genetics Division, Department of Morphology and Genetics, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aglas</LastName><ForeName>Lorenz</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, University of Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haller</LastName><ForeName>Nils</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7066-7615</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Science, University of Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria. nils.haller@plus.ac.at.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Rehabilitation and Disease Prevention, Johannes Gutenberg University of Mainz, Mainz, Germany. nils.haller@plus.ac.at.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05067426</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Block training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIIT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interval exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LIT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Load monitoring</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>All authors declare no competing interests. Based on the scientific cooperation with no commercial interest, the study has received funding from the Red Bull Athlete Performance Center. The funding body has not peer-reviewed the manuscript. This sponsor was not involved in the study design, the writing of the manuscript, or the decision to submit the manuscript for publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9077880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-022-00456-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-022-00456-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zuhl M, Kravitz L. HIIT vs continuous endurance training: battle of the aerobic titans. IDEA Fitness J. 2012;9(2):34&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helgerud J, H&#xf8;ydal K, Wang E, Karlsen T, Berg P, Bjerkaas M, et al. Aerobic high-intensity intervals improve V&#x2d9; O2max more than moderate training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(4):665&#x2013;671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17414804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins C, Stensvold D, Finlayson G, Holst J, Wisloff U, Kulseng B, et al. Effect of moderate- and high-intensity acute exercise on appetite in obese individuals. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(1):40&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24824772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf6;ggl T, Sperlich B. Polarized training has greater impact on key endurance variables than threshold, high intensity, or high volume training. Front Physiol. 2014;5:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3912323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su L, Fu J, Sun S, Zhao G, Cheng W, Dou C, et al. Effects of HIIT and MICT on cardiovascular risk factors in adults with overweight and/or obesity: a meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(1):e0210644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6349321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30689632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana RB, Naves JPA, Coswig VS, de Lira CAB, Steele J, Fisher JP, et al. Is interval training the magic bullet for fat loss? A systematic review and meta-analysis comparing moderate-intensity continuous training with high-intensity interval training (HIIT) Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(10):655&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30765340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastin PB. Energy system interaction and relative contribution during maximal exercise. Sports Med. 2001;31(10):725&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11547894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Laursen PB. High-intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle. Part II: anaerobic energy, neuromuscular load and practical applications. Sports Med. 2013;43(10):927&#x2013;954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23832851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breil FA, Weber SN, Koller S, Hoppeler H, Vogt M. Block training periodization in alpine skiing: effects of 11-day HIT on VO2max and performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(6):1077&#x2013;1086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20364385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf6;ggl T, Stieglbauer R, Sageder T, M&#xfc;ller E. hochintensives Intervall-(HIT) und Schnelligkeitstraining im Fu&#xdf;ball. Leistungssport. 2010;40(5):43&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menz V, Strobl J, Faulhaber M, Gatterer H, Burtscher M. Effect of 3-week high-intensity interval training on VO2max, total haemoglobin mass, plasma and blood volume in well-trained athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(11):2349&#x2013;2356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26164709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatle H, St&#xf8;bakk PK, M&#xf8;lmen HE, Br&#xf8;nstad E, Tj&#xf8;nna AE, Steinshamn S, et al. Effect of 24 sessions of high-intensity aerobic interval training carried out at either high or moderate frequency, a randomized trial. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(2):e88375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3917911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24516645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolen T, Chamari K, Castagna C, Wisloff U. Physiology of soccer: an update. Sports Med. 2005;35(6):501&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15974635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronnestad BR, Hansen J, Ellefsen S. Block periodization of high-intensity aerobic intervals provides superior training effects in trained cyclists. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(1):34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22646668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronnestad BR, Hansen J, Thyli V, Bakken TA, Sandbakk O. 5-week block periodization increases aerobic power in elite cross-country skiers. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;26(2):140&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25648345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGawley K, Juudas E, Kazior Z, Str&#xf6;m K, Blomstrand E, Hansson O, et al. No additional benefits of block- over evenly-distributed high-intensity interval training within a polarized microcycle. Front Physiol. 2017;8:413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5468439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28659826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bieri K, Gross M, Wachsmuth N, Schmidt W, Hoppeler H, Vogt M. HIIT im Nachwuchsfu&#xdf;ball-Blockperiodisierung von hochintensivem Intervalltraining. German Journal of Sports Medicine/Deutsche Zeitschrift fur Sportmedizin. 2013;64(10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinner C, Wahl P, Achtzehn S, Reed J, Mester J. Acute hormonal responses before and after 2 weeks of HIT in well trained junior triathletes. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(04):316&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24081622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bratland-Sanda S, Pedersen FG, Haave MN, Helgerud J, Storen O. Large inter-individual differences in responses to a block of high intensity aerobic interval training: a case series in national-level cyclists and triathletes. Int J Exerc Sci. 2020;13(2):480&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32509110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen PM, Krustrup P, Gunnarsson TP, Kiilerich K, Nybo L, Bangsbo J. VO2 kinetics and performance in soccer players after intense training and inactivity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(9):1716&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiler KS, Kjerland G&#xd8;. Quantifying training intensity distribution in elite endurance athletes: is there evidence for an &#x201c;optimal&#x201d; distribution? Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2006;16(1):49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16430681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen PB. Training for intense exercise performance: high-intensity or high-volume training? Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 2):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20840557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf6;ggl TL, Sperlich B. The training intensity distribution among well-trained and elite endurance athletes. Front Physiol. 2015;6:295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4621419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26578968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiewelhove T, Fernandez-Fernandez J, Raeder C, Kappenstein J, Meyer T, Kellmann M, et al. Acute responses and muscle damage in different high-intensity interval running protocols. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2015;56:606&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27285349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiewelhove T, Raeder C, Meyer T, Kellmann M, Pfeiffer M, Ferrauti A. Effect of repeated active recovery during a high-intensity interval-training shock microcycle on markers of fatigue. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(8):1060&#x2013;1066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26999645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwetsloot KA, John CS, Lawrence MM, Battista RA, Shanely RA. High-intensity interval training induces a modest systemic inflammatory response in active, young men. J Inflamm Res. 2014;7:9&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3920540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24520199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and external training load: 15 years on. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(2):270&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourdon PC, Cardinale M, Murray A, Gastin P, Kellmann M, Varley MC, et al. Monitoring athlete training loads: consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(Suppl 2):S2161&#x2013;S2170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M. Enhancing recovery: preventing underperformance in athletes. Human Kinetics; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M. Preventing overtraining in athletes in high-intensity sports and stress/recovery monitoring. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(Suppl 2):95&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20840567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M, Bertollo M, Bosquet L, Brink M, Coutts AJ, Duffield R, et al. Recovery and performance in sport: consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(2):240&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Monitoring training load to understand fatigue in athletes. Sports Med. 2014;44(S2):S139&#x2013;S147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25200666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Bridge MW, Meeusen R, Busschaert B, Gleeson M, Jones DA, et al. Time course of performance changes and fatigue markers during intensified training in trained cyclists. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2002;93(3):947&#x2013;956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quarrie KL, Raftery M, Blackie J, Cook CJ, Fuller CW, Gabbett TJ, et al. Managing player load in professional rugby union: a review of current knowledge and practices. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(5):421&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27506436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decroix L, De Pauw K, Foster C, Meeusen R. Guidelines to classify female subject groups in sport-science research. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(2):204&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26182438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Pauw K, Roelands B, Cheung SS, De Geus B, Rietjens G, Meeusen R. Guidelines to classify subject groups in sport-science research. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2013;8(2):111&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23428482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thoden JS, MacDougall J, Wilson B. Testing aerobic power. Physiol Test High Perform Athlete. 1991;2:107&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Perceived exertion as an indicator of somatic stress. Scand J Rehabil Med. 1970;2(2):92&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5523831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang W, Salgo IS, Medvedofsky D, Takeuchi M, Prater D, Weinert L, et al. Transthoracic 3D echocardiographic left heart chamber quantification using an automated adaptive analytics algorithm. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2016;9(7):769&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27318718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sareban M, Winkert K, Sperlich B, Berger MM, Niebauer J, Steinacker JM, et al. Speckle tracking-derived bi-atrial strain before and after eleven weeks of training in elite rowers. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6155298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30250058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerezuela-Espejo V, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Conesa-Ros E, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Are we ready to measure running power? Repeatability and concurrent validity of five commercial technologies. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;21(3):341&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32212955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess DJ. The research doesn't always apply: practical solutions to evidence-based training-load monitoring in elite team sports. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(Suppl 2):S2136&#x2013;S2141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27967277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gathercole R, Sporer B, Stellingwerff T, Sleivert G. Alternative countermovement-jump analysis to quantify acute neuromuscular fatigue. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(1):84&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mezencio B, McMaster DT, McGuigan M, Tricoli V, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: a meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(4):397&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27663764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuberger EWI, Brahmer A, Ehlert T, Kluge K, Philippi KFA, Boedecker SC, et al. Validating quantitative PCR assays for cfDNA detection without DNA extraction in exercising SLE patients. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):13581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8245561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34193884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayr B, Muller EE, Schafer C, Droese S, Breitenbach-Koller H, Schonfelder M, et al. Exercise responsive micro ribonucleic acids identify patients with coronary artery disease. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2019;26(4):348&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30373378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs R. Konsequenzerwartungen als Determinante des Sport-und Bewegungsverhaltens. Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Gesundheitspsychologie. 1994;2(4):269&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micklewright D, St Clair Gibson A, Gladwell V, Al Salman A. Development and validity of the rating-of-fatigue scale. Sports Med. 2017;47(11):2375&#x2013;2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5633636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28283993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton HR, Duthie GM, Pitchford NW, Delaney JA, Benton DT, Dascombe BJ. Effects of a 2-week high-intensity training camp on sleep activity of professional rugby league athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(7):928&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crichton N. Visual analogue scale (VAS) J Clin Nurs. 2001;10:706&#x2013;716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G, Ljunggren G, Ceci R. The increase of perceived exertion, aches and pain in the legs, heart rate and blood lactate during exercise on a bicycle ergometer. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1985;54(4):343&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4065121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, Gottschall L, Hrovatin LA, Parker S, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15(1):109&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen BA, Eriksen CW. Effects of noise letters upon the identification of a target letter in a nonsearch task. Percept Psychophys. 1974;16(1):143&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krenn B, Finkenzeller T, W&#xfc;rth S, Amesberger G. Sport type determines differences in executive functions in elite athletes. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2018;38:72&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Measures of reliability in sports medicine and science. Sports Med. 2000;30(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10907753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronnestad BR, Vikmoen O. A 11-day compressed overload and taper induces larger physiological improvements than a normal taper in elite cyclists. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29(12):1856&#x2013;1865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31410894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen PB, Shing CM, Peake JM, Coombes JS, Jenkins DG. Interval training program optimization in highly trained endurance cyclists. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(11):1801&#x2013;1807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12439086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahl P, Guldner M, Mester J. Effects and sustainability of a 13-day high-intensity shock microcycle in soccer. J Sports Sci Med. 2014;13(2):259&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3990877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24790477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolci F, Kilding AE, Chivers P, Piggott B, Hart NH. High-intensity interval training shock microcycle for enhancing sport performance: a brief review. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(4):1188&#x2013;1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31904712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romijn J, Coyle E, Sidossis L, Gastaldelli A, Horowitz J, Endert E, et al. Regulation of endogenous fat and carbohydrate metabolism in relation to exercise intensity and duration. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 1993;265(3):E380&#x2013;E391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8214047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romijn JA, Coyle EF, Sidossis LS, Rosenblatt J, Wolfe RR. Substrate metabolism during different exercise intensities in endurance-trained women. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2000;88(5):1707&#x2013;1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein S, Coyle EF, Wolfe RR. Fat metabolism during low-intensity exercise in endurance-trained and untrained men. Am J Physiol. 1994;267(6 Pt 1):E934&#x2013;E940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7810637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achten J, Gleeson M, Jeukendrup AE. Determination of the exercise intensity that elicits maximal fat oxidation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(1):92&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepley B, MacDougall JD, Cipriano N, Sutton JR, Tarnopolsky MA, Coates G. Physiological effects of tapering in highly trained athletes. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1992;72(2):706&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1559951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Hicks AL, MacDonald JR, McKelvie RS, Green HJ, Smith KM. Muscle performance and enzymatic adaptations to sprint interval training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1998;84(6):2138&#x2013;2142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9609810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, Little JP, van Essen M, Wilkin GP, Burgomaster KA, Safdar A, et al. Short-term sprint interval versus traditional endurance training: similar initial adaptations in human skeletal muscle and exercise performance. J Physiol. 2006;575(Pt 3):901&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1995688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16825308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgomaster KA, Howarth KR, Phillips SM, Rakobowchuk M, Macdonald MJ, McGee SL, et al. Similar metabolic adaptations during exercise after low volume sprint interval and traditional endurance training in humans. J Physiol. 2008;586(1):151&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17991697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daussin FN, Zoll J, Ponsot E, Dufour SP, Doutreleau S, Lonsdorfer E, et al. Training at high exercise intensity promotes qualitative adaptations of mitochondrial function in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(5):1436&#x2013;1441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18292295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hitzschke B, Wiewelhove T, Raeder C, Ferrauti A, Meyer T, Pfeiffer M, et al. Evaluation of psychological measures for the assessment of recovery and stress during a shock-microcycle in strength and high-intensity interval training. Perform Enhanc Health. 2017;5(4):147&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavorsky GS. Evidence and possible mechanisms of altered maximum heart rate with endurance training and tapering. Sports Med. 2000;29(1):13&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10688280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breitbach S, Tug S, Simon P. Circulating cell-free DNA: an up-coming molecular marker in exercise physiology. Sports Med. 2012;42(7):565&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22694348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller N, Tug S, Breitbach S, Jorgensen A, Simon P. Increases in circulating cell-free DNA during aerobic running depend on intensity and duration. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(4):455&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27617389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller N, Helmig S, Taenny P, Petry J, Schmidt S, Simon P. Circulating, cell-free DNA as a marker for exercise load in intermittent sports. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(1):e0191915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5784997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29370268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG, Destouni A, Margonis K, Jamurtas AZ, Vrettou C, Kouretas D, et al. Cell-free plasma DNA as a novel marker of aseptic inflammation severity related to exercise overtraining. Clin Chem. 2006;52(9):1820&#x2013;1824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16840584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller N, Ehlert T, Schmidt S, Ochmann D, Sterzing B, Grus F, et al. Circulating, cell-free DNA for monitoring player load in professional football. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(6):718&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30427238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez NR, DiMarco NM, Langley S, American Dietetic A, Dietitians of C, American College of Sports Medicine N et al. Position of the American Dietetic Association, Dietitians of Canada, and the American College of Sports Medicine: nutrition and athletic performance. J Am Diet Assoc. 2009;109(3):509&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19278045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Hawley JA, Wong SH, Jeukendrup AE. Carbohydrates for training and competition. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(Suppl 1):S17&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21660838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein ER, Ziegenfuss T, Kalman D, Kreider R, Campbell B, Wilborn C, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: caffeine and performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7(1):5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>