<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39720835</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Part II. Common questions and misconceptions about creatine supplementation: what does the scientific evidence really show?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2441760</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2441760</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2441760</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/15502783.2024.2441760</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Creatine monohydrate supplementation (CrM) is a safe and effective intervention for improving certain aspects of sport, exercise performance, and health across the lifespan. Despite its evidence-based pedigree, several questions and misconceptions about CrM remain. To initially address some of these concerns, our group published a narrative review in 2021 discussing the scientific evidence as to whether CrM leads to water retention and fat accumulation, is a steroid, causes hair loss, dehydration or muscle cramping, adversely affects renal and liver function, and if CrM is safe and/or effective for children, adolescents, biological females, and older adults. As a follow-up, the purpose of this paper is to evaluate additional questions and misconceptions about CrM. These include but are not limited to: 1. Can CrM provide muscle benefits without exercise? 2. Does the timing of CrM really matter? 3. Does the addition of other compounds with CrM enhance its effectiveness? 4. Does CrM and caffeine oppose each other? 5. Does CrM increase the rates of muscle protein synthesis or breakdown? 6. Is CrM an anti-inflammatory intervention? 7. Can CrM increase recovery following injury, surgery, and/or immobilization? 8. Does CrM cause cancer? 9. Will CrM increase urine production? 10. Does CrM influence blood pressure? 11. Is CrM safe to consume during pregnancy? 12. Does CrM enhance performance in adolescents? 13. Does CrM adversely affect male fertility? 14. Does the brain require a higher dose of CrM than skeletal muscle? 15. Can CrM attenuate symptoms of sleep deprivation? 16. Will CrM reduce the severity of and/or improve recovery from traumatic brain injury? Similar to our 2021 paper, an international team of creatine research experts was formed to perform a narrative review of the literature regarding CrM to formulate evidence-based responses to the aforementioned misconceptions involving CrM.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antonio</LastName><ForeName>Jose</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8930-1058</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nova Southeastern University, Department of Health and Human Performance, Davie, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Ann F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Idaho, College of Education, Health and Human Sciences, Moscow, ID, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Candow</LastName><ForeName>Darren G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6655-4482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Regina, Department of Health and Human Performance, Regina, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chilibeck</LastName><ForeName>Philip D</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Saskatchewan, College of Kinesiology, Saskatoon, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ellery</LastName><ForeName>Stacey J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash University, The Ritchie Centre, Hudson Institute of Medical Research and Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forbes</LastName><ForeName>Scott C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6896-5552</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brandon University, Department of Physical Education Studies, Brandon, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gualano</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade de Sao Paulo, Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group -School of Physical Education and Sport and Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Health System, Sports Medicine Department, La Crosse, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagim</LastName><ForeName>Andrew R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6651-5096</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lindenwood University, College of Science, Technology, and Health, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerksick</LastName><ForeName>Chad</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0458-7294</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Texas A&amp;M University, Department of Kinesiology and Sports Management, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreider</LastName><ForeName>Richard B</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3906-1658</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Agder, Department of Nutrition and Public Health, Kristiansand, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ostojic</LastName><ForeName>Sergej M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7270-2541</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Messiah University, Department of Health, Nutrition, and Exercise Science, Mechanicsburg, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rawson</LastName><ForeName>Eric S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Auburn University, School of Kinesiology, Auburn, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade de Sao Paulo, Center of Lifestyle Medicine, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roschel</LastName><ForeName>Hamilton</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade de Sao Paulo, Applied Physiology and Nutrition Research Group -School of Physical Education and Sport and Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Health System, Sports Medicine Department, La Crosse, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith-Ryan</LastName><ForeName>Abbie E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5405-304X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of North Carolina, Department of Exercise and Sport Science, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stout</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6114-1649</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Central Florida, School of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarnopolsky</LastName><ForeName>Mark A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>McMasterChildren's Hospital, Department of Pediatrics, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>VanDusseldorp</LastName><ForeName>Trisha A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9057-2720</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bonafide Health, Harrison, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willoughby</LastName><ForeName>Darryn S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine, School of Medicine, Temple TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziegenfuss</LastName><ForeName>Tim N</ForeName><Initials>TN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Applied Health Sciences, Canfield, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>MU72812GK0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003401">Creatine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003401" MajorTopicYN="Y">Creatine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064133" MajorTopicYN="N">Sports Nutritional Physiological Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sequel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opinions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social media</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>JA</b>: is the CEO and co-founder of the International Society of Sports Nutrition, an academic non-profit. The ISSN may be sponsored by companies that manufacture, market, and sell creatine-containing supplements, including Creapure, Bear Balanced, and Create. <b>DGC</b>: has conducted industry-sponsored research involving creatine supplementation and received creatine donations for scientific studies and travel support for presentations involving creatine supplementation at scientific conferences. In addition, D.G.C. serves on the Scientific Advisory Board for Alzchem and Create (companies that manufacture creatine products) and as an expert witness/consultant in legal cases involving creatine supplementation. <b>SJE</b>: serves on the Scientific Advisory Board of Alzchem. <b>SCF</b>: previously served as a scientific advisor for a company that sold creatine; has received creatine donations for scientific studies; sold creatine education resources; and is a sports nutrition advisor for the International Society of Sports Nutrition (ISSN); is a scientific advisor for Bear Balanced (a company which manufactures creatine products). <b>BG</b>: has received research grants, creatine donation for scientific studies, travel support for participation in scientific conferences, and honorarium for speaking at lectures from AlzChem (a company which manufactures creatine). Additionally, he serves as a member of the Scientific Advisory Board for Alzchem. <b>ARJ</b> and <b>CMK</b>: have consulted with and received external funding from companies that sell certain dietary ingredients and have received remuneration from companies for delivering scientific presentations at conferences. ARJ writes for online and other media outlets on topics related to exercise and nutrition. In addition, ARJ serves on the Scientific Advisory Board for Alzchem. <b>RBK</b>: has conducted sponsored research, received honorarium for presenting research, served as a scientific expert, and consulted with industry on product development related to creatine supplementation. He serves as Chair of the Creatine for Health Scientific Advisory sponsored by Alzchem. <b>SMO</b>: serves as members of the Scientific Advisory Board on creatine in health and medicine (AlzChem LLC). SMO co-owns patent &#x201c;Supplements Based on Liquid Creatine&#x201d; at European Patent Office (WO2019150323 A1). SMO has received research support related to creatine during the past 36&#x2009;months from the Ministry of Education, Science, and Technological Development; Provincial Secretariat for Higher Education and Scientific Research; Alzchem Group AG; ThermoLife International; and Hueston Hennigan LLP. SMO does not own stocks and shares in any organization. <b>MDR</b>: has performed industry- and commodity-based contract work, with recent support being received by the US National Dairy Council, The US Peanut Institute, The Center for Applied Health Sciences, MegaFood, and a three-year laboratory donation from Nutrabolt. MDR also performs consulting for personal fees with industry partners in accordance with Auburn University&#x2019;s faculty consulting and annual disclosure policies. MDR has no associated creatine grants to support. <b>ESR</b>: has conducted industry sponsored research involving creatine supplementation, has received creatine supplement donations for scientific studies and travel support for conference presentations involving creatine supplementation. In addition, ER serves on the Scientific Advisory Board for Alzchem (a company that manufactures creatine) and as an expert witness/consultant in legal cases involving creatine supplementation. <b>HR</b>: have received research grants and supplement donations for scientific studies from AlzChem, Natural Alternatives International, DuPont, J.B.S., and NotCompany. <b>ASR</b> serves as a scientific advisor for Alzchem and Create (companies which manufacturer creatine products). <b>TNZ</b>: has no conflict in terms of financial or business interests related to creatine. TNZ has received grants and contracts to conduct research on dietary supplements; has served as a paid consultant for industry; has received honoraria for speaking at conferences and writing lay articles about sports nutrition ingredients; receives royalties from the sale of several dietary supplement products (but not creatine); and has served as an expert witness on behalf of the plaintiff and defense in cases involving dietary supplements. TNZ is also a co-inventor of multiple patent applications in dietary supplements, applied nutrition, and bioactive compounds. <b>JRS</b>: has received grants and contracts to research dietary supplements, served as a paid consultant for industry, and received honoraria for speaking at conferences and writing lay articles about sports nutrition ingredients and topics. <b>MAT</b>: is the founder and CEO of Exerkine Corporation and the company sells two products that contain creatine monohydrate. The creatine monohydrate used in the two products is from Alzchem (a company that manufactures creatine). <b>AFB</b>, <b>PDC</b>, <b>TAV</b> and <b>DSW</b> declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39720835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11703406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2441760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Persky AM, Brazeau GA, Hochhaus G.. Pharmacokinetics of the dietary supplement creatine. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2003;42(6):557&#x2013;41. doi: 10.2165/00003088-200342060-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00003088-200342060-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12793840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris R, S&#xf6;derlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Lond) [Internet]. 1992.  [cited 2021 Jul
8];83(3):367&#x2013;374. Available from https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1327657/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, S&#xf6;derlund K, Timmons J, et al. Muscle creatine loading in men. J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 1996.  [cited 2021 Aug
31];81(1):232&#x2013;237. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8828669/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8828669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Stout JR. Creatine in health and disease. Nutrients [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2022 Jan
21];13(2):1&#x2013;28. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33572884/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7910963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider R, Kalman D, Antonio J, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2021 Jul
8];14(1). Available from. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28615996//</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Purpura M, Shao A, et al. Analysis of the efficacy, safety, and regulatory status of novel forms of creatine. Amino Acids [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2021 Oct
4];40(5):1369. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC3080578/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3080578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, J&#xe4;ger R, Bioavailability PM, et al. Safety, and regulatory status of creatine and related compounds: a critical review. Nutrients [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2022 Dec
17];14(5):1035. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35268011/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8912867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35268011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2023 Jan
4];14(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28615996/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Forbes SC. Perspective: creatine, a conditionally essential nutrient: building the case. Adv Nutr [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2022 Mar
8];13(1):34&#x2013;37. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34662902/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34662902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Candow DG, Forbes SC, et al. Common questions and misconceptions about creatine supplementation: what does the scientific evidence really show? J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18(1):1&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1186/s12970-021-00412-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00412-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33557850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes S, Candow D, Ferreira L, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on properties of muscle, bone, and brain function in older adults: a narrative review. J Diet Suppl [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2021 Jul
8]. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33502271/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Volek J. Effects of creatine supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and weightlifting performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(4):822&#x2013;831. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200311000-00031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200311000-00031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanhers C, Pereira B, Naughton G, et al. Creatine supplementation and upper limb strength performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2022 Mar
3];47(1):163&#x2013;173. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27328852/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27328852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda DH, Smith AE, Kendall KL, et al. The effects of creatine loading and gender on anaerobic running capacity. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2010.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];24(7):1826&#x2013;1833. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20543729/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckerson JM. Creatine as an ergogenic aid for female athletes. Strength Cond J [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];38(2):14&#x2013;23. Available from: https://journals.lww.com/nsca-scj/fulltext/2016/04000/creatine_as_an_ergogenic_aid_for_female_athletes.4.aspx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright G, Grandjean P, Pascoe D. The effects of creatine loading on thermoregulation and intermittent sprint exercise performance in a hot humid environment. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2021 Oct
4];21(3):655&#x2013;660. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17685723/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17685723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanhers C, Pereira B, Naughton G, et al. Creatine supplementation and lower limb strength performance: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sports Med [Internet]. 2015.  [cited 2022 Mar
3];45(9):1285&#x2013;1294. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25946994/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25946994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syrotuik D, Bell G. Acute creatine monohydrate supplementation: a descriptive physiological profile of responders vs. nonresponders. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2004.  [cited 2021 Jul
8];18(3):610&#x2013;617. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15320650/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck P, Kaviani M, Candow D, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Open Access J Sport Med. 2017;8:213&#x2013;226. doi: 10.2147/OAJSM.S123529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OAJSM.S123529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Chilibeck PD, et al. Variables influencing the effectiveness of creatine supplementation as a therapeutic intervention for Sarcopenia. Front Nutr. 2019;6:124. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2019.00124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6696725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31448281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brosnan ME, Brosnan JT. The role of dietary creatine. Amino Acids [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];48(8):1785&#x2013;1791. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00726-016-2188-1
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-016-2188-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26874700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaviani M, Shaw K, Chilibeck P. Benefits of creatine supplementation for vegetarians compared to omnivorous athletes: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2021 Oct
29];17(9):3041. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32349356/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7246861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32349356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt KKO, Garnham AP, Snow RJ. Skeletal muscle total creatine content and creatine transporter gene expression in vegetarians prior to and following creatine supplementation. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab [Internet]. 2004.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];14(5):517&#x2013;531. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15673098/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15673098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon A, Heywood L, Rutherford S, et al. Creatine supplementation: can it improve quality of life in the elderly without associated resistance training?
Curr Aging Sci [Internet]. 2013.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];6(3):251&#x2013;257. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24304199/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24304199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devries HA, Tichy MW, Housh TJ, et al. A method for estimating physical working capacity at the fatigue threshold (PWCFT). Ergonomics [Internet]. 1987.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];30(8):1195&#x2013;1204. Available from: https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00140138708966008
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140138708966008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3691473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerson NS, Fukuda DH, Stout JR, et al. Physical working capacity at fatigue threshold (PWCFT) is associated with sarcopenia-related body composition and measures of functionality in older adults. Arch Gerontol Geriatr [Internet]. 2014.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];59(2):300&#x2013;304. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24856645/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24856645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout J, Sue Graves B, Cramer J, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on the onset of neuromuscular fatigue threshold and muscle strength in elderly men and women (64&#x2013;86 years). J Nutr Health Aging [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2021 Jul
20];11:459&#x2013;464. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17985060/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17985060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVries HA, Brodowicz GR, Robertson LD, et al. Estimating physical working capacity and training changes in the elderly at the fatigue threshold (PWCft). Ergonomics [Internet]. 1989.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];32(8):967&#x2013;977. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2806227/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2806227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sales LP, Pinto AJ, Rodrigues SF, et al. Creatine supplementation (3 g/d) and bone health in older women: a 2-year, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Journals Gerontol Ser A [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2021 Oct
29];75(5):931&#x2013;938. Available from: https://academic.oup.com/biomedgerontology/article/75/5/931/5525440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31257405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo DM, Tritto AC, da Silva LR, et al. Effects of long-term low-dose dietary creatine supplementation in older women. Exp Gerontol. 2015;70:97&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2015.07.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2015.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26192975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Roberts MD, et al. Creatine O&#x2019;Clock: does timing of ingestion really influence muscle mass and performance? Front sport act living [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2022 Dec
30];4. Available from https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35669557//</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9163789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35669557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro F, Longobardi I, Perim P, et al. Timing of creatine supplementation around exercise: a real concern?
Nutrients [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2022 Mar
3];13(8):2844. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34445003/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8401986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34445003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Hellsten Y. Muscle blood flow and oxygen uptake in recovery from exercise. Acta Physiol Scand [Internet]. 1998.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];162(3):305&#x2013;312. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9578376/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9578376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner MJ, Casey DP. Regulation of increased blood flow (hyperemia) to muscles during exercise: a hierarchy of competing physiological needs. Physiol Rev [Internet]. 2015.  [cited 2022 Mar
3];95(2):549&#x2013;601. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25834232/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4551211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25834232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes S, Candow D. Timing of creatine supplementation and resistance training: a brief review. J Exerc Nutr [Internet]. 2018.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];1:1. Available from: https://www.journalofexerciseandnutrition.com/index.php/JEN/article/view/33
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts PA, Fox J, Peirce N, et al. Creatine ingestion augments dietary carbohydrate mediated muscle glycogen supercompensation during the initial 24&#xa0;h of recovery following prolonged exhaustive exercise in humans. Amino Acids [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2022 Dec
8];48(8):1831&#x2013;1842. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27193231/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4974290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27193231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2013.  [cited 2022 Mar
3];27(6):1609&#x2013;1617. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22990567/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22990567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Roberts MD, et al. Creatine O&#x2019;Clock: does timing of ingestion really influence muscle mass and performance? Front sport act living [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2023 Apr
19];4. Available from https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35669557/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9163789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35669557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green HJ, Chin ER, Ball-Burnett M, et al. Increases in human skeletal muscle Na(+)-k(+)-ATPase concentration with short-term training. Am J Physiol [Internet]. 1993.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];264(6):C1538&#x2013;C1541. Available from: Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8392800/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8392800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie DL. Functional insights into the creatine transporter. Subcell Biochem [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2022 Dec
18];46:99&#x2013;118. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18652074/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb PJ, Hayes A. Effects of supplement timing and resistance exercise on skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2006.  [cited 2022 Mar
8];38(11):1918&#x2013;1925. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17095924/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Krentz JR, Candow DG. Timing of creatine supplementation does not influence gains in unilateral muscle hypertrophy or strength from resistance training in young adults: a within-subject design. J Sports Med Phys Fitness [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2022 Mar
8];61(9):1219&#x2013;1225. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34610729/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34610729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Zello GA, Ling B, et al. Comparison of creatine supplementation before versus after supervised resistance training in healthy older adults. Res Sport Med [Internet]. 2014.  [cited 2022 Mar
8];22(1):61&#x2013;74. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24392772/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24392772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Ciccone V. The effects of pre versus post workout supplementation of creatine monohydrate on body composition and strength. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2013.  [cited 2022 Mar
8];10(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23919405/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23919405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurado-Castro JM, Campos-P&#xe9;rez J, Vilches-Redondo M&#xc1;, et al. Morning versus evening intake of creatine in elite female handball players. Int J Environ Res Public Health [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2022 Mar
8];19(1):393. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35010653/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8744932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinan NE, Hagele AM, Jagim AR, et al. Effects of creatine monohydrate timing on resistance training adaptations and body composition after 8&#xa0;weeks in male and female collegiate athletes. Front Sport Act Living [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];4. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36465581/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9708881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36465581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow D, Vogt E, Johannsmeyer S, et al. Strategic creatine supplementation and resistance training in healthy older adults. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab [Internet]. 2015.  [cited 2021 Jul
7];40(7):689&#x2013;694. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25993883/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25993883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Roberts MD, et al. ISSN exercise &amp; sports nutrition review update: research &amp; recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2018.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];15(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30068354/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30068354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenge GR, Simpson EJ, Greenhaff PL. Protein- and carbohydrate-induced augmentation of whole body creatine retention in humans. J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 2000.  [cited 2022 Jan
20];89(3):1165&#x2013;1171. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10956365/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney K, Bryson J, Phuyal J, et al. Creatine supplementation alters insulin secretion and glucose homeostasis in vivo. Metabolism [Internet]. 2002.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];51(4):518&#x2013;522. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11912564/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11912564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Salles Painneli DE, Roschel VH, et al. Creatine in type 2 diabetes: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2021 Jul
19];43(5):770&#x2013;778. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20881878/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20881878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves CRR, Ferreira JC, De Siqueira-Filho MA, et al. Creatine-induced glucose uptake in type 2 diabetes: a role for AMPK-&#x3b1;?
Amino Acids [Internet]. 2012.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];43(4):1803&#x2013;1807. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22349765/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22349765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eijnde O&#x2019;, Urs&#xf8; B, Richter BEA, et al. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on human muscle GLUT4 protein content after immobilization. Diabetes [Internet]. 2001.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];50(1):18&#x2013;23. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11147785/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11147785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green A, Hultman E, Macdonald I, et al. Carbohydrate ingestion augments skeletal muscle creatine accumulation during creatine supplementation in humans. Am J Physiol [Internet]. 1996.  [cited 2021 Jul
8];271(5):E821&#x2013;E826. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8944667/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8944667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AG, Arnall DA, Kokkonen J, et al. Muscle glycogen supercompensation is enhanced by prior creatine supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2001.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];33:1096&#x2013;1100. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11445755/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Chilibeck PD, Parise G, et al. Effect of &#x3b1;-Lipoic acid combined with creatine monohydrate on human skeletal muscle creatine and phosphagen concentration. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab [Internet]. 2003.  [cited 2022 Jan
20];13(3):294&#x2013;302. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14669930/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14669930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb PJ, Williams AD, Stathis CG, et al. Effects of whey isolate, creatine, and resistance training on muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];39(2):298&#x2013;307. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17277594/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornish SM, Candow DG, Jantz NT, et al. Conjugated linoleic acid combined with creatine monohydrate and whey protein supplementation during strength training. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19(1):79&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.19.1.79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.19.1.79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor DM, Crowe MJ. EFFECTS of SIX WEEKS of &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (HMB) and HMB/CREATINE SUPPLEMENTATION on STRENGTH, POWER, and ANTHROPOMETRY of HIGHLY TRAINED ATHLETES. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];21(2):419&#x2013;423. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17530933/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowe MJ, Dm O, Lukins JE. The effects of &#xdf;-hydroxy-&#xdf;-methylbutyrate (HMB) and HMB/Creatine supplementation on indices of health in highly trained athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab [Internet]. 2003.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];13(2):184&#x2013;197. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12945829/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12945829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Vandusseldorp TA, Hester GM, et al. The addition of &#x3b2;-Hydroxy &#x3b2;-Methylbutyrate (HMB) to creatine monohydrate supplementation does not improve anthropometric and performance maintenance across a collegiate rugby season. [cited 2024 Jun 13]. doi: 10.1186/s12970-020-00359-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-020-00359-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Landa J, Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xe1;zaro D, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, et al. Effect of Ten weeks of creatine monohydrate plus HMB supplementation on athletic performance tests in elite male endurance athletes. Nutrients [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];12. Available from 193. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31936727/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7019716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31936727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf3;wko E, Ostaszewski P, Jank M, et al. Creatine and &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (HMB) additively increase lean body mass and muscle strength during a weight-training program. Nutrition [Internet]. 2001.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];17(7&#x2013;8):558&#x2013;566. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11448573/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11448573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber JJ, Mcdermott AY, Mcgaughey KJ, et al. Effects of combined creatine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on repeated sprint performance in trained men. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2013.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];27(1):252&#x2013;258. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23254493/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23254493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. Effects of combined creatine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation on soccer-specific performance in elite soccer players: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];18(13):6919. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34203286/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8297001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34203286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero AA, Keskinen KL, Malvela MT, et al. Combined creatine and sodium bicarbonate supplementation enhances interval swimming. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2004.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];18(2):306&#x2013;310. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15142001/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarshin A, Fallahi V, Forbes SC, et al. Short-term co-ingestion of creatine and sodium bicarbonate improves anaerobic performance in trained taekwondo athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];18(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33478522/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7819230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33478522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadi M, Askarian A, Shirvani H, et al. Effects of four weeks of Beta-alanine supplementation combined with one week of creatine loading on physical and cognitive performance in military personnel. Int J Environ Res Public Health [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2023 Apr
19];19(13):7992. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35805647/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9265371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35805647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Kang J, et al. Effect of creatine and &#xdf;-alanine supplementation on performance and endocrine responses in strength/power athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab [Internet]. 2006.  [cited 2023 May
24];16(4):430&#x2013;446. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17136944/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17136944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Cramer JT, Mielke M, et al. Effects of twenty-eight days of beta-alanine and creatine monohydrate supplementation on the physical working capacity at neuromuscular fatigue threshold. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2006.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];20(4):928&#x2013;931. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17194255/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoeller RF, Stout JR, O&#x2019;Kroy JA, et al. Effects of 28 days of beta-alanine and creatine monohydrate supplementation on aerobic power, ventilatory and lactate thresholds, and time to exhaustion. Amino Acids [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];33(3):505&#x2013;510. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16953366/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16953366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Campbell WI, et al. The effects of creatine monohydrate supplementation with and without D-pinitol on resistance training adaptations. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2009.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];23(9):2673&#x2013;2682. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19858753/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19858753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor L, Poole C, Pena E, et al. Effects of combined creatine plus fenugreek extract vs. Creatine plus carbohydrate supplementation on resistance training adaptations. J Sports Sci Med [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];10:254. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC3761853/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam H, Yorgason NJ, Hazell TJ. Creatine co-ingestion with carbohydrate or cinnamon extract provides no added benefit to anaerobic performance. Eur J Sport Sci [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];16(6):685&#x2013;693. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26313717/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26313717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Jagim AR, Pischel I, et al. Effects of short-term ingestion of Russian tarragon prior to creatine monohydrate supplementation on whole body and muscle creatine retention and anaerobic sprint capacity: a preliminary investigation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2014.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];11(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24568653/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3975968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polyviou TP, Easton C, Beis L, et al. Effects of glycerol and creatine hyperhydration on doping-relevant blood parameters. Nutrients [Internet]. 2012.  [cited 2021 Oct
4];4(9):1171. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC3475229/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3475229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23112907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Easton C, Turner S, Pitsiladis YP. Creatine and glycerol hyperhydration in trained subjects before exercise in the heat. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];17(1):70&#x2013;91. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17460334/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17460334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beis LY, Polyviou T, Malkova D, et al. The effects of creatine and glycerol hyperhydration on running economy in well trained endurance runners. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];8(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22176668/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3283512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22176668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beis LY, Polyviou T, Malkova D, et al. The effects of creatine and glycerol hyperhydration on running economy in well trained endurance runners. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2021 Oct
4];8(1):24. Available from: http://www.jissn.com/content/8/1/24/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3283512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22176668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Bodin K, Soderlund K, et al. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on skeletal muscle phosphocreatine resynthesis. Am J Physiol [Internet]. 1994.  [cited 2024 Mar
19];266(5):E725&#x2013;E730. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8203511/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8203511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanakoski J, Kosunen V, Meririnne E, et al. Creatine and caffeine in anaerobic and aerobic exercise: effects on physical performance and pharmacokinetic considerations. Int J Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1998;36(5):258&#x2013;262. Available from: http://www.jissn.com/content/8/1/24
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9629989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Effect of caffeine on the neuromuscular system &#x2014; potential as an ergogenic aid. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab [Internet]. 2008.  [cited 2024 Oct
31];33(6):1284&#x2013;1289. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19088790/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Gillis N, Van Leemputte M, et al. Caffeine counteracts the ergogenic action of muscle creatine loading. J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 1996.  [cited 2022 Apr
8];80(2):452&#x2013;457. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8929583/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8929583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, &#x2019;Eijnde TBO, Van LM. Opposite actions of caffeine and creatine on muscle relaxation time in humans. J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 2002.  [cited 2022 Apr
8];92(2):513&#x2013;518. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11796658/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11796658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trexler ET, Smith-Ryan AE, Roelofs EJ, et al. Effects of coffee and caffeine anhydrous intake during creatine loading. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];30(5):1438&#x2013;1446. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26439785/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4808512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26439785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinho AH, Gon&#xe7;alves JS, Ara&#xfa;jo PK, et al. Effects of creatine and caffeine ingestion in combination on exercise performance: a systematic review. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];63(20):4785&#x2013;4798. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34845944/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34845944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elosegui S, L&#xf3;pez-Seoane J, Mart&#xed;nez-Ferr&#xe1;n M, et al. Interaction between caffeine and creatine when used as concurrent ergogenic supplements: a systematic review. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];32(4):285&#x2013;295. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35016154/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35016154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Smith PM, Davison RCR, et al. Caffeine is ergogenic after supplementation of oral creatine monohydrate. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2002.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];34(11):1785&#x2013;1792. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12439084/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12439084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CL, Lin JC, Cheng CF. Effect of caffeine ingestion after creatine supplementation on intermittent high-intensity sprint performance. Eur J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];111(8):1669&#x2013;1677. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21207054/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21207054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orange S, Sadler I. The effect of caffeine ingestion after creatine supplementation on peak torque production. Grad J Sport Exerc Phys Educ Res. 2015;3:80&#x2013;92. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12439084//</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakulak A, Candow DG, Totosy de Zepetnek J, et al. Effects of creatine and caffeine supplementation during resistance training on body composition, strength, endurance, rating of perceived exertion and fatigue in trained young adults. J Diet Suppl [Internet]. 2021;19(5):587&#x2013;602. Available from doi: 10.1080/19390211.2021.1904085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19390211.2021.1904085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33759701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeronimo D, Germano M, Fiorante F, et al. Caffeine potentiates the ergogenic effects of creatine. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2017:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke R, Pi&#xf1;ero A, Coleman M, et al. The effects of creatine supplementation combined with resistance training on regional measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Nutrients [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2023 Apr
29];15(9):2116. Available from: https://www.mdpi.com/2072-6643/15/9/2116/htm
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10180745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG. Creatine and strength training in older adults: an update. Transl Exerc Biomed [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Oct
28]. p. 1&#x2013;11. Available from: https://www.degruyter.com/document/doi/10.1515/teb-2024-0019/html</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/teb-2024-0019/html</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis M, Poortmans JR, Francaux M, et al. Creatine supplementation has no effect on human muscle protein turnover at rest in the postabsorptive or fed states. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab [Internet]. 2003.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];284(4):E764&#x2013;E770. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12475751/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12475751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis M, Poortmans JR, Francaux M, et al. No effect of creatine supplementation on human myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic protein synthesis after resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab [Internet]. 2003.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];285(5):E1089&#x2013;E1094. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12824083/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12824083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, Mihic S, MacLennan D, et al. Effects of acute creatine monohydrate supplementation on leucine kinetics and mixed-muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 2001.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];91(3):1041&#x2013;1047. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11509496/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Little JP, Chilibeck PD, et al. Low-dose creatine combined with protein during resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2008.  [cited 2021 Jul
19];40(9):1645&#x2013;1652. Available from: https://journals.lww.com/acsm-msse/Fulltext/2008/09000/Low_Dose_Creatine_Combined_with_Protein_during.13.aspx
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18685526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannsmeyer S, Candow DG, Brahms CM, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation and drop-set resistance training in untrained aging adults. Exp Gerontol. 2016;83:112&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2016.08.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2016.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27523919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordingley DM, Cornish SM, Candow DG. Anti-inflammatory and anti-catabolic effects of creatine supplementation: a brief review. Nutrients [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2022 Dec
8];14(3):544. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35276903/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8839648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35276903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw SK, Ma S, Kim MB, et al. Coordinated redistribution of leukocyte LFA-1 and endothelial cell ICAM-1 accompany neutrophil transmigration. J Exp Med [Internet]. 2004.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];200(12):1571&#x2013;1580. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15611287/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2212000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15611287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M. Concentric or eccentric training effect on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2002.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];34(1):63&#x2013;69. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11782649/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LL, Wells JM, Houmard JA, et al. Increases in plasma prostaglandin E 2 after eccentric exercise [Internet]. 1993.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];25(8):451&#x2013;452. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8225195/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8225195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos RVT, Bassit RA, Caperuto EC, et al. The effect of creatine supplementation upon inflammatory and muscle soreness markers after a 30km race. Life Sci. 2004;75(16):1917&#x2013;1924. doi: 10.1016/j.lfs.2003.11.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2003.11.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15306159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassit RA, Curi R, Rosa Lfbp C. Creatine supplementation reduces plasma levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines and PGE2 after a half-ironman competition. Amin Acids 2007 352 [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2021 Oct
4];35(2):425&#x2013;431. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00726-007-0582-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-007-0582-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17917696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deminice R, Rosa FT, Franco GS, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on oxidative stress and inflammatory markers after repeated-sprint exercise in humans. Nutrition. 2013;29(9):1127&#x2013;1132. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2013.03.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2013.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Conti MP, Miles MP. Creatine supplementation does not reduce muscle damage or enhance recovery from resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];21(4):1208&#x2013;1213. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18076246/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Artioli GG, Poortmans JR, et al. Exploring the therapeutic role of creatine supplementation. Amino Acids [Internet]. 2010.  [cited 2022 Jan
20];38(1):31&#x2013;44. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19253023/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19253023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Roschel H, Lancha AH, et al. In sickness and in health: the widespread application of creatine supplementation. Amino Acids. 2012;43(2):519&#x2013;529. doi: 10.1007/s00726-011-1132-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-011-1132-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausmann O, Fouad K, Wallimann T, et al. Protective effects of oral creatine supplementation on spinal cord injury in rats. Spinal Cord [Internet]. 2002.  [cited 2021 Oct
25];40(9):449&#x2013;456. Available from: https://www.nature.com/articles/3101330
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12185606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zkan &#xd6;, Duman &#xd6;, Haspolat &#x15e;, et al. Effect of systemic creatine monohydrate supplementation on denervated muscle during reinnervation: experimental study in the rat. J Reconstr Microsurg [Internet]. 2005.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];21(8):573&#x2013;580. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16292735/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16292735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Eijnde BOT, Van Leemputte M, et al. Oral creatine supplementation facilitates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol [Internet]. 2001.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];536(2):625&#x2013;633. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11600695/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston APW, Burke DG, Macneil LG, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation during cast-induced immobilization on the preservation of muscle mass, strength, and endurance. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2009.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];23(1):116&#x2013;120. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19130643/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backx EMP, Hangelbroek R, Snijders T, et al. Creatine loading does not preserve muscle mass or strength during leg immobilization in healthy, young males: a randomized controlled trial. Sports Med [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];47(8):1661&#x2013;1671. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28054322/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5507980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler TF, Nicholas SJ, Hershman EB, et al. The effect of creatine supplementation on strength recovery after anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind trial. Am J Sports Med [Internet]. 2004.  [cited 2024 Jun
13];32(2):383&#x2013;388. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14977662/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss M, Kaddurah-Daouk R. Creatine and creatinine metabolism. Physiol Rev. 2000;80(3):1107&#x2013;1213. doi: 10.1152/physrev.2000.80.3.1107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.2000.80.3.1107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10893433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirvish SS, Huang Q, Chen SC, et al. Metabolism of carcinogenic nitrosamines in the rat and human esophagus and induction of esophageal adenocarcinoma in rats. Endoscopy [Internet]. 1993.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];25(9):627&#x2013;631. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8119218/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8119218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirvish SS, Reimers KJ, Kutler B, et al. Nitrate and nitrite concentrations in human saliva for men and women at different ages and times of the day and their consistency over time. Eur J Cancer Prev [Internet]. 2000.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];9(5):335&#x2013;342. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11075887/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11075887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirvish S. The etiology of gastric cancer. Intragastric nitrosamide formation and other theories. J Natl Cancer Inst. 1983;71(3):629&#x2013;647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6350677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman PE. Review: putative mutagens and carcinogens in foods. I. Nitrate/nitrite ingestion and gastric cancer mortality. Environ Mutagen [Internet]. 1983.  [cited 2024 Jun
26];5(1):111&#x2013;121. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6832084/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6832084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfau W, Rosenvold K, Young JF. Formation of mutagenic heterocyclic aromatic amines in fried pork from duroc and landrace pigs upon feed supplementation with creatine monohydrate. Food Chem Toxicol [Internet]. 2006.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];44(12):2086&#x2013;2091. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16973250/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>dos S PR, D&#xf6;rr FA, Pinto E, et al. Can creatine supplementation form carcinogenic heterocyclic amines in humans?
J Physiol [Internet]. 2015.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];593(17):3959&#x2013;3971. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC4575580/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4575580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26148133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Grasaas E, Cvejic J. Dietary creatine and cancer risk in the U.S. population: NHANES 2017&#x2013;2020. J Funct Foods. 2023;108:105733. doi: 10.1016/j.jff.2023.105733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2023.105733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Zhu Z, Yan H, et al. Creatine promotes cancer metastasis through activation of Smad2/3. Cell Metab. 2021;33(6):1111&#x2013;1123.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2021.03.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2021.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky M, Bourgeois J, Snow R, et al. Histological assessment of intermediate- and long-term creatine monohydrate supplementation in mice and rats. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol [Internet]. 2003.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];285(4):R762&#x2013;R769. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12959920/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12959920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Liu R, Gao X, et al. Targeting serine-glycine-one-carbon metabolism as a vulnerability in cancers. Biomark Res [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];11(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37147729/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10161514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37147729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggetto L, Clottes E, Vial C. Low mitochondrial proton leak due to high membrane cholesterol content and cytosolic creatine kinase as two features of the deviant bioenergetics of Ehrlich and AS30-D tumor cells. Cancer Res. 1992;52(18):4935&#x2013;4941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1516050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi Y, Li Q, Liu B, et al. Ubiquitous mitochondrial creatine kinase promotes the progression of gastric cancer through a JNK-MAPK/JUN/HK2 axis regulated glycolysis. Gastric Cancer [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];26(1):69&#x2013;81. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36114400/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9813075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36114400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayyappan V, Jenkinson NM, Tressler CM, et al. Context-dependent roles for ubiquitous mitochondrial creatine kinase CKMT1 in breast cancer progression. Cell Rep [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];43(4):114121. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38615320/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11100297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38615320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel R, Ford CA, Rodgers L, et al. Cyclocreatine suppresses creatine metabolism and impairs prostate cancer progression. Cancer Res [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];82(14):2565&#x2013;2575. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35675421/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9381098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35675421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillie J, O&#x2019;Keefe M, Valinski H, et al. Cyclocreatine (1-carboxymethyl-2-iminoimidazolidine) inhibits growth of a broad spectrum of cancer cells derived from solid tumors. Cancer Res. 1993;53(13):3172&#x2013;3178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8319226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella PS, Marinello PC, Padilha CS, et al. Creatine supplementation does not promote tumor growth or enhance tumor aggressiveness in walker-256 tumor-bearing rats. Nutrition [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
14]. p. 79&#x2013;80. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32882636/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di BS, Ma X, Wang X, et al. Creatine uptake regulates CD8 T cell antitumor immunity. J Exp Med [Internet]. 2019.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];216(12):2869&#x2013;2882. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC6888972/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6888972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31628186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller EE, Evans AE, Cohn M. Inhibition of rate of tumor growth by creatine and cyclocreatine. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A [Internet]. 1993.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];90(8):3304&#x2013;3308. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8475072/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC46288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8475072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen CA, Askenasy N, Jain RK, et al. Creatine and cyclocreatine treatment of human colon adenocarcinoma xenografts: 31P and 1H magnetic resonance spectroscopic studies. Br J Cancer [Internet]. 1999.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];79(2):278&#x2013;285. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9888469/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2362210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9888469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Yang L. Creatine in T cell antitumor immunity and cancer immunotherapy. Nutrients [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];13(5):1633. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34067957/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8152274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34067957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brose A, Parise G, Tarnopolsky M. Creatine supplementation enhances isometric strength and body composition improvements following strength exercise training in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci [Internet]. 2003.  [cited 2021 Oct
29];58(1):B11&#x2013;B19. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12560406/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12560406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrusch M, Chilibeck P, Chad K, et al. Creatine supplementation combined with resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2001.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];33(12):2111&#x2013;2117. Available from: https://journals.lww.com/acsm-msse/Fulltext/2001/12000/Creatine_supplementation_combined_with_resistance.21.aspx
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves M, Gualano B, Roschel H, et al. Beneficial effect of creatine supplementation in knee osteoarthritis. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2021 Oct
4];43(8):1538&#x2013;1543. Available from: https://journals.lww.com/acsm-msse/Fulltext/2011/08000/Beneficial_Effect_of_Creatine_Supplementation_in.20.aspx
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Ostojic SM, et al. Meta-analysis examining the importance of creatine ingestion strategies on lean tissue mass and strength in older adults. 2021;13(6):1912. doi: 10.3390/nu13061912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13061912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8229907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coletta AM, Simon LH, Maslana K, et al. Creatine supplementation and resistance training to preserve muscle mass and attenuate cancer progression (CREATINE-52): a protocol for a double-blind randomized controlled trial. BMC Cancer [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];24(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38637770/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11025211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38637770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel DI, Gonzalez A, Moon C, et al. Exercise and creatine supplementation to augment the adaptation of exercise training among breast cancer survivors completing chemotherapy: protocol for an open-label randomized controlled trial (the THRIVE study). JMIR Res Protoc [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];11(4):e26827. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35363152/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9015753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez Aguirre-Betolaza A, Cacicedo J, Casta&#xf1;eda-Babarro A. Creatine supplementation and resistance training in patients with breast cancer (CaRtiC study): protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Oncol [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];47(4):161&#x2013;168. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38018533/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38018533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredahl EC, Busekrus RB, Hydock DS. The combined effect of creatine and resistance training on doxorubicin-induced muscle dysfunction. Nutr Cancer [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];72(6):939&#x2013;947. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31588781/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31588781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredahl EC, Hydock DS. Creatine supplementation and doxorubicin-induced skeletal muscle dysfunction: an ex vivo investigation. Nutr Cancer [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];69(4):607&#x2013;615. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28323480/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28323480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa Godinho LRL, Cella PS, Guimar&#xe3;es TAS, et al. Creatine supplementation potentiates exercise protective effects against doxorubicin-induced hepatotoxicity in mice. Antioxidants (Basel) [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];12(4):823. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37107198/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10135080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37107198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torok ZA, Busekrus RB, Hydock DS. Effects of creatine supplementation on muscle fatigue in rats receiving doxorubicin treatment. Nutr Cancer [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];72(2):252&#x2013;259. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31184509/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31184509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law D, Magrini MA, Siedlik JA, et al. Creatine and resistance training: a combined approach to attenuate doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity. Nutrients [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];15(18):4048. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37764831/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10536171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37764831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgeois JM, Nagel K, Pearce E, et al. Creatine monohydrate attenuates body fat accumulation in children with acute lymphoblastic leukemia during maintenance chemotherapy. Pediatr Blood Cancer [Internet]. 2008.  [cited 2022 Apr
5];51(2):183&#x2013;187. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18421708/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18421708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawata CM, Pannabecker TL. Mammalian urine concentration: a review of renal medullary architecture and membrane transporters. J Comp Physiol B [Internet]. 2018.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];188(6):899&#x2013;918. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29797052/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29797052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Melton C, Rasmussen CJ, et al. Long-term creatine supplementation does not significantly affect clinical markers of health in athletes. Mol Cell Biochem. 2003;244(1/2):95&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1023/A:1022469320296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022469320296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12701816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riesberg LA, Weed SA, McDonald TL, et al. Beyond muscles: the untapped potential of creatine. Int Immunopharmacol [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];37:31. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC4915971/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4915971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26778152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brewster LM, Mairuhu G, Bindraban NR, et al. Creatine kinase activity is associated with blood pressure. Circulation [Internet]. 2006.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];114(19):2034&#x2013;2039. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17075013/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17075013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armentano M, Brenner A, Hedman T, et al. The effect and safety of short-term creatine supplementation on performance of push-ups. Mil Med [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];172(3):312&#x2013;317. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17436778/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17436778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihic S, MacDonald J, McKenzie S, et al. Acute creatine loading increases fat-free mass, but does not affect blood pressure, plasma creatinine, or CK activity in men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc [Internet]. 2000.  [cited 2021 Oct
4];32(2):291&#x2013;296. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10694109/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy AJ, Watsford ML, Coutts AJ, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on aerobic power and cardiovascular structure and function. J Sci Med Sport. 2005;8(3):305&#x2013;313. doi: 10.1016/S1440-2440(05)80041-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1440-2440(05)80041-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16248471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horjus DL, Oudman I, van Montfrans GA, et al. Creatine and creatine analogues in hypertension and cardiovascular disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2024 Jun
14]. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22071819/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6823205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22071819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Gordon JJ, et al. A 2-year randomized controlled trial on creatine supplementation during exercise for postmenopausal bone health. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2023. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000003202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10487398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37144634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves CR, Murai IH, Ramona P, et al. No effect of creatine supplementation on oxidative stress and cardiovascular parameters in spontaneously hypertensive rats. J Int Soc Sport Nutr
2012 91 [Internet]. 2012.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];9(1):1&#x2013;4. Available from:
https://jissn.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1550-2783-9-13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-9-13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3342894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22480293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Gonzalez MA, Wieder R, Kim J-S, et al. Creatine supplementation attenuates hemodynamic and arterial stiffness responses following an acute bout of isokinetic exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];111(9):1965&#x2013;1971. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00421-011-1832-4
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1832-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21249385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fakih H, MacLusky N, DeCherney A, et al. Enhancement of human sperm motility and velocity in vitro: effects of calcium and creatine phosphate. Fertil Steril [Internet]. 1986.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];46(5):938&#x2013;944. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3781011/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3781011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickinson H, Ellery S, Ireland Z, et al. Creatine supplementation during pregnancy: summary of experimental studies suggesting a treatment to improve fetal and neonatal morbidity and reduce mortality in high-risk human pregnancy. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth [Internet]. 2014.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];14(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24766646/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4007139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24766646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herring CM, Bazer FW, Johnson GA, et al. Impacts of maternal dietary protein intake on fetal survival, growth, and development. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) [Internet]. 2018.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];243(6):525&#x2013;533. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29466875/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5882021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29466875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muccini AM, Tran NT, de GD, et al. Creatine metabolism in female reproduction, pregnancy and newborn health. Nutrients [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];13(2):1&#x2013;25. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC7912953/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33540766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Guingand Dl, Palmer KR, Callahan DL, et al. Creatine and pregnancy outcomes: a prospective cohort study of creatine metabolism in low-risk pregnant females. Am J Clin Nutr [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];119(3):838&#x2013;849. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38432717/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38432717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark LC, Thompson H, Beck EI. The excretion of creatine and creatinine during pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol [Internet]. 1951.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];62(3):576&#x2013;583. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14877920/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14877920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto J, Barros AS, Domingues MRM, et al. Following healthy pregnancy by NMR metabolomics of plasma and correlation to urine. J Proteome Res [Internet]. 2015.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];14(2):1263&#x2013;1274. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25529102/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25529102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Guingand Dl, Palmer KR, Callahan DL, et al. The role of creatine in placental energy metabolism at birth: initial insights from the creatine and pregnancy outcomes (CPO) cohort study of low-risk pregnancy. Placenta. 2023;140:e70. doi: 10.1016/j.placenta.2023.07.221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.placenta.2023.07.221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihatsch WA, Stahl B, Braun U. The umbilical cord creatine flux and time course of human milk creatine across lactation. Nutrients [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
26];16(3):345. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38337631/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10857059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korovljev D, Todorovic N, Stajer V, et al. Dietary intake of creatine in children aged 0&#x2013;24 months. Ann Nutr Metab [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2024 Jun
26];77(3):185&#x2013;188. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33906195/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33906195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Forbes SC, Candow DG. Do pregnant women consume enough creatine? Evidence from NHANES 2011&#x2013;2018. Ann Nutr Metab [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];78(2):114&#x2013;116. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34763333/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Stea TH, Ellery SJ, et al. Association between dietary intake of creatine and female reproductive health: evidence from NHANES 2017&#x2013;2020. Food Sci Nutr [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
14]. Available from: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/fsn3.4135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/fsn3.4135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11266896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39055234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry MJ, Schlegel M, Kowalski GM, et al. UNICORN babies: understanding circulating and cerebral creatine levels of the preterm infant. An observational study protocol. Front Physiol [Internet]. 2019.  [cited 2024 Jun
26];10:142. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC6417365/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30899224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran NT, Kelly SB, Snow RJ, et al. Assessing creatine supplementation for neuroprotection against perinatal hypoxic-ischaemic encephalopathy: a systematic review of perinatal and adult pre-clinical studies. Cells [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];10(11):2902. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34831126/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8616304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellery SJ, Kelleher M, Grigsby P, et al. Antenatal prevention of cerebral palsy and childhood disability: is the impossible possible?
J Physiol [Internet]. 2018.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];596(23):5593&#x2013;5609. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29928763/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6265564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29928763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlman JM, Tack ED, Martin T, et al. Acute systemic organ injury in term infants after asphyxia. Am J Dis Child [Internet]. 1989.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];143(5):617&#x2013;620. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2718998/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2718998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Guingand Dl, Palmer KR, Bilardi JE, et al. Acceptability of dietary or nutritional supplementation in pregnancy (ADONS) &#x2013; exploring the consumer&#x2019;s perspective on introducing creatine monohydrate as a pregnancy supplement. Midwifery [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];82. Available from 102599. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31877396/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31877396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ireland Z, Dickinson H, Snow R, et al. Maternal creatine: does it reach the fetus and improve survival after an acute hypoxic episode in the spiny mouse (acomys cahirinus)?
Am J Obstet Gynecol [Internet]. 2008.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];198(4):.e431.1&#x2013;.e431.6. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18295173/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18295173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaRosa DA, Ellery SJ, Parkington HC, et al. Maternal creatine supplementation during pregnancy prevents long-term changes in diaphragm muscle structure and function after birth asphyxia. PLoS One [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];11(3):e0149840. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26930669/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4773130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26930669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larosa DA, Ellery SJ, Snow RJ, et al. Maternal creatine supplementation during pregnancy prevents acute and long-term deficits in skeletal muscle after birth asphyxia: a study of structure and function of hind limb muscle in the spiny mouse. Pediatr Res [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];80(6):852&#x2013;860. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27466898/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27466898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellery SJ, Larosa DA, Cullen-Mcewen LA, et al. Renal dysfunction in early adulthood following birth asphyxia in male spiny mice, and its amelioration by maternal creatine supplementation during pregnancy. Pediatr Res [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];81(4):646&#x2013;653. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27997529/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27997529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellery SJ, LaRosa DA, Kett MM, et al. Dietary creatine supplementation during pregnancy: a study on the effects of creatine supplementation on creatine homeostasis and renal excretory function in spiny mice. Amino Acids [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];48(8):1819&#x2013;1830. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26695944/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26695944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran NT, Muccini AM, Snow RJ, et al. The physiological effects of creatine supplementation in fetal sheep before, during, and after umbilical cord occlusion and global hypoxia. J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];131(3):1088&#x2013;1099. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34382841/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34382841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran NT, Kowalski GM, Muccini AM, et al. Creatine supplementation reduces the cerebral oxidative and metabolic stress responses to acute in utero hypoxia in the late-gestation fetal sheep. J Physiol [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];600(13):3193&#x2013;3210. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35587817/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9542404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35587817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muccini AM, Tran NT, Hale N, et al. The effects of in utero fetal hypoxia and creatine treatment on mitochondrial function in the late gestation fetal sheep brain. Oxid Med Cell Longev [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];2022. Available from 1&#x2013;19. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35132347/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35132347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran NT, Muccini AM, Hale N, et al. Creatine in the fetal brain: a regional investigation of acute global hypoxia and creatine supplementation in a translational fetal sheep model. Front Cell Neurosci [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];17. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37066075/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10097948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37066075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartini S, Lattanzi D, Ambrogini P, et al. Maternal creatine supplementation affects the morpho-functional development of hippocampal neurons in rat offspring. Neuroscience [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];312:120&#x2013;129. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26592720/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26592720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartini S, Lattanzi D, Di Palma M, et al. Maternal creatine supplementation positively affects male rat hippocampal synaptic plasticity in adult offspring. Nutrients [Internet]. 2019.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];11(9):2014. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31461895/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31461895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de GD, Palmer KR, Snow RJ, et al. Risk of adverse outcomes in females taking oral creatine monohydrate: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2021 Oct
5];12(6):1&#x2013;26. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC7353222/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32549301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wax B, Kerksick C, Jagim A, et al. Creatine for exercise and sports performance, with recovery considerations for healthy populations. Nutrients [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2021 Jul
8];13(6):1915. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34199588/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8228369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB. Effects of creatine supplementation on performance and training adaptations. Mol Cell Biochem. 2003;244(1/2):89&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1023/A:1022465203458</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022465203458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12701815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson B, Vladich T, Blanksby B. Effects of 4&#xa0;weeks of creatine supplementation in junior swimmers on freestyle sprint and swim bench performance. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2002.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];16(4):485&#x2013;490. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12423175/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindstaff P, Kreider R, Bishop R, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on repetitive sprint performance and body composition in competitive swimmers. Int J Sport Nutr [Internet]. 1997.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];7(4):330&#x2013;348. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9407259/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9407259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juh&#xe1;sz I, Gy&#xf6;re I, Csende Z, et al. Creatine supplementation improves the anaerobic performance of elite junior fin swimmers. Acta Physiol Hung [Internet]. 2009.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];96(3):325&#x2013;336. Available from: https://akjournals.com/view/journals/036/96/3/article-p325.xml
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19706374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodorou A, Cooke C, King R, et al. The effect of longer-term creatine supplementation on elite swimming performance after an acute creatine loading. J Sports Sci [Internet]. 1999.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];17:853&#x2013;859. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10585165/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10585165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodorou A, Havenetidis K, Zanker C, et al. Effects of acute creatine loading with or without carbohydrate on repeated bouts of maximal swimming in high-performance swimmers. J Strength Cond Res [Internet]. 2005.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];19(2):265&#x2013;269. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15903360/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Mez&#xea;ncio B, Amaral S, et al. Creatine monohydrate supplementation on lower-limb muscle power in Brazilian elite soccer players. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2014.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];11(1):32. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC4077550/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24991195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohebbi H, Rahnama N, Moghadassi M, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation on sprint and skill performance in young soccer players. Middle East J Sci Res. 2012;12:397&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM. Creatine supplementation in young soccer players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab [Internet]. 2004.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];14(1):95&#x2013;103. Available from: https://journals.humankinetics.com/view/journals/ijsnem/14/1/article-p95.xml
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15129933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Silva A, Buzzachera CF, Pi&#xe7;arro IDC, et al. Effect of low dose, short-term creatine supplementation on muscle power output in elite youth soccer players. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];14(1):5. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC5296953/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28190980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda &#xc1; H, Jofr&#xe9;-Sald&#xed;a E, Torres-Banduc M, et al. Effects of a low dose of orally administered creatine monohydrate on post-fatigue muscle power in young soccer players. Nutrients [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];16(9):1324. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38732571/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11085131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38732571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Stecker RA, Harty PS, et al. Safety of creatine supplementation in active adolescents and youth: a brief review. Front Nutr. 2018;5:115. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2018.00115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2018.00115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6279854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30547033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metzger GA, Minneci PM, Gehred A, et al. Creatine supplementation in the pediatric and adolescent athlete&#x2013; a literature review. J Orthop [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];38:73&#x2013;78. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37008451/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10063391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37008451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juhasz I, Kopkane J, Hajdu P, et al. Creatine supplementation supports the rehabilitation of adolescent fin swimmers in tendon overuse injury cases. J Sports Sci Med. 2018;17:279&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5950745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29769829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Osta R, Almont T, Diligent C, et al. Anabolic steroids abuse and male infertility. Basic Clin Androl [Internet]. 2016.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];26(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26855782/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26855782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketheeswaran S, Haahr T, Povlsen B, et al. Protein supplementation intake for bodybuilding and resistance training may impact sperm quality of subfertile men undergoing fertility treatment: a pilot study. Asian J Androl [Internet]. 2019.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];21(2):208&#x2013;211. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30226218/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6413551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30226218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers ME, Arnold BL, Weltman AL, et al. Creatine supplementation increases total body water without altering fluid distribution. J Athl Train [Internet]. 2003.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];38:44. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC155510/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC155510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasrallah F, Hammami MB, Omar S, et al. Semen creatine and creatine kinase activity as an indicator of sperm quality. Clin Lab [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];66(9/2020):1751&#x2013;1757. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32902220/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32902220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer GS, Krahe R, Goodwin LA, et al. Identification of a testis-expressed creatine transporter gene at 16p11.2 and confirmation of the X-linked locus to Xq28. Genomics [Internet]. 1996.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];34(1):143&#x2013;146. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8661037/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8661037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Stea TH, Engeset D. Creatine as a promising component of paternal preconception diet. Nutrients [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];14(3):586. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35276945/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8839819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35276945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umehara T, Kawai T, Goto M, et al. Creatine enhances the duration of sperm capacitation: a novel factor for improving in vitro fertilization with small numbers of sperm. Hum Reprod [Internet]. 2018.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];33(6):1117&#x2013;1129. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29635630/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5972610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29635630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umehara T, Tsujita N, Goto M, et al. Methyl-beta cyclodextrin and creatine work synergistically under hypoxic conditions to improve the fertilization ability of boar ejaculated sperm. Anim Sci J [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];91(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33314533/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33314533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapeh RS, Zhandi M, Zaghari M, et al. Effects of guanidinoacetic acid diet supplementation on semen quality and fertility of broiler breeder roosters. Theriogenology [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];89:178&#x2013;182. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28043349/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28043349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot SA, Diaz FA, Gutierrez-Castillo EJ, et al. 94&#x2003;Effect of glycine and creatine on the. Reprod Fertil Dev [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];34(2):284. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35231224/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35231224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;ttenborg SS, Glazer CH, H&#xe6;rvig KK, et al. Semen quality among young healthy men taking protein supplements. Fertil Steril [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2024 Jun
14];114(1):89&#x2013;96. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32387273/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Ostojic SM, Forbes SC, et al. Does one dose of creatine supplementation fit all?
Adv Exerc Heal Sci [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
3]. Available from: https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S2950273X24000249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Cordingley DM, Cornish SM, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on brain function and health. Nutrients [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2022 Apr
5];14(5):921. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35267907/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8912287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35267907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris R, S&#xf6;derlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci [Internet]. 1992.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];83(3):367&#x2013;374. Available from https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1327657/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenge GR, Lambourne J, Casey A, et al. Stimulatory effect of insulin on creatine accumulation in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol - Endocrinol Metab [Internet]. 1998.  [cited 2022 Jan
20];275(6):E974&#x2013;979. Available from: https://journals.physiology.org/doi/abs/10.1152/ajpendo.1998.275.6.E974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1998.275.6.E974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9843739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Ostojic SM, et al. &#x201c;Heads up&#x201d; for creatine supplementation and its potential applications for brain health and function. Sports Med [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2023 Jul
19]. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37368234/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10721691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37368234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dechent P, Pouwels PJW, Wilken B, et al. Increase of total creatine in human brain after oral supplementation of creatine-monohydrate. Am J Physiol [Internet]. 1999.  [cited 2022 Dec
18];277(3):R698&#x2013;R704. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10484486/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10484486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordji-Nejad A, Matusch A, Kleed&#xf6;rfer S, et al. Single dose creatine improves cognitive performance and induces changes in cerebral high energy phosphates during sleep deprivation. Sci Rep [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Mar
27];14(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38418482/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10902318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38418482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan JW, Takahashi K. Cerebral energetic effects of creatine supplementation in humans. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2021 Oct
29];292(4):R1745. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC3570026/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3570026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17185404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slankamenac J, Ranisavljev M, Todorovic N, et al. Effects of six-month creatine supplementation on patient- and clinician-reported outcomes, and tissue creatine levels in patients with post-COVID-19 fatigue syndrome. Food Sci Nutr [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Mar
19];11(11):6899&#x2013;6906. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37970399/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10630839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37970399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solis M, Artioli G, Otaduy M, et al. Effect of age, diet, and tissue type on PCr response to creatine supplementation. J Appl Physiol [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2021 Oct
29];123(2):407&#x2013;414. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28572496/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28572496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan E, Gualano B, Rawson ES. Beyond muscle: the effects of creatine supplementation on brain creatine, cognitive processing, and traumatic brain injury. Eur J Sport Sci. 2019;19(1):1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2018.1500644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1500644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30086660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriarty T, Bourbeau K, Dorman K, et al. Dose&#x2013;response of creatine supplementation on cognitive function in healthy young adults. Brain Sci [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 May
10];13(9):1276. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37759877/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10526554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37759877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braissant O, Agat HH. GAMT and SLC6A8 distribution in the central nervous system, in relation to creatine deficiency syndromes: a review. J Inherit Metab Dis [Internet]. 2008.  [cited 2022 Dec
18];31(2):230&#x2013;239. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18392746/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18392746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo DG, Sung YH, Hellem TL, et al. Open-label adjunctive creatine for female adolescents with ssri-resistant major depressive disorder: a 31-phosphorus magnetic resonance spectroscopy study. J Affect Disord. 2011;135(1&#x2013;3):354&#x2013;361. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2011.07.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2011.07.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21831448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Harris RC, Swain J, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation and sleep deprivation, with mild exercise, on cognitive and psychomotor performance, mood state, and plasma concentrations of catecholamines and cortisol. Psychopharmacology (Berl) [Internet]. 2006.  [cited 2021 Oct
29];185(1):93&#x2013;103. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00213-005-0269-z
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-005-0269-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16416332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Harris RC, Howard AN, et al. Creatine supplementation, sleep deprivation, cortisol, melatonin and behavior. Physiol Behav [Internet]. 2007.  [cited 2022 Dec
17];90(1):21&#x2013;28. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17046034/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17046034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Crewther BT, Kilduff LP, et al. Skill execution and sleep deprivation: effects of acute caffeine or creatine supplementation - a randomized placebo-controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr [Internet]. 2011.  [cited 2022 Dec
18];8(1). Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21324203/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3049131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21324203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Lieberman HR, Walsh TM, et al. Creatine supplementation does not improve cognitive function in young adults. Physiol Behav [Internet]. 2008.  [cited 2022 Dec
17];95(1&#x2013;2):130&#x2013;134. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18579168/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18579168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roschel H, Gualano B, Ostojic SM, et al. Creatine supplementation and brain health. Nutrients [Internet]. 2021.  [cited 2021 Oct
26];13(2):1&#x2013;10. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC7916590/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7916590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33578876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signoretti S, Di Pietro V, Vagnozzi R, et al. Transient alterations of creatine, creatine phosphate, N-acetylaspartate and high-energy phosphates after mild traumatic brain injury in the rat. Mol Cell Biochem [Internet]. 2010.  [cited 2022 Jan
21];333(1&#x2013;2):269&#x2013;277. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19688182/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19688182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vagnozzi R, Signoretti S, Floris R, et al. Decrease in N-acetylaspartate following concussion may be coupled to decrease in creatine. J Head Trauma Rehabil [Internet]. 2013.  [cited 2022 Jan
21];28(4):284&#x2013;292. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23249772/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23249772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainsley Dean PJ, Arikan G, Opitz B, et al. Potential for use of creatine supplementation following mild traumatic brain injury. Concussion (Lond, Engl) [Internet]. 2017.  [cited 2022 Jan
21];2(2):CNC34. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30202575/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6094347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30202575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan P, Geiger J, Mattson M, et al. Dietary supplement creatine protects against traumatic brain injury. Ann Neurol [Internet]. 2000.  [cited 2021 Oct
25];48(5):723&#x2013;729. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11079535/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakellaris G, Kotsiou M, Tamiolaki M, et al. Prevention of complications related to traumatic brain injury in children and adolescents with creatine administration: an open label randomized pilot study. J Trauma [Internet]. 2006.  [cited 2022 Dec
18];61(2):322&#x2013;329. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16917445/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16917445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakellaris G, Nasis G, Kotsiou M, et al. Prevention of traumatic headache, dizziness and fatigue with creatine administration. A pilot study. Acta Paediatr [Internet]. 2008.  [cited 2021 Oct
6];97(1):31&#x2013;34. Available from:/pmc/articles/PMC2583396/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2583396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18053002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakellaris G, Partalis N, Nasis G, et al. Outcome of traumatic dysarthria and lingual problems of understanding with creatine administration. An open label randomized Pilot study. J Trauma Treat [Internet]. 2012.  [cited 2022 Jan
21];1(3):120. Available from: https://www.hilarispublisher.com/open-access/outcome-of-traumatic-dysarthria-and-lingual-problems-of-understanding-with-creatine-administration.-an-open-label-randomized-pilot-study-2167-1222.1000120.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce JM, La PL, Walker R, et al. Magnetic resonance spectroscopy of traumatic brain injury and subconcussive hits: a systematic review and meta&#x2013;analysis. J Neurotrauma [Internet]. 2022.  [cited 2024 Jun
17];39(21&#x2013;22):1455&#x2013;1476. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35838132/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9689773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35838132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alosco ML, Tripodis Y, Rowland B, et al. A magnetic resonance spectroscopy investigation in symptomatic former NFL players. Brain Imaging Behav [Internet]. 2020.  [cited 2023 Apr
28];14(5):1419&#x2013;1429. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11682-019-00060-4
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11682-019-00060-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6994233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30848432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8;dker RL, Marcussen M. Pilot study protocol of a randomized controlled trial for the potential effects of creatine monohydrate on persistent post-concussive symptoms. Front Neurol [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Jun
17];14. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37475743/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10354866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37475743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Grasaas E, Baltic S, et al. Dietary creatine is associated with lower serum neurofilament light chain levels. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab [Internet]. 2024.  [cited 2024 Jun
26]. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38780027/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38780027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>