<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35855835</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-6718</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2022</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Computational and mathematical methods in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Comput Math Methods Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feedforward Control Combined with 4F Management on Postoperative Nursing Effects and Motor Function of Meniscus Sports Injuries: Based on a Prospective Case Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5447509</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5447509</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5447509</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2022/5447509</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Because active functional training and management after knee cartilage sports injury is the key to treatment, care of patients after an operation with knee cartilage sports injury is critical.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To explore the effect of feedforward control combined with 4F management and after an operation nursing effect on patients with knee cartilage sports injury.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">According to the random number table method, 100 patients with knee cartilage sports injury who were nursed in our hospital from June 2019 to June 2021 were selected as the research objects and divided into the control group and the instance of watching, noticing, or making a statement group with 50 cases in each group according to the different nursing order. Among them, the control group adopted 4F management combined with feedforward control nursing mode: all-weather, whole-process, whole-system, and all-around services for patients. On this basis, the instance of watching, noticing, or making a statement group cooperated with early healing/repairing training to compare fear and stress-related self-test of the two groups of patients after an operation. Knee function and quality of care are scored using tables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After nursing, the knee joint function score of the instance of watching, noticing, or making a statement group was higher than that of the control group, while the pain after the operation, sleep quality, fear, and stress self-rating scale scores were significantly lower than the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The whole-process management, body position placement, risk evaluation, repairing training, all-weather service, whole-system management, and comprehensive service of the two groups of patients were very much improved. The nursing quality of watching, noticing, or making a statement group was significantly higher than the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Feedforward control combined with 4F management combined with early repairing training can effectively reduce the fear and stress after an operation pain and sleep quality of knee cartilage sports injury and help increase the recovery of knee combined function in a good way.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Qin Lu and Qunya Yu.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Qin</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Shanghai Jiao Tong University Affiliated Sixth People's Hospital, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Qunya</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9081-9866</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Shanghai Jiao Tong University Affiliated Sixth People's Hospital, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016441">Retracted Publication</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Comput Math Methods Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101277751</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-670X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="RetractionIn"><RefSource>Comput Math Methods Med. 2023 Jun 28;2023:9859164. doi: 10.1155/2023/9859164.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37416270</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007718" MajorTopicYN="Y">Knee Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007719" MajorTopicYN="N">Knee Joint</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072600" MajorTopicYN="Y">Meniscus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35855835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9288311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/5447509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Qi Y., Tang R., Shi Z., Feng G., Zhang W. Wnt5a/platelet-rich plasma synergistically inhibits IL-1&#x3b2;-induced inflammatory activity through NF-&#x3ba;B signaling pathway and prevents cartilage damage and promotes meniscus regeneration. Journal of Tissue Engineering and Regenerative Medicine . 2021;15(7):612&#x2013;624. doi: 10.1002/term.3198.Epub.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/term.3198.Epub</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33843153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J. Q., Lin Z. R., Li J., Pan L. Assessment of MRI value in diagnosis of knee joint sports injury. Journal of Practical Medical Imaging . 2015;16(6):492&#x2013;494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Li R., Luo C. L., et al. Effect of blood flow restriction training on knee function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Guangdong Medical Journal . 2019;40(10):1405&#x2013;1408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englund M., Haugen I. K., Guermazi A., et al. Evidence that meniscus damage may be a component of osteoarthritis: the Framingham study. Osteoarthritis and Cartilage . 2016;24(2):270&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2015.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2015.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4724446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26318660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noyes F. R., Chen R. C., Barber-Westin S. D., Potter H. G. Greater than 10-year results of red-white longitudinal meniscal repairs in patients 20 years of age or younger. The American Journal of Sports Medicine . 2011;39(5):1008&#x2013;1017. doi: 10.1177/0363546510392014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510392014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21278428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meckes J. K., Caram&#xe9;s B., Olmer M., et al. Compromised autophagy precedes meniscus degeneration and cartilage damage in mice. Osteoarthritis Cartilage . 2017;25(11):1880&#x2013;1889. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2017.07.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2017.07.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5650923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28801209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiranaka T., Furumatsu T., Kamatsuki Y., et al. Early chondral damage following meniscus repairs with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Asia-Pacific Journal of Sports Medicine, Arthroscopy, Rehabilitation and Technology . 2020;20(20):1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.asmart.2020.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmart.2020.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6997621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32042596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Fu P., Wu H., Pei M. Meniscus, articular cartilage and nucleus pulposus: a comparative review of cartilage-like tissues in anatomy, development and function. Cell and tissue research . 2017;370(1):53&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1007/s00441-017-2613-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00441-017-2613-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5645221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28413859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y., Qiang L., Ai G., Aihua L., Yunpeng L., Lifeng M. A comparative study of partial meniscectomy and non-surgical treatment of degenerative injuries of the medial meniscus of the knee. Journal of Clinical and Experimental Medicine . 2020;19(2):205&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jingfang Y., Wenzhi H., Fang H., Yanqin W. Effect of 4F management on early postoperative stress in patients with meniscus sports injury knee arthroscopy day surgery. Chinese Journal of Modern Nursing . 2016;22(32):4598&#x2013;4601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Huang L., Fu Y., et al. A novel process for phosphatidylserine production using a Pichia pastoris whole-cell biocatalyst with overexpression of phospholipase D from Streptomyces halstedii in a purely aqueous system. Food Chemistry . 2019;274(274):535&#x2013;542. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2018.08.105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2018.08.105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30372975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanshan H. The application of 4F management standards for service posts in the cultivation of nurses' quality. World Latest Medical Information Digest (Electronic Edition) . 2018;18(99):249&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xueling J., Naichao B., Xiaocui W. Effects of 4F management on role enhancement and optimism tendency in patients with interventional liver cancer surgery under ultrasound guidance. Chinese Journal of Clinical Oncology and Rehabilitati . 2019;26(3):345&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanmei S. Intervention effects of feed-forward control care in patients with enteral nutrition in ICU. Journal of North Sichuan Medical College . 2021;36(3):394&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aihua Y. Effects of feed-forward control care on children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. Journal of Qilu Nursing . 2022;28(7):149&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint Surgery Group of Orthopaedic Branch of Chinese Medical Association. Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of osteoarthritis. Chinese Journal of Orthopedics . 2018;38(12):705&#x2013;715. doi: 10.3760/cma.j.issn.0253-2352.2018.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.issn.0253-2352.2018.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint Surgery Group, Orthopaedic Branch of Chinese Medical Association. Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of osteoarthritis. Chinese Journal of Orthopedics . 2018;38(12):705&#x2013;715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhijun Y., Ergang W., Zhong T., et al. Analysis of the operation mode of community health service centers jointly organized by large tertiary hospitals and the government. China Health Service Management . 2020;37(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianjiang O., Zhili T., Gang C. Effects of traditional Chinese medicine package therapy combined with neuromuscular stimulation training on proprioceptive recovery of meniscus injury. Shi Zhen Guo Yi Guo Yao . 2019;30(4):921&#x2013;922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yau D. K. W., Underwood M. J., Joynt G. M., Lee A. Effect of preparative rehabilitation on recovery after cardiac surgery. Annals of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine . 2021;64 doi: 10.1016/j.rehab.2020.03.014.Epub.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rehab.2020.03.014.Epub</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sentissi O., Moullet C. Programme 4F &#xe0; Gen&#xe8;ve: activit&#xe9; physique et nutrition adapt&#xe9;es lors de troubles psychiatriques. Rev Med Suisse . 2019;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31580022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavormina R., Tavormina M. G., Nemoianni E. Dance and go on: a project of psychosocial rehabilitation on the road. Psychiatria Danubina . 2015;27(Suppl 1):S143&#x2013;S147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26417750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury N., Scott C., O'Dell M. W. Recovery in glioblastoma multiforme during inpatient rehabilitation is equivalent in first versus repeat resection: a 10-year retrospective analysis. PM &amp; R : The Journal of Injury, Function, and Rehabilitation . 2022;14(1):40&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1002/pmrj.12573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.12573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33583134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y. J., Chen K. L., Chou Y. T., Hsueh I. P., Hou C. Y., Hsieh C. L. Comparison of the responsiveness of the long-form and simplified stroke rehabilitation assessment of movement: group- and individual-level analysis. Physical Therapy . 2015;95(8):1172&#x2013;1183. doi: 10.2522/ptj.20140331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20140331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25744276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai R., Lam O. L. T., Lo E. C. M., Li L. S. W., McGrath C. Oral health-related quality of life in patients with stroke: a randomized clinical trial of oral hygiene care during outpatient rehabilitation. Scientific Reports . 2017;7(1):p. 7632. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-07666-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-07666-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5550442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuldt T., Kramp B., Dommerich S. Die stimmliche rehabilitation mit ESKA-Herrmann Stimmprothesen. Ein 10-Jahres Bericht (n=201) Laryngo-Rhino-Otologie . 2012;91 doi: 10.1055/s-0031-1291338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0031-1291338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22131175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai R., Lam O. L. T., Lo E. C. M., Li L. S. W., McGrath C. A randomized clinical trial of oral hygiene care programmes during stroke rehabilitation. Journal of dentistry . 2017;61:48&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1016/j.jdent.2017.04.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdent.2017.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28392215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing Z., Zhang Y., Huiqing Z. Evaluation of the application effect of department nursing WeChat platform in the quality management of nursing units. China Digital Medicine . 2020;15(1):139&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John R., Dhillon M. S., Syam K., Prabhakar S., Behera P., Singh H. Epidemiological profile of sports-related knee injuries in northern India: an observational study at a tertiary care centre. J Clin Orthop Trauma . 2016;7(3):207&#x2013;211. doi: 10.1016/j.jcot.2016.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcot.2016.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4949405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27489418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jochymek J., Peterkov&#xe1; T. V&#xfd;sledky dlouhodob&#xe9;ho sledov&#xe1;n&#xed; po opera&#x10d;n&#xed;m l&#xe9;&#x10d;en&#xed; pro symptomatick&#xfd; fibul&#xe1;rn&#xed; diskoidn&#xed; meniskus v d&#x11b;tsk&#xe9;m v&#x11b;kuLong-term outcomes of surgical management of symptomatic fibular discoid meniscus in childhood. Acta Chirurgiae Orthopaedicae et Traumatologiae Cechoslovaca . 2015;82(5):353&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26516954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhenfang L., Liu Y., Xuemei Z., Qiong H., Qiaoping C. Effect of early resistance training on knee joint functional rehabilitation in TKA patients. Nursing Research . 2020;34(2):355&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing F. Individualized nursing intervention observation of arthroscopic surgery for knee meniscus injury. China Disability Medicine . 2017;25(16):82&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrell B., Agnew Z., Nagarajan S., Houde J., Ivry R. B. Impaired feedforward control and enhanced feedback control of speech in patients with cerebellar degeneration. The Journal of Neuroscience . 2017;37(38):9249&#x2013;9258. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3363-16.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3363-16.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5607467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28842410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y., Yu H. Biomimetic hybrid feedback feedforward neural-network learning control. IEEE Trans Neural Netw Learn Syst . 2017;28(6):1481&#x2013;1487. doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2016.2527501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2016.2527501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28113822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGeary D. D., McGeary C. A., Gatchel R. J. A comprehensive review of telehealth for pain management: where we are and the way ahead. Pain Practice . 2012;12(7):570&#x2013;577. doi: 10.1111/j.1533-2500.2012.00534.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1533-2500.2012.00534.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22303839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nallani R., Fox C. C., Sykes K. J., et al. Pain management and education for ambulatory surgery: a qualitative study of perioperative nurses. The Journal of Surgical Research . 2021;260:419&#x2013;427. doi: 10.1016/j.jss.2020.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jss.2020.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10165861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33256986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnod A., Maindet C., George B., Minello C., Allano G., Lemaire A. A clinical approach to the management of cancer-related pain in emergency situations. Supportive Care in Cancer . 2019;27(8):3147&#x2013;3157. doi: 10.1007/s00520-019-04830-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-019-04830-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31076900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons J., Carter B., Craske J. Developing a framework to support the delivery of effective pain management for children: an exploratory qualitative study. Pain Research &amp; Management . 2020;2020(2020):5476425&#x2013;5476428. doi: 10.1155/2020/5476425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/5476425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7641711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moseley G. L., Baranoff J., Rio E., Stewart M., Derman W., Hainline B. Nonpharmacological management of persistent pain in elite athletes: rationale and recommendations. Clinical Journal of Sport Medicine . 2018;28(5):472&#x2013;479. doi: 10.1097/JSM.0000000000000601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30024479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams S., Keogh S., Douglas C. Improving paediatric pain management in the emergency department: an integrative literature review. International Journal of Nursing Studies . 2019;94:9&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2019.02.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2019.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30928719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail A., Forgeron P., Polomeno V., Gharaibeh H., Dagg W., Harrison D. Pain management interventions in the paediatric intensive care unit: a scoping review. Intensive &amp; Critical Care Nursing . 2019;54:96&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1016/j.iccn.2019.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iccn.2019.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31204106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Weng L., Chen Z., et al. Development and testing of a mobile app for pain management among cancer patients discharged from hospital treatment: randomized controlled trial. JMIR mHealth and uHealth . 2019;7(5, article e12542) doi: 10.2196/12542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6658226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31144672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen M. P., Patterson D. R. Hypnotic approaches for chronic pain management: clinical implications of recent research findings. American psychologist . 2014;69(2):167&#x2013;177. doi: 10.1037/a0035644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0035644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24547802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoseiri K., Allami M., Soroush M. R., Rastkhadiv M. Y. Assistive technologies for pain management in people with amputation: a literature review. Military Medical Research . 2018;5(1):p. 1. doi: 10.1186/s40779-018-0151-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40779-018-0151-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5778696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29502531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzghoul B. I., Abdullah N. A. Pain management practices by nurses: an application of the knowledge, attitude and practices (KAP) model. Global journal of health science . 2015;8(6):154&#x2013;160. doi: 10.5539/gjhs.v8n6p154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/gjhs.v8n6p154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4954874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26755474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goesling J., Lin L. A., Clauw D. J. Psychiatry and pain management: at the intersection of chronic pain and mental health. Current Psychiatry Reports . 2018;20(2):p. 12. doi: 10.1007/s11920-018-0872-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11920-018-0872-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29504088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X. L., Yan F. X. Effect of early exercise rehabilitation nursing on functional recovery of knee meniscus after injury. China Practical Medicine . 2019;14(34):185&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>