<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40853524</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical and Mental Recovery for Female Footballers: Considerations and Approaches for Better Practice.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02246-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Increased physiological demands in elite women's football coupled with growing demands on and off the field of play have inevitably placed more pressure on players. Recovery therefore plays a critical role in sustaining health and maintaining high performance for training and readiness to compete. Recovery strategies start with the fundamental need for adequate sleep quality and duration, and nutrition. When these are in place, recovery could be further augmented with additional recovery techniques. Where there is a priority to maximise an adaptative response, there is an argument to withhold additional recovery strategies to maximise the adaptation stimulus. Conversely, when rapid recovery is desired for an imminent match, or in a tournament setting, the application of recovery strategies must be prioritised. This article discusses the approaches that should be considered to support physical and mental recovery and regeneration strategies in the context of women's football. Whilst most recovery research is based on studies of male athletes, there is also work that exclusively focusses on female individuals; this article highlights the potential applicability of this collective work and specific considerations for female football players and offers practical recommendations. Although far from complete, there is emerging evidence of an interplay between cyclical variations of reproductive hormones, associated menstrual cycle/hormonal contraception symptoms and recovery/adaptation. Whilst there is an expected individual variability in menstrual cycle and symptoms, these additional female-specific considerations might contribute to the total stress and recovery needs of the individual athlete. Exploring the role of recovery strategies in support of training and competition for female football players represents an exciting area for future research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howatson</LastName><ForeName>Glyn</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8494-2043</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Exercise, and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health and Life Sciences, Northumbria University, Sutherland Building, Newcastle-Upon-Tyne, NE1 8ST, UK. glyn.howatson@northumbria.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Water Research Group, School of Biological Sciences, North-West University, Potchefstroom, South Africa. glyn.howatson@northumbria.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russell</LastName><ForeName>Suzanna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9146-756X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedlar</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3075-9101</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Technology and Health Sciences, St Mary's University, Twickenham, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport, Exercise and Health, Division of Surgery and Interventional Science, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halson</LastName><ForeName>Shona</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1047-3878</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Funding: This article is published in a supplement issue that was supported by the F&#xe9;d&#xe9;ration Internationale de Football Association (FIFA). Conflicts of Interest: Glyn Howatson, Charles Pedlar and Shona Halson are scientific advisors to FIFA&#x2019;s Female Health Project. Charles Pedlar is a guest editor of this supplement. Charles Pedlar played no part in the peer review or decision making of this article at the editorial level and contributed solely as an author. Charles Pedlar is also&#xa0;a&#xa0;consultant with Orreco, Galway, Ireland. Shona Halson is an Editorial Board member of Sports Medicine. Shona Halson was not involved in the selection of peer reviewers for the manuscript nor any of the subsequent editorial decisions. Glyn Howatson and Suzanna Russell have no conflicts of interest that are directly relevant to the content of this article.&#xa0; Ethics Approval: Not applicable. Consent to Participate: Not applicable. Consent for Publication: Not applicable. Availability of Data and Material: Not applicable. Code Availability: Not applicable. Authors&#x2019; Contributions: GH, SH, SR and CP all contributed to drafting and editing the work. All authors approved this version to be published and agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work in ensuring that questions related to the accuracy or integrity of any part of the work are appropriately investigated and resolved.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40853524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02246-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02246-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scott D, Bradley P. Physical analysis of the FIFA Women's World Cup France 2019&#x2122;. 2020. https://digitalhub.fifa.com/m/4f40a98140d305e2/original/zijqly4oednqa5gffgaz-pdf.pdf . Accessed 23 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FIFA. Contextual considerations for the physical preparation of players following the FIFA Women&#x2019;s World Cup. 2024. https://www.fifatrainingcentre.com/en/game/tournaments/fifa-womens-world-cup/2023/post-tournament-analysis/physical-analysis/contextual-considerations/contextual-considerations-for-the-physical-preparation-of-players-following-the-fifa-women-s-world-cup.php . Accessed 23 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selye H. The general adaptation syndrome and the diseases of adaptation. J Allergy. 1946;17(6):231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20276007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunanan AJ, et al. The general adaptation syndrome: a foundation for the concept of periodization. Sports Med. 2018;48(4):787&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29307100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK, Senefeld JW. Sex differences in human performance. J Physiol. 2024;602(17):4129&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39106346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott-Sale KJ, et al. The effects of oral contraceptives on exercise performance in women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(10):1785&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32666247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7497464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNulty KL, et al. The effects of menstrual cycle phase on exercise performance in eumenorrheic women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(10):1813&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7497427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus I, et al. Exercise-induced muscle damage: mechanism, assessment and nutritional factors to accelerate recovery. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121(4):969&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33420603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis E, Frick U, Schmidtbleicher D. Frequency variations of strength training sessions triggered by the phases of the menstrual cycle. Int J Sports Med. 1995;16(8):545&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8776210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikstrom-Frisen L, Boraxbekk CJ, Henriksson-Larsen K. Effects on power, strength and lean body mass of menstrual/oral contraceptive cycle based resistance training. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2017;57(1&#x2013;2):43&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26558833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackney AC, Kallman AL, Aggon E. Female sex hormones and the recovery from exercise: menstrual cycle phase affects responses. Biomed Hum Kinet. 2019;11(1):87&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31179123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6555618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velders M, Diel P. How sex hormones promote skeletal muscle regeneration. Sports Med. 2013;43(11):1089&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23888432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronkainen PH, et al. Postmenopausal hormone replacement therapy modifies skeletal muscle composition and function: a study with monozygotic twin pairs. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2009;107(1):25&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19246654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertone-Johnson ER, et al. Association of inflammation markers with menstrual symptom severity and premenstrual syndrome in young women. Hum Reprod. 2014;29(9):1987&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25035435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruinvels G, et al. Prevalence and frequency of menstrual cycle symptoms are associated with availability to train and compete: a study of 6812 exercising women recruited using the Strava exercise app. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(8):438&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33199360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans J, Salamonsen LA. Inflammation, leukocytes and menstruation. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2012;13(4):277&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22865231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oester C, et al. Inconsistencies in the perceived impact of the menstrual cycle on sport performance and in the prevalence of menstrual cycle symptoms: a scoping review of the literature. J Sci Med Sport. 2024;27(6):373&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38508888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill J, et al. Compression garments and recovery from exercise-induced muscle damage: a meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(18):1340&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23757486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausswirth C, Le Meur Y. Physiological and nutritional aspects of post-exercise recovery: specific recommendations for female athletes. Sports Med. 2011;41(10):861&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21923203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia FM, Krustrup P. Metabolic response and fatigue in soccer. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2007;2(2):111&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas K, et al. Etiology and recovery of neuromuscular fatigue after simulated soccer match play. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(5):955&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28060035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall S, et al. The assessment of neuromuscular fatigue during 120 min of simulated soccer exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(4):687&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28247027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GA, et al. Match exposure, consecutive match number, and recovery days affect match running during international women&#x2019;s soccer tournaments. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(3):577&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38090983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida A, et al. Acute effects of match-play on neuromuscular and subjective recovery and stress state in Division I collegiate female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(4):976&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormack WP, et al. Reduced high-intensity-running rate in college women&#x2019;s soccer when games are separated by 42 hours. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(4):436&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25365765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper LD, et al. Test-retest reliability of physiological and performance responses to 120 minutes of simulated soccer match play. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(11):3178&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26950356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, van Someren KA. The prevention and treatment of exercise-induced muscle damage. Sports Med. 2008;38(6):483&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paschalis V, et al. Eccentric exercise affects the upper limbs more than the lower limbs in position sense and reaction angle. J Sports Sci. 2010;28(1):33&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20013463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Valenciano A, et al. Injury profile in women&#x2019;s football: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51(3):423&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellingwerff T, et al. Overtraining syndrome (OTS) and relative energy deficiency in sport (RED-S): shared pathways, symptoms and complexities. Sports Med. 2021;51(11):2251&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34181189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, et al. Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: joint consensus statement of the European College of Sport Science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(1):186&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan R, et al. Postexercise cold water immersion modulates skeletal muscle PGC-1alpha mRNA expression in immersed and nonimmersed limbs: evidence of systemic regulation. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2017;123(2):451&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28546467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo CH, et al. Passive and post-exercise cold-water immersion augments PGC-1alpha and VEGF expression in human skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(11&#x2013;12):2315&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27699485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5118413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregson W, Howatson G, Thorpe R. A periodised recovery strategy framework for the elite footbll player. Aspetar Sports Med J. 2022;11:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowley ES, et al. &#x201c;Invisible Sportswomen&#x201d;: the sex data gap in sport and exercise science research. Women Sport Phys Activity J. 2021;29(2):146&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ES, et al. Methodology review: a protocol to audit the representation of female athletes in sports science and sports medicine research. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2022;32(2):114&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35168200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panduro J, et al. Physical performance and loading for six playing positions in elite female football: full-game, end-game, and peak periods. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(Suppl. 1):115&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33749045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello SE, et al. Detrimental effects on executive function and mood following consecutive days of repeated high-intensity sprint interval exercise in trained male sports players. J Sports Sci. 2022;40(7):783&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34955079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Krustrup P, Bangsbo J. Fatigue in soccer: a brief review. J Sports Sci. 2005;23(6):593&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownstein CG, et al. Etiology and recovery of neuromuscular fatigue following competitive soccer match-play. Front Physiol. 2017;8:831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29118716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5661001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, et al. Maximal voluntary contraction force, SR function and glycogen resynthesis during the first 72 h after a high-level competitive soccer game. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(12):2987&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21448723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson H, et al. Neuromuscular fatigue and recovery in elite female soccer: effects of active recovery. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(2):372&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souglis A, et al. Time course of oxidative stress, inflammation, and muscle damage markers for 5 days after a soccer match: effects of sex and playing position. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(7):2045&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29309386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enns DL, Tiidus PM. The influence of estrogen on skeletal muscle: sex matters. Sports Med. 2010;40(1):41&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20020786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goulart KNO, et al. Fatigue and recovery time course after female soccer matches: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2022;8(1):72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35657571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9166924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, et al. Muscle metabolism and impaired sprint performance in an elite women&#x2019;s football game. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(Suppl. 1):27&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roepstorff C, et al. Higher skeletal muscle alpha2AMPK activation and lower energy charge and fat oxidation in men than in women during submaximal exercise. J Physiol. 2006;574(Pt 1):125&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16600998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1817798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, et al. Skeletal muscle phenotype and game performance in elite women football players. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(Suppl. 1):39&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34427373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansdell P, et al. Physiological sex differences affect the integrative response to exercise: acute and chronic implications. Exp Physiol. 2020;105(12):2007&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansdell P, et al. Sex differences in fatigability following exercise normalised to the power-duration relationship. J Physiol. 2020;598(24):5717&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32964441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Chou TY, Nosaka K. Adequate interval between matches in elite female soccer players. J Sports Sci Med. 2023;22(4):614&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38045739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10690515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooderick J, et al. Does a self-reported sleep duration reflect actigraphy reported sleep duration in female football players? Sci Med Footb. 2025;9(1):19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38174382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotta AS, et al. Validity of the Elite HRV smartphone application for examining heart rate variability in a field-based setting. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(8):2296&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28195974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maijala A, et al. Nocturnal finger skin temperature in menstrual cycle tracking: ambulatory pilot study using a wearable Oura ring. BMC Womens Health. 2019;19(1):150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31783840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6883568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts LA, et al. Post-exercise cold water immersion attenuates acute anabolic signalling and long-term adaptations in muscle to strength training. J Physiol. 2015;593(18):4285&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26174323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4594298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake JM, et al. Modulating exercise-induced hormesis: does less equal more? J Appl Physiol (1985). 2015;119(3):172&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25977451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA, et al. Nutritional modulation of training-induced skeletal muscle adaptations. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2011;110(3):834&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21030665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, et al. An integrated, multifactorial approach to periodization for optimal performance in individual and team sports. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(5):538&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loch F, et al. Resting the mind: a novel topic with scarce insights. Considering potential mental recovery strategies for short rest periods in sports. Perform Enhance Health. 2019;6(3):148&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell S, et al. Global practitioner assessment and management of mental fatigue and mental recovery in high-performance sport: a need for evidence-based best-practice guidelines. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34(1): e14491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37728880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stults-Kolehmainen MA, Bartholomew JB. Psychological stress impairs short-term muscular recovery from resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(11):2220&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22688829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balk YA, de Jonge J. The, &#x201c;underrecovery trap&#x201d;: when physical fatigue impairs the physical and mental recovery process. Sport Exerc Perform Psychol. 2021;10(1):88&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M, et al. Recovery and performance in sport: consensus statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(2):240&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29345524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell S, et al. What is mental fatigue in elite sport? perceptions from athletes and staff. Eur J Sport Sci. 2019;19(10):1367&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31081474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toffoletti K, McGrane C, Reddan S. Addressing online harm in Australian women's sport. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell S, et al. Mental fatigue in differing occupational domains. Perform Enhancement Health 2023;11(4):100264. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peh.2023.100264 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proost M, et al. How to tackle mental fatigue: a systematic review of potential countermeasures and their underlying mechanisms. Sports Med. 2022;52(9):2129&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35543922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelands B, Bogataj S. Optimizing athletic performance through brain endurance training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;19(10):973&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39209294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loch F, et al. Acute effects of mental recovery strategies after a mentally fatiguing task. Front Psychol. 2020;11: 558856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33424674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7785754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntyre T, Nigg C, Murphy C, Oblinger-Peters V. Nature-based interventions in elite sport. In: Nixdorf I, Nixdorf R, Beckmann J, Martin S, Macintyre T, editors. Routledge handbook of mental health in elite sport. New York (NY): Routledge; 2023. p. 374&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Soh KG, Xu X. Nature scenes counter mental fatigue-induced performance decrements in soccer decision-making. Front Psychol. 2022;13: 877844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35572319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9105021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum J, Rockstroh C, Goritz AS. Heart rate variability biofeedback based on slow-paced breathing with immersive virtual reality nature scenery. Front Psychol. 2019;10:2172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31616353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6763967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axelsen JL, Kirk U, Staiano W. On-the-spot binaural beats and mindfulness reduces the effect of mental fatigue. J Cogn Enhance. 2020;4(1):31&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, et al. To nap or not to nap? A systematic review evaluating napping behavior in athletes and the impact on various measures of athletic performance. Nat Sci Sleep. 2021;13:841&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34194254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8238550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson Sl, Sargent C et al. Sleep and the athlete: narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Brit J Sports Med. 2021;55:356&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axelsen J, Kirk U, Staiano W. On-the-spot binaural beats and mindfulness reduces the effect of mental fatigue. J Cogn Enhanc. 2020;4(1):31&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Loyo J, et al. Sex differences in cognitive processing: an integrative review of electrophysiological findings. Biol Psychol. 2022;172: 108370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35662578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltz AM, Moser JS. Ovarian hormones: a long overlooked but critical contributor to cognitive brain structures and function. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2020;1464(1):156&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31639230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott-Sale KJ, et al. Methodological considerations for studies in sport and exercise science with women as participants: a working guide for standards of practice for research on women. Sports Med. 2021;51(5):843&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33725341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8053180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Martin DT. Lying to win-placebos and sport science. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2013;8(6):597&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24194442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calleja-Gonzalez J, et al. The recovery umbrella in the world of elite sport: do not forget the coaching and performance staff. Sports (Basel). 2021;9(12):169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34941807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson SMB, et al. Behavioral interventions and behavior change techniques used to improve sleep outcomes in athlete populations: a scoping review. Behav Sleep Med. 2024;22(6):820&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38965766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purcell R, Gwyther K, Rice SM. Mental health in elite athletes: increased awareness requires an early intervention framework to respond to athlete needs. Sports Med Open. 2019;5(1):46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31781988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6883009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, et al. The impact of training schedules on the sleep and fatigue of elite athletes. Chronobiol Int. 2014;31(10):1160&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armour M, et al. Australian female athlete perceptions of the challenges associated with training and competing when menstrual symptoms are present. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2020;15(3):316&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold EB, Wells C, Rasor MO. The association of inflammation with premenstrual symptoms. J Womens Health (Larchmt). 2016;25(9):865&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27135720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster R, et al. Relationship between anxiety and interleukin 10 in female soccer players with and without premenstrual syndrome (PMS). Rev Bras Ginecol Obstet. 2017;39(11):602&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28847026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10309485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster R, et al. Premenstrual syndrome, inflammatory status, and mood states in soccer players. Neuroimmunomodulation. 2019;26(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30654383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nillni YI, Toufexis DJ, Rohan KJ. Anxiety sensitivity, the menstrual cycle, and panic disorder: a putative neuroendocrine and psychological interaction. Clin Psychol Rev. 2011;31(7):1183&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21855828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3176921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>