<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33887822</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2733-7545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical activity and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Act Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of partial sleep deprivation after prolonged exercise on metabolic responses and exercise performance on the following day.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>6</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20463/pan.2021.0001</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We determined the effect of partial sleep deprivation (PSD) after an exercise session on exercise performance on the following morning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eleven male athletes performed either a normal sleep trial (CON) or a PSD trial. On the first day (day 1), all subjects performed an exercise session consisting of 90 min of running (at 75% V&#x307;O2max) followed by 100 drop jumps. Maximal strength (MVC) was evaluated before and after exercise. In the CON trial, the sleep duration was 23:00-7:00, while in the PSD trial, the sleep duration was shortened to 40% of the regular sleep duration. On the following morning (day 2), MVC, the metabolic responses during 20 min of running (at 75% V&#x307;O2max), and time to exhaustion (TTE) at 85% V&#x307;O2max were evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">On day 2, neither the MVC nor V&#x307;O2 during 20 min of running differed significantly between the two trials. However, the respiratory exchange ratio was significantly lower in the PSD trial than in the CON trial (p = 0.01). Moreover, the TTE was significantly shorter in the PSD trial than in the CON trial (p = 0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A single night of PSD after an exercise session significantly decreased endurance performance without significantly changing muscle strength or cardiopulmonary response.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamiya</LastName><ForeName>Aoi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Sports and Health Science, Ritsumeikan University, Shiga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morii</LastName><ForeName>Ikuhiro</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Sports and Health Science, Ritsumeikan University, Shiga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goto</LastName><ForeName>Kazushige</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Sports and Health Science, Ritsumeikan University, Shiga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Act Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2733-7545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy expenditure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exhaustion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maximal strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep deprivation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33887822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2021.0001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pan.2021.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beelen M, Burke LM, Gibala MJ, van Loon LJC. Nutritional strategies to promote postexercise recovery. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20:515&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21116024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xfc;ger M, de Mare&#xe9;s M, Dittmar KH, Sperlich B, Mester J. Wholebody cryotherapy's enhancement of acute recovery of running performance in well-trained athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10:605&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25561577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venter RE. Perceptions of team athletes on the importance of recovery modalities. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14 Suppl 1:S69&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bompa TO, Haff GG. Periodization: theory and methodology of training. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venter RE, Potgieter JR, Barnard JG. The use of recovery modalities by elite South African team athletes. South African J Res Sport, Phy Edu Recreation. 2010;34:167&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eagles A, Mclellan C, Hing W, Carloss N, Lovell D. Changes in sleep quantity and efficiency in professional rugby union players during home-based training and match-play. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2016;56:565&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25369280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, Skorski S, Duffield R, Julian R, Bartlett J, Meyer T. Impaired sleep and recovery after night matches in elite football players. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:1333&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26750446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oda S, Shirakawa K. Sleep onset is disrupted following pre-sleep exercise that causes large physiological excitement at bedtime. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:1789&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24859750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedelmalek S, Chtourou H, Aloui A, Aouichaoui C, Souissi N, Tabka Z. Effect of time of day and partial sleep deprivation on plasma concentrations of IL-6 during a short-term maximal performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:241&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F, Simon-Rigaud ML, Davenne D, Renaud A, Garnier A, Kantelip JP, Magnin P. Effects of sleep disturbances on subsequent physical performance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1991;63:77&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1748108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F, Bourdin H, Simon-Rigaud ML, Nguyen NU, Kantelip JP, Davenne D. Hormonal responses to exercise after partial sleep deprivation and after a hypnotic drug-induced sleep. J Sports Sci. 2001;19:89&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11217014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver SJ, Costa RJS, Laing SJ, Bilzon JLJ, Walsh NP. One night of sleep deprivation decreases treadmill endurance performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:155&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Sesbo&#xfc;&#xe9; B, Gauthier A, Larue J, Davenne D. Effects of one night's sleep deprivation on anaerobic performance the following day. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89:359&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12736846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abedelmalek S, Souissi N, Chtourou H, Denguezli M, Aouichaoui C, Ajina M, Aloui A, Dogui M, Haddouk S, Tabka Z. Effects of partial sleep deprivation on proinflammatory cytokines, growth hormone, and steroid hormone concentrations during repeated brief sprint interval exercise. Chronobiol Int. 2013;30:502&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin MR, Wang M, Campomayor CO, Collado-Hidalgo A, Cole S. Sleep deprivation and activation of morning levels of cellular and genomic markers of inflammation. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166:1756&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16983055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson RC, Jones PW. Long-term reproducibility of borg scale estimates of breathlessness during exercise. Clin Sci. 1991;80:309&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1851065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez JT, Fuchs CJ, Betts JA, van Loon LJC. Liver glycogen metabolism during and after prolonged endurance-type exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2016;311:E543&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27436612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skein M, Duffield R, Edge J, Short MJ, Mundel T. Intermittent-sprint performance and muscle glycogen after 30 h of sleep deprivation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1301&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21200339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chase JD, Roberson PA, Saunders MJ, Hargens TA, Womack CJ, Luden ND. One night of sleep restriction following heavy exercise impairs 3-km cycling time-trial performance in the morning. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42:909&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsom PD, Gaitanos GC, S&#xf6;derlund K, Ekblom B. High-intensity exercise and muscle glycogen availability in humans. Acta Physiol Scand. 1999;165:337&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10350228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray R, Paul GL, Seifert JG, Eddy DE. Responses to varying rates of carbohydrate ingestion during exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1991;23:713&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1886479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White DP, Weil JV, Zwillich CW. Metabolic rate and breathing during sleep. J Appl Physiol. 1985;59:384&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3928586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plyley MJ, Shephard RJ, Davis GM, Goode RC. Sleep deprivation and cardiorespiratory function. Influence of intermittent submaximal exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1987;56:338&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3569243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azboy O, Kaygisiz Z. Effects of sleep deprivation on cardiorespiratory functions of the runners and volleyball players during rest and exercise. Acta Physiol Hung. 2009;96:29&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19264040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin BJ. Effect of sleep deprivation on tolerance of prolonged exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1981;47:345&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7199438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri MA, Yousfi N, Mhenni T, Tayech A, Hammouda O, Driss T. Chaouachi A, Souissi N. Does one night of partial sleep deprivation affect the evening performance during intermittent exercise in Taekwondo players? J Exerc Rehabil. 2016;12:47&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4771153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26933660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bambaeichi E, Reilly T, Cable NT, Giacomoni M. Influence of time of day and partial sleep loss on muscle strength in eumenorrheic females. Ergonomics. 2005;48:1499&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16338716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symons JD, VanHelder T, Myles WS. Physical performance and physiological responses following 60 hours of sleep deprivation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20:374&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3173045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>