<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35519439</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Impact of Early Morning Training Sessions on Total Sleep Time in Collegiate Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>423</StartPage><EndPage>433</EndPage><MedlinePgn>423-433</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Early morning training sessions may affect sleep quantity in athletes. The purpose of this study is to examine differences in total sleep time of collegiate athletes on nights prior to early morning training sessions relative to non-training nights. Wristwatch monitors equipped with photoplethysmography and accelerometer technology were worn by 18 NCAA Division III collegiate athletes (Age: 20.1 &#xb1; 1.6 years, Height: 1.81 &#xb1; 0.02 m, Body Mass: 91.2 &#xb1; 6.5 kg, Body Fat %: 20.8 &#xb1; 1.6%) during a two-week period of training to monitor total sleep times. Athletes recorded time in and out of bed using a sleep diary, anxiety levels due to having to wake up in the morning, and perceived recovery status (PRS) upon waking the next day. The data were divided into: nights before non-training days (NT) and Training days (TD). Data were analyzed using univariate analysis. All athletes obtained significantly less total sleep on nights before TD relative to NT (NT: 8:15 &#xb1; 1:03 vs. TD: 6:08 &#xb1; 0:59 hh:mm; <i>p</i> &lt; 0.05). There was a positive relationship between total sleep time and recovery status (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01). Anxiety scores were inversely related to total sleep time (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01). Next-day recovery status was inversely related to anxiety scores (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001). College athletes obtained significantly less total sleep time on nights before early morning training sessions (&lt; 0700) during the off-season, regardless of sex and sport. Coaches should consider later training sessions or promote optimal sleep quantity in order to minimize the risks associated to early morning training sessions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brandon</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sport Science, University of Wisconsin-La Crosse, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mancosky</LastName><ForeName>Austin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine, Mayo Clinic Health System, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luedke</LastName><ForeName>Joel</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine, Mayo Clinic Health System, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griesmer</LastName><ForeName>Shalynn</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine, Mayo Clinic Health System, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erickson</LastName><ForeName>Jacob L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sport Science, University of Wisconsin-La Crosse, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine, Mayo Clinic Health System, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagim</LastName><ForeName>Andrew R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sport Science, University of Wisconsin-La Crosse, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine, Mayo Clinic Health System, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">college athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery status</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35519439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9022693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/SSLE5502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-15-6-423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Belenky G, Wesensten NJ, Thorne DR, Thomas ML, Sing HC, Redmond DP, Russo MB, Balkin TJ. Patterns of performance degradation and restoration during sleep restriction and subsequent recovery: A sleep dose-response study. J Sleep Res. 2003;12:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12603781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin C, Adams W, Curtis R, Sekiguchi Y. Early morning training impacts previous night&#x2019;s sleep in NCAA division I cross country runners. Women in Sport and Physical Activity Journal. 2019;28:27&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besedovsky L, Lange T, Haack M. The sleep-immune crosstalk in health and disease. Physiological Reviews. 2019;99:1325&#x2013;1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6689741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30920354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauer AA, Athey AB, Ross MJ, Grandner MA. Sleep and health among collegiate student athletes. Chest. 2019;156:1234&#x2013;1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31472156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budgett R. Fatigue and underperformance in athletes: the overtraining syndrome. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 1998;32:107&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9631215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke TM, Lisman PJ, Maguire K, Skeiky L, Choynowski JJ, Capaldi VF, 2nd, Wilder JN, Brager AJ, Dobrosielski DA. Examination of sleep and injury among college football athletes. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2020;34:609&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinoy ED, Cuellar JA, Huwa KE, Jameson JT, Watson CH, Bessman SC, Hirsch DA, Cooper AD, Drummond SPA, Markwald RR. Performance of seven consumer sleep-tracking devices compared with polysomnography. Sleep. 44:2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8120339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlacher D, Ehrlenspiel F, Adegbesan OA, El-Din HG. Sleep habits in German athletes before important competitions or games. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2011;29:859&#x2013;866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21506041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts AJ, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: the effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45:161&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25315456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han K, Kim L, Shim L. Stress and sleep disorder. Experimental Neurobiology. 2012;21:141&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3538178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23319874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin MR, Olmstead R, Carroll JE. Sleep disturbance, sleep duration, and inflammation: A systematic review and meta-analysis of cohort studies and experimental sleep deprivation. Biol Psychiatry. 2016;80:40&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26140821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff LE, Halson SL, Hebert JJ, Forsyth PL, Peiffer JJ. Longer sleep durations are positively associated with finishing place during a national multiday netball competition. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2018;32:189&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschen GW, Jones JJ, Hale L. The impact of sleep duration on performance among competitive athletes: A systematic literature review. Clin J Sport Med. 2020;30:503&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29944513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Lovell GP, Sargent C. Athletes&#x2019; precompetitive sleep behaviour and its relationship with subsequent precompetitive mood and performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(Suppl 1):S123&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent CM, Green JM, Bishop PA, Sjokvist J, Schumacker RE, Richardson MT, Curtner-Smith M. A practical approach to monitoring recovery: development of a perceived recovery status scale. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2011;25:620&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes Dos Santos M, Uftring M, Stahl CA, Lockie RG, Alvar B, Mann JB, Dawes JJ. Stress in academic and athletic performance in collegiate athletes: A narrative review of sources and monitoring strategies. Front Sports Act Living. 2020;2:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund HG, Reider BD, Whiting AB, Prichard JR. Sleep patterns and predictors of disturbed sleep in a large population of college students. J Adolesc Health. 2010;46:124&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20113918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski MD, Skaggs DL, Bishop GA, Pace JL, Ibrahim DA, Wren TA, Barzdukas A. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. J Pediatr Orthop. 2014;34:129&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Edwards B. Altered sleep-wake cycles and physical performance in athletes. Physiol Behav. 2007;90:274&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17067642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritland BM, Simonelli G, Gentili RJ, Smith JC, He X, Oh H, Balkin TJ, Hatfield BD. Sleep health and its association with performance and motivation in tactical athletes enrolled in the Reserve Officers&#x2019; Training Corps. Sleep Health. 2019;5:309&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31208712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romyn G, Robey E, Dimmock JA, Halson SL, Peeling P. Sleep, anxiety and electronic device use by athletes in the training and competition environments. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16:301&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25790844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Halson S, Roach GD. Sleep or swim? Early-morning training severely restricts the amount of sleep obtained by elite swimmers. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(Suppl 1):S310&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. The impact of training schedules on the sleep and fatigue of elite athletes. Chronobiol Int. 2014;31:1160&#x2013;1168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. The validity of activity monitors for measuring sleep in elite athletes. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport. 2016;19:848&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26794719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson SL, Roach GD. How much sleep does an elite athlete need? International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. 2021:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34021090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Romyn G, Versey N, Miller DJ, Roach GD. How well does a commercially available wearable device measure sleep in young athletes? Chronobiol Int. 2018;35:754&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29750580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprajcer M, Jay SM, Vincent GE, Vakulin A, Lack L, Ferguson SA. How the chance of missing the alarm during an on-call shift affects pre-bed anxiety, sleep and next day cognitive performance. Biol Psychol. 2018;137:133&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30059707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri M, Arabameri E. The effect of sleep deprivation on choice reaction time and anaerobic power of college student athletes. Asian J Sports Med. 2012;3:15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale KC, Owens R, Hopkins SR, Malhotra A. Sleep hygiene for optimizing recovery in athletes: Review and recommendations. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40:535&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6988893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Rosen P, Frohm A, Kottorp A, Friden C, Heijne A. Too little sleep and an unhealthy diet could increase the risk of sustaining a new injury in adolescent elite athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27:1364&#x2013;1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27539373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, Roach GD, Nedelec M, Gupta L, Leeder J, Fullagar HH, Coutts AJ, Edwards BJ, Pullinger SA, Robertson CM, Burniston JG, Lastella M, Le Meur Y, Hausswirth C, Bender AM, Grandner MA, Samuels CH. Sleep and the athlete: narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AM. Sleep and athletic performance. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2017;16:413&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29135639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>