<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39625306</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiology in review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unlocking the Heart's Guardian: Exploring Melatonin's Impact on the Cardiovascular System.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000822</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Melatonin has become a popular choice for managing insomnia and sleep-related issues due to its effectiveness in promoting sleep and its minimal risk of side effects. This has led many individuals to opt for over-the-counter melatonin as an alternative to traditional sleep medications. Recent research indicates that melatonin not only aids in addressing sleep problems but also enhances muscle recovery and performance, thereby improving daytime functioning, particularly among athletes. In the United States, the prevalence of melatonin supplement usage has risen significantly from 0.08% in 2005-2006 to 0.28% in 2017-2018. Individuals with conditions such as heart failure, hypertension, coronary heart disease, and cardiovascular risk factors like diabetes and obesity typically exhibit lower levels of melatonin in their blood at night. This deficiency increases the likelihood of experiencing adverse cardiac events. Studies have highlighted melatonin's role not only in regulating sleep but also in safeguarding against cardiovascular diseases by influencing various cardiovascular functions. In summary, the increasing utilization of melatonin underscores its recognized efficacy in mitigating sleep disturbances, with emerging evidence suggesting potential benefits for cardiovascular health. As ongoing research explores additional therapeutic avenues, the multifaceted impact of melatonin emphasizes its significance in promoting overall well-being.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Said</LastName><ForeName>Aimen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Medicine, Marshfield Clinic Health System, Marshfield, WI.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Darshini</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, GCS Medical College, Hospital and Research Centre, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Priyanshi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Bhupinder</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, NYC Health + Hospitals, Queens, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anamika</LastName><ForeName>Fnu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Cleveland Clinic, Akron General, Akron, OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aggarwal</LastName><ForeName>Kanishk</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Dayanand Medical College and Hospital, Ludhiana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Aachal</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amity Regional High School, Woodbridge, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Rohit</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Penn State Milton S. Hershey Medical Center, Hershey, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiol Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9304686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1061-5377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39625306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CRD.0000000000000822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00045415-990000000-00373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):S13&#x2013;S23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjaye-Gbewonyo D, Ng AE, Black LI. Sleep difficulties in adults: United States, 2020. NCHS Data Brief, no 436. National Center for Health Statistics. 2022. doi: 10.15620/cdc:117490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopheide JA. Insomnia overview: epidemiology, pathophysiology, diagnosis and monitoring, and nonpharmacologic therapy. Am J Manag Care. 2020;26(Suppl):S76&#x2013;S84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen ML, Poyares D, Tufik S. Insomnia and cardiovascular outcomes. Sleep Sci. 2021;14:1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaha DP. Insomnia management: a review and update. J Fam Pract. 2023;72:S31&#x2013;S36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tordjman S, Chokron S, Delorme R, et al. Melatonin: pharmacology, functions and therapeutic benefits. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2017;15:434&#x2013;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Zheng Y, Wang Z, et al. Melatonin as a therapeutic agent for alleviating endothelial dysfunction in cardiovascular diseases: emphasis on oxidative stress. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;167:115475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Somers VK, Xu H, et al. Trends in use of melatonin supplements among US adults, 1999-2018. JAMA. 2022;327:483&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond FR, Drummond LR, Campos HO, et al. Is melatonin as an ergogenic hormone a myth? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Endocrine. 2024;83:302&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardiner C, Weakley J, Burke LM, et al. The effect of caffeine on subsequent sleep: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev. 2023;69:101764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake C, Roehrs T, Shambroom J, et al. Caffeine effects on sleep taken 0, 3, or 6 hours before going to bed. J Clin Sleep Med. 2013;9:1195&#x2013;1200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobeiha M, Jafari A, Fadaei S, et al. Evidence for the benefits of melatonin in cardiovascular disease. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:888319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiki Z, Lecour S, Nduhirabandi F. Cardiovascular benefits of dietary melatonin: a myth or a reality? Front Physiol. 2018;9:528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tengattini S, Reiter RJ, Tan D-X, et al. Cardiovascular diseases: protective effects of melatonin. J Pineal Res. 2008;44:16&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco C, Sciatti E, Favero G, et al. Essential hypertension and oxidative stress: novel future perspectives. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:14489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanoboni A, Forni A, Zanoboni-Muciaccia W, et al. Effect of pinealectomy on arterial blood pressure and food and water intake in the rat. J Endocrinol Invest. 1978;1:125&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandi-Perumal SR, BaHammam AS, Ojike NI, et al. Melatonin and human cardiovascular disease. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2017;22:122&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pechanova O, Paulis L, Simko F. Impact of melatonin on central blood pressure regulation. Act Nerv Super Rediviva. 2016;58:99&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girouard H, Chulak C, LeJossec M, et al. Chronic antioxidant treatment improves sympathetic functions and &#x3b2;-adrenergic pathway in the spontaneously hypertensive rats. J Hypertens. 2003;21:179&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman E. Should melatonin be used to lower blood pressure? Hypertens Res. 2013;36:682&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulis L, &#x160;imko F. Blood pressure modulation and cardiovascular protection by melatonin: potential mechanisms behind. Physiol Res. 2007;56:671&#x2013;684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter R, Tan DX, Mayo J, et al. Melatonin as an antioxidant: biochemical mechanisms and pathophysiological implications in humans. Acta Biochim Pol. 2003;50:1129&#x2013;1146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkalayci F, Kocabas U, Altun BU, et al. Relationship between melatonin and cardiovascular disease. Cureus. 2021;13:e12935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Reiter RJ, Manchester LC, et al. Chemical and physical properties and potential mechanisms: melatonin as a broad spectrum antioxidant and free radical scavenger. Curr Top Med Chem. 2002;2:181&#x2013;197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozir&#xf3;g M, Poliwczak AR, Duchnowicz P, et al. Melatonin treatment improves blood pressure, lipid profile, and parameters of oxidative stress in patients with metabolic syndrome. J Pineal Res. 2010;50:261&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku H, Kim Y, Kim AL, et al. Protective effects of melatonin in high-fat diet-induced hepatic steatosis via decreased intestinal lipid absorption and hepatic cholesterol synthesis. Endocrinol Metab (Seoul). 2023;38:557&#x2013;567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celinski K, Konturek PC, Slomka M, et al. Effects of treatment with melatonin and tryptophan on liver enzymes, parameters of fat metabolism and plasma levels of cytokines in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease--14 months follow up. J Physiol Pharmacol. 2014;65:75&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espino J, Pariente JA, Rodr&#xed;guez AB. Role of melatonin on diabetes-related metabolic disorders. World J Diabetes. 2011;2:82&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok JX, Ooi JH, Ng KY, et al. A new perspective on the role of melatonin in diabetes and its complications. Horm Mol Biol Clin Investig. 2019;40: /j/hmbci.2019.40.issue-1/hmbci-2019-0036/hmbci-2019-0036.xml.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korkmaz A, Topal T, Tan DX, et al. Role of melatonin in metabolic regulation. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2009;10:261&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo JC, Sainz RM, Antol&#xed;n I, et al. Melatonin regulation of antioxidant enzyme gene expression. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2002;59:1706&#x2013;1713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tom&#xe1;s-Zapico C, Coto-Montes A. A proposed mechanism to explain the stimulatory effect of melatonin on antioxidative enzymes. J Pineal Res. 2005;39:99&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez-Rodriguez A, Abreu-Gonzalez P, de la Torre-Hernandez JM, et al.; MARIA Investigators. Usefulness of early treatment with melatonin to reduce infarct size in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction receiving percutaneous coronary intervention (from the Melatonin Adjunct in the Acute Myocardial Infarction Treated With Angioplasty Trial). Am J Cardiol. 2017;120:522&#x2013;526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallinen P, M&#xe4;ntt&#xe4;ri S, Leskinen H, et al. The effect of myocardial infarction on the synthesis, concentration, and receptor expression of endogenous melatonin. J Pineal Res. 2007;42:254&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attachaipanich T, Chattipakorn SC, Chattipakorn N. Potential roles of melatonin in doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity: from cellular mechanisms to clinical application. Pharmaceutics. 2023;15:785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradies G, Petrosillo G, Paradies V, et al. Melatonin, cardiolipin and mitochondrial bioenergetics in health and disease. J Pineal Res. 2010;48:297&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry M, Green DE. Cardiolipin requirement for electron transfer in complex I and III of the mitochondrial respiratory chain. J Biol Chem. 1981;256:1874&#x2013;1880.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galano A, Tan DX, Reiter RJ. On the free radical scavenging activities of melatonin&#x2019;s metabolites, AFMK and AMK. J Pineal Res. 2013;54:245&#x2013;257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DX, Manchester LC, Reiter RJ, et al. Significance of melatonin in antioxidative defense system: reactions and products. Biol Signals Recept. 2000;9:137&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Sun P, Zhen D, et al. Melatonin alleviates doxorubicin-induced mitochondrial oxidative damage and ferroptosis in cardiomyocytes by regulating YAP expression. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol. 2022;437:115902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garakyaraghi M, Siavash M, Alizadeh MK. Effects of melatonin on left ventricular ejection fraction and functional class of heart failure patients: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Res Med Sci. 2012;17:13&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai Y, Anno K. Mucopolysaccharide-degrading enzymes from the liver of the squid, Ommastrephes sloani pacificus I. hyaluronidase. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1971;242:428&#x2013;436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi M, Khosrawi S, Heshmat-Ghahdarijani K, et al. Effect of melatonin on heart failure: a design for a double-blinded randomized clinical trial. ESC Heart Fail. 2020;7:3142&#x2013;3150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IuV L, Salikova S, Stadnikov A. Extracellular matrix remodeling myocardium of the left ventricle rats with experimental heart failure after perindopril and melatonin administration. Kardiologiia. 2014;54:52&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simko F, Bednarova KR, Krajcirovicova K, et al. Melatonin reduces cardiac remodeling and improves survival in rats with isoproterenol-induced heart failure. J Pineal Res. 2014;57:177&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzida G, Prystupa A, Lachowska-Kotowska P, et al. Alteration in diurnal and nocturnal melatonin serum levels in patients with chronic heart failure. Ann Agric Environ Med. 2013;20:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez-Rodriguez A, Abreu-Gonzalez P, Reiter RJ. The potential usefulness of serum melatonin level to predict heart failure in patients with hypertensive cardiomyopathy. Int J Cardiol. 2014;174:415&#x2013;417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez-Rodriguez A, Abreu-Gonzalez P, Sanchez-Sanchez JJ, et al. Melatonin and circadian biology in human cardiovascular disease. J Pineal Res. 2010;49:14&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyos M, Guerrero JM, Perez-Cano R, et al. Serum cholesterol and lipid peroxidation are decreased by melatonin in diet-induced hypercholesterolemic rats. J Pineal Res. 2000;28:150&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura H, Nakamura Y, Narimatsu A, et al. Melatonin treatment in peri- and postmenopausal women elevates serum high-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels without influencing total cholesterol levels. J Pineal Res. 2008;45:101&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezvanfar MR, Heshmati G, Chehrei A, et al. Effect of bedtime melatonin consumption on diabetes control and lipid profile. Int J Diabetes Dev Ctries. 2017;37:74&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazyar H, Zare Javid A, Bavi Behbahani H, et al. Consumption of melatonin supplement improves cardiovascular disease risk factors and anthropometric indices in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients: a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Trials. 2021;22:231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo&#x17c;d&#x17c;an M, Mo&#x17c;d&#x17c;an M, Cha&#x142;ubi&#x144;ski M, et al. The effect of melatonin on circadian blood pressure in patients with type 2 diabetes and essential hypertension. Arch Med Sci. 2014;10:669&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadi A, Ghaedi E, Moradi S, et al. Effects of melatonin supplementation on blood pressure: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Horm Metab Res. 2019;51:157&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeland R, Madrid JA, Tan DX, et al. Melatonin, the circadian multioscillator system, and health: the need for detailed analyses of peripheral melatonin signaling. J Pineal Res. 2012;52:139&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amstrup AK, Sikjaer T, Pedersen SB, et al. Reduced fat mass and increased lean mass in response to 1 year of melatonin treatment in postmenopausal women: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2016;84:342&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozir&#xf3;g M, Poliwczak AR, Duchnowicz P, et al. Melatonin treatment improves blood pressure, lipid profile, and parameters of oxidative stress in patients with metabolic syndrome. J Pineal Res. 2011;50:261&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesri Alamdari N, Mahdavi R, Roshanravan N, et al. A double-blind, placebo-controlled trial related to the effects of melatonin on oxidative stress and inflammatory parameters of obese women. Horm Metab Res. 2015;47:504&#x2013;508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Chen Y, Chang Y, et al. New anthropometric indices or old ones: which perform better in estimating cardiovascular risks in Chinese adults. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2018;18:14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwaich KH, Al-amran FG, -Sheibani BI, et al. Melatonin effects on myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury: impact on the outcome in patients undergoing coronary artery bypass grafting surgery. Int J Cardiol. 2016;221:977&#x2013;986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barati S, Jahangirifard A, Ahmadi ZH, Tavakoli-Ardakani M, Dastan F. The effects of melatonin on the oxidative stress and duration of atrial fibrillation after coronary artery bypass graft surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Endocr Metab Immune Disord Drug Targets. 2021;21:1142&#x2013;1149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekeloef S, Halladin N, Fonnes S, et al. Effect of intracoronary and intravenous melatonin on myocardial salvage index in patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction: a randomised placebo-controlled trial. J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2017;10(5- 6):470&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez-Rodriguez A, Abreu-Gonzalez P, de la Torre-Hernandez JM, et al.; MARIA Investigators. Usefulness of early treatment with melatonin to reduce infarct size in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction receiving percutaneous coronary intervention (from the Melatonin Adjunct in the Acute Myocardial Infarction Treated With Angioplasty Trial). Am J Cardiol. 2017;120:522&#x2013;526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhanat K, Apaijai N, Chattipakorn SC, et al. Roles of melatonin and its receptors in cardiac ischemia-reperfusion injury. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2018;75:4125&#x2013;4149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halladin NL, Busch SE, Jensen SE, et al. Intracoronary and systemic melatonin to patients with acute myocardial infarction: protocol for the IMPACT trial. Dan Med J. 2014;61:A4773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekeloef S, Halladin N, Fonnes S, et al. Effect of intracoronary and intravenous melatonin on myocardial salvage index in patients with ST-elevation myocardial infarction: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2017;10:470&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dom&#xed;nguez-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Vaquero D, Abreu-Gonz&#xe1;lez P, et al. Early treatment of acute myocardial infarction with melatonin: effects on MMP-9 and adverse cardiac events. J Clin Med. 2022;11:1909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafi M, Shayesteh MR, Mortezaee K, et al. The role of melatonin on doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity: a systematic review. Life Sci. 2020;241:117173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran QH, Hoang DH, Song M, et al. Melatonin and doxorubicin synergistically enhance apoptosis via autophagy-dependent reduction of AMPK&#x3b1;1 transcription in human breast cancer cells. Exp Mol Med. 2021;53:1413&#x2013;1422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beesley SJ, Weber G, Sarge T, et al. Septic cardiomyopathy. Crit Care Med. 2018;46:625&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JH, Bhutani S, Kim CH, et al. Anti-inflammatory effects of melatonin: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. Brain Behav Immun. 2021;93:245&#x2013;253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoseini SG, Heshmat-Ghahdarijani K, Khosrawi S, et al. Effect of melatonin supplementation on endothelial function in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: a randomized, double-blinded clinical trial. Clin Cardiol. 2021;44:1263&#x2013;1271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menczel Schrire Z, Phillips CL, Chapman JL, et al. Safety of higher doses of melatonin in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Pineal Res. 2022;72:e12782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mina 2023 - 1. The short-term and long-term adverse effects of melatonin. 2023. https://www.thelancet.com/journals/eclinm/article/PIIS2589-5370(23)00260-2/fulltext. Accessed February 25, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>