<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40182713</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How different training sessions affect the sleep of professional soccer players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>125</StartPage><EndPage>133</EndPage><MedlinePgn>125-133</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2025.142644</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to compare microcycle loading and sleep patterns concerning successive match days (MD) using objective measurements of sleep and external training load (eTL). Twenty professional female soccer players (mean age: 23.3 &#xb1; 3.5 years) were monitored using a multi-sensor sleep-tracker for sleep patterns and global positioning system devices for eTL. Sleep variables included total sleep time (TOTAL), awake time (AWAKE), REM sleep, deep sleep time (DEEP), light sleep time (LIGHT), percentage of sleep time spent moving (REST), and sleep onset latency (ONSET). eTL variables included total distance covered (TD), distance at various speed thresholds, accelerations (ACC3), and decelerations (DEC3). 1) eTL influenced sleep; 2) TOTAL and REM were reduced after high eTL sessions (MD-3); 3) MD-2 facilitated recovery and improved post-session sleep compared to MD-4 and MD-3; 4) post-session TOTAL and DEEP sleep times on MD-1 were shorter compared to pre-session times, but there was no difference in REM sleep. Additionally, DEEP had a negative correlation with eTL variables, while REST had a positive correlation with certain eTL variables. REM sleep was affected after high eTL sessions, indicating that fatigue negatively impacted sleep. However, sleep increased after lower eTL sessions. Players slept less with less DEEP sleep the day before a competition (MD-1 post-session sleep). Monitoring sleep during microcycle acquisition and loading phases could assess sleep changes. Strategies should be implemented to improve sleep during loading phases and the night before matches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Institute of Sport &#x2013; National Research Instutite.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barba</LastName><ForeName>Eider</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Real Sociedad Sports Performance Department, Donostia-San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of the Basque Country (UPV/EHU), GIKAFIT Research Group, Vitoria-Gasteiz, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casamichana</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Real Sociedad Sports Performance Department, Donostia-San Sebasti&#xe1;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castellano</LastName><ForeName>Julen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of the Basque Country (UPV/EHU), GIKAFIT Research Group, Vitoria-Gasteiz, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Female</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GPS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40182713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11963127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.142644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">54705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vyazovskiy V V. Sleep, recovery, and metaregulation: Explaining the benefits of sleep. Nat Sci Sleep. 2015; 7:171&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4689288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26719733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Medicine. 2014; 44(1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva A, Narciso F V, Soalheiro I, Viegas F, Freitas LSN, Lima A, et al. Poor Sleep Quality&#x2019;s Association With Soccer Injuries: Preliminary Data. J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020; 15(5):671&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts AJ, Meyer T. Sleep and Athletic Performance: The Effects of Sleep Loss on Exercise Performance, and Physiological and Cognitive Responses to Exercise. Sports Med. 2015; 45(2):161&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25315456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Querido SM, Brito J, Figueiredo P, Carnide F, Vaz JR, Freitas SR. Postmatch Recovery Practices Carried Out in Professional Football: A Survey of 56 Portuguese Professional Football Teams. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022; 17(5):748&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes HKM, Medeiros A, M&#xf4;nico Neto M, Souza HS, Tufik S, et al. Sleep and muscle recovery: Endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothesis. Med Hypotheses. 2011; 77(2):220&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21550729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Juliff LE. Sleep, sport, and the brain. Prog Brain Res. 2017; 234:13&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29031461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Memon AR, Vincent GE. Global Research Output on Sleep Research in Athletes from 1966 to 2019: A Bibliometric Analysis. Clocks Sleep. 2020; 2(2):99&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooderick J, Wood T, Abbott W, Hayes M, Maxwell N. Does a self-reported sleep duration reflect actigraphy reported sleep duration in female football players? Sci MedFootb. 2024. Jan 4; 1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38174382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushida CA, Littner MR, Morgenthaler T, Alessi CA, Bailey D, Coleman J, Friedman L, Hirshkowitz M, Kapen S, Kramer M, Lee-Chiong T, Loube DL, Owens J, Pancer JP, Wise M. Practice Parameters for the Indications for PSG-AASM Practice Parameters SLEEP Practice Parameters for the Indications for Polysomnography and Related Procedures: 2005; 28(4):499&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16171294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira ABde M, Ribeiro BLL, Medeirosda Silva I, Fontenele-Ara&#xfa;jo J, Luis Mortatti A. Effect of Training Load Intensification on the Sleep Pattern of Young Soccer Players. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2024. Jul3; 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38959982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone JD, Rentz LE, Forsey J, Ramadan J, Markwald RR, Finomore Jnr VS, et al. Evaluations of commercial sleep technologies for objective monitoring during routine sleeping conditions. Nat Sci Sleep. 2020; 12:821&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7603649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33149712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DJ, Sargent C, Roach GD. A Validation of Six Wearable Devices for Estimating Sleep, Heart Rate and Heart Rate Variability in Healthy Adults. Sensors. 2022. Aug 1; 22(16).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9412437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36016077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, Roach GD, N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Gupta L, et al. Sleep and the athlete: Narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med. 2021; 55(7):356&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri M, Arabameri E. The effect of sleep deprivation on choice Reaction time and anaerobic power of college student athletes. Asian J Sports Med. 2012; 3(1):15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Leduc C, Dawson B, Guilhem G, Dupont G. Case Study: Sleep and Injury in Elite Soccer-A Mixed Method Approach. J Strength Cond Res. 2019. Nov; 33(11):3085&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28930876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Halson S, Abaidia AE, Ahmaidi S, Dupont G. Stress, Sleep and Recovery in Elite Soccer: A Critical Review of the Literature. Sports Med. 2015. Oct; 45(10):1387&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26206724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa J, Figueiredo P, Nakamura F, Rago V, Rebelo A, Brito J. Intra-individual variability of sleep and nocturnal cardiac autonomic activity in elite female soccer players during an international tournament. PLoS One. 2019; 14(9):0&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6748428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31527865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo P, Costa J, Lastella M, Morais J, Brito J. Sleep indices and cardiac autonomic activity responses during an international tournament in a youth national Soccer team. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021; 18(4):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7924379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33672683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Mendes B, Nikolaidis PT, Calvete F, Carri&#xe7;o S, Owen AL. Internal training load and its longitudinal relationship with seasonal player wellness in elite professional soccer. Physiol Behav. 2017; 179:262&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28668619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Sandua M, Berndsen J, Shelton A, Smith S, Norman D, McHugh D, Hader K. Loading patterns and programming practices in elite football Loading patterns and programming practices in elite football: insights from 100 elite practitioners. 2022; Sports Perform Sci Rep. 2021; 153(1):1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Lacome M, Cholley Y, Simpson BM. Neuromuscular responses to conditioned soccer sessions assessed via GPS-Embedded accelerometers: Insights into tactical periodization. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018. May 1; 13(5):577&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guridi I, Castellano J, Echeazarra I. Physical demands and internal response in football sessions according to tactical periodization. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021. Jun 1; 16(6):858&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33626511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter EM, Maughan RJ. Requirements for ethics approvals. J Sports Sci. 2009; 27(10):985&#x2013;985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19847681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacome M, Simpson BM, Cholley Y, Lambert P, Buchheit M. Small-sided games in elite soccer: Does one size fit all? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018; 13(5):568&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28714774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Rubio J, Pino J, Olivares PR, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez SJ. Validity and reliability of the WIMUTM inertial device for the assessment of joint angulations. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020. Jan 1; 17(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6982239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31892121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira JE, Forte P, Ferraz R, Leal M, Ribeiro J, Silva AJ, Barbosa TM, Monteiro AM. Monitoring accumulated training and match load in football: A systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021. Apr 8; 18(8):3906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cay G, Ravichandran V, Sadhu S, Zisk AH, Salisbury AL, Solanki D, et al. Recent Advancement in Sleep Technologies: A Literature Review on Clinical Standards, Sensors, Apps, and AI Methods. IEEE Access. 2022; 10:104737&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrabadi MA, Azimi I, Sarhaddi F, Axelin A, Niela-Vil&#xe9;n H, Myllyntausta S, et al. Sleep tracking of a commercially available smart ring and smartwatch against medical-grade actigraphy in everyday settings: Instrument validation study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020. Nov 1; 8(11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7669442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batterham AM, Hopkins WG. Making Meaningful Inferences About Magnitudes. 2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor R. Interpretation of the correlation coefficient: A basic review. J Diagn Med Sonogr. 1990. Jan; 6(1):35&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fessi MS, Zarrouk N, Di Salvo V, Filetti C, Barker AR, Moalla W. Effects of tapering on physical match activities in professional soccer players. J Sports Sci. 2016; 34(24):2189&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27065344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Garc&#xed;a A, G&#xf3;mez D&#xed;az A, Bradley PS, Morera F, Casamichana D. Quantification of a professional football team&#x2019;s external load using a microcycle structure. J Strength Cond Res. 2018; 32(12):3511&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30199452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff LE, Halson SL, Peiffer JJ. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important competitions. J Sci Med Sport. 2015. Jan 1; 18(1):13&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24629327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlacher D, Ehrlenspiel F, Adegbesan OA, El-Din HG. Sleep habits in German athletes before important competitions or games. J Sports Sci. 2011. May; 29(8):859&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21506041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moen F, Olsen M, Halm&#xf8;y G, Hrozanova M. Variations in Elite Female Soccer Players&#x2019; Sleep, and Associations With Perceived Fatigue and Soccer Games. Front Sports Act Living. 2021. Aug 25; 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8424084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34514385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>