<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36930200</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep/Wake Disorders After Sports Concussion: Risks, Revelations, and Interventions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>417</StartPage><EndPage>425</EndPage><MedlinePgn>417-425</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000931</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sleep-wake disturbances (SWDs) are among the most prevalent, persistent, and often disregarded sequelae of traumatic brain injury. Identification and treatment of SWDs in patients with traumatic brain injury is important and can complement other efforts to promote maximum functional recovery. SWDs can accentuate other consequences of traumatic brain injury, negatively affect mood, exacerbate pain, heighten irritability, and diminish cognitive abilities and the potential for recovery. The risk for sports injuries increases when athletes are sleep deprived. Sleep deprivation increases risk-taking behaviors, predisposing to injuries. SWDs are an independent risk factor for prolonged recovery after sports-related concussion. SWDs following sports-related concussion have been shown to impede recovery, rehabilitation, and return to preinjury activities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grigg-Damberger</LastName><ForeName>Madeleine M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of New Mexico School of Medicine, Albuquerque, New Mexico, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Concussion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The author has no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36930200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-202307000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Daneshvar DH, Nowinski CJ, McKee AC, Cantu RC. The epidemiology of sport-related concussion. Clin Sports Medvii 2011;30:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin HS, Diaz-Arrastia RR, Jacobsen SJ, Ilstrup DM, Garrity JA, Gorman CA. Diagnosis, prognosis, and clinical management of mild traumatic brain injury. Lancet Neurol 2015;14:506&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryan MA, Rowhani-Rahbar A, Comstock RD, Rivara F; Sports Concussion Research SeattleC. Sports- and recreation-related concussions in US youth. Pediatrics 2016;138:e20154635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon KG, Clugston JR, Dec K, et al. American medical society for sports medicine position statement on concussion in sport. Clin J Sport Med 2019;29:87&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierpoint LA, Collins C. Epidemiology of sport-related concussion. Clin Sports Med 2021;40:1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giza CC, Kutcher JS, Ashwal S, et al. Summary of evidence-based guideline update: evaluation and management of concussion in sports: report of the Guideline Development Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology 2013;80:2250&#x2013;2257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrea M, Guskiewicz KM, Marshall SW, et al. Acute effects and recovery time following concussion in collegiate football players: the NCAA Concussion Study. Jama 2003;290:2556&#x2013;2563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Register-Mihalik JK, Kay MC. The current state of sports concussion. Neurol Clin 2017;35:387&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrea M, Guskiewicz K, Randolph C, et al. Incidence, clinical course, and predictors of prolonged recovery time following sport-related concussion in high school and college athletes. J Int Neuropsychol Soc 2013;19:22&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemek R, Barrowman N, Freedman SB, et al. Clinical risk score for persistent postconcussion symptoms among children with acute concussion in the. Jama 2016;315:1014&#x2013;1025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvo&#x159;&#xe1;k J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport-the 5th international conference on concussion in sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med 2017;51:838&#x2013;847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Summerville G, Senter C. Treatment of acute sports-related concussion. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med 2019;12:117&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barkhoudarian G, Hovda DA, Giza CC. The molecular pathophysiology of concussive brain injury&#x2014;an update. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am 2016;27:373&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karton C, Hoshizaki TB. Biomechanics of sport-related neurological injury. Clin Sports Med 2021;40:19&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell DR, Southard J. The molecular pathophysiology of concussion. Clin Sports Med 2021;40:39&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier TB, Bellgowan PS, Singh R, Kuplicki R, Polanski DW, Mayer AR. Recovery of cerebral blood flow following sports-related concussion. JAMA Neurol 2015;72:530&#x2013;538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclos C, Dumont M, Wiseman-Hakes C, et al. Sleep and wake disturbances following traumatic brain injury. Pathol Biol (Paris) 2014;62:252&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontos AP, Sufrinko A, Sandel N, Emami K, Collins MW. Sport-related concussion clinical profiles: clinical characteristics, targeted treatments, and preliminary evidence. Curr Sports Med Rep 2019;18:82&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh K, Morse AM, Tkachenko N, Kothare SV. Sleep disorders associated with traumatic brain injury-A review. Pediatr Neurol 2016;60:30&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tkachenko N, Singh K, Hasanaj L, Serrano L, Kothare SV. Sleep disorders associated with mild traumatic brain injury using sport concussion assessment tool 3. Pediatr Neurol 2016;57:46.E1&#x2013;50.E1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathias JL, Alvaro PK. Prevalence of sleep disturbances, disorders, and problems following traumatic brain injury: a meta-analysis. Sleep Med 2012;13:898&#x2013;905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau BC, Collins MW, Lovell MR. Sensitivity and specificity of subacute computerized neurocognitive testing and symptom evaluation in predicting outcomes after sports-related concussion. Am J Sports Med 2011;39:1209&#x2013;1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucke-Wold BP, Smith KE, Nguyen L, et al. Sleep disruption and the sequelae associated with traumatic brain injury. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 2015;55:68&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdaugh DL, Ono KE, Reisner A, Burns TG. Assessment of sleep quantity and sleep disturbances during recovery from sports-related concussion in youth athletes. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2018;99:960&#x2013;966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guty E, Arnett P. Post-concussion symptom factors and neuropsychological outcomes in collegiate athletes. J Int Neuropsychol Soc 2018;24:684&#x2013;692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramley H, Henson A, Lewis MM, Kong L, Stetter C, Silvis M. Sleep disturbance following concussion is a risk factor for a prolonged recovery. Clin Pediatr 2017;56:1280&#x2013;1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann CR. Sleep and traumatic brain injury. Sleep Med Clin 2016;11:19&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommerauer M, Valko PO, Werth E, Baumann CR. Excessive sleep need following traumatic brain injury: a case-control study of 36 patients. J Sleep Res 2013;22:634&#x2013;639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell DR, Oldham JR, Brilliant AN, Meehan WP III. Trouble falling asleep after concussion is associated with higher symptom burden among children and adolescents. J Child Neurol 2019;34:256&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell DR, Berkstresser B, Wang F, et al. Self-reported sleep duration affects tandem gait, but not steady-state gait outcomes among healthy collegiate athletes. Gait Posture 2018;62:291&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuckerman SL, Yengo-Kahn AM, Buckley TA, Solomon GS, Sills AK, Kerr ZY. Predictors of postconcussion syndrome in collegiate student-athletes. Neurosurg Focus 2016;40:E13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr ZY, Zuckerman SL, Wasserman EB, et al. Factors associated with post-concussion syndrome in high school student-athletes. J Sci Med Sport 2018;21:447&#x2013;452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalmbach DA, Conroy DA, Falk H, et al. Poor sleep is linked to impeded recovery from traumatic brain injury. Sleep 2018;41:zsy147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantua J, Grillakis A, Mahfouz SH, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of sleep architecture and chronic traumatic brain injury. Sleep Med Rev 2018;41:61&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollayeva T, Colantonio A, Cassidy JD, Vernich L, Moineddin R, Shapiro CM. Sleep stage distribution in persons with mild traumatic brain injury: a polysomnographic study according to American Academy of Sleep Medicine standards. Sleep Med 2017;34:179&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselin N, Lassonde M, Petit D, et al. Sleep following sport-related concussions. Sleep Med 2009;10:35&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao V, Bergey A, Hill H, Efron D, McCann U. Sleep disturbance after mild traumatic brain injury: indicator of injury?. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci 2011;23:201&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbour C, Khoury S, Lavigne GJ, et al. Are NREM sleep characteristics associated to subjective sleep complaints after mild traumatic brain injury? Sleep Med 2015;16:534&#x2013;539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoury S, Chouchou F, Amzica F, et al. Rapid EEG activity during sleep dominates in mild traumatic brain injury patients with acute pain. J Neurotrauma 2013;30:633&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerasidis H, Simmons J. Quantitative EEG analysis in clinical practice: concussion injury. Clin EEG Neurosci 2021;52:114&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ancoli-Israel S, Cole R, Alessi C, Chambers M, Moorcroft W, Pollak CP. The role of actigraphy in the study of sleep and circadian rhythms. Sleep 2003;26:342&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollak CP, Tryon WW, Nagaraja H, Dzwonczyk R. How accurately does wrist actigraphy identify the states of sleep and wakefulness? Sleep 2001;24:957&#x2013;965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raikes AC, Schaefer SY. Sleep quantity and quality during acute concussion: a pilot study. Sleep 2016;38:2141&#x2013;2147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sufrinko AM, Howie EK, Elbin RJ, Collins MW, Kontos AP. A preliminary investigation of accelerometer-derived sleep and physical activity following sport-related concussion. J Head Trauma Rehabil 2018;33:E64&#x2013;E74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki Y, Khoury S, El-Khatib H, et al. Individuals with pain need more sleep in the early stage of mild traumatic brain injury. Sleep Med 2017;33:36&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tham SW, Fales J, Palermo TM. Subjective and objective assessment of sleep in adolescents with mild traumatic brain injury. J Neurotrauma 2015;32:847&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayalon L, Borodkin K, Dishon L, Kanety H, Dagan Y. Circadian rhythm sleep disorders following mild traumatic brain injury. Neurology 2007;68:1136&#x2013;1140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boivin DB, Caliyurt O, James FO, Chalk C. Association between delayed sleep phase and hypernyctohemeral syndromes: a case study. Sleep 2004;27:417&#x2013;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaffee MS, Winter WC, Jones CC, Ling G. Sleep disturbances in athletic concussion. Brain Inj 2015;29:221&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaeger K, Alhilali L, Fakhran S. Evaluation of tentorial length and angle in sleep-wake disturbances after mild traumatic brain injury. AJR Am J Roentgenol 2014;202:614&#x2013;618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raikes AC, Bajaj S, Dailey NS, et al. Diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) correlates of self-reported sleep quality and depression following mild traumatic brain injury. Front Neurol 2018;9:468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski MD, Skaggs DL, Bishop GA, et al. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. J Pediatr Orthop 2014;34:129&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luke A, Lazaro RM, Bergeron MF, et al. Sports-related injuries in youth athletes: is overscheduling a risk factor? Clin J Sport Med 2011;21:307&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Rosen P, Frohm A, Kottorp A, Friden C, Heijne A. Multiple factors explain injury risk in adolescent elite athletes: applying a biopsychosocial perspective. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2017;27:2059&#x2013;2069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Rosen P, Frohm A, Kottorp A, Friden C, Heijne A. Too little sleep and an unhealthy diet could increase the risk of sustaining a new injury in adolescent elite athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2017;27:1364&#x2013;1371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sufrinko A, Pearce K, Elbin RJ, et al. The effect of preinjury sleep difficulties on neurocognitive impairment and symptoms after sport-related concussion. Am J Sports Med 2015;43:830&#x2013;838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levitch CF, McConathey E, Aghvinian M, Himmelstein M, Lipton ML, Zimmerman ME. The impact of sleep on the relationship between soccer heading exposure and neuropsychological function in college-age soccer players. J Int Neuropsychol Soc 2020;26:633&#x2013;644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna BS, Dickinson DL, Orff HJ, Drummond SP. The effects of one night of sleep deprivation on known-risk and ambiguous-risk decisions. J Sleep Res 2007;16:245&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatraman V, Chuah YM, Huettel SA, Chee MW. Sleep deprivation elevates expectation of gains and attenuates response to losses following risky decisions. Sleep 2007;30:603&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telzer EH, Fuligni AJ, Lieberman MD, Galv&#xe1;n A. The effects of poor quality sleep on brain function and risk taking in adolescence. Neuroimage 2013;71:275&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short MA, Weber N. Sleep duration and risk-taking in adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev 2018;41:185&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Romyn G, Versey N, Miller DJ, Roach GD. How well does a commercially available wearable device measure sleep in young athletes?. Chronobiol Int 2018;35:754&#x2013;758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider KJ, Leddy JJ, Guskiewicz KM, et al. Rest and treatment/rehabilitation following sport-related concussion: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med 2017;51:930&#x2013;934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mychasiuk R, Hehar H, Ma I, Candy S, Esser MJ. Reducing the time interval between concussion and voluntary exercise restores motor impairment, short-term memory, and alterations to gene expression. Eur J Neurosci 2016;44:2407&#x2013;2417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon KG, Clugston JR, Dec K, et al. American Medical Society for Sports Medicine position statement on concussion in sport. Br J Sports Med 2019;53:213&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misch MR, Raukar NP. Sports medicine update: concussion. Emerg Med Clin North Am 2020;38:207&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederer D, Engeroff T, Lange K, Vogt L, Banzer W. Return-to-play after concussion: state of knowledge, frequency of use and application barriers of guidelines among decision-makers in rugby. Brain Inj 2018;32:1096&#x2013;1102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olympia RP, Ritter JT, Brady J, Bramley H. Return to learning after a concussion and compliance with recommendations for cognitive rest. Clin J Sport Med 2016;26:115&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall S, Bayley M, McCullagh S, et al. Updated clinical practice guidelines for concussion/mild traumatic brain injury and persistent symptoms. Brain Inj 2015;29:688&#x2013;700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumba-Brown A, Yeates KO, Sarmiento K, et al. Diagnosis and management of mild traumatic brain injury in children: a systematic review. JAMA Pediatr 2018;172:e182847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumba-Brown A, Yeates KO, Sarmiento K, et al. Centers for disease control and prevention guideline on the diagnosis and management of mild traumatic brain injury among children. JAMA Pediatr 2018;172:e182847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton SR, Kerr ZY, Brett BL, et al. Health-promoting behaviours and concussion history are associated with cognitive function, mood-related symptoms and emotional-behavioural dyscontrol in former NFL players: an NFL-LONG Study. Br J Sports Med 2021;55:683&#x2013;690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raikes AC, Dailey NS, Forbeck B, Alkozei A, Killgore WDS. Daily morning blue light therapy for post-mTBI sleep disruption: effects on brain structure and function. Front Neurol 2021;12:625431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow KM, Kirk V, Brooks B, et al. Efficacy of melatonin for sleep disturbance in children with persistent post-concussion symptoms: secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial. J Neurotrauma 2021;38:950&#x2013;959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morawska MM, B&#xfc;chele F, Moreira CG, Imbach LL, Noain D, Baumann CR. Sleep modulation Alleviates axonal damage and cognitive decline after rodent traumatic brain injury. J Neurosci 2016;36:3422&#x2013;3429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hugon J, Hourregue C, Cognat E, et al. Chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Neurochirurgie 2021;67:290&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costanza A, Radomska M, Zenga F, et al. Severe suicidality in athletes with chronic traumatic encephalopathy: a case series and overview on putative ethiopathogenetic mechanisms. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherry JD, Babcock KJ, Goldstein LE. Repetitive head trauma induces chronic traumatic encephalopathy by multiple mechanisms. Semin Neurol 2020;40:430&#x2013;438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alosco ML, Culhane J, Mez J. Neuroimaging biomarkers of chronic traumatic encephalopathy: targets for the academic memory disorders clinic. Neurotherapeutics 2021;18:772&#x2013;791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayubcha C, Revheim ME, Newberg A, et al. A critical review of radiotracers in the positron emission tomography imaging of traumatic brain injury: FDG, tau, and amyloid imaging in mild traumatic brain injury and chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging 2021;48:623&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantyh WG, Spina S, Lee A, et al. Tau positron emission tomographic findings in a former US football player with pathologically confirmed chronic traumatic encephalopathy. JAMA Neurol 2020;77:517&#x2013;521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grashow R, Weisskopf MG, Baggish A, et al. Premortem chronic traumatic encephalopathy diagnoses in professional football. Ann Neurol 2020;88:106&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan SF. Are sleep disturbances a risk for chronic traumatic encephalopathy? Only the shadow knows. J Clin Sleep Med : JCSM : official Publ Am Acad Sleep Med 2014;10:241&#x2013;242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams JW, Alosco ML, Mez J, et al. Association of probable REM sleep behavior disorder with pathology and years of contact sports play in chronic traumatic encephalopathy. Acta Neuropathol 2020;140:851&#x2013;862.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>