<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40845258</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Hydration Status on Sleep and Recovery After Heavy Resistance Exercise.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005225</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sekiguchi, Y, Jiwan, NC, Appell, CR, Moya, RM, Ky, AT, Keefe, MS, Dunn, RA, and Luk, H-Y. Impact of hydration status on sleep and recovery after heavy resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-The purpose of this study was to examine the effects of hydration status on sleep and recovery measurements before and after heavy resistance exercise (RE). Eight resistance-trained men (age, 21 &#xb1; 2 years; body mass, 82.0 &#xb1; 12.6 kg; height, 177.3 &#xb1; 6.9 cm) performed bilateral leg press and knee extensions (5 sets of 10 repetitions at 80% of 1 repetition maximum, 2 minutes rest). Participants completed 1 trial in a euhydrated state (EUH; urine specific gravity [USG] &lt; 1.020) and the other trial in a dehydrated state (DEH: USG &#x2265; 1.020), which was separated by 2 weeks. For the DEH trial, participants were restricted from consuming fluids for 24 hours before RE and were only permitted to drink 1.5 L of water after RE for the remainder of the day. For the EUH trial, participants were instructed to consume fluid for 24 hours before and 24 hours after RE to maintain euhydration. Sleep and recovery measurements were collected from a wearable sleep device that participants wore the night before (PRE) and after RE (POST). Repeated measures ANOVAs and linear mixed effect models were used to identify differences between EUH and DEH. Plasma osmolality, urine osmolality, USG, urine color, and body mass loss (p &lt; 0.05) were significantly higher in DEH than in EUH. However, there were no differences between EUH and DEH in sleep duration, efficiency, disturbance, deprivation, slow wave sleep, rapid eye movement sleep, light sleep, awaking time, resting heart rate, and heart rate variability. In conclusion, acute dehydration might not affect sleep and recovery measurements the night before and after heavy resistance exercise.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sekiguchi</LastName><ForeName>Yasuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiwan</LastName><ForeName>Nigel C</ForeName><Initials>NC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Exercise Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hope College, Holland, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Appell</LastName><ForeName>Casey R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Exercise Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moya</LastName><ForeName>Ruben M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ky</LastName><ForeName>Alan T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keefe</LastName><ForeName>Marcos S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dunn</LastName><ForeName>Ryan A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luk</LastName><ForeName>Hui-Ying</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Exercise Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep architecture</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40845258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achten J, Jeukendrup AE. Heart rate monitoring: Applications and limitations. Sports Med 33: 517&#x2013;538, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams JD, Sekiguchi Y, Seal A, et al. Dehydration impairs exercise performance independent of thirst perception: A blinded study. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49: 833, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams WM, Vandermark LW, Belval LN, et al. Impact of exercise-induced dehydration on perceived sleep quality. FASEB J 32: 905.4, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aristotelous P, Aphamis G, Sakkas GK, et al. Effects of controlled dehydration on sleep quality and quantity: A polysomnographic study in healthy young adults. J Sleep Res 28: e12662, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Bergeron MF, Mu&#xf1;oz CX, Kavouras SA. Low daily water intake profile-is it a contributor to disease? Nutr Health 30: 435&#x2013;446, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Ganio MS, Casa DJ, et al. Mild dehydration affects mood in healthy young women. J Nutr 142: 382&#x2013;388, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Soto JA, Hacker FT, et al. Urinary indices during dehydration, exercise, and rehydration. Int J Sport Nutr 8: 345&#x2013;355, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryhill S, Morton CJ, Dean A, et al. Effect of wearables on sleep in healthy individuals: A randomized crossover trial and validation study. J Clin Sleep Med 16: 775&#x2013;783, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brebbia DR, Altshuler KZ. Oxygen consumption rate and electroencephalographic stage of sleep. Science 150: 1621&#x2013;1623, 1965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength testing&#x2014;predicting a One-Rep Max from reps-to-fatigue. The Journal of Physical Education, Recreation &amp; Dance,. A Practical Approach to Strength Training. (1st ed.). Toronto, ON: Masters Press, 1993. 64. pp. 88&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Simon C, Piquard F, Ehrhart J, Brandenberger G. Effects of increased training load on vagal-related indexes of heart rate variability: A novel sleep approach. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 287: H2813&#x2013;H2818, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chennaoui M, Arnal PJ, Sauvet F, L&#xe9;ger D. Sleep and exercise: A reciprocal issue? Sleep Med Rev 20: 59&#x2013;72, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Carter R, Montain SJ, Sawka MN. Daily body mass variability and stability in active men undergoing exercise-heat stress. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 14: 532&#x2013;540, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cian C, Barraud PA, Melin B, Raphel C. Effects of fluid ingestion on cognitive function after heat stress or exercise-induced dehydration. Int J Psychophysiol 42: 243&#x2013;251, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Anci KE, Constant F, Rosenberg IH. Hydration and cognitive function in children. Nutr Rev 64: 457&#x2013;464, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driver HS, Taylor SR. Exercise and sleep. Sleep Med Rev 4: 387&#x2013;402, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HHK, Skorski S, Duffield R, et al. Sleep and athletic performance: The effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med 45: 161&#x2013;186, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganio MS, Armstrong LE, Casa DJ, et al. Mild dehydration impairs cognitive performance and mood of men. Br J Nutr 106: 1535&#x2013;1543, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R, Coyle EF. Supine exercise restores arterial blood pressure and skin blood flow despite dehydration and hyperthermia. Am J Physiol 277: H576&#x2013;H583, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavouras SA, Arnaoutis G, Makrillos M, et al. Educational intervention on water intake improves hydration status and enhances exercise performance in athletic youth. Scand J Med Sci Sports 22: 684&#x2013;689, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacevic A, Mavros Y, Heisz JJ, Fiatarone Singh MA. The effect of resistance exercise on sleep: A systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Sleep Med Rev 39: 52&#x2013;68, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubitz KA, Landers DM, Petruzzello SJ, Han M. The effects of acute and chronic exercise on sleep. A meta-analytic review. Sports Med 21: 277&#x2013;291, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin G, Zhang N, Lin Z, He L, Zhang F. Plain water intake, sleep quality, and hydration status of pregnant woman in hainan, China: A cross-sectional study. Nutrients 16: 1626, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindseth PD, Lindseth GN, Petros TV, Jensen WC, Caspers J. Effects of hydration on cognitive function of pilots. Mil Med 178: 792&#x2013;798, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Mah KE, Kezirian EJ, Dement WC. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep 34: 943&#x2013;950, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantantzis K, Drewelies J, Duezel S, et al. Dehydration predicts longitudinal decline in cognitive functioning and well-being among older adults. Psychol Aging 35: 517&#x2013;528, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masento NA, Golightly M, Field DT, Butler LT, van Reekum CM. Effects of hydration status on cognitive performance and mood. Br J Nutr 111: 1841&#x2013;1852, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ. Impact of mild dehydration on wellness and on exercise performance. Eur J Clin Nutr 57: S19&#x2013;S23, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott BP, Anderson SA, Armstrong LE, et al. National athletic trainers' association position statement: Fluid replacement for the physically active. J Athl Train 52: 877&#x2013;895, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott BP, Casa DJ, Yeargin SW, et al. Hydration status, sweat rates, and rehydration education of youth football campers. J Sport Rehabil 18: 535&#x2013;552, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DJ, Lastella M, Scanlan AT, et al. A validation study of the WHOOP strap against polysomnography to assess sleep. J Sports Sci 38: 2631&#x2013;2636, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DJ, Roach GD, Lastella M, et al. A validation study of a commercial wearable device to automatically detect and estimate sleep. Biosens (Basel) 11: 185, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DJ, Sargent C, Roach GD. A validation of six wearable devices for estimating sleep, heart rate and heart rate variability in healthy adults. Sensors (Basel) 22: 6317, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolte HW, Nolte K, Hew-Butler T. Ad libitum water consumption prevents exercise-associated hyponatremia and protects against dehydration in soldiers performing a 40-km route-march. Mil Med Res 6: 1, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osterberg KL, Horswill CA, Baker LB. Pregame urine specific gravity and fluid intake by National Basketball Association players during competition. J Athl Train 44: 53&#x2013;57, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel AV, Mihalik JP, Notebaert AJ, Guskiewicz KM, Prentice WE. Neuropsychological performance, postural stability, and symptoms after dehydration. J Athl Train 42: 66&#x2013;75, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peacock OJ, Stokes K, Thompson D Initial hydration status, fluid balance, and psychological affect during recreational exercise in adults. J Sports Sci 29: 897&#x2013;904, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piil JF, Lundbye-Jensen J, Christiansen L, et al. High prevalence of hypohydration in occupations with heat stress-perspectives for performance in combined cognitive and motor tasks. PLoS One 13: e0205321, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pross N, Demazi&#xe8;res A, Girard N, et al. Influence of progressive fluid restriction on mood and physiological markers of dehydration in women. Br J Nutr 109: 313&#x2013;321, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pross N, Demazi&#xe8;res A, Girard N, et al. Effects of changes in water intake on mood of high and low drinkers. PLoS One 9: e94754, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassin JF, Parker DC, Mace JW, et al. Human growth hormone release: Relation to slow-wave sleep and sleep-walking cycles. Science 165: 513&#x2013;515, 1969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawka MN, Burke LM, Eichner ER, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and fluid replacement. Med Sci Sports Exerc 39: 377&#x2013;390, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi Y, Adams WM, Benjamin CL, et al. Relationships between resting heart rate, heart rate variability and sleep characteristics among female collegiate cross-country athletes. J Sleep Res 28: e12836, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi Y, Adams WM, Curtis RM, Benjamin CL, Casa DJ. Factors influencing hydration status during a National Collegiate Athletics Association division 1 soccer preseason. J Sci Med Sport 22: 624&#x2013;628, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stutz J, Eiholzer R, Spengler CM. Effects of evening exercise on sleep in healthy participants: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 49: 269&#x2013;287, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpe SL, Poule KA, Bland EG. Estimation of prepractice hydration status of national collegiate athletic association division I athletes. J Athl Train 44: 624&#x2013;629, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Boros S. The effect of physical activity on sleep quality: A systematic review. Eur J Physiother 23: 11&#x2013;18, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AM. Sleep and athletic performance. Curr Sports Med Rep 16: 413&#x2013;418, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weitzman ED. Circadian rhythms and episodic hormone secretion in man. Annu Rev Med 27: 225&#x2013;243, 1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson M-MG, Morley JE. Impaired cognitive function and mental performance in mild dehydration. Eur J Clin Nutr 57: S24&#x2013;S29, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeargin SW, Casa DJ, Armstrong LE, et al. Heat acclimatization and hydration status of American football players during initial summer workouts. J Strength Cond Res 20: 463&#x2013;470, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeargin SW, Casa DJ, Judelson DA, et al. Thermoregulatory responses and hydration practices in heat-acclimatized adolescents during preseason high school football. J Athl Train 45: 136&#x2013;146, 2010.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>