<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30988847</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>66</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Training Loads, Wellness and Performance Before and During Tapering for a Water-Polo Tournament.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>131</StartPage><EndPage>141</EndPage><MedlinePgn>131-141</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2018-0053</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We investigated the effectiveness of a short-duration training period including an overloaded (weeks 1 and 2) and a reduced training load period (weeks 3 and 4) on wellness, swimming performance and a perceived internal training load in eight high-level water-polo players preparing for play-offs. The internal training load was estimated daily using the rating of perceived exertion (RPE) and session duration (session-RPE). Perceived ratings of wellness (fatigue, muscle soreness, sleep quality, stress level and mood) were assessed daily. Swimming performance was evaluated through 400-m and 20-m tests performed before (baseline) and after the end of weeks 2 and 4. In weeks 3 and 4, the internal training load was reduced by 19.0 &#xb1; 3.8 and 36.0 &#xb1; 4.7%, respectively, compared to week 1 (p = 0.00). Wellness was improved in week 4 (20.4 &#xb1; 2.8 AU) compared to week 1 and week 2 by 16.0 &#xb1; 2.2 and 17.3 &#xb1; 2.9 AU, respectively (p =0.001). At the end of week 4, swimming performance at 400-m and 20-m tests (299.0 &#xb1; 10.2 and 10.2 &#xb1; 0.3 s) was improved compared to baseline values (301.4 &#xb1; 10.9 and 10.4 &#xb1; 0.4 s, p &lt; 0.05) and the overloading training period (week 2; 302.9 &#xb1; 9.0 and 10.4 &#xb1; 0.4 s, p &lt; 0.05). High correlations were observed between the percentage reduction of the internal training load from week 4 to week 1 (-25.3 &#xb1; 5.5%) and the respective changes in 20-m time (-2.1 &#xb1; 2.2%, r = 0.88, p &lt; 0.01), fatigue perception (39.6 &#xb1; 27.1%), muscle soreness (32.5 &#xb1; 26.6%), stress levels (25.6 &#xb1; 15.1%) and the overall wellness scores (28.6 &#xb1; 21.9%, r = 0.74-0.79, p &lt; 0.05). The reduction of the internal training load improved the overall perceived wellness and swimming performance of players. The aforementioned periodization approach may be an effective training strategy in the lead-up to play-off tournaments.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Botonis</LastName><ForeName>Petros G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aquatic Sports, School of Physical Education and Sports Science, University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toubekis</LastName><ForeName>Argyris G</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aquatic Sports, School of Physical Education and Sports Science, University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Platanou</LastName><ForeName>Theodoros I</ForeName><Initials>TI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aquatic Sports, School of Physical Education and Sports Science, University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team-sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water polo training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30988847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6458570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2018-0053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2018-0053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbiss CR, Peiffer JJ, Meeusen R, Skorski S. Role of ratings of perceived exertion during self-paced exercise: what are we actually measuring? Sports Med. 2015;45:1235&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26054383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson L, Triplett-McBride T, Foster C, Doberstein S, Brice C. Impact of training patterns on incidence of illness and injury during a women&#x2019;s collegiate basketball season. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:734&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubry A, Hausswirh C, Louis J, Coutts AJ, LE Meur Y. Functional overreaching: the key to peak performance during the taper? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46:1769&#x2013;1777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25134000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barroso R, Cardoso RK, do Carmo EC, Tricoli V. Perceived exertion in coaches and young swimmers with different training experience. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9:212&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23630106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosque tL, Montpetit J, Arvisais D, Mujika I. Effects of tapering on performance: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1358&#x2013;1365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botonis PG, Toubekis AG, Platanou TI. Physiological responses of water-polo players under different tactical strategies. J Sports Sci Med. 2015;14:84&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4306787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25729294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botonis PG, Toubekis AG, Terzis GD, Geladas ND, Platanou TI. Performance decrement and skill deterioration during a water polo game are linked with the conditioning level of the athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:1033&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26349048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Racinais JC, Bilborough JC, Burdon PC, Voss SC, Hocking J, Cordy J, Mendez-Villanueva A, Coutts AJ. Monitoring fitness, fatigue and running performance during a pre-season training camp in elite football players. J Sci Med Sport. 2013;16:550&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23332540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canossa S, Abraides JA, Soares S, Vila MH, Rodriguez N, Argudo FM, Fernandes RJ, Garganta JM. Contrasting morphology and training background in waterpolo teams of different competitive levels. Motritz, Rio Claro. 2014;20:272&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ, Reaburn P. Monitoring changes in rugby league players&#x2019; perceived stress and recovery during intensified training. Percept Motor Skills. 2008;106:904&#x2013;916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18712214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, Gottschall L, Hrovatin LA, Parker S, Eads M, Dodge C. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15:109&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas CG, Aoki MS, Franciscon CA, Arruda AF, Carling C, Moreira A. Psychophysiological responses tooverloadingand tapering phases in elite youngsoccerplayers. PediatrExercSci. 2014;26:195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24722819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Domrow N. Relationships between training load, injury, and fitness in sub-elite collision sport athletes. J Sports Sci. 2007;25:1507&#x2013;1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudino P, Iaia FM, Strudwick AJ, Hawkins RD, Alberti G, Atkinson G, Gregson W. Factors influencing perception of effort (session rating of perceived exertion) during elite soccer training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10:860&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25671338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper SL, Mackinnon LT. Monitoring overtraining in athletes. Recommendations. Sports Med. 1995;20:321&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8571005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper SL, Mackinnon LT, Howard A. Physiological and psychometric variables for monitoring recovery during tapering for major competition. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;31:1205&#x2013;1210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Linear models and effect magnitudes for research, clinical and practical applications. Sportscience. 2010;14:49&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Rampinini E, Coutts AJ, Sassi A, Marcora SM. Use of RPE-based training load in soccer. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:1042&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15179175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns RA, Houmard JA, Kobe RW, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Bruno NJ, Wells JM, Shinebarger MH. Effects of taper on swim power, stroke distance and performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24:1141&#x2013;1146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1435162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupo C, Capranica L, Tessitore A. The validity of session-RPE method for quantifying training load in water polo. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014a;9:656&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24231176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupo C, Condello G, Capranica A. Women&#x2019;s water polo world championships: technical and tactical aspects of winning and losing teams in close and unbalanced games. J Strength Cond Res. 2014b;28:210&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23588481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzi V, D&#x2019;Ottavio S, Impellizzeri FM, Chaouachi A, Chamari K, Castagna C. Profile of weekly training load in elite male professional basketball players. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:1399&#x2013;1406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5:367&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20861526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira A, Bilsborough JC, Sullivan CJ, Ciancosi M, Aoki MS, Coutts AJ. Training periodization of professional Australian football players during an entire Australian Football League season. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10:566&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25405365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I. Tapering and peaking for optimal performance. Champain, IL: Human kinetics; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Chatard JC, Busso T, Geyssant A, Barale F, Lacoste L.. Effects of training on performance in competitive swimming. Can J ApplPhysiol. 1995;20:395&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8563672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S, Pyne D, Busso T. Physiological changes associated with the pre-event taper in athletes. Sports Med. 2004;34:891&#x2013;927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15487904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JA, Moreira A, Crewther BT, Nosaka K, Viveiros L, Aoki MS. Monitoring training load, recovery-stress state, immune-endocrine responses, and physical performance in elite female basketball players during a periodized training program. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:2973&#x2013;2980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24736768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papoti M, Martins LE, Cunha SA, Zagatto AM, Gobatto CA. Effects of taper on swimming force and swimmer performance after an experimental ten-week training program. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:538&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raglin JS, Koceja DM, Stager JM, Harms CA. Mood, neuromuscular function, and performance during training in female swimmers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:372&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8776226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos Veliz R, Requena B, Suarez-Arrones L, Newton RU, S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E. Effects of 18-week in-season heavy-resistanceand powertrainingon throwing velocity,strength, jumping, and maximal sprint swim performance of elite malewaterpoloplayers. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:1007&#x2013;1014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24077370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saw AE, Main LC, Gastin PB. Monitoring the athlete training response: subjective self-reported measures trump commonly used objective measures: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2015;0:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26423706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>