<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35734393</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2689-288X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurotrauma reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurotrauma Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hiding in Plain Sight: Factors Influencing the Neuroinflammatory Response to Sport-Related Concussion.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>200</StartPage><EndPage>206</EndPage><MedlinePgn>200-206</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1089/neur.2021.0081</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sport-related concussion (SRC) is a major concern among athletes and clinicians around the world. Research into fluid biomarkers of SRC has made significant progress in understanding the complex underlying pathophysiology of concussion. However, little headway has been made toward clinically validating any biomarkers to improve the clinical management of SRC. A major obstacle toward clinical translation of any fluid biomarker is the heterogeneity of SRC overlapping with multiple physiological systems involved in pathology and recovery. Neuroinflammation post-SRC is one such system that may confound fluid biomarker data on many fronts. Neuroinflammatory processes consist of cell mediators, both within the central nervous system and the periphery, that play vital roles in regulating the response to brain injury. Further, neuroinflammation is influenced by many biopsychosocial variables present in most athletic populations. In this commentary, we propose that future fluid biomarker research should take a systems biology approach in the context of the neuroinflammatory response to SRC. We highlight how biological variables, such as age, sex, immune challenges, and hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA)-axis responses to stress, may alter neuroinflammation. Further, we underscore the importance of accounting for health and lifestyle variables, such as diet, exercise, sleep, and pre-morbid medical factors, when measuring inflammatory markers of SRC. To successfully move toward clinical translation, fluid biomarker research should take a more holistic approach in study design and data interpretation, collecting information on hidden variables that may be influencing the neuroinflammatory response to SRC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Jason B. Tabor et al., 2022; Published by Mary Ann Liebert, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tabor</LastName><ForeName>Jason B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Injury Prevention Research Centre, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hotchkiss Brain Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alberta Children's Hospital Research Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCrea</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meier</LastName><ForeName>Timothy B</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Emery</LastName><ForeName>Carolyn A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Injury Prevention Research Centre, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hotchkiss Brain Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alberta Children's Hospital Research Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Debert</LastName><ForeName>Chantel T</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hotchkiss Brain Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alberta Children's Hospital Research Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurotrauma Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101773091</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2689-288X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fluid biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroinflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport-related concussion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No competing financial interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35734393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9153987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neur.2021.0081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1089/neur.2021.0081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McCrea M, Broglio SP, McAllister TW, et al. Association of blood biomarkers with acute sport-related concussion in collegiate athletes: findings from the NCAA and Department of Defense CARE Consortium. JAMA Netw Open 2020;3(1):e1919771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6991302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31977061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattinson CL, Meier TB, Guedes VA, et al. Plasma biomarker concentrations associated with return to sport following sport-related concussion in collegiate athletes&#x2014;a Concussion Assessment, Research, and Education (CARE) Consortium Study. JAMA Netw Open 2020;3(8):e2013191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32852552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zetterberg H, Blennow K.. Fluid biomarkers for mild traumatic brain injury and related conditions. Nat Rev Neurol 2016;12(10):563&#x2013;574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27632903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier TB, Huber DL, Bohorquez-Montoya L, et al. A prospective study of acute blood-based biomarkers for sport-related concussion. Ann Neurol 2020;87(6):907&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7477798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitta ME, Savitz J, Nelson LD, et al. Acute elevation of serum inflammatory markers predicts symptom recovery after concussion. Neurology 2019;93(5):e497&#x2013;e507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31270219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mc Fie S, Abrahams S, Patricios J, et al. Inflammatory and apoptotic signalling pathways and concussion severity: a genetic association study. J Sports Sci 2018;36(19):2226&#x2013;2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29509495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cash A, Theus MH. Mechanisms of blood-brain barrier dysfunction in traumatic brain injury. Int J Mol Sci 2020;21(9):3344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7246537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32397302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thelin EP, Zeiler FA, Ercole A, et al. Serial sampling of serum protein biomarkers for monitoring human traumatic brain injury dynamics: a systematic review. Front Neurol 2017;8:300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5494601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28717351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokiko-Cochran ON, Godbout JP, Tapp ZM. A tilted axis: maladaptive inflammation and HPA axis dysfunction contribute to consequences of TBI. Front Neurol 2019;10:345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6491704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31068886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figaji AA. Anatomical and physiological differences between children and adults relevant to traumatic brain injury and the implications for clinical assessment and care. Front Neurol 2017;8:685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5735372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29312119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T, Shirane R, Sato S, et al. Developmental changes of cerebral blood flow and oxygen metabolism in children. Am J Neuroradiol 1999;20(5):917&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7056161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10369366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraunberger E, Esser MJ. Neuro-inflammation in pediatric traumatic brain injury&#x2014;from mechanisms to inflammatory networks. Brain Sci 2019;9(11):319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6895990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31717597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prange MT, Margulies SS. Regional, directional, and age-dependent properties of the brain undergoing large deformation. J Biomech Eng 2002;124(2):244&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12002135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabert K, Michoel T, Karavolos MH, et al. Microglial brain region-dependent diversity and selective regional sensitivities to aging. Nat Neurosci 2016;19(3):504&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4768346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldrimer M, Ridefelt P, R&#xf6;d&#xf6;&#xf6; P, et al. Population-based pediatric reference intervals for hematology, iron and transferrin. Scandinavian journal of clinical and laboratory investigation, 2013;73(3):253&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23448533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yegin O. Chemotaxis in childhood. Pediatr Res 1983;17(3):183&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6835722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rea IM, Gibson DS, McGilligan V, et al. Age and age-related diseases: role of inflammation triggers and cytokines. Front Immunol 2018;9:586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5900450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29686666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirtcliff EA, Dahl RE, Pollak SD. Pubertal development: correspondence between hormonal and physical development. Child Dev 2009;80(2):327&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2727719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19466995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz C, Karali K, Fodelianaki G, et al. Neurosteroids as regulators of neuroinflammation. Front Neuroendocrinol 2019;55:100788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31513776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley N, Jeltema D, Duan Y, et al. The NLRP3 inflammasome: an overview of mechanisms of activation and regulation. Int J Mol Sci 2019;20(13):3328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6651423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31284572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakkar R, Wang R, Sareddy G, et al. NLRP3 inflammasome activation in the brain after global cerebral ischemia and regulation by 17&#x3b2;-estradiol. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2016;2016:8309031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5097821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27843532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryanpour R, Pasbakhsh P, Zibara K, et al. Progesterone therapy induces an M1 to M2 switch in microglia phenotype and suppresses NLRP3 inflammasome in a cuprizone-induced demyelination mouse model. Int Immunopharmacol 2017;51:131&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28830026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brambilla DJ, Matsumoto AM, Araujo AB, et al. The effect of diurnal variation on clinical measurement of serum testosterone and other sex hormone levels in men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2009;94(3):907&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2681273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd R, Cheung AS, Pang K, et al. Sexual dimorphism in innate immunity: the role of sex hormones and epigenetics. Front Immunol 2020;11:604000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33584674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadel S, Kovats S.. Sex hormones regulate innate immune cells and promote sex differences in respiratory virus infection. Front Immunol 2018;9:1653&#x2013;1653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6062604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30079065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doran SJ, Ritzel RM, Glaser EP, et al. Sex differences in acute neuroinflammation after experimental traumatic brain injury are mediated by infiltrating myeloid cells. J Neurotrauma 2019;36(7):1040&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6444913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30259790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wunderle MK, Hoeger KM, Wasserman ME, et al. Menstrual phase as predictor of outcome after mild traumatic brain injury in women. J Head Trauma Rehabil 2014;29(5):E1&#x2013;E8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5237582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24220566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arlt W, Stewart PM. Adrenal corticosteroid biosynthesis, metabolism, and action. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 2005;34(2):293&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15850843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer RL, Deak T.. A users guide to HPA axis research. Physiol Behav 2017;178:43&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5451309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27871862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sierra A, Gottfried-Blackmore A, Milner TA, et al. Steroid hormone receptor expression and function in microglia. Glia 2008;56(6):659&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18286612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herold MJ, McPherson KG, Reichardt HM. Glucocorticoids in T cell apoptosis and function. Cell Mol Life Sci 2006;63(1):60&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2792342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16314919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hue CD, Cho FS, Cao S, et al. Dexamethasone potentiates in vitro blood-brain barrier recovery after primary blast injury by glucocorticoid receptor-mediated upregulation of ZO-1 tight junction protein. J Cereb Blood Flow Metabol 2015;35(7):1191&#x2013;1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4640274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25757751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador E, Shityakov S, F&#xf6;rster C.. Glucocorticoids and endothelial cell barrier function. Cell Tissue Res 2014;355(3):597&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3972429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24352805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie E, Emery C, Debert C.. Analysis of serum cortisol to predict recovery in paediatric sport-related concussion. Brain Inj 2018;32(4):523&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29400570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacioglu A, Kelestimur F, Tanriverdi F.. Pituitary dysfunction due to sports-related traumatic brain injury. Pituitary 2019;22(3):322&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30637622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shultz SR, Sun M, Wright DK, et al. Tibial fracture exacerbates traumatic brain injury outcomes and neuroinflammation in a novel mouse model of multitrauma. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 2015;35(8):1339&#x2013;1347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4528010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald SJ, Sun M, Agoston DV, et al. The effect of concomitant peripheral injury on traumatic brain injury pathobiology and outcome. J Neuroinflammation 2016;13(1):90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4847339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27117191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcia MA, Bonsall DR, Bloomfield PS, et al. Stress and neuroinflammation: a systematic review of the effects of stress on microglia and the implications for mental illness. Psychopharmacology 2016;233(9):1637&#x2013;1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4828495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26847047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsland AL, Walsh C, Lockwood K, et al. The effects of acute psychological stress on circulating and stimulated inflammatory markers: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Behav Immun 2017;64:208&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28089638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger E, Castagn&#xe9; R, Chadeau-Hyam M, et al. Multi-cohort study identifies social determinants of systemic inflammation over the life course. Nat Commun 2019;10(1):773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6377676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30770820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niraula A, Wang Y, Godbout JP, et al. Corticosterone production during repeated social defeat causes monocyte mobilization from the bone marrow, glucocorticoid resistance, and neurovascular adhesion molecule expression. J Neurosci 2018;38(9):2328&#x2013;2340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5830519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29382712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tursich M, R.W.J. Neufeld RWJ, P.A. Frewen PA, et al. Association of trauma exposure with proinflammatory activity: a transdiagnostic meta-analysis. Transl Psychiatry 2014;4:e413&#x2013;e413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4119223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25050993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowlati Y, Herrmann N, Swardfager W, et al. A meta-analysis of cytokines in major depression. Biol Psychiatry 2010;67(5):446&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20015486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galland L. Diet and inflammation. Nutr Clin Pract 2010;25(6):634&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21139128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo HM, Santos LE, Ferreira ST. Diet-derived fatty acids, brain inflammation, and mental health. Front Neurosci 2019;13:265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6448040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30983955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGrattan AM, McGuinness B, McKinley MC, et al. Diet and inflammation in cognitive ageing and Alzheimer's disease. Curr Nutr Rep 2019;8(2):53&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6486891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30949921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeira MH, Boia R, Ambr&#xf3;sio AF, et al. Having a coffee break: the impact of caffeine consumption on microglia-mediated inflammation in neurodegenerative diseases. Mediators Inflamm 2017;2017:4761081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5307009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28250576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imhof A, Froehlich M, Brenner H, et al. Effect of alcohol consumption on systemic markers of inflammation. Lancet 2001;357(9258):763&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11253971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton SR, Kranz S, SMalin SK, et al. Factors associated with energy expenditure and energy balance in acute sport-related concussion. J Athl Train 2021;56(8):860&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33150378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton SR, Malin SK, Kranz S, et al. Whole-body metabolism, carbohydrate utilization, and caloric energy balance after sport concussion: a pilot study. Sports Health 2020;12(4):382&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32520660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walrand S, Gaulmin R, Aubin R, et al. Nutritional factors in sport-related concussion. Neurochirurgie 2021;67(3):255&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33582206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowson MM, McClave SA. Does the intestinal microbiome impact athletic performance? Curr Gastroenterol Rep 2020;22(11):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32827270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsios GS, Moe RH, Kitas GD. Exercise and inflammation. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol 2020;34(2):101504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32249021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK, Febbraio MA. Muscle as an endocrine organ: focus on muscle-derived interleukin-6. Physiol Rev 2008;88:1379&#x2013;1406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18923185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mee-Inta O, Zhao ZW, Kuo YM. Physical exercise inhibits inflammation and microglial activation. Cells 2019;8(7):691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31324021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy JJ, Master CL, Mannix R, et al. Early targeted heart rate aerobic exercise versus placebo stretching for sport-related concussion in adolescents: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2021;5(11):792&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34600629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5th International Conference on Concussion in Sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med 2017;51(11):838&#x2013;847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathbone ATL, Tharmaradinam S, Jiang S, et al. A review of the neuro- and systemic inflammatory responses in post concussion symptoms: Introduction of the &#x201c;post-inflammatory brain syndrome&#x201d; PIBS. Brain Behav Immun 2015;46:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25736063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullington JM, Simpson NS, Meier-Ewert HK, et al. Sleep loss and inflammation. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab 2010;24(5):775&#x2013;784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3548567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21112025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rainsford KD. Ibuprofen: pharmacology, efficacy and safety. Inflammopharmacology 2009;17(6):275&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19949916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cain DW, Cidlowski JA. Immune regulation by glucocorticoids. Nat Rev Immunol 2017;17(4):233&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9761406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28192415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panzner P, Malkusov&#xe1; I, Vachov&#xe1; M, et al. Bronchial inflammation in seasonal allergic rhinitis with or without asthma in relation to natural exposure to pollen allergens. Allergol Immunopathol (Madr) 2015;43(1):3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24075536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furman D, Davis MM. New approaches to understanding the immune response to vaccination and infection. Vaccine 2015;33(40):5271&#x2013;5281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4581990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26232539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyanathan M, Afkhami S, Smaill F, et al. Immunological considerations for COVID-19 vaccine strategies. Nat Rev Immunol 2020;20(10):615&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7472682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32887954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>