<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24149155</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1303-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sports science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Challenges in Maintaining Emotion Regulation in a Sleep and Energy Deprived State Induced by the 4800Km Ultra-Endurance Bicycle Race; The Race Across AMerica (RAAM).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>481</StartPage><EndPage>488</EndPage><MedlinePgn>481-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Multiday ultra-endurance races present athletes with a significant number of physiological and psychological challenges. We examined emotions, the perceived functionality (optimal-dysfunctional) of emotions, strategies to regulate emotions, sleep quality, and energy intake-expenditure in a four-man team participating in the Race Across AMerica (RAAM); a 4856km continuous cycle race. Cyclists reported experiencing an optimal emotional state for less than 50% of total competition, with emotional states differing significantly between each cyclist over time. Coupled with this emotional disturbance, each cyclist experienced progressively worsening sleep deprivation and daily negative energy balances throughout the RAAM. Cyclists managed less than one hour of continuous sleep per sleep episode, high sleep latency and high percentage moving time. Of note, actual sleep and sleep efficiency were better maintained during longer rest periods, highlighting the importance of a race strategy that seeks to optimise the balance between average cycling velocity and sleep time. Our data suggests that future RAAM cyclists and crew should: 1) identify beliefs on the perceived functionality of emotions in relation to best (functional-optimal) and worst (dysfunctional) performance as the starting point to intervention work; 2) create a plan for support sufficient sleep and recovery; 3) create nutritional strategies that maintain energy intake and thus reduce energy deficits; and 4) prepare for the deleterious effects of sleep deprivation so that they are able to appropriately respond to unexpected stressors and foster functional working interpersonal relationships. Key PointsCompleting the Race Across AMerica (RAAM); a 4856km continuous cycle race associated with sleep disturbance, an energy-deficient state, and experiencing intense unwanted emotions.Cyclists reported experiencing an optimal emotional state for less than 50% of total competition and actual sleep and sleep efficiency was better maintained during longer rest periods.We suggest that future RAAM cyclists and crew should:Identify individual beliefs on the perceived functionality of emotional states in relation to best (optimal) and worst (dysfunctional) performance as the starting point to identifying if emotion regulation strategies should be initiated.Plan for enhanced sleep and recovery not just plan and train for maintaining a high average velocity;Create nutritional strategies that maintain energy intake and thus reduce energy deficits;Psychologically prepare cyclists and crew for the deleterious effects of sleep deprivation so that they both are able to appropriately respond to unexpected stressors and foster functional interpersonal working relationships.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lahart</LastName><ForeName>Ian M</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Performing Arts and Leisure, University of Wolverhampton , Walsall, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lane</LastName><ForeName>Andrew M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hulton</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Godfrey</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedlar</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Mathew G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whyte</LastName><ForeName>Gregory P</ForeName><Initials>GP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1303-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emotion regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy expenditure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mood</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultra-endurance exercise</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adam K., Oswald I. (1983) Protein synthesis, bodily renewal and the sleep-wake cycle. Clinical Science (Lond) 65, 561-567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6194928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ancoli-Israel S., Cole R., Alessi C., Chambers M., Moorcroft W., Pollak C.P. (2003) The role of actigraphy in the study of sleep and circadian rhythms. Sleep 26, 342-392</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12749557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie C.J., Lane A.M. (2012) The role of glucose in self-control: Another look at the evidence and an alternative conceptualization. Personality and Social Psychology Review 16(2),143-153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21896791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie C.J., Lane A.M., Wilson M. (2012) A possible role for emotion and emotion regulation in physiological responses to false performance feedback in 10km laboratory cycling. Applied Psychophysiology and Biofeedback 37(4), 269-277</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22752648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beedie C.J., Terry P.C., Lane A.M. (2000) The Profile of Mood States and athletic Performance: Two meta-analyses. Journal of Applied Sport Psychology 12, 49-68</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belenky G., Wesensten N.J., Thorne D.R., Thomas M.L., Sing H.C., Redmond D.P. (2003) Patterns of performance degradation and restoration during sleep restriction and subsequent recovery: a sleep dose-response study. Journal of Sleep Research 12, 1-12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12603781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen R.L., Adams J.H., Myburgh K.H. (2006) Nausea and high serum osmolality during a simulated ultraendurance adventure race: a case-control study. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance 1, 176-185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke L.M. (2001) Nutritional practices of male and female endurance cyclists. Sports Medicine 31, 521-532</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11428689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devonport T.J., Lane A.M., Hanin Y. (2005) Affective state profiles of athletes prior to best, worst and performance-induced injury outcomes. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 4, 382-394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3899654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24501552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devonport T.J., Lane A.M., Lloyd J. (2011) Keeping your cool: A case study of a female explorer's solo North Pole expedition. Journal of Human Performance in Extreme Environment 22, 333-337</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21982755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driver H.S., Taylor S.R. (2000) Exercise and sleep. Sleep Medicine Reviews 4, 387-402</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gailliot M.T., Baumeister R.F. (2007) The physiology of willpower: Linking blood glucose to self-control. Personality and Social Psychology Review 11, 303-327</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18453466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagger M.S., Wood C., Stiff C., Chatzisarantis N.L. (2010) Ego depletion and the strength model of self-control: a meta-analysis. Psychological Bulletin 136(4), 495-525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20565167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanin Y.L. (2010) Coping with anxiety in sport. Coping in sport: Theory, methods, and related constructs. Nicholls A.R.Hauppauge, NY: Nova Science; 159-175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne J.A. (2000) REM sleep - by default?. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews 24, 777-797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11118606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulton A.T., Lahart I., Williams K.L., Godfrey R., Charlesworth S., Wilson M., Pedlar C., Whyte G. (2010) Energy expenditure in the Race Across America (RAAM). International Journal of Sports Medicine 31, 463-467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20455193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup A.E., Jentjens R.L., Moseley L. (2005) Nutritional considerations in triathlon. Sports Medicine 35, 163-181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15707379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeukendrup A., Brouns F., Wagenmakers A.J., Saris W.H. (1997) Carbohydrate-electrolyte feedings improve 1 h time trial cycling performance. International Journal of Sports Medicine 18, 125-129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9081269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson P., Dahlstrom U., Brostrom A. (2006) Factors and interventions influencing health-related quality of life in patients with heart failure: a review of the literature. European Journal of Cardiovascular Nursing 5, 5-15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15967727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knechtle B., Enggist A., Jehle T. (2005) Energy turnover at the Race Across AMerica (RAAM) - a case report. International Journal of Sports Medicine 26, 499-503</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16037895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lack L.C., Wright H.R. (2007a) Treating chronobiological components of chronic insomnia. Sleep Medicine 8, 637-644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17383935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lack L.C., Wright H.R. (2007b) Chronobiology of sleep in humans. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences 64, 1205-1215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11136055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17364140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane A.M., Wilson (2011) Emotions and emotional intelligence among ultra-endurance runners. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport 14, 358-362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21440500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane A.M., Beedie C.J., Devonport T.J., Stanley D.M. (2011) Instrumental emotion regulation in sport: relationships between beliefs about emotion and emotion regulation strategies used by athletes. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports 21, e445-e451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21819448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane A.M., Beedie C.J., Jones M.V., Uphill M., Devonport T.J. (2012) The BASES Expert Statement on emotion regulation in sport. Journal of Sports Sciences 30(11), 1189-1195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22709410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Uchiyama M., Shibui K., Kim K., Kudo Y., Tagaya H. (2000) Diurnal preference, sleep habits, circadian sleep propensity and melatonin rhythm in healthy human subjects. Neuroscience Letters 280, 199-202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10675795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews G., Jones D.M., Chamberlain A.G. (1990) Refining the measurement of mood: The UWIST Mood Adjective Checklist. British Journal of Psychology 81, 17-42</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGinty D., Szymusiak R. (1990) Keeping cool: a hypothesis about the mechanisms and functions of slow-wave sleep. Trends in Neurosciences 13, 480-487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1703678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niven K., Totterdell P., Miles E., Sheeran P., Webb T. (2013). Achieving the same for less: Improving mood depletes blood glucose for people with poor (but not good) emotion control. Cognition &amp; Emotion 27(1), 133-140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22712512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedlar C.R., Lane A.M., Lloyd J.C., Dawson J., Emegbo S., Stanley N. (2007) Sleep profiles and mood state changes during an expedition to the South Pole: a case study of a female explorer. Wilderness and Environmental Medicine 18, 13-25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17590059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raglin J.S., Morgan WP. (1994) Development of a scale for use in monitoring training-induced distress in athletes. International Journal of Sports Medicine 15, 84-88</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8157374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A., Hauri P.J., Kripke D.F., Lavie P. (1995) The role of actigraphy in the evaluation of sleep disorders. Sleep 18, 288-302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7618029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher Y.O., Ahlgrim C., Prettin S., Pottgiesser T. (2011) Physiology, power output, and racing strategy of a Race Across America finisher. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 43(5), 885-889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R. S., Walsh J., Dement W. (1998) Sleep deprivation and the race across America. Journal of Sleep 22, 303-304</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley D.M., Beedie C.J., Lane A.M., Friesen A.P., Devonport T.J. (2012). Emotion regulation strategies used by runners prior to training and competition. International Journal of Sport and Exercise Psychology 10, 159-171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry P.C., Lane A.M., Fogarty G.J. (2003) Construct validity of the Profile of Mood States - Adolescents for use with adults. Psychology of Sport and Exercise 4, 125-139</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh R.M., Noakes T.D., Hawley J.A., Dennis S.C. (1994) Impaired high-intensity cycling performance time at low levels of dehydration. International Journal of Sports Medicine 7, 392-398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8002117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams K., George K., Hulton A., Godfrey R., Lahart I., Wilson M.G., Charlesworth S., Warburton D., Gaze D., Whyte G. (2011) A unique case series of novel biomarkers of cardiac damage in cyclists completing the 4800 km Race Across America (RAAM). Current medicinal chemistry 18(23), 3446-3451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21756241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>