<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36419805</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1984-0659</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sleep science (Sao Paulo, Brazil)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sleep Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep and nutritional profile of endurance and ultra-endurance running athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>441</StartPage><EndPage>447</EndPage><MedlinePgn>441-447</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5935/1984-0063.20220076</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sleeping and eating before and during an ultramarathon can directly affect an athlete's performance, who may also have their physiological adaptations and recovery process hindered by sleeping problems. Endurance and ultra-endurance athletes may have different sleep and nutrition profiles. Thus, this study aimed to describe the sleep profile (during preparation) and nutritional profile (during competition) of endurance (10-20km) and ultra-endurance (50-100km) running athletes. For this, 16 healthy volunteers answered questionnaires related to sleep quality (Pittsburgh sleep quality index), chronotype (morningness-eveningness questionnaire), and sleepiness (excessive daytime sleepiness questionnaire). Immediately after a competition, a form prepared by the research team about nutritional variables and volunteers' food records during the competition was applied. According to test scoring criteria (Pittsburgh sleep quality index &gt;5; sleepiness &gt;10), endurance running athletes showed low sleep quality. In addition, all athletes showed consumption of carbohydrates and lipids below the recommended, but excessive consumption of proteins. A positive association between sleepiness and sodium intake in endurance runners was observed (r=0.862; <i>p</i>=0.027). Sleep efficiency and race time showed a negative correlation only for ultra-endurance athletes (r=-0.834; <i>p</i>=0.039). The data obtained show that endurance athletes presented more sleep pattern alterations, however, endurance and ultra-endurance athletes showed inadequate nutritional consumption during the competition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dos Santos</LastName><ForeName>Nadia Esteves</ForeName><Initials>NE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Estadual de Campinas, Faculdade de Ci&#xea;ncias Aplicadas - Limeira - S&#xe3;o Paulo - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daniel</LastName><ForeName>Natalia Vilela Silva</ForeName><Initials>NVS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Estadual de Campinas, Faculdade de Ci&#xea;ncias Aplicadas - Limeira - S&#xe3;o Paulo - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franco</LastName><ForeName>Beatriz</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Estadual de Campinas, Faculdade de Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica - Campinas - S&#xe3;o Paulo - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bastos</LastName><ForeName>Andre Marana</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Estadual de Campinas, Faculdade de Ci&#xea;ncias Aplicadas - Limeira - S&#xe3;o Paulo - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belli</LastName><ForeName>Taisa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Estadual de Campinas, Faculdade de Ci&#xea;ncias Aplicadas - Limeira - S&#xe3;o Paulo - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esteves</LastName><ForeName>Andrea Maculano</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Estadual de Campinas, Faculdade de Ci&#xea;ncias Aplicadas - Limeira - S&#xe3;o Paulo - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Sleep Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101598477</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1984-0063</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition Personnel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Running</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36419805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9670775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5935/1984-0063.20220076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Belli T, Macedo DV, Ara&#xfa;jo GG, Reis IGM, Scariot PPM, Lazarim FL, et al. Mountain ultramarathon induces early increases of muscle damage, inflammation, and risk for acute renal injury. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa RJS, Knechtle B, Tarnopolsky M, Hoffman MD. Nutrition for ultramarathon running: trail, track, and road. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019 Mar;29(2):130&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30943823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin T, Arnal PJ, Hoffman MD, Millet GY. Sleep habits and strategies of ultramarathon runners. PloS One. 2018;13(5):e0194705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5942705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29742118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Goulet EDB, Maughan RJ. Considerations in the use of body mass change to estimate change in hydration status during a 161 kilometer ultramarathon running competition. Sports Med. 2018 Feb;48(2):243&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28895063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirshkowitz M, Whiton K, Albert SM, Alessi C, Bruni O, DonCarlos L, et al. National Sleep Foundation&#x2019;s sleep time duration recommendations: methodology and results summary. Sleep Health. 2015 Mar;1(1):40&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thun E, Bjorvatn B, Flo E, Harris A, Pallesen S. Sleep, circadian rhythms, and athletic performance. Sleep Med Rev. 2015 Oct;23:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25645125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saugy J, Place N, Millet GY, Degache F, Schena F, Millet GP. Alterations of neuromuscular function after the World&#x2019;s Most challenging mountain ultra-marathon. PLoS One. 2013 Jun;8(6):e65596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3694082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23840345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filardi M, Morini S, Plazzi G. Pre-race sleep management strategy and chronotype of offshore solo sailors. Nat Sci Sleep. 2020;12:263&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7210035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32440242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skein M, Duffield R, Edge J, Short MJ, Mundel T. Intermittent-sprint performance and muscle glycogen after 30 h of sleep deprivation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1301&#x2013;1311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21200339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes HKM, Medeiros A, M&#xf4;nico Neto M, Souza HS, Tufik S, et al. Sleep and muscle recovery: endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothesis. Med Hypotheses. 2011 Aug;77(2):220&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21550729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiller NB, Roberts JD, Beasley L, Chapman S, Pinto JM, Smith L, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition Position Stand: nutritional considerations for single-stage ultra-marathon training and racing. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2019 Nov;16(1):50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6839090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31699159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa RJ, Knechtle B, Tarnopolsky M, Hoffman MD. Nutrition for ultramarathon running: trail, track, and road. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019 Mar;29(2):130&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30943823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva NVD, Santos NE, Gobatto CA, Hoffmann LM, Esteves AM, Belli T. Nutritional strategies of an athlete with type 1 diabetes mellitus during a 217-km ultramarathon. Wilderness Environ Med. 2022 Mar;331(1):128&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34996696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimber NE, Ross JJ, Mason SL, Speedy DB. Energy balance during an ironman triathlon in male and female triathletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2002 Mar;12(1):47&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11993622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DT, Erdman KA, Burke LM, American College of Sports Medicine Joint Position Statement Nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(3):543&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AM. Sleep and athletic performance. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2017 Nov/Dec;16(6):413&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29135639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedito-Silva AA, Menna-Barreto LS, Marques N, Tenreiro S. In: Chronobiology: its role in clinical medicine, general biology and agriculture, part B. Hayes DK, Pauly JE, Reiter RJ, editors. New York: Wiley-Liss;; 1990. A self-assessment questionnaire for the determination of morningness-eveningness types in Brazil; pp. 89&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2217379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989 May;28(2):193&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns MW. A new method for measuring daytime sleepiness: the Epworth sleepiness scale. Sleep. 1991 Dec;14(6):540&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1798888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) Report of a WHO consultation. Geneva: WHO; 1997. Obesity: preventing and managing the global epidemic.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11234459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minist&#xe9;rio da Sa&#xfa;de (BR) Instituto de Alimenta&#xe7;&#xe3;o e Nutri&#xe7;&#xe3;o. Secretaria de Programas Especiais . Registro Fotogr&#xe1;fico para Inqu&#xe9;ritos Diet&#xe9;ticos - Utens&#xed;lios e Por&#xe7;&#xf5;es. Campinas: N&#xfa;cleo de Estudos e Pesquisas em Alimenta&#xe7;&#xe3;o (NEPA). Universidade Estadual de Campinas (UNICAMP); 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;cleo de Estudos e Pesquisas em Alimenta&#xe7;&#xe3;o (NEPA) Universidade Estadual de Campinas (UNICAMP) Tabela brasileira de composi&#xe7;&#xe3;o de alimentos. 4&#xaa;. Campinas: NEPA/UNICAMP; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JA, Benedict FG. A biometric study of human basal metabolism. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 1918;4(12):370&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1091498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16576330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. New York: Routledge Academic; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohayon M, Wickwire EM, Hirshkowitz M, Albert SM, Avidan A, Daly FJ, et al. National Sleep Foundation&#x2019;s sleep quality recommendations: first report. Sleep Health. 2017;3(1):6&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28346153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DT, Erdman KA, Burke LM. American College of Sports Medicine Joint Position Statement. Nutrition and Athletic Performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016 Mar;48(3):543&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine (US) Dietary reference intakes. The essential guide to nutrient requirements. Washington: The National Academies Press; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brager AJ, Demiral S, Choynowski J, et al. Earlier shift in race pacing can predict future performance during a single-effort ultramarathon under sleep deprivation. Sleep Sci. 2020;13(1):25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32670489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Pupo JS, Arins KM, Guglielmo AGL, Santos SG. Caracter&#xed;sticas fisiol&#xf3;gicas de corredores meio-fundistas de diferentes n&#xed;veis competitivos. Rev Educ F&#xed;sica/UEM. 2011;22(1):119&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Hew-Butler T, Stuempfle KJ. Exercise-associated hyponatremia and hydration status in 161-km ultramarathoners. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013 Apr;45(4):784&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23135369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandner MA, Jackson N, Gerstner JR, Knutson KL. Sleep symptoms associated with intake of specific dietary nutrients. J Sleep Res. 2014 Feb;23(1):22&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3866235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23992533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perea C, Moura MG, Stulbach T, Caparros DR. Adequa&#xe7;&#xe3;o da dieta quanto ao objetivo do exerc&#xed;cio. RBNE. 2015;9(50):129&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>