<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36930212</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep and Sport Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>408</StartPage><EndPage>416</EndPage><MedlinePgn>408-416</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000638</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Elite athletes and coaches believe sleep is the most important recovery strategy and widely consider it critical to optimal performance. Despite this perceived importance, there are numerous circumstances that can reduce sleep quantity and quality in athletic populations. Because of the effects of sleep loss on various physical, neurophysiological, and cognitive parameters, such perturbations can have consequences for performance and recovery outcomes. Although peer-reviewed literature examining the interaction between sleep, performance, and recovery in athletes is increasing, understanding of these issues remains equivocal. Perhaps most pertinently, the effect of sleep on sport performance does not align with a one-size-fits-all approach and rather depends on numerous factors such as type of sport, scheduling, time of the season, and the intraindividual requirements for sleep. The relationship between brain plasticity and memory, which in turn can influence learning processes and long-term memory consolidation, suggests that sleep may play an important role in learning new skills and tactics for both elite and developing athletes. The aim of this special issue review was to analyze the evidence of sleep loss on sport performance and recovery, with a specific focus on elite athletes. An assessment of these sleep-compromising situations that elite athletes may face during a typical season and practical considerations for alleviating these issues is also provided to further the understanding for medical professionals, scientists, and applied sporting practitioners alike.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fullagar</LastName><ForeName>Hugh H K</ForeName><Initials>HHK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport &amp; Exercise Discipline Group, Faculty of Health, University of Technology Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vincent</LastName><ForeName>Grace E</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health, Medical and Applied Sciences, Appleton Institute, Central Queensland University, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCullough</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Human and Machine Cognition, Pensacola, Florida, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halson</LastName><ForeName>Shona</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, Fitzroy, Victoria, Australia ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fowler</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane City, Queensland, Australia .</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36930212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000000638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-202307000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M. Enhancing recovery: Preventing underperformance in athletes. In: Kellmann M, ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellmann M. Preventing overtraining in athletes in high-intensity sports and stress/recovery monitoring. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2010;20(suppl 2):95&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer T, Wegmann M, Poppendieck W, Fullagar HHK. Regenerative interventions in professional football. Sports Orthop Traumatol 2014;30:112&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Halson S, Abaidia AE, Ahmaidi S, Dupont G. Stress, sleep and recovery in elite soccer: a critical review of the literature. Sports Med 45, 2015: 1387&#x2013;1400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med 2014;44(suppl 1):S13&#x2013;S23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts AJ, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: the effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and physiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med 2015;45:161&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skein M, Duffield R, Minett GM, Snape A, Murphy A. The effect of overnight sleep deprivation after competitive rugby league matches on postmatch physiological and perceptual recovery. Int J Sport Physiol Perform 2013;8:556&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Mah KE, Kezirian EJ, Dement WC. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep 2011;34:943&#x2013;950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah R. Sleep-dependent memory consolidation. Nature 2005;437:1272&#x2013;1278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran A. The Psychology of Concentration in Sport Performers: A Cognitive Analysis. Hove: Psychology Press, 1996; 317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar HH, Skorski S, Duffield R, Julian R, Bartlett J, Meyer T. Impaired sleep and recovery after night matches in elite football players. J Sports Sci 2016;34:1333&#x2013;1339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitchford N, Robertson SJ, Sargent C, Cordy J, Bishop DJ, Bartlett JD. A change in training environment alters sleep quality but not quantity in elite Australian Rules football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2016;12:75&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Halson S, Roach G. Early-morning training severely restricts the amount of sleep obtained by elite swimmers. Eur J Sport Sci 2014;14:S310&#x2013;S5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Lastella SL, Roach GD. The impact of training schedules on the sleep and fatigue of elite athletes. Chronobiol Int 2014;31:1160&#x2013;1168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalor B, Halson SL, Tran J, Kemp JG, Cormack SJ. Compromise of competition sleep compared with habitual sleep in elite Australian footballers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13:29&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller D, Sargent C, Vincent GE, Roach GD, Halson SL, Lastella M. Sleep/wake behaviours in elite athletes from three different football codes. J Sports Sci Med 2017;16:604&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald D, Beckmans C, Joyce D, Mills K. The influence of sleep and training load on illness in nationally competitive male Australian Football athletes: a cohort study over one season . J Sci Med Sport 2019;22:130&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venter RE. Perceptions of team athletes on the importance of recovery modalities. Eur J Sport Sci 2014;14(suppl 1):S69&#x2013;S76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff LE, Halson SL, Peiffer JJ. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important competitions. J Sci Med Sport 2015;18:13&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Glaister M, Pizzoferro K, Dawson J, Pedlar C. Sleep duration and quality in elite athletes measured using wristwatch actigraphy. J Sports Sci 2012;30:541&#x2013;545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff L, Peiffer J, Halson S. Night games: physiological, neuroendocrine and psychometric mechanisms to explain poor sleep . Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2017;13:867&#x2013;873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Duffield R, Skorski S, Coutts AJ, Julian R, Meyer T. Sleep and recovery in team sport: current sleep-related issues facing professional team-sport athletes . Int J Sport Physiol Perform 2015;10:950&#x2013;957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach G, Teng E, Mattey E, Halson S, Sargent C. Sleeping to a schedule: does chronotype play a part? In: Kennedy G, Sargent C, eds. Australasian Chronobiology Society: Little Clock, Big Clock: Molecular to Physiological Clocks. Melbourne, Australia: Australasian Chronobiology Society, 2011; 01&#x2013;04.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler PM, Duffield R, Morrow I, Roach G, Vaile J. Effects of sleep hygiene and artificial bright light interventions on recovery from simulated international air travel. Eur J Appl Physiol 2015;115:541&#x2013;553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler P, Crowcroft S, Mendham A, et al. Efficacy of Light Exposure &amp; Sleep Hygiene for Improving Athletic Performance Recovery Following Long-Haul travel. Melbourne, Australia: Exercise and Sport Science Australia&#x2014;Research to Practice, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. Sleep monitoring in athletes: motivation, methods, miscalculations and why it matters . Sports Med 2019;49:1487&#x2013;1497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent G, Aisbett B, Wolkow A, Jay SM, Ridgers ND, Ferguson SA. Sleep in wildland firefighters: what do we know and why does it matter? Int J Wildland Fire 2018;27:73&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyner LA, Horne JA. Sleep restriction and serving accuracy in performance tennis players, and effects of caffeine. Physiol Behav 2013;120:93&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarraya S, Jarraya M, Chtourou H, Souissi N. Effect of time of day and partial sleep deprivation on the reaction time and the attentional capacities of the handball goalkeeper. Biol Rhythm Res 2014;45:183&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards BJ, Waterhouse J. Effects of one night of partial sleep deprivation upon diurnal rhythms of accuracy and consistency in throwing darts. Chronobiol Int 2009;26:756&#x2013;768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL, Juliff LE. Sleep, sport, and the brain. Prog Brain Res 2017;234:13&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank MG, Benington JH. The role of sleep in memory consolidation and brain plasticity: dream or reality? Neuroscientist 2006;12:477&#x2013;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallesen S, Gundersen HS, Kristoffersen M, Bjorvatn B, Thun E, Harris A. The effects of sleep deprivation on soccer skills. Percept Mot Skills 2017;124:812&#x2013;829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fietze I, Strauch J, Holzhausen M, et al. Sleep quality in professional ballet dancers. Chronobiol Int 2009;26:1249&#x2013;1262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumortier J, Mariman A, Boone J, et al. Sleep, training load and performance in elite female gymnasts. Eur J Sport Sci 2018;18:151&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinnerton S, Reilly T. Effects of Sleep Loss and Time of Day in Swimmers. London, United Kingdom: E and FN Spon, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staunton C, Gordon B, Custovic E, Stanger J, Kingsley M. Sleep patterns and match performance in elite Australian basketball athletes. J Sci Med Sport 2017;20:786&#x2013;789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejri M, Hammouda O, Zouaoui K, et al. Effect of two types of partial sleep deprivation on Taekwondo players' performance during intermittent exercise. Biol Rhythm Res 2014;45:17&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skein M, Duffield R, Edge J, Short MJ, M&#xfc;ndel T. Intermittent-sprint performance and muscle glycogen after 30 h of sleep deprivation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2011;43:1301&#x2013;1311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi L, Davis GM, Plyley M, Goode R, Shephard RJ. Sleep deprivation, chronic exercise and muscular performance. Ergonomics 1985;28:591&#x2013;601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Sesbo&#xfc;&#xe9; B, Gauthier A, Larue J, Davenne D. Effects of one night's sleep deprivation on anaerobic performance the following day. Eur J Appl Physiol 2003;89:359&#x2013;366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin BJ. Effect of sleep deprivation on tolerance of prolonged exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 1981;47:345&#x2013;354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symons JD, VanHelder T, Myles WS. Physical performance and physiological responses following 60 hours of sleep deprivation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 1988;20:374&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F, Simon-Rigaud ML, Davenne D, et al. Effects of sleep disturbances on subsequent physical performance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 1991;63:77&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Deykin T. Effects of partial sleep loss on subjective states, psychomotor and physical performance tests. J Hum Move Stud 1983;9:157&#x2013;170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin F, Bourdin H, Simon-Rigaud ML, Nguyen NU, Kantelip JP, Davenne D. Hormonal responses to exercise after partial sleep deprivation and after a hypnotic drug-induced sleep. J Sports Sci 2001;19:89&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Hales A. Effects of Partial Sleep Deprivation on Performance Measures in Females. London, United Kingdom: Taylor and Francis, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson JA. Sleep is of the brain, by the brain and for the brain. Nature 2005;437:1254&#x2013;1256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond SP, Anderson DE, Straus LD, Vogel EK, Perez VB. The effects of two types of sleep deprivation on visual working memory capacity and filtering efficiency. PLoS One 2012;7:e35653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sateia MJ, Doghramji K, Doghramji PJ, Morin CM. Evaluation of chronic insomnia. An American Academy of Sleep Medicine review. Sleep 2000;23:243&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake MJ, Trinder JA, Allen NB. Mechanisms underlying the association between insomnia, anxiety, and depression in adolescence: implications for behavioral sleep interventions. Clin Psychol Rev 2018;63:25&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray A, Fullagar H, Turner AP. Recovery practices in Division 1 collegiate athletes in North America. Phys Ther Sport 2018;32:67&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale J, Banfi G, Galbiati A, Ferini-Strambi L, La Torre A. Effect of night-game on actigraphy-based sleep quality and perceived recovery in top-level volleyball athletes . Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2019;14:265&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rae DE, Chin T, Dikgomo K, et al. One night of partial sleep deprivation impairs recovery from a single exercise training session. Eur J Appl Physiol 2017;117:699&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durmer JS, Dinges DF. Neurocognitive consequences of sleep deprivation. Semin Neurol 2005;25:117&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi B, He D, Zhang M, Xue J, Zhou D. Short sleep duration predicts risk of metabolic syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev 2014;18:293&#x2013;297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Main LC, Dawson B, Heel K, Grove JR, Landers GJ, Goodman C. Relationship between inflammatory cytokines and self-report measures of training overload. Res Sports Med 2010;18:127&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laux P, Krumm B, Diers M, Flor H. Recovery-stress balance and injury risk in professional football players: a prospective study. J Sports Sci 2015;33:2140&#x2013;2148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vyazovskiy V, Delogu A. NREM and REM sleep: complementary roles in recovery after wakefulness. Neuroscientist 2014;20:203&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Nutrition, sleep and recovery. Eur J Sport Sci 2008;8:119&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes HK, Medeiros A, et al. Sleep and muscle recovery: endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothesis. Med Hypotheses 2011;77:220&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor SR, Rogers GG, Driver HS. Effects of training volume on sleep, psychological, and selected physiological profiles of elite female swimmers. Med Sci Sports Exerc 1997;29:688&#x2013;693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts S, Teo W, Warmington S. Effects of training and competition on the sleep of elite athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis . Br J Sports Med 2019;53:513&#x2013;522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;lling S, Steinacker JM, Endler S, Ferrauti A, Meyer T, Kellmann M. The longer the better: sleep-wake patterns during preparation of the world rowing junior championships. Chronobiol Int 2016;33:73&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Tejero-Gonz&#xe1;lez Carlos M, del Campo-Vecino J. Relationships between training load, salivary cortisol responses and performance during season training in middle and long distance runners. PLoS One 2014;9:e106066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iellamo F, Legramante JM, Pigozzi F, et al. Conversion from vagal to sympathetic predominance with strenuous training in high-performance world class athletes. Circulation 2001;105:2719&#x2013;2724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess H, Trinder J, Kim Y, Luke D. Sleep and circadian influences on cardiac autonomic nervous system activity. Am J Physiol 1997;273:1761&#x2013;1768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Roach G. Sleep duration is reduced in elite athletes following night-time competition. Chronobiol Int 2016;33:667&#x2013;670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell S, Bird S, Jacbson G, Driller M. Sleep and stress hormone responses to training and competition in elite female athletes. Eur J Sport Sci 2018;18:611&#x2013;618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivlighan KT, Granger DA. Salivary alpha-amylase response to competition: relation to gender, previous experience, and attitudes. Psychoneuroendocrinology 2006;31:703&#x2013;714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veale JP, Pearce AJ. Physiological responses of elite junior Australian Rules footballers during match-play. J Sports Sci Med 2009;8:314&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnet MH, Arand DL. Hyperarousal and insomnia: state of the science. Sleep Med Rev 2010;14:9&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhart K, Phelps JR. Amber lenses to block blue light and improve sleep: a randomized trial. Chronobiol Int 2009;26:1602&#x2013;1612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunican IC, Higgins CC, Jones MJ, et al. Caffeine use in a Super Rugby game and its relationship to post-game sleep. Eur J Sport Sci 2018;18:513&#x2013;523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feige B, Gann H, Brueck R, et al. Effects of alcohol on polysomnographically recorded sleep in healthy subjects. Alcohol Clin Exp Res 2006;30:1527&#x2013;1537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice C, Stannard SR, Barnes MJ. The effects of binge drinking behaviour on recovery and performance after a rugby match. J Sci Med Sport 2014;17:244&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finan PH, Quartana PJ, Smith MT. The effects of sleep continuity disruption on positive mood and sleep architecture in healthy adults. Sleep 2015;38:1735&#x2013;1742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Reilly T, Atkinson G, Edwards B. Jet lag: trends and coping strategies. Lancet 2007;369:1117&#x2013;1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thun E, Bjorvatn B, Flo E, Harris A, Pallesen S. Sleep, circadian rhythms, and athletic performance. Sleep Med Rev 2015;23:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler PM, Kenz W, Crowcroft S, et al. Greater effect of east versus west travel on jet lag, sleep, and team sport performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2017;49:2548&#x2013;2561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler PM, McCall A, Jones M, Duffield R. Effects of long-haul transmeridian travel on player preparedness: case study of a national team at the 2014 FIFA World Cup. J Sci Med Sport 2017;20:322&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;lling S, Treff G, Winkert K, et al. The effect of westward travel across five time zones on sleep and subjective jet-lag ratings in athletes before and during the 2015's World Rowing Junior Championships. J Sports Sci 2017;35:2240&#x2013;2248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler P, Duffield R, Howle K, Waterson A, Vaile J. Effects of northbound long-haul international air travel on sleep quantity and subjective jet lag and wellness in professional Australian soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2015;10:648&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler P, Duffield R, Vaile J. Effects of simulated domestic and international air travel on sleep, performance, and recovery for team sports. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2015;25:441&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roach G, Matthews R, Naweed A, Kontou TG, Sargent C. Flat-out napping: the quantity and quality of sleep obtained in a seat during the daytime increase as the angle of recline of the seat increases. Chronobiol Int 2018;35:872&#x2013;883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler P, Duffield R, Vaile J. Effects of domestic air travel on technical and tactical performance and recovery in soccer. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2014;9:378&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedelec M, Leduc C, Dawson B, Guilhem G, Dupont G. Case study: sleep and injury in elite soccer. A mixed method approach. J Strength Cond Res 2017 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetsugi M, Mizuki Y, Yamamoto K, Uchida S, Watanabe Y. The effect of placebo administration on the first-night effect in healthy young volunteers. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry 2007;31:839&#x2013;847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton HR, Duthie GM, Pitchford NW, Delaney JA, Benton DT, Dascombe BJ. Effects of a 2-week high-intensity training camp on sleep activity of professional rugby league athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2017;12:928&#x2013;933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond LK, Dawson B, Stewart G, Cormack S, Hillman DR, Eastwood PR. The effect of interstate travel on the sleep patterns and performance of elite Australian rules footballers. J Sci Med Sport 2007;10:252&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz J, Simon RD. Sleep extension improves serving accuracy: a study with college varsity tennis players. Physiol Behav 2015;151:541&#x2013;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinbourne R, Miller J, Smart D, Dulson DK, Gill N. The effects of sleep extension on sleep, performance, immunity and physical stress in rugby players. Sports 2018;6:42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C. Extended sleep and the effects on mood and athletic performance in collegiate swimmers. Sleep 2008:31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Famodu OA, Montgomery-Downs H, Thomas JM, Gilleland DL, Bryner RW, Olfert MD. 0083 Impact of a single week of sleep extension on performance, mood, and nutrition among female college track athletes. Sleep 2017;40(suppl 1):A32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach GD, Halson SL, Sargent C. Sleep/wake behaviours of elite athletes from individual and team sports. Eur J Sport Sci 2015;15:94&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romyn G, Lastella M, Miller DJ, Versey NG, Roach GD, Sargent C. Daytime naps can be used to supplement night-time sleep in athletes. Chronobiol Int 2018;35:865&#x2013;868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit E, Mougin F, Bourdin H, Tio G, Haffen E. A 20-min nap in athletes changes subsequent sleep architecture but does not alter physical performances after normal sleep or 5-h phase-advance conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol 2014;114:305&#x2013;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell S, Beaven CM, Driller M. The influence of match-day napping in elite female netball athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 2018;13:1143&#x2013;1148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daaloul H, Souissi N, Davenne D. Effects of napping on alertness, cognitive, and physical outcomes of karate athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2019;51:338&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irish LA, Kline CE, Gunn HE, Buysse DJ, Hall MH. The role of sleep hygiene in promoting public health: a review of empirical evidence. Sleep Med Rev 2015;22:23&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knufinke M, Nieuwenhuys A, Geurts SAE, Coenen AML, Kompier MAJ. Self-reported sleep quantity, quality and sleep hygiene in elite athletes. J Sleep Res 2018;27:78&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caia J, Scott TJ, Halson SL, Kelly VG. The influence of sleep hygiene education on sleep in professional rugby league athletes. Sleep Health 2018;4:364&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell S, Driller MW. Sleep-hygiene education improves sleep indices in elite female athletes. Int J Exerc Sci 2017;10:522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ryswyk E, Weeks R, Bandick L, et al. A novel sleep optimisation programme to improve athletes' well-being and performance. Eur J Sport Sci 2017;17:144&#x2013;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Meyer T. The effect of an acute sleep hygiene strategy following a late-night soccer match on recovery of players. Chronobiol Int 2016;33:490&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada T, Wada K, Tsuji F, et al. Intervention study using a leaflet entitled &#x201c;three benefits of 'go to bed early! get up early! and intake nutritionally rich breakfast!' a message for athletes&#x201d; to improve the soccer performance of university soccer team. Sleep Biol Rhythms 2016;14:65&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemann D, Nissen C, Palagini L, Otte A, Perlis ML, Spiegelhalder K. The neurobiology, investigation, and treatment of chronic insomnia. Lancet Neurol 2015;14:547&#x2013;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemann D, Spiegelhalder K, Feige B, et al. The hyperarousal model of insomnia: a review of the concept and its evidence. Sleep Med Rev 2010;14:19&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller M. The role of sleep and sleep disorders in the development, diagnosis, and management of neurocognitive disorders. Front Neurol 2015;23:224.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>