<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30276172</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2288-176X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Brief ideas about evidence-based recovery in team sports.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>545</StartPage><EndPage>550</EndPage><MedlinePgn>545-550</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12965/jer.1836244.122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Performance in team sports is the expression of complex, dynamic, interactive, and multidimensional processes. It is now well-established that optimum recovery after practice or match is a key factor of team sport performance. During season and tournaments, improving recovery could offer an advantage for following performance. As a consequence of the professionalization of different roles in staffs, new particular roles have been developed within the team sports physician core in order to improve recovery protocols. Presently, scientific literature presents a big amount of methods used to enhance recovery based on the type of practice, time between session or competitions and equipment and/or staff accessible. These practices, usually used by teams are related to: ergonutritional, water therapy, massages techniques, stretching compression garments, sleep strategies and psychological implements. Besides, travel fatigue has been recognized by athletes and coaches as a challenging problem that could benefit from practical solutions. Nowadays, players have to play a lot of matches without enough time to recover among them, therefore the use of well-managed recovery can lead to a competitive advantage. Although the main purpose of applied sport sciences investigation is to categorize the protocols as well as providing approaches for individual recovery, the stages to recognize the most appropriate recovery plans in the field of team sports come from the analysis of the individual parameters.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez</LastName><ForeName>Julio</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2575-7168</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Sports, University of the Basque Country, Vitoria, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mielgo-Ayuso</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European University of Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sampaio</LastName><ForeName>Jaime</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center in Sports Sciences, Health Sciences and Human Development (CIDESD), CreativeLab Research Community, Vila Real, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delextrat</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Health Sciences Department, Oxford Brookes University, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ostojic</LastName><ForeName>Sergej M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Belgrade School of Medicine, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marques-Jim&#xe9;nez</LastName><ForeName>Diego</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Sports, University of the Basque Country, Vitoria, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arratibel</LastName><ForeName>I&#xf1;aki</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Activity and Sports, University of the Basque Country, Vitoria, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;nchez-Ure&#xf1;a</LastName><ForeName>Braulio</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Movement and Quality Life School, Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica, Heredia, Costa Rica.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dupont</LastName><ForeName>Gregory</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Lille, EA 7369 - URePSSS - Unit&#xe9; de Recherche Pluridisciplinaires Sport Sant&#xe9; Soci&#xe9;t&#xe9;, Research Department, Lille Olympique Sporting Club (LOSC), Lille, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schelling</LastName><ForeName>Xavi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Complex Systems in Sport Research Group SGR, National Institute of Physical Education of Catalonia (INEFC), University of Lleida, Lleida, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Terrados</LastName><ForeName>Nicol&#xe1;s</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Functional Biology, University of Oviedo, Oviedo, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2288-176X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Team sports</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30276172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.1836244.122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jer-14-4-545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Australian Institute of Sport [Internet] Bruce (Australia): Australian Institute of Sport; 2014.  [cited 2018 Mar 23]. Adapted from:  http://www.ausport.gov.au/ais.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J. Performance in sports: with specific emphasis on the effect of intensified training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(Suppl 4):88&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26589122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin HJ, Boniquit NT, Hastings ES. The traveling athlete. Adolesc Med State Art Rev. 2015;26:189&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26514039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borresen J, Lambert MI. Autonomic control of heart rate during and after exercise: measurements and implications for monitoring training status. Sports Med. 2008;38:633&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18620464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brockett CL, Morgan DL, Proske U. Predicting hamstring strain injury in elite athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:379&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15076778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. Monitoring training status with HR measures: do all roads lead to Rome? Front Physiol. 2014;5:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3936188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24578692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Terrados N, Mielgo-Ayuso J, Delextrat A, Jukic I, Vaquera A, Torres L, Schelling X, Stojanovic M, Ostojic SM. Evidence- based post-exercise recovery strategies in basketball. Phys Sportsmed. 2016;44:74&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26512912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carling C, McCall A, Le Gall F, Dupont G. The impact of short periods of match congestion on injury risk and patterns in an elite football club. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:764&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26682867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung KC, Lark ME, Cederna PS. Treating the Football athlete: coaches&#x2019; perspective from the University of Michigan. Hand Clin. 2017;33:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5125515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27886827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke MJ, Broderick C, Hopewell S, Juszczak E, Eisinga A. Compression stockings for preventing deep vein thrombosis in airline passengers. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;9:CD004002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6457834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27624857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ. In the age of technology, Occam&#x2019;s razor still applies. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9:741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25171538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djaoui L, Haddad M, Chamari K, Dellal A. Monitoring training load and fatigue in soccer players with physiological markers. Physiol Behav. 2017;181:86&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28886966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlert T, Simon P, Moser DA. Epigenetics in sports. Sports Med. 2013;43:93&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23329609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folgado H, Duarte R, Marques P, Sampaio J. The effects of congested fixtures period on tactical and physical performance in elite football. J Sports Sci. 2015;33:1238&#x2013;1247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25765524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox JL, Scanlan AT, Stanton R. A review of player monitoring approaches in basketball: current trends and future directions. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:2021&#x2013;2029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28445227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. The training-injury prevention paradox: should athletes be training smarter and harder? Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:273&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagan MJ, Lambert SM. A randomised crossover study of low-ankle- pressure graduated-compression tights in reducing flight-induced ankle oedema. Med J Aust. 2008;188:81&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18205579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Monitoring training load to understand fatigue in athletes. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 2):S139&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25200666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson JS. Decline of physiologic training effects during the competitive season in members of the U.S. Nordic ski team. Med Sci Sports. 1975;7:213&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1207434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herring SA, Kibler WB, Putukian M. Team physician consensus statement: 2013 update. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:1618&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23860390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JC, Mill&#xe1;n IS. Validation of musculoskeletal ultrasound to assess and quantify muscle glycogen content. A novel approach. Phys Sportsmed. 2014;42:45&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25295766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Hooper DR, Kupchak BR, Saenz C, Brown LE, Vingren JL, Luk HY, DuPont WH, Szivak TK, Flanagan SD, Caldwell LK, Eklund D, Lee EC, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Volek JS, Fleck SJ, Maresh CM. The effects of a roundtrip trans-American jet travel on physiological stress, neuromuscular performance, and recovery. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2016;121:438&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27283914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann TN, Lamberts RP, Lambert MI. High responders and low responders: factors associated with individual variation in response to standardized training. Sports Med. 2014;44:1113&#x2013;1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24807838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKinney R., Jr Being right isn&#x2019;t always enough: NFL culture and team physicians&#x2019; conflict of interest. Hastings Cent Rep. 2016;46(Suppl 2):S33&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27870083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JA, Pumpa KL, Pyne DB. Responses of lower-body power and match running demands following long-haul travel in international rugby sevens players. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:686&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27359207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittermayr M, Fries D, Gruber H, Peer S, Klingler A, Fischbach U, Gunga HC, Koralewski E, Faulhaber M, Simmer M, Schobersberger W. Leg edema formation and venous blood flow velocity during a simulated long-haul flight. Thromb Res. 2007;120:497&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17250877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno J, Ramos-Castro J, Rodas G, Tarrag&#xf3; JR, Capdevila L. Individual recovery profiles in basketball players. Span J Psychol. 2015;18:E24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25908013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM. Editorial: post-exercise recovery: fundamental and interventional physiology. Front Physiol. 2016;7:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4720789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26834646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Waterhouse J, Edwards B. A review on some of the problems associated with long-distance journeys. Clin Ter. 2008;159:117&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18463771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Hunter RL, Hunter TJ. Competition modeling of American football: observational data and implications for high school, collegiate, and professional player conditioning. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:58&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16503692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels CH. Jet lag and travel fatigue: a comprehensive management plan for sport medicine physicians and high-performance support teams. Clin J Sport Med. 2012;22:268&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22450594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saugy M, Lundby C, Robinson N. Monitoring of biological markers indicative of doping: the athlete biological passport. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:827&#x2013;832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24659506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan V, Singh J, Pandi-Perumal SR, Brown GM, Spence DW, Cardinali DP. Jet lag, circadian rhythm sleep disturbances, and depression: the role of melatonin and its analogs. Adv Ther. 2010;27:796&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20827520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenland K, Deddens JA. Effect of travel and rest on performance of professional basketball players. Sleep. 1997;20:366&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9381060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens JM, Halson S, Miller J, Slater GJ, Askew CD. Cold-water immersion for athletic recovery: one size does not fit all. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12:2&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27294485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JL, Amann M, Duchateau J, Meeusen R, Rice CL. Neural contributions to muscle fatigue: from the brain to the muscle and back again. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:2294&#x2013;2306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5033663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27003703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrados N, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Jukic I, Ostojic SM. Physiological and medical strategies in post-competition recovery&#x2013;practical implications based on scientific evidence. Ser J Sports Sci. 2009;3:29&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton HR, Miller J, Taylor L, Sargent C, Lastella M, Fowler PM. Impact of short- compared to long-haul international travel on the sleep and wellbeing of national wheelchair basketball athletes. J Sports Sci. 2018;36:1476&#x2013;1484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29099652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, Schelling X. Critical process for the implementation of technology in sport organizations. Strength Cond J. 2017;39:54&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaile J, Halson S, Graham S. Recovery review: science vs. practice. J Aust Strength Cond. 2010;18(Suppl 2):5&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiewelhove T, Raeder C, Meyer T, Kellmann M, Pfeiffer M, Ferrauti A. Markers for routine assessment of fatigue and recovery in male and female team sport athletes during high-intensity interval training. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0139801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4596858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26444557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams C, Rollo I. Carbohydrate nutrition and team sport performance. Sports Med. 2015;45(Suppl 1):S13&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4672015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>