<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40786891</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1817-1737</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jul-Sep</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of thoracic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Thorac Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of table tennis combined with resistance training on the rehabilitation of patients with coronary heart disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>160</StartPage><EndPage>168</EndPage><MedlinePgn>160-168</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/atm.atm_6_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of the study was to explore the influence of table tennis combined with resistance training on coronary heart disease (CHD) rehabilitation and to evaluate its potential in improving cardiopulmonary function, arterial stiffness, blood lipids, and psychological indicators in participants with CHD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Seventy patients with confirmed CHD were chosen and randomly separated into two groups, 35 cases each. The test group performed table tennis combined with resistance training, and the reference group (RG) received standard resistance training as the control group. By comparing the differences in cardiopulmonary function, arterial stiffness, sleep and diet, psychological indicators, and blood lipids between the two groups of patients, the role of table tennis combined with resistance training in CHD rehabilitation was evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Relative to the control group, participants in the table tennis exercise combined with the resistance training group had significant improvement in cardiopulmonary function (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In addition, table tennis combined with resistance training can reduce patients' arterial stiffness, improve sleep and eating habits, and reduce blood lipid levels. Relative to the RG, the data possess the statistical significance (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Finally, the psychological quality of the two groups of patients was compared. The anxiety, depression, and confrontation ability of the patients in the test group were 7.15 &#xb1; 0.39, 7.03 &#xb1; 0.29, and 6.86 &#xb1; 0.46, respectively, which were superior to the RG. The comparison among the participants of data possesses the statistical significance (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.005).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The research results show that table tennis combined with resistance training possesses an essential influence on CHD rehabilitation. It can significantly enhance patients' cardiopulmonary function, reduce arterial stiffness, improve sleeping and eating habits, reduce blood lipid levels, and improve psychological indicators. As a low-intensity aerobic exercise, table tennis possesses an essential influence on facilitating the recovery of patients with CHD and is worthy of further promotion and application in clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2024 Annals of Thoracic Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Guochang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Sports and Arts, Huanghe Science and Technology College, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education Institute, Hubei University of Science and Technology, Xianning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Thorac Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101280721</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1998-3557</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arterial stiffness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary heart disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep and diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">table tennis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40786891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12333962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/atm.atm_6_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ATM-20-160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Parry Williams G, Sharma S. The effects of endurance exercise on the heart: Panacea or poison? Nat Rev Cardiol. 2020;17:402&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32152528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeno FP, Ramis TR, Munhoz SV, Farinha JB, Moritz CE, Leal Menezes R, et al. Effect of aerobic and resistance exercise training on inflammation, endothelial function and ambulatory blood pressure in middle-aged hypertensive patients. J Hypertens. 2020;38:2501&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32694343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zavalishina SY, Pravdov DM, Bakulina ED, et al. Strengthening the general functional capabilities of the body in the conditions of a feasible increase in muscle activity after intervention on the heart. Biomed Pharmacol J. 2020;13:597&#x2013;602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsios GS, Moe RH, van der Esch M, van Zanten JJ, Fenton SA, Koutedakis Y, et al. The effects of exercise on cardiovascular disease risk factors and cardiovascular physiology in rheumatoid arthritis. Rheumatol Int. 2020;40:347&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31802210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen D, Abreu A, Ambrosetti M, Cornelissen V, Gevaert A, Kemps H, et al. Exercise intensity assessment and prescription in cardiovascular rehabilitation and beyond: Why and how: A position statement from the secondary prevention and rehabilitation section of the European Association of Preventive Cardiology. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2022;29:230&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34077542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt B, Fonarow GC, Goldberg LR, Guglin M, Josephson RA, Forman DE, et al. Cardiac rehabilitation for patients with heart failure: JACC expert panel. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021;77:1454&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33736829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldridge N, Taylor RS. Cost-effectiveness of exercise therapy in patients with coronary heart disease, chronic heart failure and associated risk factors: A systematic review of economic evaluations of randomized clinical trials. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2020;27:1045&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31657233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witvrouwen I, Van Craenenbroeck EM, Abreu A, Moholdt T, Kr&#xe4;nkel N. Exercise training in women with cardiovascular disease: Differential response and barriers &#x2013; Review and perspective. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2021;28:779&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30889981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bischoff Ferrari HA, Vellas B, Rizzoli R, Kressig RW, da Silva JA, Blauth M, et al. Effect of Vitamin D supplementation, omega-3 fatty acid supplementation, or a strength-training exercise program on clinical outcomes in older adults: The DO-HEALTH randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2020;324:1855&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7656284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33170239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanssen H, Boardman H, Deiseroth A, Moholdt T, Simonenko M, Kr&#xe4;nkel N, et al. Personalized exercise prescription in the prevention and treatment of arterial hypertension: A consensus document from the European Association of Preventive Cardiology (EAPC) and the ESC council on hypertension. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2022;29:205&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33758927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golledge J. Update on the pathophysiology and medical treatment of peripheral artery disease. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2022;19:456&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34997200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhya B, Kitzman DW. Heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: New approaches to diagnosis and management. Clin Cardiol. 2020;43:145&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7021648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31880340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su JJ, Yu DS, Paguio JT. Effect of eHealth cardiac rehabilitation on health outcomes of coronary heart disease patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Adv Nurs. 2020;76:754&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31769527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton RE, Tew GA, Aning JJ, Gilbert SE, Lewis L, Saxton JM. Effects of short-term, medium-term and long-term resistance exercise training on cardiometabolic health outcomes in adults: Systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:341&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Haehling S, Arzt M, Doehner W, Edelmann F, Evertz R, Ebner N, et al. Improving exercise capacity and quality of life using non-invasive heart failure treatments: Evidence from clinical trials. Eur J Heart Fail. 2021;23:92&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32392403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ijaz N, Buta B, Xue QL, Mohess DT, Bushan A, Tran H, et al. Interventions for frailty among older adults with cardiovascular disease: JACC state-of-the-art review. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79:482&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8852369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handelsman Y, Jellinger PS, Guerin CK, Bloomgarden ZT, Brinton EA, Budoff MJ, et al. Consensus statement by the American Association of Clinical endocrinologists and American College of Endocrinology on the management of dyslipidemia and prevention of cardiovascular disease algorithm &#x2013; 2020 executive summary. Endocr Pract. 2020;26:1196&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33471721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott MM, Ferrucci L, Gonzalez Freire M, Kosmac K, Leeuwenburgh C, Peterson CA, et al. Skeletal muscle pathology in peripheral artery disease: A brief review. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2020;40:2577&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9571495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen N, Cadarso Su&#xe1;rez C, Lado Baleato O, D&#xed;az Louzao C, Gil CP, Reeh J, et al. Improvement in VO(2peak) predicts readmissions for cardiovascular disease and mortality in patients undergoing cardiac rehabilitation. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2020;27:811&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31744334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokayed H, Quan TZ, Alkhaled L, et al. Real-time human detection and counting system using deep learning computer vision techniques. Artif Intell Appl. 2023;1:221&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Novaes J, da Silva Telles LG, Monteiro ER, da Silva Araujo G, Vingren JL, Silva Panza P, et al. Ischemic preconditioning improves resistance training session performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:2993&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32224716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams A. Human-centric functional computing as an approach to human-like computation. Artif Intell Appl. 2023;1:118&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>