<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41591657</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sleep and Circadian Interventions to Improve Athletes' Mental Health, Mood and Well-Being: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02387-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sleep and circadian interventions (e.g. interventions aimed at promoting circadian alignment and supporting stable well-entrained sleep-wake patterns) are predominantly implemented in athletes to improve performance, recovery and adaptation to travel. Emerging evidence from the broader population demonstrates that improving sleep and circadian health can also improve mental health, mood and well-being.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the current evidence on the effectiveness of sleep and circadian interventions for improving mental health, mood and well-being in athlete populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Seven databases (CENTRAL, CINAHL, Embase, MEDLINE, PsycINFO, Scopus, SPORTDiscus) were searched from inception to 23 September, 2024 in accordance with the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) guidelines. Eligible studies involved athletes (participating in sport at any level) and evaluated sleep or circadian interventions aimed at improving sleep and/or circadian health, with mental health, mood or well-being outcomes. Sleep interventions directly manipulated sleep through behavioural, environmental or educational approaches. Studies without a comparator/baseline, using indirect methods (e.g. brainwave entrainment) to improve sleep or solely sleep restriction, were excluded. Two reviewers independently screened studies, extracted data, and assessed methodological quality and risk of bias using the Cochrane risk-of-bias tool and Joanna Briggs Institute checklist. Data were synthesised using a multi-level random-effects meta-analysis and pre-specified meta-regression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 21 sleep and circadian interventions have been implemented in sporting environments to improve the mental health of athletes. The interventions that have been investigated are constrained by limited sample sizes, a lack of female representation, a low-quality study design and inconsistent measurement of mental health, making it difficult to draw definitive conclusions of the efficacy of these strategies. The results of the meta-analysis showed that sleep and circadian interventions had a more substantial impact on positive affect compared to negative (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.68, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The interventions were also found to be more effective in improving anxiety, tension and vigour compared to other subjective mood states. The limited interventions with a circadian component (e.g. light exposure) consistently found improvements in outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Sleep and circadian interventions appear to have the strongest effects on positive affect, anxiety, tension and vigour in athletes. Future research should address the limitations of existing studies by focusing on diverse and representative samples, incorporating a longer term follow-up after interventions, using consistent mental health measurements and developing interventions specifically aimed at improving athletes' circadian rhythms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The protocol was registered in the PROSPERO database (#CRD42023467548).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walsh</LastName><ForeName>Elie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, School of Psychological Sciences, Monash University, VIC, 270 Ferntree Gully Road, Notting Hill, 3168, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leota</LastName><ForeName>Josh</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Sleep and Circadian Disorders, Departments of Medicine and Neurology, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huynh</LastName><ForeName>Minh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Trobe University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liddle</LastName><ForeName>Sarah K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drummond</LastName><ForeName>Sean P A</ForeName><Initials>SPA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, School of Psychological Sciences, Monash University, VIC, 270 Ferntree Gully Road, Notting Hill, 3168, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Facer-Childs</LastName><ForeName>Elise R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4549-9266</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia. Elise.Facer-Childs@monash.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, School of Psychological Sciences, Monash University, VIC, 270 Ferntree Gully Road, Notting Hill, 3168, Australia. Elise.Facer-Childs@monash.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IE240100162</GrantID><Agency>Australian Research Council</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>578917724</GrantID><Agency>Wu Tsai Human Performance Alliance</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: Elie Walsh was supported by an Australian Government RTP Scholarship and a Monash University (School of Psychological Sciences) Strategic Project Grant. Elise R.&#xa0;Facer-Childs is supported by an Australian Research Council Grant (IE240100162). Elise R.&#xa0;Facer-Childs and Josh Leota have received funding from the Wu Tsai Human Performance Alliance and the Joe and Clara Tsai Foundation (these funders did not have a direct role in this study). The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. Ethics approval: Not applicable. Consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Availability of data and material: All data relevant to the study are included in the article or uploaded as supplementary information. Authors&#x2019; contributions: EW: conceptualisation, methodology, investigation, data curation, writing (original draft). JL: methodology, investigation, data curation, writing (original draft). MH: writing (review and editing, data curation, SKL: conceptualisation, writing (review and editing), supervision. SPAD: conceptualisation, writing (review and editing), supervision. ERF-C: conceptualisation, methodology, writing (review and editing), supervision. All authors read and approved the final version of the article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41591657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02387-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02387-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Reardon CL, Hainline B, Aron CM, Baron D, Baum AL, Bindra A, et al. Mental health in elite athletes: International Olympic Committee consensus statement (2019). Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(11):667&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31097450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-100715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;kesdotter C, Kentt&#xe4; G, Eloranta S, Franck J. The prevalence of mental health problems in elite athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2020;23(4):329&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31806359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.10.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouttebarge V, Castaldelli-Maia JM, Gorczynski P, Hainline B, Hitchcock ME, Kerkhoffs GM, et al. Occurrence of mental health symptoms and disorders in current and former elite athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(11):700&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31097451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-100671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice SM, Purcell R, De Silva S, Mawren D, McGorry PD, Parker AG. The mental health of elite athletes: a narrative systematic review. Sports Med. 2016;46:1333&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26896951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4996886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0492-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Promoting mental health: concepts, emerging evidence, practice: summary report. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundqvist C, Andersson G. Let&#x2019;s talk about mental health and mental disorders in elite sports: a narrative review of theoretical perspectives. Front Psychol. 2021;12:700829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34267715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8275956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.700829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keyes CL. The mental health continuum: from languishing to flourishing in life. J Health Soc Behav. 2002;43(2):207&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12096700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/3090197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundqvist C, Jederstr&#xf6;m M, Korhonen L, Timpka T. Nuances in key constructs need attention in research on mental health and psychiatric disorders in sports medicine. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2022;8(3):e001414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9438056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2022-001414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galderisi S, Heinz A, Kastrup M, Beezhold J, Sartorius N. Toward a new definition of mental health. World Psychiatry. 2015;14(2):231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26043341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4471980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galderisi S. The need for a consensual definition of mental health. World Psychiatry. 2024;23(1):52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38214632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10785984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.21150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell JA. Core affect and the psychological construction of emotion. Psychol Rev. 2003;110(1):145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12529060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-295X.110.1.145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breslow L. A quantitative approach to the World Health Organization definition of health: physical, mental and social well-being. Int J Epidemiol. 1972;1(4):347&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4669083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/1.4.347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edition F. Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders. Am Psychiatr Assoc. 2013;21(21):591&#x2013;643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook JD, Charest J. Sleep and performance in professional athletes. Curr Sleep Med Rep. 2023;9(1):56&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36683842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9843114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40675-022-00243-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heller HC, Herzog E, Brager A, Poe G, Allada R, Scheer FA, et al. The negative effects of travel on student athletes through sleep and circadian Ddsruption. J Biol Rhythms. 2024;39(1):5&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37978840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/07487304231207330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim JE, Leota J, Mascaro L, Hoffman D, Facer-Childs ER. Sleep patterns before and after competition: a real-world examination of elite athletes. J Sports Sci. 2023;41(22):2014&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38314742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2308960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Halson SL, Sargent C, Roach GD, N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Gupta L, et al. Sleep and the athlete: narrative review and 2021 expert consensus recommendations. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(7):356&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff L. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important competitions. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;18(1):13&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24629327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2014.02.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrozanova M, Firing K, Moen F. &#x201c;When i sleep poorly, it impacts everything&#x201d;: an exploratory qualitative investigation of stress and sleep in junior endurance athletes. Front Psychol. 2021;12:618379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33658963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7917256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.618379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron KG, Reid KJ. Circadian misalignment and health. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2014;26(2):139&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24892891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4677771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09540261.2014.911149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M. Research on pre-competition mood state of sports athletes and their individual differences. Rev Psicol Deporte J Sport Psychol. 2021;30(2):87&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons N, Mandal S, Paton B, Ahmed I. Are circadian rhythms a new frontier in athletic performance? Curr Sports Med Rep. 2022;21(1):5&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35018891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000000929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker WH, Walton JC, DeVries AC, Nelson RJ. Circadian rhythm disruption and mental health. Transl Psychiatry. 2020;10(1):28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32066704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7026420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-020-0694-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codo&#xf1;er-Franch P, Gombert M, Mart&#xed;nez-Raga J, Cenit MC. Circadian disruption and mental health: the chronotherapeutic potential of microbiome-based and dietary strategies. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(8):7579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37108739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10146651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms24087579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facer-Childs ER, Hoffman D, Tran JN, Drummond SP, Rajaratnam SM. Sleep and mental health in athletes during COVID-19 lockdown. Sleep. 2021;44(5):zsaa261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33535229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/zsaa261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeGates TA, Fernandez DC, Hattar S. Light as a central modulator of circadian rhythms, sleep and affect. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2014;15(7):443&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24917305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4254760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn3743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leota J, Hoffman D, Czeisler M&#xc9;, Mascaro L, Drummond SP, Anderson C, et al. Eastward jet lag is associated with impaired performance and game outcome in the national basketball association. Front Physiol. 2022;13:892681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35784873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9245584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.892681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leatherwood WE, Dragoo JL. Effect of airline travel on performance: a review of the literature. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(9):561&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23143931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Rensburg DCCJ, Van Rensburg AJ, Fowler P, Fullagar H, Stevens D, Halson S, et al. How to manage travel fatigue and jet lag in athletes? A systematic review of interventions. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:960&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnar D, Bartel K, Kakoschke N, Lang C. Sleep interventions designed to improve athletic performance and recovery: a systematic review of current approaches. Sports Med. 2018;48:683&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29352373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0832-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha LA, Costa JA, Marques EA, Brito J, Lastella M, Figueiredo P. The impact of sleep interventions on athletic performance: a systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2023;9(1):58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10354314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00599-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AC, Silva A, Edwards BJ, Tod D, Amaral AS, de Alc&#xe2;ntara BD, et al. Sleep extension in athletes: what we know so far: a systematic review. Sleep Med. 2021;77:128&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2020.11.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirschen GW, Jones JJ, Hale L. The impact of sleep duration on performance among competitive athletes: a systematic literature review. Clin J Sport Med. 2020;30(5):503&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29944513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale KC, Owens R, Hopkins SR, Malhotra A. Sleep hygiene for optimizing recovery in athletes: review and recommendations. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40(08):535&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6988893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0905-3103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwyther K, Rice S, Purcell R, Pilkington V, Santesteban-Echarri O, Bailey A, et al. Sleep interventions for performance, mood and sleep outcomes in athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2022;58:102094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychsport.2021.102094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl. 1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4008810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0147-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes-Robertson S, Dudley E, Vadgama P, Cook C, Drawer S, Kilduff L. Circadian disruption and remedial interventions: effects and interventions for jet lag for athletic peak performance. Sports Med. 2012;42:185&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22299812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11596850-000000000-00000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshikawa M, Uchida S, Dohi M. Intervention for reducing sleep disturbances after a 12-time zone transition. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(7):1803&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGeever A, Mallon N, Bruinvels G, Pedlar CR, Doherty R, Van Someren KA. The association of sleep with subjective wellbeing and performance in female athletes: a systematic review. J Sport Exerc Sci. 2024;8(2):1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gee B, Orchard F, Clarke E, Joy A, Clarke T, Reynolds S. The effect of non-pharmacological sleep interventions on depression symptoms: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Sleep Med Rev. 2019;43:118&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30579141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2018.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler L, Patel C, Lovecka L, Gardani M, Walasek L, Ellis J, et al. Improving university students&#x2019; mental health using multi-component and single-component sleep interventions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med. 2022;100:354&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36198252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2022.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott AJ, Webb TL, Martyn-St James M, Rowse G, Weich S. Improving sleep quality leads to better mental health: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Sleep Med Rev. 2021;60:101556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34607184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8651630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2021.101556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma LL, Wang YY, Yang ZH, Huang D, Weng H, Zeng XT. Methodological quality (risk of bias) assessment tools for primary and secondary medical studies: what are they and which is better? Mil Med Res. 2020;7:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:I4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn Z, Barker TH, Moola S, Tufanaru C, Stern C, McArthur A, et al. Methodological quality of case series studies: an introduction to the JBI critical appraisal tool. JBI Evid Synth. 2020;18(10):2127&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Softw. 2010;36(3):1&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v036.i03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pustejovsky JE, Tipton E. Meta-analysis with robust variance estimation: expanding the range of working models. Prev Sci. 2022;23(3):425&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33961175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11121-021-01246-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuman V, Sander D, Scherer KR. Levels of valence. Front Psychol. 2013;4:261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23717292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3651968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombetti G. Appraising valence. J Conscious Stud. 2005;12(8&#x2013;9):103&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diener E, Emmons RA. The independence of positive and negative affect. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1984;47(5):1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6520704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.47.5.1105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah CD, Mah KE, Kezirian EJ, Dement WC. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep. 2011;34(7):943&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21731144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3119836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5665/SLEEP.1132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritland BM, Simonelli G, Gentili RJ, Smith JC, He X, Mantua J, et al. Effects of sleep extension on cognitive/motor performance and motivation in military tactical athletes. Sleep Med. 2019;58:48&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31096123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2019.03.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts SS, Teo WP, Aisbett B, Warmington SA. Extended sleep maintains endurance performance better than normal or restricted sleep. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(12):2516&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31246714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentouati E, Romdhani M, Abid R, Khemila S, Garbarino S, Souissi N. The combined effects of napping and self-selected motivation music during warming up on cognitive and physical performance of karate athletes. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1214504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37520834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10372344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1214504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souabni M, Hammouda O, Souabni M, Romdhani M, Souissi W, Ammar A, et al. Nap improved game-related technical performance and physiological response during small-sided basketball game in professional players. Biol Sport. 2023;40(2):389&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.116004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Famodu O, Montgomery-Downs H, Thomas J, Gilleland D, Bryner R, Olfert M. 0083 impact of a single week of sleep extension on performance, mood, and nutrition among female college track athletes. J Sleep Sleep Disord Res. 2017;40(Suppl._1):A32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C, Anguera J, Gazzaley A, Luke A. 0749 sleep loading improves visual search response time and reduces fatigue in professional baseball players. Sleep. 2017;40:A278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleepj/zsx050.748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris O, Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Abdessalem R, Hsouna H, Glenn JM, et al. A 90 min daytime nap opportunity is better than 40 min for cognitive and physical performance. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(13):4650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32605240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7369743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17134650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boland N, Donohoe B, Duffaut C, Goldman J. Sleep extension and consistency improve athletic performance in NCAA Division I collegiate athletes. Clinical Journal of Sport Medicine. 2023;33(3):285. In: 2023 AMSSM Research Podium Presentations. https://doi.org/10.1097/JSM.0000000000001128</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lever JR, Murphy AP, Duffield R, Fullagar HH. A combined sleep hygiene and mindfulness intervention to improve sleep and well-being during high-performance youth tennis tournaments. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;16(2):250&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32781440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-1008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ryswyk E, Weeks R, Bandick L, O&#x2019;Keefe M, Vakulin A, Catcheside P, et al. A novel sleep optimisation programme to improve athletes&#x2019; well-being and performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(2):144&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27574901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2016.1221470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnar D, Lee S, Roane BM, Blum DJ, Kahn M, Jang E, et al. Evaluation of a brief sleep intervention designed to improve the sleep, mood, and cognitive performance of esports athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(7):4146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35409833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8998799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19074146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Meyer T. The effect of an acute sleep hygiene strategy following a late-night soccer match on recovery of players. Chronobiol Int. 2016;33(5):490&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27031035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/07420528.2016.1149190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffield R, Murphy A, Kellett A, Reid M. Recovery from repeated on-court tennis sessions: combining cold-water immersion, compression, and sleep interventions. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(2):273&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23799825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2012-0359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender A, Werthner P, Samuels C. 0792 sleep optimization improves mood differently between Canadian team curlers and rowers. Sleep. 2017;40:A293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleepj/zsx050.791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charest J, Bender A, Bastien C, Samuels C. Sleep interventions improve subjective sleep, mood, and race performance in Canadian national team speed skaters. Sleep Med. 2017;40:e51&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2017.11.144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler PM, Knez W, Thornton HR, Sargent C, Mendham AE, Crowcroft S, et al. Sleep hygiene and light exposure can improve performance following long-haul air travel. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;16(4):517&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33152686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Kamarck T, Mermelstein R. Perceived stress scale. Meas Stress Guide Health Soc Sci. 1994;10(2):1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada T, Wada K, Tsuji F, Krejci M, Kawada T, Noji T, et al. Intervention study using a leaflet entitled &#x2018;three benefits of &#x201c;go to bed early! get up early! and intake nutritionally rich breakfast!&#x201d; a message for athletes&#x2019; to improve the soccer performance of university soccer team. Sleep Biol Rhythms. 2016;14:65&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41105-015-0035-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandi-Perumal SR, Smits M, Spence W, Srinivasan V, Cardinali DP, Lowe AD, et al. Dim light melatonin onset (DLMO): a tool for the analysis of circadian phase in human sleep and chronobiological disorders. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2007;31(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16884842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2006.06.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris A, Gundersen H, M&#xf8;rk-Andreassen P, Thun E, Bjorvatn B, Pallesen S. Restricted use of electronic media, sleep, performance, and mood in high school athletes: a randomized trial. Sleep Health. 2015;1(4):314&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleh.2015.09.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomaso CC, Johnson AB, Nelson TD. The effect of sleep deprivation and restriction on mood, emotion, and emotion regulation: three meta-analyses in one. Sleep. 2021;44(6):zsaa289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33367799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/zsaa289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin CL, Curtis RM, Huggins RA, Sekiguchi Y, Jain RK, McFadden BA, et al. Sleep dysfunction and mood in collegiate soccer athletes. Sports Health. 2020;12(3):234&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7222673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120916735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade A, Bevilacqua G, Casagrande P, Brandt R, Coimbra D. Sleep quality associated with mood in elite athletes. Phys Sportsmed. 2019;47(3):312&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30477376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00913847.2018.1553467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;hmer MN, Hamers PC, Bindels PJ, Oppewal A, van Someren EJ, Festen DA. Are we still in the dark? A systematic review on personal daily light exposure, sleep-wake rhythm, and mood in healthy adults from the general population. Sleep Health. 2021;7(5):610&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34420891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleh.2021.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey AG. Treating sleep and circadian problems to promote mental health: perspectives on comorbidity, implementation science and behavior change. Sleep. 2022;45(4):zsac026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35079830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8996031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/zsac026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam RW, Teng MY, Jung YE, Evans VC, Gottlieb JF, Chakrabarty T, et al. Light therapy for patients with bipolar depression: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Can J Psychiatry. 2020;65(5):290&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31826657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0706743719892471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedrosian TA, Nelson R. Timing of light exposure affects mood and brain circuits. Transl Psychiatry. 2017;7(1):e1017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28140399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5299389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/tp.2016.262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao L, Jiang R, Zhang K, Qian Z, Chen P, Lv Y, et al. Light therapy in non-seasonal depression: an update meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2020;291:113247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekelund R, Holmstr&#xf6;m S, Gustafsson H, Ivarsson A, Lundqvist C, Stenling A. Interventions for improving mental health in athletes: a scoping review. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2025;18(1). https://doi.org/10.1080/1750984X.2023.2258383</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry PC, Parsons-Smith RL. Mood profiling for sustainable mental health among athletes. Sustainability. 2021;13(11):6116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13116116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsanas A, Saunders K, Bilderbeck A, Palmius N, Osipov M, Clifford G, et al. Daily longitudinal self-monitoring of mood variability in bipolar disorder and borderline personality disorder. J Affect Disord. 2016;205:225&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27449555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5296237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2016.06.065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maciejewski DF, van Lier PA, Branje SJ, Meeus WH, Koot HM. A 5&#x2010;year longitudinal study on mood variability across adolescence using daily diaries. Child Dev. 2015;86(6):1908&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26464350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cdev.12420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saner NJ, Lee MJ, Pitchford NW, Broatch JR, Roach GD, Bishop DJ, et al. The effect of sleep restriction, with or without high-intensity interval exercise, on behavioural alertness and mood state in young healthy males. J Sleep Res. 2024;33(2):e13987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37434366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.13987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pires GN, Bezerra AG, Tufik S, Andersen ML. Effects of acute sleep deprivation on state anxiety levels: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med. 2016;24:109&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27810176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2016.07.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenze SJ, Miller IW. Use of ecological momentary assessment in mood disorders research. Clin Psychol Rev. 2010;30(6):794&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20619520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2010.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh RJ, van Buuren M, Hollarek M, Sijtsma H, Lee NC, Krabbendam L. Social contexts, momentary mood and affective variability in early adolescence: an exploratory ecological momentary assessment study. J Early Adolesc. 2024;44(1):59&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02724316231160147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey AG. Sleep and circadian functioning: critical mechanisms in the mood disorders? Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2011;7:297&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21166537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-032210-104550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascaro L, Leota J, Hoffman D, Rajaratnam SM, Drummond SP, Facer-Childs ER. Disruptions to sleep and circadian rhythms are associated with poorer athlete mental health in female, but not male, elite Australian Rules footballers. J Sleep Res. 2024;33(6):e14186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38471498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11596983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.14186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvani MI, Perret C. The influence of blue light on sleep, performance and wellbeing in young adults: a systematic review. Front Physiol. 2022;13:943108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36051910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9424753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.943108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauducco S, Richardson C, Gradisar M. Chronotype, circadian rhythms and mood. Curr Opin Psychol. 2020;34:77&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31786494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.copsyc.2019.09.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills C, Ghani S, Tubbs A, Fernandez FX, Athey A, Turner R, et al. Chronotype and social support among student athletes: impact on depressive symptoms. Chronobiol Int. 2021;38(9):1319&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34039131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07420528.2021.1927072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NA, Repa LM, Garland SN. Mindful larks and lonely owls: the relationship between chronotype, mental health, sleep quality, and social support in young adults. J Sleep Res. 2022;31(1):e13442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34272788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.13442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller MW, Lastella M, Sharp AP. Individualized sleep education improves subjective and objective sleep indices in elite cricket athletes: a pilot study. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(17):2021&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2019.1616900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamers SM, Westerhof GJ, Bohlmeijer ET, ten Klooster PM, Keyes CL. Evaluating the psychometric properties of the mental health continuum&#x2010;short form (MHC&#x2010;SF). J Clin Psychol. 2011;67(1):99&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20973032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.20741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>