<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32282460</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-8918</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current sports medicine reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Sports Med Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Electronic Nicotine Delivery Systems on Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>146</StartPage><EndPage>150</EndPage><MedlinePgn>146-150</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/JSR.0000000000000705</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid rise in popularity of Electronic Nicotine Delivery Systems (ENDS), or vaping, has not eluded the athletic population. Increasing use of youth sports participants, as well as collegiate and professionals, means sports medicine providers and coaches alike should be familiar with the effects of these devices. Current evidence demonstrates an impact on both the cardiovascular and pulmonary systems. These effects appear less significant than smoking tobacco cigarettes, but the extent and longevity of the consequences of ENDS use is unclear. Mechanisms for recovery, such as sleep and injury healing, also are affected. Lastly, the emergence of life-threatening pulmonary disease associated with ENDS use may have devastating effects on an athlete. This article will highlight the recent literature on the impact of ENDS on athletes and athletic performance, as well as the potentially life-threatening consequences of use.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Scott E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Madigan Army Medical Center, Tacoma, WA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henderson</LastName><ForeName>Colin A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Couperus</LastName><ForeName>Kyle S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Sports Med Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101134380</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1537-890X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electronic Nicotine Delivery Systems</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013178" MajorTopicYN="N">Sports Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072137" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vaping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32282460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000000705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00149619-202004000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ndel T. Nicotine: sporting friend or foe? A review of athlete use, performance consequences and other considerations. Sports Med. 2017; 47:2497&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajek P, Etter JF, Benowitz N, et al. Electronic cigarettes: review of use, content, safety, effects on smokers and potential for harm and benefit. Addiction. 2014; 109:1801&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobb NK, Byron MJ, Abrams DB, Shields PG. Novel nicotine delivery systems and public health: the rise of the &#x201c;E-Cigarette.&#x201d; Am. J. Public Health. 2010; 100:2340&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King BA, Gammon DG, Marynak KL, Rogers T. Electronic cigarette sales in the United States, 2013-2017. JAMA. 2018; 320:1379&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palazzolo D, Nelson JM, Hudson Z. The use of HPLC-PDA in determining nicotine and nicotine-related alkaloids from e-liquids: a comparison of five e-liquid brands purchased locally. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2019; 16. pii: E3015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald A, Middlekauff HR. Electronic cigarettes and cardiovascular health: what do we know so far? Vasc. Health Risk Manag. 2019; 15:159&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Food and Drug Administration. Vaporizers, e-cigarettes, and other electronic nicotine delivery systems (ENDS). FDA [Internet]. 2019 Sep 12 [cited 2019 Oct 7]. Available from: http://www.fda.gov/tobacco-products/products-ingredients-components/vaporizers-e-cigarettes-and-other-electronic-nicotine-delivery-systems-ends.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang TW, Asman K, Gentzke AS, et al. Tobacco product use among adults&#x2014;United States, 2017. MMWR Morb. Mortal. Wkly Rep. 2018; 67:1225&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang TW, Gentzke A, Sharapova S, et al. Tobacco product use among middle and high school students&#x2014;United States, 2011-2017. MMWR Morb. Mortal. Wkly Rep. 2018; 67:629&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentzke AS, Creamer M, Cullen KA, et al. Vital signs: tobacco product use among middle and high school students&#x2014;United States, 2011-2018. MMWR Morb. Mortal. Wkly Rep. 2019; 68:157&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen KA, Ambrose BK, Gentzke AS, et al. Notes from the field: Use of electronic cigarettes and any tobacco product among middle and high school students&#x2014;United States, 2011-2018. MMWR Morb. Mortal. Wkly Rep. 2018; 67:1276&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao W, Xu G, Lu J, et al. Changes in electronic cigarette use among adults in the United States, 2014-2016. JAMA. 2018; 319:2039&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers JW, Leas EC, Allem JP, et al. Why do people use electronic nicotine delivery systems (electronic cigarettes)? A content analysis of Twitter, 2012&#x2013;2015. PLoS One. 2017; 12:e0170702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;aranovi&#x107; S&#x110;, Vi&#x107;i&#x107; J, Pe&#x161;i&#x107; I, et al. The influence of tobacco use on pulmonary function in elite athletes. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2019; 16. pii: E3515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WADA publishes 2019 List of Prohibited Substances and Methods (28 September 2018) [Internet]. World Anti-Doping Agency. 2018 [cited 2019 Oct 14]. Available from: https://www.wada-ama.org/en/media/news/2018-09/wada-publishes-2019-list-of-prohibited-substances-and-methods.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDuff D, Stull T, Castaldelli-Maia JM, et al. Recreational and ergogenic substance use and substance use disorders in elite athletes: a narrative review. Br. J. Sports Med. 2019; 53:754&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veliz P, McCabe SE, McCabe VV, Boyd CJ. Adolescent sports participation, e-cigarette use, and cigarette smoking. Am. J. Prev. Med. 2017; 53:e175&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middlekauff HR, Park J, Moheimani RS. Adverse effects of cigarette and noncigarette smoke exposure on the autonomic nervous system: mechanisms and implications for cardiovascular risk. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 2014; 64:1740&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ndel T, Machal M, Cochrane DJ, Barnes MJ. A randomised, placebo-controlled, crossover study investigating the effects of nicotine gum on strength, power and anaerobic performance in nicotine-na&#xef;ve, active males. Sports Med. Open. 2017; 3:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandonai T, Tam E, Bruseghini P, et al. The effects of oral smokeless tobacco administration on endurance performance. J. Sport Health Sci. 2018; 7:465&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadruz W Jr., Claggett B, Gon&#xe7;alves A, et al. Smoking and cardiac structure and function in the elderly: the ARIC study (atherosclerosis risk in communities). Circ. Cardiovasc. Imaging. 2016; 9:e004950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farsalinos KE, Tsiapras D, Kyrzopoulos S, et al. Acute effects of using an electronic nicotine-delivery device (electronic cigarette) on myocardial function: comparison with the effects of regular cigarettes. BMC Cardiovasc. Disord. 2014; 14:78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moheimani RS, Bhetraratana M, Yin F, et al. Increased cardiac sympathetic activity and oxidative stress in habitual electronic cigarette users: implications for cardiovascular risk. JAMA Cardiol. 2017; 2:278&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melstrom P, Sosnoff C, Koszowski B, et al. Systemic absorption of nicotine following acute secondhand exposure to electronic cigarette aerosol in a realistic social setting. Int. J. Hyg. Environ. Health. 2018; 221:816&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, Rees VW, Koutrakis P, et al. Cardiac autonomic effects of secondhand exposure to nicotine from electronic cigarettes: an exploratory study. Environ. Epidemiol. 2019; 3. pii: e033):e033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benowitz NL, Burbank AD. Cardiovascular toxicity of nicotine: implications for electronic cigarette use. Trends Cardiovasc. Med. 2016; 26:515&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotts JE, Jordt SE, McConnell R, Tarran R. What are the respiratory effects of e-cigarettes? BMJ. 2019; 366:l5275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farsalinos KE, Polosa R. Safety evaluation and risk assessment of electronic cigarettes as tobacco cigarette substitutes: a systematic review. Ther. Adv. Drug Saf. 2014; 5:67&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meo SA, Ansary MA, Barayan FR, et al. Electronic cigarettes: impact on lung function and fractional exhaled nitric oxide among healthy adults. Am. J. Mens Health. 2019; 13:1557988318806073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lappas AS, Tzortzi AS, Konstantinidi EM, et al. Short-term respiratory effects of e-cigarettes in healthy individuals and smokers with asthma. Respirology. 2018; 23:291&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennimata SA, Palamidas A, Kaltsakas G, et al. Acute effect of e-cigarette on pulmonary function in healthy subjects and smokers. Eur. Respir. J. 2012; 40(Suppl. 56):P1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamidas A, Gennimata SA, Kaltsakas G, et al. Acute effect of an e-cigarette with and without nicotine on lung function. Tob Induc Dis. 2014; 12:A34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulay M-&#xc8;, Henry C, Boss&#xe9; Y, et al. Acute effects of nicotine-free and flavour-free electronic cigarette use on lung functions in healthy and asthmatic individuals. Respir. Res. 2017; 18:33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson JL, Zhou L, Brighton L, et al. Temporal structure/function variation in cultured differentiated human nasal epithelium associated with acute single exposure to tobacco smoke or E-cigarette vapor. Inhal. Toxicol. 2017; 29:137&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dicpinigaitis PV, Lee Chang A, Dicpinigaitis AJ, Negassa A. Effect of e-cigarette use on cough reflex sensitivity. Chest. 2016; 149:161&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JB, Olgin JE, Nah G, et al. Cigarette and e-cigarette dual use and risk of cardiopulmonary symptoms in the Health eHeart Study. PLoS One. 2018; 13:e0198681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell R, Barrington-Trimis JL, Wang K, et al. Electronic cigarette use and respiratory symptoms in adolescents. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2017; 195:1043&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outbreak of lung injury associated with e-cigarette use, or vaping [Internet]. [cited 2019 Sep 29]. Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/tobacco/basic_information/e-cigarettes/severe-lung-disease.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youmans AJ, Harwood J. Gross and histopathological findings in the first reported vaping-induced lung injury death in the United States. Am. J. Forensic Med. Pathol. 2020; 41:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiani DC. Vaping-induced lung injury. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020; 382:960&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layden JE, Ghinai I, Pray I, et al. Pulmonary illness related to e-cigarette use in Illinois and Wisconsin&#x2014;preliminary report. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020; 382:903&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dohnalek HM, Harley EH. Analysis of electronic cigarette-related injury presenting to U.S. emergency departments, 2008-2017. J. Emerg. Med. 2019; 57:399&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maessen GC, Wijnhoven AM, Neijzen RL, et al. Nicotine intoxication by e-cigarette liquids: a study of case reports and pathophysiology. Clin. Toxicol. (Phila.). 2019; 58:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AM. Sleep and athletic performance. Curr. Sports Med. Rep. 2017; 16:413&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaehne A. Effects of nicotine on sleep during consumption, withdrawal and replacement therapy. Sleep Med. Rev. 2009; 13:363&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boddu S, Bojanowski CM, Scholten E, et al. Investigating the effects of different forms of tobacco use on sleep quality and cough: a matter of gender? In: A26 Environmental Modifiers of Lung Disease [internet]. American Thoracic Society; 2019 [cited 2019 Oct 16]. p. A1180&#x2013;A1180. American Thoracic Society International Conference abstracts. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1164/ajrccm-conference.2019.199.1_MeetingAbstracts.A1180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema AN, Newton JB, Boorman-Padgett JF, et al. Nicotine impairs intra-substance tendon healing after full thickness injury in a rat model. J. Orthop. Res. 2019; 37:94&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donigan JA, Fredericks DC, Nepola JV, Smucker JD. The effect of transdermal nicotine on fracture healing in a rabbit model. J. Orthop. Trauma. 2012; 26:724&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Helen G, Havel C, Dempsey DA, et al. Nicotine delivery, retention and pharmacokinetics from various electronic cigarettes. Addiction. 2016; 111:535&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackowski OA, Hammond D, O&#x2019;Connor RJ, et al. Considerations and future research directions for e-cigarette warnings&#x2014;findings from expert interviews. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2017; 14. pii: E781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston CJ, Freeman RJ, Costales VC, et al. Electronic nicotine delivery systems or e-cigarettes: American College of Preventive Medicine's practice statement. Am. J. Prev. Med. 2019; 56:167&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>