<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30197545</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-1608</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><PubDate><Year>2018</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature and science of sleep</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Sci Sleep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From pillow to podium: a review on understanding sleep for elite athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>243</StartPage><EndPage>253</EndPage><MedlinePgn>243-253</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/NSS.S158598</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sleep is considered vital to human health and well-being, and is critical to physiological and cognitive functioning. Elite athletes experience high training and competition demands, and are often exposed to various factors, situations, and environments that can cause sleep impairments. Previous research has shown that athletes commonly experience sleep loss in the lead up to and following competition, which could have significant impacts on their preparation, performance, and recovery. In particular, the results from previous research show significant reductions in total sleep time (~1:40 h:min) and significant increases in sleep latency (~45 minutes) following evening competition. Napping is common in both the training and competition setting in athletes; however, research on the effect of napping on physiology and performance is limited. In contrast, research on strategies and interventions to improve sleep are increasing in the athletic population, with sleep hygiene research resulting in significant improvements in key sleep indices. This review investigates the physiological importance of sleep in athletes, current tools to monitor athletes' sleep, the role of sleep for cognitive functioning and athletic performance, the prevalence of sleep disturbances and the potential mechanisms causing sleep disturbances, the role of napping, and different intervention strategies to improve sleep.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Donnell</LastName><ForeName>Shannon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health, Sport and Human Performance, University of Waikato, Hamilton, New Zealand, mdriller@waikato.ac.nz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beaven</LastName><ForeName>Christopher M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health, Sport and Human Performance, University of Waikato, Hamilton, New Zealand, mdriller@waikato.ac.nz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Driller</LastName><ForeName>Matthew W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health, Sport and Human Performance, University of Waikato, Hamilton, New Zealand, mdriller@waikato.ac.nz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Sci Sleep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101537767</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1179-1608</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronobiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">competition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30197545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6112797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NSS.S158598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">nss-10-243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Argus C, Driller M, Ebert T, Martin D, Halson S. The effects of 4 different recovery strategies on repeat sprint-cycling performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2013;8(5):542&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23412547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey V, Leveritt M, Gill N. Effect of recovery modality on 4-hour repeated treadmill running performance and changes in physiological variables. J Sci Med Sport. 2004;7(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15139159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeder J, Glaister M, Pizzoferro K, Dawson J, Pedlar C. Sleep duration and quality in elite athletes measured using wristwatch actigraphy. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(6):541&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22329779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff L, Halson S, Peiffer J. Understanding sleep disturbance in athletes prior to important compeititons. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;18(1):13&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24629327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. Sleep and the elite athlete. Sports Sci Exch. 2013;26(113):1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venter R. Role of sleep in performance and recovery of athletes: a review article. S Afr J Res Sport Phys Educ Recreation. 2012;34(1):167&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmadopoulos A, Sargent C, Darwent D, Zhou X, Roach G. Alternatives to polysomnography (PSG): a validation of wrist actigraphy and a partial-PSG system. Behav Res Methods. 2014;46(4):1032&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24442593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mack DC, Patrie JT, Suratt PM, et al. Development and preliminary validation of heart rate and breathing rate detection using a passive, ballistocardiography-based sleep monitoring system. IEEE Trans Inf Technol Biomed. 2009;13(1):111&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19129030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall W, Erwin C, Edinger J, Krystal A, Marsh G. Ambulatory polysomnography: technical aspects and normative values. J Clin Neurophysiol. 1992;9(1):68&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1552010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roky R, Herrera C, Ahmed Q. Sleep in athletes and the effects of Ramadan. J Sports Sci. 2012;30(1):S75&#x2013;S84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22694752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushida C, Littner M, Morgenthaler T, et al. Practice parameters for the indications for polysomnography and related procedures: an update for 2005. Sleep. 2005;28(4):499&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16171294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ancoli-Israel S, Cole R, Alessi C, Chambers M, Moorcroft W, Pollak C. The role of actigraphy in the study of sleep and circadian rhythms. Sleep. 2003;26(3):342&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12749557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A. The role and validity of actigraphy in sleep medicine: an update. Sleep Med Rev. 2011;15(4):259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21237680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller M, McQuillan J, O&#x2019;Donnell S. Inter-device reliability of an automatic-scoring actigraph for measuring sleep in healthy adults. Sleep Sci. 2016;9(3):198&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5241607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28123660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller M, O&#x2019;Donnell S, Tavares F. What wrist should you wear your actigraphy device on? Analysis of dominant vs. non-dominant wrist actigraphy for measuring sleep in healthy adults. Sleep Sci. 2017;10(3):132&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5699857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29410743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh A, Hauri P, Kripke D, Lavie P. The role of actigraphy in the evaluation of sleep disorders. Sleep. 1995;18(4):288&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7618029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushida C, Chang A, Gadkary C, Guilleminault C, Carrillo O, Dement W. Comparison of actigraphy, polysomnographic, and subjective assessment of sleep parameters in sleep-disordered patients. Sleep Med. 2001;2(5):389&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunican I, Murray K, Slater J, et al. Laboratory and home comparison of wrist-activity monitors and polysomnography in middle-aged adults. Sleep Biol Rhythms. 2018;16(1):85&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caia J, Thornton H, Kelly V, et al. Does self-perceived sleep reflect sleep estimated via activity monitors in professional rugby league athletes? J Sports Sci. 2018;36(13):1492&#x2013;1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29087784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse D, Reynolds C, Monk T, Berman S, Kupfer D. The Pittsburg Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Research. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns M. A new method for measuring daytime sleepiness: the epworth sleepiness scale. Sleep. 1991;14(6):540&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1798888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driller M, Mah C, Halson S. Development of the athlete sleep behavior questionnaire: a tool for identifying maladaptive sleep practices in elite athletes. Sleep Sci. 2018;11(1):37&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5916575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29796200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels C, James L, Lawson D, Meeuwisse W. The athlete sleep screening questionnaire: a new tool for assessing and managing sleep in elite athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(7):418&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26002952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thun E, Bjorvatn B, Flo E, Harris A, Pallesen S. Sleep, circadian rhythms, and athletic performance. Sleep Med Rev. 2015;23:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25645125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N, Souissi M, Souissi H, et al. Effect of time of day and partial sleep deprivation on short-term, high-power output. Chronobiol Int. 2008;25(6):1062&#x2013;1076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19005905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Edwards B. Altered sleep-wake cycles and physical performance in athletes. Physiol Behav. 2007;90(2&#x2013;3):274&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17067642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R, Guilleminault C, Efron B. Circadian rhythms and enhanced athletic performance in the national football league. Sleep. 1997;20(5):362&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9381059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenne D. Sleep of athletes &#x2013; problems and possible solutions. Biol Rhythm Res. 2009;40(1):45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. Nutrition, sleep and recovery. Eur J Sport Sci. 2008;8(2):119&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro C, Bortz R, Mitchell D, Bartel P, Jooste P. Slow-wave sleep: a recovery period after exercise. Science. 1981;214(4526):1353&#x2013;1254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7302594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weitzman E. Circadian rhythms and episodic hormone secretion in man. Annu Rev Med. 1976;27:225&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">180872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatti R, De Palo E. An update: salivary hormones and physical exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21(2):157&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21129038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi G, De Vita F, Salvagno G, Gelati M, Montagnana M, Guidi G. Measurement of morning saliva cortisol in athletes. Clin Biochem. 2009;42(9):904&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19250929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook C, Beaven C. Salivary testosterone is related to self-selected training load in elite female athletes. Physiol Behav. 2013;116:8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23531473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaven C, Gill N, Cook C. Salivary testosterone and cortisol responses in professional rugby players after four resistance exercise protocols. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(2):426&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen S, Kvorning K, Sj&#xf8;aard G. The effect of short-term strength training on human skeletal muscle: the importance of physioloigcally elevated hormone levels. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2001;11(6):347&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M, Antunes H, Medeiros A, et al. Sleep and muscle recovery: endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothesis. Medical Hypotheses. 2011;77(2):220&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21550729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filaire E, Sagnol M, Ferrand C, Maso F, Lac G. Psychophysiological stress in judo athletes during competitions. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2001;41(2):263&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11447372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloom S, Johnson R, Park D, Rennie M, Sulaiman W. Differences in the metabolic and hormonal response to exercise between racing cyclists and untrained individuals. J Physiol. 1976;258(1):1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1308956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">940045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Julian R, Bartlett J, Meyer T. Impaired sleep and recovery after night matches in elite football players. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(14):1333&#x2013;1339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26750446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Roach G. Sleep duration is reduced in elite athletes following night-time competitions. Chronobiol Int. 2016;33(6):667&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27097227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shearer D, Jones R, Kilduff L, Cook C. Effects of competition on the sleep patterns of elite rugby union players. Eur J Sport Sci. 2015;15(8):681&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26255667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff L, Halson S, Hebert J, Forsyth P, Peiffer J. Longer sleep durations are positively associated with finishing place during a national mulit-day netball competition. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(1):189&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell S, Bird S, Jacobson G, Driller M. Sleep and stress hormone responses to training and competition in elite female athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(5):611&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29482452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juliff L, Peiffer J, Halson S. Night games: physiological, neuroendocrine and pyschometric mechanisms to explain poor sleep. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;18:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29252066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinbourne R, Miller K, Smart D, Dulson D, Gill N. The effects of sleep extension on sleep, performance, immunity and physical stress in rugby players. Sports. 2018;6(2) pii:E42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balbo M, Leproult R, Van Cauter E. Impact of sleep and its disturbances on hypothalamo-pituitary-adrenal axis activity. Int J Endocrinol. 2010;2010:759234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2902103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20628523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cauter E, Spiegel K, Tasali E, Leproult R. Metabolic consequences of sleep and sleep loss. Sleep Med. 2008;9(1):S23&#x2013;S28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4444051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omisade A, Buxton O, Rusak B. Impact of acute sleep restricition on cortisol and leptin levels in young women. Physiol Behav. 2010;99(5):651&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20138072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leproult R, Copinschi G, Buxton O, Van Cauter E. Sleep loss results in an elevation of cortisol levels the next evening. Sleep. 1997;20(10):865&#x2013;870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9415946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knutson K, Spiegel K, Penev P, Van Cauter E. The metabolic consequence of sleep deprivation. Sleep Med Rev. 2007;11(3):163&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1991337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17442599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri S, Lin L, Austin D, Young T, Mignot E. Short sleep duration is associated with reduced leptin, elevated ghrelin, and increased body mass index. PloS Medicine. 2004;1(3):e62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC535701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15602591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteleone P, Maj M, Fusco M, Orazzo C, Kemali D. Physical exercise at night blunts the nocturnal increase of plasma melatonin levels in healthy humans. Life Sciences. 1990;47(22):1989&#x2013;1995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2273939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escames G, Ozturk G, Ba&#xf1;o-Ot&#xe1;lora B, et al. Exercise and melatonin in humans: reciprocal benefits. J Pineal Res. 2012;52(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21848991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buxton O, Frank S, L&#x2019;Hermite-Baleriaux M, Leproult R, Turek F, Van Cauter E. Roles of intensity and duration of nocturnal exercise in causing phase delays of human circadian rhythms. Am J Physiology. 1997;273(3 Pt 1):E536&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9316443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson J. Sleep is of the brain, by the brain and for the brain. Nature. 2005;437(7063):1254&#x2013;1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16251949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belenky G, Wesensten N, Thorne D, et al. Patterns of performance degradation and restoration during sleep restriction and subsequent recovery: a sleep dose-response study. J Sleep Res. 2003;12(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12603781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stickgold R. Sleep-dependent memory consolidation. Nature. 2005;437(7063):1272&#x2013;1278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16251952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerouali Y, Jemel B, Godbout R. The effects of early and late night partial sleep deprivation on automatic and selective attention: an ERP study. Brain Res. 2010;1308:87&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19799884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Hammes D, Coutts A, Meyer T. Sleep and athletic performance: the effects of sleep loss on exercise performance, and phyiological and cognitive responses to exercise. Sports Med. 2015;45(2):161&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25315456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mograss MA, Guillem F, Brazzini-Poisson V, Godbout R. The effects of total sleep deprivation on recognition memory processes: a study of event-related potential. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2009;91(4):343&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19340944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri M, Arabameri E. The effect of sleep deprivation on choice reaction time and anaerobic power of college student athletes. Asian J Sports Med. 2012;3(1):15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards B, Waterhouse J. Effects of one night of partial sleep deprivation upon diurnal rhythms of accuracy and consistency in throwing darts. Chronobiol Int. 2009;26(4):756&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19444754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyner L, Horne J. Sleep restriction and serving accuracy in performance tennis players, and effects of caffine. Physiol Behav. 2013;120:93&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23916998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Cheikh R, Latiri I, Dogui M, Ben Saad H. Effects of one-night sleep deprivation on selective attention and isometric force in adolescent karate athletes. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2017;57(6):752&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27244131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach G, Halson S, Sargent C. Sleep/wake behaviours of elite athletes from individual and team sports. Eur J Sport Sci. 2015;15(2):94&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24993935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Roach G, Halson S, Martin D, West N, Sargent C. Sleep/wake behaviour of endurance cyclists before and during competition. J Sports Sci. 2015;33(3):293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25105558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuomilehto H, Vuorinen V, Penttil&#xe4; E, et al. Sleep of professional athletes: underexploited potential to improve health and performance. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(7):704&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27173843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Lastella M, Halson S, Roach G. The impact of training schedules on the sleep and fatigue of elite athletes. Chronobiol Int. 2014;31(10):1160&#x2013;1168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Meyer T. The effect of an acute sleep hygiene strategy following a late-night soccer match on recovery of players. Chronobiol Int. 2016;33(5):490&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27031035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Duffield R, Skorski S, Coutts A, Julian R, Meyer T. Sleep and recovery in team sport: current sleep-related issues facing professional team-sport athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(8):950&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25756787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romyn G, Robey E, Dimmock J, Halson S, Peeling P. Sleep, anxiety and electronic device use by athletes in the training and competition environments. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16(3):301&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25790844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oda S, Shirakawa K. Sleep onset is disrupted following pre-sleep exercise that causes large physiological excitement at bedtime. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(9):1789&#x2013;1799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24859750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chennaoui M, Arnal P, Sauvet F, L&#xe9;ger D. Sleep and exercise: a reciprocal issue? Sleep Med Rev. 2015;20:59&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25127157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Halson S, Abaidia A, Ahmaidi S, Dupont G. Stress, sleep and recovery in elite soccer: a critical review of the literature. Sports Med. 2015;45(10):1387&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26206724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xe4;uchi K. The thermophyiological cascade leading to sleep initiation in relation to phase of entertainment. Sleep Med Rev. 2007;11(6):439&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17764994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshikawa M, Uchida S, Hirano Y. A subjective assessment of the prevelance and factors associated with poor sleep quality amongst elite japanese athletes. Sports Med. 2018;4:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5826912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29484576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C, Kezirian E, Marcello B, Dement W. Poor sleep quality and insufficient sleep of a collegiate student-athlete population. J National Sleep Foundation. 2018;4(3):251&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29776619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell S, Beaven C, Driller M. Sleep/wake behavior prior to and following competition in elite female athletes. Sport Sci Health. 2018;11(1):37&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitchford N, Robertson S, Sargent C, Cordy J, Bishop D, Bartlett J. A change in training environment alters sleep quality but not quantity in elite australian rules football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(1):75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27080592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunican I, Higgins C, Jones M, et al. Caffeine use in a super rugby game and its relationship to post-game sleep. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018 Feb 12; Epub.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29431593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mah C, Mah K, Kezirian E, Dement W. The effects of sleep extension on the athletic performance of collegiate basketball players. Sleep. 2011;34(7):943&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21731144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milewski M, Skaggs D, Bishop G, et al. Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. J Pediatr Orthop. 2014;34(2):129&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit E, Mougin F, Bourdin H. A 20-min nap in athletes changes subsequent sleep architecture but does not alter physical performances after normal sleep or 5-h phase-advance conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(2):305&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24276580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse J, Atkinson G, Edwards B, Reilly T. The role of a short post-lunch nap in improving cognitive, motor, and sprint performance in participants with partial sleep deprivation. J Sports Sci. 2007;25(14):1557&#x2013;1566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies D, Graham K, Chow C. The effect of prior endurance training on nap sleep patterns. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(1):87&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20308699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargent C, Halson S, Roach G. Sleep or swim? Early-morning training severly restricts the amount of sleep obtained by elite swimmers. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(1):310&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton H, Duthie G, Pitchford N, Delaney J, Benton D, Dascombe B. Effects of a two-week high intensity training camp on sleep activity of professional rugby league athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;12(7):928&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell S, Beaven C, Driller M. The influence of match-day napping in elite female netball athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018 Mar 15; Epub.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29543074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lastella M, Lovell G, Sargent C. Athletes&#x2019; precompetitive sleep behavior and its relationship with subsequent precompetitive mood and performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(Suppl 1):123&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24444196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastin D, Bryson J, Corwyn R. Assessment of sleep hygiene using the sleep hygiene index. J Behav Med. 2006;29(3):223&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16557353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacks P, Rotert M. Knowledge and practice of sleep hygiene techniques in insomniacs and good sleepers. Behav Res Ther. 1986;24(3):365&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3729908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakinuma M, Takahashi M, Kato N, et al. Effect of brief sleep hygiene education for workers of an information technology company. Ind Health. 2010;48(6):758&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20616458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishinoue N, Takano T, Kaku A, et al. Effects of sleep hygiene education and behavioral therapy on sleep quality of white-collar workers: a randomized controlled trial. Ind Health. 2012;50(2):123&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22293726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa I, Araujo J, Azevedo C. The effect of a sleep hygiene education program on the sleep-wake cycle of Brazilian adolescent students. Sleep Biol Rhythms. 2007;5(4):251&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebhart C, Erlacher D, Schredl M. Moderate exercise plus sleep education improves self-reported sleep quality, daytime mood, and vitality in adults with chronic sleep complaints: a waiting list-controlled trial. Sleep Disord. 2011;2011:809312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23471095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar H, Skorski S, Duffield R, Meyer T. The effect of an acute sleep hygiene strategy following a late-night soccer match on recovery of players. Chronobiol Int. 2016;33(5):1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27031035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell S, Driller M. Sleep-hygiene education improves sleep indices in elite female athletes. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10(4):522&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffield R, Murphy A, Kellett A, Reid M. Recovery from repeated on-court tennis sessions: combining cold-water immersion, compression, and sleep interventions. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(2):273&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23799825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ryswyk E, Weeks R, Bandick L, et al. A novel sleep optimisation program to improve athletes&#x2019; well-being and performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(2):144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27574901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarraya M, Jarraya S, Chtourou H, Souiss N, Chamari K. The effect of partial sleep deprivation on reaction time and the attentional capacities of the handball goalkeeper. Biol Rhythm Res. 2013;44(3)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott JP, McNaughton LR, Polman RC. Effects of sleep deprivation and exercise on cognitive, motor performance and mood. Physiol Behav. 2006;87(2):396&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16403541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond LK, Dawson B, Hillman DR, Eastwood PR. The effect of interstate travel on sleep patterns of elite Australian rules footballers. J Sci Med Sport. 2004;7(2):186&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15362314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>