<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41782153</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mild hyperbaric oxygen therapy on subjective sleep quality, aerobic, anaerobic exercise test, brain and muscle tissue oxygenation response in Chinese University male athletes after muscle fatigue.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01587-y</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Chaoyi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Measurement and Evaluation in Exercise Bioinformation of Hebei Province, Physical Education College, Hebei Normal University, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biological Center, China institute of sport science, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Minxiao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biological Center, China institute of sport science, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorenzo</LastName><ForeName>Santiago</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine, Bradenton, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biological Center, China institute of sport science, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Zhijian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biological Center, China institute of sport science, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Xue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biological Center, China institute of sport science, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jiexiu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biological Center, China institute of sport science, Beijing, China. zhaojiexiu@ciss.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>(L2024B35)</GrantID><Agency>the Doctoral Research Initiation Fund Project of Hebei Normal University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>(2025JT05)</GrantID><Agency>Hebei Province Sports Science and Technology Research Project Funding</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>(BJ2026361)</GrantID><Agency>Funded by Science Research Project of Hebei Education Department</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>(5212020)</GrantID><Agency>the General Research of Natural Science Foundation of Beijing</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mild hyperbaric oxygen therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tissue oxygenation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Ethical Committee of the China Institute of Sport Science (Approval Project Number CISSLA-2020062801), and adhered to the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. In this study, written informed consent, outlining the study&#x2019;s benefits and potential risks, was obtained from all participants. Consent for publication: Written informed consent for publication of personal and clinical information and any potentially identifying images was obtained from all participants included in this study. We declare that this manuscript is our original work and has not been published in any other journal or publication, nor is it under consideration for publication elsewhere. All listed authors have made contributions to this manuscript and have jointly approved the final version of the manuscript. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41782153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01587-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01587-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wan JJ, Qin Z, Wang PY, Sun Y, Liu X. Muscle fatigue: general Understanding and treatment. Exp Mol Med. 2017;49(10):e384. https://doi.org/10.1038/emm.2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann M, Dickhuth HH, Gendrisch G, et al. Training-overtraining. A prospective, experimental study with experienced middle- and long-distance runners. Int J Sports Med. 1991;12(5):444&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-2007-1024711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmikli SL, Brink MS, de Vries WR, Backx FJ. Can we detect non-functional overreaching in young elite soccer players and middle-long distance runners using field performance tests? Br J Sports Med. 2011;45(8):631&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsm.2009.067462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Rumpf MC, Hertzog M, Castagna C, Farooq A, Girard O, Hader K. Acute and residual soccer Match-Related fatigue: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(3):539&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-017-0798-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, McCall A, Carling C, et al. Recovery in soccer: part ii-recovery strategies. Sports Med. 2013;43(1):9&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-012-0002-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, Zinner C, Hauser A, Holmberg HC, Wegrzyk J. The impact of hyperoxia on human performance and recovery. Sports Med. 2017;47(3):429&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-016-0590-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinale DA, Ekblom B. Hyperoxia for performance and training. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(13):1515&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2017.1398893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babul S, Rhodes EC. The role of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in sports medicine. Sports Med. 2000;30(6):395&#x2013;403. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200030060-00002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii Y, Deie M, Adachi N, Yasunaga Y, Sharman P, Miyanaga Y, Ochi M. Hyperbaric oxygen as an adjuvant for athletes. Sports Med. 2005;35(9):739&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200535090-00001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyboer M 3rd, Sharma D, Santiago W, McCulloch N. Hyperbaric oxygen therapy: side effects defined and quantified. Adv Wound Care (New Rochelle). 2017;6(6):210&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1089/wound.2016.0718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burtscher J, Mallet RT, Pialoux V, Millet GP, Burtscher M. Adaptive responses to hypoxia and/or hyperoxia in humans. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2022;37(13&#x2013;15):887&#x2013;912. https://doi.org/10.1089/ars.2021.0280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara A. Mild hyperbaric oxygen: mechanisms and effects. J Physiol Sci. 2019;69(4):573&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12576-019-00678-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu C, Xu M, Lorenzo S, Huang P, Rao Z, Geng X, Zhao J. Effects of mild hyperbaric oxygen therapy on timing sequence recovery of muscle fatigue in Chinese university male athletes. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2024;22(4):305&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesf.2024.04.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takemura A, Eda N, Saito T, Shimizu K. Mild hyperbaric oxygen for the early improvement of mood disturbance induced by high-intensity exercise. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2022;62(2):250&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.23736/S0022-4707.21.11971-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SH, Park SJ, Shin MS, Kim CK. The effects of low-pressure hyperbaric oxygen treatment before and after maximal exercise on lactate concentration, heart rate recovery, and antioxidant capacity. J Exerc Rehabil. 2018;14(6):980&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.12965/jer.1836468.234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker R, Kayser B, Rae E, Raunch L, Bosch A, Noakes T. Hyperoxia improves 20 Km cycling time trial performance by increasing muscle activation levels while perceived exertion stays the same. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101(6):771&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-007-0458-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branco BH, Fukuda DH, Andreato LV, Santos JF, Esteves JV, Franchini E. The effects of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on Post-Training recovery in Jiu-Jitsu athletes. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(3):e0150517. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0150517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihailovic T, Bouzigon R, Bouillod A, Grevillot J, Ravier G. Post-Exercise hyperbaric oxygenation improves recovery for subsequent performance. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2023;94(2):427&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1080/02701367.2021.2002797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallette MM, Stewart DG, Cheung SS. The effects of hyperoxia on Sea-Level exercise Performance, Training, and recovery: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):153&#x2013;75. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-017-0791-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrich S, Hasler ED, M&#xfc;ller-Mottet S, Keusch S, Furian M, Latshang TD, Schneider S, Saxer S, Bloch KE. Mechanisms of improved exercise performance under hyperoxia. Respiration. 2017;93(2):90&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1159/000453620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF 3rd, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh sleep quality index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. 1989;28(2):193&#x2013;213. https://doi.org/10.1016/0165-1781(89)90047-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan C, Wang J, Lu J, Yin J, An Y, Ye J, Cao G, Qiu J. The limitations of using the Pittsburgh sleep quality index to assess athletes&#x2019; sleep quality: evidence from reliability and validity in Chinese professional athletes. Psychol Res Behav Manag. 2024;17:2603&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.2147/PRBM.S463289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ryswyk E, Weeks R, Bandick L, O&#x2019;Keefe M, Vakulin A, Catcheside P, Barger L, Potter A, Poulos N, Wallace J, Antic NA. A novel sleep optimization programme to improve athletes&#x2019; well-being and performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(2):144&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2016.1221470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triki R, Ben Abderrahman A, Salhi I, Rhibi F, Saeidi A, Almaqhawi A, Hackney AC, Laher I, Granacher U, Zouhal H. Effects of time-of-day resistance training on muscle strength, hormonal adaptations, and sleep quality during ramadan fasting. Front Nutr. 2024;11:1439738.https://doi/10.3389/fnut.2024.1439738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu C, Wu Z, Xu M, Lorenzo S, Dong Y, Wang Z, Qin F, Zhao J. Cryotherapy on subjective sleep Quality, muscle, and inflammatory response in Chinese Middle- and Long-Distance runners after muscle damage. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(10):2883&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Tian Y, Nie J, Xu J, Liu D. Red light and the sleep quality and endurance performance of Chinese female basketball players. J Athl Train. 2012;47(6):673&#x2013;8.https://doi/10.4085/1062-6050-47.6.08.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieur F, Benoit H, Busso T, Castells J, Geyssant A, Denis C. Effects of moderate hyperoxia on oxygen consumption during submaximal and maximal exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(3):235&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-002-0707-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takken T, van der Net J, Helders PJ. The reliability of an aerobic and an anaerobic exercise tolerance test in patients with juvenile onset dermatomyositis. J Rheumatol. 2005;32(4):734&#x2013;9. https://www.jrheum.org/content/32/4/734.long.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones B, Hesford CM, Cooper CE. The use of portable NIRS to measure muscle oxygenation and haemodynamics during a repeated sprint running test. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2013;789:185&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-7411-1_26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig J, H&#xf6;per S, van der Venne P, M&#xfc;rner-Lavanchy I, Resch F, Kaess M. Resting state prefrontal cortex oxygenation in adolescent non-suicidal self-injury - A near-infrared spectroscopy study. Neuroimage Clin. 2021;31:102704. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nicl.2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science:a practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol. 2013;26;4:863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2013.00863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M, Sacco P. Muscle damage and soreness after endurance exercise of the elbow flexors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(6):920-7. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-200206000-00003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su QS, Tian Y, Zhang JG, Zhang H. Effects of allicin supplementation on plasma markers of exercise-induced muscle damage,IL-6 and antioxidant capacity. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;103(3):275&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-008-0699-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, You J, Ma H, Zhou M, Huang C. Efficacy and safety of hyperbaric oxygen therapy for fibromyalgia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2023;13(1):e062322. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2022-062322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis K, Katz J, Djaiani C, O&#x2019;Leary G, Uehling J, Carroll J, Santa Mina D, Clarke H, Gofeld M, Katznelson R. Evaluation of a Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy Intervention in Individuals with Fibromyalgia.Pain Med. 2021;22(6):1324&#x2013;1332. https://doi.org/10.1093/pm/pnaa416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harch PG, Andrews SR, Rowe CJ, Lischka JR, Townsend MH, Yu Q, Mercante DE. Hyperbaric oxygen therapy for mild traumatic brain injury persistent postconcussion syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Med Gas Res. 2020;10(1):8&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.4103/2045-9912.279978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker JM, Mulatya C, Hebert D, Wilson SH, Lindblad AS, Weaver LK. Sleep assessment in a randomized trial of hyperbaric oxygen in U.S. service members with post concussive mild traumatic brain injury compared to normal controls. Sleep Med. 2018;51:66&#x2013;79. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sleep.2018.06.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Y, Tan J, Nie Y, Lu Y, Mei X, Tu C.Hyperbaric oxygen therapy is safe and effective for the treatment of sleep disorders in children with cerebral palsy. Neurol Res. 2017;39(3):239&#x2013;247. https://doi.org/10.1080/01616412.2016.1275454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson A, Uusij&#xe4;rvi J, Eksborg S, Lindholm P. Tissue oxygenation measured with near-infrared spectroscopy during normobaric and hyperbaric oxygen breathing in healthy subjects. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(4):757&#x2013;761. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-010-1403-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T. Acute and chronic effects of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on blood circulation of human muscle and tendon in vivo. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(10):2765-70. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e31826791da.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie W, Chen X, Ma X, Song S, Ma H, You J, Huang C. Effect of hyperbaric oxygen therapy combined with repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on vascular cognitive impairment: a randomised controlled trial protocol.BMJ Open. 2023;13(11):e073532. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2023-073532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousin N, Goutay J, Girardie P, Favory R, Drumez E, Mathieu D, Poissy J, Parmentier E, Duburcq T. Effects of high oxygen tension on healthy volunteer microcirculation. Diving Hyperb Med. 2022; 52(4):260&#x2013;270. https://doi.org/10.28920/dhm52.4.260-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter MS, Fenton J, Reed KE. The effects of hyperoxia on repeated sprint cycling performance &amp; muscle fatigue.J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22(12):1344&#x2013;1348.https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgos C, Henr&#xed;quez-Olgu&#xed;n C, Andrade DC, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, Araneda OF, White A,Cerda-Kohler H. Effects of Exercise Training under Hyperbaric Oxygen on Oxidative Stress Markers and Endurance Performance in Young Soccer Players: A Pilot Study. J Nutr Metab. 2016;2016:5647407. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/5647407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadanny A, Hachmo Y, Rozali D, Catalogna M, Yaakobi E, Sova M, Gattegno H, Abu Hamed R, Lang E, Polak N, Friedman M, Finci S, Zemel Y, Bechor Y, Gal N, Efrati S. Effects of Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy on Mitochondrial Respiration and Physical Performance in Middle-Aged Athletes: A Blinded, Randomized Controlled Trial. Sports Med Open. 2022;8(1):22. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-021-00403-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manselin TA, S&#xf6;derg&#xe5;rd O, Larsen FJ, Lindholm P. Aerobic efficiency is associated with the improvement in maximal power output during acute hyperoxia. Physiol Rep. 2017;5(2):e13119. https://doi.org/10.14814/phy2.13119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara A, Nagatomo F, Fujino H, Kondo H. Exposure to mild hyperbaric oxygen increases blood flow and resting energy expenditure but not oxidative stress. J Sci Res Rep. 2014;3(14):1886&#x2013;1896. https://journaljsrr.com/index.php/JSRR/article/view/138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser A, Zinner C, Born DP, Wehrlin JP, Sperlich B. Does hyperoxic recovery during cross-country skiing team sprints enhance performance?Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(4):787&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;94. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000000157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozenek R, Fobel BF, Banks JC, Russo AC, Lacourse MG, Strauss MB. Does hyperbaric oxygen exposure affect high-intensity, short-duration exercise performance?J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(4):1037-41. https://doi.org/10.1519/R-21296.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez Villela M, Dunworth SA, Kraft BD, Harlan NP, Natoli MJ, Suliman HB, Moon RE. Effects of high-intensity interval training with hyperbaric oxygen. Front Physiol. 2022; 13:963799. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.963799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, Schiffer T, Achtzehn S, Mester J, Holmberg HC. Pre-exposure to hyperoxic air does not enhance power output during subsequent sprint cycling. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(2):301-5. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-010-1507-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, Zinner C, Krueger M, Wegrzyk J, Achtzehn S, Holmberg HC. Effects of hyperoxia during recovery from 5&#xd7;30-s bouts of maximal-intensity exercise.J Sports Sci. 2012;30(9):851-8. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2012.671531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawada S, Fukaya K, Ohtani M, Kobayashi K, Fukusaki C. Effects of pre-exposure to hyperbaric hyperoxia on high-intensity exercise performance.J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(1):66&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e31815eefa2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoi Y, Yanagihashi R, Morishita K, Goto N, Fujiwara T, Abe K. Recovery effects of repeated exposures to normobaric hyperoxia on local muscle fatigue.J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(8):2173-9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000000386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperlich B, Zinner C, Krueger M, Wegrzyk J, Mester J, Holmberg HC. Ergogenic effect of hyperoxic recovery in elite swimmers performing high-intensity intervals. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21(6):e421-9. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01349.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroon JC. The effect of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on cognition, performance, proteomics,and telomere length-The difference between zero and one: A case report. Front Neurol. 2022;13:949536. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2022.949536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimoda M, Enomoto M, Horie M, Miyakawa S, Yagishita K. Effects of hyperbaric oxygen on muscle fatigue after maximal intermittent plantar flexion exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(6):1648-56. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000000809.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>