<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31341450</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1658-3639</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Season>Jul-Aug</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Health Sci (Qassim)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of aerobic and anaerobic exercise on estrogen level, fat mass, and muscle mass among postmenopausal osteoporotic females.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>10-16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The life expectancy of women increases with the advancement in modern medicine, leading them to spent about two decades in menopausal state along with its associated complications. The process of aging triggers a deleterious cascade of physiological changes in the body. Hence, the aim of our study is to determine the effects of both aerobic and anaerobic exercises on estrogen level in postmenopausal osteoporotic females.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A randomized control trial was conducted among 94 postmenopausal osteoporotic females, randomly divided into two equal groups. The participants in Group A were assigned to perform aerobic exercise, whereas Group B performed resistance exercises. Each group performed exercises for 12 weeks, whereas reading was collected for blood estrogen level, fat mass, and muscle mass before exercise training and after 12 weeks of training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twelve weeks of aerobic and anaerobic exercise program based on the American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM); frequency, intensity, time, and type protocol has beneficial effect on estradiol level and lean mass, whereas inversely correlated with fat mass of postmenopausal osteoporotic female.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study concluded that 12 weeks of exercise programs was found to be effective in improving estradiol level of postmenopausal osteoporotic female. The efficacy of anaerobic exercise was found to be more potent on estradiol level and lean mass than aerobic exercises as only 36 sessions of resisted exercises performed during a period of 12 weeks provided more significant result than 72 session of aerobic exercises.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Razzak</LastName><ForeName>Zainab Abdul</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Ziauddin College of Rehabilitation Sciences, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Amna Aamir</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Ziauddin College of Rehabilitation Sciences, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farooqui</LastName><ForeName>Sumaira Imran</ForeName><Initials>SI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Ziauddin College of Rehabilitation Sciences, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Health Sci (Qassim)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528042</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1658-3639</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">estrogen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osteoporosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postmenopausal</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31341450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6619462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Top&#xe7;uoglu A, Uzun H, Aydin S, Kahraman N, Vehid S, Zeybek G, et al. The effect of hormone replacement therapy on oxidized low density lipoprotein levels and paraoxonase activity in postmenopausal women. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2005;205:79&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15635276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold EB, Bromberger J, Crawford S, Samuels S, Greendale GA, Harlow SD, et al. Factors associated with age at natural menopause in a multiethnic sample of midlife women. Am J Epidemiol. 2001;153:865&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11323317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sowers MR, La Pietra MT. Menopause:Its epidemiology and potential association with chronic diseases. Epidemiol Rev. 1995;17:287&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8654512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming LE, Levis S, LeBlanc WG, Dietz NA, Arheart KL, Wilkinson JD, et al. Earlier age at menopause, work, and tobacco smoke exposure. Menopause. 2008;15:1103&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2703810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dratva J, G&#xf3;mez Real F, Schindler C, Ackermann-Liebrich U, Gerbase MW, Probst-Hensch NM, et al. Is age at menopause increasing across Europe? Results on age at menopause and determinants from two population-based studies. Menopause. 2009;16:385&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19034049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisar N, Sohoo NA. Severity of menopausal symptoms and the quality of life at different status of menopause:A community based survey from rural Sindh, Pakistan. Int J Collab Res Intern Med Public Health. 2010;2:118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapur P, Sinha B, Pereira BM. Measuring climacteric symptoms and age at natural menopause in an Indian population using the greene climacteric scale. Menopause. 2009;16:378&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jassim GA, Al-Shboul Q. Attitudes of Bahraini women towards the menopause:Implications for health care policy. Maturitas. 2008;59:358&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18495386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer W, Sandridge AL, Chehabeddine RS. The frequency distribution of age at natural menopause among Saudi Arabian women. Maturitas. 2003;46:263&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14625123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaze N, Joshi S. Yoga and menopausal transition. J Midlife Health. 2010;1:56&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3122509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21716773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter MS, Gentry-Maharaj A, Ryan A, Burnell M, Lanceley A, Fraser L, et al. Prevalence, frequency and problem rating of hot flushes persist in older postmenopausal women:Impact of age, body mass index, hysterectomy, hormone therapy use, lifestyle and mood in a cross-sectional cohort study of 10,418 British women aged 54-65. BJOG. 2012;119:40&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzi RJ, Helzlsouer KJ, Fetting JH. Prevalence of menopausal symptoms among women with a history of breast cancer and attitudes toward estrogen replacement therapy. J Clin Oncol. 1995;13:2737&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7595732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez JA, Garcia FC, Palacios S, P&#xe9;rez M. Epidemiology of risk factors and symptoms associated with menopause in Spanish women. Maturitas. 2009;62:30&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19010615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi M, Jouyandeh Z, Nayebzadeh F. Prevalence of menopause symptoms among Iranian women. J Fam Reprod Health. 2012;6:1&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnatz PF, Serra J, O'Sullivan DM, Sorosky JI. Menopausal symptoms in hispanic women and the role of socioeconomic factors. Obstet Gynecol Surv. 2006;61:187&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson VW. Aging, estrogens, and episodic memory in women. Cogn Behav Neurol. 2009;22:205&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2791907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson RA, Vittinghoff E, Kanaya AM, Miles TP, Resnick HE, Kritchevsky SB, et al. Urinary incontinence in elderly women:Findings from the health, aging, and body composition study. Obstet Gynecol. 2004;104:301&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geusens P, Autier P, Boonen S, Vanhoof J, Declerck K, Raus J, et al. The relationship among history of falls, osteoporosis, and fractures in postmenopausal women. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;83:903&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12098147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iatrakis G, Haronis N, Sakellaropoulos G, Kourkoubas A, Gallos M. Psychosomatic symptoms of postmenopausal women with or without hormonal treatment. Psychother Psychosom. 1986;46:116&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3628680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbil N. Attitudes towards menopause and depression, body image of women during menopause. Alex J Med. 2018;54:241&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman EW. Associations of depression with the transition to menopause. Menopause. 2010;17:823&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20531231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumel JE, Castelo-Branco C, Binfa L, Gramegna G, Tacla X, Aracena B, et al. Quality of life after the menopause:A population study. Maturitas. 2000;34:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10687878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier V, Rabasa-Lhoret R, Barbat-Artigas S, Elisha B, Karelis AD, Aubertin-Leheudre M, et al. Menopause and sarcopenia:A potential role for sex hormones. Maturitas. 2011;68:331&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21353405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toth MJ, Tchernof A, Sites CK, Poehlman ET. Menopause-related changes in body fat distribution. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2000;904:502&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Gallagher D, Poehlman ET, Wolper C, Nonas K, Nelson D, et al. Menopausal changes in body composition and energy expenditure. Exp Gerontol. 1994;29:377&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7925757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltais ML, Desroches J, Dionne IJ. Changes in muscle mass and strength after menopause. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2009;9:186&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19949277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasalathanthri S. Menopause and exercise:Linking pathophysiology to effects. Arch Med. 2015;28:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira LD, Oliveira ML, Lirani-Galv&#xe3;o AP, Marin-Mio RV, Santos RN, Lazaretti-Castro M, et al. Physical exercise and osteoporosis:Effects of different types of exercises on bone and physical function of postmenopausal women. Arq Bras Endocrinol Metabol. 2014;58:514&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25166042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindsay R. The menopause and osteoporosis. Obstet Gynecol. 1996;87:16S&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8559548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiessl H, Frost HM, Jee WS. Estrogen and bone-muscle strength and mass relationships. Bone. 1998;22:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9437507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Maatouq MA, El-Desouki MI, Othman SA, Mattar EH, Babay ZA, Addar M, et al. Prevalence of osteoporosis among postmenopausal females with diabetes mellitus. Saudi Med J. 2004;25:1423&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15494815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold BA. Image Analysis Inc. Assignee. Automated X-ray Bone Densitometer. United States Patent US 6,320,931. 2001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahoor S, Ayub U. Prevalence of osteoporosis in postmenopausal women visiting police and services hospital, PESHAWAR, NWFP. J Postgrad Med Inst. 2011;24:4&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwamoto J, Takeda T, Ichimura S. Effect of exercise training and detraining on bone mineral density in postmenopausal women with osteoporosis. J Orthop Sci. 2001;6:128&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11484097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asikainen TM, Kukkonen-Harjula K, Miilunpalo S. Exercise for health for early postmenopausal women:A systematic review of randomised controlled trials. Sports Med. 2004;34:753&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15456348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz RS, Evans WJ. Effects of exercise on body composition and functional capacity of the elderly. J Gerontol Ser A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1995;50:147&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7493209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elavsky S, McAuley E. Physical activity, symptoms, esteem, and life satisfaction during menopause. Maturitas. 2005;52:374&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16198515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketabipoor SM, Jahromi MK. Effect of aerobic exercise in water on serum estrogen and C-reactive protien and body mass index level in obese and normal weight postmenopausal women. Womens Health Bull. 2015;2:e25048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan MF, Dowsett M, Folkerd E, Bingham S, Wareham N, Lu S, et al. Usual physical activity and endogenous sex hormones in postmenopausal women:The European prospective investigation into cancer-norfolk population study. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2007;16:900&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson C, Lampe JW, Tworoger SS, Ulrich CM, Bowen D, Irwin ML, et al. Effects of a moderate intensity exercise intervention on estrogen metabolism in postmenopausal women. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2004;13:868&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copeland JL, Consitt LA, Tremblay MS. Hormonal responses to endurance and resistance exercise in females aged 19-69 years. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57:B158&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11909881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackney AC. Exercise as a stressor to the human neuroendocrine system. Medicina (Kaunas) 2006;42:788&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17090977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truesdale KP, Roberts A, Cai J, Berge JM, Stevens J. Comparison of eight equations that predict percent body fat using skinfolds in American youth. Child Obes. 2016;12:314&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4964757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27045618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aandstad A, Holtberget K, Hageberg R, Holme I, Anderssen SA. Validity and reliability of bioelectrical impedance analysis and skinfold thickness in predicting body fat in military personnel. Mil Med. 2014;179:208&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24491619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donnell E, Kirwan LD, Goodman JM. Aerobic exercise training in healthy postmenopausal women:Effects of hormone therapy. Menopause. 2009;16:770&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19240655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peltz G, Aguirre MT, Sanderson M, Fadden MK. The role of fat mass index in determining obesity. Am J Hum Biol. 2010;22:639&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2929934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20737611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports of Medicine, editor. ACSM's Health-Related Physical Fitness Assessment Manual. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams and Wilkins; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HK, Jung MK, Park E, Lee CY, Jee YS, Eun D, et al. The effect of warm-ups with stretching on the isokinetic moments of collegiate men. J Exerc Rehabil. 2018;14:78&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29511656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauersen JB, Bertelsen DM, Andersen LB. The effectiveness of exercise interventions to prevent sports injuries:A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:871&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24100287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MJ, Close L, Gillon SC, Molassiotis A, Lee PH, Farquhar MC, et al. Use of the modified borg scale and numerical rating scale to measure chronic breathlessness:A pooled data analysis. Eur Respir J. 2016;47:1861&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26989107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guazzi M, Adams V, Conraads V, Halle M, Mezzani A, Vanhees L, et al. Clinical recommendations for cardiopulmonary exercise testing data assessment in specific patient populations. Eur Heart J. 2012;33:2917&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22952138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honisett SY, Tangalakis K, Wark J, Apostolopoulos V, Stojanovska L. The effects of hormonal therapy and exercise on bone turnover in postmenopausal women:A randomised double-blind pilot study. Pril (Makedon Akad Nauk Umet Odd Med Nauki) 2016;37:23&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27883319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghadasi M, Siavashpour S. The effect of 12 weeks of resistance training on hormones of bone formation in young sedentary women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22562545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenney WL, Wilmore J, Costill D. Physiology of Sport and Exercise. 6th ed. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teoman N, Ozcan A, Acar B. The effect of exercise on physical fitness and quality of life in postmenopausal women. Maturitas. 2004;47:71&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14706768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Buonani C, Viezel J, Silva EP, Diniz TA, Santos VR, et al. Effect of combined aerobic and resistance training in body composition of obese postmenopausal women. Motriz. 2015;21:61&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>