<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33420583</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1993-0402</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Chinese journal of integrative medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Chin J Integr Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Tai Chi and Resistance Training on Cancer-Related Fatigue and Quality of Life in Middle-Aged and Elderly Cancer Patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>265</StartPage><EndPage>272</EndPage><MedlinePgn>265-272</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11655-021-3278-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To study the effect of Tai Chi (TC) and resistance training (RT) with different intensity on the cancer-related fatigue (CRF) and quality of life (QoL) of middle-aged and elderly cancer patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Totally 120 cancer patients were enrolled and randomly assigned to 4 groups by a random number table, including TC group, high-intensity 60% one repetition maximum (1-RM) RT group (HIRT), low-intensity (30% 1-RM) RT group (LIRT) and control group, 30 patients in each group. Participants in the TC group received 24-form simplified Yang-style TC training at a frequency of 40 min per day, 3 days per week for 12 weeks. Patients in the two RT groups received 10 sessions, 6 designated movements per day, 3 days per week for 12 weeks. The 1-RM of 6 muscle groups, fat mass (FM), lean body mass (LBM), along with the scores of Brief Fatigue Inventory (BFI), QoL questionnaire for Chinese cancer patients receiving chemobiotherapy (QLQ-CCC), Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7), Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) and Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI) were measured before and after training. The adverse effect was also observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After 12-week intervention, patients in both TC and RT groups showed significant improvements in CRF and QLQ-CCC compared to pre-treatment (P&lt;0.05). Compared with the LIRT and TC groups, patients in the HIRT group improved more significantly in increasing muscle strength and LBM, and reducing in FM (P&lt;0.05). Patients in the TC group significantly increased in lower limb muscle strength compared with the LIRT group (P&lt;0.05). In addition, patients in the TC group showed more significant improvements in scores of GAD-7, PHQ-9 and PSQI than 2 RT groups (P&lt;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">TC and RT, both low- and high-intensity training, can significantly increase muscle strength, reduce CRF and improve QoL in the middle-aged and elderly cancer patients. TC has a better effect than RT in terms of sleep quality and mental health. The long-term application is needed to substantiate the effect of TC as an alternative exercise in cancer patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Duan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, 210023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, 210023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, 210023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Ling-Li</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, 210023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, 210023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabiliation Medicine, Nanjing Jiangning Hospital, Nanjing, 211101, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Jiangsu Cancer Hospital, Nanjing, 210009, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiyuan Hospital, China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences, Beijing, 100091, China. guoyan0314@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing, 210023, China. pitx3@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Chin J Integr Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101181180</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1672-0415</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026302" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tai Ji</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tai chi</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer-related fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33420583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11655-021-3278-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11655-021-3278-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hickok JT, Roscoe JA, Morrow GR, Mustian K, Okunieff P, Bole CW, et al. Frequency, severity, clinical course, and correlates of fatigue in 372 patients during 5 weeks of radiotherapy for cancer. Cancer 2005;104:1772&#x2013;1778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.21364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digant G, Christopher G. James LF. The relationship between cancer-related fatigue and patient satisfaction with quality of life in cancer. J Pain Symptom Manag 2007;34:40&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2006.10.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mock V, Atkinson A, Barsevick A, Cella D, Cimprich B, Cleeland C, et al. NCCN practice guidelines for cancer-related fatigue: version 2000. Oncology 2000;14:151&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11195408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carole SM, Hsieh CC, Sprod LK, Carter SD, Hayward R. Effects of supervised exercise training on cardiopulmonary function and fatigue in breast cancer survivors during and after treatment. Cancer 2007;110:918&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.22862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller JT, Hartland MC, Maloney LT, Davison K. Therapeutic effects of aerobic and resistance exercises for cancer survivors: a systematic review of meta-analyses of clinical trials. Br J Sports Med 2018;52:1311&#x2013;1322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juvet LK, Thune I, Elvsaas IK, Fors EA, Lundgren S, Bertheussen G, et al. The effect of exercise on fatigue and physical functioning in breast cancer patients during and after treatment and at 6 months follow-up: a meta-analysis. Breast 2017;33:166&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.breast.2017.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessels E, Husson O, van der CM, Cornelis F. The effect of exercise on cancer-related fatigue in cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neuropsych Dis Treat 2018;14:479&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S150464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustian KM, Morrow GR, Carroll JK, Figueroa Moseley CD, Jean Pierre P, Williams GC, et al. Integrative nonpharmacologic behavioral interventions for the management of cancer-related fatigue. Oncologist 2007;12:52&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1634/theoncologist.12-S1-52</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauss D, Tjaden C, Hackert T, Schneider L, Ulrich CM, Wiskemann J, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness and muscle strength in pancreatic cancer patients. Supp Care Cancer 2017;25:2797&#x2013;2807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-017-3694-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano J, Hashizume K, Fukushima T, Ueno K, Matsuura E, Ikio Y, et al. Effects of aerobic and resistance exercises on physical symptoms in cancer patients: a meta-analysis. Integr Cancer Ther 2018;17:1048&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1534735418807555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan C, Chen SY, Wong MK, Lai JS. Tai Chi Chuan exercise for patients with cardiovascular disease. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med 2013;2013:983208&#x2013;983217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24348732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3855938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Guo Y. Traditional Chinese practice, a promising integrative intervention for chronic non-infectious disease management. Chin J Integr Med 2018;24:886&#x2013;890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11655-018-2572-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S, Yu J, Ruan Y, Liu X, Xiu L, Yue X, et al. Ameliorative effects of Tai Chi on cancer-related fatigue: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Supp Care Cancer 2018;26:2091&#x2013;2102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-018-4136-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni X, Chan RJ, Yates P, Hu W, Huang X, Lou Y. The effects of Tai Chi on quality of life of cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Supper Care Cancer 2019;27:3701&#x2013;3716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-019-04911-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas GN, Hong AWL, Tomlinson B, Lau E, Lam CWK, Sanderson JE, et al. Effects of Tai Chi and resistance training on cardiovascular risk factors in elderly Chinese subjects: a 12-month longitudinal, randomized, controlled intervention study. Clin Eneocrinol 2005;63:663&#x2013;669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2265.2005.02398.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen C, Williams JS, Chyu M, Paige RL, Stephens AL, Chauncey KB, et al. Comparison of the effects of Tai Chi and resistance training on bone metabolism in the elderly: a feasibility study. Am J Chin Med 2017;35:369&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0192415X07004898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winters-Stone KM, Li F, Horak F, Luoh S, Bennett JA, Nail L, et al. Comparison of Tai Chi vs. strength training for fall prevention among female cancer survivors: study protocol for the GET FIT trial. BMC Cancer 2012;12:577&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2407-12-577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza TR, Wang XS, Cleeland CS, Morrissey M, Johnson BA, Wendt JK, et al. The rapid assessment of fatigue severity in cancer patients: use of the Brief Fatigue Inventory. Cancer 1999;85:1186&#x2013;1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0142(19990301)85:5&lt;1186::AID-CNCR24&gt;3.0.CO;2-N</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyidova-Khoshknabi D, Davis MP, Walsh D. Systematic review of cancer-related fatigue measurement questionnaires. Am J Hosp Palliat Care 2011;28:119&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049909110381590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Collet JP, Lau J. The effect of Tai Chi on health outcomes in patients with chronic conditions. Arch Intern Med 2004;164:493&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.164.5.493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, Vechin FC, Conceicao MS, Damas F, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 2018;48:361&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0795-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza TR, Wang S, Cleeland CS, Morrissey M, Johnson BA, Wendt JK, et al. The rapid assessment of fatigue severity in cancer patients. Cancer 1999;85:1186&#x2013;1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0142(19990301)85:5&lt;1186::AID-CNCR24&gt;3.0.CO;2-N</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyne DJ, O&#x2019;Sullivan DE, Heer EV, Hilsden RJ, Sajobi TT, Cheung WY, et al. Prognostic factors of adjuvant chemotherapy discontinuation among stage M colon cancer patients: a survey of medical oncologists and a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cancer Med 2020;9:1613&#x2013;1627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.2843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Sawada M, Noriyama Y, Arita K, Ota T, Sadamatsu M, et al. Tai Chi exercise versus rehabilitation for the elderly with cerebral vascular disorder: a single-blinded randomized controlled trial. Psychogeriatrics 2010;10:160&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1479-8301.2010.00334.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, Lowe B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med 2006;166:1092&#x2013;1097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oechsle K, Ullrich A, Marx G, Benze G, Wowretzko F, Zhang YY, et al. Prevalence and predictors of distress, anxiety, depression, and quality of life in bereaved family caregivers of patients with advanced cancer. Am J Hosp Palliat Med 2020;37:201&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049909119872755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Int Med 2001;16:606&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocalevent RD, Hinz A, Brahler E. Standardization of the depression screener patient health questionnaire (PHQ-9) in the general population. J Gen Hosp Psychiat 2013;35:551&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2013.04.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorsen L, Nilsen TS, Raastad T, Courneya KS, Skovlund E, Fossa SD, et al. A randomized controlled trial on the effectiveness of strength training on clinical and muscle cellular outcomes in patients with prostate cancer during androgen deprivation therapy: rationale and design. BMC Cancer 2012;12:123&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2407-12-123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horneber M, Fischer I, Dimeo F, Ruffer JU, Weis J. Cancer-related fatigue: epidemiology, pathogenesis, diagnosis, and treatment. Dtsch Arztebl Int 2012;109:161&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3314239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider CM, Hsieh CC, Sprod LK, Carter SD, Hayward R. Exercise training manages cardiopulmonary function and fatigue during and following cancer treatment in male cancer survivors. Integr Cancer Ther 2016;6:235&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1534735407305871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider CM, Hsieh CC, Sprod LK, Carter SD, Hayward R. Cancer treatment-induced alterations in muscular fitness and quality of life: the role of exercise training. Ann Oncol 2007;18:1957&#x2013;1962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdm364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Backer IC, Vreugdenhil G, Nijziel MR, Kester AD, van Breda E, Schep G. Long-term follow-up after cancer rehabilitation using high-intensity resistance training: persistent improvement of physical performance and quality of life. Br J Cancer 2008;99:30&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.bjc.6604433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janelsins MC, Davis PG, Wideman L, Katula JA, Sprod LK, Peppone LJ, et al. Effects of Tai Chi Chuan on insulin and cytokine levels in a randomized controlled pilot study on breast cancer survivors. Clin Br Cancer 2011;11:161&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clbc.2011.03.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan GE, Perri MG, Theriaque DW, Hutson AD, Eckel RH, Stacpoole PW, et al. Exercise training, without weight loss, increases insulin sensitivity and post-heparin plasma lipase activity in previously sedentary adults. Diabetes Care 2003;26:557&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.26.3.557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu WH, Hsu RWW, Lin ZR, Fan CH. Effects of circuit exercise and Tai Chi on body composition in middle-aged and older women. Geriatr Gerontol Int 2015;15:282&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ggi.12270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren XM, Li YD, Yang XY, Li J, Li HL, Yuan ZZ, et al. The effects of Tai Chi training in patients with heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol 2017;8:989&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wayne Peter M, Lee MS, Novakowski KJ, Ligibel OJ, Carlson LE, et al. Tai Chi and Qigong for cancer-related symptoms and quality of life: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cancer Surv 2018;12:256&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-017-0665-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>