<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34567354</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Influence of a Total Body Resistance Training Program on Autonomic Modulation and Strength Variables in Young Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>802</StartPage><EndPage>814</EndPage><MedlinePgn>802-814</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this study was to examine autonomic modulation using multiple quantitative measures before and after a resistance training (RT) intervention. Seventeen young adults (age 18-35 years) were tested for body composition, muscular strength, and autonomic activity. The RT protocol targeted total-body large muscle groups, which were performed three days a week for eight-weeks. Autonomic assessments included respiratory sinus arrhythmia (RSA), static handgrip exercise, Valsalva maneuver, heart rate variability (HRV), and tilt-table testing. The main finding was that tilt-table duration increased by 68 seconds (<i>p</i> = 0.05) after RT. Upper body strength increased by 11.2 kg (<i>p</i> = 0.001) and lower body strength increased by 68.3 kg (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001) following completion of the RT intervention. The average total lean mass increased by 1.5 kg (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.01), while total fat mass was unchanged (&#x394; = 0.5 kg, <i>p</i> = 0.23). RSA (&#x394; = 0.4, <i>p</i> = 0.89), Valsalva ratio (&#x394; = -0.09, <i>p</i> = 0.48), static handgrip (&#x394; = 8 mm Hg, <i>p</i> = 0.07), and HRV (&#x394; = -0.4, <i>p</i> = 0.53) were not affected by RT. The results from this study suggest that RT improves tilt-table tolerance in a young healthy population as evidence by improved tilt-table duration. However, RT seemed to have no effect on cardio-vagal or adrenergic function.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altherr</LastName><ForeName>Cody A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Exercise Physiology Laboratory, School of Kinesiology, Ball State University, Muncie, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Exercise Physiology Laboratory, School of Kinesiology, Ball State University, Muncie, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soave</LastName><ForeName>Kayla M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Exercise Physiology Laboratory, School of Kinesiology, Ball State University, Muncie, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagelkirk</LastName><ForeName>Paul R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Exercise Physiology Laboratory, School of Kinesiology, Ball State University, Muncie, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Pozzi</LastName><ForeName>Andrew T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative Exercise Physiology Laboratory, School of Kinesiology, Ball State University, Muncie, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthostatic tolerance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tilt-table testing</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34567354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8439684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/JKPQ5969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-14-2-802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Baltimore, MD: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Indianapolis, IN: Wolters Kluwer; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anton MM, Cortez-Cooper MY, DeVan AE, Neidre DB, Cook JN, Tanaka H. Resistance training increases basal limb blood flow and vascular conductance in aging humans. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101(5):1351&#x2013;1355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16840576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benrud-Larson LM, Dewar MS, Sandroni P, Rummans TA, Haythornthwaite JA, Low PA. Quality of life in patients with postural tachycardia syndrome. Mayo Clin Proc. 2002;77(6):531&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12059122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, Ragg KE, Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Staron RS. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(1&#x2013;2):50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter JR, Ray CA, Downs EM, Cooke WH. Strength training reduces arterial blood pressure but not sympathetic neural activity in young normotensive subjects. J Appl Physiol. 2003;94(6):2212&#x2013;2216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carthy ER. Autonomic dysfunction in essential hypertension: A systematic review. Ann Med Surg. 2014;3(1):2&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4268473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25568776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier S, Kanaley J, Carhart R, Jr, Frechette V, Tobin M, Bennett N, Luckenbaugh A, Fernhall B. Cardiac autonomic function and baroreflex changes following 4 weeks of resistance versus aerobic training in individuals with pre-hypertension. Acta Physiol. 2009;195(3):339&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18774947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Convertino VA. Gender differences in autonomic functions associated with blood pressure regulation. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 1998;275(6):R1909&#x2013;R1920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9843880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke WH, Carter JR. Strength training does not affect vagal&#x2013;cardiac control or cardiovagal baroreflex sensitivity in young healthy subjects. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;93(5&#x2013;6):719&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15517338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordina RL, O'Meagher S, Karmali A, Rae CL, Liess C, Kemp GJ, Puranik R, Singh N, Celermajer DS. Resistance training improves cardiac output, exercise capacity, and tolerance to positive airway pressure in Fontan physiology. Int J Cardiol. 2013;168(2):780&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23154055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C. The development of skeletal muscle hypertrophy through resistance training: The role of muscle damage and muscle protein synthesis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(3):485&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29282529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Smith B, Jacobsen DJ, Kirk E, DuBose K, Hyder M, Bailey B, Washburn R. The role of exercise for weight loss and maintenance. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2004;18(6):1009&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15561636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JM, Ziegler MG, Patwardhan AR, Ott JB, Kim CS, Leonelli FM, Knapp CF. Gender differences in autonomic cardiovascular regulation: Spectral, hormonal, and hemodynamic indexes. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91(6):2611&#x2013;2618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11717226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedorowski A, Ricci F, Sutton R. Orthostatic hypotension and cardiovascular risk. Kardiol Pol. 2019;77(11):1020&#x2013;1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31713533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K, Kanazawa H, Aizawa Y, Ardell JL, Shivkumar K. Cardiac innervation and sudden cardiac death. Circ Res. 2015;116(12):2005&#x2013;2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26044253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerhart H, Tai YL, Fennell C, Mayo X, Kingsley JD. Autonomic modulation in older women: Using resistance exercise as a countermeasure. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10(2):178&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5360374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28344732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberger JJ. Sympathovagal balance: How should we measure it? Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 1999;276(4):H1273&#x2013;H1280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10199852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Osburn SC, Mumford PW, Roberson PA, Romero MA, Fox CD, Johnson CA, Parry HA, Kavazis AN, Moon JR, Badisa VLD, Mwashote BM, Ibeanusi V, Young KC, Roberts MD. Muscle fiber hypertrophy in response to 6 weeks of high-volume resistance training in trained young men is largely attributed to sarcoplasmic hypertrophy. PLoS One. 2019;14(6):e0215267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31166954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K, Naiki T. Adaptation and remodeling of vascular wall; biomechanical response to hypertension. J Mech Behav Biomed Mater. 2009;2(1):3&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19627803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan KS, Fahs CA, Shinsako KK, Jae SY, Fernhall B. Heart rate recovery and heart rate complexity following resistance exercise training and detraining in young men. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2007;293(5):H3180&#x2013;3186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan KS, Sosnoff J, Jae S, Gates G, Fernhall B. Acute resistance exercise reduces heart rate complexity and increases qtc interval. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29(4):289&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17990212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwasaki K-i, Zhang R, Zuckerman JH, Levine BD. Dose-response relationship of the cardiovascular adaptation to endurance training in healthy adults: How much training for what benefit? J Appl Physiol. 2003;95(4):1575&#x2013;1583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12832429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izzard AS, Rizzoni D, Agabiti-Rosei E, Heagerty AM. Small artery structure and hypertension: Adaptive changes and target organ damage. J Hypertens. 2005;23(2):247&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15662208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannel WB, Brand N, Skinner JJ, Jr, Dawber TR, McNamara PM. The relation of adiposity to blood pressure and development of hypertension. The Framingham study. Ann Intern Med. 1967;67(1):48&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6028658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khurana RK, Setty A. The value of the isometric hand-grip test--studies in various autonomic disorders. Clin Auton Res. 1996;6(4):211&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8902317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley JD, Figueroa A. Acute and training effects of resistance exercise on heart rate variability. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2016;36(3):179&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25524332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, Dudley GA, Dooly C, Feigenbaum MS, Fleck SJ, Franklin B, Fry AC, Hoffman JR, Newton RU, Potteiger J, Stone MH, Ratamess NA, Triplett-McBride T American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(2):364&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Korthuis RJ, Duncker DJ, Bache RJ. Comprehensive Physiology. American Physiological Society; 2010. Control of blood flow to cardiac and skeletal muscle during exercise; pp. 705&#x2013;769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical issues relating to scientific discovery in exercise science. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak P. Quantitative autonomic testing. JoVE. 2011;53:e2502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21788940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel N, Choudhary N, Tompkins C, Ammar KA, Tajik AJ, Chandrasekaran K, Paterick TE. Syncope in young women: Broadening the differential diagnosis. Rev Cardiovas Med. 2017;18(3):100&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29111543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandercock GRH, Bromley P, Brodie DA. Reliability of three commercially available heart rate variability instruments using short-term (5-min) recordings. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2004;24(6):359&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15522045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuenke MD, Herman JR, Gliders RM, Hagerman FC, Hikida RS, Rana SR, Ragg KE, Staron RS. Early-phase muscular adaptations in response to slow-speed versus traditional resistance-training regimens. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(10):3585&#x2013;3595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott JM, Jones LW, Hornsby WE, Koelwyn GJ, Khouri MG, Joy AA, Douglas PS, Lakoski SG. Cancer therapy-induced autonomic dysfunction in early breast cancer: Implications for aerobic exercise training. Int J Cardiol. 2014;171(2):e50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4116686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24365613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheriff DD. Muscle pump function during locomotion: Mechanical coupling of stride frequency and muscle blood flow. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2003;284(6):H2185&#x2013;H2191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12742830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sims ST, Heather AK. Myths and methodologies: Reducing scientific design ambiguity in studies comparing sexes and/or menstrual cycle phases. Exp Physiol. 2018;103(10):1309&#x2013;1317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slordahl S, Madslien VO, Stoylen A, Kjos A, Helgerud J, Wisloff U. Atrioventricular plane displacement in untrained and trained females. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(11):1871&#x2013;1875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15514500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart JM, Medow MS, Montgomery LD, McLeod K. Decreased skeletal muscle pump activity in patients with postural tachycardia syndrome and low peripheral blood flow. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2004;286(3):H1216&#x2013;1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14576081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart JM, Medow MS, Sutton R, Visintainer P, Jardine DL, Wieling W. Mechanisms of vasovagal syncope in the young: Reduced systemic vascular resistance versus reduced cardiac output. J Am Heart Assoc. 2017;6(1):e004417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5523632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28100453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira EL, Painelli VS, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva-Batista C, Longo AR, Aihara AY, Cardoso FN, Peres BA, Tricoli V. Perceptual and neuromuscular responses adapt similarly between high-load resistance training and low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Strength Cond Res Epub. 2020 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas JR, Salazar W, Landers DM. What is missing in p&lt;. 05? Effect size. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1991;62(3):344&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1925064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Gestel AJ, Steier J. Autonomic dysfunction in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) J Thorac Dis. 2010;2(4):215&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3256465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22263050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallin BG, Charkoudian N. Sympathetic neural control of integrated cardiovascular function: Insights from measurement of human sympathetic nerve activity. Muscle Nerve. 2007;36(5):595&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17623856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: Effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11(4):209&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winker R, Barth A, Bidmon D, Ponocny I, Weber M, Mayr O, Robertson D, Diedrich A, Maier R, Pilger A. Endurance exercise training in orthostatic intolerance: A randomized, controlled trial. Hypertension. 2005;45(3):391&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zygmunt A, Stanczyk J. Methods of evaluation of autonomic nervous system function. Arch Med Sci. 2010;6(1):11&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22371714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>