<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27601778</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A comparison of low volume 'high-intensity-training' and high volume traditional resistance training methods on muscular performance, body composition, and subjective assessments of training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>241</StartPage><EndPage>249</EndPage><MedlinePgn>241-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5604/20831862.1201813</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Most studies of resistance training (RT) examine methods that do not resemble typical training practices of persons participating in RT. Ecologically valid RT programs more representative of such practices are seldom compared. This study compared two such approaches to RT. Thirty participants (males, n = 13; females, n = 17) were randomised to either a group performing low volume 'High Intensity Training' (HIT; n = 16) or high volume 'Body-building' (3ST; n = 14) RT methods 2x/week for 10 weeks. Outcomes included muscular performance, body composition, and participant's subjective assessments. Both HIT and 3ST groups improved muscular performance significantly (as indicated by 95% confidence intervals) with large effect sizes (ES; 0.97 to 1.73 and 0.88 to 1.77 respectively). HIT had significantly greater muscular performance gains for 3 of 9 tested exercises compared with 3ST (p &lt; 0.05) and larger effect sizes for 8 of 9 exercises. Body composition did not significantly change in either group. However, effect sizes for whole body muscle mass changes were slightly more favourable in the HIT group compared with the 3ST group (0.27 and -0.34 respectively) in addition to whole body fat mass (0.03 and 0.43 respectively) and whole body fat percentage (-0.10 and -0.44 respectively). Significant muscular performance gains can be produced using either HIT or 3ST. However, muscular performance gains may be greater when using HIT. Future research should look to identify which components of ecologically valid RT programs are primarily responsible for these differences in outcome.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giessing</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Sportwissenschaft, University of Koblenz-Landau, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eichmann</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Sportwissenschaft, University of Koblenz-Landau, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steele</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health, Exercise and Sport Science, Southampton Solent University, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fisher</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health, Exercise and Sport Science, Southampton Solent University, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drop-sets</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscular failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Repetition maximum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Volitional fatigue</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2016</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27601778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4993139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/20831862.1201813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1201813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Loenneke JP, Loprinzi PD. Am J Health Promot. 2016. Combined associations of muscle-strengthening activities and accelerometer-assessed physical activity on multimorbidity: Findings from NHANES. Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26730562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Loenneke JP, Loprinzi PD. Participation in muscle-strengthening activites as an altenrative method for the prevention of multimorbidity. Prev Med. 2015;81:54&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26264252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Loenneke JP, Loprinzi PD. Lower extremeity strength, systemic inflammation and all-cause mortality: Application to the &#x201c;fat but fit&#x201d; paradigm using cross-sectional and longitudinal designs. Physiol Behav. 2015;149:199&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26072175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Loenneke JP, Loprinzi PD. Mayo Clin Proc. 2015. Determining the importance of meeting muscle-strengthening activity guidelines: Is the behaviour or the outcome of the behaviour (Strength) a more important determinant of all-cause mortality? Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26723715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Kupelian V, Visser M, Simonsick EM, Goodpaster BH, Kritchevsky SB, Tylavsky FA, Rubin SM, Harris TB. Strength, but not muscle mass, is associated with mortality in the health, aging and body composition study cohort. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61(1):72&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Sui X, Lobelo F, Morrow JR, Jackson JW, Sjostrom M, Blair SN. Association between muscular strength and mortality in men: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2008;337:439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2453303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artero EG, Lee DC, Ruiz JR, Sui X, Ortega FB, Church TS, Lavie CJ, Castillo MJ, Balir SN. A prospective study of muscular strength and all-cause mortality in men with hypertension. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;57(18):1831&#x2013;1837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3098120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srikanthan P, Karlamangla AS. Muscle mass index as a predictor of longevity in older adults. Am J Med. 2014;127(6):547&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24561114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli RN, Otto RM. Strength training: single versus multiple sets. Sports Med. 1998;26(2):73&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9777681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith D, Bruce-Low S. Strength training methods and the work of Arthur Jones. J Exerc Physiol. 2004;7(6):52&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Burkett LN, Ball SD. A meta-analysis to determine the dose response for strength development. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(3):456&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Maximizing strength development in athletes: a meta-analysis to determine the dose-response relationship. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(2):377&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe BL, LeMura LM, Cole PJ. Quantitative analysis of single- vs multiple-set programs in resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(1):35&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winett RA. Meta-analyses do not support performance of multiple sets or high volume resistance training. J Exerc Physiol. 2004;7(5):10&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto RM, Carpinelli RN. A critical analysis of the single versus multiple set debate. J Exerc Physiol. 2006;9(1):32&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise: a meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(6):1890&#x2013;1901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frohlich M, Emrich E, Schmidtbleicher D. Outcome effects of single-set versus multiple-set training &#x2013; an advanced replication study. Res Sports Med. 2010;18:157&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20623433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(4):1150&#x2013;1159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli RN. Critical review of a meta-analysis for the effect of single and multiple sets of resistance training on strength gains. Medicina Sportiva. 2012;16(3):122&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J. Beware the meta-analysis: is multiple set training really better than single set training for muscle hypertrophy? J Exerc Physiol. 2012;15(6):23&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. Evidence-Based Resistance Training Recommendations. Medicina Sportiva. 2011;15(3):147&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. Evidence-based resistance training recommendations for muscular hypertrophy. Medicina Sportiva. 2013;17(4):217&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PWM, McEwen M, Robbins DW. Strength and neuromuscular adaptation following on, four, and eight sets of high intensity resistance exercise in trained males. Eur J Apply Physiol. 2011;111:3007&#x2013;3016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21451937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Fleck SJ, Leite T, Leite RD, Pinto RS, Fernandes L, Simao R. J Strength Cond Res. 2014. Does respsonse of 1, 3 and 5 sets of resistance exercise on strength, local muscular endurance and hypertrophy. Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25546444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Botton CE, Wilhelm EN, Bottaro M, Brown LE, Lacerda F, Gaya A, Moraes K, Peruzzolo A, Pinto RS. Time course of low- and high-volume strength training on neuromuscular adaptations and muscle quality in older women. Age. 2014;36:881&#x2013;892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4039257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24414336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Wilhelm EN, Botton CE, Rech A, Bottaro M, Brown LE, Pinto RS. Effects of single vs. multiple-set short-term strength training in elderly women. Age. 2014;36(6):9720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4214965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25358552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raedelli R, Wilhelm EN, Botton CE, Bottaro M, Cadore EL, Brown LE, Pinto RS. Effect of two difference strength training volumes on muscle hypertrophy and quality in elderly women. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2013;53(Suppl1-3):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raedelli R, Botton CE, Wilhelm EN, Bottaro M, Lacerda F, Gaya A, Moraes K, Peruzzolo A, Brown LE, Pinto RS. Low- and high-volume strength training induces similar neuromuscular improvements in muscle quality in elderly women. Exp Gerontol. 2013;48(8):710&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23603619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadir ZA, Nadzalan AM, Yusof SM, Aiman S, Shapie MNM. Single- versus three-set resistance training on strength and power among untrained men. In: Adnan R, Ismail SI, Sulaiman N, editors. Proceedings of the International Colloquium on Sports Science, Exercise, Engineering and Technology 2014 (ICoSSEET 2014) London: Springer; 2014. pp. 177&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adnan MA, Kadir ZA, Yusof SM, Mazaulan M, Mohamed MAAR. Single versus two sets of resistance training on muscular endurance, strength and fat percentages among recreationally trained men. In: Adnan R, Ismail SI, Sulaiman N, editors. Proceedings of the International Colloquium on Sports Science, Exercise, Engineering and Technology 2014 (ICoSSEET 2014) London: Springer; 2014. pp. 249&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa CS, Teixeira BC, Bittencourt A, Lemos L, Marques NR, Radaelli R, Kruger RL, Reischak-Oliveira A, Pinto RS. Effects of high and low volume of strength training on muscle strength, muscle volume and lipid profile in postmenopausal women. J Exerc Sci Fitness. 2014;12(2):62&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker JS, Davies D, Cooper SM, Wong DP, Buchan DS, Kilgore L. BioMed Res Int. 2013. Strength and body composition changes I recreationally strength-trained individuals: comparison of one versus three sets resistance-training programmes.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3780552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24083231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giessing J, Preuss P, Greiwing A, Goebel S, Muller A, Schischek A, Stephan A. Fundamental definitions of decisive training parameters of single-set training and multiple-set training for muscle hypertrophy. In: Giessing J, Frohlich M, Preuss P, editors. Current Results of Strength Training Research. Goettingen: Cuvillier; 2005. pp. 9&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J. Intensity; in-ten-si-ty; noun. 1. Often used ambiguously within resistance training. 2. Is it time to drop the term altogether? Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1586&#x2013;1588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23403526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duehring MD, Feldmann CR, Ebben WP. Strength and conditioning practices of united states high school strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(8):2188&#x2013;2203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19826308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durrell DL, Pujol TJ, Barnes JT. A survey of the scientific data and training methods utilized by collegiate strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(2):268&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Blackard DO. Strength and conditioning practices of national football league strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15(1):48&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Carroll RM, Simenz CJ. Strength and conditioning practices of national hockey league strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(4):889&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Hintz MJ, Simenz CJ. Strength and conditioning practices of major league baseball strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;19(3):538&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simenz CJ, Dugan CA, Ebben WP. Strength and conditioning practices of national basketball association strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(3):495&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A. Nautilus bulletin #1. DeLand, FL: Nautilus Sports/Medical Industries; 1970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A. Nautilus bulletin #2. DeLand, FL: Nautilus Sports/Medical Industries; 1971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darden E. The Nautilus Book. McGraw Hill; 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darden E. The Nautilus Bodybulding Book. McGraw Hill; 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darden E. The New High Intensity Training. Rodale; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryzcki M. A Practical Approach to Strength Training. Blue River Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, Dudley DA, Dooly C, Feigenbaum MS, Fleck SJ, Franklin B, Fry AC, Hoffman JR, Newton RU, Potteiger J, Stone MH, Ratamess NA, Triplett-McBride T. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(2):364&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giessing J. How intense are your weight training workouts? NSCA's Performance Training J. 2007;6:11&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM. The application of training to failure in periodized multiple-set resistance exercise training programs. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:628&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC, Kraemer WJ. Resistance exercise overtraining and overreaching: neuroendocrine responses. Sports Med. 1997;23(2):106&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9068095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow C. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(6):1609&#x2013;1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22990567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JB, Stone MH, O'Bryant HS, Conley MS, Johnson RL, Nieman DC, Honeycutt DR, Hoke TP. Effects of single vs. multiple sets of weight training: impact of volume, intensity, and variation. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(3):143&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee D, Jessee TC, Stone MH, Blessing D. Leg and hip endurance adaptations to three-weight programs. J Appl Sport Sci Res. 1992;6(2):92&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanborn K, Boros R, Hruby J, Schilling B, O'Bryant HS, Johnson RL, Hoke T, Stone ME, Stone MH. Short-term performance effects of weight training with multiple sets not to failure vs. a single set to failure in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14(3):328&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stowers T, McMillan J, Scala D, Davis V, Wilson D, Stone M. The short-term effects of three difference strength-power training methods. NSCA J. 1983;5(3):24&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, McGuff D, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. Resistance training to momentary muscular failure improves cardiovascular fitness in humans: a review of acute physiological responses and chronic physiological adaptations. J Exerc Physiol. 2012;15(3):53&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112:155&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitley E, Ball J. Statistics review 4: sample size calculations. Crit Care. 2002;6:335&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC137461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12225610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leahy S, O'Neil C, Sohun R, Jakeman P. A comparison of dual energy X-ray absorptiometry and bioelectrical impedance analysis to measure total and segmental body composition in healthy young adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:589&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21614505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browning LM, Mugridge O, Dixon AK, Aitken SW, Prentice AM, Jebb SA. Measuring abdominal adipose tissue: comparison of simpler methods with MRI. Obes Facts. 2011;4:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21372606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of Strength and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli R. Assessment of one repetition maximum (1RM) and 1RM prediction equations: Are they really necessary? Medicina Sportiva. 2011;15(2):91&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. The use of specialized training techniques to maximize muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J. 2011;33(4):60&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Nagasawa M, Yanagisawa O, Kizuka T, Ishii N, Takamatsu K. Muscular adaptation to combinations of high- and low-intensity resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(4):730&#x2013;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Halaki M, Chow CM. A novel scale to assess resistance-exercise effort. J Sports Sci. 2012;30:1405&#x2013;1413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22873691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giessing J, Fisher J, Steele J, Rothe F, Raubold K, Eichmann B. The effects of low volume resistance training with and without advanced techniques in trained participants. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2016;56(3):249&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:2857&#x2013;2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 2013;43:179&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23338987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Garzarella L, De Hoyos D, Pollock ML. Single versus multiple sets in long term recreational weightlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(1):235&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock ML. Prescribing exercise for fitness and adherence. In: Dishman RK, editor. Exercise Adherence: Its Impacts on Public Health. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1988. pp. 259&#x2013;277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung ME, Bourne JE, Little JP. Where does HIT fit? An examination of the affective response to high-intervals in comparison to continuous moderate- and vigorous-intensity exercise in the exercise intensity-affect continuum. PLoS One. 2014;8(9):e114541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4259348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25486273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez N, Kilpatrick MW, Salomon K, Jung ME, Little JP. Affective and enjoyment responses to high-intensity interval training in overweight-to-obese and insufficiently active adults. J Sport Exerc Psychol. 2015;37(2):138&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25996105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, Price TB, Hoffman EP, Angelopoulos TJ, Gordon PM, Moyna NM, Pescatello LS, Visich PS, Zoeller RF, Seip RL, Clarkson PM. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(6):964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>