<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40761992</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Activity as a Lifestyle Intervention for Type 1 Diabetics: A Comprehensive Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e87351</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e87351</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e87351</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.87351</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this study was to assess the influence of aerobic and resistance training on anthropometric measures such as body mass index, body weight, fat mass, and fat-free mass among type 1 diabetics. A thorough literature review was performed on PubMed. Our search yielded 196 articles. We included eight studies that dealt with type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM) patients who met our inclusion criteria and consisted of randomized controlled trials, systematic reviews, and meta-analyses. This review article found that resistance exercise increased muscle mass and reduced fat mass in T1DM patients. Increasing the duration and intensity of physical activity led to an increase in fat-free mass. Parental support among type 1 diabetic children showed positive attitudes towards a healthy lifestyle. Addressing stigma among adolescents with T1DM is important, and personal and community knowledge about the condition can help facilitate physical activity participation. Collaboration between healthcare providers, families, and peers is essential in managing physical activity in T1DM patients. Having a staff member with specific training to provide physical activity advice can benefit diabetes teams. Further research over a longer duration is necessary to confirm these outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Alzahrani et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alzahrani</LastName><ForeName>Noha A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Preventive Medicine, Ministry of National Guard-Health Affairs, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdulwahab</LastName><ForeName>Ihdaa J</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Preventive Medicine, Ministry of National Guard-Health Affairs, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alotaybi</LastName><ForeName>Moteab S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Preventive Medicine, Ministry of National Guard, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Albogami</LastName><ForeName>Abdulaziz</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Dentistry, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, SAU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body weight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thinness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 1 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40761992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12321317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.87351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Global incidence, prevalence, and mortality of type 1 diabetes in 2021 with projection to 2040: a modelling study. Gregory GA, Robinson TI, Linklater SE, et al. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2022;10:741&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36113507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of type 1 diabetes mellitus on skeletal muscle: clinical observations and physiological mechanisms. Krause MP, Riddell MC, Hawke TJ. Pediatr Diabetes. 2011;12:345&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20860561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerobic as well as resistance exercises are good for patients with type 1 diabetes. Wr&#xf3;bel M, Rokicka D, Czuba M, et al. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2018;144:93&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30121304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of lifestyle intervention in patients with type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis. Chen L, Pei JH, Kuang J, Chen HM, Chen Z, Li ZW, Yang HZ. Metabolism. 2015;64:338&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25467842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of exercise training on cardiorespiratory fitness and biomarkers of cardiometabolic health: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Lin X, Zhang X, Guo J, et al. J Am Heart Assoc. 2015;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4608087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26116691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise interventions in adults with type 1 diabetes. Yardley JE, Hay J, Abou-Setta AM, Marks SD, McGavock J. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2014;106:393&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25451913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity/exercise and diabetes: a Position Statement of the American Diabetes Association. Colberg SR, Sigal RJ, Yardley JE, et al. Diabetes Care. 2016;39:2065&#x2013;2079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27926890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Substrate metabolism during different exercise intensities in endurance-trained women. Romijn JA, Coyle EF, Sidossis LS, Rosenblatt J, Wolfe RR. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2000;88:1707&#x2013;1714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity and mortality in individuals with diabetes mellitus: a prospective study and meta-analysis. Sluik D, Buijsse B, Muckelbauer R, et al. Arch Intern Med. 2012;172:1285&#x2013;1295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22868663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What are the health benefits of physical activity in type 1 diabetes mellitus? A literature review. Chimen M, Kennedy A, Nirantharakumar K, Pang TT, Andrews R, Narendran P. Diabetologia. 2012;55:542&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22189486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity interventions in children and young people with Type 1 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Quirk H, Blake H, Tennyson R, Randell TL, Glazebrook C. Diabet Med. 2014;31:1163&#x2013;1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4232875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24965376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combined aerobic and resistance training performed under conditions of normobaric hypoxia and normoxia has the same impact on metabolic control in men with type 1 diabetes. Wr&#xf3;bel M, Rokicka D, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A, et al. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:13058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8701162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34948667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benefits of physical activity in children and adolescents with type 1 diabetes: a systematic review. Absil H, Baudet L, Robert A, Lysy PA. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2019;156:107810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31401153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glycemic, inflammatory and oxidative stress responses to different high-intensity training protocols in type 1 diabetes: a randomized clinical trial. Farinha JB, Ramis TR, Vieira AF, et al. J Diabetes Complications. 2018;32:1124&#x2013;1132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30270019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical outcomes to exercise training in type 1 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ostman C, Jewiss D, King N, Smart NA. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2018;139:380&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29223408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise training improves but does not normalize left ventricular systolic and diastolic function in adolescents with type 1 diabetes. Gusso S, Pinto T, Baldi JC, Derraik JG, Cutfield WS, Hornung T, Hofman PL. Diabetes Care. 2017;40:1264&#x2013;1272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28720592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is exercise a therapeutic tool for improvement of cardiovascular risk factors in adolescents with type 1 diabetes mellitus? A randomised controlled trial. Salem MA, AboElAsrar MA, Elbarbary NS, ElHilaly RA, Refaat YM. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2010;2:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3238209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of long-term swimming program on glycemia control in 14-19-year aged healthy girls and girls with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Sideravici&#x16b;te S, Gaili&#x16b;niene A, Visagurskiene K, Vizbaraite D. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16816547/ Medicina (Kaunas) 2006;42:513&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16816547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise training and cardiovascular risk factors in type 1 diabetic adolescent girls. Heyman E, Toutain C, Delamarche P, et al. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2007;19:408&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18089908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Experimental study on physical exercise in diabetes: pathophysiology and therapeutic effects. Messina G, Alioto A, Parisi MC, et al. Eur J Transl Myol. 2023;33:11560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37817671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise training and glycemic control in adolescents with poorly controlled type 1 diabetes mellitus. Roberts L, Jones TW, Fournier PA. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2002;15:621&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12014521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerobic circuit exercise training: effect on adolescents with well-controlled insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. Mosher PE, Nash MS, Perry AC, LaPerriere AR, Goldberg RB. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1998;79:652&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9630144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity and sedentary behavior in adolescents with type 1 diabetes. Michaliszyn SF, Faulkner MS. Res Nurs Health. 2010;33:441&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4354709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20672318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise management in type 1 diabetes: a consensus statement. Riddell MC, Gallen IW, Smart CE, et al.  https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S2213858717300141. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2017;5:377&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28126459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A combined insulin reduction and carbohydrate feeding strategy 30 min before running best preserves blood glucose concentration after exercise through improved fuel oxidation in type 1 diabetes mellitus. West DJ, Stephens JW, Bain SC, Kilduff LP, Luzio S, Still R, Bracken RM. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:279&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21154013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resistance versus aerobic exercise: acute effects on glycemia in type 1 diabetes. Yardley JE, Kenny GP, Perkins BA, et al. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:537&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3579339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23172972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anticipated basal insulin reduction to prevent exercise-induced hypoglycemia in adults and adolescents living with type 1 diabetes. Tagougui S, Legault L, Heyman E, et al. Diabetes Technol Ther. 2022;24:307&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35099281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Personalized exercise for adolescents with diabetes or obesity. Faulkner MS, Michaliszyn SF, Hepworth JT, Wheeler MD. Biol Res Nurs. 2014;16:46&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4354702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23965300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parental correlates of physical activity in children and early adolescents. Gustafson SL, Rhodes RE. Sports Med. 2006;36:79&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16445312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating a model of parental influence on youth physical activity. Trost SG, Sallis JF, Pate RR, Freedson PS, Taylor WC, Dowda M. Am J Prev Med. 2003;25:277&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14580627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Associations of parental influence and 10-11-year-old children's physical activity: are they mediated by children's perceived competence and attraction to physical activity? M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4; S, Ray C, Roos E. Scand J Public Health. 2014;42:45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24026356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of correlates of physical activity of children and adolescents. Sallis JF, Prochaska JJ, Taylor WC. https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Judith-Prochaska/publication/12521182_'A_Review_of_Correlates_of_Physical_Activity_of_Children_and_Adolescents'/links/5da12881a6fdcc8fc3491b40/A-Review-of-Correlates-of-Physical-Activity-of-Children-and-Adolescents.pdf. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:963&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10795788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correlates of physical activity in youth: a review of quantitative systematic reviews. Biddle SJH, Atkin AJ, Cavill N, Foster C. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2011;23:25&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>"You can't just jump on a bike and go": a qualitative study exploring parents' perceptions of physical activity in children with type 1 diabetes. Quirk H, Blake H, Dee B, Glazebrook C. BMC Pediatr. 2014;14:313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4297408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25526774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The challenges of being physically active: a qualitative study of young people with type 1 diabetes and their parents. Fried L, Chetty T, Cross D, et al. Can J Diabetes. 2021;45:421&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33223421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriers to physical activity among patients with type 1 diabetes. Brazeau AS, Rabasa-Lhoret R, Strychar I, Mircescu H. Diabetes Care. 2008;31:2108&#x2013;2109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2571055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18689694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The meaning of living with a long-term disease. To revalue and be revalued. Lundman B, Jansson L. J Clin Nurs. 2007;16:109&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17584419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The fight against stigma: an overview of stigma-reduction strategies and interventions. Heijnders M, Van Der Meij S. http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/13548500600595327. Psychol Health Med. 2006;11:353&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17130071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peer victimization among school-aged children with chronic conditions. Sentenac M, Arnaud C, Gavin A, Molcho M, Gabhainn SN, Godeau E. Epidemiol Rev. 2012;34:120&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A meta-analytic test of intergroup contact theory. Pettigrew TF, Tropp LR. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2006;90:751&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16737372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development and psychometric evaluation of the Chronic Illness Anticipated Stigma Scale. Earnshaw VA, Quinn DM, Kalichman SC, Park CL. J Behav Med. 2013;36:270&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4370181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22526525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypoglycaemia, fear of hypoglycaemia and quality of life in children with Type 1 diabetes and their parents. Johnson SR, Cooper MN, Davis EA, Jones TW. Diabet Med. 2013;30:1126&#x2013;1131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23808967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan CJ. Albert Bandura Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey: Prentice Hall, 1986, xiii + 617 pp. Hardback. US$39.50. Behav change [Internet. Vol. 25. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall; 1986. Social Foundations of Thought and Action: A Social Cognitive Theory; pp. 37&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>"Having diabetes shouldn't stop them": healthcare professionals' perceptions of physical activity in children with Type 1 diabetes. Quirk H, Blake H, Dee B, Glazebrook C. BMC Pediatr. 2015;15:68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26084937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parental socialization of child and adolescent physical activity: a meta-analysis. Pugliese J, Tinsley B. J Fam Psychol. 2007;21:331&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17874918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Building physical activity and sedentary behavior support into care for youth with type 1 diabetes: patient, parent and diabetes professional perceptions. MacMillan F, Kirk A, Mutrie N, Moola F, Robertson K. Pediatr Diabetes. 2016;17:140&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25482088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>