<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20548842</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2093-2650</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Korean diabetes journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean Diabetes J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of resistance training on muscle and body fat mass and muscle strength in type 2 diabetic women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101</StartPage><EndPage>110</EndPage><MedlinePgn>101-10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4093/kdj.2010.34.2.101</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Our goal was to investigate the effects of low intensity resistance training on body fat, muscle mass and strength, cardiovascular fitness, and insulin sensitivity in type 2 diabetes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-eight overweight women with type 2 diabetes were randomly assigned to a resistance training group (RG, n = 13) or a control group (CG, n = 15). RG performed resistance training using elastic bands, of which strength was equal to 40 to 50% of one repetition maximum (1RM), for three days per week. Each exercise consisted of three sets for 60 minutes. We assessed abdominal fat using computed tomography, muscle mass using dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, and muscle strength using Keiser's chest and leg press. Insulin sensitivity was measured using the insulin tolerance test, and aerobic capacity was expressed as oxygen uptake at the anaerobic threshold (AT-VO(2)) before and after the 12-week exercise program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The age of participants was 56.4 +/- 7.1 years, duration of diabetes was 5.9 +/- 5.5 years, and BMI was 27.4 +/- 2.5 kg/m(2), without significant differences between two groups. During intervention, a greater increase in muscle mass and greater decreases in both total fat mass and abdominal fat were observed in RG compared to those of CG (P = 0.015, P = 0.011, P = 0.010, respectively). Increase in 1RM of upper and lower extremities was observed in the RG (P = 0.004, P = 0.040, respectively), without changes in AT-VO(2) and insulin resistance in either group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In conclusion, the low intensity resistance training was effective in increasing muscle mass and strength and reducing total fat mass without change of insulin sensitivity in type 2 diabetic patients.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Hwi Ryun</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Center, Eulji Hospital, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Kyung Ah</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ku</LastName><ForeName>Yun Hyi</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahn</LastName><ForeName>Hee Jung</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koo</LastName><ForeName>Bo-Kyung</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ho Chul</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Min</LastName><ForeName>Kyung Wan</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean Diabetes J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101477168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1976-9180</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal fat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20548842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2883348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/kdj.2010.34.2.101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baron AD, Brechtel G. Insulin differentially regulates systemic and skeletal muscle vascular resistance. Am J Physiol. 1993;265:E61&#x2013;E67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8338155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan AS, Hurlbut DE, Lott ME, Ivey FM, Fleg J, Hurley BF, Goldberg AP. Insulin action after resistive training in insulin resistant older men and women. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2001;49:247&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11300234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra A, Alappan NK, Vikram NK, Goel K, Gupta N, Mittal K, Bhatt S, Luthra K. Effect of supervised progressive resistance-exercise training protocol on insulin sensitivity, glycemia, lipids, and body composition in Asian Indians with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2008;31:1282&#x2013;1287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2453659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18316394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Boule NG, Wells GA, Prud'homme D, Fortier M, Reid RD, Tulloch H, Coyle D, Phillips P, Jennings A, Jaffey J. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147:357&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibanez J, Izquierdo M, Arguelles I, Forga L, Larrion JL, Garcia-Unciti M, Idoate F, Gorostiaga EM. Twice-weekly progressive resistance training decreases abdominal fat and improves insulin sensitivity in older men with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:662&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha BS, Won YJ, Lee JH, Nam SY, Song YD, Lee EJ, Lim SK, Kim KR, Lee HC, Huh KB, Shin MJ, Lee JH. The correlation between insulin resistance and the visceral fat vs skeletal muscle ratio in middle-aged women. J Korean Diabetes Assoc. 1996;20:395&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourier A, Gautier JF, De Kerviler E, Bigard AX, Villette JM, Garnier JP, Duvallet A, Guezennec CY, Cathelineau G. Mobilization of visceral adipose tissue related to the improvement in insulin sensitivity in response to physical training in NIDDM: effects of branched-chain amino acid supplements. Diabetes Care. 1997;20:385&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9051392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An KH. Effect of low intensity aerobic exercise in type 2 diabetic patients. Korea Sport Res. 2005;16:421&#x2013;429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HR, Ku YH, Ahn HJ, Jeong JY, Ryu SR, Koo BK, Han KA, Min KW. Maximal muscle strength deteriorates with age in subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Korean Diabetes J. 2009;33:412&#x2013;420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HR, Han KA, Ku YH, Ahn HJ, Koo BK, Min KW. Relationship of maximal muscle strength with body mass index and aerobics capacity in type 2 diabetic patients. Korean Diabetes J. 2009;33:511&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Wasserman DH, Castaneda-Sceppa C. Physical activity/exercise and type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2004;27:2518&#x2013;2539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15451933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Daly RM, Owen N, Jolley D, De Courten M, Shaw J, Zimmet P. High-intensity resistance training improves glycemic control in older patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25:1729&#x2013;1736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12351469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda C, Layne JE, Munoz-Orians L, Gordon PL, Walsmith J, Foldvari M, Roubenoff R, Tucker KL, Nelson ME. A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise training to improve glycemic control in older adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25:2335&#x2013;2341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson RM, Stegink Jansen CW, Hogan HA, Nassif MD. Material properties of Thera-Band Tubing. Phys Ther. 2001;81:1437&#x2013;1445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes CJ, Hurd K, Jones A, Sprigle S. Resistance properties of Thera-Band tubing during shoulder abduction exercise. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1999;29:413&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10416181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An KH, Min KW, Han KA. The effects of aerobic training versus resistance training in non-obese type 2 diabetics. J Korean Diabetes Assoc. 2005;29:486&#x2013;494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonora E, Moghetti P, Zancanaro C, Cigolini M, Querena M, Cacciatori V, Corgnati A, Muggeo M. Estimates of in vivo insulin action in man: comparison of insulin tolerance tests with euglycemic and hyperglycemic glucose clamp studies. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1989;68:374&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2645308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean CM, Richards CL, Malouin F. Task-related circuit training improves performance of locomotor tasks in chronic stroke: a randomized, controlled pilot trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2000;81:409&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borkan GA, Gerzof SG, Robbins AH, Hults DE, Silbert CK, Silbert JE. Assessment of abdominal fat content by computed tomography. Am J Clin Nutr. 1982;36:172&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7091027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. 2nd ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majima M, Kondoh T, Eguchi KF, Fujii H, Komiyama G, Suzuki E, Sowa K. Effect of endurance exercise at intensity corresponding to anaerobic threshold on improvement of cardiorespiratory fitness in stroke patients aged below 59 and over 60 years. Jpn J Rehabil Med. 1998;35:485&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM's guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 7th ed. New York: Lippincott Williams and Wilkins; 2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer WJ. Designing resistance training programs. 2nd ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannuzzi-Sucich M, Prestwood KM, Kenny AM. Prevalence of sarcopenia and predictors of skeletal muscle mass in healthy, older men and women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57:M772&#x2013;M777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12456735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung DJ, Joo KC. The effects of resistance exercise by elastic band for improved to daily living physical fitness in old-age women. Exercise Sci. 2003;12:253&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KB. The effect of elastic band training on serum leptin level and health-related physical fitness in obese women with diabetes. Korea Sport Res. 2004;15:713&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuppini A, Matteini P. Obesity and metabolic syndrome: clinical and therapeutic review. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2005;64:45&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16128165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori Y, Hoshino K, Yokota K, Yokose T, Tajima N. Increased visceral fat and impaired glucose tolerance predict the increased risk of metabolic syndrome in Japanese middle-aged men. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes. 2005;113:334&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15977101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon YC, Park JH, Yun MS, Park SK. The effects of muscular resistance training on abdominal fat and insulin concentration in obese middle-aged women. J Sport Leis Stud. 2002;17:127&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KS, Kim MH. The analysis of relationships on plasma leptin and insulin, glucose levels and body composition in obese women with NIDDM during band training. Exercise Sci. 2002;11:131&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han TR. Exercise in the elderly. J Korean Acad Rehabil Med. 2002;26:121&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So WY, Jun TW, Seo DI, Chang H, Seo HK, Eom WS, Park ST, Park JY, Lee HJ, Park SK, Kim JH, Song W. Effects of 12 weeks elastic band exercise on body composition, cardiorespiratory function and physical fitness of middle-aged obese women. Korean J Obes. 2008;17:132&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holten MK, Zacho M, Gaster M, Juel C, Wojtaszewski JF, Dela F. Strength training increases insulin-mediated glucose uptake, GLUT4 content, and insulin signaling in skeletal muscle in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2004;53:294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dela F, Kjaer M. Resistance training, insulin sensitivity and muscle function in the elderly. Essays Biochem. 2006;42:75&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17144881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng YJ, Gregg EW, De Rekeneire N, Williams DE, Imperatore G, Caspersen CJ, Kahn HS. Muscle-strengthening activity and its association with insulin sensitivity. Diabetes Care. 2007;30:2264&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17586746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon BA, Benson AC, Bird SR, Fraser SF. Resistance training improves metabolic health in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2009;83:157&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19135754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks N, Layne JE, Gordon PL, Roubenoff R, Nelson ME, Castaneda-Sceppa C. Strength training improves muscle quality and insulin sensitivity in Hispanic older adults with type 2 diabetes. Int J Med Sci. 2007;4:19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1752232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PL, Vannier E, Hamada K, Layne J, Hurley BF, Roubenoff R, Castaneda-Sceppa C. Resistance training alters cytokine gene expression in skeletal muscle of adults with type 2 diabetes. Int J Immunopathol Pharmacol. 2006;19:739&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17166396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colberg SR, Parson HK, Nunnold T, Herriott MT, Vinik AI. Effect of an 8-week resistance training program on cutaneous perfusion in type 2 diabetes. Microvasc Res. 2006;71:121&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16438993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldi JC, Snowling N. Resistance training improves glycaemic control in obese type 2 diabetic men. Int J Sports Med. 2003;24:419&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12905089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>