<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36727905</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Body Composition of Competitive Bodybuilders: A Systematic Review of Published Data and Recommendations for Future Work.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>726</StartPage><EndPage>732</EndPage><MedlinePgn>726-732</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004155</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bauer, P, Majisik, A, Mitter, B, Csapo, R, Tschan, H, Hume, P, Mart&#xed;nez-Rodr&#xed;guez, A, and Makivic, B. Body composition of competitive bodybuilders: a systematic review of published data and recommendations for future work. J Strength Cond Res 37(3): 726-732, 2023-The purpose of this review was to systematically summarize studies measuring the body composition of competitive bodybuilding athletes to provide recommended values for preparation and during competition. The protocol was preregistered with PROSPERO (CRD42020197921) and followed the guidelines of the Preferred Reported Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analysis. A search of 5 electronic databases (PubMed, Web of Science, SportDiscus, CINAHL, and Scopus) was conducted to retrieve all relevant publications from January 1, 2000, up to June 13, 2021. Of 16 studies meeting the inclusion criteria, 6 presented longitudinal data on competition preparation and were discussed in detail. In the general preparation phase, body fat levels of bodybuilding athletes ranged between 15.3 and 25.2% (female) and from 9.6 to 16.3% (male). Close to competition, however, body fat levels were substantially lower, ranging from 8.1 to 18.3% for female and 5.8-10.7% for male athletes. All studies comparing relative body fat values at various time points during competition preparation found significant reductions between 30 and 60% in relative body fat, whereas lean mass was mostly maintained. Findings from the studies included in this review suggest that most bodybuilding competitors keep resistance training volume high while increasing aerobic training volume when preparing for competition. Findings on energy intake and macronutrient distribution were unclear and should be addressed in future studies. Further research, especially on contest preparation, is warranted and should include more details about training programs, nutritional strategies, psychosocial situation, anabolic androgen steroid, and supplement use as well as measurement protocols and preparation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bauer</LastName><ForeName>Pascal</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Vienna, Centre for Sports Science and University Sports, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Majisik</LastName><ForeName>Alan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Vienna, Centre for Sports Science and University Sports, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitter</LastName><ForeName>Benedikt</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Vienna, Centre for Sports Science and University Sports, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Csapo</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Vienna, Centre for Sports Science and University Sports, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tschan</LastName><ForeName>Harald</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Vienna, Centre for Sports Science and University Sports, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hume</LastName><ForeName>Patria</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Rodr&#xed;guez</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Analytical Chemistry, Nutrition and Food Sciences, Faculty of Sciences, University of Alicante, Alicante, Spain ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Makivic</LastName><ForeName>Bojan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Applied Science, Wiener Neustadt, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002149" MajorTopicYN="Y">Energy Intake</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36727905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202303000-00023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ackland TR, Lohman TG, Sundgot-Borgen J, et al. Current status of body composition assessment in sport: Review and position statement on behalf of the ad hoc research working group on body composition health and performance, under the auspices of the I.O.C. Medical Commission. Sports Med 42: 227&#x2013;249, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey DG, Pliego GJ, Raymond RL. Body composition and metabolic changes following bariatric surgery: Effects on fat mass, lean mass and basal metabolic rate: Six months to one-year follow-up. Obes Surg 16: 1602&#x2013;1608, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutilaki VB, Levy M, Beninc&#xe1; SC, Zanlourensi CB, de Freitas GBL, Mazur CE. Body roundness Index: Relationship with traditional methods of predicting body fat in bodybuilders. Br J Exerc Presc Physiol 11: 905&#x2013;911, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cyrino ES, Santar&#xe9;m Sobrinho JM, Maest&#xe1; N, et al. [Morphological profile of elite Brazilian bodybuilders in competitive period]. Rev Bras Med Do Esporte 14: 460&#x2013;465, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Freitas Junior WR, Ilias EJ, Kassab P, et al. Assessment of the body composition and the loss of fat-free mass through bioelectric impedance analysis in patients who underwent open gastric bypass. Sci World J 843253: 1&#x2013;5, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza, Santos DC, JAB dos, De Jesus DM, Gentil P. Biochemical profile and body composition alteration of amateur bodybuilders during the pre-contest period. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 3: 20&#x2013;26, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faintuch J, Soriano FG, Ladeira JP, et al. Changes in body fluid and energy compartments during prolonged hunger strike. Rev Hosp Clin Fac Med Sao Paulo 55: 47&#x2013;54, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, de Lira CAB, Paoli A, et al. Nutrition, pharmacological and training strategies adopted by six bodybuilders: Case report and critical review. Eur J Transl Myol 27: 51&#x2013;66, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graybeal AJ, Moore ML, Cruz MR, Tinsley GM. Body composition assessment in male and female bodybuilders: A 4-compartment model comparison of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry and impedance-based devices. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1676&#x2013;1689, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Fitschen PJ, Aragon AA, Cronin J, Schoenfeld BJ. Recommendations for natural bodybuilding contest preparation: Resistance and cardiovascular training. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 55: 164&#x2013;178, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Isola V, Suonp&#xe4;&#xe4; M, et al. The effects of intensive weight reduction on body composition and serum hormones in female fitness competitors. Front Physiol 689: 1&#x2013;16, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huygens W, Claessens AL, Thomis M, et al. Body composition estimations by BIA versus anthropometric equations in body builders and other power athletes. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 42: 45&#x2013;55, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper AM, Langan-Evans C, Hudson JF, et al. Come back skinfolds, all is forgiven: A narrative review of the efficacy of common body composition methods in applied sports practice. Nutrients 13: 1&#x2013;19, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert CP, Frank LL, Evans WJ. Macronutrient considerations for the sport of bodybuilding. Sports Med 34: 317&#x2013;327, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longstrom JM, Colenso-Semple LM, Waddell BJ, et al. Physiological, psychological and performance-related changes following physique competition: A case-series. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 5: 1&#x2013;14, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maest&#xe1; N, Cyrino ES, Nardo Junior N, et al. Antropometria de atletas culturistas em rela&#xe7;&#xe3;o &#xe0; refer&#xea;ncia populacional. Rev Nutr 13: 135&#x2013;141, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;estu J, J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e J, Valter I, J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e T. Increases in ghrelin and decreases in leptin without altering adiponectin during extreme weight loss in male competitive bodybuilders. Metabolism 57: 221&#x2013;225, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makiel K, Suder A, Kasza S, Kubasiak K. Body composition and dietary patterns in professional and amateur bodybuilders. Anthropol Rev 83: 225&#x2013;238, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell L, Slater G, Hackett D, Johnson N, O'connor H. Physiological implications of preparing for a natural male bodybuilding competition. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 619&#x2013;629, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLoS Med 6: 1&#x2013;6, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moura RF, De Moraes WM, De Castro BM, et al. Carbohydrate refeed does not modify GVT-performance following energy restriction in bodybuilders. Clin Nutr ESPEN 43: 308&#x2013;316, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva DRP, et al. Effect of two- versus three-way split resistance training routines on body composition and muscular strength in bodybuilders: A pilot study. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 25: 559&#x2013;565, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts BM, Helms ER, Trexler ET, Fitschen PJ. Nutritional recommendations for physique athletes. J Hum Kinet 71: 79&#x2013;108, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossow LM, Fukuda DH, Fahs CA, Loenneke JP, Stout JR. Natural bodybuilding competition preparation and recovery: A 12-month case study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 8: 582&#x2013;592, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva PR, Trindade R, De Rose EH. Composi&#xe7;&#xe3;o corporal, somatotipo e proporcionalidade de culturistas de elite do Brasil . Rev Bras Med do Esporte 9: 403&#x2013;407, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spendlove J, Mitchell L, Gifford J, et al. Dietary intake of competitive bodybuilders. Sports Med 45: 1041&#x2013;1063, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Ploeg GE, Brooks AG, Withers RT, et al. Body composition changes in female bodybuilders during preparation for competition. Eur J Clin Nutr 55: 268&#x2013;277, 2001.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>