<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26526941</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2233-6834</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise nutrition &amp; biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Nutrition Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The interaction effects of aerobic exercise training and vitamin D supplementation on plasma lipid profiles and insulin resistance in ovariectomized rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>173</StartPage><EndPage>182</EndPage><MedlinePgn>173-82</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5717/jenb.2015.15070703</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this study was to determine the interaction effects of aerobic exercise training and vitamin D supplementation on indices of obesity and plasma lipid profiles in ovariectomized (OVX) rats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty female Wistar rats were divided into 5 groups: aerobic training (3 days/week for 8 weeks; AT; n = 8), aerobic training and vitamin D supplementation (OVX + AT + Vit D; n = 8), vitamin D supplementation (OVX + Vit D; n = 8), ovariectomized control (OVX + C, n = 8) and SHAM (n = 8). After blood sampling, visceral fat was taken from the abdominal cavity and weighed immediately. Data was statistically analyzed by One-way ANOVA and Repeated measure ANOVA tests with a 0.05 significance level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Body weight, visceral fat, BMI and food intake decreased significantly in OVX + AT + Vit D (P &lt; 0.001); whereas these variables increased significantly in OVX + C (P &lt; 0.001) and SHAM (P &lt; 0.023) groups. At the end of two-months of follow-up, we observed significant differences in TC, TG, HDL-C, LDL-C, glucose, insulin, and HOMA-IR in all groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It seems that aerobic training with vitamin D, due to the involvement of muscle mass and exposure to dynamic pressure on the bones and muscles, increased energy expenditure, stimulated insulin exudation and glucose homeostasis, decreased insulin resistance and improved the lipid profile in ovariectomized rats.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babaei</LastName><ForeName>Parvin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Guilan University of Medical Sciences, Rasht, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Damirchi</LastName><ForeName>Arsalan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Faculty of physical education and sport sciences, University of Guilan, Rasht, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoseini</LastName><ForeName>Rastegar</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Faculty of physical education and sport sciences, University of Guilan, Rasht, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Nutrition Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101572566</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-6834</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic Training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Food Intake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postmenopausal Women</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Visceral Fat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamin D</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plasma lipid profiles and insulin resistance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26526941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4624118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5717/jenb.2015.15070703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jenb-19-3-173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cooke PS, Naaz A. Role of estrogens in adipocyte development and function. Experimental biology and medicine. 2004;229:1127&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15564439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wajchenberg BL. Subcutaneous and visceral adipose tissue: their relation to the metabolic syndrome. Endocrine reviews. 2000;21:697&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11133069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainslie D, Morris M, Wittert G, Turnbull H, Proietto J, Thorburn A. Estrogen deficiency causes central leptin insensitivity and increased hypothalamic neuropeptide Y. International journal of obesity and related metabolic disorders: journal of the International Association for the Study of Obesity. 2001;25:1680&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11753591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Zmuda JM, Cauley JA, Shea PR, Ferrell RE. Vitamin D receptor genotype is associated with fat-free mass and sarcopenia in elderly men. The Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2004;59:10&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambacciani M, Ciaponi M, Cappagli B, Piaggesi L, De Simone L, Orlandi R, et al. Body weight, body fat distribution, and hormonal replacement therapy in early postmenopausal women. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 1997;82:414&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9024228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munoz J, Derstine A, Gower BA. Fat distribution and insulin sensitivity in postmenopausal women: influence of hormone replacement. Obesity research. 2002;10:424&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12055317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray GA, Bellanger T. Epidemiology, trends, and morbidities of obesity and the metabolic syndrome. Endocrine. 2006;29:109&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16622298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarti C, Gallagher J. The metabolic syndrome: prevalence, CHD risk, and treatment. Journal of Diabetes and its Complications. 2006;20:121&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16504841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller DE, Kaufman KD. Metabolic syndrome: a clinical and molecular perspective. Annu Rev Med. 2005;56:45&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15660501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijder MB, van Dam RM, Visser M, Deeg DJ, Dekker JM, Bouter LM, et al. Adiposity in relation to vitamin D status and parathyroid hormone levels: a population-based study in older men and women. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 2005;90:4119&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobnig H, Pilz S, Scharnagl H, Renner W, Seelhorst U, Wellnitz B, et al. Independent association of low serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D levels with all-cause and cardiovascular mortality. Archives of internal medicine. 2008;168:1340&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18574092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid IR, Bolland MJ, Grey A. Effects of vitamin D supplements on bone mineral density: a systematic review and meta-analysis. The Lancet. 2014;383:146&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman D, Krishnan AV, Swami S, Giovannucci E, Feldman BJ. The role of vitamin D in reducing cancer risk and progression. Nature Reviews Cancer. 2014;14:342&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24705652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen D, Rasmussen K, Rasmussen LM, Bruunsgaard H, Brandi L. The influence of vitamin D analogs on calcification modulators, N-terminal pro-B-type natriuretic peptide and inflammatory markers in hemodialysis patients: a randomized crossover study. BMC nephrology. 2014;15:130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4136403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25112372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zittermann A. Vitamin D in preventive medicine: are we ignoring the evidence? British Journal of Nutrition. 2003;89:552&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12720576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman AW, Frankel J, Heldt AM, Grodsky GM. Vitamin D deficiency inhibits pancreatic secretion of insulin. Science. 1980;209:823&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6250216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadowaki S, Norman AW. Dietary vitamin D is essential for normal insulin secretion from the perfused rat pancreas. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 1984;73:759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC425078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6323527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittas AG, Lau J, Hu FB, Dawson-Hughes B. The role of vitamin D and calcium in type 2 diabetes. A systematic review and meta-analysis. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 2007;92:2017&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2085234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jungert A, Roth HJ, Neuh&#xe4;user-Berthold M. Associations of serum 25-hydroxycholecalciferol and parathyroid hormone with serum lipids differ by sex and vitamin D status. Public health nutrition. 2014:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10271575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25355402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sene-Fiorese M, Duarte FO, Scarmagnani FR, Cheik NC, Manzoni MS, Nonaka KO, et al. Efficiency of Intermittent Exercise on Adiposity and Fatty Liver in Rats Fed With High-fat Diet. Obesity. 2008;16:2217&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18719640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malin SK, Kashyap SR, Hammel J, Miyazaki Y, DeFronzo RA, Kirwan JP. Adjusting Glucose-Stimulated Insulin Secretion for Adipose Insulin Resistance: An Index of &#x3b2;-Cell Function in Obese Adults. Diabetes care. 2014;37:2940&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4207203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25139885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association AD. Standards of medical care in diabetes-2010. Diabetes care. 2010;33:S11&#x2013;S61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2797382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20042772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svejme O, Ahlborg H, Karlsson M. Physical activity reduces bone loss in the distal forearm in post-menopausal women-a 25-year prospective study. Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports. 2014;24:159&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22846059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarbal F, Stefanick ML, Salmoirago-Blotcher E, Manson JE, Albert CM, LaMonte MJ, et al. Obesity, physical activity, and their interaction in incident atrial fibrillation in postmenopausal women. Journal of the American Heart Association. 2014;3:e001127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4310412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25142057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier A, Dos Santos G, Guillas G, Bertsch J, Duclos M, Boutron-Ruault M-C, et al. Recent Recreational Physical Activity and Breast Cancer Risk in Postmenopausal Women in the E3N Cohort. Cancer Epidemiology Biomarkers &amp; Prevention. 2014;23:1893&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25114017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, Weltman JY, Patrie JT, Saliba SA, Gaesser GA, Barrett EJ, et al. Predictors of improvement in endothelial function after exercise training in a diverse sample of postmenopausal women. Journal of Women&#x2019;s Health. 2014;23:260&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3952526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24299160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinoda M, Latour M, Lavoie J. Effects of physical training on body composition and organ weights in ovariectomized and hyperestrogenic rats. International journal of obesity and related metabolic disorders: journal of the International Association for the Study of Obesity. 2002;26:335&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11896488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier M-S, Couturier K, Latour J-G, Lavoie J-M. Concurrent exercise prevents high-fat-diet-induced macro-vesicular hepatic steatosis. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2003;94:2127&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12547845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latour MG, Shinoda M, Lavoie J-M. Metabolic effects of physical training in ovariectomized and hyperestrogenic rats. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2001;90:235&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11133915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Nakkash L, Janjulia T, Peterson K, Lucy D, Wilson D, Peterson A, et al. Genistein and exercise do not improve cardiovascular risk factors in the ovariectomized rat. Climacteric. 2014;17:136&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23679226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucolo G, David H. Quantitative determination of serum triglycerides by the use of enzymes. Clinical chemistry. 1973;19:476&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4703655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allain CC, Poon LS, Chan CS, Richmond W, Fu PC. Enzymatic determination of total serum cholesterol. Clinical chemistry. 1974;20:470&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4818200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finley PR, Schifman RB, Williams RJ, Lichti DA. Cholesterol in high-density lipoprotein: use of Mg2+/dextran sulfate in its enzymic measurement. Clinical chemistry. 1978;24:931&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">207463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedewald WT, Levy RI, Fredrickson DS. Estimation of the concentration of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol in plasma, without use of the preparative ultracentrifuge. Clinical chemistry. 1972;18:499&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4337382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leinonen E, Hurt-Camejo E, Wiklund O, Hult&#xe9;n LM, Hiukka A, Taskinen M-R. Insulin resistance and adiposity correlate with acute-phase reaction and soluble cell adhesion molecules in type 2 diabetes. Atherosclerosis. 2003;166:387&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12535753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei P, Mehdizadeh R, Ansar MM, Damirchi A. Effects of ovariectomy and estrogen replacement therapy on visceral adipose tissue and serum adiponectin levels in rats. Menopause international. 2010;16:100&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damirchi A, Mehdizade R, Ansar M, Soltani B, Babaei P. Effects of aerobic exercise training on visceral fat and serum adiponectin concentration in ovariectomized rats. Climacteric. 2010;13:171&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19886815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major GC, Alarie FP, Dor&#xe9; J, Tremblay A. Calcium plus vitamin D supplementation and fat mass loss in female very low-calcium consumers: potential link with a calcium-specific appetite control. British journal of nutrition. 2009;101:659&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19263591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Boul&#xe9; NG, Wells GA, Prud&#x2019;homme D, Fortier M, et al. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: a randomized trial. Annals of internal medicine. 2007;147:357&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madden KM. Evidence for the benefit of exercise therapy in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes, metabolic syndrome and obesity: targets and therapy. 2013;6:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23847428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, Johannsen NM, Lavie CJ, Earnest CP, Church TS. The role of exercise and physical activity in weight loss and maintenance. Progress in cardiovascular diseases. 2014;56:441&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3925973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SR, O&#x2019;Neil PM, Astrup A, Finer N, Sanchez-Kam M, Fraher K, et al. Early weight loss while on lorcaserin, diet and exercise as a predictor of week 52 weight-loss outcomes. Obesity. 2014;22:2137&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25044799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan S, Gustafson MB, Campbell C, Gaikwad NW, Keim NL. Association between circulating endogenous androgens and insulin sensitivity changes with exercise training in midlife women. Menopause. 2014;21:967&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24496084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunout D, Barrera G, Leiva L, Gattas V, de la Maza MP, Avenda&#xf1;o M, et al. Effects of vitamin D supplementation and exercise training on physical performance in Chilean vitamin D deficient elderly subjects. Experimental gerontology. 2006;41:746&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16797903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorde R, Sneve M, Torjesen P, Figenschau Y. No improvement in cardiovascular risk factors in overweight and obese subjects after supplementation with vitamin D3 for 1 year. Journal of internal medicine. 2010;267:462&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20141565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneve M, Figenschau Y, Jorde R. Supplementation with cholecalciferol does not result in weight reduction in overweight and obese subjects. European Journal of Endocrinology. 2008;159:675&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumb G, Mawer E, Stanbury S. The apparent vitamin D resistance of chronic renal failure: a study of the physiology of vitamin D in man. The American Journal of Medicine. 1971;50:421&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LUMB G, Stanbury S. The distribution and storage of vitamin D and its metabolites in human tissues. Clinical science. 1972;43:413431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4342673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao D, Trayhurn P, Bing C. 1, 25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 inhibits the cytokine-induced secretion of MCP-1 and reduces monocyte recruitment by human preadipocytes. International journal of obesity. 2013;37:357&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3428854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22508334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcotorchino J, Gouranton E, Romier B, Tourniaire F, Astier J, Malezet C, et al. Vitamin D reduces the inflammatory response and restores glucose uptake in adipocytes. Molecular nutrition &amp; food research. 2012;56:1771&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23065818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumiya Y, Hopkins T, Morris C, Sato K, Zeng L, Viereck J, et al. Fast/Glycolytic muscle fiber growth reduces fat mass and improves metabolic parameters in obese mice. Cell metabolism. 2008;7:159&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2828690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18249175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hale GE, Shufelt CL. Hormone therapy in menopause: An update on cardiovascular disease considerations. Trends in Cardiovascular Medicine. 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26270318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donneyong MM, Hornung CA, Taylor KC, Baumgartner RN, Myers JA, Eaton CB, et al. Risk of Heart Failure Among Postmenopausal Women A Secondary Analysis of the Randomized Trial of Vitamin D Plus Calcium of the Women&#x2019;s Health Initiative. Circulation: Heart Failure. 2015;8:49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4303506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25398967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major GC, Alarie F, Dor&#xe9; J, Phouttama S, Tremblay A. Supplementation with calcium+ vitamin D enhances the beneficial effect of weight loss on plasma lipid and lipoprotein concentrations. The American journal of clinical nutrition. 2007;85:54&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17209177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejnmark L, Vestergaard P, Heickendorff L, Mosekilde L. Simvastatin does not affect vitamin d status, but low vitamin d levels are associated with dyslipidemia: results from a randomised, controlled trial. International journal of endocrinology. 2009:2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2778175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20016680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kota SK, Jammula S, Kota SK, Tripathy PR, Panda S, Modi KD. Effect of vitamin D supplementation in type 2 diabetes patients with pulmonary tuberculosis. Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research &amp; Reviews. 2011;5:85&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22813409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J-H, Keisala T, Solakivi T, Minasyan A, Kalueff AV, Tuohimaa P. Serum cholesterol and expression of ApoAI, LXR&#x3b2; and SREBP2 in vitamin D receptor knock-out mice. The Journal of steroid biochemistry and molecular biology. 2009;113:222&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19429425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene NP, Martin SE, Crouse SF. Acute exercise and training alter blood lipid and lipoprotein profiles differently in overweight and obese men and women. Obesity. 2012;20:1618&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung K, Bae S. Effects of a regular walking exercise program on behavioral and biochemical aspects in elderly people with type II diabetes. Nursing &amp; health sciences. 2012;14:438&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22676205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorde R, Grimnes G. Vitamin D and metabolic health with special reference to the effect of vitamin D on serum lipids. Progress in lipid research. 2011;50:303&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21640757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaskonen T, Mervaala E, Sumuvuori V, Sepp&#xe4;nen-Laakso T, Karppanen H. Effects of calcium and plant sterols on serum lipids in obese Zucker rats on a low-fat diet. British Journal of Nutrition. 2002;87:239&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12064332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid IR, Mason B, Horne A, Ames R, Clearwater J, Bava U, et al. Effects of calcium supplementation on serum lipid concentrations in normal older women:: A randomized controlled trial. The American journal of medicine. 2002;112:343&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11904107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni Z, Smogorzewski M, Massry SG. Effects of parathyroid hormone on cytosolic calcium of rat adipocytes. Endocrinology. 1994;135:1837&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7525254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemel MB, Shi H, Greer B, Dirienzo D, Zemel PC. Regulation of adiposity by dietary calcium. The FASEB Journal. 2000;14:1132&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10834935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamatani H, Takahashi K, Yoshida T, Soga T, Kurachi H. Differences in the fatty acid metabolism of visceral adipose tissue in postmenopausal women. Menopause. 2014;21:170&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23760430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuzawa Y. Obesity and metabolic syndrome: the contribution of visceral fat and adiponectin. Diabetes Management. 2014;4:391&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Despr&#xe9;s J-P, Lemieux I. Abdominal obesity and metabolic syndrome. Nature. 2006;444:881&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caron-Jobin M, Morisset AS, Tremblay A, Huot C, L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; D, Tchernof A. Elevated serum 25 (OH) D concentrations, vitamin D, and calcium intakes are associated with reduced adipocyte size in women. Obesity. 2011;19:1335&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi E, Negri C, Targher G, Faccioli N, Lanza M, Zoppini G, et al. Both resistance training and aerobic training reduce hepatic fat content in type 2 diabetic subjects with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (the RAED2 Randomized Trial) Hepatology. 2013;58:1287&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23504926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wamberg L, Kampmann U, St&#xf8;dkilde-J&#xf8;rgensen H, Rejnmark L, Pedersen S, Richelsen B. Effects of vitamin D supplementation on body fat accumulation, inflammation, and metabolic risk factors in obese adults with low vitamin D levels-results from a randomized trial. European journal of internal medicine. 2013;24:644&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23566943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azadbakht L, Mirmiran P, Esmaillzadeh A, Azizi T, Azizi F. Beneficial effects of a Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension eating plan on features of the metabolic syndrome. Diabetes care. 2005;28:2823&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16306540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talaei A, Mohamadi M, Adgi Z. The effect of vitamin D on insulin resistance in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2013;5:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3586569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23443033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delvin EE. Importance of vitamin D in insulin resistance. Bulletin de l&#x2019;Academie nationale de medecine. 2010;195:1091&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22375372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damirchi A, Tehrani BS, Alamdari KA, Babaei P. Influence of aerobic training and detraining on serum BDNF, insulin resistance, and metabolic risk factors in middle-aged men diagnosed with metabolic syndrome. Clinical Journal of Sport Medicine. 2014;24:513&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gemert WA, Monninkhof EM, May AM, Peeters PH, Schuit AJ. Effect of exercise on insulin sensitivity in healthy postmenopausal women: the SHAPE study. Cancer Epidemiology Biomarkers &amp; Prevention. 2015;24:81&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25342388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zittermann A. Vitamin D and disease prevention with special reference to cardiovascular disease. Progress in biophysics and molecular biology. 2006;92:39&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16600341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segersten U, Correa P, Hewison M, Hellman P, Dralle H, Carling T, et al. 25-Hydroxyvitamin D3-1&#x3b1;-hydroxylase expression in normal and pathological parathyroid glands. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 2002;87:2967&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12050281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson R, Thomas G, Arnold A. Identification of 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 receptors and activities in muscle. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 1985;260:8882&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2991224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestro B, Molero S, Bajo S, Davila N, Calle C. Transcriptional activation of the human insulin receptor gene by 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D3. Cell biochemistry and function. 2002;20:227&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12125099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Q, Li Y, Boucher B, Leung P. A novel role for vitamin D: modulation of expression and function of the local renin-angiotensin system in mouse pancreatic islets. Diabetologia. 2011;54:2077&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojuka EO. Role of calcium and AMP kinase in the regulation of mitochondrial biogenesis and GLUT4 levels in muscle. Proceedings of the Nutrition Society. 2004;63:275&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15294043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desvergne B, Wahli W. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors: nuclear control of metabolism 1. Endocrine reviews. 1999;20:649&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10529898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinberg H, Baron A. Vascular function, insulin resistance and fatty acids. Diabetologia. 2002;45:623&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12107742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty M, Thomas C. PTH excess may promote weight gain by impeding catecholamine-induced lipolysis-implications for the impact of calcium, vitamin D, and alcohol on body weight. Medical hypotheses. 2003;61:535&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wannamethee SG, Welsh P, Papacosta O, Lennon L, Whincup PH, Sattar N. Elevated parathyroid hormone, but not vitamin D deficiency, is associated with increased risk of heart failure in older men with and without cardiovascular disease. Circulation: Heart Failure. 2014;7:732&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25104043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng S, Massaro JM, Fox CS, Larson MG, Keyes MJ, McCabe EL, et al. Adiposity, cardiometabolic risk, and vitamin D status: the Framingham Heart Study. Diabetes. 2010;59:242&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2797928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>