<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40495947</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2219-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease: A story of muscle and mass.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>105346</StartPage><MedlinePgn>105346</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">105346</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3748/wjg.v31.i20.105346</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Skeletal muscle alterations (SMA) are increasingly recognized as both contributors and consequences of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD), affecting disease progression and outcomes. Sarcopenia is common in patients with MASLD, with a prevalence ranging from 20% to 40% depending on the population and diagnostic criteria used. In advanced stages, such as metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis and fibrosis, its prevalence is even higher. Sarcopenia exacerbates insulin resistance, systemic inflammation, and oxidative stress, all of which worsen MASLD. It is an independent risk factor for fibrosis progression and poor outcomes including mortality. Myosteatosis refers to the abnormal accumulation of fat within muscle tissue, leading to decreased muscle quality. Myosteatosis is prevalent (&gt; 30%) in patients with MASLD, especially those with obesity or type 2 diabetes, although this can vary with the imaging techniques used. It reduces muscle strength and metabolic efficiency, further contributing to insulin resistance and is usually associated with advanced liver disease, cardiovascular complications, and lower levels of physical activity. Altered muscle metabolism, which includes mitochondrial dysfunction and impaired amino acid metabolism, has been reported in metabolic syndromes, including MASLD, although its actual prevalence is unknown. Altered muscle metabolism limits glucose uptake and oxidation, worsening hyperglycemia and lipotoxicity. Reduced muscle perfusion and oxygenation due to endothelial dysfunction and systemic metabolic alterations are common in MASLD associated with comorbidities, such as obesity, hypertension, and atherosclerosis. It decreases the muscle capacity for aerobic metabolism, leading to fatigue and reduced physical activity in patients with MASLD, aggravating metabolic dysfunction. Various SMA in MASLD worsen insulin resistance and hepatic fat accumulation, may accelerate progression to fibrosis and cirrhosis, and increase the risk of cardiovascular disease and mortality. Management strategies for SMA include resistance training, aerobic exercise, and nutritional support (<i>e.g.</i>, high-protein diets, vitamin D, and omega-3 fatty acids), which are essential for mitigating skeletal muscle loss and improving outcomes. However, pharmacological agents that target the muscle and liver (such as glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists) show promise but have not yet been approved for the treatment of MASLD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isakov</LastName><ForeName>Vasily</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Federal Research Center of Nutrition, Biotechnology and Food Safety, Moscow 115446, Russia. vasily.isakov@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005234" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatty Liver</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007333" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin Resistance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008099" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008103" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver Cirrhosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065626" MajorTopicYN="Y">Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018384" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative Stress</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary patterns</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-protein diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myosteatosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal muscle alterations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal muscle mass index</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: Isakov V has nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40495947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12146937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v31.i20.105346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver (EASL); European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD); European Association for the Study of Obesity (EASO) EASL-EASD-EASO Clinical Practice Guidelines on the management of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD) J Hepatol. 2024;81:492&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38851997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanwal F, Neuschwander-Tetri BA, Loomba R, Rinella ME. Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease: Update and impact of new nomenclature on the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases practice guidance on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatology. 2024;79:1212&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38445559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golabi P, Isakov V, Younossi ZM. Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease: Disease Burden and Disease Awareness. Clin Liver Dis. 2023;27:173&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37024201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng G, Targher G, Byrne CD, Yilmaz Y, Wai-Sun Wong V, Adithya Lesmana CR, Adams LA, Boursier J, Papatheodoridis G, El-Kassas M, M&#xe9;ndez-S&#xe1;nchez N, Sookoian S, Castera L, Chan WK, Ye F, Treeprasertsuk S, Cortez-Pinto H, Yu HH, Kim W, Romero-G&#xf3;mez M, Nakajima A, Win KM, Kim SU, Holleboom AG, Sebastiani G, Ocama P, Ryan JD, Lup&#x219;or-Platon M, Ghazinyan H, Al-Mahtab M, Hamid S, Perera N, Alswat KA, Pan Q, Long MT, Isakov V, Mi M, Arrese M, Sanyal AJ, Sarin SK, Leite NC, Valenti L, Newsome PN, Hagstr&#xf6;m H, Petta S, Yki-J&#xe4;rvinen H, Schattenberg JM, Castellanos Fern&#xe1;ndez MI, Leclercq IA, Aghayeva G, Elzouki AN, Tumi A, Sharara AI, Labidi A, Sanai FM, Matar K, Al-Mattooq M, Akroush MW, Benazzouz M, Debzi N, Alkhatry M, Barakat S, Al-Busafi SA, Rwegasha J, Yang W, Adwoa A, Opio CK, Sotoudeheian M, Wong YJ, George J, Zheng MH. Global burden of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease, 2010 to 2021. JHEP Rep. 2025;7:101271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11840544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39980749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg IH. Sarcopenia: origins and clinical relevance. J Nutr. 1997;127:990S&#x2013;991S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9164280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, Boirie Y, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Cederholm T, Cooper C, Landi F, Rolland Y, Sayer AA, Schneider SM, Sieber CC, Topinkova E, Vandewoude M, Visser M, Zamboni M Writing Group for the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People 2 (EWGSOP2), and the Extended Group for EWGSOP2. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48:16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng C, Ou Q, Ou X, Pan D. Association between non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and risk of sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2024;14:e078933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11086578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38719326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evuri P, Selvi C, E M, A A, Karunakaran P, K M, R M, A C, I S. Study of Prevalence of Sarcopenia in Chronic Liver Disease and its Impact on Outcomes. IJIRMS. 2022;7:335&#x2013;339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Himoto T, Miyatake K, Maeba T, Masaki T. Verification of the Nutritional and Dietary Factors Associated with Skeletal Muscle Index in Japanese Patients with Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease. Can J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;2020:3576974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7368962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32695733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik A, Javaid S, Malik MI, Qureshi S. Relationship between sarcopenia and metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD): A systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Hepatol. 2024;29:101544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39214253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, He J, Sun Q. The prevalence and effects of sarcopenia in patients with metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD): A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Nutr. 2024;43:2005&#x2013;2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39053329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Real Martinez Y, Fernandez-Garcia CE, Fuertes-Yebra E, Calvo Soto M, Berlana A, Barrios V, Caldas M, Gonzalez Moreno L, Garcia-Buey L, Molina Baena B, Sampedro-Nu&#xf1;ez M, Beceiro MJ, Garc&#xed;a-Monz&#xf3;n C, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Rodr&#xed;guez &#xc1;. Assessment of skeletal muscle alterations and circulating myokines in metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease: A cross-sectional study. World J Gastroenterol. 2025;31:100039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11755261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39991673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Wijarnpreecha K, Sandhu KK, Cholankeril G, Ahmed A. Sarcopenia in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and all-cause and cause-specific mortality in the United States. Liver Int. 2021;41:1832&#x2013;1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33641244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai Y, Xiao Q. The Common Mechanisms of Sarcopenia and NAFLD. Biomed Res Int. 2017;2017:6297651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5745668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29387723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung GE, Oh S, Ahn DW, Kim SH, Jung YJ, Kim JW, Kim BG, Lee KL, Jeong JB. Effects of additive interactions among obesity, visceral adiposity, and sarcopenia on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Sci Rep. 2023;13:3628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9984466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36869158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikolasevic I, Pavic T, Kanizaj TF, Bender DV, Domislovic V, Krznaric Z. Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease and Sarcopenia: Where Do We Stand? Can J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;2020:8859719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33204675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinn DH, Kang D, Kang M, Guallar E, Hong YS, Lee KH, Park J, Cho J, Gwak GY. Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and accelerated loss of skeletal muscle mass: A longitudinal cohort study. Hepatology. 2022;76:1746&#x2013;1754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35588190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M, Xiang L, Yao J, Zhang J, Zhu S, Wang D, Liu C, Li G, Wang J, Gao Y, Xie C, Ma X, Xu L, Zhou J. Comprehensive Transcriptome Profiling of NAFLD- and NASH-Induced Skeletal Muscle Dysfunction. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2022;13:851520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8899658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35265044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Du J, Ge X, Peng W, Guo X, Li W, Huang S. Circulating Ism1 Reduces the Risk of Type 2 Diabetes but not Diabetes-Associated NAFLD. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2022;13:890332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9195582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35712241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YH, Kim SU, Song K, Park JY, Kim DY, Ahn SH, Lee BW, Kang ES, Cha BS, Han KH. Sarcopenia is associated with significant liver fibrosis independently of obesity and insulin resistance in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: Nationwide surveys (KNHANES 2008-2011) Hepatology. 2016;63:776&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26638128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhanji RA, Narayanan P, Allen AM, Malhi H, Watt KD. Sarcopenia in hiding: The risk and consequence of underestimating muscle dysfunction in nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Hepatology. 2017;66:2055&#x2013;2065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28777879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petta S, Ciminnisi S, Di Marco V, Cabibi D, Camm&#xe0; C, Licata A, Marchesini G, Crax&#xec; A. Sarcopenia is associated with severe liver fibrosis in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2017;45:510&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28028821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okubo T, Atsukawa M, Tsubota A, Ono H, Kawano T, Yoshida Y, Arai T, Hayama K, Itokawa N, Kondo C, Iwakiri K. Low vitamin D levels accelerates muscle mass loss in patients with chronic liver disease. PLoS One. 2024;19:e0299313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10965050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38530830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu R, Shi Q, Liu L, Chen L. Relationship of sarcopenia with steatohepatitis and advanced liver fibrosis in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a meta-analysis. BMC Gastroenterol. 2018;18:51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5907709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29673321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golabi P, Gerber L, Paik JM, Deshpande R, de Avila L, Younossi ZM. Contribution of sarcopenia and physical inactivity to mortality in people with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. JHEP Rep. 2020;2:100171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32964202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harring M, Golabi P, Paik JM, Shah D, Racila A, Cable R, Srishord M, Younossi ZM. Sarcopenia Among Patients With Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD) Is Associated With Advanced Fibrosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;21:2876&#x2013;2888.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36848980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijarnpreecha K, Panjawatanan P, Thongprayoon C, Jaruvongvanich V, Ungprasert P. Sarcopenia and risk of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: A meta-analysis. Saudi J Gastroenterol. 2018;24:12&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29451179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai C, Song X, Chen Y, Chen X, Yu C. Relationship between relative skeletal muscle mass and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hepatol Int. 2020;14:115&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6994447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31290072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tovo CV, Fernandes SA, Buss C, de Mattos AA. Sarcopenia and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: Is there a relationship? A systematic review. World J Hepatol. 2017;9:326&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5332422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28293382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G, Lee SE, Lee YB, Jun JE, Ahn J, Bae JC, Jin SM, Hur KY, Jee JH, Lee MK, Kim JH. Relationship Between Relative Skeletal Muscle Mass and Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease: A 7-Year Longitudinal Study. Hepatology. 2018;68:1755&#x2013;1768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29679374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Xiang H, Tan L, Zhou J, Tang J, Hu X, Yang M. Psoriasis Is Associated With Myosteatosis but Not Sarcopenia: A Case-Control Study. Front Med (Lausanne) 2021;8:754932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8554055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34722590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henin G, Loumaye A, Deldicque L, Leclercq IA, Lanthier N. Unlocking liver health: Can tackling myosteatosis spark remission in metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease? Liver Int. 2024;44:1781&#x2013;1796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38623714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henin G, Loumaye A, Leclercq IA, Lanthier N. Myosteatosis: Diagnosis, pathophysiology and consequences in metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease. JHEP Rep. 2024;6:100963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10844870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38322420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamiliou A, Lekakis V, Chrysavgis L, Cholongitas E. Prevalence and impact on the outcome of myosteatosis in patients with cirrhosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hepatol Int. 2024;18:688&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11014812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38329701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MJ, Cho YK, Kim EH, Lee MJ, Lee WJ, Kim HK, Jung CH. Association between metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease and myosteatosis measured by computed tomography. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2024;15:1942&#x2013;1952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11446687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39011807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebadi M, Tsien C, Bhanji RA, Dunichand-Hoedl AR, Rider E, Motamedrad M, Mazurak VC, Baracos V, Montano-Loza AJ. Myosteatosis in Cirrhosis: A Review of Diagnosis, Pathophysiological Mechanisms and Potential Interventions. Cells. 2022;11:1216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8997850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35406780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geladari E, Alexopoulos T, Kontogianni MD, Vasilieva L, Mani I, Tenta R, Sevastianos V, Vlachogiannakos I, Alexopoulou A. The Presence of Myosteatosis Is Associated with Age, Severity of Liver Disease and Poor Outcome and May Represent a Prodromal Phase of Sarcopenia in Patients with Liver Cirrhosis. J Clin Med. 2023;12:3332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10179726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37176772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamiliou A, Lekakis V, Xynos G, Cholongitas E. Prevalence of and Impact on the Outcome of Myosteatosis in Patients with Hepatocellular Carcinoma: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Cancers (Basel) 2024;16:952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10930530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38473314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han E, Kim MK, Lee HW, Ryu S, Kim HS, Jang BK, Suh Y. Muscle fat contents rather than muscle mass determines nonalcoholic steatohepatitis and liver fibrosis in patients with severe obesity. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2022;30:2440&#x2013;2449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36319600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachit M, De Rudder M, Thissen JP, Schakman O, Bouzin C, Horsmans Y, Vande Velde G, Leclercq IA. Myosteatosis rather than sarcopenia associates with non-alcoholic steatohepatitis in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease preclinical models. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2021;12:144&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33244884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachit M, Kwanten WJ, Thissen JP, Op De Beeck B, Van Gaal L, Vonghia L, Verrijken A, Driessen A, Horsmans Y, Francque S, Leclercq IA. Muscle fat content is strongly associated with NASH: A longitudinal study in patients with morbid obesity. J Hepatol. 2021;75:292&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33865909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Rios RS, Wang XX, Yu Y, Zheng KI, Huang OY, Tang LJ, Ma HL, Jin Y, Targher G, Byrne CD, Pan XY, Zheng MH. Sex influences the association between appendicular skeletal muscle mass to visceral fat area ratio and non-alcoholic steatohepatitis in patients with biopsy-proven non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Br J Nutr. 2022;127:1613&#x2013;1620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34176541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HK, Bae SJ, Lee MJ, Kim EH, Park H, Kim HS, Cho YK, Jung CH, Lee WJ, Choe J. Association of Visceral Fat Obesity, Sarcopenia, and Myosteatosis with Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease without Obesity. Clin Mol Hepatol. 2023;29:987&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10577332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37403320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakegawa T, Sugimoto K, Saito K, Yunaiyama D, Araki Y, Wada T, Takahashi H, Yoshimasu Y, Takeuchi H, Itoi T. Favorable liver and skeletal muscle changes in patients with MASLD and T2DM receiving glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist: A prospective cohort study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2024;103:e38444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11155541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38847728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakravarthy MV, Siddiqui MS, Forsgren MF, Sanyal AJ. Harnessing Muscle-Liver Crosstalk to Treat Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2020;11:592373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33424768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rab&#xf8;l R, Petersen KF, Dufour S, Flannery C, Shulman GI. Reversal of muscle insulin resistance with exercise reduces postprandial hepatic de novo lipogenesis in insulin resistant individuals. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:13705&#x2013;13709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3158147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21808028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, Liu C, Xue Y, Wang J, Xue C, Yanagita T, Gao X, Wang Y. Long-term fatty liver-induced insulin resistance in orotic acid-induced nonalcoholic fatty liver rats. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2016;80:735&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26775542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gad H. Study of Plasma Adiponectin and Insulin Resistance in Subjects with Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease. Arch Gen Intern Med. 2018;2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamzina L, Veilleux A, Bergeron S, Marette A. Increased activation of the mammalian target of rapamycin pathway in liver and skeletal muscle of obese rats: possible involvement in obesity-linked insulin resistance. Endocrinology. 2005;146:1473&#x2013;1481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15604215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Lawrence JC Jr, Jung DY, Ko HJ, Keller SR, Kim JK, Magnuson MA, Harris TE. Fat cell-specific ablation of rictor in mice impairs insulin-regulated fat cell and whole-body glucose and lipid metabolism. Diabetes. 2010;59:1397&#x2013;1406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2874700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20332342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Yuan H, Niu Y, Niu W, Fu L. The role of AMPK/mTOR/S6K1 signaling axis in mediating the physiological process of exercise-induced insulin sensitization in skeletal muscle of C57BL/6 mice. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2012;1822:1716&#x2013;1726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22846606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivas DA, Yaspelkis BB 3rd, Hawley JA, Lessard SJ. Lipid-induced mTOR activation in rat skeletal muscle reversed by exercise and 5'-aminoimidazole-4-carboxamide-1-beta-D-ribofuranoside. J Endocrinol. 2009;202:441&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5055835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19574345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan Y, Pan X, Luo J, Xiao X, Li J, Bestman PL, Luo M. Association of Inflammatory Cytokines With Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease. Front Immunol. 2022;13:880298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vansaun MN, Mendonsa AM, Lee Gorden D. Hepatocellular proliferation correlates with inflammatory cell and cytokine changes in a murine model of nonalchoholic fatty liver disease. PLoS One. 2013;8:e73054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24039859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed AA, Shousha WG, Shaker O, Mahdy ME, Ibrahim EMA, Mohmoud S, Khairalla A. Role of Serum Adiponectin, IL-6 and Hs CRP in Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Egyptian Patients. IJBCRR. 2014;4:493&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kempinska-Podhorodecka A, Wunsch E, Milkiewicz P, Stachowska E, Milkiewicz M. The Association between SOCS1-1656G&gt;A Polymorphism, Insulin Resistance and Obesity in Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD) Patients. J Clin Med. 2019;8:1912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6912432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31717271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang LQ, Franck N, Egan B, Sj&#xf6;gren RJ, Katayama M, Duque-Guimaraes D, Arner P, Zierath JR, Krook A. Autocrine role of interleukin-13 on skeletal muscle glucose metabolism in type 2 diabetic patients involves microRNA let-7. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2013;305:E1359&#x2013;E1366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24105413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucarey JL, Trujillo-Gonz&#xe1;lez I, Paules EM, Espinosa A. Myokines and Their Potential Protective Role Against Oxidative Stress in Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease (MASLD) Antioxidants (Basel) 2024;13:1363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11591161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39594505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Sahar NE, Javaid HMA, Pak ES, Liang G, Wang Y, Ha H, Huh JY. Exercise-Induced Irisin Decreases Inflammation and Improves NAFLD by Competitive Binding with MD2. Cells. 2021;10:3306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8699279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34943814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong Q, Hu Z, Zhang F, Cui A, Chen X, Jiang H, Gao J, Chen X, Han Y, Liang Q, Ye D, Shi L, Chin YE, Wang Y, Xiao H, Guo F, Liu Y, Zang M, Xu A, Li Y. Fibroblast growth factor 21 improves hepatic insulin sensitivity by inhibiting mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 in mice. Hepatology. 2016;64:425&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5726522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26926384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camporez JP, Jornayvaz FR, Petersen MC, Pesta D, Guigni BA, Serr J, Zhang D, Kahn M, Samuel VT, Jurczak MJ, Shulman GI. Cellular mechanisms by which FGF21 improves insulin sensitivity in male mice. Endocrinology. 2013;154:3099&#x2013;3109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3749479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23766126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z, Tian H, Lam KS, Lin S, Hoo RC, Konishi M, Itoh N, Wang Y, Bornstein SR, Xu A, Li X. Adiponectin mediates the metabolic effects of FGF21 on glucose homeostasis and insulin sensitivity in mice. Cell Metab. 2013;17:779&#x2013;789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23663741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartesaghi S, Wallenius K, Hovdal D, Liljeblad M, Wallin S, Dekker N, Barlind L, Davies N, Seeliger F, Winzell MS, Patel S, Theisen M, Brito L, Bergenhem N, Andersson S, Peng XR. Subcutaneous delivery of FGF21 mRNA therapy reverses obesity, insulin resistance, and hepatic steatosis in diet-induced obese mice. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids. 2022;28:500&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9079007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35592498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano K, Yamaguchi K, Seko Y, Okishio S, Ishiba H, Tochiki N, Takahashi A, Kataoka S, Okuda K, Liu Y, Fujii H, Umemura A, Moriguchi M, Okanoue T, Itoh Y. Hepatocyte-specific fibroblast growth factor 21 overexpression ameliorates high-fat diet-induced obesity and liver steatosis in mice. Lab Invest. 2022;102:281&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34732847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makarova E, Kazantseva A, Dubinina A, Denisova E, Jakovleva T, Balybina N, Bgatova N, Baranov K, Bazhan N. Fibroblast Growth Factor 21 (FGF21) Administration Sex-Specifically Affects Blood Insulin Levels and Liver Steatosis in Obese A(y) Mice. Cells. 2021;10:3440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8700098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34943946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falamarzi K, Malekpour M, Tafti MF, Azarpira N, Behboodi M, Zarei M. The role of FGF21 and its analogs on liver associated diseases. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022;9:967375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9705724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36457562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin R, Banton S, Tran VT, Konomi JV, Li S, Jones DP, Vos MB. Amino Acid Metabolism is Altered in Adolescents with Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease-An Untargeted, High Resolution Metabolomics Study. J Pediatr. 2016;172:14&#x2013;19.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5321134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26858195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby A, Secher A, Lage K, Nordsborg NB, Dmytriyev A, Lundby C, Olsen JV. Quantitative maps of protein phosphorylation sites across 14 different rat organs and tissues. Nat Commun. 2012;3:876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3621391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22673903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JK, Fillmore JJ, Sunshine MJ, Albrecht B, Higashimori T, Kim DW, Liu ZX, Soos TJ, Cline GW, O'Brien WR, Littman DR, Shulman GI. PKC-theta knockout mice are protected from fat-induced insulin resistance. J Clin Invest. 2004;114:823&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC516267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15372106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilon G, Charbonneau A, White PJ, Dallaire P, Perreault M, Kapur S, Marette A. Endotoxin mediated-iNOS induction causes insulin resistance via ONOO&#x207b; induced tyrosine nitration of IRS-1 in skeletal muscle. PLoS One. 2010;5:e15912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3011021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21206533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon SE, Fl&#xfc;ck M, Booth FW. Selected Contribution: Skeletal muscle focal adhesion kinase, paxillin, and serum response factor are loading dependent. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2001;90:1174&#x2013;83; discussion 1165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11181634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang DD, Turner CE, Gunst SJ. Expression of non-phosphorylatable paxillin mutants in canine tracheal smooth muscle inhibits tension development. J Physiol. 2003;553:21&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12949231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoteit M, Dagher M, Tzenios N, Al Kaaki N, Rkein G, Chahine AR, Sacre Y, Hotayt S, Matar R, Hallal M, Maitar M, Hotayt B. Influence of Sugar-Sweetened Beverages Intake on Sarcopenic Obesity, Visceral Obesity, and Sarcopenia in Lebanese Patients with MASLD: A Case-Control Study. Healthcare (Basel) 2024;12:591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10931226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38470703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long MT, Noureddin M, Lim JK. AGA Clinical Practice Update: Diagnosis and Management of Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease in Lean Individuals: Expert Review. Gastroenterology. 2022;163:764&#x2013;774.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9398982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwimmer JB, Ugalde-Nicalo P, Welsh JA, Angeles JE, Cordero M, Harlow KE, Alazraki A, Durelle J, Knight-Scott J, Newton KP, Cleeton R, Knott C, Konomi J, Middleton MS, Travers C, Sirlin CB, Hernandez A, Sekkarie A, McCracken C, Vos MB. Effect of a Low Free Sugar Diet vs Usual Diet on Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease in Adolescent Boys: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA. 2019;321:256&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6440226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30667502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutoukidis DA, Koshiaris C, Henry JA, Noreik M, Morris E, Manoharan I, Tudor K, Bodenham E, Dunnigan A, Jebb SA, Aveyard P. The effect of the magnitude of weight loss on non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Metabolism. 2021;115:154455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33259835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilar-Gomez E, Martinez-Perez Y, Calzadilla-Bertot L, Torres-Gonzalez A, Gra-Oramas B, Gonzalez-Fabian L, Friedman SL, Diago M, Romero-Gomez M. Weight Loss Through Lifestyle Modification Significantly Reduces Features of Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis. Gastroenterology. 2015;149:367&#x2013;78.e5; quiz e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25865049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selezneva KS, Isakov VA, Sentsova TB, Kirillova OO. [An analysis of the efficacy of low-calorie and isocaloric diets in obese patients with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis] Vopr Pitan. 2014;83:72&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25816629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rachakonda V, Wills R, DeLany JP, Kershaw EE, Behari J. Differential Impact of Weight Loss on Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Resolution in a North American Cohort with Obesity. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2017;25:1360&#x2013;1368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28605159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand AC. Nutrition and Muscle in Cirrhosis. J Clin Exp Hepatol. 2017;7:340&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5719462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29234200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaskolka Meir A, Rinott E, Tsaban G, Zelicha H, Kaplan A, Rosen P, Shelef I, Youngster I, Shalev A, Bl&#xfc;her M, Ceglarek U, Stumvoll M, Tuohy K, Diotallevi C, Vrhovsek U, Hu F, Stampfer M, Shai I. Effect of green-Mediterranean diet on intrahepatic fat: the DIRECT PLUS randomised controlled trial. Gut. 2021;70:2085&#x2013;2095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin-Alejandre BA, Cantero I, Perez-Diaz-Del-Campo N, Monreal JI, Elorz M, Herrero JI, Benito-Boillos A, Quiroga J, Martinez-Echeverria A, Uriz-Otano JI, Huarte-Muniesa MP, Tur JA, Martinez JA, Abete I, Zulet MA. Effects of two personalized dietary strategies during a 2-year intervention in subjects with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: A randomized trial. Liver Int. 2021;41:1532&#x2013;1544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33550706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulou SK, Detopoulou P, Voulgaridou G, Tsoumana D, Spanoudaki M, Sadikou F, Papadopoulou VG, Zidrou C, Chatziprodromidou IP, Giaginis C, Nikolaidis P. Mediterranean Diet and Sarcopenia Features in Apparently Healthy Adults over 65 Years: A Systematic Review. Nutrients. 2023;15:1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10005300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36904104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreo-L&#xf3;pez MC, Contreras-Bol&#xed;var V, Garc&#xed;a-Fontana B, Garc&#xed;a-Fontana C, Mu&#xf1;oz-Torres M. The Influence of the Mediterranean Dietary Pattern on Osteoporosis and Sarcopenia. Nutrients. 2023;15:3224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10385532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37513646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez LJ, Veronese N, Smith L, Ragusa FS, Schir&#xf2; P, Di Bella G, Barbagallo M. Associations Between Adherence to the Mediterranean Diet and Incident Sarcopenia in Prospective Cohort Studies. Nutrients. 2025;17:313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11768633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39861443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacciatore S, Calvani R, Marzetti E, Picca A, Coelho-J&#xfa;nior HJ, Martone AM, Massaro C, Tosato M, Landi F. Low Adherence to Mediterranean Diet Is Associated with Probable Sarcopenia in Community-Dwelling Older Adults: Results from the Longevity Check-Up (Lookup) 7+ Project. Nutrients. 2023;15:1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9959184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36839385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazri NSM, Vanoh D, Soo KL. Natural Food for Sarcopenia: A Narrative Review. Malays J Med Sci. 2022;29:28&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9438863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36101538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granic A, Sayer AA, Cooper R, Robinson SM. Nutrition in the prevention and treatment of skeletal muscle ageing and sarcopenia: a single nutrient, a whole food and a whole diet approach. Proc Nutr Soc. 2024:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7616828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39417264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagherniya M, Mahdavi A, Shokri-Mashhadi N, Banach M, Von Haehling S, Johnston TP, Sahebkar A. The beneficial therapeutic effects of plant-derived natural products for the treatment of sarcopenia. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:2772&#x2013;2790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9745475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35961944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayakrishnan V, Kannappan P, Balakarthikeyan J, Kim CY. Rodent model intervention for prevention and optimal management of sarcopenia: A systematic review on the beneficial effects of nutrients &amp; non-nutrients and exercise to improve skeletal muscle health. Ageing Res Rev. 2024;102:102543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39427886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musso G, Pinach S, Mariano F, Saba F, De Michieli F, Framarin L, Berrutti M, Paschetta E, Parente R, Lizet Castillo Y, Leone N, Castellino F, Cassader M, Gambino R. Effect of phospholipid curcumin Meriva on liver histology and kidney disease in nonalcoholic steatohepatitis: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Hepatology. 2025;81:560&#x2013;575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38809154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rondanelli M, Gasparri C, Barrile GC, Battaglia S, Cavioni A, Giusti R, Mansueto F, Moroni A, Nannipieri F, Patelli Z, Razza C, Tartara A, Perna S. Effectiveness of a Novel Food Composed of Leucine, Omega-3 Fatty Acids and Probiotic Lactobacillus paracasei PS23 for the Treatment of Sarcopenia in Elderly Subjects: A 2-Month Randomized Double-Blind Placebo-Controlled Trial. Nutrients. 2022;14:4566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9656258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36364828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besora-Moreno M, Llaurad&#xf3; E, Valls RM, Tarro L, Pedret A, Sol&#xe0; R. Antioxidant-rich foods, antioxidant supplements, and sarcopenia in old-young adults &#x2265;55 years old: A systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies and randomized controlled trials. Clin Nutr. 2022;41:2308&#x2013;2324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36099667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SH, Bae YJ. Association of Dietary Vegetable and Fruit Consumption with Sarcopenia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Nutrients. 2024;16:1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11174889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38892640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong F, Liu Y, Lebaka VR, Mohammed A, Ye W, Chen B, Korivi M. Effect of Exercise Training on Serum Transaminases in Patients With Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Front Physiol. 2022;13:894044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9273783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35837021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Peng Q, Cao C, Xu Z, Zhang B. Effect of Different Exercise Methods on Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease: A Meta-Analysis and Meta-Regression. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:3242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33801028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu L, Zhang W, Ao Y, Zheng Z, Hu H. Efficacy of aerobic and resistance exercises in improving visceral adipose in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Z Gastroenterol. 2022;60:1644&#x2013;1658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9661875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#x142;omko J, Zalewska M, Niemiro W, Kujawski S, S&#x142;upski M, Januszko-Giergielewicz B, Zawadka-Kunikowska M, Newton J, Hodges L, Kubica J, Zalewski P. Evidence-Based Aerobic Exercise Training in Metabolic-Associated Fatty Liver Disease: Systematic Review with Meta-Analysis. J Clin Med. 2021;10:1659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8069623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33924482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Song Y, Zhu J, Ding P, Chen N. Effectiveness of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction vs. conventional high-intensity resistance training in older people diagnosed with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2024;14:28427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11574083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39558011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morcillo-Losa JA, D&#xed;az-Mart&#xed;nez MDP, Ceylan H&#x130;, Moreno-Vecino B, Bragazzi NL, P&#xe1;rraga Montilla J. Effects of High-Intensity Interval Training on Muscle Strength for the Prevention and Treatment of Sarcopenia in Older Adults: A Systematic Review of the Literature. J Clin Med. 2024;13:1299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10931549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38592165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessier AJ, Chevalier S. An Update on Protein, Leucine, Omega-3 Fatty Acids, and Vitamin D in the Prevention and Treatment of Sarcopenia and Functional Decline. Nutrients. 2018;10:1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6116139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30115829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Connolly ED, Cross HR, Wu G. Dietary protein and amino acid intakes for mitigating sarcopenia in humans. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2025;65:2538&#x2013;2561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38803274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang HH, Wang YJ, Jiang HY, Yu HW, Chen YQ, Chiou A, Kuo JC. Sarcopenia-related changes in serum GLP-1 level affect myogenic differentiation. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2024;15:1708&#x2013;1721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11446708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38926763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong J, Park S, Kim TH, Lee JE, Cho H, Oh J, Lee S, Jo H, Lee H, Lee K, Park J, Jacob L, Pizzol D, Rhee SY, Kim S, Yon DK. Worldwide burden of antidiabetic drug-induced sarcopenia: An international pharmacovigilance study. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2025;129:105656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39447350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng F, Wu W, Fan X, Zhong X, Wang N, Wang Y, Pan T, Du Y. Dulaglutide Protects Mice against Diabetic Sarcopenia-Mediated Muscle Injury by Inhibiting Inflammation and Regulating the Differentiation of Myoblasts. Int J Endocrinol. 2023;2023:9926462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10425251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37584041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao R, Lin C, Cai X, Wang J, Wang Y, Lv F, Yang W, Ji L. Characterizing body composition modifying effects of a glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor-based agonist: A meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2025;27:259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39431379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang J, Qin L, Zhong J, Xia N, Liang Y. GLP-1RA Liraglutide and Semaglutide Improves Obesity-Induced Muscle Atrophy via SIRT1 Pathway. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. 2023;16:2433&#x2013;2446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10439806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37602204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linge J, Birkenfeld AL, Neeland IJ. Muscle Mass and Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists: Adaptive or Maladaptive Response to Weight Loss? Circulation. 2024;150:1288&#x2013;1298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39401279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeland IJ, Linge J, Birkenfeld AL. Changes in lean body mass with glucagon-like peptide-1-based therapies and mitigation strategies. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2024;26 Suppl 4:16&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38937282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanim H, Chaudhuri A, Hejna J, Dandona P. 12608 Preserving Lean Body Mass During Weight Loss In Elderly Obese Patients With Glp-1 Receptor Agonist Treatment. J Endocr Soc. 2024;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunn E, Jaiswal N, Gavin M, Uehara K, Stefkovich M, Drareni K, Calhoun R, Lee M, Holman CD, Baur JA, Seale P, Titchenell PM. Antibody blockade of activin type II receptors preserves skeletal muscle mass and enhances fat loss during GLP-1 receptor agonism. Mol Metab. 2024;80:101880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10832506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38218536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastaitis J, Gomez D, Le Rouzic V, Stec M, Khan N, Na E, Mcwilliams T, Min S, Sleeman M. 207-OR: Myostatin Inhibition Synergizes with GLP-1R Agonism to Accelerate Weight Loss in Male, Obese Nonhuman Primates. Diabetes. 2023;72</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianping W, Xuelian Z, Anjiang W, Haiying X. Efficacy and Safety of Glucagon-like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists in the Treatment of Metabolic Associated Fatty Liver Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2021;55:586&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34039937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njei B, Al-Ajlouni Y, Lemos SY, Ugwendum D, Ameyaw P, Njei LP, Boateng S. Efficacy and Safety of GLP-1 Receptor Agonists in Patients With Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Cureus. 2024;16:e71366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11556413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39534801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forlano R, Malik H, Mullish BH, Yee M, Izzi&#x2010;engbeaya C, Manousou P. The beneficial hepatic effects of glucagon&#x2010;like peptide 1 receptor agonists in patients with diabetes and metabolic dysfunction&#x2010;associated steatotic liver disease are independent of weight loss. Liver Int. 2024;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwamoto Y, Kimura T, Dan K, Iwamoto H, Sanada J, Fushimi Y, Katakura Y, Shimoda M, Yamasaki Y, Nogami Y, Shirakiya Y, Nakanishi S, Mune T, Kaku K, Kaneto H. Tirzepatide, a dual glucose-dependent insulinotropic polypeptide/glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor agonist, exhibits favourable effects on pancreatic &#x3b2;-cells and hepatic steatosis in obese type 2 diabetic db/db mice. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2024;26:5982&#x2013;5994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39344853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawamura T, Mizoguchi R, Ohmori A, Kometani M, Yoneda T, Karashima S. Effects of the switch from dulaglutide to tirzepatide on glycemic control, body weight, and fatty liver: a retrospective study. J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2024;23:2105&#x2013;2113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11599550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39610482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loomba R, Hartman ML, Lawitz EJ, Vuppalanchi R, Boursier J, Bugianesi E, Yoneda M, Behling C, Cummings OW, Tang Y, Brouwers B, Robins DA, Nikooie A, Bunck MC, Haupt A, Sanyal AJ SYNERGY-NASH Investigators. Tirzepatide for Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatohepatitis with Liver Fibrosis. N Engl J Med. 2024;391:299&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38856224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>