<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24278871</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2288-176X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of long-term resistance exercise on body composition, blood lipid factors, and vascular compliance in the hypertensive elderly men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>271</StartPage><EndPage>277</EndPage><MedlinePgn>271-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12965/jer.130010</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hypertension is designated as either essential (primary) hypertension or secondary hypertension and is defined as a consistently elevated blood pressure exceeding 140/90 mmHg. Hypertension is called "the silent killer" because it often causes no symptoms for many years, even decades, until it finally damages certain critical organs. In various causes of hypertension, obesity is an increasing health problem worldwide, and several epidemiological studies have identified a positive association between obesity and an increased incidence of hypertension. Therefore, in the present study, we investigated the effect of long-term resistance exercise on body composition, blood lipid profile, vascular compliance, and blood pressure in the elderly men. For this study, the In-Body test, blood lipid profile, and analysis of vascular compliance and blood pressure were performing before and after in experiment. The twenty male subjects aged between 68 and 72 yr were recruited from the 'Y' senior towers in Korea. All subjects performed exercises on a weight training machines 40 min once a day for 52 weeks. The exercise intensity for resistance training was 60% of the 10 RM maximal voluntary contraction test. All subjects before performing resistance exercise showed an increase in hypertension following enhanced %fat, blood lipid factors (TC, LDL-C), whereas decreased lean body mass (LBM), vascular compliance. However, 52 weeks of resistance exercise suppressed %fat and LDL-C, whereas improved LBM, vascular compliance, resulting in reducing hypertensive levels in the elderly men. We suggest that resistance exercise can be a valuable tool for the remarkable improvement of hypertension.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyun-Sub</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Sports, College of Natural Science, Dae Jeon University, Daejeon, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Dae-Geun</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2288-176X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood lipid profile</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular compliance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24278871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.130010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jer-9-2-10-271_277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acelajado MC, Oparil S. Hypertension in the elderly. Clin Geriatr Med. 2009;25:391&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19765488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghamohammadzadeh R, Heagerty AM. Obesity-related hypertension: epidemiology, pathophysiology, treatments, and the contribution of perivascular adipose tissue. Ann Med. 2012;44:S74&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22713152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand: the recommended quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory and muscular fitness, and flexibility in healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30:975&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9624661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baigent C, Keech A, Kearney PM, Blackwell L, Buck G, Pollicino C, Kirby A, Sourjina T, Peto R, Collins R, Simes R, Cholesterol Treatment Trial-ists&#x2019; (CTT) Collaborators Efficacy and safety of cholesterol-lowering treatment: prospective meta-analysis of data from 90,056 participants in 14 randomised trials of statins. Lancet. 2005;366:1267&#x2013;1278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16214597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakris GL. Current perspectives on hypertension and metabolic syndrome. J Manag Care Pharm. 2007;13:S3&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10438322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17605509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battagin AM, Dal Corso S, Soares CL, Ferreira S, Let&#xed;cia A, Souza Cd, Malaguti C. Pressure response after resistance exercise for different body segments in hypertensive people. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2010;95:405&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20802964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjarnason-Wehrens B, Mayer-Berger W, Meister ER, Baum K, Hambrecht R, Gielen S. Recommendations for resistance exercise in cardiac rehabilitation. Recommendations of the German Federation for Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil. 2004;11:352&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacher J, Guerin AP, Pannier B, Marchais SJ, Safar ME, London GM. Impact of aortic stiffness on survival in end-stage renal disease. Circulation. 1999;19:2434&#x2013;2439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10318666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlberg B, Nilsson PM. Hypertension in the elderly: what is the goal blood pressure target and how can this be attained? Curr Hypertens Rep. 2010;12:331&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Hemmelgarn B, Alhaider S, Quan H, Campbell N, Rabi D. Meta-analysis of adverse cardiovascular outcomes associated with antecedent hypertension after myocardial infarction. Am J Cardiol. 2009;104:141&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19576336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Fagard RH. Effect of resistance training on resting blood pressure: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Hypertens. 2005;23:251&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15662209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cottell KE, Dorfman LR, Straight CR, Delmonico MJ, Lofgren IE. The effects of diet education plus light resistance training on coronary heart disease risk factors in community-dwelling older adults. J Nutr Health Aging. 2011;15:762&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickerson LM, Gibson MV. Management of hypertension in older persons. Am Fam Physician. 2005;71:469&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15712622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagard RH, Cornelissen VA. Effect of exercise on blood pressure control in hypertensive patients. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil. 2007;14:12&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17301622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagard RH. Exercise is good for your blood pressure: effects of endurance training and resistance training. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2006;33:853&#x2013;856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16922820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros I, Taxildaris K, Tokmakidis S, Kalapotharakos V, Aggelousis N, Athanasopoulos S, Zeeris I, Katrabasas I. The effects of strength training, cardiovascular training and their combination on flexibility of inactive older adults. Int J Sports Med. 2002;23:112&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11842358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelecek N, Il&#xe7;in N, Suba&#x15f;i SS, Acar S, Demir N, Ormen M. The effects of resistance training on cardiovascular disease risk factors in postmenopausal women: a randomized-controlled trial. Health Care Women Int. 2012;33:1072&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry SL, Barzel B, Wood-Bradley RJ, Burke SL, Head GA, Armitage JA. The developmental origins of obesity related hypertension. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2012;39:799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21801195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;n Jim&#xe9;nez O, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R. Strength training improves insulin sensitivity and plasma lipid levels without altering body composition in overweight and obese subjects. Endocrinol Nutr. 2011;58:169&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21459690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, Price TB, Hoffman EP, Angelopoulos TJ, Gordon PM, Moyna NM, Pescatello LS, Visich PS, Zoeller RF, Seip RL, Clarkson PM. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karagiannis A, Hatzitolios AI, Athyros VG, Deligianni K, Charalambous C, Papathanakis C, Theodosiou G, Drakidis T, Chatzikaloudi V, Kamilali C, Matsiras S, Matziris A, Savopoulos C, Baltatzi M, Rudolf J, Tziomalos K, Mikhailidis DP. Implementation of guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension. The impulsion study. Open Cardiovasc Med J. 2009;3:26&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19557149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea Centers for Disease Control and Prevention 2010 Korean National Health Statistics. Korea: Home office; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotchen TA. Obesity-related hypertension: epidemiology, pathophysiology, and clinical management. Am J Hypertens. 2010;23:1170&#x2013;1178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20706196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamina S, Okoye GC. Therapeutic effect of a moderate intensity interval training program on the lipid profile in men with hypertension: a randomized controlled trial. Niger J Clin Pract. 2012;15:42&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22437088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo MS, Lin LL, Yao WJ, Ma MC. Training and detraining effects of the resistance vs. endurance program on body composition, body size, and physical performance in young men. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:2246&#x2013;2254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota MR, Pardono E, Lima LC, Arsa G, Bottaro M, Campbell CS, Sim&#xf5;es HG. Effects of treadmill running and resistance exercises on lowering blood pressure during the daily work of hypertensive subjects. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:2331&#x2013;2338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19826291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nindl BC, Harman EA, Marx JO, Gotshalk LA, Frykman PN, Lammi E, Palmer C, Kraemer WJ. Regional body composition changes in women after 6 months of periodized physical training. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:2251&#x2013;2259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr JS, Dengo AL, Rivero JM, Davy KP. Arterial destiffening with atorvastatin in overweight and obese middle-aged and older adults. Hypertension. 2009;54:763&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19687343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS, Franklin BA, Fagard RH, Farguhar WB, Kelley GA, Ray CA. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and hypertension. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:533&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15076798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safar ME, Balkau B, Lange C, Protogerou AD, Czernichow S, Blacher J, Levy BI, Smulyan H. Hypertension and vascular dynamics in men and women with metabolic syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013;61:12&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23287369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidell JC, Visscher TL. Body weight and weight change and their health implications for the elderly. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2000;54:S33&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11041073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treuth MS, Ryan AS, Pratley RE, Rubin MA, Miller JP, Nicklas BJ, Sorkin J, Harman SM, Goldberg AP, Hurley BF. Effects of strength training on total and regional body composition in older men. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77:614&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8002507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JG, Staessen JA, Franklin SS, Fagard R, Gueyffier F. Systolic and diastolic blood pressure lowering as determinants of cardiovascular outcome. Hypertension. 2005;45:907&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15837826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson NL, Sutton-Tyrrell K, Rosano C, Boudreau RM, Hardy SE, Simonsick EM, Najjar SS, Launer LJ, Yaffe K, Atkinson HH, Satterfield S, Newman AB. Arterial stiffness and cognitive decline in well-functioning older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011;66:1336&#x2013;1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3210954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21768503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Haskell WL, Ades PA, Amsterdam EA, Bittner V, Franklin BA, Gulanick M, Laing ST, Stewart KJ, American Heart Association Council on Clinical Cardiology; American Heart Association Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism Resistance exercise in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: 2007 update: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association Council on Clinical Cardiology and Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism. Circulation. 2007;116:572&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17638929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>