<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24740742</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2190-5991</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cachexia, sarcopenia and muscle</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Osteosarcopenic obesity: the role of bone, muscle, and fat on health.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>183</StartPage><EndPage>192</EndPage><MedlinePgn>183-92</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13539-014-0146-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Osteopenia/osteoporosis, sarcopenia, and obesity are commonly observed in the process of aging, and recent evidence suggests a potential interconnection of these syndromes with common pathophysiology. The term osteosarcopenic obesity has been coined to describe the concurrent appearance of obesity in individuals with low bone and muscle mass. Although our understanding of osteosarcopenic obesity's etiology, prevalence, and consequences is extremely limited, it is reasonable to infer its negative impact in a population that is aging in an obesogenic environment. It is likely that these individuals will present with poorer clinical outcomes caused by the cascade of metabolic abnormalities associated with these changes in body composition. Clinical outcomes include but are not limited to increased risk of fractures, impaired functional status (including activities of daily living), physical disability, insulin resistance, increased risk of infections, increased length of hospital stay, and reduced survival. These health outcomes are likely to be worse when compared to individuals with obesity, sarcopenia, or osteopenia/osteoporosis alone. Interventions that utilize resistance training exercise in conjunction with increased protein intake appear to be promising in their ability to counteract osteosarcopenic obesity.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ormsbee</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Food and Exercise Sciences, The Florida State University, 120 Convocation Way, Tallahassee, FL, 32306-1493, USA, mormsbee@fsu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prado</LastName><ForeName>Carla M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilich</LastName><ForeName>Jasminka Z</ForeName><Initials>JZ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purcell</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siervo</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Folsom</LastName><ForeName>Abbey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panton</LastName><ForeName>Lynn</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101552883</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2190-5991</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24740742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4159494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13539-014-0146-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Maia YL, Ormsbee M, Sawyer MB, Baracos VE. Assessment of nutritional status in cancer&#x2014;the relationship between body composition and pharmacokinetics. Anti Cancer Agents Med Chem. 2013;13:1197&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23919745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilich JZ, Brownbill RA. Habitual and low-impact activities are associated with better bone outcomes and lower body fat in older women. Calcif Tissue Int. 2008;83:260&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18815824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilich-Ernst J, Brownbill RA, Ludemann MA, Fu R. Critical factors for bone health in women across the age span: how important is muscle mass? Medscape Womens Health. 2002;7:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12142855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Force USPST. Screening for osteoporosis: recommendation statement. Am Fam Physician. 2011;83:1197&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21568254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burge R, Dawson-Hughes B, Solomon DH, Wong JB, King A, Tosteson A. Incidence and economic burden of osteoporosis-related fractures in the United States, 2005&#x2013;2025. J Bone Miner Res. 2007;22:465&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17144789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen CJ. Primer on the metabolic bone diseases and disorders of mineral metabolism. New York: Wiley; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewiecki EM, Watts NB, McClung MR, Petak SM, Bachrach LK, Shepherd JA, et al. Official positions of the international society for clinical densitometry. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89:3651&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman TG, Chen Z. Dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry. In: Heymsfield SB, Lohman T, Wang Z, Going S, editors. Human body composition. 2nd ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2005. p. 523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R, Kehayias JJ, Dawson-Hughes B, Heymsfield SB. Use of dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry in body-composition studies: not yet a gold standard". Am J Clin Nutr. 1993;58:589&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8237861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Wang Z, Baumgartner RN, Ross R. Human body composition: advances in models and methods. Annu Rev Nutr. 1997;17:527&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9240939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus R, Kosek J, Pfefferbaum A, Horning S. Age-related loss of trabecular bone in premenopausal women: a biopsy study. Calcif Tissue Int. 1983;35:406&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6616313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggs BL, Wahner HW, Dunn WL, Mazess RB, Offord KP, Melton 3rd LJ. Differential changes in bone mineral density of the appendicular and axial skeleton with aging: relationship to spinal osteoporosis. J Clin Invest. 1981;67:328&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC370572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7462421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes MR. Effects of aging on muscle fibre type and size. Sports Med. 2004;34:809&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15462613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Smith R, Aulet M, Bensen B, Lichtman S, Wang J, et al. Appendicular skeletal muscle mass: measurement by dual-photon absorptiometry. Am J Clin Nutr. 1990;52:214&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2375286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbe0rg I. The epidemiologic and methodologic problems in determining nutritional status of older persons. (Summary comments). Am J Clin Nutr. 1989;50:1231&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2816807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, Boirie Y, Cederholm T, Landi F, et al. Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: report of the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People. Age Ageing. 2010;39:412&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Park SW, Harris TB, Kritchevsky SB, Nevitt M, Schwartz AV, et al. The loss of skeletal muscle strength, mass, and quality in older adults: the health, aging and body composition study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61:1059&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17077199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Baumgartner RN, Ross R, Rosenberg IH, Roubenoff R. Skeletal muscle cutpoints associated with elevated physical disability risk in older men and women. Am J Epidemiol. 2004;159:413&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN, Koehler KM, Gallagher D, Romero L, Heymsfield SB, Ross RR, et al. Epidemiology of sarcopenia among the elderly in New Mexico. Am J Epidemiol. 1998;147:755&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9554417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN. Body composition in healthy aging. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2000;904:437&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Wells JC, Smith SR, Stephan BC, Siervo M. Sarcopenic obesity: a critical appraisal of the current evidence. Clin Nutr. 2012;31:583&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22809635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauretani F, Russo CR, Bandinelli S, Bartali B, Cavazzini C, Di Iorio A, et al. Age-associated changes in skeletal muscles and their effect on mobility: an operational diagnosis of sarcopenia. J Appl Physiol. 2003;95:1851&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14555665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland Y, Czerwinski S, Abellan Van Kan G, Morley JE, Cesari M, Onder G, et al. Sarcopenia: its assessment, etiology, pathogenesis, consequences and future perspectives. J Nutr Health Aging. 2008;12:433&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3988678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18615225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang T, Streeper T, Cawthon P, Baldwin K, Taaffe DR, Harris TB. Sarcopenia: etiology, clinical consequences, intervention, and assessment. Osteoporos Int. 2010;21:543&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2832869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19779761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Obesity: preventing and managing the global epidemic. WHO obesity technical report series 894. Geneva: World Health Organization 2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11234459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidell JC, Flegal KM. Assessing obesity: classification and epidemiology. Br Med Bull. 1997;53:238&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9246834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi-Sunyer FX. Obesity: criteria and classification. Proc Nutr Soc. 2000;59:505&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1017/S0029665100000732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0029665100000732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11115784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Physical status: the use and interpretation of anthropometry. Report of a WHO Expert Committee. World Health Organ Tech Rep Ser. 1995;854:1&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8594834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN, Wayne SJ, Waters DL, Janssen I, Gallagher D, Morley JE. Sarcopenic obesity predicts instrumental activities of daily living disability in the elderly. Obes Res. 2004;12:1995&#x2013;2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15687401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher D, Visser M, De Meersman RE, Sepulveda D, Baumgartner RN, Pierson RN, et al. Appendicular skeletal muscle mass: effects of age, gender, and ethnicity. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:229&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9216968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lean ME, Han TS, Morrison CE. Waist circumference as a measure for indicating need for weight management. BMJ. 1995;311:158&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2550221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7613427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention. National obesity trends. In: Services USDoHaH, ed. Atlanta: Center for Disease Control and Prevention; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R. Sarcopenic obesity: does muscle loss cause fat gain? Lessons from rheumatoid arthritis and osteoarthritis. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2000;904:553&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R. Sarcopenic obesity: the confluence of two epidemics. Obes Res. 2004;12:887&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15229325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamboni M, Mazzali G, Fantin F, Rossi A, Di Francesco V. Sarcopenic obesity: a new category of obesity in the elderly. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2008;18:388&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binkley N, Buehring B. Beyond FRAX: it's time to consider "sarco-osteopenia". J Clin Densitom. 2009;12:413&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19733110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sowers MF, Kshirsagar A, Crutchfield MM, Updike S. Joint influence of fat and lean body composition compartments on femoral bone mineral density in premenopausal women. Am J Epidemiol. 1992;136:257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1415147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sowers M, Kshirsagar A, Crutchfield M, Updike S. Body composition, age and femoral bone mass of young adult women. Ann Epidemiol. 1991;1:245&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1669505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burr DB. Muscle strength, bone mass, and age-related bone loss. J Bone Miner Res. 1997;12:1547&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9333114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proctor DN, Melton LJ, Khosla S, Crowson CS, O'Connor MK, Riggs BL. Relative influence of physical activity, muscle mass and strength on bone density. Osteoporos Int. 2000;11:944&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11193247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost HM. On our age-related bone loss: insights from a new paradigm. J Bone Miner Res. 1997;12:1539&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9333113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost HM. Mechanical usage, bone mass, bone fragility: a brief overview. In: Kleerekoper M, Krane SM, editors. Clinical disorders of bone and mineral metabolism: proceedings of the Laurence and Dorothy Fallis International Symposium. New York: Mary Ann Liebert; 1989. pp. 15&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenholm S, Harris TB, Rantanen T, Visser M, Kritchevsky SB, Ferrucci L. Sarcopenic obesity: definition, cause and consequences. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2008;11:693&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2633408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18827572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzat-Zadeh Z, Dodge BG, Elam M, Feresin R, Browne J, Kim JS et al., eds. The underlying mechanisms by which estrogen regulates energy metabolism and body composition. FASEB J. 2012;26:56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopelman PG. Obesity as a medical problem. Nature. 2000;404:635&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10766250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer MR, Clegg DJ, Prossnitz ER, Barton M. Obesity, insulin resistance and diabetes: sex differences and role of oestrogen receptors. Acta Physiol. 2011;203:259&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3110567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21281456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issa RI, Griffin TM. Pathobiology of obesity and osteoarthritis: integrating biomechanics and inflammation. Pathobiol Aging Age Relat Dis. 2012;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3364606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22662293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Heber D. Sarcopenic obesity in the elderly and strategies for weight management. Nutr Rev. 2012;70:57&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22221216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malafarina V, Uriz-Otano F, Iniesta R, Gil-Guerrero L. Sarcopenia in the elderly: diagnosis, physiopathology and treatment. Maturitas. 2012;71:109&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22153348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton LA, Sumukadas D. Optimal management of sarcopenia. Clin Interv Aging. 2010;5:217&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20852669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilich, J. Z., Kelly, O. J., Inglis, J. E., Panton, L. B., Duque, G., &amp; Ormsbee, M. J. Interrelationship among muscle, fat, and bone: connecting the dots on cellular, hormonal, and whole body levels. Ageing Res Rev. 2014;15C;51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24632496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai AG, Williamson DF, Glick HA. Direct medical cost of overweight and obesity in the USA: a quantitative systematic review. Obes Rev. 2011;12:50&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2891924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20059703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trogdon JG, Finkelstein EA, Hylands T, Dellea PS, Kamal-Bahl SJ. Indirect costs of obesity: a review of the current literature. Obes Rev. 2008;9:489&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18331420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Shepard DS, Katzmarzyk PT, Roubenoff R. The healthcare costs of sarcopenia in the United States. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004;52:80&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsini LS, Rousculp MD, Long SR, Wang S. Health care utilization and expenditures in the United States: a study of osteoporosis-related fractures. Osteoporos Int. 2005;16:359&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15340799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens GA, Singh GM, Lu Y, Danaei G, Lin JK, Finucane MM, et al. National, regional, and global trends in adult overweight and obesity prevalences. Popul Health Metrics. 2012;10:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23167948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flegal KM, Carroll MD, Ogden CL, Curtin LR. Prevalence and trends in obesity among US adults, 1999-2008. JAMA. 2010;303:235&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20071471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health. Clinical guidelines on the identification, evaluation, and treatment of overweight and obesity in adults&#x2013;the Evidence report. National Institutes of Health1998 Sep. Report No.: 1071-7323 (Print) 1071-7323 (Linking).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner JJ, Beck MA. The impact of obesity on the immune response to infection. Proc Nutr Soc. 2012;71:298&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4791086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison KK, Ford ES, Cogswell ME, Dietz WH. Percentage of body fat and body mass index are associated with mobility limitations in people aged 70 and older from NHANES III. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50:1802&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12410898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenholm S, Sainio P, Rantanen T, Alanen E, Koskinen S. Effect of co-morbidity on the association of high body mass index with walking limitation among men and women aged 55&#xa0;years and older. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2007;19:277&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17726357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I. Influence of sarcopenia on the development of physical disability: the Cardiovascular Health Study. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2006;54:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16420198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantin F, Di Francesco V, Fontana G, Zivelonghi A, Bissoli L, Zoico E, et al. Longitudinal body composition changes in old men and women: interrelationships with worsening disability. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2007;62:1375&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18166688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landi F, Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Liperoti R, Russo A, Giovannini S, Tosato M, et al. Sarcopenia and mortality risk in frail older persons aged 80&#xa0;years and older: results from ilSIRENTE study. Age Ageing. 2013;42:203&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23321202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M, Kritchevsky SB, Goodpaster BH, Newman AB, Nevitt M, Stamm E, et al. Leg muscle mass and composition in relation to lower extremity performance in men and women aged 70 to 79: the health, aging and body composition study. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50:897&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panula J, Pihlajamaki H, Mattila VM, Jaatinen P, Vahlberg T, Aarnio P, et al. Mortality and cause of death in hip fracture patients aged 65 or older: a population-based study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2011;12:105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21599967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost SA, Nguyen ND, Center JR, Eisman JA, Nguyen TV. Excess mortality attributable to hip-fracture: a relative survival analysis. Bone. 2013;56:23&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23684802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orwig DL, Chan J, Magaziner J. Hip fracture and its consequences: differences between men and women. Orthop Clin N Am. 2006;37:611&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17141019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osnes EK, Lofthus CM, Meyer HE, Falch JA, Nordsletten L, Cappelen I, et al. Consequences of hip fracture on activities of daily life and residential needs. Osteoporos Int. 2004;15:567&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14730422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boonen S, Autier P, Barette M, Vanderschueren D, Lips P, Haentjens P. Functional outcome and quality of life following hip fracture in elderly women: a prospective controlled study. Osteoporos Int. 2004;15:87&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14605799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper C. The crippling consequences of fractures and their impact on quality of life. Am J Med. 1997;103:12S&#x2013;7S. discussion 7S-9S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9302893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland Y, Lauwers-Cances V, Cristini C, Abellan van Kan G, Janssen I, Morley JE, et al. Difficulties with physical function associated with obesity, sarcopenia, and sarcopenic-obesity in community-dwelling elderly women: the EPIDOS (EPIDemiologie de l'OSteoporose) Study. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89:1895&#x2013;900</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Kim TN, Kim SH. Sarcopenic obesity is more closely associated with knee osteoarthritis than is nonsarcopenic obesity: a cross-sectional study. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64:3947&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM. Body composition in chemotherapy: the promising role of CT scans. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2013;16:525&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23799328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Lieffers JR, McCargar LJ, Reiman T, Sawyer MB, Martin L, et al. Prevalence and clinical implications of sarcopenic obesity in patients with solid tumours of the respiratory and gastrointestinal tracts: a population-based study. Lancet Oncol. 2008;9:629&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18539529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oros S, Ianas O, Vladoiu S, Giurcaneanu M, Ionescu L, Neacsu E, et al. Does obesity protect postmenopausal women against osteoporosis? Acta Endocrinol-Buch. 2012;8:67&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankowska EA, Rogucka E, Medras M. Are general obesity and visceral adiposity in men linked to reduced bone mineral content resulting from normal ageing? A population-based study. Andrologia. 2001;33:384&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11736801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compston JE, Watts NB, Chapurlat R, Cooper C, Boonen S, Greenspan S, et al. Obesity is not protective against fracture in postmenopausal women: GLOW. Am J Med. 2011;124:1043&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4897773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22017783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sjoblom S, Suuronen J, Rikkonen T, Honkanen R, Kroger H, Sirola J. Relationship between postmenopausal osteoporosis and the components of clinical sarcopenia. Maturitas. 2013;75:175&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23628279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inzerillo AM, Epstein S. Osteoporosis and diabetes mellitus. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2004;5:261&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15211098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell-Jones D, Khan R. Insulin-associated weight gain in diabetes&#x2014;causes, effects and coping strategies. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2007;9:799&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17924864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley JE. Diabetes, sarcopenia, and frailty. Clin Geriatr Med. 2008;24:455&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18672182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadji P, Gnant M, Body JJ, Bundred NJ, Brufsky A, Coleman RE, et al. Cancer treatment-induced bone loss in premenopausal women: a need for therapeutic intervention? Cancer Treat Rev. 2012;38:798&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22429722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wust RC, Degens H. Factors contributing to muscle wasting and dysfunction in COPD patients. Int J Chronic Obstructive Pulm Dis. 2007;2:289&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2695204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18229567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biskobing DM. COPD and osteoporosis. Chest. 2002;121:609&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakey W, Yang LY, Yancy W, Chow SC, Hicks C. Short communication: from wasting to obesity: initial antiretroviral therapy and weight gain in HIV-infected persons. AIDS Res Hum Retrovir. 2013;29:435&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23072344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudgeon WD, Phillips KD, Carson JA, Brewer RB, Durstine JL, Hand GA. Counteracting muscle wasting in HIV-infected individuals. HIV Med. 2006;7:299&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16945075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakaran B, Dowling EA, Branch JD, Swain DP, Leutholtz BC. Effect of 14&#xa0;weeks of resistance training on lipid profile and body fat percentage in premenopausal women. Br J Sports Med. 1999;33:190&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10378072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treuth MS, Ryan AS, Pratley RE, Rubin MA, Miller JP, Nicklas BJ, et al. Effects of strength training on total and regional body composition in older men. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77:614&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8002507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger EH, Klein-Nulend J. Mechanotransduction in bone&#x2014;role of the lacuno-canalicular network. FASEB J. 1999;13(Suppl):S101&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10352151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zernicke R, MacKay C, Lorincz C. Mechanisms of bone remodeling during weight-bearing exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2006;31:655&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17213879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan X, Roy E, Zhu L, Murphy TC, Ackert-Bicknell C, Hart CM, et al. Nitric oxide regulates receptor activator of nuclear factor-kappaB ligand and osteoprotegerin expression in bone marrow stromal cells. Endocrinology. 2004;145:751&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14563699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasten TP, Collin-Osdoby P, Patel N, Osdoby P, Krukowski M, Misko TP, et al. Potentiation of osteoclast bone-resorption activity by inhibition of nitric oxide synthase. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1994;91:3569&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC43621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7513424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntyre I, Zaidi M, Alam AS, Datta HK, Moonga BS, Lidbury PS, et al. Osteoclastic inhibition: an action of nitric oxide not mediated by cyclic GMP. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1991;88:2936&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC51355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1849281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner CH, Robling AG. Exercise as an anabolic stimulus for bone. Curr Pharm Des. 2004;10:2629&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toigo M, Boutellier U. New fundamental resistance exercise determinants of molecular and cellular muscle adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;97:643&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams GR, McCue SA. Localized infusion of IGF-I results in skeletal muscle hypertrophy in rats. J Appl Physiol. 1998;84:1716&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9572822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Alnaqeeb M, Simpson H, Goldspink G. Cloning and characterization of an IGF-1 isoform expressed in skeletal muscle subjected to stretch. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 1996;17:487&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8884603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med. 2005;35:339&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormsbee MJ, Thyfault JP, Johnson EA, Kraus RM, Choi MD, Hickner RC. Fat metabolism and acute resistance exercise in trained men. J Appl Physiol. 2007;102:1767&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17234805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Gentile CL, Martin-Pressman R, Ormsbee MJ, Everett M, Zwicky L, et al. Increased dietary protein and combined high intensity aerobic and resistance exercise improves body fat distribution and cardiovascular risk factors. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2006;16:373&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17136940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormsbee MJ, Choi MD, Medlin JK, Geyer GH, Trantham LH, Dubis GS, et al. Regulation of fat metabolism during resistance exercise in sedentary lean and obese men. J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:1529&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19265063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villareal DT, Chode S, Parimi N, Sinacore DR, Hilton T, Armamento-Villareal R, et al. Weight loss, exercise, or both and physical function in obese older adults. N Engl J Med. 2011;364:1218&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3114602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21449785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Boileau RA, Erickson DJ, Painter JE, Shiue H, Sather C, et al. A reduced ratio of dietary carbohydrate to protein improves body composition and blood lipid profiles during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2003;133:411&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12566476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Gentile CL, Pressman R, Everett M, Ormsbee MJ, Martin J, et al. Moderate protein intake improves total and regional body composition and insulin sensitivity in overweight adults. Metab Clin Exp. 2008;57:757&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18502257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baer DJ, Stote KS, Paul DR, Harris GK, Rumpler WV, Clevidence BA. Whey protein but not soy protein supplementation alters body weight and composition in free-living overweight and obese adults. J Nutr. 2011;141:1489&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3145217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21677076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Role of protein absorption and nutrient timing on muscle mass accretion. 110th Abbott Nutrition Research Conference; Ross Park Conference Centre, Columbus, Ohio2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Murphy CH, Longland TM, Phillips SM. Role of protein and amino acids in promoting lean mass accretion with resistance exercise and attenuating lean mass loss during energy deficit in humans. Amino Acids. 2013;45:231&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23645387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solerte SB, Gazzaruso C, Bonacasa R, Rondanelli M, Zamboni M, Basso C, et al. Nutritional supplements with oral amino acid mixtures increases whole-body lean mass and insulin sensitivity in elderly subjects with sarcopenia. Am J Cardiol. 2008;101:69E&#x2013;77E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18514630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantzer R, Heijnen CJ, Kavelaars A, Laye S, Capuron L. The neuroimmune basis of fatigue. Trends Neurosci. 2014;37:39&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3889707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24239063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>