<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31156746</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Home-Based Exercise Training Systems, Combined with Diet, on Cardiometabolic Health.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>871</StartPage><EndPage>885</EndPage><MedlinePgn>871-885</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The efficacy of exercise training systems designed to be used in the home on cardiometabolic outcomes remains largely unknown. This investigation included two studies. Study 1 tested the effects a multi-exercise pulley system (NordicTrack Fusion CST with video trainer) and Study 2 an incline trainer (NordicTrack X22i with video trainer), both combined with daily food provision, for 12-weeks on indices of cardiometabolic health. Study 1 enrolled 27 adults (11 men, 16 women, 33.8&#xb1;4.4 years of age) and Study 2 enrolled 29 adults (11 men, 18 women, 40.8&#xb1;12.5 years of age). Pre- and post-intervention measurements were performed for body weight, fat mass, lean tissue mass, and visceral fat by dual energy x-ray absorptiometry, blood pressure, aerobic fitness and body circumferences. For Study 1, there were significant decreases in body weight, fat mass, visceral fat, diastolic blood pressure (DBP), resting heart rate (RHR), and all circumference sites, while there was an increase in aerobic fitness (all p&lt;0.001). Both males and females exhibited significant improvement in all these outcomes. For Study 2, there were significant decreases in body weight, fat mass, visceral fat, DBP, RHR, all circumference sites (all p&lt;0.001), and lean tissue mass (LTM) (p=0.006), and an increase in aerobic fitness (p&lt;0.001). Both males and females exhibited significant changes in all these outcomes, except LTM which did not change in females. Both studies exhibited high exercise session attendance and high dietary adherence. Overall these data indicate the potential efficacy of home-based training systems, when combined with diet, on selected cardiometabolic outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Christian K</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatrics, Research, Education, and Clinical Center (GRECC), VA Greater Los Angeles Healthcare System, LOS ANGELES, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Segovia</LastName><ForeName>David E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatrics, Research, Education, and Clinical Center (GRECC), VA Greater Los Angeles Healthcare System, LOS ANGELES, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lankford</LastName><ForeName>D Eli</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Performance and Recreation, Brigham Young University - Idaho, Rexburg, ID, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6533109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/WEFP3647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 9th ed. Baltimore, MD: Lippincott, Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astrand PO, Ryhming I. A nomogram for calculation of aerobic capacity (physical fitness) from pulse rate during sub-maximal work. J Appl Physiol. 1954;7(2):218&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13211501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth FW, Roberts CK, Laye MJ. Lack of exercise is a major cause of chronic diseases. Compr Physiol. 2012;2(2):1143&#x2013;1211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth FW, Roberts CK, Thyfault JP, Ruegsegger GN, Toedebusch RG. Role of inactivity in chronic diseases: Evolutionary insight and pathophysiological mechanisms. Physiol Rev. 2017;97(4):1351&#x2013;1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6347102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaway C, Chumlea W, Bouchard C, Himes J, Lohman T, Martin A. Circumferences. In: Lohman T, Roche A, Martorell R, editors. Anthropometric standardization reference manual. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crumb-Johnson R, Smith-Banes M, Hatcher L, Hagan DW. Assessment of differences between compliers and noncompliers in outpatient research diet studies. J Am Diet Assoc. 1993;93(9):1041&#x2013;1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8360411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Hill JO, Jacobsen DJ, Potteiger J, Sullivan DK, Johnson SL, Heelan K, Hise M, Fennessey PV, Sonko B, Sharp T, Jakicic JM, Blair SN, Tran ZV, Mayo M, Gibson C, Washburn RA. Effects of a 16-month randomized controlled exercise trial on body weight and composition in young, overweight men and women: The midwest exercise trial. Arch Intern Med. 2003;163(11):1343&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12796071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Daly RM, Owen N, Jolley D, Vulikh E, Shaw J, Zimmet P. Home-based resistance training is not sufficient to maintain improved glycemic control following supervised training in older individuals with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2005;28(1):3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Vulikh E, Owen N, Jolley D, Shaw J, Zimmet P. Community center&#x2013;based resistance training for the maintenance of glycemic control in adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2006;29(12):2586&#x2013;2591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17130189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franz JR, Kram R. The effects of grade and speed on leg muscle activations during walking. Gait Posture. 2012;35(1):143&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3262943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21962846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon BA, Benson AC, Bird SR, Fraser SF. Resistance training improves metabolic health in type 2 diabetes: A systematic review. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2009;83(2):157&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19135754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse AR, Atkinson SA, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Increased consumption of dairy foods and protein during diet- and exercise-induced weight loss promotes fat mass loss and lean mass gain in overweight and obese premenopausal women. J Nutr. 2011;141(9):1626&#x2013;1634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3159052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longland TM, Oikawa SY, Mitchell CJ, Devries MC, Phillips SM. Higher compared with lower dietary protein during an energy deficit combined with intense exercise promotes greater lean mass gain and fat mass loss: A randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2016;103(3):738&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26817506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifflin MD, St Jeor ST, Hill LA, Scott BJ, Daugherty SA, Koh YO. A new predictive equation for resting energy expenditure in healthy individuals. Am J Clin Nutr. 1990;51(2):241&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2305711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotnikoff RC, Eves N, Jung M, Sigal RJ, Padwal R, Karunamuni N. Multicomponent, home-based resistance training for obese adults with type 2 diabetes: A randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes. 2010;34(12):1733&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20531348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts CK, Barnard RJ. Effects of exercise and diet on chronic disease. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98(1):3&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15591300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts CK, Hevener AL, Barnard RJ. Metabolic syndrome and insulin resistance: Underlying casues and modification by exercise training. Compr Physiol. 2013;3(1):1&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23720280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tchernof A, Despr&#xe9;s JP. Pathophysiology of human visceral obesity: An update. Physiol Rev. 2013;93(1):359&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23303913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windhauser MM, Evans MA, McCullough ML, Swain JF, Lin PH, Hoben KP, Plaisted CS, Karanja NM, Vollmer WM. Dietary adherence in the dietary approaches to stop hypertension trial. Dash collaborative research group. J Am Diet Assoc. 1999;99(8 Suppl):S76&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10450298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>