<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27182348</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Racial/Ethnic Differences in Bone Mineral Density of Young Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>197</StartPage><EndPage>205</EndPage><MedlinePgn>197-205</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>An estimated 1.5 million people suffer a bone disease-related fracture every year. Most work investigating bone mineral density (BMD) focuses on post-menopausal females but a report from the Surgeon General in 2004 stated that of particular concern are men, racial and ethnic minorities, poor individuals, individuals with disabilities, and individuals living in rural areas. The purpose of this study was to examine the racial/ethnic differences in bone mineral density of young adults and to investigate any correlations with variables suggested to influence BMD. BMD was assessed at a younger age than most studies based on the assumption that osteoporosis is a pediatric disorder that manifests in old age. Whole-body BMD, percent body fat (BF), fat mass (FM), and lean mass (LM) of 103 college-aged Blacks, Whites, and Hispanics (18 - 34 years of age) were measured using a Lunar Prodigy Dual Energy X-ray Absorptiometry (DEXA). Blacks and Whites were taller than Hispanics. Blacks had higher BMD than Whites and Hispanics. Blacks and Whites had higher t-scores than Hispanics. Weight and LM correlated with BMD for all three groups. Height correlated with BMD for Blacks only. FM correlated with BMD for Hispanics only. In conclusion, BMD is suggested to be higher in Blacks than Whites and Hispanics. LM is suggested to be an important component of bone health. It is important to stress resistance training for building and maintaining bone health throughout life.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilkin</LastName><ForeName>Linda D</ForeName><Initials>LD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Laboratory; Department of Kinesiology; California State University, San Bernardino; San Bernardino, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Laboratory; Department of Kinesiology; California State University, San Bernardino; San Bernardino, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sims</LastName><ForeName>Tristan D</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Laboratory; Department of Kinesiology; California State University, San Bernardino; San Bernardino, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haddock</LastName><ForeName>Bryan L</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Laboratory; Department of Kinesiology; California State University, San Bernardino; San Bernardino, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fat Mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lean Mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoporosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percent Body Fat</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27182348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4738873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/NJIO5473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Araujo AB, Travison TG, Harris SS, Holick MF, Turner AK, McKinlay JB. Race/ethnic differences in bone mineral density in men. Osteoporos Int. 2007;18(7):943&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17340219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barondess DA, Nelson DA, Schlaen SE. Whole body bone, fat, and lean mass in Black and White men. J Bone Miner Res. 1997;12(6):967&#x2013;971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9169357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomfield SA. Contributions of physical activity to bone health over the lifespan. Topics in Geriatric Rehabilitation. 2005;21(1):68&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xf4;t&#xe9; KA, Adams WC. Effect of bone density on body composition estimates in young adult Black and White women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1993;25(2):290&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8450735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettinger B, Sidney S, Cummings SR, Libanati C, Bikle DD, Tekawa IS, Tolan K, Steiger P. Racial differences in bone density between young adult Black and White subjects persist after adjustment for anthropometric, lifestyle, and biochemical differences. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1997;82(2):429&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9024231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fast Facts on Osteoporosis by the National Osteoporosis Foundation.  Retrieved January 26, 2010, from  http://www.nof.org/osteoporosis/diseasefacts.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferretti JL, Capozza RF, Cointry GR, Garc&#xed;a SL, Plotkin H, Alvarez Filgueira ML, Zanchetta JR. Gender-related differences in the relationship between densitometric values of whole-body bone mineral content and lean body mass in humans between 2 and 87 years of age. Bone. 1998;22(6):683&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9626409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George A, Tracy JK, Meyer WA, Flores RH, Wilson PD, Hochberg MC. Racial differences in bone mineral density in older men. J Bone Miner Res. 2003;18:2238&#x2013;2244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14672360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaney RP, Abrams S, Dawson-Hughes B, Looker A, Marcus R, Matkovic V, Weaver C. Peak Bone Mass. Osteoporos Int. 2000;11:985&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11256898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry YM, Eastell R. Ethnic and gender differences in bone mineral density and bone turnover in young adults: Effect of bone size. Osteoporos Int. 2000;11(6):512&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10982167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus R. Role of exercise in preventing and treating osteoporosis. Osteoporos. 2001;27(1):131&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11285991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz O, Russell M, Daley TL, Baumgartner RN, Waki M, Lichtman S, et al. Differences in skeletal muscle and bone mineral mass between Black and White females and their relevance to estimates of body composition. Am J Clin Nutr. 1992;55:8&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1728823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzoli R, Bonjour J, Chevalley T. Dietary protein intakes and bone growth. Int Cong Ser. 2007;1297:50&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis JF, Haskell W, Wood P. Physical activity assessment methodology in the Five-City Project. Am J Epidemiol. 1985;121:91&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3964995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;nau E. The peak bone mass concept: Is it still relevant? Pediatr Nephrol. 2004;19:825&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15197638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snow-Harter C, Marcus R. Exercise, bone mineral density, and osteoporosis. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1991;19(1):351&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1936090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Cauley JA, Danielson M, Nevitt MC, Lang TF, Bauer DC, et al. Race and sex effects on the association between muscle strength, soft tissue, and bone mineral density in healthy elders: The health, aging and body composition study. J Bone Miner Res. 2001;16(7):1343&#x2013;1352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11450711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosteson ANA, Hammond CS. Quality-of-life assessment in osteoporosis. Pharmacoecon. 2002;20(5):289&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Bone Health and Osteoporosis: A Report of the Surgeon General. Rockville, MD: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Surgeon General; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner DR, Heyward VH. Measures of body composition in Blacks and Whites: A comparative reveiw. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;71(6):1392&#x2013;1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10837277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Aguirre M, Bhudhikanok GS, Kendall CG, Kirsch S, Marcus R, Bachrach LK. Bone mass and hip axis length in healthy Asian, Black, Hispanic, and White American youths. J Bone Miner Res. 1997;12(11):1922&#x2013;1935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9383697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>