<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37191158</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-097X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical physiology and functional imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Physiol Funct Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute exercise affects dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry body composition estimates but not standardised ultrasound measurements of subcutaneous adipose tissue.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>345</StartPage><EndPage>353</EndPage><MedlinePgn>345-353</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cpf.12832</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ultrasound has been demonstrated to be a highly accurate and reliable tool for measuring subcutaneous adipose tissue thickness and is robust against changes in hydration status or acute food or fluid intake. However, the effect of prior acute exercise is unexamined. This study examined the impact of an acute endurance exercise and resistance exercise session on standardised brightness-mode ultrasound measurements of subcutaneous adipose tissue thickness compared to skinfolds and dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry body composition estimates. In a randomised cross-over design, 30 active adults (24.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.9&#x2009;years) undertook physique assessment via standardised brightness-mode ultrasound, skinfolds and dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry before, immediately and 45&#x2009;min after an acute endurance or resistance exercise session. The mean sum of eight subcutaneous adipose tissue thickness measured via standardised brightness-mode ultrasound increased (0.6&#x2009;mm, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04) immediately postendurance exercise but was not meaningful when evaluated against the technical error of measurement of the investigator. A significant (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.01) but not meaningful decrease in the sum of eight skinfolds occurred immediately (-1.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.4&#x2009;mm) and 45&#x2009;min (-1.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.4&#x2009;mm) postresistance exercise. Comparatively, endurance exercise elicited a meaningful decrease of total mass (460&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;30&#x2009;g) and trunk lean mass (680&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;90&#x2009;g) dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry estimates. Findings from this study indicate standardised client presentation may be unnecessary when employing either standardised brightness-mode ultrasound or skinfolds for body composition assessment unlike dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Scandinavian Society of Clinical Physiology and Nuclear Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ong</LastName><ForeName>Jun N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3941-9784</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ducker</LastName><ForeName>Kagan J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Allied Health, Curtin University, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Furzer</LastName><ForeName>Bonnie J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dymock</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Applied Statistics, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Landers</LastName><ForeName>Grant J</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Research Training Program stipend</GrantID><Agency>Australian Commonwealth Government</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Physiol Funct Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101137604</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-0961</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015502" MajorTopicYN="N">Absorptiometry, Photon</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012885" MajorTopicYN="N">Skinfold Thickness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050151" MajorTopicYN="Y">Subcutaneous Fat</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brightness-mode</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skinfold thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subcutaneous adipose tissue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasonography</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37191158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ackland, T.R., Lohman, T.G., Sundgot-Borgen, J., Maughan, R.J., Meyer, N.L., Stewart, A.D. et al. (2012) Current status of body composition assessment in sport: review and position statement on behalf of the ad hoc research working group on body composition health and performance, under the auspices of the I.O.C. Medical Commission. Sports Medicine, 42, 227-249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackland, T.R. &amp; M&#xfc;ller, W. (2018) Imaging method: Ultrasound. In: Hume, P.A., Kerr, D.A. &amp; Ackland, T.R. (Eds.) Best practice protocols for physique assessment in sport. Springer Singapore, pp. 131-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo, D., Teixeira, V.H., Carvalho, P. &amp; Amaral, T.F. (2018) Exercise induced dehydration status and skinfold compressibility in athletes: an intervention study. Asia Pacific Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 27, 189-194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker, G.L. (1969) Human adipose tissue composition and age. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 22, 829-835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bone, J.L., Ross, M.L., Tomcik, K.A., Jeacocke, N.A., Hopkins, W.G. &amp; Burke, L.M. (2017) Manipulation of muscle creatine and glycogen changes DXA estimates of body composition. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 49, 1029-1035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg, G. (1998) Borg's perceived exertion and pain scales. Human Kinetics, Champaign.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes, A.C., Landers, G.J., Binnie, M.J., Goods, P.S.R., Fulton, S.K. &amp; Ackland, T.R. (2020) Body composition assessment in athletes: Comparison of a novel ultrasound technique to traditional skinfold measures and criterion DXA measure. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 23, 1006-1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hind, K., Slater, G., Oldroyd, B., Lees, M., Thurlow, S., Barlow, M. et al. (2018) Interpretation of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry-derived body composition change in athletes: a review and recommendations for best practice. Journal of Clinical Densitometry, 21, 429-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hume, P.A., Sheerin, K.R. &amp; de Ridder, J.H. (2018) Non-imaging method: Surface anthropometry. In: Hume, P.A., Kerr, D.A. &amp; Ackland, T.R. (Eds.) Best practice protocols for physique assessment in sport. Springer Singapore, pp. 61-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavouras, S.A. (2002) Assessing hydration status. Current Opinion in Clinical Nutrition and Metabolic Care, 5, 519-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr, A., Slater, G.J. &amp; Byrne, N. (2017) Impact of food and fluid intake on technical and biological measurement error in body composition assessment methods in athletes. British Journal of Nutrition, 117, 591-601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr, A., Slater, G.J., Byrne, N. &amp; Nana, A. (2016) Reliability of 2 different positioning protocols for dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry measurement of body composition in healthy adults. Journal of Clinical Densitometry, 19, 282-289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lytle, J.R., Stanelle, S.T., Kravits, D.M., Ellsworth, R.L., Martin, S.E., Green, J.S. et al. (2020) Effects of an acute strength and conditioning training session on dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry results. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 34, 901-904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan, R.J. &amp; Shirreffs, S.M. (2008) Development of individual hydration strategies for athletes. International Journal of Sport Nutrition and Exercise Metabolism, 18, 457-472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay, A.K.A., Stellingwerff, T., Smith, E.S., Martin, D.T., Mujika, I., Goosey-Tolfrey, V.L. et al. (2022) Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 17, 317-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, T.L. (2003) Seventeen-point dermal ultrasound scoring system-a reliable measure of skin thickness in patients with systemic sclerosis. Rheumatology, 42, 1559-1563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, W., F&#xfc;rhapter-Rieger, A., Ahammer, H., Lohman, T.G., Meyer, N.L., Sardinha, L.B. et al. (2020) Relative body weight and standardised brightness-mode ultrasound measurement of subcutaneous fat in athletes: an international multicentre reliability study, under the auspices of the IOC medical commission. Sports Medicine, 50, 597-614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, W., Horn, M., F&#xfc;rhapter-Rieger, A., Kainz, P., Kr&#xf6;pfl, J.M., Maughan, R.J. et al. (2013) Body composition in sport: a comparison of a novel ultrasound imaging technique to measure subcutaneous fat tissue compared with skinfold measurement. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 47, 1028-1035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, W., Lohman, T.G., Stewart, A.D., Maughan, R.J., Meyer, N.L., Sardinha, L.B. et al. (2016) Subcutaneous fat patterning in athletes: selection of appropriate sites and standardisation of a novel ultrasound measurement technique: ad hoc working group on body composition, health and performance, under the auspices of the IOC Medical Commission. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 50, 45-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, W. &amp; Maughan, R.J. (2013) The need for a novel approach to measure body composition: is ultrasound an answer? British Journal of Sports Medicine, 47, 1001-1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana, A., Slater, G.J., Hopkins, W.G. &amp; Burke, L.M. (2012) Effects of daily activities on dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry measurements of body composition in active people. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 44, 180-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana, A., Slater, G.J., Hopkins, W.G. &amp; Burke, L.M. (2013) Effects of exercise sessions on DXA measurements of body composition in active people. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 45, 178-185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton, K., Hayward, S., Charles, S. &amp; Rees, M. (1998) The effects of hypohydration and hyperhydration on skinfold measurements. In: Norton, K., Olds, T. &amp; Dollman, J. (Eds.) Kinanthropometry VI: proceedings of the sixth scientific conference of the international society for the advancement of kinanthropometry. International Society for the Advancement of Kinanthropometry, pp. 253-266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, J.N., Ducker, K.J., Furzer, B.J., Dymock, M. &amp; Landers, G.J. (2022a) Food and fluid intake and hydration status does not affect ultrasound measurements of subcutaneous adipose tissue in active adults. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 25, 548-552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, J.N., Ducker, K.J., Furzer, B.J., Dymock, M. &amp; Landers, G.J. (2022b) Measures of body composition via dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry, ultrasound and skinfolds are not impacted by the menstrual cycle in active eumenorrheic females. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 25, 115-121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. (2020) R: A language and environment for statistical computing R Foundation for Statistical Computing. R Core Team.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Sanchez, N. &amp; Galloway, S.D.R. (2015) Errors in dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry estimation of body composition induced by hypohydration. International Journal of Sport Nutrition and Exercise Metabolism, 25, 60-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltin, B. (2007) Exercise hyperaemia: Magnitude and aspects on regulation in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 583, 819-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senay, Jr. L.C. &amp; Pivarnik, J.M. (1985) Fluid shifts during exercise. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 13, 335-388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sjogaard, G. &amp; Saltin, B. (1982) Extra- and intracellular water spaces in muscles of man at rest and with dynamic exercise. American Journal of Physiology-Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 243, R271-R280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater, G.J., Shaw, G. &amp; Kerr, A. (2018) Athlete considerations for physique measurement. In: Hume, P.A., Kerr, D.A. &amp; Ackland, T.R. (Eds.) Best Practice Protocols for Physique Assessment in Sport. Springer Singapore, pp. 47-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart, A.D. &amp; Hannan, W.J. (2000) Prediction of fat and fat-free mass in male athletes using dual X-ray absorptiometry as the reference method. Journal of Sports Sciences, 18, 263-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf6;rchle, P., M&#xfc;ller, W., Sengeis, M., Ahammer, H., F&#xfc;rhapter-Rieger, A., Bachl, N. et al. (2017) Standardized ultrasound measurement of subcutaneous fat patterning: high reliability and accuracy in groups ranging from lean to obese. Ultrasound in Medicine &amp; Biology, 43, 427-438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, L.W. (1962) The chemical composition of adipose tissue of man and mice. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Physiology and Cognate Medical Sciences, 47, 179-188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner, D.R. (2013) Ultrasound as a tool to assess body fat. Journal of Obesity, 2013, 1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner, D.R. &amp; Cotter, J.D. (2021) Ultrasound measurements of subcutaneous fat thickness are robust against hydration changes. International Journal of Sports Nutrition and Exercise Metabolism, 31, 244-249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner, D.R., Thompson, B.J., Anderson, D.A. &amp; Schwartz, S (2019) A-mode and B-mode ultrasound measurement of fat thickness: a cadaver validation study. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 73, 518-523.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>