<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">23167451</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-6632</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>1281</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann N Y Acad Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical activity in obesity and metabolic syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>141</StartPage><EndPage>159</EndPage><MedlinePgn>141-59</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/j.1749-6632.2012.06785.x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Biological aging is typically associated with a progressive increase in body fat mass and a loss of lean body mass. Owing to the metabolic consequences of reduced muscle mass, it is understood that normal aging and/or decreased physical activity may lead to a higher prevalence of metabolic disorders. Lifestyle modification, specifically changes in diet, physical activity, and exercise, is considered the cornerstone of obesity management. However, for most overweight people it is difficult to lose weight permanently through diet or exercise. Thus, prevention of weight gain is thought to be more effective than weight loss in reducing obesity rates. A key question is whether physical activity can extenuate age-related weight gain and promote metabolic health in adults. Current guidelines suggest that adults should accumulate about 60 minutes of moderate-intensity physical activity daily to prevent unhealthy weight gain. Because evidence suggests that resistance training may promote a negative energy balance and may change body fat distribution, it is possible that an increase in muscle mass after resistance training may be a key mediator leading to better metabolic control.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2012 New York Academy of Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strasser</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Sciences and Health Systems Management, Institute for Nutritional Sciences and Physiology, University for Health Sciences, Medical Informatics and Technology, Hall in Tirol, Austria. barbara.strasser@umit.at</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann N Y Acad Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7506858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0077-8923</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001835" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Weight</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009043" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Activity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057185" MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015430" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Gain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23167451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3715111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.2012.06785.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Lara-Castro C, Byrne NM, et al. Weight loss needed to maintain visceral adipose tissue during aging. Int. J. Body Comp. Res. 2005;3:55&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson PWF, D'Augostino RB, Sullivan L, et al. Overweight and obesity as determinants of cardiovascular risk. The Framingham experience. Arch. Intern. Med. 2002;162:1867&#x2013;1872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12196085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prospective Studies Collaboration. Body-mass index and cause-specific mortality in 900.000 adults: a collaborative analyses of 57 prospective studies. Lancet. 2009;373:1083&#x2013;1096. et al.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2662372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19299006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozaffarian D, Hao T, Rimm EB, et al. Changes in diet and lifestyle and long-term weight gain in women and men. N. Engl. J. Med. 2011;364:2392&#x2013;2404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3151731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21696306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell KE, Paluch AE, Blair SN. Physical activity for health: what kind? How much? How intense? On top of what. Annu. Rev. Pub. Health. 2011;32:349&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekelund U, Besson H, Luan J, et al. Physical activity and gain in abdominal adiposity and body weight: prospective cohort study in 288,498 men and women. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2011;93:826&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21346093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manson JE, Greenland P, LaCroix AZ, et al. Walking compared with vigorous exercise for the prevention of cardiovascular events in women. N. Engl. J. Med. 2002;347:716&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12213942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuomilehto J, Lindstr&#xf6;m J, Eriksson JG, et al. Prevention of type 2 diabetes mellitus by changes in lifestyles among subjects with impaired glucose tolerance. N. Engl. J. Med. 2001;344:1343&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11333990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn V, Halle M, Schmidt-Trucks&#xe4;ss A, et al. Physical activity and the metabolic syndrome in elderly German men and women. Results from the population-based KORA-survey. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:511&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2646038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19074996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM, Neilson HK, Lynch BM. State of the epidemiological evidence on physical activity and cancer prevention. Eur. J. Cancer. 2010;46:2593&#x2013;2604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20843488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services. Physical Activity Guidelines for Americans. US Department of Health and Human Services. Washington, DC: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pate RR, Pratt M, Blair SN, et al. Physical activity and public health. A recommendation from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the American College of Sports Medicine. JAMA. 1995;273:402&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7823386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR, et al. Updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2007;116:1081&#x2013;1093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flegal KM, Carroll MD, Ogden CL. Prevalence of obesity and trends in the distribution of body mass index among US adults, 1999&#x2013;2010. JAMA. 2012;307:491&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22253363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saris WH, Blair SN, van Baak MA, et al. How much physical activity is enough to prevent unhealthy weight gain? Outcome of the IASO 1st Stock Conference and consensus statement. Obes. Rev. 2003;4:101&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12760445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2009;41:459&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Barr ELM, Healy GN, et al. Television viewing time and mortality: the AusDiab study. Circulation. 2010;121:384&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20065160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzmarzyk PT, Church TS, Craig CL, et al. Sitting time and mortality from all causes, cardiovascular disease, and cancer. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2009;41:998&#x2013;1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay MS, Colley RC, Saunders TJ, et al. Physiological and health implications of a sedentary lifestyle. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 2010;35:725&#x2013;740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21164543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey Data 2003&#x2013;2004, 2005&#x2013;2006. Atlanta, GA: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS); 2010.  Available at:  http://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nhanes.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen N, Sparling PB, Healy GN, et al. Sedentary behavior: emerging evidence for a new health risk. Mayo Clin. Proc. 2010;85:1138&#x2013;1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2996155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21123641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu FB, Leitzmann MF, Stampfer MJ, et al. Physical activity and television watching in relation to risk for type 2 diabetes mellitus in men. Arch. Intern. Med. 2001;161:1542&#x2013;1548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11427103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy GN, Wijndaele K, Dunstan DW, et al. Objectively measured sedentary time, physical activity, and metabolic risk: the Australian Diabetes, Obesity and Lifestyle Study (AusDiab) Diabetes Care. 2008;31:369&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18000181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews CE, George SM, Moore SC, et al. Amount of time spent in sedentary behaviors and cause-specific mortality in US adults. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2012;95:437&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3260070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22218159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton MT, Hamilton DG, Zderic TW. Role of low energy expenditure and sitting in obesity, metabolic syndrome, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Diabetes. 2007;56:2655&#x2013;2667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17827399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manson JE, Greenland P, LaCroix AZ, et al. Walking compared with vigorous exercise for the prevention of cardiovascular events in women. N. Engl. J. Med. 2002;347:716&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12213942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manini TM, Everhart JE, Patel KV, et al. Daily activity energy expenditure and mortality among older adults. JAMA. 2006;296:171&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16835422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews CE, Jurj AL, Shu XO, et al. Influence of exercise, walking, cycling, and overall nonerxercise physical activity on mortality in Chinese women. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2007;165:1343&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17478434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Salmon J, Healy GN, et al. Association of television viewing with fasting and 2-h-postchallenge plasma glucose levels in adults without diagnosed diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2007;30:516&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17327314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ES, Li C, Zhao G, et al. Sedentary behavior, physical activity, and concentrations of insulin among US adults. Metabolism. 2010;59:1268&#x2013;1275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20060142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorp AA, Healy GN, Owen N, et al. Deleterious associations of sitting time and television viewing time with cardio-metabolic risk biomarkers: Aus-Diab 2004&#x2013;2005. Diabetes Care. 2010;33:327&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19918003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bey L, Hamilton MT. Suppression of skeletal muscle lipoprotein lipase activity during physical inactivity: a molecular reason to maintain daily low-intensity activity. J. Physiol. 2003;551:673&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12815182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamburg NM, McMackin CJ, Huang AL, et al. Physical inactivity rapidly induces insulin resistance and microvascular dysfunction in healthy volunteers. Arterioscler. Thromb. Vasc. Biol. 2007;27:2650&#x2013;2656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2596308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17932315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton MT, Hamilton DG, Zderic TW. Exercise physiology versus inactivity physiology: An essential concept for understanding lipoprotein lipase regulation. Exer. Sport Sci. Rev. 2004;32:161&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15604935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megeney LA, Neufer PD, Dohm PD, et al. Effects of muscle activity and fiber composition on glucose transport and GLUT-4. Am. J. Physiol. 1993;264:E583&#x2013;E593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8476037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy GN, Dunstan DW, Salmon E, et al. Objectively measured light-intensity physical activity is independent associated with 2-h plasma glucose. Diabetes Care. 2007;30:1384&#x2013;1389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17473059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu FB, Li TY, Colditz GA, et al. Television watching and other sedentary behaviors in relation to risk of obesity and type 2 diabetes mellitus in women. JAMA. 2003;289:1785&#x2013;1791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanck HM, McCullough ML, Patel AV, et al. Sedentary behavior, recreational physical activity, and 7-year weight gain among postmenopausal US women. Obes. Res. 2007;15:1578&#x2013;1588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17557996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung TT, Hu FB, Yu J, et al. Leisure-time physical activity, television watching, and plasma biomarkers of obesity and cardiovascular disease risk. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2000;152:1171&#x2013;1178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11130623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beunza JJ, Martinez-Gonzalez MA, Ebrahim S, et al. Sedentary behaviors and risk of incident hypertension&#x2014;the SUN cohort. Am. J. Hypert. 2007;20:1156&#x2013;1162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17954361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmerhorst HJF, Wijndaele K, Brage S, et al. Objectively measured sedentary time predicts insulin resistance, independent of moderate and vigorous physical activity. Diabetes. 2009;58:1776&#x2013;1779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2712788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19470610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren TY, Barry V, Hooker SP, et al. Sedentary behaviors increase risk of cardiovascular disease mortality in men. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2010;42:879&#x2013;885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2857522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy GN, Dunstan DW, Salmon J, et al. Television time and continuous metabolic risk in physically active adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2008;40:639&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18317383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Salmon J, Owen N, et al. Associations of TV viewing and physical activity with the metabolic syndrome in Australian adults. Diabetologia. 2005;48:2254&#x2013;2261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16211373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ES, Kohl HW, Mokdad AH, et al. Sedentary behavior, physical activity, and the metabolic syndrome among US adults. Obes. Res. 2005;13:608&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15833947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijndaele K, Brage S, Besson H, et al. Television viewing and incident cardiovascular disease: prospective associations and mediation analysis in the EPIC Norfolk Study. PLoS One. 2011;6:e20058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balkau B, Mhamdi L, Oppert JM, et al. Physical activity and insulin sensitivity: the RISK study. Diabetes. 2008;57:2613&#x2013;2618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2551669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18591396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy GN, Dunstan DW, Salmon J, et al. Breaks in sedentary time: beneficial associations with metabolic risk. Diabetes Care. 2008;31:661&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18252901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan CB, Spangler E, Valcour J, et al. Cross-sectional relationship of pedometer-determined ambulatory activity to indicators of health. Obes. Res. 2003;11:1563&#x2013;1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14694222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshioka M, Ayabe M, Yahiro T, et al. Long-period accelerometer monitoring shows the role of physical activity in overweight and obesity. Int. J. Obes. 2005;29:502&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15672105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leskinen T, Sipil&#xe4; S, Alen M, et al. Leisure-time physical activity and high-risk fat: a longitudinal population-based twin study. Int. J. Obes. 2009;33:1211&#x2013;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19721451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternfeld B, Wang H, Quesenberry CP, et al. Physical activity and changes in weight and waist circumference in midlife women: findings from the Study of Women's Health Across the Nation. Am. J. Epidemiol. 2004;160:912&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15496544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Jacobs DR, Leon AS, et al. Physical activity and body weight: associations over ten years in the CARDIA study. Coronary artery risk development in young adults. Int. J. Obes. Relat. Metab. Disord. 2000;24:1475&#x2013;1487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11126345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu FB. Physical activity, sedentary behaviors, and obesity. In: Hu FB, editor. Obesity Epidemiology. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2008. pp. 301&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coakley EH, Rimm EB, Colditz G, et al. Predictors of weight change in men: results from the Health Professionals Follow-up Study. Int. J. Obes. Relat. Metab. Disord. 1998;22:89&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9504316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Pietro L, Dziura J, Blair SN. Estimated change in physical activity level (PAL) and prediction of 5-year weight change in men: the Aerobics Center Longitudinal Study. Int. J. Obes. Relat. Disord. 2004;28:1541&#x2013;1547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15543159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raynor DA, Phelan S, Hill JO, et al. Television viewing and long-term weight maintenance: results from the National Weight Control Registry. Obesity. 2006;14:1816&#x2013;1824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17062812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slentz CA, Duscha BD, Johnson JL, et al. Effects of the amount of exercise on body weight, body composition, and measure of central obesity: STRRIDE&#x2014;a randomized controlled study. Arch. Intern. Med. 2004;164:31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Janssen I, Dawson J, et al. Exercise-induced reduction in obesity and insulin resistance in women: a randomized controlled trial. Obes. Res. 2004;12:789&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15166299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Dagnone D, Jones PJ, et al. Reduction in obesity and related comorbid conditions after diet-induced weight loss or exercise-induced weight loss in men. Ann. Intern. Med. 2000;133:92&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10896648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogelholm M. Walking for the management of obesity. 2005. Dis. Manage. Health Outcomes. 2005;13:9&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Spreitzer A, Haber P. Fat loss depends on energy deficit only, independently of the method for weight loss. Ann. Nutr. Metab. 2007;51:428&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18025815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakicic JM, Marcus BH, Gallagher KI, et al. Effect of exercise duration and intensity on weight loss in overweight, sedentary women: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2003;290:1323&#x2013;1330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12966123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakicic JM, Marcus BH, Gallagher KI, et al. Effect of exercise on 24-month weight loss in overweight women. Arch. Intern. Med. 2008;168:1550&#x2013;1559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2829743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18663167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakicic JM, Otto AD, Lang W, et al. The effect of physical activity on 18-month weight change in overweight adults. Obesity. 2011;19:100&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4427898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20539299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadden TA, Webb VL, Moran CH, et al. Lifestyle Modification for Obesity. New developments in diet, physical activity, and behavior therapy. Circulation. 2012;125:1157&#x2013;1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3313649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22392863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffery RW, Wing RR, Sherwood NE, et al. Physical activity and weight loss: does prescribing higher physical activity goals improve outcome. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2003;78:684&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14522725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leibel RL, Rosenbaum M, Hirsch J. Changes in energy expenditure resulting from altered body weight. N. Engl. J. Med. 1995;332:621&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7632212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum M, Vandenborne K, Goldsmith R, et al. Effects of experimental weight perturbation on skeletal muscle work efficiency in human subjects. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2003;285:R183&#x2013;R192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12609816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy MH, Hardman AE. Training effects of short and long bouts of brisk walking in sedentary women. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 1998;30:152&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bielinski R, Schutz Y, J&#xe9;quier E. Energy metabolism during postexercise recovery in man. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 1985;42:69&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3893093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Park JH, Kwon YC, et al. The effect of combined aerobic and resistance exercise training on abdominal fat in obese middle-aged women. J. Physiol. Anthropol. Appl. Human Sci. 2003;22:129&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuff DJ, Meneilly GS, Martin A, et al. Effective exercise modality to reduce insulin resistance in women with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2003;26:2977&#x2013;2982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14578226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher G, Hyatt TC, Hunter GR, et al. Effect of diet with and without exercise training on markers of inflammation and fat distribution in overweight women. Obesity. 2012;20:715&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21183937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Rissanen J, Pedwell H, et al. Influence of diet and exercise on skeletal muscle and visceral adipose tissue in men. J. Appl. Physiol. 1996;81:2445&#x2013;2455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9018491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, et al. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am. J. Physiol. 1997;273:E99&#x2013;E107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinsier RL, Schutz Y, Bracco D. Reexamination of the relationship of resting metabolic rate to fat-free mass and to the metabolically active components of fat-free mass in humans. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 1992;55:790&#x2013;794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1550060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cauza E, Hanusch-Enserer U, Strasser B, et al. The relative benefits of endurance and strength training on the metabolic factors and muscle function of people with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 2005;86:1527&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16084803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi E, Negri C, Zanolin ME, et al. Metabolic effects of aerobic training and resistance training in type 2 diabetic subjects. A randomized controlled trial (the READ2 study) Diabetes Care. 2012;35:676&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3308269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22344613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church TS, Blair SN, Cocreham S, et al. Effects of aerobic and resistance training on Hemoglobin A1c levels in patients with type 2 diabetes. A randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2010;304:2253&#x2013;2262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemmer JT, Ivey FM, Ryan AS, et al. Effect of strength training on resting metabolic rate and physical activity: age and gender comparisons. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2001;33:532&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11283427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prately R, Nicklas B, Rubin M, et al. Strength training increases resting metabolic rate and norepinephrine levels in healthy 50- to 65-yr-old men. J. Appl. Physiol. 1994;76:133&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8175496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ, et al. Recovery after heavy resistance exercise and skeletal muscle androgen receptor and insulin-like growth factor-I isoform expression in strength trained men. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2011;25:767&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little JP, Safdar A, Benton CR, et al. Skeletal muscle and beyond: the role of exercise as a mediator of systemic mitochondrial biogenesis. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 2011;36:598&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21888528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, Kaczor JJ, Mahoney DJ, et al. Oxidative stress and the mitochondrial theory of aging in human skeletal muscle. Exp. Gerontol. 2004;39:1391&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15489062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, Brose AN, Tarnopolsky MA. Resistance exercise training decreases oxidative damage to DNA and increases cytochrome oxidase activity in older adults. Exp. Gerontol. 2005;40:173&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15763394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melov S, Tarnopolsky MA, Beckman K, et al. Resistance exercise reverses aging in human skeletal muscle. PLoS One. 2007;2:e465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1866181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17520024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grundy SM. Metabolic Syndrome: Connecting and reconciling cardiovascular and diabetes worlds. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 2006;47:1093&#x2013;1100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16545636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, St-Onge M, Heshka S, et al. Lifestyle behaviors associated with lower risk of having the metabolic syndrome. Metabolism. 2004;53:1503&#x2013;1511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15536610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakka TA, Laaksonen DE, Lakka HM, et al. Sedentary lifestyle, poor cardiorespiratory fitness, and the metabolic syndrome. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2003;35:1279&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin ML, Ainsworth BE, Mayer-Davis EJ, et al. Physical activity and the metabolic syndrome in a tri-ethnic sample of women. Obes. Res. 2002;10:1030&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12376584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaMonte MJ, Barlow CE, Jurca R, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness is inversely associated with the incidence of metabolic syndrome: a prospective study of men and women. Circulation. 2005;112:505&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekelund U, Brage S, Franks P, et al. Physical activity energy expenditure predicts progression toward the metabolic syndrome independently of aerobic fitness in middle-aged healthy Caucasians: the Medical Research Council Ely Study. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:1195&#x2013;1200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laaksonen DE, Lakka HM, Salonen JT, et al. Low levels of leisure-time physical activity and cardiorespiratory fitness predict development of the metabolic syndrome. Diabetes Care. 2002;25:1612&#x2013;1618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12196436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broekhuizen LN, Boekholdt SM, Arsenault BJ, et al. Physical activity, metabolic syndrome, and coronary risk: the EPIC-Norfolk prospective population study. Eur. J. Cardiovasc. Prev. Rehabil. 2011;18:209&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21450666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atlantis E, Martin SA, Haren MT, et al. Inverse associations between muscle mass, strength, and the metabolic syndrome. Metabolism. 2009;58:1013&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19394973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurca R, LaMonte MJ, Church TS, et al. Associations of muscle strength and aerobic fitness with metabolic syndrome in men. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2004;36:1301&#x2013;1307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurca R, LaMonte MJ, Barlow CE, et al. Association of muscular strength with incidence of metabolic syndrome in men. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2005;37:1849&#x2013;1855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16286852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tjonna AE, Lee SJ, Rognmo O, et al. Aerobic Interval Training versus continuous moderate exercise as a treatment for the metabolic syndrome. A pilot study. Circulation. 2009;118:346&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18606913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll S, Dudfield M. What is the relationship between exercise and metabolic abnormalities? A review of the metabolic syndrome. Sports Med. 2004;34:371&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15157122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Siebert U, Schobersberger W. Resistance training in the treatment of the metabolic syndrome. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of resistance training on metabolic clustering in patients with abnormal glucose metabolism. Sports Med. 2010;40:397&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzmarzyk PT, Lear SA. Physical activity for obese individuals: a systematic review of effects on chronic disease risk factors. Obes. Rev. 2012;13:95&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21951422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trayhurn P, Beattie JH. Physiological role of adipose tissue: white adipose tissue as an endocrine and secretary organ. Proc. Nutr. Soc. 2001;60:329&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11681807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiris AN, Sothmann MS, Hoffmann RG, et al. Adiposity fat distribution and cardiovascular risk. Ann. Intern. Med. 1989;110:867&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2655520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieves DJ, Cnop M, Retzlaff B, et al. The atherogenic lipoprotein profile associated with obesity and insulin resistance is largely attributable to intra-abdominal fat. Diabetes. 2003;52:172&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12502509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail I, Keating SE, Baker MK, et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of aerobic vs. resistance exercise training on visceral fat. Obes. Rev. 2012;13:68&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21951360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourier A, Gautier JF, De Kerviler E, et al. Mobilization of visceral adipose tissue related to the improvement in insulin sensitivity in response to physical training in NIDDM. Effects of branched-chain amino acids supplements. Diabetes Care. 1997;20:385&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9051392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritzlaff CJ, Wideman L, Blumer J, et al. Catecholamine release, growth hormone secretion, and energy expenditure during exercise vs. recovery in men. J. Appl. Physiol. 2000;89:937&#x2013;946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Arvandi M, Siebert U. Resistance training, visceral obesity and inflammatory response: a review of the evidence. Obes. Rev. 2012;13:578&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22385646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slentz CA, Aiken LB, Houmard JA, et al. Inactivity, exercise, and visceral fat. STRRIDE: a randomized, controlled study of exercise intensity and amount. J. Appl. Physiol. 2005;99:1613&#x2013;1618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohkawara K, Tanaka S, Miyachi M, et al. A dose-response relation between aerobic exercise and visceral fat reduction: systematic review of clinical trials. Int. J. Obes. 2007;31:1786&#x2013;1797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17637702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slentz CA, Houmard JA, Kraus WE. Exercise, abdominal obesity, skeletal muscle, and metabolic risk: evidence for a dose response. Obesity. 2009;17:S27&#x2013;S33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3762482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Brock DW, Wetzstein CJ, et al. Exercise training prevents regain of visceral fat for 1 year following weight loss. Obesity. 2010;18:690&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2913900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19816413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Hannan PJ, Stovitz SD, et al. Strength training and adiposity in premenopausal women: strong, healthy, and empowered study. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 2007;86:566&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Emerging Risk Factors Collaboration. Major lipids, apolipoproteins, and risk of vascular disease. JAMA. 2009;302:1993&#x2013;2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3284229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19903920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus WE, Houmard JA, Duscha BD, et al. Effects of the amount and intensity of exercise on plasma lipoproteins. N. Engl. J. Med. 2002;347:1483&#x2013;1492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12421890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holme I, Hostmark AT, Anderssen SA. ApoB but not LDL-cholesterol is reduced by exercise training in overweight healthy men. Results from the 1-year randomized Oslo Diet and Exercise Study. J. Intern. Med. 2007;262:235&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17645591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkinos PF, Holland JC, Narayan P, et al. Miles run per week and high-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels in healthy, middle-aged men. A dose-response relationship. Arch. Intern. Med. 1995;155:415&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7848025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halle M, Berg A, K&#xf6;nig D, et al. Differences in the concentration and composition of low-density lipoprotein subfraction particles between sedentary and trained hypercholesterolemic men. Metabolism. 1997;46:186&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9030827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ring-Dimitriou S, von Duvillard SP, Paulweber B, et al. Nine months aerobic fitness induced changes on blood lipids and lipoproteins in untrained subjects versus controls. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2007;99:291&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17186304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS, Vu Tran Z. Aerobic exercise, lipids and lipoproteins in overweight and obese adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int. J. Obes. 2005;29:881&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2443827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15824746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon AS, Sanchez OA. Response of blood lipids to exercise training alone or combined with dietary intervention. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2001;33:S502&#x2013;S515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11427777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzmarzyk PT, Leon AS, Rankinen T, et al. Changes in blood lipids consequent to aerobic exercise training related to changes in body fatness and aerobic fitness. Metabolism. 2001;50:841&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11436192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pischon T, Girman CJ, Sacks FM, et al. Non-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol and apolipoprotein B in the prediction of coronary heart disease in men. Circulation. 2005;112:3375&#x2013;3383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16316964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y, Blumenthal RS, Flaws JA, et al. Non-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol level as a predictor of cardiovascular disease mortality. Arch. Intern. Med. 2001;161:1413&#x2013;1419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11386890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Impact of progressive resistance training on lipids and lipoproteins in adults: a meta-analysis of randomized trials. Prev. Med. 2009;48:9&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19013187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wooten JS, Phillips MD, Mitchell JB, et al. Resistance exercise and lipoproteins in postmenopausal women. Int. J. Sports Med. 2011;32:7&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3354704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21086242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baigent C, Keech A, Kearney PM, et al. Efficacy and safety of cholesterol-lowering treatment: prospective meta-analysis of data from 90,056 participants in 14 randomised trials of statins. Lancet. 2005;366:1267&#x2013;1278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16214597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon DJ, Probstfield JL, Garrison RJ, et al. High-density lipoprotein cholesterol and cardiovascular disease. Four prospective American studies. Circulation. 1989;79:8&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2642759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley BF, Hansen ED, Sheaff AK. Strength training as a countermeasure to aging muscle and chronic disease. Sports Med. 2011;41:289&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21425888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amati F, Dube JJ, Cohen PM, et al. Physical inactivity and obesity underlie the insulin resistance of aging. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:1547&#x2013;1549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2713647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19401446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Emerging Risk Factors Collaboration. Diabetes mellitus, fasting glucose, and risk of cause-specific death. N. Engl. J. Med. 2011;364:829&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4109980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21366474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowler WC, Barrett-Connor E, Fowler SE, et al. Reduction in the incidence of type 2 diabetes with lifestyle intervention or metformin. N. Engl. J. Med. 2002;346:393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1370926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11832527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan DA, Espeland MA, Foster GD, et al. Look AHEAD (Action for Health in diabetes): design and methods for a clinical trial of weight loss for the prevention of cardiovascular disease in type 2 diabetes. Control Clin. Trials. 2003;24:610&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14500058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Look AHEAD Research Group. Reduction in weight and cardiovascular disease risk factors in individuals with type 2 diabetes: one-year results of the Look AHEAD trial. Diabetes Care. 2007;30:1374&#x2013;1383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2665929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17363746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boul&#xe9; NG, Haddad E, Kenney GP, et al. Effects of exercise on glycemic control and body mass in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a meta-analysis of controlled clinical trials. JAMA. 2001;286:1218&#x2013;1227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11559268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boul&#xe9; NG, Weisnagel SJ, Lakka TA, et al. Effects of exercise training on glucose homeostasis: the HERITAGE Family Study. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:108&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikus CR, Oberlin DJ, Libla JL, et al. Lowering physical activity impairs glycemic control in healthy volunteers. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2012;44:225&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4551428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21716152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dijk JW, Manders RJ, Tummers K, et al. Both resistance- and endurance-type exercise reduce the prevalence of hyperglycemia in individuals with impaired glucose tolerance and in insulin-treated type 2 diabetic patients. Diabetologia. 2012;55:1273&#x2013;1282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3331783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22124605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenney GP, Boul&#xe9; NG, et al. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: a randomized trial. Ann. Intern. Med. 2007;147:357&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winnick JJ, Sherman WM, Habash DL, et al. Short-term aerobic exercise training in obese humans with type 2 diabetes mellitus improves whole-body insulin sensitivity through gains in peripheral, not hepatic insulin sensitivity. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 2008;93:771&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2266960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18073312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holten MK, Zacho M, Gaster M, et al. Strength training increases insulin-mediated glucose uptake, glut4 content, and insulin signaling in skeletal muscle in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2004;53:294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen ND, Dunstan DW, Robinson C, et al. Improved endthelial function following a 14-month resistance exercise training program in adults with type 2 diabetes. Diab. Res. Clin. Pract. 2008;79:405&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18006170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loreto CD, Fanelli C, Lucidi P, et al. Make your diabetic patients walk. Long-term impact of different amounts of physical activity on type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:1295&#x2013;1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15920042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajpeyi S, Tanner CJ, Slentz CA, et al. Effect of exercise intensity and volume on persistence of insulin sensitivity during training cessation. J. Appl. Physiol. 2009;106:1079&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little JP, Gillen JB, Percival ME, et al. Low-volume high-intensity interval training reduces hyperglycemia and increases muscle mitochondrial capacity in patients with type 2 diabetes. J. Appl. Physiol. 2011;111:1554&#x2013;1560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21868679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boule NG, Kenny GP, Haddad E, et al. Meta-analysis of the effect of structured exercise training on cardiorespiratory fitness in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetologia. 2003;46:1071&#x2013;1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12856082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hordern MD, Dunstan DW, Prins JB, et al. Exercise prescription for patients with type 2 diabetes and pre-diabetes: a position statement from Exercise and Sport Science Australia. J. Sci. Med. Sport. 2012;15:25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umpierre D, Ribeiro PAB, Kramer CK, et al. Physical activity advice only or structured exercise training and association with HbA1c levels in type 2 diabetes. JAMA. 2011;305:1790&#x2013;1799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dub&#xe9; JJ, Allison KF, Rousson V, et al. Exercise dose and insulin sensitivity: relevance for diabetes prevention. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2012;44:793&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3328621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22051572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dijk JW, Tummers K, Stehouwer CD, et al. Exercise therapy in type 2 diabetes: is daily exercise required to optimize glycemic control. Diabetes Care. 2012;35:948&#x2013;954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3329820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22399700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hills AP, Schultz SP, Soares MJ, et al. Resistance training for obese, type 2 diabetic adults: a review of the evidence. Obes. Rev. 2010;11:740&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20003071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flack KD, Davy KP, Hulver MW, et al. Aging, resistance training, and diabetes prevention. J. Aging Res. 2011;2011:127315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3010636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21197110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaster M, Vach W, Beck-Nielsen H, et al. GLUT4 expression at the plasma membrane is related to fibre volume in human skeletal muscle fibres. APMIS. 2002;110:611&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12529013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cauza E, Strehblow C, Metz-Schimmerl S, et al. Effects of progressive strength training on muscle mass in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients determined by computed tomography. Wien. Med. Wochenschr. 2009;159:141&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19343291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaw KT, Wareham N, Luben R, et al. Glycated haemoglobin, diabetes, and mortality in men in Norfolk cohort of European Prospective Investigation of Cancer and Nutrition (EPIC-Norfolk) BMJ. 2001;322:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC26599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11141143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manley S. Haemoglobin A1c&#x2014;marker for complications of type 2 diabetes: the experience from the UK Prospective Diabetes Study (UKPDS) Clin. Chem. Lab. Med. 2003;41:1182&#x2013;1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14598868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Daly RM, Owen N, et al. Home-based resistance training is not sufficient to maintain improved glycemic control following supervised training in older individuals with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G, Barengo NC, Tuomilehto J, et al. Relationship of physical activity and body mass index to the risk of hypertension: a prospective study in Finland. Hypertension. 2004;43:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14656958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelton SP, Chin A, Xin X, et al. Effect of aerobic exercise on blood pressure: a meta-analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Ann. Intern. Med. 2002;136:493&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11926784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagard RH, Cornelissen VA. Effect of exercise on blood pressure control in hypertensive patients. Eur. J. Cardiovasc. Prev. Rehabil. 2007;14:12&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17301622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nualnim N, Parkhurst K, Dhindsa M, et al. Effects of swimming training on blood pressure and vascular function in adults &gt;50 years of age. Am. J. Cardiol. 2012;109:1005&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22244035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Klag MJ, Caballero B, et al. Plasma insulin levels and incidence of hypertension in African Americans and whites. Arch. Intern. Med. 1999;159:498&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10074959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DE, Elliott EJ, Naughton GA. Exercise for type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2006;3:CD002968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelton PK, He J, Appel LJ, et al. Primary prevention of hypertension: clinical and public health advisory from the National High Blood Pressure Education Program. JAMA. 2002;299:1882&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12377087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagberg JM, Park JJ, Brown MD. The role of exercise training in the treatment of hypertension: an update. Sports Med. 2000;30:193&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10999423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Fargard RH. Effects of endurance training on blood pressure, blood pressure-regulating mechanisms, and cardiovascular risk factors. Hypertension. 2005;46:667&#x2013;675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16157788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS, Franklin BA, Fagard R, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand: exercise and hypertension. Med. Sci. Sports Exer. 2004;36:533&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15076798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Fagard RH. Effect of resistance training on resting blood pressure: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J. Hypertens. 2005;23:251&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15662209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Fagard RH, Coeckelberghs E, et al. Impact of resistance training on blood pressure and other cardiovascular risk factors. A meta-analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Hypertension. 2011;58:950&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21896934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou NPE, Fotiadis G, Athanasiadou Z, et al.  The effects of resistance training on ApoB/ApoA-I ratio, Lp(a) and inflammatory markers in patients with type 2 diabetes. Endocrine. 2012 doi:  10.1007/s12020-012-9650-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-012-9650-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22407494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson KA, Fiatarone Singh MA. Effects of exercise on adiponectin: a systematic review. Obesity. 2008;16:241&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18239630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Effects of aerobic exercise on C-reactive protein, body composition, and maximum oxygen consumption in adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Metabolism. 2006;55:1500&#x2013;1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17046553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balducci S, Zanuso S, Nicolucci A, et al. Anti-inflammatory effect of exercise training in subjects with type 2 diabetes and the metabolic syndrome is dependent on exercise modalities and independent of weight loss. Nutr. Metab. Cardiovasc. Dis. 2010;20:608&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19695853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M, Bishop NC, Stensel DJ, et al. The anti-inflammatory effects of exercise: mechanisms and implications for the prevention and treatment of disease. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2011;11:607&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21818123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>