<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39416488</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Changes in muscle quality and biomarkers of neuromuscular junctions and muscle protein turnover following 12 weeks of resistance training in older men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>285</StartPage><EndPage>292</EndPage><MedlinePgn>285-292</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2024.141064</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The present study aimed to investigate the effects of 12 weeks of resistance training (RT) on body composition [fat mass (FM), lean body mass (LBM)], muscle quality upper and lower (MQU, MQL), muscle size [cross sectional area (CSA), quadriceps cross-sectional area (QCSA)], biomarkers of neuromuscular junctions [C-terminal agrin fragment (CAF)], and muscle protein turnover [N-terminal peptide (P3NP), 3-methylhistidine (3MH), skeletal muscle-specific isoform of troponin T (sTnT)] in older men. Thirty elderly men (age 66.23 &#xb1; 0.57 years) were randomly divided into two groups: resistance training group (RT, n=15) and control group (CON, n=15). Participants in RT performed resistance training protocols with the intensity of 60% one-repetition maximum (3 &#xd7; /week, 4 sets of the six exercise circuits). Blood samples were assessed before (pre-test) and after (post-test) a 12-week intervention. The ANCOVA (2 &#xd7; 2; group &#xd7; time; with the baseline variable as the covariate) revealed significant interaction effects; the greater increases for LBM (P &lt; 0.001), CSA (P &lt; 0.001), QCSA (P &lt; 0.001), MQU (P &lt; 0.05), MQL (P &lt; 0.01), 3MH (P &lt; 0.05) were noted in RT than CON, and greater decreases for FM (P &lt; 0.001) and CAF (P &lt; 0.001) in RT than CON. No interaction effect was found for P3NP and sTnT. The time effect was found for all variables besides P3NP in RT, but no time effect was revealed in CON. The 12-week RT was an effective strategy for improving the concentrations of neuromuscular junction biomarkers such as 3-MH and CAF in older adults, and may lead to favourable changes in body composition, muscle quality, and muscle size.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Institute of Sport &#x2013; National Research Instutite.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mastalerz</LastName><ForeName>Andrzej</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education, Jozef Pilsudski University of Physical Education in Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hooshmand-Moghadam</LastName><ForeName>Bizhan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moazamigoudarzi</LastName><ForeName>Shadi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sciences for Quality of Life, University of Bologna, Rimini, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Golestani</LastName><ForeName>Fateme</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, University of Birjand, Birjand, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hooshmand-Moghadam</LastName><ForeName>Babak</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johne</LastName><ForeName>Monika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education, Jozef Pilsudski University of Physical Education in Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma&#x107;ka&#x142;a</LastName><ForeName>Krzysztof</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Track and Field, Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences, Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorenz</LastName><ForeName>Katarzyna</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education, Jozef Pilsudski University of Physical Education in Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maculewicz</LastName><ForeName>Ewelina</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education, Jozef Pilsudski University of Physical Education in Warsaw, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular Junctions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Turnover</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11475000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.141064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">54385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Landi F, Schneider SM, Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga C, Arai H, Boirie Y, Chen LK, Fielding RA, Martin FC, Michel J, Sieber C, Stout JR, Studenski SA, Vellas B, Woo J, Zamboni M, Cederholm T. Prevalence of and interventions for sarcopenia in ageing adults: A systematic review. Report of the International Sarcopenia Initiative (EWGSOP and IWGS). Age Ageing. 2014; 43(6):48&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4204661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25241753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandervoort AA, Symons TB. Functional and metabolic consequences of sarcopenia. Can. J. Appl. Physiol. 2001; 26(1):90&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11173671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondoc I, Cochrane SK, Church TS, Dahinden P, Hettwer S, Hsu FC, Stafford RS, Pahor M, Buford TW, Blair SN, Church T, Ashmore JA, Frierson G, Jordan AN, Morss G, Rodarte RQ, Wallace JM, Guralnik JM, Hadley EC, Romashkan S, King AC, Haskell WL, Pruitt LA, Abbott-Pilolla K, Bolen K, Fortmann S, Laws A, Prosak C, Wallace K, Fielding R, Nelson M, Kaplan RM, Groessl EJ, Pahor M, Perri M, Caudle C, Crump L, Hayden S, Holmes L, Maraldi C, Quirin C, Newman AB, Studenski S, Goodpaster BH, Glynn NW, Aiken EK, Anthony S, Kadosh J, Kost P, Newman M, Taylor CA, Vincent P, Kritchevsky SB, Brubaker P, Demons J, Furberg C, Katula JA, Marsh A, Nicklas BJ, Williamson JD, Fries R, Kennedy K, Murphy KM, Nagaria S, Wickley-Krupel K, Miller ME, Espeland M, Hsu FC, Rejeski WJ, Babcock DP, Costanza L, Harvin LN, Kaltenbach L, Lang W, Roberson WA, Rushing J, Rushing S, Walkup MP, Gill TM. Effects of a one-year physical activity program on serum C-terminal Agrin Fragment (CAF) concentrations among mobility-limited older adults. J Nutr Health Aging. 2015; 19(9):922&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4682669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26482694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratt J, De Vito G, Narici M, Segurado R, Pessanha L, Dolan J, Conroy J, Boreham C. Plasma C-Terminal Agrin Fragment as an Early Biomarker for Sarcopenia: Results from the GenoFit Study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2021; 76(12):2090&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8599080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33993303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Jajtner AR, Beyer KS, Townsend JR, Emerson NS, Scanlon TC, Oliveira LP, Hoffman JR, Stout JR. Biomarkers of muscle quality: N-terminal propeptide of type III procollagen and C-terminal agrin fragment responses to resistance exercise training in older adults. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2014; 5(2):139&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4053565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24197815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young VR, Munro HN. N (&#x3c4;)-Methylhistidine (3-methylhistidine) and muscle protein turnover: an overview. Fed Proc. 1978; 37(9):2291&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">350635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kochlik B, Stuetz W, P&#xe9;r&#xe8;s K, F&#xe9;art C, Tegner J, Rodriguez-Ma&#xf1;as L, Grune T, Weber D. Associations of plasma 3-methylhistidine with frailty status in french cohorts of the FRAILOMIC initiative. J Clin Med. 2019; 8(7):1010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31295923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brotto MA, Biesiadecki BJ, Brotto LS, Nosek TM, Jin JP. Coupled expression of troponin T and troponin I isoforms in single skeletal muscle fibers correlates with contractility. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2006; 290(2):C567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1409758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16192301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clause KC, Tchao J, Powell MC, Liu LJ, Huard J, Keller BB, Tobita K. Developing cardiac and skeletal muscle share fast-skeletal myosin heavy chain and cardiac troponin-I expression. PLoS One. 2012. Jul 10; 7(7):e40725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3393685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22808244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvani R, Marini F, Cesari M, Tosato M, Anker SD, Von Haehling S, Miller RR, Bernabei R, Landi F, Marzetti E. Biomarkers for physical frailty and sarcopenia: State of the science and future developments. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2015; 6(4):278&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4670735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigdeli S, Dehghaniyan MH, Amani-Shalamzari S, Rajabi H, Gahreman DE. Functional training with blood occlusion influences muscle quality indices in older adults. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2020; 90:104110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32473556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Fukuda DH, Stout JR, Townsend JR, Emerson NS, Boone CH, Beyer KS, Oliveira LP, Hoffman JR. Muscle quality index improves with resistance exercise training in older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2014; 53:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshmand-Moghadam B, Eskandari M, Golestani F, Rezae S, Mahmoudi N, Gaeini AA. The effect of 12-week resistance exercise training on serum levels of cellular aging process parameters in elderly men. Exp Gerontol. 2020; 141:111090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32919015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratt J, De Vito G, Narici M, Boreham C. Neuromuscular Junction Aging: A Role for Biomarkers and Exercise. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2021; 76(4):576&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32832976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling CHY, de Craen AJM, Slagboom PE, Gunn DA, Stokkel MPM, Westendorp RGJ, Maier AB. Accuracy of direct segmental multi-frequency bioimpedance analysis in the assessment of total body and segmental body composition in middle-aged adult population. Clinical Nutrition. 2011; 30(5):610&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21555168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herda AA, Herda TJ, Costa PB, Ryan ED, Stout JR, Cramer J. Muscle performance, size, and safety responses after eight weeks of resistance training and protein supplementation: A randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled clinical trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2013; 27(11):3091&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbat-Artigas S, Rolland Y, Zamboni M, Aubertin-Leheudre M. How to assess functional status: A new muscle quality index. J Nutr Health Aging. 2012; 16(1):67&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22238004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Heymsfield SB, Baumgartner RN, Ross R. Estimation of skeletal muscle mass by bioelectrical impedance analysis. J Appl Physiol. 2000; 89(2):465&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10926627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith WN, Del Rossi G, Adams JB, Abderlarahman KZ, Asfour SA, Roos BA, Signorile JF. Simple equations to predict concentric lower-body muscle power in older adults using the 30-second chair-rise test: a pilot study. Clin Interv Aging. 2010; 5:173&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2920197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Xiong WC, Mei L. Neuromuscular Junction Formation, Aging, and Disorders. Annu Rev Physiol. 2018; 80:159&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29195055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drey M, Sieber CC, Bauer JM, Uter W, Dahinden P, Fariello RG, Vrijbloed JW, Zech A, Freiberger E, Pfeifer K, Bertsch T. C-terminal Agrin Fragment as a potential marker for sarcopenia caused by degeneration of the neuromuscular junction. Exp Gerontol. 2013; 48(1):76&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22683512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, H&#xe4;Kkinen K. Similar increases in strength after short-term resistance training due to different neuromuscular adaptations in young and older men. J Strength Cond Res. 2014; 28(11):3041&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25051001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes MR, Roby MA, Eason MK, Harris MB. Remodeling of the neuromuscular junction precedes sarcopenia related alterations in myofibers. Exp Gerontol. 2010; 45(5):389&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2854317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20226849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Fragala MS, Hoffman JR, Robinson EH, Mccormack WP, Townsend JR, Jatjner AR, Emerson NS, Oliveira LP, Fukuda DH. C-terminal agrin fragment is inversely related to neuromuscular fatigue in older men. Muscle Nerve. 2015; 51(1):132&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25186664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, He EJ, Kawakubo M, Schroeder ET, Yarasheski K, Opiteck GJ, Reicin A, Chen F, Lam R, Tsou JA, Castaneda-Sceppa C, Binder EF, Azen SP, Sattler FR. N-terminal propeptide of type III procollagen as a biomarker of anabolic response to recombinant human GH and testosterone. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009; 94(11):4224&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2775648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19837911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AE, Meinhardt U, Hansen JL, Walker IH, Stone G, Howe CJ, Leung KC, Seibel MJ, Baxter RC, Handelsman DJ, Kazlauskas R, Ho KKY. Pharmacodynamics of growth hormone abuse biomarkers and the influence of gender and testosterone: A randomized double-blind placebocontrolled study in young recreational athletes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2008; 93(6):2213&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18381573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foldvari M, Clark M, Laviolette LC, Bernstein MA, Kaliton D, Castaneda C, Pu CT, Hausdorff JM, Fielding RA, Fiatarone Singh MA. Association of muscle power with functional status in communitydwelling elderly women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2000; 55(4):M192&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10811148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarasheski KE, Zachwieja JJ, Campbell JA, Bier DM. Effect of growth hormone and resistance exercise on muscle growth and strength in older men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 1995; 268(2 31&#x2013;2):E268&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7864103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Meredith CN, O&#x2019;Reilly KP, Knuttgen HG, Evans WJ. Strength conditioning in older men: Skeletal muscle hypertrophy and improved function. J Appl Physiol. 1988; 64(3):1038&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3366726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalinkovich A, Livshits G. Sarcopenia &#x2013; The search for emerging biomarkers. Ageing Res Rev. 2015; 22:58&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25962896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King GW, Abreu EL, An-Cheng L, Chertoff KK, Brotto L, Kelly PJ, Brotto M. A multimodal assessment of balance in elderly and young adults. Oncotarget. 2016; 7(12):13297&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4924642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26934319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banitalebi E, Faramarzi M, Ghahfarokhi MM, SavariNikoo F, Soltani N, Bahramzadeh A. Osteosarcopenic obesity markers following elastic band resistance training: A randomized controlled trial. Exp Gerontol. 2020; 135:110884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32092502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huxley AF, Simmons RM. Proposed mechanism of force generation in striated muscle. Nature. 1971; 233(5321):533&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4939977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks N, Layne JE, Gordon PL, Roubenoff R, Nelson ME, Castaneda-Sceppa C. Strength training improves muscle quality and insulin sensitivity in Hispanic older adults with type 2 diabetes. Int J Med Sci. 2007; 4(1):19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1752232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikberg S, S&#xf6;rl&#xe9;n N, Brand&#xe9;n L, Johansson J, Nordstr&#xf6;m A, Hult A, Nordstr&#xf6;m P. Effects of Resistance Training on Functional Strength and Muscle Mass in 70-Year-Old Individuals With Presarcopenia: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2019; 20(1):28&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murlasits Z, Reed J, Wells K. Effect of resistance training frequency on physiological adaptations in older adults. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2012; 10(1):28&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Lopez P. Exercise effects on muscle quality in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2021; 11(1):21085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8548567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34702909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Fukuda DH, Stout JR, Townsend JR, Emerson NS, Boone CH, Beyer KS, Oliveira LP, Hoffman JR. Muscle quality index improves with resistance exercise training in older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2014; 53:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luciano TF, Marques SO, Pieri BL, De Souza DR, Ara&#xfa;jo L V., Nesi RT, Scheffer DL, Comin VH, Pinho RA, Muller AP, de Souza CT. Responses of skeletal muscle hypertrophy in wistar rats to different resistance exercise models. Physiol Res. 2017; 66(2):317&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27982685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilwik R, Snijders T, Leenders M, Groen BBL, van Kranenburg J, Verdijk LB, Van Loon LJC. The decline in skeletal muscle mass with aging is mainly attributed to a reduction in type II muscle fiber size. Exp Gerontol. 2013; 48(5):492&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23425621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>