<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32868680</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of 2 Weekly Frequencies of Resistance Training on Muscular Strength, Body Composition, and Metabolic Biomarkers in Resistance-Trained Older Women: Effects of Detraining and Retraining.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1437</StartPage><EndPage>1444</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1437-1444</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003799</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Amarante do Nascimento, M, Nunes, JPA, Pina, FLC, Ribeiro, AS, Carneiro, NH, Venturini, D, Barbosa, DS, Mayhew, JL, and Cyrino, ES. Comparison of 2 weekly frequencies of resistance training on muscular strength, body composition, and metabolic biomarkers in resistance-trained older women: Effects of detraining and retraining. J Strength Cond Res 36(5): 1437-1444, 2022-This study aimed to compare the effects of 2 weekly frequencies of resistance training (RT) on muscular strength, body composition, and metabolic biomarkers in previously resistance-trained older women after detraining and retraining. Forty subjects (&gt;60 years) performed RT (8 exercises, 1 set of 10-15 repetitions maximum) 2 (G2x) or 3 (G3x) times per week over 12 weeks of training and retraining. After training, subjects were detrained for 12 weeks. After detraining, there were significant decreases (p &lt; 0.05) in upper-body (&#x223c;12%) and lower-body (&#x223c;14%) muscular strength, fat-free mass (FFM) (&#x223c;2%), and testosterone (&#x223c;26%), whereas increases were revealed for fat mass (FM) (&#x223c;4%), relative body fat (&#x223c;3%), fasting glucose (&#x223c;8%), low-density lipoprotein cholesterol (LDL-C) (&#x223c;21%), and triglycerides (&#x223c;24%), with no differences between groups (p &gt; 0.05). Following retraining, there were significant increases (p &lt; 0.05) for upper (&#x223c;7%) and lower (&#x223c;10%) muscular strength, FFM (&#x223c;2%), and testosterone (&#x223c;20%). In contrast, decreases were found for FM (&#x223c;7%), relative body fat (&#x223c;3%), fasting glucose (&#x223c;6%), LDL-C (&#x223c;14%), and triglycerides (&#x223c;21%), also with no differences between groups (p &gt; 0.05). Gains after retraining were lower than after training (p &lt; 0.05) only for upper- and lower-body muscular strength (&#x223c;6%) and testosterone (&#x223c;11%). Total cholesterol, high-density lipoprotein cholesterol, IGF-1, and C-reactive protein did not change at any point in the study for either group (p &gt; 0.05). Our results suggest that older women can regain previous RT program benefits following detraining, regardless of the weekly training frequency. However, some fitness components may take longer to reestablish than the initial training level.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amarante do Nascimento</LastName><ForeName>Matheus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paran&#xe1; State University-UNESPAR, Paranava&#xed; Campus, Physical Education Department, Paranava&#xed;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pina</LastName><ForeName>F&#xe1;bio L C</ForeName><Initials>FLC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Science, University of Northern Paran&#xe1;-UNOPAR, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Science, University of Northern Paran&#xe1;-UNOPAR, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carneiro</LastName><ForeName>Nelson H</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venturini</LastName><ForeName>Danielle</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Analyses Laboratory, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbosa</LastName><ForeName>D&#xe9;cio S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Analyses Laboratory, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayhew</LastName><ForeName>Jerry L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science Department, Truman State University, Kirksville, Missouri.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008078">Cholesterol, LDL</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014280">Triglycerides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3XMK78S47O</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013739">Testosterone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>IY9XDZ35W2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005947">Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008078" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholesterol, LDL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005947" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013739" MajorTopicYN="N">Testosterone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014280" MajorTopicYN="N">Triglycerides</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202205000-00037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Hulmi JJ, Kraemer WJ, et al. Strength, endurance or combined training elicit diverse skeletal muscle myosin heavy chain isoform proportion but unaltered androgen receptor concentration in older men. Int J Sports Med 30: 879&#x2013;887, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amarante do Nascimento M, Janu&#xe1;rio RS, Gerage AM, et al. Familiarization and reliability of one repetition maximum strength testing in older women. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1636&#x2013;1642, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine, Chodzko-Zajko WJ, Proctor DN, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 1510&#x2013;1530, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Hill VJ, Adams GR, et al. Gender differences in resistance-training-induced myofiber hypertrophy among older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 58: 108&#x2013;116, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beneka A, Malliou P, Fatouros I, et al. Resistance training effects on muscular strength of elderly are related to intensity and gender. J Sci Med Sport 8: 274&#x2013;283, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkley TE, Leng X, Miller ME, et al. Chronic inflammation is associated with low physical function in older adults across multiple comorbidities. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 64: 455&#x2013;461, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell EL, Seynnes OR, Bottinelli R, et al. Skeletal muscle adaptations to physical inactivity and subsequent retraining in young men. Biogerontology 14: 247&#x2013;259, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante EF, Ribeiro AS, do Nascimento MA, et al. Effects of different resistance training frequencies on fat in overweight/obese older women. Int J Sports Med 39: 527&#x2013;534, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Col&#xf3;n-Emeric CS, Whitson HE, Pavon J, Hoenig H. Functional decline in older adults. Am Fam Physician 88: 388&#x2013;394, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa CS, Baroni BM, Radaelli R, et al. Effects of strength training and detraining on knee extensor strength, muscle volume and muscle quality in elderly women. Age (Omaha) 35: 1899&#x2013;1904, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: Revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing 48: 16&#x2013;31, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha PM, Nunes JP, Tomeleri CM, et al. Resistance training performed with single and multiple sets induces similar improvements in muscular strength, muscle mass, muscle quality, and IGF-1 in older women: A randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1008&#x2013;1016, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes MR, Holdren AN, McCoy RW. Adaptations to short-term muscle unloading in young and aged men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 40: 856&#x2013;863, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Dreyer HC, Pennings B, et al. Skeletal muscle protein anabolic response to resistance exercise and essential amino acids is delayed with aging. J Appl Physiol 104: 1452&#x2013;1461, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott KJ, Sale C, Cable NT. Effects of resistance training and detraining on muscle strength and blood lipid profiles in postmenopausal women. Br J Sports Med 36: 340&#x2013;345, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG, Kambas A, Katrabasas I, et al. Strength training and detraining effects on muscular strength, anaerobic power, and mobility of inactive older men are intensity dependent. Br J Sports Med 39: 776&#x2013;780, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Buchner A, Lang AG. Statistical power analyses using G*Power 3.1: Tests for correlation and regression analyses. Behav Res Methods 41: 1149&#x2013;1160, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: Position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2019&#x2013;2052, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedewald WT, Levy RI, Fredrickson DS. Estimation of the concentration of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol in plasma, without use of the preparative ultracentrifuge. Clin Chem 18: 499&#x2013;502, 1972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegly JC, Turesky NA, Strotman BA, et al. Satellite cell regulation of muscle mass is altered at old age. J Appl Physiol 97: 1082&#x2013;1090, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o DA, Taaffe DR. Resistance exercise dosage in older adults: Single- versus multiset effects on physical performance and body composition. J Am Geriatr Soc 53: 2090&#x2013;2097, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, Kallinen M, Newton RU, Kraemer WJ. Neuromuscular adaptation during prolonged strength training, detraining and re-strength-training in middle-aged and elderly people. Eur J Appl Physiol 83: 51&#x2013;62, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, et al. Selective muscle hypertrophy, changes in EMG and force, and serum hormones during strength training in older women. J Appl Physiol 91: 569&#x2013;580, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henwood TR, Taaffe DR. Detraining and retraining in older adults following long-term muscle power or muscle strength specific training. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 63: 751&#x2013;758, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvid L, Aagaard P, Justesen L, et al. Effects of aging on muscle mechanical function and muscle fiber morphology during short-term immobilization and subsequent retraining. J Appl Physiol 109: 1628&#x2013;1634, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihalainen JK, Inglis A, M&#xe4;kinen T, et al. Strength training improves metabolic health markers in older individual regardless of training frequency. Front Physiol 10: 32, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Iba&#xf1;ez J, et al. Effects of strength training on muscle power and serum hormones in middle-aged and older men. J Appl Physiol 90: 1497&#x2013;1507, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacroix A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Beurskens R, Granacher U. Effects of supervised vs. unsupervised training programs on balance and muscle strength in older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2341&#x2013;2361, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landi F, Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Liperoti R, et al. Sarcopenia and mortality risk in frail olderpersons aged 80 years and older: Results from iLSIRENTE study. Age Ageing 42: 203&#x2013;209, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo A, Carvalho J, Santos P. Effects of training and detraining on physical fitness, physical activity patterns, cardiovascular variables, and HRQOL after 3 health-promotion interventions in institutionalized elders. Int J Family Med 2010: 486097, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins RA, Ver&#xed;ssimo MT, Coelho e Silva MJ, Cumming SP, Teixeira AM. Effects of aerobic and strength-based training on metabolic health indicators in older adults. Lipids Health Dis 9: 76, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx JO, Ratamess NA, Nindl BC, et al. Low-volume circuit versus high-volume periodized resistance training in women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 635&#x2013;643, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer F, Scharhag-Rosenberger F, Carlsohn A, et al. The intensity and effects of strength training in the elderly. Dtsch Arztebl Int 108: 359&#x2013;364, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabuco HC, Tomeleri CM, Junior PS, et al. Effects of higher habitual protein intake on resistance-training-induced changes in body composition and muscular strength in untrained older women: A clinical trial study. Nutr Health 25: 103&#x2013;112, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento MA, Gerage AM, Silva DRPD, et al. Effect of resistance training with different frequencies and subsequent detraining on muscle mass and appendicular lean soft tissue, IGF-1, and testosterone in older women. Eur J Sport Sci 19: 199&#x2013;207, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilha CS, Ribeiro AS, Fleck SJ, et al. Effect of resistance training with different frequencies and detraining on muscular strength and oxidative stress biomarkers in older women. Age (Dordr) 37: 104, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina FLC, Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effects of different weekly sets-equated resistance training frequencies on muscular strength, muscle mass, and body fat in older women. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2990&#x2013;2995, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Fleck SJ, et al. Effects of traditional and pyramidal resistance training systems on muscular strength, muscle mass, and hormonal responses in older women: A randomized crossover trial. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1888&#x2013;1896, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Pina FLC, et al. Resistance training in older women: Comparison of single vs. multiple sets on muscle strength and body composition. Isokinet Exerc Sci 23: 53&#x2013;60, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Tomeleri CM, Souza MF, et al. Effect of resistance training on C-reactive protein, blood glucose and lipid profile in older women with differing levels of RT experience. Age (Dordr) 37: 109, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetta C, Hvid LG, Justesen L, et al. Effects of aging on human skeletal muscle after immobilization and retraining. J Appl Physiol 107: 1172&#x2013;1180, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Henwood TR, Nalls MA, et al. Alterations in muscle attenuation following detraining and retraining in resistance-trained older adults. Gerontology 55: 217&#x2013;223, 2009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>