<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32149876</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>Suppl 12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Seasonal Effects of Strength Endurance vs. Power Training in Young Female Soccer Athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S90</StartPage><EndPage>S96</EndPage><MedlinePgn>S90-S96</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003564</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lesinski, M, Prieske, O, Chaabene, H, and Granacher, U. Seasonal effects of strength endurance vs. power training in young female soccer athletes. J Strength Cond Res 35(12S): S90-S96, 2021-This study examined the seasonal effects of strength endurance training (SET) vs. power training (PT) on physical fitness and body composition in young female soccer players. Thirty-six young female elite soccer players (15 &#xb1; 1 years; maturity offset +3 &#xb1; 1 years) were allocated to progressive SET (n = 19) or PT (n = 17). Over the course of one soccer season, SET performed slow movement velocity, moderate intensity (50-60% of the 1 repetition maximum [1RM]; 20-40 repetitions) strength exercises while PT performed moderate-to-high intensity (50-95% of the 1RM; 3-8 repetitions), high movement velocity strength exercises (2 sessions&#xb7;wk-1). Before and after training, tests were performed for the assessment of muscle strength (1RM leg press), jump performance (countermovement jump [CMJ], drop jump [DJ]), muscular endurance (ventral Bourban test), linear speed (10 m, 20 m), change-of-direction (CoD) speed (T-test), dynamic balance (Y-balance test), sport-specific performance (kicking velocity), and body composition (lean body mass and fat mass). An analysis of covariance was used to test for between-group differences at post-test with baseline values as covariate. No significant between-group differences were observed in terms of total training volume over the respective soccer seasons (p = 0.069; d = 0.68). At post-test, SET showed significantly better ventral Bourban and T-test performances (d = 1.28-2.28; p = 0.000-0.001) compared with PT. However, PT resulted in significantly better 1RM leg press, DJ, 10-m, and 20-m sprint performances (d = 0.85-1.44; p = 0.000-0.026). No significant between-group differences were observed at post-test for CMJ, Y-balance test, kicking performance, and body composition (d = 0.20-0.74, p = 0.051-0.594). Our findings are mainly in accordance with the principle of training specificity. Both SET and PT are recommended to be implemented in young female elite soccer players according to the respective training period.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lesinski</LastName><ForeName>Melanie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Training and Movement Sciences, University of Potsdam, Research Focus Cognition Sciences, Potsdam, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prieske</LastName><ForeName>Olaf</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaabene</LastName><ForeName>Helmi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Granacher</LastName><ForeName>Urs</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059385" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plyometric Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202112002-00014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arena R. Exercise testing. In: ACSMs Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Lupash E, ed. Baltimore, MD: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong N, McManus AM. Physiology of elite young male athletes. Med Sport Sci 56: 1&#x2013;22, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Sale DG. Velocity specificity of resistance training. Sports Med 15: 374&#x2013;388, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Young JD, Whitten JHD, et al. Effectiveness of traditional strength vs. power training on muscle strength, power and speed with youth: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol 8: 423, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berjan Bacvarevic B, Pazin N, Bozic PR, et al. Evaluation of a composite test of kicking performance. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1945&#x2013;1952, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bompa T, Buzzichelli C. Periodization: Training for Sports. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brughelli M, Cronin J, Levin G, Chaouachi A. Understanding change of direction ability in sport: A review of resistance training studies. Sports Med 38: 1045&#x2013;1063, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H, Prieske O, Lesinski M, Sandau I, Granacher U. Short-term seasonal development of anthropometry, body composition, physical fitness, and sport-specific performance in young Olympic weightlifters. Sports (Basel, Switzerland) 7: E242, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H, Prieske O, Negra Y, Granacher U. Change of direction speed: Toward a strength training approach with accentuated eccentric muscle actions. Sports Med 48: 1773&#x2013;1779, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, MI: Erlbaum, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coren S. The lateral preference inventory for measurement of handedness, footedness, eyedness, and earedness: Norms for young adults. Bull Psychon Soc 31: 1&#x2013;3, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faigenbaum AD, Myer GD. Resistance training among young athletes: Safety, efficacy and injury prevention effects. Br J Sports Med 44: 56&#x2013;63, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipa A, Byrnes R, Paterno MV, Myer GD, Hewett TE. Neuromuscular training improves performance on the star excursion balance test in young female athletes. J Orthop Sports Physic Therap 40: 551&#x2013;558, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco-Marquez F, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Gonzalez-Suarez JM, et al. Effects of combined resistance training and plyometrics on physical performance in young soccer players. Int J Sports Med 36: 906&#x2013;914, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Muehlbauer T, Doerflinger B, Strohmeier R, Gollhofer A. Promoting strength and balance in adolescents during physical education: Effects of a short-term resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 25: 940&#x2013;949, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 674&#x2013;688, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesinski M, Prieske O, Granacher U. Effects and dose-response relationships of resistance training on physical performance in youth athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 50: 781&#x2013;795, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesinski M, Prieske O, Helm N, Granacher U. Effects of soccer training on anthropometry, body composition, and physical fitness during a soccer season in female elite young athletes: A prospective cohort study. Front Physiol 8: 1093, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling CH, de Craen AJ, Slagboom PE, et al. Accuracy of direct segmental multi-frequency bioimpedance analysis in the assessment of total body and segmental body composition in middle-aged adult population. Clin Nutr 30: 610&#x2013;615, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Oliver JL. The youth physical development model: A new approach to long-term athletic development. Strength Cond J 34: 61&#x2013;72, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Dizdar D, Jukic I, Cardinale M. Reliability and factorial validity of squat and countermovement jump tests. J Strength Cond Res 18: 551&#x2013;555, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus AM, Armstrong N. Physiology of elite young female athletes. Med Sport Sci 56: 23&#x2013;46, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirwald RL, Baxter-Jones AD, Bailey DA, Beunen GP. An assessment of maturity from anthropometric measurements. Med Sci Sports Exerc 34: 689&#x2013;694, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moir G, Button C, Glaister M, Stone MH. Influence of familiarization on the reliability of vertical jump and acceleration sprinting performance in physically active men. J Strength Cond Res 18: 276&#x2013;280, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Sandercock G, Ramirez-Campillo R, et al. A meta-analysis of resistance training in female youth: Its effect on muscular strength, and shortcomings in the literature. Sports Med 48: 1661&#x2013;1671, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negra Y, Chaabene H, Hammami M, Hachana Y, Granacher U. Effects of high-velocity resistance training on athletic performance in prepuberal male soccer athletes. J Strength Cond Res 30: 3290&#x2013;3297, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauole K, Madole K, Garhammer J, Lacourse M, Rozenek R. Reliability and validity of the T-test as a measure of agility, leg power, and leg speed in college-aged men and women. J Strength Cond Res 14: 443&#x2013;450, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisky PJ, Rauh MJ, Kaminski TW, Underwood FB. Star excursion balance test as a predictor of lower extremity injury in high school basketball players. J Orthop Sports Physic Therap 36: 911&#x2013;919, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potdevin FJ, Alberty ME, Chevutschi A, Pelayo P, Sidney MC. Effects of a 6-week plyometric training program on performances in pubescent swimmers. J Strength Cond Res 25: 80&#x2013;86, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo DI, Kim E, Fahs CA, et al. Reliability of the one-repetition maximum test based on muscle group and gender. J Sports Sci Med 11: 221&#x2013;225, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soligard T, Myklebust G, Steffen K, et al. Comprehensive warm-up programme to prevent injuries in young female footballers: Cluster randomised controlled trial. BMJ 337: a2469, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolen T, Chamari K, Castagna C, Wisloff U. Physiology of soccer: An update. Sports Med 35: 501&#x2013;536, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tschopp M, Bourban P, H&#xfc;bner K, Marti B. Reliability of a standardized, dynamic trunk muscle strength test: Experiences with healthy male elite athletes. Swiss J Sports Med Sports Traumatol 49: 67&#x2013;72, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young WB, Dawson B, Henry GJ. Agility and change-of-direction speed are independent skills: Implications for training for agility in invasion sports. Int J Sports Sci Coach 10: 159&#x2013;169, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>