<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39840189</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Weight Loss on Testosterone Levels: A Review of BMI and Testosterone.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e76139</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e76139</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e76139</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.76139</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this review is to explore the relationship between weight loss (WL), specifically reductions in body mass index (BMI), and increases in testosterone levels. Obesity and excess body fat are linked to reduced testosterone levels, which can lead to metabolic dysfunctions, reduced libido, and diminished muscle mass. To attain this purpose, this review will summarize current evidence on how weight reduction interventions, including dietary changes, exercise, and bariatric surgery, affect testosterone production in overweight and obese individuals. WL, particularly through fat reduction, has a positive influence on testosterone levels. Both moderate and significant reductions in BMI are associated with notable increases in serum testosterone levels. Dietary interventions, particularly low-carbohydrate and Mediterranean diets, have been linked to increased testosterone production in men with obesity. Exercise, particularly resistance training, has also been shown to improve hormonal profiles by lowering fat mass and boosting testosterone levels. Additionally, bariatric surgery has been identified as one of the most effective methods for increasing testosterone in morbidly obese individuals, with improvements sustained over time. The findings have indicated that there is strong evidence that WL, particularly through reductions in BMI, leads to increased testosterone levels. This relationship is mediated by improvements in insulin sensitivity, reduced inflammation, and lower levels of aromatase activity (the enzyme that converts testosterone to estrogen in fat tissue). Effective interventions, including diet, exercise, and bariatric surgery, have the potential to restore hormonal balance, improving overall health outcomes for men with obesity or higher BMI. Further research is needed to optimize interventions and explore long-term benefits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Okobi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okobi</LastName><ForeName>Okelue E</ForeName><Initials>OE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Medficient Health Systems, Laurel, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Lakeside Medical Center, Belle Glade, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khoury</LastName><ForeName>Paola</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De la Vega</LastName><ForeName>Raul J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Hialeah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Figueroa</LastName><ForeName>Raphael S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Hialeah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Dhaarak</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Hialeah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mangiliman</LastName><ForeName>Bernadin Dina A</ForeName><Initials>BDA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine and Community Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Hialeah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vera Colon</LastName><ForeName>Olga L</ForeName><Initials>OL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Hialeah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urruela-Barrios</LastName><ForeName>Rodolfo J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdussalam</LastName><ForeName>Abdul K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Hialeah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diaz-Miret</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hernandez Borges</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine and Family Medicine, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bariatric surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body mass index (bmi)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hormonal health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">testosterone levels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39840189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11745839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.76139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Testosterone: a vascular hormone in health and disease. Kelly DM, Jones TH. J Endocrinol. 2013;217:0&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23549841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of testosterone in male sexual function. Corona G, Maggi M. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2022;23:1159&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9789013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ylli D, Sidhu S, Parikh T, et al. Endotext [Internet] South Dartmouth: MDText.com, Inc.; 2022. Endocrine changes in obesity.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obesity and male infertility: mechanisms and management. Leisegang K, Sengupta P, Agarwal A, Henkel R. Andrologia. 2021;53:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32399992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassar GN, Leslie SW. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; [ Sep; 2024 ]. 2024. Physiology, testosterone.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30252384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC: new CDC data show adult obesity prevalence remains high.  [
Jan;
2024 
]. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/obesity/data/adult.html https://www.cdc.gov/obesity/data/adult.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC: Adult obesity facts.  [
Nov;
2024 
]. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/obesity/adult-obesity-facts/index.html https://www.cdc.gov/obesity/adult-obesity-facts/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obesity and male hypogonadism: tales of a vicious cycle. Carrageta DF, Oliveira PF, Alves MG, Monteiro MP. Obes Rev. 2019;20:1148&#x2013;1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31035310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Male obesity-related secondary hypogonadism - pathophysiology, clinical implications and management. Fernandez CJ, Chacko EC, Pappachan JM. Eur Endocrinol. 2019;15:83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6785957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31616498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obesity: epidemiology, pathophysiology, and therapeutics. Lin X, Li H. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;12:706978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8450866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34552557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adipose tissue dysfunction and obesity-related male hypogonadism. Genchi VA, Rossi E, Lauriola C, et al. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:8194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9330735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35897769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obesity, a serious etiologic factor for male subfertility in modern society. Liu Y, Ding Z. Reproduction. 2017;154:0&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28747541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of aromatase on the reproductive function of obese males. Xu X, Sun M, Ye J, et al. Horm Metab Res. 2017;49:572&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endocrine disrupting chemicals and male fertility: from physiological to molecular effects. Lahimer M, Abou Diwan M, Montjean D, et al. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1232646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10598475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37886048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signatures of metabolic diseases on spermatogenesis and testicular metabolism. Carrageta DF, Pereira SC, Ferreira R, Monteiro MP, Oliveira PF, Alves MG. Nat Rev Urol. 2024;21:477&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38528255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swerdloff RS, Wang C, Sinha Hikim AP, et al. Hormones, Brain and Behavior. New York: Academic Press; 2002. Hypothalamic-pituitary-gonadal axis in men; pp. 1&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zierle-Ghosh A, Jan A. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; [ Sep; 2024 ]. 2024. Physiology, body mass index.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30571077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effectiveness of web-based programs on the reduction of childhood obesity in school-aged children: a systematic review. Antwi F, Fazylova N, Garcon MC, Lopez L, Rubiano R, Slyer JT. JBI Libr Syst Rev. 2012;10:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27820152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Testosterone and obesity. Kelly DM, Jones TH. Obes Rev. 2015;16:581&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25982085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How much does obesity affect the male reproductive function? Bellastella G, Menafra D, Puliani G, et al. Int J Obes Supp. 2019;9:50&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6683183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31391924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short-term effects of surgical weight loss after sleeve gastrectomy on sex steroids plasma levels and PSA concentration in men with severe obesity. Di Vincenzo A, Silvestrin V, Bertoli E, et al. Aging Male. 2020;23:464&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30449231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bariatric surgery impact on reproductive hormones, semen analysis, and sperm DNA fragmentation in men with severe obesity: prospective study. Wood GJ, Tiseo BC, Paluello DV, et al. Obes Surg. 2020;30:4840&#x2013;4851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The male patient with obesity undergoing metabolic and bariatric surgery: changes in testosterone levels correlate with weight loss after one-anastomosis gastric bypass and Roux-en-Y gastric bypass. Jedamzik J, Bichler C, Felsenreich DM, et al. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2023;19:699&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36740523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of bariatric surgery on androgen profile and ovarian volume in obese polycystic ovary syndrome patients with infertility. Ezzat RS, Abdallah W, Elsayed M, Saleh HS, Abdalla W. Saudi J Biol Sci. 2021;28:5048&#x2013;5052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34466081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of bariatric surgery on endogenous sex hormones and sex&#xa0;hormone-binding globulin levels: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Emami MR, Safabakhsh M, Khorshidi M, Moradi Moghaddam O, Mohammed SH, Zarezadeh M, Alizadeh S. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2021;17:1621&#x2013;1636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34187743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low-fat diets and testosterone in men: systematic review and meta-analysis of intervention studies. Whittaker J, Wu K. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2021;210:105878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33741447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low-carbohydrate diets and men's cortisol and testosterone: systematic review and meta-analysis. Whittaker J, Harris M. Nutr Health. 2022;28:543&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9716400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35254136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Percent body fat was negatively correlated with testosterone levels in males. Ma H, Sun J, Wu X, Mao J, Han Q. PLoS One. 2024;19:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38170701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weight loss as therapeutic option to restore fertility in obese men: a meta-analytic study. Santi D, Greco C, Barbonetti A, Simoni M, Maggi M, Corona G. World J Mens Health. 2024;42:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11937353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39344112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Male adiposity, sperm parameters and reproductive hormones: an updated systematic review and collaborative meta-analysis. Salas-Huetos A, Maghsoumi-Norouzabad L, James ER, et al. Obes Rev. 2021;22:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32705766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weight gain and obesity rates in transgender and gender-diverse adults before and during hormone therapy. Kyinn M, Banks K, Leemaqz SY, Sarkodie E, Goldstein D, Irwig MS. Int J Obes (Lond) 2021;45:2562&#x2013;2569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of time restricted eating versus daily calorie restriction on sex hormones in males and females with obesity. Lin S, Cienfuegos S, Ezpeleta M, Pavlou V, Runchey MC, Varady KA. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2024;78:814&#x2013;817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38866976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Body composition and testosterone in men: a Mendelian randomization study. Ikehata Y, Hachiya T, Kobayashi T, Ide H, Horie S. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2023;14:1277393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10711270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38089610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weight loss more than glycemic control may improve testosterone in obese type 2 diabetes mellitus men with hypogonadism. Giagulli VA, Castellana M, Carbone MD, et al. Andrology. 2020;8:654&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31919991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Society of Endocrinology Clinical Practice Guideline: endocrine work-up in obesity. Pasquali R, Casanueva F, Haluzik M, et al. Eur J Endocrinol. 2020;182:0&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31855556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gut microbiota steroid sexual dimorphism and its impact on gonadal steroids: influences of obesity and menopausal status. Mayneris-Perxachs J, Arnoriaga-Rodr&#xed;guez M, Luque-C&#xf3;rdoba D, et al. Microbiome. 2020;8:136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7504665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32951609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Testosterone treatment, weight loss, and health-related quality of life and psychosocial function in men: a 2-year randomized controlled trial. Grossmann M, Robledo KP, Daniel M, et al. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2024;109:2019&#x2013;2028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11244181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38335137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aromatase inhibitors plus weight loss improves the hormonal profile of obese hypogonadal men without causing major side effects. Colleluori G, Chen R, Turin CG, et al. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2020;11:277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32499757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of testosterone therapy in obese men with low testosterone levels, for losing weight, controlling obesity complications, and preventing cardiovascular events: protocol of a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Mangolim AS, Brito LA, Nunes-Nogueira VS. Medicine (Baltimore) 2018;97:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5944503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29703008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>