<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38235388</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscle fitness and cardiovascular risk of obese college students.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1252052</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1252052</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1252052</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2023.1252052</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Purpose:</b> The aim of this study was to investigate the effect of blood flow restriction (BFR) combined with low-intensity resistance training (RT) on cardiovascular risk factors in obese individuals. <b>Methods:</b> Twenty-six male obese college students were recruited and randomly assigned to a control group (CON, <i>n</i> = 8), a low-intensity RT group (RT, <i>n</i> = 9), and a combined BFR training and low-intensity RT group (BFRT, <i>n</i> = 9). <b>Results:</b> The subjects in BFRT group showed significant reductions in body fat percentage and waist-to-hip ratio and a significant increase in lean mass and muscle mass; the peak torque, peak power, and endurance ratio of knee extensors and elbow flexors were significantly upregulated; the root mean square (RMS) for the medial femoral muscle, lateral femoral muscle and biceps significantly increased; the diastolic blood pressure (DBP) showed a significant decrease. The BFRT group also showed significant up-regulations in RMS of the difference between the adjacent R-R intervals (RMSSD), high-frequency power (HF) of parasympathetic modulatory capacity, the standard deviation of R-R intervals (SDNN) of overall heart rate variability (HRV) changes and low-frequency power (LF) of predominantly sympathetic activity. In addition, glycated hemoglobin (HbA1C), insulin resistance index (HOMA-IR) and fasting blood glucose (FBG) were all significantly downregulated in BFRT group. In parallel, low-density lipoprotein (LDL-C) significantly reduced while high-density lipoprotein (HDL-C) significantly increased in BFRT group. <b>Conclusion:</b> BFR combined with low-intensity RT training effectively improved body composition index, increased muscle mass, improved neuromuscular activation, enhanced muscle strength and endurance, which in turn improved abnormal glucolipid metabolism and enhanced cardiac autonomic regulation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Su, Wang, Wang, He, Yang and Luan.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Yanhong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Human Science in Liaoning Province, College of Physical Education, Liaoning Normal University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Fuqing</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Human Science in Liaoning Province, College of Physical Education, Liaoning Normal University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Human Science in Liaoning Province, College of Physical Education, Liaoning Normal University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Shiyong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Human Science in Liaoning Province, College of Physical Education, Liaoning Normal University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sports Human Science in Liaoning Province, College of Physical Education, Liaoning Normal University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luan</LastName><ForeName>Zhilin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Institute for Medical Sciences, Dalian Medical University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucolipid metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular activation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38235388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10791898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1252052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1252052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ak&#x131;no&#x11f;lu B., Kocahan T. (2020). Russian current versus high voltage current with isokinetic training on the quadriceps muscle strength and endurance. J. Exerc Rehabil. 16 (3), 272&#x2013;278. 10.12965/jer.2040260.130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.2040260.130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32724785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh Pahlavani H. (2022). Exercise therapy for people with sarcopenic obesity: myokines and adipokines as effective actors. Front. Endocrinol. (Lausanne) 13, 811751. 10.3389/fendo.2022.811751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2022.811751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35250869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand (2009). American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 41 (3), 687&#x2013;708. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barthelemy J. C., Pichot V., Hupin D., Berger M., Celle S., Mouhli L., et al. (2022). Targeting autonomic nervous system as a biomarker of well-ageing in the prevention of stroke. Front. Aging Neurosci. 14, 969352. 10.3389/fnagi.2022.969352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2022.969352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9521604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36185479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjarnason-Wehrens B., Mayer-Berger W., Meister E. R., Baum K., Hambrecht R., Gielen S., et al. (2004). Recommendations for resistance exercise in cardiac rehabilitation. Recommendations of the German federation for cardiovascular prevention and rehabilitation. Eur. J. Cardiovasc Prev. Rehabil. 11 (4), 352&#x2013;361. 10.1097/01.hjr.0000137692.36013.27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.hjr.0000137692.36013.27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt B., Aguilar D., Deswal A., Dunbar S. B., Francis G. S., Horwich T., et al. (2016). Contributory risk and management of comorbidities of hypertension, obesity, diabetes mellitus, hyperlipidemia, and metabolic syndrome in chronic heart failure: a scientific statement from the American heart association. Circulation 134 (23), e535&#x2013;e578. 10.1161/cir.0000000000000450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/cir.0000000000000450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27799274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A. M., Standley R. A., Anthony S. J., Grench K. E., Helbling N. L., DeLany J. P., et al. (2022). Weight loss and exercise differentially affect insulin sensitivity, body composition, cardiorespiratory fitness, and muscle strength in older adults with obesity: a randomized controlled trial. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 77 (5), 1088&#x2013;1097. 10.1093/gerona/glab240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glab240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9071425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34406407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C., Wiegel P., Gollhofer A., K&#xf6;nig D. (2019). Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 49 (1), 95&#x2013;108. 10.1007/s40279-018-0994-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0994-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6349784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Zhou Y., Pan X., Li X., Long J., Zhang H., et al. (2020). Associations between health-related physical fitness and cardiovascular disease risk factors in overweight and obese university staff. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 17 (23), 9031. 10.3390/ijerph17239031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17239031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7730253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33287419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Ma C., Wang J., Gu Y., Gao Y. (2021). Effects of 40% of maximum oxygen uptake intensity cycling combined with blood flow restriction training on body composition and serum biomarkers of Chinese college students with obesity. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 19 (1), 168. 10.3390/ijerph19010168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19010168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8750492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S., Kim K., Kim S. M., Lee G., Jeong S. M., Park S. Y., et al. (2018). Association of obesity or weight change with coronary heart disease among young adults in South Korea. JAMA Intern Med. 178 (8), 1060&#x2013;1068. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.2310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.2310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6143106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29913019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G., Tornatore G., Caccavale F., Longo S., Esposito F., C&#xe8; E. (2021). The activation of gluteal, thigh, and lower back muscles in different squat variations performed by competitive bodybuilders: implications for resistance training. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 18 (2), 772. 10.3390/ijerph18020772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18020772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33477561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lima T. R., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Chica D. A., Sui X., Santos Silva D. A. (2022). The independent and joint associations among muscle strength, abdominal obesity and cardiometabolic variables among adults. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 22 (7), 1122&#x2013;1131. 10.1080/17461391.2021.1902571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2021.1902571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doehner W., Gerstein H. C., Ried J., Jung H., Asbrand C., Hess S., et al. (2020). Obesity and weight loss are inversely related to mortality and cardiovascular outcome in prediabetes and type 2 diabetes: data from the ORIGIN trial. Eur. Heart J. 41 (28), 2668&#x2013;2677. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32402060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elagizi A., Kachur S., Lavie C. J., Carbone S., Pandey A., Ortega F. B., et al. (2018). An overview and update on obesity and the obesity paradox in cardiovascular diseases. Prog. Cardiovasc Dis. 61 (2), 142&#x2013;150. 10.1016/j.pcad.2018.07.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcad.2018.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29981771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ESC Committee for Practice Guidelines (CPG); ESC National Cardiac SocietiesESC Committee for Practice Guidelines CPGESC National Cardiac Societies (2019). 2019 ESC/EAS guidelines for the management of dyslipidaemias: lipid modification to reduce cardiovascular risk. Atherosclerosis 290, 140&#x2013;205. 10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2019.08.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2019.08.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31591002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs C. A., Loenneke J. P., Thiebaud R. S., Rossow L. M., Kim D., Abe T., et al. (2015). Muscular adaptations to fatiguing exercise with and without blood flow restriction. Clin. Physiol. Funct. Imaging 35 (3), 167&#x2013;176. 10.1111/cpf.12141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grundy S. M. (2016). Metabolic syndrome update. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 26 (4), 364&#x2013;373. 10.1016/j.tcm.2015.10.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tcm.2015.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26654259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackney K. J., Everett M., Scott J. M., Ploutz-Snyder L. (2012). Blood flow-restricted exercise in space. Extreme Physiology Med. 1 (1), 12. 10.1186/2046-7648-1-12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2046-7648-1-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23849078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henrique D. L. M., Carlos Ramis T. R., Ribeiro J. L. (2019). Effects of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction on the perceived exertion, muscular resistance and endurance in healthy young adults. Sport Sci. Health 15, 503&#x2013;510. 10.1007/s11332-019-00536-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-019-00536-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorge M. L., de Oliveira V. N., Resende N. M., Paraiso L. F., Calixto A., Diniz A. L., et al. (2011). The effects of aerobic, resistance, and combined exercise on metabolic control, inflammatory markers, adipocytokines, and muscle insulin signaling in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Metabolism 60 (9), 1244&#x2013;1252. 10.1016/j.metabol.2011.01.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2011.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junior A. F., Schamne J. C., Perandini L. A. B., Chimin P., Okuno N. M. (2019). Effects of walking training with restricted blood flow on HR and HRV kinetics and HRV recovery. Int. J. Sports Med. 40 (9), 585&#x2013;591. 10.1055/a-0942-7479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0942-7479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31272111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A., Strazar K. (2011). Frequent low-load ischemic resistance exercise to failure enhances muscle oxygen delivery and endurance capacity. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 21 (6), e231&#x2013;e241. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01260.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01260.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou N. P., Fotiadis G., Kapelouzou A., Kostakis A., Liapis C. D., Vrabas I. S. (2013). The differential anti-inflammatory effects of exercise modalities and their association with early carotid atherosclerosis progression in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabet. Med. 30 (2), e41&#x2013;e50. 10.1111/dme.12055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dme.12055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23078531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambi&#x10d; T., Novakovi&#x107; M., Toma&#x17e;in K., Strojnik V., Jug B. (2019). Blood flow restriction resistance exercise improves muscle strength and hemodynamics, but not vascular function in coronary artery disease patients: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Front. Physiol. 10, 656. 10.3389/fphys.2019.00656</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katta N., Loethen T., Lavie C. J., Alpert M. A. (2021). Obesity and coronary heart disease: epidemiology, pathology, and coronary artery imaging. Curr. Probl. Cardiol. 46 (3), 100655. 10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2020.100655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpcardiol.2020.100655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32843206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr Z. Y., Collins C. L., Comstock R. D. (2010). Epidemiology of weight training-related injuries presenting to United States emergency departments, 1990 to 2007. Am. J. Sports Med. 38 (4), 765&#x2013;771. 10.1177/0363546509351560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546509351560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S. S., Ning H., Wilkins J. T., Allen N., Carnethon M., Berry J. D., et al. (2018). Association of body mass index with lifetime risk of cardiovascular disease and compression of morbidity. JAMA Cardiol. 3 (4), 280&#x2013;287. 10.1001/jamacardio.2018.0022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2018.0022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5875319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29490333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S. R., Lee G., Choi S., Oh Y. H., Son J. S., Park M., et al. (2022). Changes in predicted lean body mass, appendicular skeletal muscle mass, and body fat mass and cardiovascular disease. J. Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 13 (2), 1113&#x2013;1123. 10.1002/jcsm.12962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8978024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35212175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kj&#xf8;llesdal M. K. R., Ariansen I., N&#xe6;ss &#xd8; E. (2020). Early adulthood weight, subsequent midlife weight change and risk of cardiovascular disease mortality: an analysis of Norwegian cardiovascular surveys. Int. J. Obes. (Lond) 44 (2), 399&#x2013;408. 10.1038/s41366-019-0467-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41366-019-0467-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31636374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapik J. J., Staab J. S., Harman E. A. (1996). Validity of an anthropometric estimate of thigh muscle cross-sectional area. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 28 (12), 1523&#x2013;1530. 10.1097/00005768-199612000-00013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199612000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8970148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W. J., Marchitelli L., Gordon S. E., Harman E., Dziados J. E., Mello R., et al. (1990). Hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise protocols. J. Appl. Physiol. 69 (4), 1442&#x2013;1450. 10.1152/jappl.1990.69.4.1442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1990.69.4.1442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2262468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawman H. G., Troiano R. P., Perna F. M., Wang C. Y., Fryar C. D., Ogden C. L. (2016). Associations of relative handgrip strength and cardiovascular disease biomarkers in U.S. Adults, 2011-2012. Am. J. Prev. Med. 50 (6), 677&#x2013;683. 10.1016/j.amepre.2015.10.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2015.10.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7337414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. W., Yu K., Shyh-Chang N., Jiang Z., Liu T., Ma S., et al. (2022). Pathogenesis of sarcopenia and the relationship with fat mass: descriptive review. J. Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 13 (2), 781&#x2013;794. 10.1002/jcsm.12901</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8977978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35106971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lira F. S., Yamashita A. S., Uchida M. C., Zanchi N. E., Gualano B., Martins E., Jr., et al. (2010). Low and moderate, rather than high intensity strength exercise induces benefit regarding plasma lipid profile. Diabetol. Metab. Syndr. 2, 31. 10.1186/1758-5996-2-31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-5996-2-31</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2888772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20492685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o M. E., Ugrinowitsch C., Laurentino G., Libardi C. A., Aihara A. Y., Cardoso F. N., et al. (2015). Effects of exercise intensity and occlusion pressure after 12 weeks of resistance training with blood-flow restriction. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 115 (12), 2471&#x2013;2480. 10.1007/s00421-015-3253-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3253-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26323350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke J. P., Fahs C. A., Rossow L. M., Thiebaud R. S., Mattocks K. T., Abe T., et al. (2013). Blood flow restriction pressure recommendations: a tale of two cuffs. Front. Physiol. 4, 249. 10.3389/fphys.2013.00249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2013.00249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24058346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Jaramillo P., Lopez-Lopez J. P., Tole M. C., Cohen D. D. (2022). Muscular strength in risk factors for cardiovascular disease and mortality: a narrative review. Anatol. J. Cardiol. 26 (8), 598&#x2013;607. 10.5152/AnatolJCardiol.2022.1586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/AnatolJCardiol.2022.1586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9403882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35924286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luebbers P. E., Fry A. C., Kriley L. M., Butler M. S. (2014). The effects of a 7-week practical blood flow restriction program on well-trained collegiate athletes. J. Strength Cond. Res. 28 (8), 2270&#x2013;2280. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000000385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000000385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24476782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A., Hamlin M. J., Ross J. J., Taylor R., Manimmanakorn N. (2013). Effects of low-load resistance training combined with blood flow restriction or hypoxia on muscle function and performance in netball athletes. J. Sci. Med. Sport 16 (4), 337&#x2013;342. 10.1016/j.jsams.2012.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2012.08.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22999393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millar P. J., Levy A. S., McGowan C. L., McCartney N., MacDonald M. J. (2012). Isometric handgrip training lowers blood pressure and increases heart rate complexity in medicated hypertensive patients. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 23 (5), 620&#x2013;626. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01435.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01435.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22260503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myint P. K., Kwok C. S., Luben R. N., Wareham N. J., Khaw K. T. (2014). Body fat percentage, body mass index and waist-to-hip ratio as predictors of mortality and cardiovascular disease. Heart 100 (20), 1613&#x2013;1619. 10.1136/heartjnl-2014-305816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/heartjnl-2014-305816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24966306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naci H., Salcher-Konrad M., Dias S., Blum M. R., Sahoo S. A., Nunan D., et al. (2019). How does exercise treatment compare with antihypertensive medications? A network meta-analysis of 391 randomised controlled trials assessing exercise and medication effects on systolic blood pressure. Br. J. sports Med. 53 (14), 859&#x2013;869. 10.1136/bjsports-2018-099921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe6;ss-Schmidt E. T., Morthorst M., Pedersen A. R., Nielsen J. F., Stubbs P. W. (2017). Corticospinal excitability changes following blood flow restriction training of the tibialis anterior: a preliminary study. Heliyon 3 (1), e00217. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2016.e00217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2016.e00217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5241574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28127587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neeland I. J., Poirier P., Despr&#xe9;s J. P. (2018). Cardiovascular and metabolic heterogeneity of obesity: clinical challenges and implications for management. Circulation 137 (13), 1391&#x2013;1406. 10.1161/circulationaha.117.029617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.117.029617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5875734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29581366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osawa Y., Studenski S. A., Ferrucci L. (2018). Knee extension rate of torque development and peak torque: associations with lower extremity function. J. Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 9 (3), 530&#x2013;539. 10.1002/jcsm.12285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5989739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29569834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson S. J., Hussain S. R. (2015). A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 45 (2), 187&#x2013;200. 10.1007/s40279-014-0264-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0264-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera E., Zhu X.M., Horner N. S., Bedi A., Ayeni O. R., Khan M. (2022). Effects of blood flow restriction therapy for muscular strength, hypertrophy, and endurance in healthy and special populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin. J. Sport Med. 32 (5), 531&#x2013;545. 10.1097/jsm.0000000000000991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/jsm.0000000000000991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36083329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piepoli M. F., Conraads V., Corr&#xe0; U., Dickstein K., Francis D. P., Jaarsma T., et al. (2011). Exercise training in heart failure: from theory to practice. A consensus document of the heart failure association and the European association for cardiovascular prevention and rehabilitation. Eur. J. Heart Fail 13 (4), 347&#x2013;357. 10.1093/eurjhf/hfr017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurjhf/hfr017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21436360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell-Wiley T. M., Poirier P., Burke L. E., Despr&#xe9;s J. P., Gordon-Larsen P., Lavie C. J., et al. (2021). Obesity and cardiovascular disease: a scientific statement from the American heart association. Circulation 143 (21), e984&#x2013;e1010. 10.1161/cir.0000000000000973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/cir.0000000000000973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33882682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo B., Menduni M., Borboni P., Picconi F., Frontoni S. (2021). Autonomic nervous system in obesity and insulin-resistance-the complex interplay between leptin and central nervous system. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 22 (10), 5187. 10.3390/ijms22105187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22105187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34068919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saatmann N., Zaharia O. P., Loenneke J. P., Roden M., Pesta D. H. (2021). Effects of blood flow restriction exercise and possible applications in type 2 diabetes. Trends Endocrinol. Metab. 32 (2), 106&#x2013;117. 10.1016/j.tem.2020.11.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2020.11.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33358931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder E. C., Franke W. D., Sharp R. L., Lee D. C. (2019). Comparative effectiveness of aerobic, resistance, and combined training on cardiovascular disease risk factors: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS One 14 (1), e0210292. 10.1371/journal.pone.0210292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0210292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30615666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa J., Neto G. R., Santos H. H., Ara&#xfa;jo J. P., Silva H. G., Cirilo-Sousa M. S. (2017). Effects of strength training with blood flow restriction on torque, muscle activation and local muscular endurance in healthy subjects. Biol. Sport 34 (1), 83&#x2013;90. 10.5114/biolsport.2017.63738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2017.63738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5377566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steidl-M&#xfc;ller L., Hildebrandt C., M&#xfc;ller E., Fink C., Raschner C. (2018). Limb symmetry index in competitive alpine ski racers: reference values and injury risk identification according to age-related performance levels. J. Sport Health Sci. 7 (4), 405&#x2013;415. 10.1016/j.jshs.2018.09.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2018.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6230217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30450248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strand B. H., Wills A. K., Langballe E. M., Rosness T. A., Engedal K., Bjertness E. (2017). Weight change in midlife and risk of mortality from dementia up to 35 Years later. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 72 (6), 855&#x2013;860. 10.1093/gerona/glw157</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glw157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27510654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talib I., Sundaraj K., Lam C. K. (2021). Crosstalk in mechanomyographic signals from elbow flexor muscles during submaximal to maximal isometric flexion, pronation, and supination torque tasks. J. Biomech. Eng. 143 (1), 011001. 10.1115/1.4047850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4047850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32691054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallis J., Shelley S., Degens H., Hill C. (2021). Age-related skeletal muscle dysfunction is aggravated by obesity: an investigation of contractile function, implications and treatment. Biomolecules 11 (3), 372. 10.3390/biom11030372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom11030372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8000988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33801275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada T., Reed J. L., Vidal-Almela S., Mistura M., Kamiya K., Way K. L. (2022). Sex-specific associations of fat mass and muscle mass with cardiovascular disease risk factors in adults with type 2 diabetes living with overweight and obesity: secondary analysis of the Look AHEAD trial. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 21 (1), 40. 10.1186/s12933-022-01468-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-022-01468-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8925200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35292039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X., Chen S., Wang P., Xu Q., Zhang Y., Luo Y., et al. (2022). Insulin resistance mediates obesity-related risk of cardiovascular disease: a prospective cohort study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 21 (1), 289. 10.1186/s12933-022-01729-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12933-022-01729-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9789633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36564775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Li Z., Tongtong C., Zhang W., Li X. (2023). Effect of continuous and intermittent blood flow restriction deep-squat training on thigh muscle activation and fatigue levels in male handball players. Sci. Rep. 13 (1), 19152. 10.1038/s41598-023-44523-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-44523-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10628241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37932313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J. M., Lowery R. P., Joy J. M., Loenneke J. P., Naimo M. A. (2013). Practical blood flow restriction training increases acute determinants of hypertrophy without increasing indices of muscle damage. J. Strength Cond. Res. 27 (11), 3068&#x2013;3075. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828a1ffa</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828a1ffa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23446173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wormser D., Kaptoge S., Di Angelantonio E., Wood A. M., Pennells L., Thompson A., et al. (2011). Separate and combined associations of body-mass index and abdominal adiposity with cardiovascular disease: collaborative analysis of 58 prospective studies. Lancet 377 (9771), 1085&#x2013;1095. 10.1016/s0140-6736(11)60105-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(11)60105-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3145074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21397319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav R. L., Yadav P. K., Yadav L. K., Agrawal K., Sah S. K., Islam M. N. (2017). Association between obesity and heart rate variability indices: an intuition toward cardiac autonomic alteration - a risk of CVD. Diabetes Metab. Syndr. Obes. 10, 57&#x2013;64. 10.2147/dmso.S123935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/dmso.S123935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5322847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28255249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Silva A., Buzzachera C. F., Pi&#xe7;arro I. D. C., Januario R. S. B., Ferreira L. H. B., McAnulty S. R., et al. (2017). Effect of low dose, short-term creatine supplementation on muscle power output in elite youth soccer players. J. Int. Soc. Sports Nutr. 14, 5. 10.1186/s12970-017-0162-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0162-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28190980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q., He X. J., Li Y. D., Zhang Y. Z., Ding C. S., Li G. X., et al. (2022). Dose-response relationship of blood flow restriction training on isometric muscle strength, maximum strength and lower limb extensor strength: a meta-analysis. Front. Physiol. 13, 1046625. 10.3389/fphys.2022.1046625</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.1046625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9800008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T., Abe T., Sato Y., Midorikawa T., Kearns C. F., Inoue K., et al. (2005). Muscle fiber cross-sectional area is increased after two weeks of twice daily KAATSU-resistance training. Int. J. Kaatsu Train. Res. 1 (2), 65&#x2013;70. 10.3806/ijktr.1.65</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3806/ijktr.1.65</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T., Ogasawara R., Sakamaki M., Ozaki H., Sato Y., Abe T. (2011). Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 111 (10), 2525&#x2013;2533. 10.1007/s00421-011-1873-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1873-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusuf S., Anand S. (2011). Body-mass index, abdominal adiposity, and cardiovascular risk. Lancet 378 (9787), 226&#x2013;227. 10.1016/s0140-6736(11)61120-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(11)61120-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21763930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Tian G., Wang X. (2022). Effects of low-load blood flow restriction training on hemodynamic responses and vascular function in older adults: a meta-analysis. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 19 (11), 6750. 10.3390/ijerph19116750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19116750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35682336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Zheng Y., Ma X., Qiang L., Lin A., Zhou M. (2022). Low-intensity resistance exercise combined with blood flow restriction is more conducive to regulate blood pressure and autonomic nervous system in hypertension patients-compared with high-intensity and low-intensity resistance exercise. Front. Physiol. 13, 833809. 10.3389/fphys.2022.833809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.833809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9065267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35514351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y., Manson J. E., Yuan C., Liang M. H., Grodstein F., Stampfer M. J., et al. (2017). Associations of weight gain from early to middle adulthood with major health outcomes later in life. Jama 318 (3), 255&#x2013;269. 10.1001/jama.2017.7092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.7092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5817436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28719691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>