<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38665854</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Fitness Responses after Sixteen Weeks of Three Fitness Program Trainings in Untrained Subjects.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>54</StartPage><EndPage>72</EndPage><MedlinePgn>54-72</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The remarkable popularity of fitness trends like high intensity functional training (HIFT), choreographed high intensity classes (CHIC) and resistance (RT) trainings raises the question on their effect on cardio-respiratory, lactate removal rate, endurance and body composition responses. The purpose of this study was to assess and compare these effects. Ninety-five participants were randomly assigned into 16 weeks of these trainings, five sessions/week. Anthropometric and fitness tests were carried out before training (PRE), after eight (8W) and sixteen weeks (16W). Body composition measures demonstrated significant decrease in body fat percentage (<i>p</i>&lt;0.001, <i>d</i>=0.17-0.54) for all groups and fat mass (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.001, <i>d</i>= 0.26-0.53) for HIFT and CHIC in 8W,16W and in 16W for RT (<i>p</i>= 0.03, <i>d</i>= 0.14), also significant increase in fat free mass only in HIFT (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.002, <i>d</i>= 0.06-0.21) and RT (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.001, <i>d</i>= 0.17-0.33) in 8W,16W. Cardio-respiratory measures demonstrated significant improvements in maximal aerobic capacity for HIFT (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.001, <i>d</i>= 0.58-1.26) and CHIC (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.001, <i>d</i>= 0.45-1.21) in 8W,16W. Endurance tests demonstrated significant improvements in 8W,16W in aerobic endurance among HIFT (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.001, <i>d</i>= 1.28-3.19) and CHIC (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.001, <i>d</i>= 1.16-1.79), in muscle absolute endurance in three groups (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.002, <i>d</i>= 0.14-1.17)and muscle relative endurance in HIFT (<i>p</i>&lt; 0.02, <i>d</i>= 0.13-0.2)and RT (<i>p</i>= 0.03, <i>d</i>= 0.3) in 16W. We can conclude that HIFT and CHIC are effective for cardio-respiratory and endurance improvement and all three programs are effective in reducing body fat.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamdouni</LastName><ForeName>Habil</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar - Said, Maniuba, Tunisia, Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tunisian Research Laboratory 'Sports Performance Optimization' (LR09SEP01), National Center of Medicine and Science in Sports (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia, Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kliszczewicz</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kennesaw State University, Department of Exercise Science and Sports Management, Kennesaw, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zouhal</LastName><ForeName>Hassane</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>M2S, Laboratoire Mouvement, Sport, Sant&#xe9;, EA 1274, Universit&#xe9; Rennes, Rennes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut International des Sciences du Sport (2I2S), Irodouer, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ben Abderrahman</LastName><ForeName>Abderraouf</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar - Said, Maniuba, Tunisia, Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tunisian Research Laboratory 'Sports Performance Optimization' (LR09SEP01), National Center of Medicine and Science in Sports (CNMSS), Tunis, Tunisia, Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIFT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lactate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organic responses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stamina</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38665854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11042898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/JJMA6757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-17-4-54</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Hopkins WG, Marcora SM. Similar sensitivity of time to exhaustion and time - trial time to changes in endurance. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2008;40(3):574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18379223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson T, Kearney JT. Effects of three resistance training programs on muscular strength and absolute and relative endurance. Research Quarterly for Exercise and Sport. 1982;53(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7079558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechke E, Kliszczewicz B, Feito Y, Kelemen H, Nickerson B. Resting cardiac autonomic activity and body composition following a 16- week high - intensity functional training intervention in women: A pilot study. Universidad de Alicante &#xc1;rea de Educaci&#xf3;n F&#xed;sica y Deporte. 2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D, Edge J, Thomas C, Mercier J. Effects of high - intensity training on muscle lactate transporters and postexercise recovery of muscle lactate and hydrogen ions in women. American Journal of Physiology - Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology. 2008;295(6):R1991&#x2013;R1998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18832090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisebois MF, Rigby BR, Nichols DL. Physiological and fitness adaptations after eight weeks of high - intensity functional training in physically inactive adults. Sports. 2018;6(4):146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6316712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30428527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Gabbett TJ, Bourgeois F, de S&#xe1; Souza H, Miranda RC, Mez&#xea;ncio B, Soncin R, Cardoso Filho CA, Bottaro M, Hernandez AJ. Crossfit overview: Systematic review and meta - analysis. Sports medicine - open. 2018;4(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5826907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29484512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Academic press; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I Crossfit, editor. Crossfit Level 1 training guide. 2019. p. 258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feito Y, Heinrich KM, Butcher SJ, Poston WSC. High - intensity functional training (hift): Definition and research implications for improved fitness. Sports. 2018;6(3):76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6162410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30087252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felstead A, Bishop D, Fuller A, Jewson N, Lee T, Unwin L. Moving to the music: Learning processes, training and productive systems&#x2013;the case of exercise to music instruction. Cardiff School of Social Sciences. 2006:43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer W. Designing resistance training programs, 4e. Human Kinetics; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdouni H, Kliszczewicz B, Zouhal H, Rhibi F, Ben Salah FZ, Ben Abderrahman A. Effect of three fitness programs on strength, speed, flexibility and muscle power on sedentary subjects. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2022;62(1):25&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey AL. Quantifying and comparing activity in group exercise classes - a literature review. Journal of Fitness Research. 2012;1(1):50&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helgerud J, Engen LC, Wisl&#xf8;ff U, Hoff J. Aerobic endurance training improves soccer performance. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise. 2001;33(11):1925&#x2013;1931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11689745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Seelhorst D, Snyder S. Comparison of metabolic and heart rate responses to super slow vs. Traditional resistance training. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research. 2003;17(1):76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM, Carter H. The effect of endurance training on parameters of aerobic fitness. Sports medicine. 2000;29(6):373&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10870864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juel C, Klarskov C, Nielsen JJ, Krustrup P, Mohr M, Bangsbo J. Effect of high - intensity intermittent training on lactate and h+ release from human skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology - Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2004;286(2):E245&#x2013;E251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14559724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung AP. The impact of resistance training on distance running performance. Sports Medicine. 2003;33(7):539&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12762828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Roberts MD, Smith -, Ryan A, Kleiner SM, Jager R, Collins R, Cooke M, Davis JN, Galvan E. Issn exercise &amp; sports nutrition review update: Research &amp; recommendations. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition. 2018;15(1):1&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30068354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim PS, MAYHEW JL, PETERSON DF. A modified ymca bench press test as a predictor of 1 repetition maximum bench press strength. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research. 2002;16(3):440&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12173960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kliszczewicz B, Feito Y, Bycura D, Brown D, Price B. Vagal response to 15 - weeks of high - intensity functional training: A pilot study. Journal of Sport and Human Performance. 2016;4(3)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise. 2004;36(4):674&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leger LA, Mercier D, Gadoury C, Lambert J. The multistage 20 metre shuttle run test for aerobic fitness. Journal of sports sciences. 1988;6(2):93&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3184250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le&#xf3;n -, Quismondo J, Garc&#xed;a -, Unanue J, Burillo P. Best practices for fitness center business sustainability: A qualitative vision. Sustainability. 2020;12(12):5067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le&#xf3;n -, Quismondo J, Garc&#xed;a -, Unanue J, Burillo P. Service perceptions in fitness centers: Ipa approach by gender and age. International journal of environmental research and public health. 2020;17(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32326141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangran&#xe9; A. Training art, tracking discourse. Novia University of Applied Sciences; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuzaka A, Takahashi Y, Yamazoe M, Kumakura N, Ikeda A, Wilk B, Bar -, Or O. Validity of the multistage 20 - m shuttle - run test for japanese children, adolescents, and adults. Pediatric Exercise Science. 2004;16(2):113&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menezes FJd, J&#xfa;nior, Jesus &#xcd;Cd, Leite N. Predictive equations of maximum oxygen consumption by shuttle run test in children and adolescents: A systematic review. Revista Paulista de Pediatria. 2019;37(2):241&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6651308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30892544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mialich MS, Sicchieri JMF, Junior AAJ. Analysis of body composition: A critical review of the use of bioelectrical impedance analysis. International Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2014;2(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Krustrup P, Nielsen JJ, Nybo L, Rasmussen MK, Juel C, Bangsbo J. Effect of two different intense training regimens on skeletal muscle ion transport proteins and fatigue development. American Journal of Physiology - Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology. 2007;292(4):R1594&#x2013;R1602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosley PE. Bigorexia: Bodybuilding and muscle dysmorphia. European Eating Disorders Review: The Professional Journal of the Eating Disorders Association. 2009;17(3):191&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18759381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murawska -, Cialowicz E, Wojna J, Zuwala -, Jagiello J. Crossfit training changes brain - derived neurotrophic factor and irisin levels at rest, after wingate and progressive tests, and improves aerobic capacity and body composition of young physically active men and women. Journal of Physiology and Pharmacology. 2015;66(6):811&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26769830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murlasits Z, Kneffel Z, Thalib L. The physiological effects of concurrent strength and endurance training sequence: A systematic review and meta - analysis. Journal of sports sciences. 2018;36(11):1212&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28783467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical issues relating to scientific discovery in exercise science. International journal of exercise science. 2019;12(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver -, L&#xf3;pez A, Garc&#xed;a -, Valverde A, Sabido R. Summary of the evidence on responses and adaptations derived from crossfit training. A systematic review. Retos. 2022;46:309&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilegaard H, Domino K, Noland T, Juel C, Hellsten Y, Halestrap AP, Bangsbo J. Effect of high - intensity exercise training on lactate/h+ transport capacity in human skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology - Endocrinology and Metabolism. 1999;276(2):E255&#x2013;E261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9950784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotkin DL, Roberts MD, Haun CT, Schoenfeld BJ. Muscle fiber type transitions with exercise training: Shifting perspectives. Sports. 2021;9(9):127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8473039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34564332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riebe D, Ehrman JK, Liguori G, Magal M. Medicine ACoS Acsm&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Wolters Kluwer; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riseth L, Nost TH, Nilsen TI, Steinsbekk A. Long - term members&#x2019; use of fitness centers: A qualitative study. BMC sports science, medicine and rehabilitation. 2019;11:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6383217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30828457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabag A, Najafi A, Michael S, Esgin T, Halaki M, Hackett D. The compatibility of concurrent high intensity interval training and resistance training for muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta - analysis. Journal of sports sciences. 2018;36(21):2472&#x2013;2483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlegel P. CrossfitR training strategies from the perspective of concurrent training: A systematic review. Journal of sports science &amp; medicine. 2020;19(4):670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp R, Costill D, Fink W, King D. Effects of eight weeks of bicycle ergometer sprint training on human muscle buffer capacity. International journal of sports medicine. 1986;7(1):13&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3957514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultana RN, Sabag A, Keating SE, Johnson NA. The effect of low - volume high - intensity interval training on body composition and cardiorespiratory fitness: A systematic review and meta - analysis. Sports Medicine. 2019;49(11):1687&#x2013;1721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31401727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR. Worldwide survey of fitness trends for 2020. ACSM&#x2019;S Health &amp; Fitness Journal. 2019;23(6):10&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR. Worldwide survey of fitness trends for 2022. ACSM&#x2019;s Health &amp; Fitness Journal. 2022;26(1):11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen D, Utesch T, Wu J, Robertson S, Liu J, Hu G, Chen H. Effects of different protocols of high intensity interval training for vo2max improvements in adults: A meta - analysis of randomised controlled trials. Journal of science and medicine in sport. 2019;22(8):941&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30733142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Chida M, Ichioka M, Suda Y. Blood lactate parameters related to aerobic capacity and endurance performance. European journal of applied physiology and occupational physiology. 1987;56(1):7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3830147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>