<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41243337</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Histamine mediates food intake, but not muscle adaptations, following 10&#xa0;weeks of resistance training in humans.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP289240</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Histamine receptor antagonists, commonly used for allergies, block histamine signalling and can impair adaptations to high-intensity and endurance exercise. Because it remains unclear whether this is a universal mechanism of muscle adaptation, this study investigated histamine receptor blockade effects on resistance training adaptations. Acute study: Eight men performed three resistance training sessions with intake of either placebo, H<sub>1</sub>-receptor antihistamine (180&#xa0;mg fexofenadine) or combined H<sub>1</sub>/H<sub>2</sub>-receptor antihistamine (540&#xa0;mg fexofenadine/40&#xa0;mg famotidine). Post-exercise femoral arterial blood flow (ultrasound) was unaffected by histamine blockade. Chronic study: Eighteen men performed 10&#xa0;weeks of resistance training with placebo (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;9) or H<sub>1</sub>-receptor antihistamine (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;9, 180&#xa0;mg fexofenadine) intake before each session. Pre- and post-intervention measures included maximal strength (1RM), muscle volume (MRI), fat mass (skinfolds), fat free mass, oral glucose tolerance (OGTT), vascular function, dietary intake (food diaries) and muscle proteome profiling. Both groups similarly increased muscle volume (+7 &#xb1; 3% and +8 &#xb1; 3%; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.318) and maximal strength (+14% and +20%) and reduced diastolic blood pressure (-6 and -5&#xa0;mmHg), total OGTT glucose (-24% and -10%) and insulin (-10% and -9%). Unexpectedly the blockade group gained fat mass (+0.6 &#xb1; 0.6 kg), whereas the placebo group did not (-0.3 &#xb1; 0.8 kg; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.011), potentially related to increased carbohydrate intake (+29 &#xb1; 20% vs. -7 &#xb1; 19%; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.005). In conclusion histamine blockade did not impair resistance training-induced adaptations, suggesting that intercellular H<sub>1</sub>-histaminergic crosstalk is not a universal mechanism across training modalities. However antihistamine intake increased food intake and fat mass, possibly reflecting histamine's role in appetite regulation. KEY POINTS: Post-resistance exercise femoral arterial blood flow is unaffected by single H<sub>1</sub> or combined H<sub>1</sub>/H<sub>2</sub> receptor histamine blockade. H<sub>1&#xa0;</sub>histamine receptor blockade does not impair resistance training adaptations, such as increases in muscle volume and maximal strength, and decreases in blood pressure, glucose and insulin levels. Histaminergic crosstalk in the muscle microenvironment is involved in endurance and high-intensity interval training adaptations, but this may not be a universal mechanism across all training modalities. Histamine blockade leads to increased habitual carbohydrate intake and fat mass following 10&#xa0;weeks of resistance training, possibly due to histamine's role in hypothalamic appetite regulation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology &#xa9; 2025 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van de Loock</LastName><ForeName>Alexia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3471-1869</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vandecauter</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8789-470X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ullrich</LastName><ForeName>Max</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-3079-6110</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lievens</LastName><ForeName>Eline</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2549-3369</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schro&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Helene</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8473-552X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moreno-Justicia</LastName><ForeName>Roger</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8587-4772</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk Foundation Center for Basic Metabolic Research, University of Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weyns</LastName><ForeName>Anneleen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Thienen</LastName><ForeName>Ruud</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calders</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6327-8155</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deshmukh</LastName><ForeName>Atul S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2278-1843</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk Foundation Center for Basic Metabolic Research, University of Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van der Stede</LastName><ForeName>Thibaux</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2038-2504</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit for Molecular Immunology and Inflammation, Center for Inflammation Research, Flanders Institute for Biotechnology (VIB), Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Pediatrics, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derave</LastName><ForeName>Wim</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2225-5587</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>G080321N</GrantID><Agency>Fonds Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">H1&#x2010;antihistamines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fat mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">food intake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">histamine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle adaptation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41243337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP289240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdul&#x2010;Ghani, M. A., Matsuda, M., Balas, B., &amp; DeFronzo, R. A. (2007). Muscle and liver insulin resistance indexes derived from the oral glucose tolerance test. Diabetes Care, 30(1), 89&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainsworth, B. E., Haskell, W. L., Leon, A. S., Jacobs, D. R., Montoye, H. J., Sallis, J. F., &amp; Paffenbarger, R. S. (1993). Compendium of physical activities &#x2013; Classification of energy costs of human physical activities. Official Journal of the American College of Sports Medicine, 25(1), 71&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton, R. E., Tew, G. A., Aning, J. J., Gilbert, S. E., Lewis, L., &amp; Saxton, J. M. (2020). Effects of short&#x2010;term, medium&#x2010;term and long&#x2010;term resistance exercise training on cardiometabolic health outcomes in adults: Systematic review with meta&#x2010;analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 54(6), 341&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle, T., &amp; Earle, R. (2008). Essentials of strength training and conditioning (3rd ed., p. 394). Human Kinetics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker, J., Riley, G., Romero, M. R., Haynes, A. R., Hilton, H., Simon, M., Hancock, J., Tateossian, H., Ripoll, V. M., &amp; Blanco, G. (2010). Identification of a Z&#x2010;band associated protein complex involving KY, FLNC and IGFN1. Experimental Cell Research, 316, 1856&#x2013;1870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett&#x2010;O'Keefe, Z., Kaplon, R. E., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2013). Sustained postexercise vasodilatation and histamine receptor activation following small muscle&#x2010;mass exercise in humans. Experimental Physiology, 98, 268&#x2013;277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstr&#xf6;m, J. (1975). Percutaneous needle biopsy of skeletal muscle in physiological and clinical research. Scandinavian Journal of Clinical and Laboratory Investigation, 35(7), 609&#x2013;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betz, M. W., Fuchs, C. J., Chedd, F., Monsegue, A. P., Hendriks, F. K., van Kranenburg, J. M. X., Goessens, J., Houben, A., Verdijk, L. B., van Loon, L. J. C., &amp; Snijders, T. (2025). Post&#x2010;exercise cooling lowers skeletal muscle microvascular perfusion and blunts amino acid incorporation into muscle tissue in active young adults. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 57(9), 1866&#x2013;1876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisconti, A. V., C&#xe8;, E., Longo, S., Venturelli, M., Coratella, G., Shokohyar, S., Ghahremani, R., Rampichini, S., Limonta, E., &amp; Esposito, F. (2019). Evidence of improved vascular function in the arteries of trained but not untrained limbs after isolated knee&#x2010;extension training. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blandina, P., &amp; Passani, M. B. (2016). In P. Blandina, &amp; M. B. Passani (Eds.), Histamine receptors. Springer International Publishing. https://link.springer.com/10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;319&#x2010;40308&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazev, R., Carl, C. S., Ng, Y. K., Molendijk, J., Voldstedlund, C. T., Zhao, Y., Xiao, D., Kueh, A. J., Miotto, P. M., Haynes, V. R., Hardee, J. P., Chung, J. D., McNamara, J. W., Qian, H., Gregorevic, P., Oakhill, J. S., Herold, M. J., Jensen, T. E., Lisowski, L., &#x2026; Parker, B. L. (2022). Phosphoproteomics of three exercise modalities identifies canonical signaling and C18ORF25 as an AMPK substrate regulating skeletal muscle function. Cell Metabolism, 34(10), 1561&#x2013;1577.e9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousquet, J., Sch&#xfc;nemann, H. J., Samolinski, B., Demoly, P., Baena&#x2010;Cagnani, C. E., Bachert, C., Bonini, S., Boulet, L. P., Bousquet, P. J., Brozek, J. L., Canonica, G. W., Casale, T. B., Cruz, A. A., Fokkens, W. J., Fonseca, J. A., van Wijk, R. G., Grouse, L., Haahtela, T., Khaltaev, N., &#x2026; World Health Organization Collaborating Center for Asthma and Rhinitis. (2012). Allergic rhinitis and its impact on asthma (ARIA): Achievements in 10 years and future needs. Journal of Allergy and Clinical Immunology, 130(5), 1049&#x2013;1062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, O., &amp; Sherwin, R. (2013). Influence of VMH fuel sensing on hypoglycemic responses. Trends in Endocrinology and Metabolism, 24(12), 616&#x2013;624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifford, P. S., &amp; Hellsten, Y. (2004). Vasodilatory mechanisms in contracting skeletal muscle. Journal of Applied Physiology, 97(1), 393&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conn, V. S., Koopman, R. J., Ruppar, T. M., Phillips, L. J., Mehr, D. R., &amp; Hafdahl, A. R. (2014). Insulin sensitivity following exercise interventions: Systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of outcomes among healthy adults. Journal of Primary Care &amp; Community Health, 5(3), 211&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig, B. W., Everhart, J., &amp; Brown, R. (1989). The influence of high&#x2010;resistance training on glucose tolerance in young and elderly subjects. Mechanisms of Ageing and Development, 49(2), 147&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demichev, V., Szyrwiel, L., Yu, F., Teo, G. C., Rosenberger, G., Niewienda, A., Ludwig, D., Decker, J., Kaspar&#x2010;Schoenefeld, S., Lilley, K. S., M&#xfc;lleder, M., Nesvizhskii, A. I., &amp; Ralser, M. (2022). dia&#x2010;PASEF data analysis using FragPipe and DIA&#x2010;NN for deep proteomics of low sample amounts. Nature Communications, 13(1), 3944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond, L. R., Campos, H. O., Drummond, F. R., de Oliveira, G. M., Fernandes, J., Amorim, R. P., da, C. Monteiro, M., Lara, H. F. G., Leite, L. H. R., &amp; Coimbra, C. C. (2022). Acute and chronic effects of physical exercise on IgA and IgG levels and susceptibility to upper respiratory tract infections: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Pflugers Archiv: European Journal of Physiology, 474(12), 1221&#x2013;1248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, J., Yun, H., Wang, H., Bai, X., Su, Y., Ge, X., Wang, Y., Gu, B., Zhao, L., Yu, J. G., &amp; Song, Y. (2024). Proteomic profiling of muscular adaptations to short&#x2010;term concentric versus eccentric exercise training in humans. Molecular and Cellular Proteomics, 23(4), 100748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durnin, J., &amp; Rahaman, M. M. (1967). The assessment of the amount of fat in the human body from measurements of skinfold thickness. British Journal of Nutrition, 21(3), 681&#x2013;689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan, B., &amp; Sharples, A. P. (2023). Molecular responses to acute exercise and their relevance for adaptations in skeletal muscle to exercise training. Physiological Reviews, 103(3), 2057&#x2013;2170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ely, M. R., Mangum, J. E., Needham, K. W., Minson, C. T., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2024). Effect of histamine&#x2010;receptor antagonism on the circulating inflammatory cell and cytokine response to exercise: A pilot study. Physiological Reports, 12(3), e15936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ely, M. R., Romero, S. A., Sieck, D. C., Mangum, J. E., Luttrell, M. J., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2017). A single dose of histamine&#x2010;receptor antagonists before downhill running alters markers of muscle damage and delayed&#x2010;onset muscle soreness. Journal of Applied Physiology, 122(3), 631&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs, C. J., Kouw, I. W. K., Churchward&#x2010;Venne, T. A., Smeets, J. S., Senden, J. M., van Marken Lichtenbelt, W. D., Verdijk, L. B., &amp; van Loon, L. J. C. (2020). Postexercise cooling impairs muscle protein synthesis rates in recreational athletes. The Journal of Physiology, 598(4), 755&#x2013;772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe, J. J., Broatch, J. R., Trewin, A. J., Hanson, E. D., Argus, C. K., Garnham, A. P., Halson, S. L., Polman, R. C., Bishop, D. J., &amp; Petersen, A. C. (2019). Cold water immersion attenuates anabolic signaling and skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy, but not strength gain, following whole&#x2010;body resistance training. Journal of Applied Physiology, 127(5), 1403&#x2013;1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, D. J., Marsh, C. E., Thomas, H. J., Lester, L., Scurrah, K. J., Haynes, A., &amp; Naylor, L. H. (2023). Exercise and artery function in twins: Sex differences in a cross&#x2010;over trial. Hypertension, 80(6), 1343&#x2013;1352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas, H. L., Sergeeva, O. A., &amp; Selbach, O. (2008). Histamine in the nervous system. Physiological Reviews, 88(3), 1183&#x2013;1241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad&#x2010;T&#xf3;volli, R., Dragano, N. R. V., Ramalho, A. F. S., &amp; Velloso, L. A. (2017). Development and function of the blood&#x2010;brain barrier in the context of metabolic control. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 11, 224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriquez&#x2010;Olguin, C., Meneses&#x2010;Valdes, R., Kritsiligkou, P., &amp; Fuentes&#x2010;Lemus, E. (2023). From workout to molecular switches: How does skeletal muscle produce, sense, and transduce subcellular redox signals? Free Radical Biology and Medicine, 209, 355&#x2013;365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry, C. (2005). Basal metabolic rate studies in humans: Measurement and development of new equations. Public Health Nutrition, 8(7a), 1133&#x2013;1152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holten, M. K., Zacho, M., Gaster, M., Juel, C., Wojtaszewski, J. F. P., &amp; Dela, F. (2004). Strength training increases insulin&#x2010;mediated glucose uptake, GLUT4 content, and insulin signaling in skeletal muscle in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes, 53(2), 294&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes, D. C., Ellefsen, S., &amp; Baar, K. (2018). Adaptations to endurance and strength training. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 8(6), a029769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi, J. J., Halonen, E. J., Sharples, A. P., O'connell, T. M., Kuikka, L., Lappi, V.&#x2010;M., Salokas, K., Keskitalo, S., Varjosalo, M., &amp; Ahtiainen, J. P. (2025). Human skeletal muscle possesses both reversible proteomic signatures and a retained proteomic memory after repeated resistance training. The Journal of Physiology, 603(9), 2655&#x2013;2673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaar, S. J., Natesan, S., McCutcheon, R., &amp; Howes, O. D. (2020). Antipsychotics: Mechanisms underlying clinical response and side&#x2010;effects and novel treatment approaches based on pathophysiology. Neuropharmacology, 172, 107704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick, C. M., Wilborn, C. D., Roberts, M. D., Smith&#x2010;Ryan, A., Kleiner, S. M., J&#xe4;ger, R., Collins, R., Cooke, M., Davis, J. N., Galvan, E., Greenwood, M., Lowery, L. M., Wildman, R., Antonio, J., &amp; Kreider, R. B. (2018). ISSN exercise &amp; sports nutrition review update: Research &amp; recommendations. Journal of International Society of Sports Nutrition, 15(1), 38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luttrell, M. J., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2017). The intriguing role of histamine in exercise responses. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 45(1), 16&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuda, M., &amp; DeFronzo, R. A. (1999). Insulin sensitivity indices obtained from oral glucose tolerance testing. Diabetes Care, 22(9), 1462&#x2013;1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccord, J. L., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2006). H 1 and H 2 receptors mediate postexercise hyperemia in sedentary and endurance exercise&#x2010;trained men and women. Journal of Applied Physiology, 101(6), 1693&#x2013;1701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKendry, J., Stokes, T., McLeod, J. C., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2021). Resistance exercise, aging, disuse, and muscle protein metabolism. Comprehensive Physiology, 11(3), 2249&#x2013;2278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, W. J., Sherman, W. M., &amp; Ivy, J. L. (1984). Effect of strength training on glucose tolerance and post&#x2010;glucose insulin response. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 16(6), 539&#x2013;543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moesgaard, L., Moreno&#x2010;Justicia, R., Schmalbruch, J., Jessen, S., Stocks, B., Bangsbo, J., Deshmukh, A. S., &amp; Hostrup, M. (2024). Muscle fiber proteomics reveals sex&#x2010; and fiber type&#x2010;specific adaptations to resistance training. Available at: http://biorxiv.org/lookup/doi/10.1101/2024.09.16.612737</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno&#x2010;Justicia, R., Van der Stede, T., Stocks, B., Laitila, J., Seaborne, R. A., van de Loock, A., Lievens, E., Samodova, D., Mar&#xed;n&#x2010;Arraiza, L., Dmytriyeva, O., Browaeys, R., van Vossel, K., Moesgaard, L., Yigit, N., Anckaert, J., Weyns, A., Van Thienen, R., Sahl, R. E., Zanoteli, E., &#x2026; Deshmukh, A. S. (2025). Human skeletal muscle fiber heterogeneity beyond myosin heavy chains. Nature Communications, 16(1), 1764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murgia, M., Nogara, L., Baraldo, M., Reggiani, C., Mann, M., &amp; Schiaffino, S. (2021). Protein profile of fiber types in human skeletal muscle: A single&#x2010;fiber proteomics study. Skeletal Muscle, 11(1), 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo, J. L., Pinto, M. D., Nosaka, K., &amp; Steele, J. (2024). Maximal number of repetitions at percentages of the one repetition maximum: A meta&#x2010;regression and moderator analysis of sex, age, training status, and exercise. Sports Medicine, 54(2), 303&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Donovan, S. D., Lenz, M., Goossens, G. H., van der Kallen, C. J. H., Eussen, S., Stehouwer, C. D. A., van Greevenbroek, M. M., Schram, M. T., Sep, S. J., Peeters, R. L. M., Blaak, E. E., van Riel, N. A. W., de Kok, T., &amp; Arts, I. C. W. (2019). Improved quantification of muscle insulin sensitivity using oral glucose tolerance test data: The MISI Calculator. Scientific Reports, 9, 9388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neill, A., Williams, M. W., Resneck, W. G., Milner, D. J., Capetanaki, Y., &amp; Bloch, R. J. (2002). Sarcolemmal organization in skeletal muscle lacking desmin: Evidence for cytokeratins associated with the membrane skeleton at costameres. Molecular Biology of the Cell, 13, 2347&#x2013;2359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ookuma, K., Yoshimatsu, H., Sakata, T., Fujimoto, K., &amp; Fukagawa, K. (1989). Hypothalamic sites of neuronal histamine action on food intake by rats. Brain Research, 490(2), 268&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons, M. E., &amp; Ganellin, C. R. (2006). Histamine and its receptors. British Journal of Pharmacology, 147 Suppl 1(Suppl 1), S127&#x2013;S135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passali, D., Cingi, C., Staffa, P., Passali, F., Muluk, N. B., &amp; Bellussi, M. L. (2018). The International Study of the Allergic Rhinitis Survey: Outcomes from 4 geographical regions. Asia Pacific Allergy, 8(1), e7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake, J. M., Oliver Neubauer, X., Walsh, N. P., &amp; Simpson, R. J. (2017). Recovery of the immune system after exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology, 122(5), 1077&#x2013;1087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellinger, T. K., Dumke, B. R., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2013). Effect of H1&#x2010; and H2&#x2010;histamine receptor blockade on postexercise insulin sensitivity. Physiological Reports, 1(2), e00033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellinger, T. K., Simmons, G. H., Maclean, D. A., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2010). Local histamine H1&#x2010;and H2&#x2010;receptor blockade reduces postexercise skeletal muscle interstitial glucose concentrations in humans. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism, 35(5), 617&#x2013;626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xe5;degran, G., &amp; Saltin, B. (1999). Nitric oxide in the regulation of vasomotor tone in human skeletal muscle. The American Physiological Society, 276(6), H1951&#x2013;H1960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratliff, J. C., Barber, J. A., Palmese, L. B., Reutenauer, E. L., &amp; Tek, C. (2010). Association of prescription H1 antihistamine use with obesity: Results from the national health and nutrition examination survey. Obesity (Silver Spring), 18(12), 2398&#x2013;2400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riem, L., Pinette, M., DuCharme, O., Pabon, V., Morris, J., Coggins, A., Harold, L., Costanzo, K. E., Cousins, M., Hein, R., Rhodes, M., Lievens, E., Feng, X., Benusa, S. D., Breeding, T., Derave, W., &amp; Blemker, S. S. (2025). Big bones mean big muscles: AI quantifies 71 individual muscles across the body, revealing widespread links between muscle, bone, and size. bioRxiv. Available at: http://biorxiv.org/lookup/doi/10.1101/2025.04.01.646599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie, M. E., Phipson, B., Wu, D., Hu, Y., Law, C. W., Shi, W., &amp; Smyth, G. K. (2015). Limma powers differential expression analyses for RNA&#x2010;sequencing and microarray studies. Nucleic Acids Research, 43(7), e47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, L. A., Raastad, T., Markworth, J. F., Figueiredo, V. C., Egner, I. M., Shield, A., Cameron&#x2010;Smith, D., Coombes, J. S., &amp; Peake, J. M. (2015). Post&#x2010;exercise cold water immersion attenuates acute anabolic signalling and long&#x2010;term adaptations in muscle to strength training. The Journal of Physiology, 593(18), 4285&#x2013;4301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, M. D., McCarthy, J. J., Hornberger, T. A., Phillips, S. M., Mackey, A. L., Nader, G. A., Boppart, M. D., Kavazis, A. N., Reidy, P. T., Ogasawara, R., Libardi, C. A., Ugrinowitsch, C., Booth, F. W., &amp; Esser, K. A. (2023). Mechanisms of mechanical overload&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Current understanding and future directions. Physiological Reviews, 103(4), 2679&#x2013;2757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero, S. A., Hocker, A. D., Mangum, J. E., Luttrell, M. J., Turnbull, D. W., Struck, A. J., Ely, M. R., Sieck, D. C., Dreyer, H. C., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2016). Evidence of a broad histamine footprint on the human exercise transcriptome. The Journal of Physiology, 594(17), 5009&#x2013;5023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozenek, R., Ward, P., Long, S., &amp; Garhammer, J. (2002). Effects of high&#x2010;calorie supplements on body composition and muscular strength following resistance training. The Journal of Sports Medicine and Physical Fitness, 42(3), 340&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieck, D. C., Kobak, S. H., Larson, E. A., Dreyer, H. C., Fogarty, M. J., Sieck, G. C., Minson, C. T., &amp; Halliwill, J. R. (2025). Histamine is a molecular transducer of adaptation to endurance exercise training in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 138(6), 1398&#x2013;1410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, F. M., Duarte&#x2010;Mendes, P., Teixeira, A. M., Soares, C. M., &amp; Ferreira, J. P. (2024). The effects of combined exercise training on glucose metabolism and inflammatory markers in sedentary adults: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Scientific Reports, 14(1), 1936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater, G. J., Dieter, B. P., Marsh, D. J., Helms, E. R., Shaw, G., &amp; Iraki, J. (2019). Is an energy surplus required to maximize skeletal muscle hypertrophy associated with resistance training. Frontiers in Nutrition, 6, 131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storey, J. D., &amp; Tibshirani, R. (2003). Statistical significance for genomewide studies. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 100(16), 9440&#x2013;9445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidball, J. G., &amp; Villalta, S. A. (2010). Regulatory interactions between muscle and the immune system during muscle regeneration. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 298(5), R1173&#x2013;R1187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Stede, T., Blancquaert, L., Stassen, F., Everaert, I., Van Thienen, R., Vervaet, C., Gliemann, L., Hellsten, Y., &amp; Derave, W. (2021). Histamine H 1 and H 2 receptors are essential transducers of the integrative exercise training response in humans. Science Advances, 7, 2856&#x2013;2870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Stede, T., Spaas, J., de Jager, S., de Brandt, J., Hansen, C., Stautemas, J., Vercammen, B., de Baere, S., Croubels, S., van Assche, C. H., Pastor, B. C., Vandenbosch, M., Van Thienen, R., Verboven, K., Hansen, D., Bov&#xe9;, T., Lapauw, B., van Praet, C., Hellsten, Y., &#x2026; Derave, W. (2023). Extensive profiling of histidine&#x2010;containing dipeptides reveals species&#x2010; and tissue&#x2010;specific distribution and metabolism in mice, rats, and humans. Acta Physiologica, 239(1), e14020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Stede, T., Moreno&#x2010;Justicia, R., van de Casteele, F., Lievens, E., van de Loock, A., Vandecauter, J., Merseburger, P., van den Eynden, J., van Haver, D., Staes, A., Devos, S., Hostrup, M., Mestdagh, P., Vandesompele, J., Stocks, B., Deshmukh, A. S., &amp; Derave, W. (2025). Deconvoluting fiber type proportions from human skeletal muscle transcriptomics and proteomics data using FibeRtypeR. Available at: http://biorxiv.org/lookup/doi/10.1101/2025.09.17.676778</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Stede, T., Van de Loock, A., Turiel, G., Hansen, C., Tamariz&#x2010;Ellemann, A., Ullrich, M., Lievens, E., Spaas, J., Yigit, N., Anckaert, J., Nuytens, J., de Baere, S., Van Thienen, R., Weyns, A., de Wilde, L., van Eenoo, P., Croubels, S., Halliwill, J. R., Mestdagh, P., &#x2026; Derave, W. (2025). Cellular deconstruction of the human skeletal muscle microenvironment identifies an exercise&#x2010;induced histaminergic crosstalk. Cell Metabolism, 37(4), 842&#x2013;856.e7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise, S. K., Damask, C., Roland, L. T., Ebert, C., Levy, J. M., Lin, S., Luong, A., Rodriguez, K., Sedaghat, A. R., Toskala, E., Villwock, J., Abdullah, B., Akdis, C., Alt, J. A., Ansotegui, I. J., Azar, A., Baroody, F., Benninger, M. S., Bernstein, J., &#x2026; Zhang, L. (2018). International consensus statement on allergy and rhinology: Allergic rhinitis. International Forum of Allergy &amp; Rhinology, 8, 108&#x2013;352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanai, K., &amp; Passani, M. B. (2021). The Functional Roles of Histamine Receptors.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Z., &amp; Wang, Y. (2012). Apolipoprotein C&#x2010;III and hepatic triglyceride&#x2010;rich lipoprotein production. Current Opinion in Lipidology, 23(3), 206&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Zhang, Y. J., Zhang, H. W., Ye, W. B., &amp; Korivi, M. (2021). Low&#x2010;to&#x2010;moderate&#x2010;intensity resistance exercise is more effective than high&#x2010;intensity at improving endothelial function in adults: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(13), 6723.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>