<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">22674717</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>590</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Consumption of a high-fat diet, but not regular endurance exercise training, regulates hypothalamic lipid accumulation in mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4377</StartPage><EndPage>4389</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4377-89</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.233288</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Obesity is characterised by increased storage of fatty acids in an expanded adipose tissue mass and in peripheral tissues such as the skeletal muscle and liver, where it is associated with the development of insulin resistance. Insulin resistance also develops in the central nervous system with high-fat feeding. The capacity for hypothalamic cells to accumulate/store lipids, and the effects of obesity remain undefined. The aims of this study were (1) to examine hypothalamic lipid content in mice with increased dietary fat intake and in obese ob/ob mice fed a low-fat diet, and (2) to determine whether endurance exercise training could reduce hypothalamic lipid accumulation in high-fat fed mice. Male C57BL/6 mice were fed a low- (LFD) or high-fat diet (HFD) for 12 weeks; ob/ob mice were maintained on a chow diet. HFD-exercise (HFD-ex) mice underwent 12 weeks of high-fat feeding with 6 weeks of treadmill exercise training (increasing from 30 to 70 min day(-1)). Hypothalamic lipids were assessed by unbiased mass spectrometry. The HFD increased body mass and hepatic lipid accumulation, and induced glucose intolerance, while the HFD-ex mice had reduced body weight and improved glucose tolerance. A total of 335 lipid molecular species were identified and quantified. Lipids known to induce insulin resistance, including ceramide (22%&#x2191;), diacylglycerol (25%&#x2191;), lysophosphatidylcholine (17%&#x2191;), cholesterol esters (60%&#x2191;) and dihexosylceramide (33%&#x2191;), were increased in the hypothalamus of HFD vs. LFD mice. Hypothalamic lipids were unaltered with exercise training and in the ob/ob mice, suggesting that obesity per se does not alter hypothalamic lipids. Overall, hypothalamic lipid accumulation is regulated by dietary lipid content and is refractory to change with endurance exercise training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borg</LastName><ForeName>Melissa L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology of Lipid Metabolism laboratory, Department of Physiology, Monash University, Clayton, Victoria, 3800, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Omran</LastName><ForeName>Simin Fallah</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weir</LastName><ForeName>Jacquelyn</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meikle</LastName><ForeName>Peter J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watt</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002518">Ceramides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004075">Diglycerides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014280">Triglycerides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017346">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2012 Sep 1;590(17):4121. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2012.239491.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">22962031</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002518" MajorTopicYN="N">Ceramides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059305" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet, High-Fat</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="Y">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004075" MajorTopicYN="N">Diglycerides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007031" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypothalamus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007333" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin Resistance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050356" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lipid Metabolism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008810" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred C57BL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008820" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Obese</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009043" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Activity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017346" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014280" MajorTopicYN="N">Triglycerides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22674717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3473292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.233288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jphysiol.2012.233288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersson A, Sjodin A, Olsson R, Vessby B. Effects of physical exercise on phospholipid fatty acid composition in skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 1998;274:E432&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9530125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belgardt BF, Mauer J, Wunderlich FT, Ernst MB, Pal M, Spohn G, Bronneke HS, Brodesser S, Hampel B, Schauss AC, Bruning JC. Hypothalamic and pituitary c-Jun N-terminal kinase 1 signaling coordinately regulates glucose metabolism. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107:6028&#x2013;6033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2851918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20231445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benoit SC, Kemp CJ, Elias CF, Abplanalp W, Herman JP, Migrenne S, Lefevre AL, Cruciani-Guglielmacci C, Magnan C, Yu F, Niswender K, Irani BG, Holland WL, Clegg DJ. Palmitic acid mediates hypothalamic insulin resistance by altering PKC-theta subcellular localization in rodents. J Clin Invest. 2009;119:2577&#x2013;2589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2735917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19726875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronfman M, Morales MN, Orellana A. Diacylglycerol activation of protein kinase C is modulated by long-chain acyl-CoA. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1988;152:987&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3377782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce CR, Thrush AB, Mertz VA, Bezaire V, Chabowski A, Heigenhauser GJ, Dyck DJ. Endurance training in obese humans improves glucose tolerance and mitochondrial fatty acid oxidation and alters muscle lipid content. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291:E99&#x2013;E107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16464906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coll T, Eyre E, Rodriguez-Calvo R, Palomer X, Sanchez RM, Merlos M, Laguna JC, Vazquez-Carrera M. Oleate reverses palmitate-induced insulin resistance and inflammation in skeletal muscle cells. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:11107&#x2013;11116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18281277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutler RG, Kelly J, Storie K, Pedersen WA, Tammara A, Hatanpaa K, Troncoso JC, Mattson MP. Involvement of oxidative stress-induced abnormalities in ceramide and cholesterol metabolism in brain aging and Alzheimer's disease. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2004;101:2070&#x2013;2075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC357053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14970312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond GB. Reporting ethical matters in The Journal of Physiology: standards and advice. J Physiol. 2009;587:713&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2669962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19218620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folch J, Lees M, Sloane Stanley GH. A simple method for the isolation and purification of total lipides from animal tissues. J Biol Chem. 1957;226:497&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13428781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freed LM, Wakabayashi S, Bell JM, Rapoport SI. Effect of inhibition of beta-oxidation on incorporation of [U-14C]palmitate and [1-14C]arachidonate into brain lipids. Brain Res. 1994;645:41&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8062099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao S, Zhu G, Gao X, Wu D, Carrasco P, Casals N, Hegardt FG, Moran TH, Lopaschuk GD. Important roles of brain-specific carnitine palmitoyltransferase and ceramide metabolism in leptin hypothalamic control of feeding. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:9691&#x2013;9696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3111271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21593415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Delany JP, Otto AD, Kuller L, Vockley J, South-Paul JE, Thomas SB, Brown J, McTigue K, Hames KC, Lang W, Jakicic JM. Effects of diet and physical activity interventions on weight loss and cardiometabolic risk factors in severely obese adults: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2010;304:1795&#x2013;1802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20935337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X. Lipid alterations in the earliest clinically recognizable stage of Alzheimer's disease: implication of the role of lipids in the pathogenesis of Alzheimer's disease. Curr Alzheimer Res. 2005;2:65&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15977990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X, D MH, McKeel DW, Jr, Kelley J, Morris JC. Substantial sulfatide deficiency and ceramide elevation in very early Alzheimer's disease: potential role in disease pathogenesis. J Neurochem. 2002;82:809&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12358786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannun YA, Obeid LM. The Ceramide-centric universe of lipid-mediated cell regulation: stress encounters of the lipid kind. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:25847&#x2013;25850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12011103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haughey NJ, Cutler RG, Tamara A, McArthur JC, Vargas DL, Pardo CA, Turchan J, Nath A, Mattson MP. Perturbation of sphingolipid metabolism and ceramide production in HIV-dementia. Ann Neurol. 2004;55:257&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14755730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Goodpaster BH, Kelley DE. Effects of weight loss and physical activity on muscle lipid content and droplet size. Obes Res. 2004;12:761&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15166296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland WL, Bikman BT, Wang LP, Yuguang G, Sargent KM, Bulchand S, Knotts TA, Shui G, Clegg DJ, Wenk MR, Pagliassotti MJ, Scherer PE, Summers SA. Lipid-induced insulin resistance mediated by the proinflammatory receptor TLR4 requires saturated fatty acid-induced ceramide biosynthesis in mice. J Clin Invest. 2011;121:1858&#x2013;1870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3083776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21490391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland WL, Brozinick JT, Wang LP, Hawkins ED, Sargent KM, Liu Y, Narra K, Hoehn KL, Knotts TA, Siesky A, Nelson DH, Karathanasis SK, Fontenot GK, Birnbaum MJ, Summers SA. Inhibition of ceramide synthesis ameliorates glucocorticoid-, saturated-fat-, and obesity-induced insulin resistance. Cell Metab. 2007;5:167&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G, Lindstrom J, Valle TT, Eriksson JG, Jousilahti P, Silventoinen K, Qiao Q, Tuomilehto J. Physical activity, body mass index, and risk of type 2 diabetes in patients with normal or impaired glucose regulation. Arch Intern Med. 2004;164:892&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15111376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itani SI, Ruderman NB, Schmieder F, Boden G. Lipid-induced insulin resistance in human muscle is associated with changes in diacylglycerol, protein kinase C, and I&#x3ba;B-&#x3b1;. Diabetes. 2002;51:2005&#x2013;2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12086926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karmi A, Iozzo P, Viljanen A, Hirvonen J, Fielding BA, Virtanen K, Oikonen V, Kemppainen J, Viljanen T, Guiducci L, Haaparanta-Solin M, Nagren K, Solin O, Nuutila P. Increased brain fatty acid uptake in metabolic syndrome. Diabetes. 2010;59:2171&#x2013;2177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2927939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20566663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan RS, Drosatos K, Goldberg IJ. Creating and curing fatty hearts. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2010;13:145&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5628503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinridders A, Schenten D, Konner AC, Belgardt BF, Mauer J, Okamura T, Wunderlich FT, Medzhitov R, Bruning JC. MyD88 signaling in the CNS is required for development of fatty acid-induced leptin resistance and diet-induced obesity. Cell Metab. 2009;10:249&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3898351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19808018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam TK, Pocai A, Gutierrez-Juarez R, Obici S, Bryan J, Aguilar-Bryan L, Schwartz GJ, Rossetti L. Hypothalamic sensing of circulating fatty acids is required for glucose homeostasis. Nat Med. 2005;11:320&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Pinnamaneni SK, Eo SJ, Cho IH, Pyo JH, Kim CK, Sinclair AJ, Febbraio MA, Watt MJ. Saturated, but not n-6 polyunsaturated, fatty acids induce insulin resistance: role of intramuscular accumulation of lipid metabolites. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:1467&#x2013;1474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16357064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y, Hirose H, Ohneda M, Johnson JH, McGarry JD, Unger RH. &#x3b2;-Cell lipotoxicity in the pathogenesis of non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus of obese rats: impairment in adipocyte-beta-cell relationships. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1994;91:10878&#x2013;10882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC45129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7971976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennox WG. The cerebral circulation XIV. The respiration quotient of the brain and of the experiments in man. Arch Neuro Psychiatr. 1931;26:719&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson MP, Kapogiannis D, Greig NH. Tweaking energy metabolism to prevent and treat neurological disorders. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2010;88:437&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3743231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20856237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurchie EJ. Dietary lipids in the regulation of membrane fluidity and function. In: Aloid RC, Curtain CC, Gordon LM, editors. Physiological Regulation of Membrane Fluidity. New York: Publisher: Alan R. Liss; 1988. pp. 189&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meikle PJ, Wong G, Tsorotes D, Barlow CK, Weir JM, Christopher MJ, MacIntosh GL, Goudey B, Stern L, Kowalczyk A, Haviv I, White AJ, Dart AM, Duffy SJ, Jennings GL, Kingwell BA. Plasma lipidomic analysis of stable and unstable coronary artery disease. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2011;31:2723&#x2013;2732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21903946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JC, Gnaedinger JM, Rapoport SI. Utilization of plasma fatty acid in rat brain: distribution of [14C]palmitate between oxidative and synthetic pathways. J Neurochem. 1987;49:1507&#x2013;1514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2889801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell TW, Turner N, Hulbert AJ, Else PL, Hawley JA, Lee JS, Bruce CR, Blanksby SJ. Exercise alters the profile of phospholipid molecular species in rat skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2004;97:1823&#x2013;1829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15208292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montell E, Turini M, Marotta M, Roberts M, Noe V, Ciudad CJ, Mace K, Gomez-Foix AM. DAG accumulation from saturated fatty acids desensitizes insulin stimulation of glucose uptake in muscle cells. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2001;280:E229&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11158925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes JC, Coope A, Morari J, Cintra DE, Roman EA, Pauli JR, Romanatto T, Carvalheira JB, Oliveira AL, Saad MJ, Velloso LA. High-fat diet induces apoptosis of hypothalamic neurons. PLoS One. 2009;4:e5045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2661137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19340313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton WT, Abe T, Poduslo SE, DeVries GH. The lipid composition of isolated brain cells and axons. J Neurosci Res. 1975;1:57&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1223319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono H, Pocai A, Wang Y, Sakoda H, Asano T, Backer JM, Schwartz GJ, Rossetti L. Activation of hypothalamic S6 kinase mediates diet-induced hepatic insulin resistance in rats. J Clin Invest. 2008;118:2959&#x2013;2968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2447927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18618016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peruzzo B, Pastor FE, Blazquez JL, Schobitz K, Pelaez B, Amat P, Rodriguez EM. A second look at the barriers of the medial basal hypothalamus. Exp Brain Res. 2000;132:10&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10836632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petridou A, Nikolaidis MG, Matsakas A, Schulz T, Michna H, Mougios V. Effect of exercise training on the fatty acid composition of lipid classes in rat liver, skeletal muscle, and adipose tissue. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;94:84&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15682327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posey KA, Clegg DJ, Printz RL, Byun J, Morton GJ, Vivekanandan-Giri A, Pennathur S, Baskin DG, Heinecke JW, Woods SC, Schwartz MW, Niswender KD. Hypothalamic proinflammatory lipid accumulation, inflammation, and insulin resistance in rats fed a high-fat diet. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2009;296:E1003&#x2013;1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2681305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapoport SI. In vivo labeling of brain phospholipids by long-chain fatty acids: relation to turnover and function. Lipids. 1996;31(Suppl):S97&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8729102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ropelle ER, Flores MB, Cintra DE, Rocha GZ, Pauli JR, Morari J, de Souza CT, Moraes JC, Prada PO, Guadagnini D, Marin RM, Oliveira AG, Augusto TM, Carvalho HF, Velloso LA, Saad MJ, Carvalheira JB. IL-6 and IL-10 anti-inflammatory activity links exercise to hypothalamic insulin and leptin sensitivity through IKK&#x3b2; and ER stress inhibition. PLoS Biol. 2010;8:pii: e1000465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2927536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20808781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Dagnone D, Jones PJ, Smith H, Paddags A, Hudson R, Janssen I. Reduction in obesity and related comorbid conditions after diet-induced weight loss or exercise-induced weight loss in men. A randomized, controlled trial. Ann Intern Med. 2000;133:92&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10896648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawai H, Domae N, Okazaki T. Current status and perspectives in ceramide-targeting molecular medicine. Curr Pharm Des. 2005;11:2479&#x2013;2487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16026301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schievella AR, Regier MK, Smith WL, Lin LL. Calcium-mediated translocation of cytosolic phospholipase A2 to the nuclear envelope and endoplasmic reticulum. J Biol Chem. 1995;270:30749&#x2013;30754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8530515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimabukuro M, Higa M, Zhou YT, Wang MY, Newgard CB, Unger RH. Lipoapoptosis in beta-cells of obese prediabetic fafa rats. Role of serine palmitoyltransferase overexpression. J Biol Chem. 1998;273:32487&#x2013;32490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9829981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simopoulos AP. Evolutionary aspects of diet, the omega-6/omega-3 ratio and genetic variation: nutritional implications for chronic diseases. Biomed Pharmacother. 2006;60:502&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17045449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turpin SM, Ryall JG, Southgate R, Darby I, Hevener AL, Febbraio MA, Kemp BE, Lynch GS, Watt MJ. Examination of &#x2018;lipotoxicity&#x2019; in skeletal muscle of high-fat fed and obob mice. J Physiol. 2009;587:1593&#x2013;1605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger RH. Minireview: weapons of lean body mass destruction: the role of ectopic lipids in the metabolic syndrome. Endocrinology. 2003;144:5159&#x2013;5165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12960011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt MJ, Hoy AJ, Muoio DM, Coleman RA. Distinct roles of specific fatty acids in cellular processes: implications for interpreting and reporting experiments. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;302:E1&#x2013;E3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3774556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22180647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt MJ, Steinberg GR. Regulation and function of triacylglycerol lipases in cellular metabolism. Biochem J. 2008;414:313&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18717647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellen KE, Hotamisligil GS. Inflammation, stress, and diabetes. J Clin Invest. 2005;115:1111&#x2013;1119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1087185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15864338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>