<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33842881</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2624-9367</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in sports and active living</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Sports Act Living</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increased Leg Strength After Concurrent Aerobic and Resistance Exercise Training in Older Adults Is Augmented by a Whole Food-Based High Protein Diet Intervention.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>653962</StartPage><MedlinePgn>653962</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">653962</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fspor.2021.653962</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Most studies in older adults have utilized powdered protein supplements or oral nutrition solutions as a source of additional dietary protein, but whole foods may provide a greater anabolic stimulus than protein isolated from food matrices. Therefore, the present study investigated a concurrent aerobic and resistance exercise training program in older adults, in the absence or presence of a high protein whole food-based dietary intervention, for effects on strength, physical function, and body composition. Community-dwelling older adults (<i>n</i> = 56; M/F, 28/28; age, 69.3 &#xb1; 4.0 years; BMI, 26.6 &#xb1; 3.7 kg m<sup>-2</sup>) participated in a 12-week intervention after randomization to either nutrition only (NUTR; <i>n</i> = 16), exercise only (EX, <i>n</i> = 19), or nutrition plus exercise (NUTR + EX, <i>n</i> = 21) groups. NUTR and NUTR + EX followed a dietary intervention targeting an increase in protein-rich meals at breakfast, lunch, and dinner. Exercise training in EX and NUTR + EX consisted of 24 min sessions of concurrent aerobic and resistance exercise performed three times per week. Daily protein intake increased in NUTR and NUTR + EX, but not EX. The increase in 1RM leg press strength was greater (Interaction effect, <i>P</i> = 0.012) in NUTR + EX [29.6 (18.1, 41.0) kg] than increases observed in NUTR [11.1 (-1.3, 23.6) kg] and EX [12.3 (0.9, 23.8) kg]. The increase in 1RM chest press strength was greater (interaction effect, <i>P</i> = 0.031) in NUTR + EX [6.3 (4.0, 8.6) kg] than the increase observed in NUTR [2.9 (0.3, 5.5) kg], but not EX [6.3 (3.9, 8.7) kg]. Hand-grip strength and sit-to-stand performance were each improved in all three groups, with no differences observed between groups (interaction effect, <i>P</i> = 0.382 and <i>P</i> = 0.671, respectively). An increase in percentage body fat was observed in NUTR, but not in EX or NUTR + EX (interaction effect, <i>P</i> = 0.018). No between-group differences were observed for change in lean body mass (interaction effect, <i>P</i> = 0.402). Concurrent aerobic and resistance exercise training improves strength and physical function in older adults, but combining this training with an increase in daily protein intake through whole foods may be advantageous to increase lower limb strength.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Timmons, Hone, Cogan, Duffy and Egan.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timmons</LastName><ForeName>James F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Sport and Health, School of Public Health, Physiotherapy and Sports Science, University College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hone</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Performance, Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cogan</LastName><ForeName>Karl E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Sport and Health, School of Public Health, Physiotherapy and Sports Science, University College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duffy</LastName><ForeName>Orlaith</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medfit Proactive Healthcare, Blackrock Co., Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egan</LastName><ForeName>Brendan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Performance, Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Cellular Biotechnology, Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Florida Institute for Human and Machine Cognition, Pensacola, FL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Sports Act Living</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101765780</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2624-9367</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combined training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lean body mass (LBM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical function</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>BE is formerly (previous 36 months) or presently funded under the Health, and Glycemic Management pillars, respectively, of the Enterprise Ireland-funded technology centres Meat Technology Ireland, and Food for Health Ireland, whose focus is on the potential benefits of meat and dairy ingredients for human health. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33842881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8034230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.653962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abou Sawan S., van Vliet S., Parel J. T., Beals J. W., Mazzulla M., West D. W. D., et al. (2018). Translocation and protein complex co-localization of mTOR is associated with postprandial myofibrillar protein synthesis at rest and after endurance exercise. Physiol. Rep. 6:13628. 10.14814/phy2.13628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.13628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer J., Morley J. E., Schols A., Ferrucci L., Cruz-Jentoft A. J., Dent E., et al. (2019). Sarcopenia: a time for action. An SCWD Position Paper. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 10, 956&#x2013;961. 10.1002/jcsm.12483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6818450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer J. M., Verlaan S., Bautmans I., Brandt K., Donini L. M., Maggio M., et al. (2015). Effects of a vitamin D and leucine-enriched whey protein nutritional supplement on measures of sarcopenia in older adults, the PROVIDE study: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J. Am. Med. Dir. Assoc. 16, 740&#x2013;747. 10.1016/j.jamda.2015.05.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2015.05.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26170041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnefoy M., Cornu C., Normand S., Boutitie F., Bugnard F., Rahmani A., et al. (2003). The effects of exercise and protein-energy supplements on body composition and muscle function in frail elderly individuals: a long-term controlled randomised study. Br. J. Nutr. 89, 731&#x2013;739. 10.1079/BJN2003836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/BJN2003836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12720593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borde R., Hortobagyi T., Granacher U. (2015). Dose-response relationships of resistance training in healthy old adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 45, 1693&#x2013;1720. 10.1007/s40279-015-0385-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0385-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd N. A., Beals J. W., Martinez I. G., Salvador A. F., Skinner S. K. (2019). Food-first approach to enhance the regulation of post-exercise skeletal muscle protein synthesis and remodeling. Sports Med. 49, 59&#x2013;68. 10.1007/s40279-018-1009-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-1009-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30671904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd N. A., Gorissen S. H., van Vliet S., Snijders T., van Loon L. J. (2015). Differences in postprandial protein handling after beef compared with milk ingestion during postexercise recovery: a randomized controlled trial. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 102, 828&#x2013;836. 10.3945/ajcn.114.103184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.114.103184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26354539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak N. M., Res P. T., de Groot L. C., Saris W. H., van Loon L. J. (2012). Protein supplementation augments the adaptive response of skeletal muscle to resistance-type exercise training: a meta-analysis. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 96, 1454&#x2013;1464. 10.3945/ajcn.112.037556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.112.037556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanet A., Verlaan S., Salles J., Giraudet C., Patrac V., Pidou V., et al. (2017). Supplementing breakfast with a vitamin D and leucine-enriched whey protein medical nutrition drink enhances postprandial muscle protein synthesis and muscle mass in healthy older men. J. Nutr. 147, 2262&#x2013;2271. 10.3945/jn.117.252510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.117.252510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28835387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang S. H., Beason T. S., Hunleth J. M., Colditz G. A. (2012). A systematic review of body fat distribution and mortality in older people. Maturitas 72, 175&#x2013;191. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2012.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2012.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3367099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22595204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chodzko-Zajko W. J., Proctor D. N., Fiatarone Singh M. A., Minson C. T., Nigg C. R., Salem G. J., et al. (2009). American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 41, 1510&#x2013;1530. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a0c95c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a0c95c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19516148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark B. C., Manini T. M. (2010). Functional consequences of sarcopenia and dynapenia in the elderly. Curr. Opin. Clin. Nutr. Metab. Care 13, 271&#x2013;276. 10.1097/MCO.0b013e328337819e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0b013e328337819e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20154609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper C., Fielding R., Visser M., van Loon L. J., Rolland Y., Orwoll E., et al. (2013). Tools in the assessment of sarcopenia. Calcif. Tissue Int. 93, 201&#x2013;210. 10.1007/s00223-013-9757-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00223-013-9757-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3744387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23842964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft A. J., Bahat G., Bauer J., Boirie Y., Bruyere O., Cederholm T., et al. (2019).Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing 48, 16&#x2013;31. 10.1093/ageing/afy169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afy169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly R. M., O'Connell S. L., Mundell N. L., Grimes C. A., Dunstan D. W., Nowson C. A. (2014). Protein-enriched diet, with the use of lean red meat, combined with progressive resistance training enhances lean tissue mass and muscle strength and reduces circulating IL-6 concentrations in elderly women: a cluster randomized controlled trial. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 99, 899&#x2013;910. 10.3945/ajcn.113.064154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.113.064154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson L. E., Hudson R., Kilpatrick K., Kuk J. L., McMillan K., Janiszewski P. M., et al. (2009). Effects of exercise modality on insulin resistance and functional limitation in older adults: a randomized controlled trial. Arch. Intern. Med. 169, 122&#x2013;131. 10.1001/archinternmed.2008.558</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2008.558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19171808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico M. J., Harris T. B., Visser M., Park S. W., Conroy M. B., Velasquez-Mieyer P., et al. (2009). Longitudinal study of muscle strength, quality, and adipose tissue infiltration. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 90, 1579&#x2013;1585. 10.3945/ajcn.2009.28047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2009.28047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico M. J., Kostek M. C., Johns J., Hurley B. F., Conway J. M. (2008). Can dual energy X-ray absorptiometry provide a valid assessment of changes in thigh muscle mass with strength training in older adults? Eur. J. Clin. Nutr. 62, 1372&#x2013;1378. 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutz N. E., Bauer J. M., Barazzoni R., Biolo G., Boirie Y., Bosy-Westphal A., et al. (2014). Protein intake and exercise for optimal muscle function with aging: recommendations from the ESPEN Expert Group. Clin. Nutr. 33, 929&#x2013;936. 10.1016/j.clnu.2014.04.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2014.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24814383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliot T. A., Cree M. G., Sanford A. P., Wolfe R. R., Tipton K. D. (2006). Milk ingestion stimulates net muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 38, 667&#x2013;674. 10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formica M. B., Gianoudis J., Nowson C. A., O'Connell S. L., Milte C., Ellis K. A., et al. (2020). Effect of lean red meat combined with a multicomponent exercise program on muscle and cognitive function in older adults: a 6-month randomized controlled trial. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 112, 113&#x2013;128. 10.1093/ajcn/nqaa104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/nqaa104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera W. R., Hughes V. A., Fielding R. A., Fiatarone M. A., Evans W. J., Roubenoff R. (1985). Aging of skeletal muscle: a 12-yr longitudinal study. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985). 88, 1321&#x2013;1326. 10.1152/jappl.2000.88.4.1321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.4.1321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10749826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furman E. F. (2006). Undernutrition in older adults across the continuum of care: nutritional assessment, barriers, and interventions. J. Gerontol. Nurs. 32, 22&#x2013;27. 10.3928/0098-9134-20060101-11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/0098-9134-20060101-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16475461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greig C. A., Young A., Skelton D. A., Pippet E., Butler F. M., Mahmud S. M. (1994). Exercise studies with elderly volunteers. Age Ageing 23, 185&#x2013;189. 10.1093/ageing/23.3.185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/23.3.185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8085501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guralnik J. M., Simonsick E. M., Ferrucci L., Glynn R. J., Berkman L. F., Blazer D. G., et al. (1994). A short physical performance battery assessing lower extremity function: association with self-reported disability and prediction of mortality and nursing home admission. J. Gerontol. 49, M85&#x2013;94. 10.1093/geronj/49.2.M85</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geronj/49.2.M85</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8126356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hone M., Nugent A. P., Walton J., McNulty B. A., Egan B. (2020). Habitual protein intake, protein distribution patterns and dietary sources in Irish adults with stratification by sex and age. J. Hum. Nutr. Diet. 33, 465&#x2013;476. 10.1111/jhn.12736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jhn.12736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31997529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes V. A., Frontera W. R., Wood M., Evans W. J., Dallal G. E., Roubenoff R., et al. (2001). Longitudinal muscle strength changes in older adults: influence of muscle mass, physical activity, and health. J. Gerontol. Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 56, B209&#x2013;B217. 10.1093/gerona/56.5.B209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/56.5.B209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11320101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung Y., Wijnhoven H. A. H., Visser M., Verbeke W. (2019). Appetite and protein intake strata of older adults in the European Union: socio-demographic and health characteristics, diet-related and physical activity behaviours. Nutrients 11:11040777. 10.3390/nu11040777</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11040777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6521269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30987278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karavirta L., Hakkinen K., Kauhanen A., Arija-Blazquez A., Sillanpaa E., Rinkinen N., et al. (2011). Individual responses to combined endurance and strength training in older adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 43, 484&#x2013;490. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181f1bf0d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181f1bf0d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20689460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karelis A. D., Messier V., Supp&#xe8;re C., Briand P., Rabasa-Lhoret R. (2015). Effect of cysteine-rich whey protein (immunocal&#xae;) supplementation in combination with resistance training on muscle strength and lean body mass in non-frail elderly subjects: a randomized, double-blind controlled study. J. Nutr. Health Aging 19, 531&#x2013;536. 10.1007/s12603-015-0442-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12603-015-0442-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25923482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C. O., Lee K. R. (2013). Preventive effect of protein-energy supplementation on the functional decline of frail older adults with low socioeconomic status: a community-based randomized controlled study. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 68, 309&#x2013;316. 10.1093/gerona/gls167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/gls167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labata-Lezaun N., Llurda-Almuzara L., L&#xf3;pez-de-Celis C., Rodr&#xed;guez-Sanz J., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Rueda V., Hidalgo-Garc&#xed;a C., et al. (2020). Effectiveness of protein supplementation combined with resistance training on muscle strength and physical performance in elderly: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 12:12092607. 10.3390/nu12092607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12092607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32867103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C. D., Tsauo J. Y., Wu Y. T., Cheng C. P., Chen H. C., Huang Y. C., et al. (2017). Effects of protein supplementation combined with resistance exercise on body composition and physical function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 106, 1078&#x2013;1091. 10.3945/ajcn.116.143594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.116.143594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch N. A., Metter E. J., Lindle R. S., Fozard J. L., Tobin J. D., Roy T. A., et al. (1985). Muscle quality. I. Age-associated differences between arm and leg muscle groups. J. Appl. Physiol.. 86, 188&#x2013;194. 10.1152/jappl.1999.86.1.188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1999.86.1.188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9887130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malafarina V., Uriz-Otano F., Gil-Guerrero L., Iniesta R. (2013). The anorexia of ageing: physiopathology, prevalence, associated comorbidity and mortality. A systematic review. Maturitas 74, 293&#x2013;302. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2013.01.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2013.01.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23415063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall R. N., Smeuninx B., Morgan P. T., Breen L. (2020). Nutritional strategies to offset disuse-induced skeletal muscle atrophy and anabolic resistance in older adults: from whole-foods to isolated ingredients. Nutrients 12:12051533. 10.3390/nu12051533</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12051533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32466126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCambridge J., Witton J., Elbourne D. R. (2014). Systematic review of the Hawthorne effect: new concepts are needed to study research participation effects. J. Clin. Epidemiol. 67, 267&#x2013;277. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.08.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3969247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24275499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean R. R., Mangano K. M., Hannan M. T., Kiel D. P., Sahni S. (2016). Dietary protein intake is protective against loss of grip strength among older adults in the framingham offspring cohort. J Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 71, 356&#x2013;361. 10.1093/gerona/glv184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glv184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5864162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26525088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meex R. C. R., Blaak E. E., van Loon L. J. C. (2019). Lipotoxicity plays a key role in the development of both insulin resistance and muscle atrophy in patients with type 2 diabetes. Obes. Rev. 20, 1205&#x2013;1217. 10.1111/obr.12862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6852205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31240819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley J. E. (2005). Decreased food intake with aging. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 56, 81&#x2013;88. 10.1093/gerona/56.suppl_2.81</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/56.suppl_2.81</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11730241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton C., Toomey C., McCormack W. G., Francis P., Saunders J., Kerin E., et al. (2016). Protein supplementation at breakfast and lunch for 24 weeks beyond habitual intakes increases whole-body lean tissue mass in healthy older adults. J. Nutr. 146, 65&#x2013;69. 10.3945/jn.115.219022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.115.219022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26581685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson M. D., Sen A., Gordon P. M. (2011). Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: a meta-analysis. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 43, 249&#x2013;258. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181eb6265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181eb6265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts H. C., Denison H. J., Martin H. J., Patel H. P., Syddall H., Cooper C., et al. (2011). A review of the measurement of grip strength in clinical and epidemiological studies: towards a standardised approach. Age Ageing 40, 423&#x2013;429. 10.1093/ageing/afr051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afr051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21624928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal R. J., Kenny G. P., Boule N. G., Wells G. A., Prud'homme D., Fortier M., et al. (2007). Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: a randomized trial. Ann. Intern. Med. 147, 357&#x2013;369. 10.7326/0003-4819-147-6-200709180-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-147-6-200709180-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamatakis E., Lee I. M., Bennie J., Freeston J., Hamer M., O'Donovan G., et al. (2018). Does strength-promoting exercise confer unique health benefits? a pooled analysis of data on 11 population cohorts with all-cause, cancer, and cardiovascular mortality endpoints. Am. J. Epidemiol. 187, 1102&#x2013;1112. 10.1093/aje/kwx345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwx345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29099919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavoian D., Ampomah K., Amano S., Law T. D., Clark B. C. (2019). Changes in DXA-derived lean mass and MRI-derived cross-sectional area of the thigh are modestly associated. Sci. Rep. 9:10028. 10.1038/s41598-019-46428-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-46428-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6624257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31296891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Haaf D. S. M., Nuijten M. A. H., Maessen M. F. H., Horstman A. M. H., Eijsvogels T. M. H., Hopman M. T. E. (2018). Effects of protein supplementation on lean body mass, muscle strength, and physical performance in nonfrail community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 108, 1043&#x2013;1059. 10.1093/ajcn/nqy192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/nqy192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30475963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tieland M., van de Rest O., Dirks M. L., Mensink M., van Loon L. J. C, de Groot L. C. P. G. M., et al. (2012). Protein supplementation improves physical performance in frail elderly people: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J. Am. Med. Dir. Assoc. 13, 720&#x2013;726. 10.1016/j.jamda.2012.07.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2012.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22889730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmons J. F., Minnock D., Hone M., Cogan K. E., Murphy J. C., Egan B. (2018). Comparison of time-matched aerobic, resistance or concurrent exercise training in older adults. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 28, 2272&#x2013;2283. 10.1111/sms.13254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29947107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor D. A., Gorissen S. H. M., Phillips S. M. (2019). Perspective: protein requirements and optimal intakes in aging: are we ready to recommend more than the recommended daily allowance? Adv. Nutr. 9, 171&#x2013;182. 10.1093/advances/nmy003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/advances/nmy003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5952928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29635313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vliet S., Shy E. L., Abou Sawan S., Beals J. W., West D. W., Skinner S. K., et al. (2017). Consumption of whole eggs promotes greater stimulation of postexercise muscle protein synthesis than consumption of isonitrogenous amounts of egg whites in young men. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 106, 1401&#x2013;1412. 10.3945/ajcn.117.159855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.117.159855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28978542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M., Deeg D. J., Lips P., Harris T. B., Bouter L. M. (2000). Skeletal muscle mass and muscle strength in relation to lower-extremity performance in older men and women. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 48, 381&#x2013;386. 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2000.tb04694.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2000.tb04694.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10798463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe R. R. (2006). The underappreciated role of muscle in health and disease. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 84, 475&#x2013;482. 10.1093/ajcn/84.3.475</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/84.3.475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood R. H., Reyes R., Welsch M. A., Favaloro-Sabatier J., Sabatier M., Matthew Lee C., et al. (2001). Concurrent cardiovascular and resistance training in healthy older adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 33, 1751&#x2013;1758. 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>