<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">28674320</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2018</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1880-3873</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of atherosclerosis and thrombosis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Atheroscler Thromb</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of 24-Week Aerobic and Resistance Training on Carotid Artery Intima-Media Thickness and Flow Velocity in Elderly Women with Sarcopenic Obesity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1117</StartPage><EndPage>1124</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1117-1124</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5551/jat.39065</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Sarcopenic obesity (SO) is closely associated with cardiovascular disease (CVD) in elderly women. Increases in body fat and decreases in muscle mass are closely associated with increased carotid intima-media thickness (CIMT). The aim of this study was to examine the influence of a 24-week aerobic and resistance training program on carotid parameters in SO.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Fifty elderly women (74.1&#xb1;6.1 years) with SO were randomly divided into an exercise group and a control group. The exercise group performed combined exercise over 24 weeks, consisting of resistance and aerobic training for 50-80 min, 5 times a week. Carotid variables were measured using B-mode ultrasound. The differences in the carotid variables and the relative changes between baseline and after 24 weeks were evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In the analysis of variance (ANOVA) results, CIMT (p=0.013), systolic flow velocity (p=0.007), diastolic flow velocity (p=0.006), and wall shear rate (p=0.010) showed significant interactions. In paired t-test results of the exercise group, CIMT significantly decreased (p&#xff1c;0.01) and systolic flow velocity (p&#xff1c;0.01), diastolic flow velocity (p&#xff1c;0.001), and wall shear rate (p&#xff1c;0.05) significantly increased after 24 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The 24-week combined exercise effectively decreased CIMT and increased carotid flow velocity and wall shear ratio. Therefore, combined exercise is thought to contribute to the improvement of the risk of CVD in elderly women with SO.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Jinkee</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Rehabilitation, Dong Ju College, Busan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Yoochan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Taekwondo for Health and Culture, Dong-A University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Taekwondo, Dong-A University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Hyuntea</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Care &amp; Science, Dong-A University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Convergence Bio-Health, Dong-A University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>J Atheroscler Thromb</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9506298</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1340-3478</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001783" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Flow Velocity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059168" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carotid Intima-Media Thickness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carotid flow velocity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carotid intima-media thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combined exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenic obesity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5551/jat.39065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chung JY, Kang HT, Lee DC, Lee HR, Lee YJ: Body composition and its association with cardiometabolic risk factors in the elderly: A focus on sarcopenic obesity. Arch Gerontol Geriat, 2013; 56: 270-278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23079031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim S, Kim JH, Yoon JW, Kang SM, Choi SH, Park YJ, Kim KW, Lim JY, Park KS, Jang HC: Sarcopenic obesity: Prevalence and association with metabolic syndrome in the korean longitudinal study on health and aging (klosha). Diabetes Care, 2010; 33: 1652-1654</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2890376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20460442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SH, Park JH, Song PS, Kim DK, Kim KH, Seol SH, Kim HK, Jang HJ, Lee JG, Park HY, Park J, Shin KJ, Kim DI, Moon YS: Sarcopenic obesity as an independent risk factor of hypertension. J Am Soc Hypertens, 2013; 7: 420-425</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23910010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batsis JA, Mackenzie TA, Barre LK, Lopez-Jimenez F, Bartels SJ: Sarcopenia, sarcopenic obesity and mortality in older adults: Results from the national health and nutrition examination survey iii. Eur J Clin Nutr, 2014; 68: 1001-1007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24961545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polak JF, Pencina MJ, Pencina KM, O'Donnell CJ, Wolf PA, D'Agostino RB: Carotid-wall intima-media thickness and cardiovascular events. New Engl J Med, 2011; 365: 213-221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3153949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21774709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellinazzi VR, Cipolli JA, Pimenta MV, Guimaraes PV, Pio-Magalhaes JA, Coelho OR, Biering-Sorensen T, Matos-Souza JR, Sposito AC, Nadruz W: Carotid flow velocity/diameter ratio is a predictor of cardiovascular events in hypertensive patients. J Hypertens, 2015; 33: 2054-2060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26237558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang SY, Bai CH, Chen JR, Yeh WT, Chen HJ, Chiu HC, Shiu RS, Pan WH: Common carotid end-diastolic velocity and intima-media thickness jointly predict ischemic stroke in taiwan. Stroke, 2011; 42: 1338-1344</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato A, Ishida J, Endo Y, Takita T, Furuhashi M, Maruyama Y, Odamaki M: Association of abdominal visceral adiposity and thigh sarcopenia with changes of arteriosclerosis in haemodialysis patients. Nephrol Dial Transpl, 2011; 26: 1967-1976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20980356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang SY, Bai CH, Cheng HM, Chen JR, Yeh WT, Hsu PF, Liu WL, Pan WH: Common carotid artery end-diastolic velocity is independently associated with future cardiovascular events. Eur J Prev Cardiol, 2016; 23: 116-124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25691545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neto LSS, Karnikowiski MGO, Tavares AB, Lima RM: Association between sarcopenia, sarcopenic obesity, muscle strength and quality of life variables in elderly women. Braz J Phys Ther, 2012; 16: 360-367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22983215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard DR, Dionne IJ, Brochu M: Sarcopenic/obesity and physical capacity in older men and women: Data from the nutrition as a determinant of successful aging (nuage)-the quebec longitudinal study. Obesity, 2009; 17: 2082-2088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19373219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villareal DT, Holloszy JO: Dhea enhances effects of weight training on muscle mass and strength in elderly women and men. Am J Physiol-Endoc M, 2006; 291: E1003-E1008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16787962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent HK, Bourguignon C, Vincent KR: Resistance training lowers exercise-induced oxidative stress and homocysteine levels in overweight and obese older adults. Obesity, 2006; 14: 1921-1930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17135607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okura T, Nakata Y, Ohkawara K, Numao S, Katayama Y, Matsuo T, Tanaka K: Effects of aerobic exercise on metabolic syndrome improvement in response to weight reduction. Obesity, 2007; 15: 2478-2484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17925474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan SJ, Li W, Wang JX: Effects of six months of combined aerobic and resistance training for elderly patients with a long history of type 2 diabetes. J Sport Sci Med, 2012; 11: 495-501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balducci S, Zanuso S, Cardelli P, Salvi L, Bazuro A, Pugliese L, Maccora C, Iacobini C, Conti FG, Nicolucci A, Pugliese G, Investigators I: Effect of high- versus low-intensity supervised aerobic and resistance training on modifiable cardiovascular risk factors in type 2 diabetes; the italian diabetes and exercise study (ides). Plos One, 2012; 7: 1-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3504024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23185314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyachi M, Kawano H, Sugawara J, Takahashi K, Hayashi K, Yamazaki K, Tabata I, Tanaka H: Unfavorable effects of resistance training on central arterial compliance - a randomized intervention study. Circulation, 2004; 110: 2858-2863</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15492301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawano H, Tanaka H, Miyachi M: Resistance training and arterial compliance: Keeping the benefits while minimizing the stiffening. J Hypertens, 2006; 24: 1753-1759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16915024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K: Effects of eccentric and concentric resistance training on arterial stiffness. J Hum Hypertens, 2006; 20: 348-354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16496019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colberg SR, Albright AL, Blissmer BJ, Braun B, Chasan-Taber L, Fernhall B, Regensteiner JG, Rubin RR, Sigal RJ, Med ACS, Assoc AD: Exercise and type 2 diabetes. Med Sci Sport Exer, 2010; 42: 2282-2303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21084931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heran BS, Chen JMH, Ebrahim S, Moxham T, Oldridge N, Rees K, Thompson DR, Taylor RS: Exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation for coronary heart disease. Cochrane Db Syst Rev, 2011; Ver. 2: 1-93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21735386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler G, Adams V, Goto Y: Role of exercise in the prevention of cardiovascular disease: Results, mechanisms, and new perspectives. Eur Heart J, 2013; 34: 1790-1799</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23569199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bean JF, Vora A, Frontera WR: Benefits of exercise for community-dwelling older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehab, 2004; 85: S31-S42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir H, Artas H, Serhatlioglu S, Ogur E: Effects of overweight on luminal diameter, flow velocity and intimamedia thickness of carotid arteries. Diagn Interv Radiol, 2006; 12: 142-146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16972220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang YN, Kohara K, Hiwada K: Association between risk factors for atherosclerosis and mechanical forces in carotid artery. Stroke, 2000; 31: 2319-2324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11022057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feairheller DL, Diaz KM, Kashem MA, Thakkar SR, Veerabhadrappa P, Sturgeon KM, Ling CY, Williamson ST, Kretzschmar J, Lee H, Grimm H, Babbitt DM, Vin C, Fan XX, Crabbe DL, Brown MD: Effects of moderate aerobic exercise training on vascular health and blood pressure in african americans. J Clin Hypertens, 2014; 16: 504-510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24779748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholten RR, Thijssen DJH, Lotgering FK, Hopman MTE, Spaanderman MEA: Cardiovascular effects of aerobic exercise training in formerly preeclamptic women and healthy parous control subjects. Am J Obstet Gynecol, 2014; 211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24769012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Swart A, Exterkate A, Naylor LH, Black MA, Cable NT, Thijssen DHJ: Impact of age, sex and exercise on brachial and popliteal artery remodelling in humans. Atherosclerosis, 2010; 210: 525-530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20197189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrkjeland R, Stensaeth KH, Anderssen S, Njerve IU, Arnesen H, Seljeflot I, Solheim S: Effects of exercise training on carotid intima-media thickness in patients with type 2 diabetes and coronary artery disease. Influence of carotid plaques. Cardiovasc Diabetol, 2016; 15:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4724125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26801098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho YG, Song HJ, Kim JM, Park KH, Paek YJ, Cho JJ, Caterson I, Kang JG: The estimation of cardiovascular risk factors by body mass index and body fat percentage in korean male adults. Metabolism, 2009; 58: 765-771</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I: Influence of sarcopenia on the development of physical disability: The cardiovascular health study. J Am Geriatr Soc, 2006; 54: 56-62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16420198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thijssen DHJ, Cable NT, Green DJ: Impact of exercise training on arterial wall thickness in humans. Clin Sci, 2012; 122: 311-322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3233305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22150253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou NP, Iliadis F, Liapis CD: Exercise and carotid atherosclerosis. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg, 2008; 35: 264-272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17988901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eigenbrodt ML, Sukhija R, Rose KM, Tracy RE, Couper DJ, Evans GW, Bursac Z, Mehta JL: Common carotid artery wall thickness and external diameter as predictors of prevalent and incident cardiac events in a large population study. Cardiovasc Ultrasound, 2007; 5: 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1831763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17349039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai CH, Chen JR, Chiu HC, Pan WH: Lower blood flow velocity, higher resistance index, and larger diameter of extracranial carotid arteries are associated with ischemic stroke independently of carotid atherosclerosis and cardiovascular risk factors. J Clin Ultrasound, 2007; 35: 322-330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17471583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gando Y, Yamamoto K, Kawano H, Murakami H, Ohmori Y, Kawakami R, Sanada K, Higuchi M, Tabata I, Miyachi M: Attenuated age-related carotid arterial remodeling in adults with a high level of cardiorespiratory fitness. J Atheroscler Thromb, 2011; 18: 248-254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21123955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czernichow S, Bertrais S, Oppert JM, Galan P, Blacher J, Ducimetiere P, Hercberg S, Zureik M: Body composition and fat repartition in relation to structure and function of large arteries in middle-aged adults (the su.Vi.Max study). Int J Obesity, 2005; 29: 826-832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15917850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik J, Kudlicka J, Tuka V, Chytilova E, Adamec J, Rocinova K, Tesar V: Common carotid wall shear stress and carotid atherosclerosis in end-stage renal disease patients. Physiol Res, 2012; 61: 355-361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22670700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogoh S, Brothers RM, Barnes Q, Eubank WL, Hawkins MN, Purkayastha S, O-Yurvati A, Raven PB: The effect of changes in cardiac output on middle cerebral artery mean blood velocity at rest and during exercise. J Physiol-London, 2005; 569: 697-704</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16210355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey A, Parashar A, Kumbhani DJ, Agarwal S, Garg J, Kitzman D, Levine BD, Drazner M, Berry JD: Exercise training in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Circ-Heart Fail, 2015; 8: 33-U73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25399909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto N, Prasad A, Hastings JL, Arbab-Zadeh A, Bhella PS, Shibata S, Palmer D, Levine BD: Cardiovascular effects of 1 year of progressive and vigorous exercise training in previously sedentary individuals older than 65 years of age. Circulation, 2010; 122: 1797-1805</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3730488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves AJ, Ribeiro F, Goldhammer E, Rivlin Y, Rosenschein U, Viana JL, Duarte JA, Sagiv M, Oliveira J: Exercise training improves diastolic function in heart failure patients. Med Sci Sport Exer, 2012; 44: 776-785</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22005747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Triplett NT: Effects of a short-term resistance program using elastic bands versus weight machines for sedentary middle-aged women. J Strength Cond Res, 2008; 22: 1441-1448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyle UG, Genton L, Hans D, Pichard C: Validation of a bioelectrical impedance analysis equation to predict appendicular skeletal muscle mass (asmm). Clin Nutr, 2003; 22: 537-543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14613755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CMM, Wells JCK, Smith SR, Stephan BCM, Siervo M: Sarcopenic obesity: A critical appraisal of the current evidence. Clin Nutr, 2012; 31: 583-601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22809635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>