<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">29385007</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Alcohol After Resistance Exercise Does Not Affect Muscle Power Recovery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1938</StartPage><EndPage>1944</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1938-1944</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002455</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Levitt, DE, Idemudia, NO, Cregar, CM, Duplanty, AA, Hill, DW, and Vingren, JL. Alcohol after resistance exercise does not affect muscle power recovery. J Strength Cond Res 34(7): 1938-1944, 2020-The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of alcohol consumed after heavy eccentric resistance exercise on measures of muscle power. After familiarization and an initial eccentric exercise bout to control for the "repeated-bout effect," 10 recreationally resistance-trained men completed 2 identical heavy eccentric squat bouts (4 sets of 10 repetitions at 110% of concentric 1-repetition maximum) 1 week apart. Each exercise bout was followed by ingestion of a beverage containing either alcohol (1.09 g ethanol&#xb7;kg fat-free body mass) or no alcohol (placebo; volume of alcohol replaced with water). Vertical jump (VJ) peak power, VJ peak force, VJ jump height, change-of-direction ability (shuttle run), sprint acceleration (sprint test), and muscle soreness were measured before (PRE), 24 hours after (24H), and 48 hours after (48H) each eccentric exercise bout. Although the exercise bout resulted in significantly (p &#x2264; 0.05) decreased VJ peak power at 24H, significantly decreased VJ jump height at 24H, and significantly increased muscle soreness at 24H and 48H, consuming alcohol after the exercise bout did not affect any of the performance outcome measures. When consumed after a non-novel heavy eccentric resistance exercise bout, alcohol did not affect soreness or recovery of muscular power. Practitioners can use this information to advise their athletes with regard to responsible alcohol use after non-novel exercise. Although short-term anaerobic performance does not seem compromised as a result of acute postexercise alcohol ingestion, practitioners and athletes should be aware of potential long-term effects of such alcohol use.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levitt</LastName><ForeName>Danielle E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotion, and Recreation, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Idemudia</LastName><ForeName>Nosakhare O</ForeName><Initials>NO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotion, and Recreation, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cregar</LastName><ForeName>Carianne M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotion, and Recreation, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duplanty</LastName><ForeName>Anthony A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Texas Woman's University, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>David W</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotion, and Recreation, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vingren</LastName><ForeName>Jakob L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotion, and Recreation, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000428" MajorTopicYN="N">Alcohol Drinking</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="Y">instrumentation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29385007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202007000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arnold L, Henry A, Poron F, Baba-Amer Y, van Rooijen N, Plonquet A, Gherardi RK, Chazaud B. Inflammatory monocytes recruited after skeletal muscle injury switch into antiinflammatory macrophages to support myogenesis. J Exp Med 204: 1057&#x2013;1069, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes MJ, M&#xfc;ndel T, Stannard SR. Acute alcohol consumption aggravates the decline in muscle performance following strenuous eccentric exercise. J Sci Med Sport 13: 189&#x2013;193, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes MJ, M&#xfc;ndel T, Stannard SR. Post-exercise alcohol ingestion exacerbates eccentric-exercise induced losses in performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 1009&#x2013;1014, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes MJ, M&#xfc;ndel T, Stannard SR. A low dose of alcohol does not impact skeletal muscle performance after exercise-induced muscle damage. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 725&#x2013;729, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry AE, Piazza-Gardner AK. Drunkorexia: Understanding the co-occurrence of alcohol consumption and eating/exercise weight management behaviors. J Am Coll Health 60: 236&#x2013;243, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne C, Eston R. The effect of exercise-induced muscle damage on isometric and dynamic knee extensor strength and vertical jump performance. J Sports Sci 20: 417&#x2013;425, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Alcohol Use and Your Health, 2016. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/alcohol/fact-sheets/alcohol-use.htm. Accessed October 5, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The analysis of variance. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum, 1988. pp. 273&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Fry CS, Glynn EL, Dreyer HC, Dhanani S, Timmerman KL, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Rapamycin administration in humans blocks the contraction-induced increase in skeletal muscle protein synthesis. J Physiol 587: 1535&#x2013;1546, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn MS, Wang MQ. Effects of physical activity on substance use among college students. Am J Health Stud 18: 126&#x2013;132, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duplanty AA, Budnar RG, Luk HY, Levitt DE, Hill DW, McFarlin BK, Huggett DB, Vingren JL. Effect of acute alcohol ingestion on resistance exercise-induced mTORC1 signaling in human muscle. J Strength Cond Res 31: 54&#x2013;61, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugvad A, Haugvad L, Hamarsland H, Paulsen G. Ethanol does not delay muscle recovery but decreases testosterone/cortisol ratio. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 2175&#x2013;2183, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Highton JM, Twist C, Eston RG. The effects of exercise-induced muscle damage on agility and sprint running performance. J Exerc Sci Fit 7: 24&#x2013;30, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Hoad M, Goodall S, Tallent J, Bell PG, French DN. Exercise-induced muscle damage is reduced in resistance-trained males by branched chain amino acids: A randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 9: 20, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;rvinen TAH, J&#xe4;rvinen TLN, K&#xe4;&#xe4;ri&#xe4;inen M, Kalimo H, J&#xe4;rvinen M. Muscle injuries: Biology and treatment. Am J Sports Med 33: 745&#x2013;764, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Newton RU, Nindl BC, Volek JS, McCormick M, Gotshalk LA, Gordon SE, Fleck SJ, Campbell WW, Putukian M, Evans WJ. Effects of heavy-resistance training on hormonal response patterns in younger vs. older men. J Appl Physiol 87: 982&#x2013;992, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaStayo PC, Woolf JM, Lewek MD, Snyder-Mackler L, Reich T, Lindstedt SL. Eccentric muscle contractions: Their contribution to injury, prevention, rehabilitation, and sport. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 33: 557&#x2013;571, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levitt DE, Duplanty AA, Budnar RG, Luk H-Y, Fernandez A, Layman TJ, Fancher DL, Hill DW, McFarlin BK, Vingren JL. The effect of post-resistance exercise alcohol ingestion on lipopolysaccharide-stimulated cytokines. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 311&#x2013;318, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levitt DE, Luk H-Y, Duplanty AA, McFarlin BK, Hill DW, Vingren JL. Effect of alcohol after muscle-damaging resistance exercise on muscular performance recovery and inflammatory capacity in women. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 1195&#x2013;1206, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan M. Administration, scoring, and interpretation of selected tests. In: Haff GG and Triplett NT, eds. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. (4th ed.). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2016. pp. 259&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeay Y, Stannard SR, Mundel T, Foskett A, Barnes M. Effect of alcohol consumption on recovery from eccentric exercise induced muscle damage in females. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 27: 115&#x2013;121, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore MJ, Werch C. Relationship between vigorous exercise frequency and substance use among first-year drinking college students. J Am Coll Health 56: 686&#x2013;690, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newham DJ, Jones DA, Clarkson PM. Repeated high-force eccentric exercise: Effects on muscle pain and damage. J Appl Physiol 63: 1381&#x2013;1386, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Sakamoto K, Newton M, Sacco P. How long does the protective effect on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage last? Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 1490&#x2013;1495, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice C, Stannard SR, Barnes MJ. The effects of binge drinking behaviour on recovery and performance after a rugby match. J Sci Med Sport 17: 244&#x2013;248, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice C, Stannard SR, Barnes MJ. Effects of heavy episodic drinking on physical performance in club level rugby union players. J Sci Med Sport 18: 268&#x2013;271, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenborn CA, Adams PF, Peregoy JA. Health behaviors of adults: United States, 2008-2010. Vital Health Stat 10 257: 1&#x2013;184, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon L, Jolley SE, Molina PE. Alcoholic myopathy: Pathophysiologic mechanisms and clinical implications. Alcohol Res Curr Rev 38: 207&#x2013;217, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiner JL, Lang CH. Dysregulation of skeletal muscle protein metabolism by alcohol. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 308: E699&#x2013;E712, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twist C, Eston R. The effects of exercise-induced muscle damage on maximal intensity intermittent exercise performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 94: 652&#x2013;658, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingren JL, Hill DW, Buddhadev H, Duplanty A. Postresistance exercise ethanol ingestion and acute testosterone bioavailability. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 1825&#x2013;1832, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Proud CG. The mTOR pathway in the control of protein synthesis. Physiol 21: 362&#x2013;369, 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>