<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25566461</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2233-6834</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise nutrition &amp; biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Nutrition Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of vitamin D supplementation and circuit training on indices of obesity and insulin resistance in T2D and vitamin D deficient elderly women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>249</StartPage><EndPage>257</EndPage><MedlinePgn>249-57</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5717/jenb.2014.18.3.249</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of vitamin D supplementation and circuit training on body composition, abdominal fat, blood lipids, and insulin resistance in T2D and vitamin D deficient elderly women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Fifty-two elderly women were randomly assigned to either the vitamin D supplementation with circuit training group (D+T: n = 15), the circuit training group (T: n = 13), the vitamin D supplementation group (D: n = 11), or the control group (CON: n = 13). The subjects in D took vitamin D supplements at 1,200 IU per day for 12 weeks; the subjects in T exercised 3 to 4 times per week, 25 to 40 minutes per session for 12 weeks; and the subjects in D+T participated in both treatments. Subjects in CON were asked to maintain normal daily life pattern for the duration of the study. Body composition, abdominal fat, blood lipids, and surrogate indices for insulin resistance were measured at pre- and post-test and the data were compared among the four groups and between two tests by utilizing two-way ANOVA with repeated measures. The main results of the present study were as follows:</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">1) Body weight, fat mass, percent body fat, and BMI decreased significantly in T, whereas there were no significant changes in the variables in D and CON. Lean body mass showed no significant changes in all groups. 2) TFA and SFA decreased significantly in T, whereas there were no significant changes in the variables in D and CON. The other abdominal fat related variables showed no significant changes in all groups. 3) TC, TG, HDL-C, and LDL-C showed improvements in T, whereas there were no significant changes in the variables in D and CON. 4) Fasting glucose, fasting insulin, and HOMA-IR tended to be lower in D+T.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It was concluded that the 12 weeks of vitamin D supplementation and circuit training would have positive effects on abdominal fat and blood lipid profiles in T2D and vitamin D deficient elderly women. Vitamin D supplementation was especially effective when it was complemented with exercise training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyoung-Jun</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Physical Education, Kyung Hee University, Gyeonggi-do, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Chang-Kyun</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Physical Education, Kyung Hee University, Gyeonggi-do, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Hyon</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Physical Education, Kyung Hee University, Gyeonggi-do, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Man-Gyoon</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Physical Education, Kyung Hee University, Gyeonggi-do, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Nutrition Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101572566</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2233-6834</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal fat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Circuit training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamin D</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25566461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5717/jenb.2014.18.3.249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jenb-18-3-249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran A, Snehalatha C, Ma RC. Diabetes in South-East Asia: An update for 2013 for the IDF Diabetes Atlas. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice. 2014;103(2):231&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24300015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittas AG, Lau J, Hu FB, Dawson-Hughes B. The role of vitamin D and calcium in type 2 diabetes. A systematic review and meta-analysis. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2007;92(6):2017&#x2013;2029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2085234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scragg R, Sowers M, Bell C. Third national health and nutrition examination survey: Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D, diabetes, and ethnicity in the third national health and nutrition examination survey. Diabetes Care. 2004;27(12):2813&#x2013;2818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15562190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delvin EE. Importance of vitamin D in insulin resistance. Bulletin de l'Acad&#xe9;mie Nationale de M&#xe9;decine. 2010;195(4-5):1091&#x2013;1102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22375372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Boul&#xe9; NG, Wells GA, Prud&#x2019;homme D, Fortier M, Reid RD, Tulloch H, Coyle D, Phillips P, Jennings A, Jaffey J. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: a randomized trial. Annals of Internal Medicine. 2007;147(6):357&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Standards of medical care in diabetes-2013. Diabetes Care. 2013;36(1):11&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotnikoff RC, Taylor LM, Wilson PM, Courneya KS, Sigal RJ, Birkett N, Raine K, Svenson LW. Factors associated with physical activity in Canadian adults with diabetes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2006;38(8):1526&#x2013;1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16888470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eves ND, Plotnikoff RC. Resistance training and type 2 diabetes: Considerations for implementation at the population level. Diabetes Care. 2006;29(8):1933&#x2013;1941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews DR, Hosker JP, Rudenski AS, Naylor BA, Treacher DF, Turner RC. Homeostasis model assessment: insulin resistance and &#x3b2;-cell function from fasting plasma glucose and insulin concentrations in man. Diabetologia. 1985;28(7):412&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3899825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Korean Nutrition Society . Dietary reference intakes for Koreans. First revision. Seoul: Hanareum planning; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen CR, Kreider C, Kerksick B, Campbell B, Slonaker M, Greenwood J, Baer E, Pfau M, Grimstvedt C, Wilborn A, Thomas L, Autrey T, Magrans B, Marcello C, Mulligan D, Rohle L, Taylor A, Vacanti S, Ounpraseuth P, Casey R. Effects of the Curves? Fitness and Weight Loss Program on Markers of Health. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2004;36(5):106&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton B. Vitamin D and human skeletal muscle. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports. 2010;20(2):182&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2860762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19807897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato Y, Iwamoto J, Kanoko T, Satoh K. Low-dose vitamin D prevents muscular atrophy and reduces falls and hip fractures in women after stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Cerebrovascular Diseases. 2005;20(3):187&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16088114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunout D, Barrera G, Leiva L, Gattas V, de la Maza MP, Avenda&#xf1;o M, Hirsch S. Effects of vitamin D supplementation and exercise training on physical performance in Chilean vitamin D deficient elderly subjects. Experimental Gerontology. 2006;41(8):746&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16797903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madden KM. Evidence for the benefit of exercise therapy in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes, Metabolic Syndrome and Obesity. 2013;3(6):233&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23847428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou NP, Iliadis F, Angelopoulou N, Perrea D, Ampatzidis G, Liapis CD, Alevizos M. The antiinflammatory effects of exercise training in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. European Journal of Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation. 2007;14(6):837&#x2013;843. (2007)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18043308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Despr&#xe9;s JP, Lemieux I. Abdominal obesity and metabolic syndrome. Nature. 2006;444(7121):881&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caron-Jobin M, Morisset AS, Tremblay A, Huot C, L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; D, Tchernof A. Elevated serum 25(OH)D concentrations, vitamin D, and calcium intakes are associated with reduced adipocyte size in women. Obesity(Silver Spring) 2011;19(7):1335&#x2013;1341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wamberg L, Kampmann U, St&#xf8;dkilde-J&#xf8;rgensen H, Rejnmark L, Pedersen SB, Richelsen B. Effects of vitamin D supplementation on body fat accumulation, inflammation, and metabolic risk factors in obese adults with low vitamin D levels - results from a randomized trial. European Journal of Internal Medicine. 2013;24(7):644&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23566943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi E, Negri C, Targher G, Faccioli N, Lanza M, Zoppini G, Zanolin E, Schena F, Bonora E, Moghetti P. Both resistance training and aerobic training reduce hepatic fat content in type 2 diabetic subjects with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (the RAED2 randomized trial) Hepatology. 2013;58(4):1287&#x2013;1295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23504926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zittermann A, Frisch S, Berthold HK, Gotting C, Kuhn J, Kleesiek K. Vitamin D supplementation enhances the beneficial effects of weight loss on cardiovascular disease risk markers. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2009;89(5):1321&#x2013;1327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19321573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naharci I, Bozoglu E, Kocak N, Doganci S, Doruk H, Serdar M. Effect of vitamin D on insulin sensitivity in elderly patients with impaired fasting glucose. Geriatrics and Gerontology International. 2012;12(3):454&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22212745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heikkinen AM, Tuppurainen MT, Niskanen L, Komulainen M, Penttil&#xe4; I, Saarikoski S. Long-term vitamin D3 supplementation may have adverse effects on serum lipids during postmenopausal hormone replacement therapy. European Journal of Endocrinology. 1997;137(5):495&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9405029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major GC, Alarie F, Dor&#xe9; J, Phouttama S, Tremblay A. Supplementation with calcium + vitamin D enhances the beneficial effect of weight loss on plasma lipid and lipoprotein concentrations. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2007;85(1):54&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17209177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung K, Bae S. Effects of a regular walking exercise program on behavioral and biochemical aspects in elderly people with type II diabetes. Nursing and Health Sciences. 2012;14(4):438&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22676205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene NP, Martin SE, Crouse SF. Acute exercise and training alter blood lipid and lipoprotein profiles differently in overweight and obese men and women. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2012;20(8):1618&#x2013;1627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen JL, McGuire DK. Impaired glucose tolerance and impaired fasting glucose-a review of diagnosis, clinical implication and management. Diabetes Disorder Research. 2005;2(1):9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16305067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypp&#xf6;nen E, Power C. Vitamin D status and glucose homeostasis in the 1958 British birth cohort: the role of obesity. Diabetes Care. 2006;29(10):2244&#x2013;2246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17003300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talaei A, Mohamadi M, Adgi Z. The effect of vitamin D on insulin resistance in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetology and Metabolic Syndrome. 2013;5(1):8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3586569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23443033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukala WR, Page R, Lonsdale C, Lys I, Rowlands D, Krebs J, Leikis M, Cheema BS. Exercise improves quality of life in indigenous Polynesian peoples with type 2 diabetes and visceral obesity. Journal of Physical Activity and Health. 2013;10(5):699&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23307554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umpierre D, Ribeiro PA, Kramer CK, Leit&#xe3;o CB, Zucatti AT, Azevedo MJ, Gross JL, Ribeiro JP, Schaan BD. Physical activity advice only or structured exercise training and association with HbA1c levels in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of the American Medical Association. 2011;305(17):1790&#x2013;1799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>