<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20196854</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-7075</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance training in overweight women on a ketogenic diet conserved lean body mass while reducing body fat.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1743-7075-7-17</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The aim of the present study was to compare the effects of 10 weeks resistance training in combination with either a regular diet (Ex) or a low carbohydrate, ketogenic diet (Lc+Ex) in overweight women on body weight and body composition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">18 untrained women between 20 and 40 years with BMI &gt;/= 25 kg*m-2 were randomly assigned into the Ex or Lc+Ex group. Both groups performed 60-100 min of varied resistance exercise twice weekly. Dietary estimates were based on two 4-day weighed records. Body composition was estimated using Dual Energy X-ray Absorptiometry. Fasting blood samples were analyzed for total-, HDL- and LDL-cholesterol, triacylglycerols, and glucose.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">16 subjects were included in the analyses. Percentage of energy (En%) from carbohydrates, fat and protein was 6, 66, and 22 respectively in the (Lc+Ex) group and 41, 34, 17 in the Ex group. Mean weight change (pre-post) was -5.6 +/- 2.6 kg in Lc+Ex; (p &lt; 0.001) and 0.8 +/- 1.5 kg in Ex; (p = 0.175). The Lc+Ex group lost 5.6 +/- 2.9 kg of fat mass (p = 0.001) with no significant change in lean body mass (LBM), while the Ex group gained 1.6 +/- 1.8 kg of LBM (p = 0.045) with no significant change in fat mass (p = 0.059). Fasting blood lipids and blood glucose were not significantly affected by the interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Resistance exercise in combination with a ketogenic diet may reduce body fat without significantly changing LBM, while resistance exercise on a regular diet may increase LBM in without significantly affecting fat mass. Fasting blood lipids do not seem to be negatively influenced by the combination of resistance exercise and a low carbohydrate diet.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jabekk</LastName><ForeName>Pal T</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Medicine, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Sognsveien 220, Oslo, Norway. jabekk@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moe</LastName><ForeName>Ingvild A</ForeName><Initials>IA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meen</LastName><ForeName>Helge D</ForeName><Initials>HD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomten</LastName><ForeName>Sissel E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xf8;stmark</LastName><ForeName>Arne T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-7075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20196854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-7-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1743-7075-7-17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Westman EC, Feinman RD, Mavropoulos JC, Vernon MC, Volek JS, Wortman JA, Yancy WS, Phinney SD. Low-carbohydrate nutrition and metabolism. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;86:276&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feinman RD, Volek JS. Low carbohydrate diets improve atherogenic dyslipidemia even in the absence of weight loss. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2006;3:24. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-3-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-3-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1488852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16790045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Feinman RD. Carbohydrate restriction improves the features of Metabolic Syndrome. Metabolic Syndrome may be defined by the response to carbohydrate restriction. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2005;2:31. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-2-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-2-31</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1323303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16288655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hession M, Rolland C, Kulkarni U, Wise A, Broom J. Systematic review of randomized controlled trials of low-carbohydrate vs. low-fat/low-calorie diets in the management of obesity and its comorbidities. Obes Rev. 2009;10:36&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-789X.2008.00518.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2008.00518.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18700873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accurso A, Bernstein RK, Dahlqvist A, Draznin B, Feinman RD, Fine EJ, Gleed A, Jacobs DB, Larson G, Lustig RH, Manninen AH, McFarlane SI, Morrison K, Nielsen JV, Ravnskov U, Roth KS, Silvestre R, Sowers JR, Sundberg R, Volek JS, Westman EC, Wood RJ, Wortman J, Vernon MC. Dietary carbohydrate restriction in type 2 diabetes mellitus and metabolic syndrome: time for a critical appraisal. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2008;5:9. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-5-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-5-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2359752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18397522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Fernandez ML, Feinman RD, Phinney SD. Dietary carbohydrate restriction induces a unique metabolic state positively affecting atherogenic dyslipidemia, fatty acid partitioning, and metabolic syndrome. Prog Lipid Res. 2008;47:307&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1016/j.plipres.2008.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.plipres.2008.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18396172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordmann AJ, Nordmann A, Briel M, Keller U, Yancy WS Jr, Brehm BJ, Bucher HC. Effects of low-carbohydrate vs low-fat diets on weight loss and cardiovascular risk factors: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166:285&#x2013;293. doi: 10.1001/archinte.166.3.285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.3.285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16476868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dashti HM, Al Zaid NS, Mathew TC, Al Mousawi M, Talib H, Asfar SK, Behbahani AI. Long term effects of ketogenic diet in obese subjects with high cholesterol level. Mol Cell Biochem. 2006;286:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s11010-005-9001-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11010-005-9001-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16652223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noakes M, Foster PR, Keogh JB, James AP, Mamo JC, Clifton PM. Comparison of isocaloric very low carbohydrate/high saturated fat and high carbohydrate/low saturated fat diets on body composition and cardiovascular risk. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2006;3:7. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-3-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-3-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1368980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16403234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shai I, Schwarzfuchs D, Henkin Y, Shahar DR, Witkow S, Greenberg I, Golan R, Fraser D, Bolotin A, Vardi H, Tangi-Rozental O, Zuk-Ramot R, Sarusi B, Brickner D, Schwartz Z, Sheiner E, Marko R, Katorza E, Thiery J, Fiedler GM, Bluher M, Stumvoll M, Stampfer MJ. Weight loss with a low-carbohydrate, Mediterranean, or low-fat diet. N Engl J Med. 2008;359:229&#x2013;241. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa0708681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0708681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18635428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner CD, Kiazand A, Alhassan S, Kim S, Stafford RS, Balise RR, Kraemer HC, King AC. Comparison of the Atkins, Zone, Ornish, and LEARN diets for change in weight and related risk factors among overweight premenopausal women: the A TO Z Weight Loss Study: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2007;297:969&#x2013;977. doi: 10.1001/jama.297.9.969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.297.9.969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17341711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacks FM, Bray GA, Carey VJ, Smith SR, Ryan DH, Anton SD, McManus K, Champagne CM, Bishop LM, Laranjo N, Leboff MS, Rood JC, de Jonge L, Greenway FL, Loria CM, Obarzanek E, Williamson DA. Comparison of weight-loss diets with different compositions of fat, protein, and carbohydrates. N Engl J Med. 2009;360:859&#x2013;873. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa0804748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0804748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19246357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine EJ, Feinman RD. Thermodynamics of weight loss diets. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2004;1:15. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-1-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-1-15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC543577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15588283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW, Sitren HS, Daniels MJ, Langkamp-Henken B. Effects of variation in protein and carbohydrate intake on body mass and composition during energy restriction: a meta-regression 1. Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;83:260&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16469983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feinman RD, Fine EJ. Nonequilibrium thermodynamics and energy efficiency in weight loss diets. Theor Biol Med Model. 2007;4:27. doi: 10.1186/1742-4682-4-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1742-4682-4-27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1947950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17663761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman LM, Heilbronn LK, Martin CK, Alfonso A, Smith SR, Ravussin E. Effect of calorie restriction with or without exercise on body composition and fat distribution. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007;92:865&#x2013;872. doi: 10.1210/jc.2006-2184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2006-2184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17200169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Dagnone D, Jones PJ, Smith H, Paddags A, Hudson R, Janssen I. Reduction in obesity and related comorbid conditions after diet-induced weight loss or exercise-induced weight loss in men. A randomized, controlled trial. Ann Intern Med. 2000;133:92&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10896648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bopp MJ, Houston DK, Lenchik L, Easter L, Kritchevsky SB, Nicklas BJ. Lean mass loss is associated with low protein intake during dietary-induced weight loss in postmenopausal women. J Am Diet Assoc. 2008;108:1216&#x2013;1220. doi: 10.1016/j.jada.2008.04.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jada.2008.04.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3665330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18589032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaston TB, Dixon JB, O'Brien PE. Changes in fat-free mass during significant weight loss: a systematic review. Int J Obes (Lond) 2007;31:743&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17075583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Gomez AL, Love DM, Weyers AM, Hesslink R Jr, Wise JA, Kraemer WJ. Effects of an 8-week weight-loss program on cardiovascular disease risk factors and regional body composition. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2002;56:585&#x2013;592. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12173568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willi SM, Oexmann MJ, Wright NM, Collop NA, Key LL Jr. The effects of a high-protein, low-fat, ketogenic diet on adolescents with morbid obesity: body composition, blood chemistries, and sleep abnormalities. Pediatrics. 1998;101:61&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1542/peds.101.1.61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.101.1.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9417152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Sharman MJ, Love DM, Avery NG, Gomez AL, Scheett TP, Kraemer WJ. Body composition and hormonal responses to a carbohydrate-restricted diet. Metabolism. 2002;51:864&#x2013;870. doi: 10.1053/meta.2002.32037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2002.32037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12077732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young CM, Scanlan SS, Im HS, Lutwak L. Effect of body composition and other parameters in obese young men of carbohydrate level of reduction diet. Am J Clin Nutr. 1971;24:290&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5548734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky VM. Science and practice of strength training. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, Manore MM, Rankin JW, Smith BK. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:459&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Pedwell H, Rissanen J. Response of total and regional lean tissue and skeletal muscle to a program of energy restriction and resistance exercise. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1995;19:781&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8589778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballor DL, Katch VL, Becque MD, Marks CR. Resistance weight training during caloric restriction enhances lean body weight maintenance. Am J Clin Nutr. 1988;47:19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3337037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, van Loon LJ. Aging, exercise, and muscle protein metabolism. J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:2040&#x2013;2048. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.91551.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.91551.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard DR, Soucy L, Senechal M, Dionne IJ, Brochu M. Impact of resistance training with or without caloric restriction on physical capacity in obese older women. Menopause. 2009;16:66&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1097/gme.0b013e31817dacf7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/gme.0b013e31817dacf7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18779759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda C, Layne JE, Munoz-Orians L, Gordon PL, Walsmith J, Foldvari M, Roubenoff R, Tucker KL, Nelson ME. A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise training to improve glycemic control in older adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25:2335&#x2013;2341. doi: 10.2337/diacare.25.12.2335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.25.12.2335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DE, Elliott EJ, Naughton GA. Exercise for type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2006;3:CD002968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Boule NG, Wells GA, Prud'homme D, Fortier M, Reid RD, Tulloch H, Coyle D, Phillips P, Jennings A, Jaffey J. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147:357&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiegler P, Cunliffe A. The role of diet and exercise for the maintenance of fat-free mass and resting metabolic rate during weight loss. Sports Med. 2006;36:239&#x2013;262. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200636030-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636030-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16526835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yancy WS Jr, Olsen MK, Guyton JR, Bakst RP, Westman EC. A low-carbohydrate, ketogenic diet versus a low-fat diet to treat obesity and hyperlipidemia: a randomized, controlled trial. Ann Intern Med. 2004;140:769&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15148063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brehm BJ, Seeley RJ, Daniels SR, D'Alessio DA. A randomized trial comparing a very low carbohydrate diet and a calorie-restricted low fat diet on body weight and cardiovascular risk factors in healthy women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003;88:1617&#x2013;1623. doi: 10.1210/jc.2002-021480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2002-021480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12679447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Phinney SD, Forsythe CE, Quann EE, Wood RJ, Puglisi MJ, Kraemer WJ, Bibus DM, Fernandez ML, Feinman RD. Carbohydrate restriction has a more favorable impact on the metabolic syndrome than a low fat diet. Lipids. 2009;44:297&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1007/s11745-008-3274-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11745-008-3274-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19082851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkworth GD, Noakes M, Clifton PM, Buckley JD. Effects of a low carbohydrate weight loss diet on exercise capacity and tolerance in obese subjects. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009;17:1916&#x2013;1923. doi: 10.1038/oby.2009.134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2009.134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19373224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner CD, Kiazand A, Alhassan S, Kim S, Stafford RS, Balise RR, Kraemer HC, King AC. Comparison of the Atkins, Zone, Ornish, and LEARN diets for change in weight and related risk factors among overweight premenopausal women: the A TO Z Weight Loss Study: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2007;297:969&#x2013;977. doi: 10.1001/jama.297.9.969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.297.9.969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17341711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phinney SD. Ketogenic diets and physical performance. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2004;1:2. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-1-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-1-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC524027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15507148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen TP. Slank med ketolysekuren: en enklere vei til et lettere liv. Oslo: Gyldendal fakta; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Norwegian Food Safety Authority, Norwegian Directorate for Health, The Department of Nutrition UoO. Norwegian Food Composition Tables. 2006. http://matportalen.no/matvaretabellen</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster GD, Wyatt HR, Hill JO, McGuckin BG, Brill C, Mohammed BS, Szapary PO, Rader DJ, Edman JS, Klein S. A randomized trial of a low-carbohydrate diet for obesity. N Engl J Med. 2003;348:2082&#x2013;2090. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa022207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa022207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12761365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sondike SB, Copperman N, Jacobson MS. Effects of a low-carbohydrate diet on weight loss and cardiovascular risk factor in overweight adolescents. J Pediatr. 2003;142:253&#x2013;258. doi: 10.1067/mpd.2003.4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mpd.2003.4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12640371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samaha FF, Iqbal N, Seshadri P, Chicano KL, Daily DA, McGrory J, Williams T, Williams M, Gracely EJ, Stern L. A low-carbohydrate as compared with a low-fat diet in severe obesity. N Engl J Med. 2003;348:2074&#x2013;2081. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa022637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa022637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12761364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dansinger ML, Gleason JA, Griffith JL, Selker HP, Schaefer EJ. Comparison of the Atkins, Ornish, Weight Watchers, and Zone diets for weight loss and heart disease risk reduction: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2005;293:43&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1001/jama.293.1.43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.293.1.43</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15632335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halyburton AK, Brinkworth GD, Wilson CJ, Noakes M, Buckley JD, Keogh JB, Clifton PM. Low- and high-carbohydrate weight-loss diets have similar effects on mood but not cognitive performance. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;86:580&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keogh JB, Brinkworth GD, Noakes M, Belobrajdic DP, Buckley JD, Clifton PM. Effects of weight loss from a very-low-carbohydrate diet on endothelial function and markers of cardiovascular disease risk in subjects with abdominal obesity. Am J Clin Nutr. 2008;87:567&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18326593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner CD, Kiazand A, Alhassan S, Kim S, Stafford RS, Balise RR, Kraemer HC, King AC. Comparison of the Atkins, Zone, Ornish, and LEARN diets for change in weight and related risk factors among overweight premenopausal women: the A TO Z Weight Loss Study: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2007;297:969&#x2013;977. doi: 10.1001/jama.297.9.969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.297.9.969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17341711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boden G, Sargrad K, Homko C, Mozzoli M, Stein TP. Effect of a low-carbohydrate diet on appetite, blood glucose levels, and insulin resistance in obese patients with type 2 diabetes. Ann Intern Med. 2005;142:403&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15767618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnstone AM, Horgan GW, Murison SD, Bremner DM, Lobley GE. Effects of a high-protein ketogenic diet on hunger, appetite, and weight loss in obese men feeding ad libitum. Am J Clin Nutr. 2008;87:44&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18175736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClernon FJ, Yancy WS Jr, Eberstein JA, Atkins RC, Westman EC. The effects of a low-carbohydrate ketogenic diet and a low-fat diet on mood, hunger, and other self-reported symptoms. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2007;15:182&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1038/oby.2007.516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2007.516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17228046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Sharman MJ. Cardiovascular and hormonal aspects of very-low-carbohydrate ketogenic diets. Obes Res. 2004;12(Suppl 2):115S&#x2013;123S. doi: 10.1038/oby.2004.276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2004.276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15601959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz JM, Linfoot P, Dare D, Aghajanian K. Hepatic de novo lipogenesis in normoinsulinemic and hyperinsulinemic subjects consuming high-fat, low-carbohydrate and low-fat, high-carbohydrate isoenergetic diets. Am J Clin Nutr. 2003;77:43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12499321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manninen AH. Very-low-carbohydrate diets and preservation of muscle mass. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2006;3:9. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-3-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-3-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1373635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meckling KA, O'Sullivan C, Saari D. Comparison of a low-fat diet to a low-carbohydrate diet on weight loss, body composition, and risk factors for diabetes and cardiovascular disease in free-living, overweight men and women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89:2717&#x2013;2723. doi: 10.1210/jc.2003-031606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2003-031606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15181047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geliebter A, Maher MM, Gerace L, Gutin B, Heymsfield SB, Hashim SA. Effects of strength or aerobic training on body composition, resting metabolic rate, and peak oxygen consumption in obese dieting subjects. Am J Clin Nutr. 1997;66:557&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9280173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Ross R. Effects of sex on the change in visceral, subcutaneous adipose tissue and skeletal muscle in response to weight loss. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1999;23:1035&#x2013;1046. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0801038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0801038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10557024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Exercise, protein metabolism, and muscle growth. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2001;11:109&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11255140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browning JD, Weis B, Davis J, Satapati S, Merritt M, Malloy CR, Burgess SC. Alterations in hepatic glucose and energy metabolism as a result of calorie and carbohydrate restriction. Hepatology. 2008;48:1487&#x2013;1496. doi: 10.1002/hep.22504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.22504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18925642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer WJ. Designing resistance training programs. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meckling KA, Sherfey R. A randomized trial of a hypocaloric high-protein diet, with and without exercise, on weight loss, fitness, and markers of the Metabolic Syndrome in overweight and obese women. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2007;32:743&#x2013;752. doi: 10.1139/H07-059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/H07-059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17622289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Evans E, Baum JI, Seyler J, Erickson DJ, Boileau RA. Dietary protein and exercise have additive effects on body composition during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2005;135:1903&#x2013;1910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16046715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming J, Sharman MJ, Avery NG, Love DM, Gomez AL, Scheett TP, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS. Endurance capacity and high-intensity exercise performance responses to a high fat diet. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2003;13:466&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14967870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlenbusch M, Haub M, Munoz K, MacConnie S, Stillwell B. Effect of high-fat or high-carbohydrate diets on endurance exercise: a meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2005;15:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15902985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert EV, Speechly DP, Dennis SC, Noakes TD. Enhanced endurance in trained cyclists during moderate intensity exercise following 2 weeks adaptation to a high fat diet. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69:287&#x2013;293. doi: 10.1007/BF00392032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00392032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7851362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowlands DS, Hopkins WG. Effects of high-fat and high-carbohydrate diets on metabolism and performance in cycling. Metabolism. 2002;51:678&#x2013;690. doi: 10.1053/meta.2002.32723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2002.32723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12037719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muoio DM, Leddy JJ, Horvath PJ, Awad AB, Pendergast DR. Effect of dietary fat on metabolic adjustments to maximal VO2 and endurance in runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1994;26:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White AM, Johnston CS, Swan PD, Tjonn SL, Sears B. Blood ketones are directly related to fatigue and perceived effort during exercise in overweight adults adhering to low-carbohydrate diets for weight loss: a pilot study. J Am Diet Assoc. 2007;107:1792&#x2013;1796. doi: 10.1016/j.jada.2007.07.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jada.2007.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17904939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlierf G, Reinheimer W, Stossberg V. Diurnal patterns of plasma triglycerides and free fatty acids in normal subjects and in patients with endogenous (type IV) hyperlipoproteinemia. Nutr Metab. 1971;13:80&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1159/000175323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000175323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5123770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharman MJ, Kraemer WJ, Love DM, Avery NG, Gomez AL, Scheett TP, Volek JS. A ketogenic diet favorably affects serum biomarkers for cardiovascular disease in normal-weight men. J Nutr. 2002;132:1879&#x2013;1885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12097663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer EJ, Audelin MC, McNamara JR, Shah PK, Tayler T, Daly JA, Augustin JL, Seman LJ, Rubenstein JJ. Comparison of fasting and postprandial plasma lipoproteins in subjects with and without coronary heart disease. Am J Cardiol. 2001;88:1129&#x2013;1133. doi: 10.1016/S0002-9149(01)02047-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-9149(01)02047-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11703957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Sharman MJ, Forsythe CE. Modification of lipoproteins by very low-carbohydrate diets. J Nutr. 2005;135:1339&#x2013;1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15930434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilz S, Scharnagl H, Tiran B, Seelhorst U, Wellnitz B, Boehm BO, Schaefer JR, Marz W. Free fatty acids are independently associated with all-cause and cardiovascular mortality in subjects with coronary artery disease. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91:2542&#x2013;2547. doi: 10.1210/jc.2006-0195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2006-0195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16595593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Efficacy of aerobic exercise on coronary heart disease risk factors. Prev Cardiol. 2008;11:71&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18401233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL. The influence of exercise on the concentrations of triglyceride and cholesterol in human plasma. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1984;12:205&#x2013;244. doi: 10.1249/00003677-198401000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00003677-198401000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6376133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galletly C, Moran L, Noakes M, Clifton P, Tomlinson L, Norman R. Psychological benefits of a high-protein, low-carbohydrate diet in obese women with polycystic ovary syndrome--a pilot study. Appetite. 2007;49:590&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1016/j.appet.2007.03.222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.appet.2007.03.222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17509728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavropoulos JC, Yancy WS, Hepburn J, Westman EC. The effects of a low-carbohydrate, ketogenic diet on the polycystic ovary syndrome: a pilot study. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2005;2:35. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-2-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-2-35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1334192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16359551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos A, Bakker SJ, Links TP, Gans RO, Wolffenbuttel BH. Thyroid function is associated with components of the metabolic syndrome in euthyroid subjects. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007;92:491&#x2013;496. doi: 10.1210/jc.2006-1718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2006-1718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17090642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amati F, Dube JJ, Stefanovic-Racic M, Toledo FG, Goodpaster BH. Improvements in insulin sensitivity are blunted by subclinical hypothyroidism. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:265&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett JB, Woods MN, Lamon-Fava S, Schaefer EJ, McNamara JR, Spiegelman D, Hertzmark E, Goldin B, Longcope C, Gorbach SL. Plasma lipid and lipoprotein levels during the follicular and luteal phases of the menstrual cycle. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89:776&#x2013;782. doi: 10.1210/jc.2003-030506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2003-030506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14764796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>