<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34649266</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Twelve Months of Time-restricted Eating and Resistance Training Improves Inflammatory Markers and Cardiometabolic Risk Factors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2577</StartPage><EndPage>2585</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2577-2585</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002738</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Recently, a modified intermittent fasting protocol was demonstrated to be able to maintain muscle mass and strength, decrease fat mass, and improve some inflammation and cardiovascular risk factors in healthy resistance-trained males after 2 months. The present study sought to investigate the long-term effects on these parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The experiment was a single-blind randomized study. Twenty healthy subjects were enrolled and underwent 12 months of either a time-restricted eating (TRE) diet or a normal diet (ND) protocol, along with resistance training. In the TRE protocol, subjects consumed their energy needs in three meals during an 8-h period of time each day (1 pm, 4 pm, and 8 pm). Subjects in the ND group also had three meals, which were consumed at 8 am, 1 pm, and 8 pm. Groups were matched for kilocalories consumed and macronutrient distribution at baseline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">After 12 months of TRE, body mass, fat mass, insulin-like growth factor 1, and testosterone were significantly lower compared with ND. Moreover, inflammatory markers (interleukin 6, interleukin 1&#x3b2;, and tumor necrosis factor &#x3b1;), insulin sensitivity (fasting glucose, insulin, and homeostatic model assessment for insulin resistance index), and lipid profile (cholesterol, HDL, and LDL) significantly improved after TRE compared with ND. Finally, subjects in TRE spontaneously decreased their daily energy intake, whereas those in ND maintained their starting kilocalories per day. No adverse events were reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our results suggest that long-term TRE combined with a resistance training program is feasible, safe, and effective in reducing inflammatory markers and risk factors related to cardiovascular and metabolic diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moro</LastName><ForeName>Tatiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tinsley</LastName><ForeName>Grant</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pacelli</LastName><ForeName>Francesco Q</ForeName><Initials>FQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marcolin</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bianco</LastName><ForeName>Antonino</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Educational Science and Human Movement, University of Palermo, Palermo, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paoli</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04668378</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C583557">IGF1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>67763-96-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007334">Insulin-Like Growth Factor I</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050154" MajorTopicYN="N">Adiposity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000083202" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiometabolic Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002149" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Intake</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005215" MajorTopicYN="N">Fasting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007333" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin Resistance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007334" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin-Like Growth Factor I</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34649266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10115489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202112000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alberti KG Eckel RH Grundy SM, et al. Harmonizing the metabolic syndrome: a joint interim statement of the International Diabetes Federation Task Force on Epidemiology and Prevention; National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute; American Heart Association; World Heart Federation; International Atherosclerosis Society; and International Association for the Study of Obesity. <i>Circulation</i>. 2009;120(16):1640&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer UE, Briss PA, Goodman RA, Bowman BA. Prevention of chronic disease in the 21st century: elimination of the leading preventable causes of premature death and disability in the USA. <i>Lancet</i>. 2014;384(9937):45&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24996589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willett WC, Koplan JP, Nugent R, Dusenbury C, Puska P, Gaziano TA. Prevention of chronic disease by means of diet and lifestyle changes. In: Jamison DT Breman JG, et al., editors. <i>Disease Control Priorities in Developing Countries</i>. Washington (DC): The World Bank; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omura JD, Watson KB, Loustalot F, Fulton JE, Carlson SA. Types of physical activity recommended by primary care providers for patients at risk for cardiovascular disease. <i>Prev Chronic Dis</i>. 2021;18:E43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33964123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greaves CJ Sheppard KE Abraham C, et al. Systematic review of reviews of intervention components associated with increased effectiveness in dietary and physical activity interventions. <i>BMC Public Health</i>. 2011;11:119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3048531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21333011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratner R Goldberg R Haffner S, et al. Impact of intensive lifestyle and metformin therapy on cardiovascular disease risk factors in the diabetes prevention program. <i>Diabetes Care</i>. 2005;28(4):888&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1307521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15793191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvie MN Pegington M Mattson MP, et al. The effects of intermittent or continuous energy restriction on weight loss and metabolic disease risk markers: a randomized trial in young overweight women. <i>Int J Obes (Lond)</i>. 2011;35(5):714&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3017674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20921964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halberg N Henriksen M S&#xf6;derhamn N, et al. Effect of intermittent fasting and refeeding on insulin action in healthy men. <i>J Appl Physiol (1985)</i>. 2005;99(6):2128&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16051710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heilbronn LK, Ravussin E. Calorie restriction extends life span&#x2014;but which calories?
<i>PLoS Med</i>. 2005;2(8):e231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1196473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16120010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson MP, Wan R. Beneficial effects of intermittent fasting and caloric restriction on the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular systems. <i>J Nutr Biochem</i>. 2005;16(3):129&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15741046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson MP, Longo VD, Harvie M. Impact of intermittent fasting on health and disease processes. <i>Ageing Res Rev</i>. 2017;39:46&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5411330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27810402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Tinsley G, Bianco A, Moro T. The influence of meal frequency and timing on health in humans: the role of fasting. <i>Nutrients</i>. 2019;11(4):719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30925707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandri M Barberi L Bijlsma AY, et al. Signalling pathways regulating muscle mass in ageing skeletal muscle: the role of the IGF1&#x2013;Akt&#x2013;mTOR&#x2013;FoxO pathway. <i>Biogerontology</i>. 2013;14(3):303&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23686362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnosky AR, Hoddy KK, Unterman TG, Varady KA. Intermittent fasting vs daily calorie restriction for type 2 diabetes prevention: a review of human findings. <i>Transl Res</i>. 2014;164(4):302&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24993615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasiou CA, Karfopoulou E, Yannakoulia M. Weight regaining: from statistics and behaviors to physiology and metabolism. <i>Metabolism</i>. 2015;64(11):1395&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T Tinsley G Bianco A, et al. Effects of eight weeks of time-restricted feeding (16/8) on basal metabolism, maximal strength, body composition, inflammation, and cardiovascular risk factors in resistance-trained males. <i>J Transl Med</i>. 2016;14(1):290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5064803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27737674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM Forsse JS Butler NK, et al. Time-restricted feeding in young men performing resistance training: a randomized controlled trial. <i>Eur J Sport Sci</i>. 2017;17(2):200&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27550719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM Moore ML Graybeal AJ, et al. Time-restricted feeding plus resistance training in active females: a randomized trial. <i>Am J Clin Nutr</i>. 2019;110(3):628&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31268131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramsey KM, Bass J. Circadian clocks in fuel harvesting and energy homeostasis. <i>Cold Spring Harb Symp Quant Biol</i>. 2011;76:63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3970906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21890641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaix A, Zarrinpar A. The effects of time-restricted feeding on lipid metabolism and adiposity. <i>Adipocyte</i>. 2015;4(4):319&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4573188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26451290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatori M Vollmers C Zarrinpar A, et al. Time-restricted feeding without reducing caloric intake prevents metabolic diseases in mice fed a high-fat diet. <i>Cell Metab</i>. 2012;15(6):848&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3491655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22608008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarrinpar A, Chaix A, Yooseph S, Panda S. Diet and feeding pattern affect the diurnal dynamics of the gut microbiome. <i>Cell Metab</i>. 2014;20(6):1006&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4255146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25470548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasumoto Y Hashimoto C Nakao R, et al. Short-term feeding at the wrong time is sufficient to desynchronize peripheral clocks and induce obesity with hyperphagia, physical inactivity and metabolic disorders in mice. <i>Metabolism</i>. 2016;65(5):714&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27085778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SA, Velingkaar N, Makwana K, Chaudhari A, Kondratov R. Calorie restriction regulates circadian clock gene expression through BMAL1 dependent and independent mechanisms. <i>Sci Rep</i>. 2016;6:25970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4864379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27170536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SA, Chaudhari A, Gupta R, Velingkaar N, Kondratov RV. Circadian clocks govern calorie restriction-mediated life span extension through BMAL1- and IGF-1-dependent mechanisms. <i>FASEB J</i>. 2016;30(4):1634&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4799504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26700733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q, Townsend MK, Okereke OI, Franco OH, Hu FB, Grodstein F. Adiposity and weight change in mid-life in relation to healthy survival after age 70 in women: prospective cohort study. <i>BMJ</i>. 2009;339:b3796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3230231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19789407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WEIR JB. New methods for calculating metabolic rate with special reference to protein metabolism. <i>J Physiol</i>. 1949;109(1&#x2013;2):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1392602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15394301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacelli QF, Paoli A, Zolesi V, Norfini A, Donati A, Reggiani C. Implementation and ground validation of a facility for functional and structural analysis of proximal upper limb muscles in microgravity. <i>Basic Appl Myol</i>. 2009;19:77&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turconi G, Bazzano R, Roggi C, Cena H. Reliability and relative validity of a quantitative food-frequency questionnaire for use among adults in Italian population. <i>Int J Food Sci Nutr</i>. 2010;61(8):846&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20666692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvie M Wright C Pegington M, et al. The effect of intermittent energy and carbohydrate restriction v. daily energy restriction on weight loss and metabolic disease risk markers in overweight women. <i>Br J Nutr</i>. 2013;110(8):1534&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5857384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23591120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen MD Ryan DH Apovian CM, et al. 2013 AHA/ACC/TOS guideline for the management of overweight and obesity in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines and the Obesity Society. <i>Circulation</i>. 2014;129(25 Suppl 2):S102&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5819889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24222017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manore MM. Weight management for athletes and active individuals: a brief review. <i>Sports Med</i>. 2015;45(Suppl 1):S83&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4672016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DM, Gonzalez MC, Pereira AZ, Redman LM, Heymsfield SB. Time to correctly predict the amount of weight loss with dieting. <i>J Acad Nutr Diet</i>. 2014;114(6):857&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24699137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidell JC, Muller DC, Sorkin JD, Andres R. Fasting respiratory exchange ratio and resting metabolic rate as predictors of weight gain: the Baltimore longitudinal study on aging. <i>Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord</i>. 1992;16(9):667&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1328091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valtuena S, Salas-Salvado J, Lorda PG. The respiratory quotient as a prognostic factor in weight-loss rebound. <i>Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord</i>. 1997;21(9):811&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9376895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashtary-Larky D, Bagheri R, Tinsley GM, Asbaghi O, Paoli A, Moro T. Effects of intermittent fasting combined with resistance training on body composition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Physiol Behav</i>. 2021;237:113453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cangemi R, Friedmann AJ, Holloszy JO, Fontana L. Long-term effects of calorie restriction on serum sex-hormone concentrations in men. <i>Aging Cell</i>. 2010;9(2):236&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3569090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20096034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Kaur G. Intermittent fasting dietary restriction regimen negatively influences reproduction in young rats: a study of hypothalamo-hypophysial-gonadal axis. <i>PLoS One</i>. 2013;8(1):e52416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3558496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23382817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Cancellara P, Pompei P, Moro T. Ketogenic diet and skeletal muscle hypertrophy: a frenemy relationship?
<i>J Hum Kinet</i>. 2019;68:233&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6724590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31531148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulcelik NE, Halil M, Ariogul S, Usman A. Adipocytokines and aging: adiponectin and leptin. <i>Minerva Endocrinol</i>. 2013;38(2):203&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23732375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerqueira FM da Cunha FM Caldeira da Silva CC, et al. Long-term intermittent feeding, but not caloric restriction, leads to redox imbalance, insulin receptor nitration, and glucose intolerance. <i>Free Radic Biol Med</i>. 2011;51(7):1454&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21816219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sull JW Kim HJ Yun JE, et al. Serum adiponectin is associated with family history of diabetes independently of obesity and insulin resistance in healthy Korean men and women. <i>Eur J Endocrinol</i>. 2009;160(1):39&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kershaw EE, Flier JS. Adipose tissue as an endocrine organ. <i>J Clin Endocrinol Metab</i>. 2004;89(6):2548&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15181022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varady KA Bhutani S Klempel MC, et al. Alternate day fasting for weight loss in normal weight and overweight subjects: a randomized controlled trial. <i>Nutr J</i>. 2013;12(1):146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3833266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24215592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhutani S, Klempel MC, Kroeger CM, Trepanowsk JF, Varady KA. Alternate day fasting and endurance exercise combine to reduce body weight and favorably alter plasma lipids in obese humans. <i>Obesity (Silver Spring)</i>. 2013;21(7):1370&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh DK, Ciaraldi T, Henry RR. Adiponectin in health and disease. <i>Diabetes Obes Metab</i>. 2007;9(3):282&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17391153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oda N Imamura S Fujita T, et al. The ratio of leptin to adiponectin can be used as an index of insulin resistance. <i>Metabolism</i>. 2008;57(2):268&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18191059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falahi E, Khalkhali Rad AH, Roosta S. What is the best biomarker for metabolic syndrome diagnosis?
<i>Diabetes Metab Syndr</i>. 2015;9(4):366&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25470629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trepanowski JF Kroeger CM Barnosky A, et al. Effect of alternate-day fasting on weight loss, weight maintenance, and cardioprotection among metabolically healthy obese adults: a randomized clinical trial. <i>JAMA Intern Med</i>. 2017;177(7):930&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28459931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllister MJ, Gonzalez AE, Waldman HS. Time restricted feeding reduces inflammation and cortisol response to a firegrounds test in professional firefighters. <i>J Occup Environ Med</i>. 2021;63(5):441&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33928938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yumuk V Tsigos C Fried M, et al. European guidelines for obesity management in adults. <i>Obes Facts</i>. 2015;8(6):402&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26641646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>