<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32342452</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0065-2598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>1228</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in experimental medicine and biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Exp Med Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise and Type 2 Diabetes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>91</StartPage><EndPage>105</EndPage><MedlinePgn>91-105</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/978-981-15-1792-1_6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The epidemic of diabetes mellitus has already become a serious global health threat. In the past three decades, the number of people with diabetes mellitus has quadrupled globally, and diabetes mellitus is known as the ninth major cause of death in the world nowadays. The increasing prevalence of type 2 diabetes mellitus is in coincidence with the augmentation of obesity in most developed countries as well as in developing countries. A sedentary lifestyle is well-known as one of the major reasons for the rising epidemic of type 2 diabetes mellitus besides the other reasons such as adopting energy-dense diets relative to the actual need for energy and population aging. Exercise as a regular physical activity at a medium to vigorous intensity is found to be an efficient influencer that would switch back most of the known type 2 diabetes mellitus factors toward healthier positions. Exercise is proven to have clinical benefits, such as improved insulin sensitivity, reductions in glycosylated hemoglobin (A1C) and increased peak oxygen consumption (VO<sub>2</sub>peak) which are definitely preventive toward diabetes. Exercise training can favorably affect glycemic parameters, the lipid profile, blood pressure, and high-sensitivity C-reactive protein. Exercise improves blood glucose control in type 2 diabetes, reduces cardiovascular risk factors, and regulates body weight by reducing body fat percentage and enhancing lean mass. In this chapter, the effect of regular exercise on the prevention of diabetes and short-term glucose and energy metabolism will be discussed. In addition, the effect of exercise on most common complications of type 2 diabetes including cardiovascular diseases, dyslipidemia, nephropathy, neuropathy, and retinopathy will be reviewed.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amanat</LastName><ForeName>Sasan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, School of Health, Larestan University of Medical Sciences, Larestan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghahri</LastName><ForeName>Simin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Shahrood University of Technology, Shahrood, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dianatinasab</LastName><ForeName>Aria</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Student Research Committee, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fararouei</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Public Health, Department of Epidemiology, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dianatinasab</LastName><ForeName>Mostafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Center for Health Related Social and Behavioral Sciences Research, Shahroud University of Medical Sciences, Shahroud, Iran. dianatinasab@sums.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Exp Med Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0121103</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0065-2598</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006442">Glycated Hemoglobin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006442" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycated Hemoglobin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007333" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin Resistance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32342452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-15-1792-1_6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association (2018) 2. Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: standards of medical care in diabetes&#x2014;2018. Diabetes Care 41(Suppl 1):S13&#x2013;S27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Qu S, Zhang P, Chattopadhyay S, Gregg EW, Albright A, Hopkins D, Pronk NP (2015) Economic evaluation of combined diet and physical activity promotion programs to prevent type 2 diabetes among persons at increased risk: a systematic review for the Community Preventive Services Task Force. Ann Intern Med 163(6):452&#x2013;460</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26167962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4913890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Ye W, Chen Q, Zhang Y, Kuo C-H, Korivi M (2019) Resistance exercise intensity is correlated with attenuation of HbA1c and insulin in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health 16(1):140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30621076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6339182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Chen R, Wang H, Liang F (2015) Mechanisms linking inflammation to insulin resistance. Int J Endocrinol 2015:1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Ley SH, Hu FB (2018) Global aetiology and epidemiology of type 2 diabetes mellitus and its complications. Nat Rev Endocrinol 14(2):88</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29219149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorge MLMP, de Oliveira VN, Resende NM, Paraiso LF, Calixto A, Diniz ALD, Resende ES, Ropelle ER, Carvalheira JB, Espindola FS (2011) The effects of aerobic, resistance, and combined exercise on metabolic control, inflammatory markers, adipocytokines, and muscle insulin signaling in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Metabolism 60(9):1244&#x2013;1252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AminiLari Z, Fararouei M, Amanat S, Sinaei E, Dianatinasab S, AminiLari M, Daneshi N, Dianatinasab M (2017) The effect of 12 weeks aerobic, resistance, and combined exercises on omentin-1 levels and insulin resistance among type 2 diabetic middle-aged women. Diabetes Metab J 41(3):205&#x2013;212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28537059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5489501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colberg SR, Sigal RJ, Yardley JE, Riddell MC, Dunstan DW, Dempsey PC, Horton ES, Castorino K, Tate DF (2016) Physical activity/exercise and diabetes: a position statement of the American Diabetes Association. Diabetes Care 39(11):2065&#x2013;2079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27926890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6908414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association (2017) 2. Classification and diagnosis of diabetes. Diabetes Care 40(Suppl 1):S11&#x2013;S24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association (2019) 12. Older adults: standards of medical care in diabetes&#x2014;2019. Diabetes Care 42(Suppl 1):S139&#x2013;S147</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association (2018) 4. Lifestyle management: standards of medical care in diabetes&#x2014;2018. Diabetes Care 41(Supplement 1):S38&#x2013;S50</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osama A-J, Shehab AE-K (2015) Psychological wellbeing and biochemical modulation in response to weight loss in obese type 2 diabetes patients. Afr Health Sci 15(2):503&#x2013;512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26124797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4480496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association (2019) 8. Obesity management for the treatment of type 2 diabetes: standards of medical care in diabetes&#x2014;2019. Diabetes Care 42(Supplement 1):S81&#x2013;S89</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young-Hyman D, De Groot M, Hill-Briggs F, Gonzalez JS, Hood K, Peyrot M (2016) Psychosocial care for people with diabetes: a position statement of the American Diabetes Association. Diabetes Care 39(12):2126&#x2013;2140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27879358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5127231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howley E (2015) Type of activity: resistance, aerobic and leisure versus occupational physical activity. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11427761 . Retrieved 14 June 2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association (2017) 5. Prevention or delay of type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care 40(Suppl 1):S44&#x2013;S47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kriska A (2000) Physical activity and the prevention of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Sports Med 29(3):147&#x2013;151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10739265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orozco LJ, Buchleitner AM, Gimenez-Perez G, i Figuls MR, Richter B, Mauricio D (2008) Exercise or exercise and diet for preventing type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cochrane Database Syst Rev (3):CD003054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hordern MD, Dunstan DW, Prins JB, Baker MK, Singh MAF, Coombes JS (2012) Exercise prescription for patients with type 2 diabetes and pre-diabetes: a position statement from Exercise and Sport Science Australia. J Sci Med Sport 15(1):25&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feito Y, Patel P, Sal Redondo A, Heinrich KM (2019) Effects of eight weeks of high intensity functional training on glucose control and body composition among overweight and obese adults. Sports 7(2):51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30813279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6409795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laaksonen DE, Lindstr&#xf6;m J, Lakka TA, Eriksson JG, Niskanen L, Wikstr&#xf6;m K, Aunola S, Kein&#xe4;nen-Kiukaanniemi S, Laakso M, Valle TT (2005) Physical activity in the prevention of type 2 diabetes: the Finnish diabetes prevention study. Diabetes 54(1):158&#x2013;165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ades PA (2015) A lifestyle program of exercise and weight loss is effective in preventing and treating type 2 diabetes mellitus: why are programs not more available? Prev Med 80:50&#x2013;52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25818810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4581884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romijn J, Coyle E, Sidossis L, Gastaldelli A, Horowitz J, Endert E, Wolfe R (1993) Regulation of endogenous fat and carbohydrate metabolism in relation to exercise intensity and duration. Am J Phys Endocrinol Metab 265(3):E380&#x2013;E391</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knab AM, Shanely RA, Corbin KD, Jin F, Sha W, Nieman DC (2011) A 45-minute vigorous exercise bout increases metabolic rate for 14 hours. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43(9):1643&#x2013;1648</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Moro T, Marcolin G, Neri M, Bianco A, Palma A, Grimaldi K (2012) High-Intensity Interval Resistance Training (HIRT) influences resting energy expenditure and respiratory ratio in non-dieting individuals. J Transl Med 10(1):237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3551736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heden T, Lox C, Rose P, Reid S, Kirk EP (2011) One-set resistance training elevates energy expenditure for 72 h similar to three sets. Eur J Appl Physiol 111(3):477&#x2013;484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20886227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha FA, Midgley AW, McNaughton LR, Farinatti PT (2016) Effect of continuous and intermittent bouts of isocaloric cycling and running exercise on excess postexercise oxygen consumption. J Sci Med Sport 19(2):187&#x2013;192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25747467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Li Q, Liu J, Jia S (2016) Irisin, an exercise-induced myokine as a metabolic regulator: an updated narrative review. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 32(1):51&#x2013;59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25952527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huh JY, Siopi A, Mougios V, Park KH, Mantzoros CS (2015) Irisin in response to exercise in humans with and without metabolic syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metabol 100(3):E453&#x2013;E457</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pekkala S, Wiklund PK, Hulmi JJ, Ahtiainen JP, Horttanainen M, P&#xf6;ll&#xe4;nen E, M&#xe4;kel&#xe4; KA, Kainulainen H, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Nyman K (2013) Are skeletal muscle FNDC5 gene expression and irisin release regulated by exercise and related to health? J Physiol 591(21):5393&#x2013;5400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24000180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3936375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escot&#xe9; X, G&#xf3;mez-Zorita S, L&#xf3;pez-Yoldi M, Milton-Laskibar I, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Quintela A, Mart&#xed;nez J, Moreno-Aliaga M, Portillo M (2017) Role of omentin, vaspin, cardiotrophin-1, TWEAK and NOV/CCN3 in obesity and diabetes development. Int J Mol Sci 18(8):1770</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28809783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5578159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanford KI, Goodyear LJ (2014) Exercise and type 2 diabetes: molecular mechanisms regulating glucose uptake in skeletal muscle. Adv Physiol Educ 38(4):308&#x2013;314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25434013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4315445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer HF, Witczak CA, Taylor EB, Fujii N, Hirshman MF, Goodyear LJ (2006) AS160 regulates insulin-and contraction-stimulated glucose uptake in mouse skeletal muscle. J Biol Chem 281(42):31478&#x2013;31485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16935857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtaszewski JF, Higaki Y, Hirshman MF, Michael MD, Dufresne SD, Kahn CR, Goodyear LJ (1999) Exercise modulates postreceptor insulin signaling and glucose transport in muscle-specific insulin receptor knockout mice. J Clin Invest 104(9):1257&#x2013;1264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10545524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">409827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassidy S, Thoma C, Hallsworth K, Parikh J, Hollingsworth KG, Taylor R, Jakovljevic DG, Trenell MI (2016) High intensity intermittent exercise improves cardiac structure and function and reduces liver fat in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomised controlled trial. Diabetologia 59(1):56&#x2013;66</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26350611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Way KL, Hackett DA, Baker MK, Johnson NA (2016) The effect of regular exercise on insulin sensitivity in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diabetes Metab J 40(4):253&#x2013;271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4995180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Wasserman DH, Castaneda-Sceppa C, White RD (2006) Physical activity/exercise and type 2 diabetes: a consensus statement from the American Diabetes Association. Diabetes Care 29(6):1433&#x2013;1438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16732040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domingueti CP, Dusse LMSA, das Gra&#xe7;as Carvalho M, de Sousa LP, Gomes KB, Fernandes AP (2016) Diabetes mellitus: the linkage between oxidative stress, inflammation, hypercoagulability and vascular complications. J Diabetes Complicat 30(4):738&#x2013;745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gemert WA, May AM, Schuit AJ, Oosterhof BY, Peeters PH, Monninkhof EM (2016) Effect of weight loss with or without exercise on inflammatory markers and adipokines in postmenopausal women: the SHAPE-2 trial, a randomized controlled trial. Cancer Epidemiol Prev Biomarkers 25(5):799&#x2013;806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi E, Negri C, Zanolin ME, Milanese C, Faccioli N, Trombetta M, Zoppini G, Cevese A, Bonadonna RC, Schena F (2012) Metabolic effects of aerobic training and resistance training in type 2 diabetic subjects: a randomized controlled trial (the RAED2 study). Diabetes Care 35(4):676&#x2013;682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22344613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3308269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn B, Herbst A, Pfeifer M, Krakow D, Zimny S, Kopp F, Melmer A, Steinacker JM, Holl RW (2015) Impact of physical activity on glycemic control and prevalence of cardiovascular risk factors in adults with type 1 diabetes: a cross-sectional multicenter study of 18,028 patients. Diabetes Care 38(8):1536&#x2013;1543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26015557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittenbecher C, Menzel J, Carstensen-Kirberg M, Biemann R, di Giuseppe R, Fritsche A, Isermann B, Herder C, Aleksandrova K, Boeing H (2016) Omentin-1, adiponectin, and the risk of developing type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care 39(6):e79&#x2013;e80</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27208328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK (2017) Anti-inflammatory effects of exercise: role in diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Eur J Clin Investig 47(8):600&#x2013;611</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclos M, Dejager S, Postel-Vinay N, di Nicola S, Qu&#xe9;r&#xe9; S, Fiquet B (2015) Physical activity in patients with type 2 diabetes and hypertension&#x2013;insights into motivations and barriers from the MOBILE study. Vasc Health Risk Manag 11:361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26170686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4492639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Morais PK, Sales MM, de Almeida JA, Motta-Santos D, de Sousa CV, Sim&#xf5;es HG (2015) Effects of aerobic exercise intensity on 24-h ambulatory blood pressure in individuals with type 2 diabetes and prehypertension. J Phys Ther Sci 27(1):51&#x2013;56</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CCL, Hess CN, Hiatt WR, Goldfine AB (2016) Atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease and heart failure in type 2 diabetes&#x2014;mechanisms, management, and clinical considerations. Circulation 133(24):2459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginsberg HN, MacCallum PR (2009) The obesity, metabolic syndrome, and type 2 diabetes mellitus pandemic: Part I. Increased cardiovascular disease risk and the importance of atherogenic dyslipidemia in persons with the metabolic syndrome and type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Cardiometab Syndr 4(2):113&#x2013;119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19614799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2901596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Parhofer KG (2014) Diabetic dyslipidemia. Metabolism 63(12):1469&#x2013;1479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25242435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gondim OS, de Camargo VTN, Gutierrez FA, de Oliveira Martins PF, Passos MEP, Momesso CM, Santos VC, Gorj&#xe3;o R, Pithon-Curi TC, Cury-Boaventura MF (2015) Benefits of regular exercise on inflammatory and cardiovascular risk markers in normal weight, overweight and obese adults. PLoS One 10(10):e0140596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26474157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4608693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakil-ur-Rehman S, Karimi H, Gillani SA (2017) Effects of supervised structured aerobic exercise training program on high and low density lipoprotein in patients with type II diabetes mellitus. Pak J Med Sci 33(1):96</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28367180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5368338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarathna R, Tyagi R, Kaur G, Vendan V, Acharya IN, Anand A, Singh A, Nagendra HR (2019) Efficacy of a validated yoga protocol on dyslipidemia in diabetes patients: NMB-2017 India trial. Medicines 6(4):100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31614579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6963794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chudyk A, Petrella RJ (2011) Effects of exercise on cardiovascular risk factors in type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Care 34(5):1228&#x2013;1237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3114506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cugusi L, Cadeddu C, Nocco S, Orr&#xf9; F, Bandino S, Deidda M, Caria A, Bassareo PP, Piras A, Cabras S, Mercuro G (2015) Effects of an aquatic-based exercise program to improve cardiometabolic profile, quality of life, and physical activity levels in men with type 2 diabetes mellitus. PM R 7(2):141&#x2013;148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gjevestad GO, Holven KB, Ulven SM (2015) Effects of exercise on gene expression of inflammatory markers in human peripheral blood cells: a systematic review. Curr Cardiovasc Risk Rep 9(7):34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26005511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4439514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellavere F, Cacciatori V, Bacchi E, Gemma M, Raimondo D, Negri C, Thomaseth K, Muggeo M, Bonora E, Moghetti P (2018) Effects of aerobic or resistance exercise training on cardiovascular autonomic function of subjects with type 2 diabetes: a pilot study. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis 28(3):226&#x2013;233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29402509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu C-R, Chen Y-T, Sheu WH-H (2015) Glycemic variability and diabetes retinopathy: a missing link. J Diabetes Complicat 29(2):302&#x2013;306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praidou A, Harris M, Niakas D, Labiris G (2017) Physical activity and its correlation to diabetic retinopathy. J Diabetes Complicat 31(2):456&#x2013;461</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loprinzi PD, Brodowicz GR, Sengupta S, Solomon SD, Ramulu PY (2014) Accelerometer-assessed physical activity and diabetic retinopathy in the United States. JAMA Ophthalmol 132(8):1017&#x2013;1019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25124951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Han X, Wu C, Shang X, Zhang L, He M (2019) Effect of physical activity on reducing the risk of diabetic retinopathy progression: 10-year prospective findings from the 45 and up study. Available at SSRN 3347912</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boor P, Celec P, Behuliak M, Gran&#x10d;i&#x10d; P, Kebis A, Kukan M, Pronayov&#xe1; N, Liptaj T, Ostendorf T, &#x160;ebekov&#xe1; K (2009) Regular moderate exercise reduces advanced glycation and ameliorates early diabetic nephropathy in obese Zucker rats. Metabolism 58(11):1669&#x2013;1677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai H, Li G, Zhang P, Xu D, Chen L (2017) Effect of exercise on the quality of life in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Qual Life Res 26(3):515&#x2013;530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27990609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Dennis SM, Kiernan MC, Harmer AR (2019) Aerobic exercise training may improve nerve function in type 2 diabetes and pre-diabetes: a systematic review. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 35(2):e3099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;a EM, Meling S, Nyhus L-K, Str&#xf8;mstad G, Mangerud KM, Helgerud J, Bratland-Sanda S, St&#xf8;ren &#xd8; (2017) High-intensity aerobic interval training improves aerobic fitness and HbA1c among persons diagnosed with type 2 diabetes. Eur J Appl Physiol 117(3):455&#x2013;467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28160083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory JM, Muldowney JA, Engelhardt BG, Tyree R, Marks-Shulman P, Silver HJ, Donahue EP, Edgerton DS, Winnick JJ (2019) Aerobic exercise training improves hepatic and muscle insulin sensitivity, but reduces splanchnic glucose uptake in obese humans with type 2 diabetes. Nutr Diabetes 9(1):1&#x2013;12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nojima H, Yoneda M, Watanabe H, Yamane K, Kitahara Y, Sekikawa K, Yamamoto H, Yokoyama A, Hattori N, Kohno N (2017) Association between aerobic capacity and the improvement in glycemic control after the exercise training in type 2 diabetes. Diabetol Metab Syndr 9(1):63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28828040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5563031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dede ND, Ipekci S, Kebapcilar L, Arslan M, Kurban S, Yildiz M, Gonen MS (2018) Effect of aerobic exercise training on serum malondialdehyde level and quality of life in type 2 diabetes. In: 20th European congress of endocrinology: 2018: BioScientifica</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Castro CA, da Silva KA, Rocha MC, Sene-Fiorese M, Nonaka KO, Malavazi I, de Freitas Anibal F, de Oliveira Duarte ACG (2018) Exercise and omentin: their role in the crosstalk between muscle and adipose tissues in type 2 diabetes mellitus rat models. Front Physiol:9, 1881</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGinley SK, Armstrong MJ, Boul&#xe9; NG, Sigal RJ (2015) Effects of exercise training using resistance bands on glycaemic control and strength in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Acta Diabetol 52(2):221&#x2013;230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takenami E, Iwamoto S, Shiraishi N, Kato A, Watanabe Y, Yamada Y, Yamada S, Ishii N (2019) Effects of low-intensity resistance training on muscular function and glycemic control in older adults with type 2 diabetes. J Diabetes Investig 10(2):331&#x2013;338</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30175458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddell MC, Sigal RJ (2013) Physical activity, exercise and diabetes. Can J Diabetes 37(6):359&#x2013;360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24321713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>