<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40903011</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Resistance versus High-Intensity Interval Training on Myokines and Cancer Cell Suppression in Breast Cancer Survivors: A Randomized Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>9</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003848</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Reducing recurrence and mortality is crucial for breast cancer survivors. We investigated the effects of a 12-wk resistance training (RT) versus high-intensity interval training (HIIT) program on myokines, cytokines secreted by skeletal muscle cells at rest in response to muscle contraction, and cancer cell inhibition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-eight survivors of breast cancer (age = 55.5 &#xb1; 8.8 yr, body mass index = 27.9 &#xb1; 5.1 kg&#xb7;m -2 , time since diagnosis = 31 &#xb1; 12.3 months) were randomly allocated to a 12-wk supervised moderate to high-intensity RT ( n = 14) or HIIT ( n = 14) program 3 d&#xb7;wk -1 . Resting blood was collected before and after exercise program (at least 48 h before the first and after the last exercise session) to measure serum levels of myokines (decorin, interleukin 6 [IL-6], secreted protein acidic and rich in cysteine [SPARC], and oncostatin M [OSM]) and triple negative MDA-MB-231 cell growth in vitro , using real-time cellular analysis to determine growth rate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Exercise attendance was 85% for RT and 81% for HIIT. Serum levels of SPARC for RT and OSM for HIIT significantly ( P &lt; 0.05) increased (11% to 15%) after 12 wk, with no significant differences between groups. MDA-MB-231 cell growth was significantly ( P &lt; 0.05) reduced for both RT and HIIT by 22% and 25%, respectively, with no significant difference between groups. Reductions in MDA-MB-231 cell growth in HIIT were associated with improvements in lean and fat mass.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A program of RT or HIIT can increase levels of myokines (an effect considered beneficial given their potential cancer-suppressive effects) and inhibit growth of MDA-MB-231 cells in survivors of breast cancer. In addition, the development of the antitumor environment may be mediated by exercise-related changes in muscle strength and body composition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bettariga</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4977-5494</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taaffe</LastName><ForeName>Dennis R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crespo-Garcia</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clay</LastName><ForeName>Timothy D</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE Santi</LastName><ForeName>Mauro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomolecular Sciences, Section of Hygiene, University of Urbino Carlo Bo, Urbino, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baldelli</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomolecular Sciences, Section of Hygiene, University of Urbino Carlo Bo, Urbino, ITALY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adhikari</LastName><ForeName>Sanjeev</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gray</LastName><ForeName>Elin S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galv&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Daniel A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton</LastName><ForeName>Robert U</ForeName><Initials>RU</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015850">Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000097724">Myokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="Y">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073116" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cancer Survivors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045744" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line, Tumor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cytokines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015850" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049109" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Proliferation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000097724" MajorTopicYN="N">Myokines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BREAST CANCER</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CANCER CELL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIGH-INTENSITY INTERVAL TRAINING</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MYOKINE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RESISTANCE TRAINING</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40903011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-00899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Laversanne M, Sung H, et al. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin . 2024;74(3):229&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brewster AM, Hortobagyi GN, Broglio KR, et al. Residual risk of breast cancer recurrence 5 years after adjuvant therapy. J Natl Cancer Inst . 2008;100(16):1179&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen RN, Esen B, Mellemkj&#xe6;r L, et al. The incidence of breast cancer recurrence 10&#x2013;32 years after primary diagnosis. J Natl Cancer Inst . 2022;114(3):391&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes SC, Newton RU, Spence RR, Galv&#xe3;o DA. The Exercise and Sports Science Australia position statement: exercise medicine in cancer management. J Sci Med Sport . 2019;22(11):1175&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone KM, Wiskemann J, et al. Exercise guidelines for cancer survivors: consensus statement from international multidisciplinary roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2019;51(11):2375&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joaquim A, Le&#xe3;o I, Antunes P, et al. Impact of physical exercise programs in breast cancer survivors on health-related quality of life, physical fitness, and body composition: evidence from systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Front Oncol . 2022;12:955505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudiarasu C, Lopez P, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. What are the most effective exercise, physical activity and dietary interventions to improve body composition in women diagnosed with or at high-risk of breast cancer? A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Cancer . 2023;129(23):3697&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Taaffe DR, Crespo-Garcia C, Clay TD, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Newton RU. Effects of resistance training vs high intensity interval training on body composition, muscle strength, cardiorespiratory fitness, and quality of life in survivors of breast cancer: a randomized trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat . 2025;210(2):261&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM, Stone CR, Cheung WY, Hayes SC. Physical activity and mortality in cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JNCI Cancer Spectr . 2020;4(1):pkz080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SC, Lee IM, Weiderpass E, et al. Association of leisure-time physical activity with risk of 26 types of cancer in 1.44 million adults. JAMA Intern Med . 2016;176(6):816&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Taaffe DR, Borsati A, et al. Exercise and inflammation in female survivors of breast cancer: systematic review and meta-analysis with secondary mediation analysis on body composition. J Cancer Surviv . 2025. doi:10.1007/s11764-025-01873-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-025-01873-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Taaffe DR, Borsati AG, et al. Effects of exercise on inflammation in female survivors of nonmetastatic breast cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Natl Cancer Inst . 2025;177(10):1984&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Galvao D, Taaffe D, et al. Association of muscle strength and cardiorespiratory fitness with all-cause and cancer-specific mortality in patients diagnosed with cancer: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med . 2025;59(10):722&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Bishop C, Kim JS, Newton RU. Suppressive effects of exercise-conditioned serum on cancer cells: a narrative review of the influence of exercise mode, volume, and intensity. J Sport Health Sci . 2024;13(4):484&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Newton RU. Effects of short- and long-term exercise training on cancer cells in vitro: insights into the mechanistic associations. J Sport Health Sci . 2024;14:100994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK, Akerstr&#xf6;m TC, Nielsen AR, Fischer CP. Role of myokines in exercise and metabolism. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2007;103(3):1093&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Exercise training mode effects on myokine expression in healthy adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci . 2024;13(6):764&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Newton RU, Gray E, Taaffe DR. Exercise-induced myokines and their effect on prostate cancer. Nat Rev Urol . 2021;18(9):519&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldelli G, De Santi M, Gervasi M, et al. The effects of human sera conditioned by high-intensity exercise sessions and training on the tumorigenic potential of cancer cells. Clin Transl Oncol . 2021;23(1):22&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dethlefsen C, Lillelund C, Midtgaard J, et al. Exercise regulates breast cancer cell viability: systemic training adaptations versus acute exercise responses. Breast Cancer Res Treat . 2016;159(3):469&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devin JL, Hill MM, Mourtzakis M, Quadrilatero J, Jenkins DG, Skinner TL. Acute high intensity interval exercise reduces colon cancer cell growth. J Physiol . 2019;597(8):2177&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurgan N, Tsakiridis E, Kouvelioti R, Moore J, Klentrou P, Tsiani E. Inhibition of human lung cancer cell proliferation and survival by post-exercise serum is associated with the inhibition of Akt, mTOR, p70 S6K, and Erk1/2. Cancers (Basel) . 2017;9(5):46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J-S, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Acute effect of high-intensity interval aerobic exercise on serum myokine levels and resulting tumour-suppressive effect in trained patients with advanced prostate cancer. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2023;26(4):795&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettariga F, Taaffe DR, Crespo-Garcia C, et al. A single bout of resistance or high-intensity interval training increases anti-cancer myokines and suppresses cancer cell growth in vitro in survivors of breast cancer. Breast Cancer Res Treat . 2025;213(1):171&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes DC, Ellefsen S, Baar K. Adaptations to endurance and strength training. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med . 2018;8(6):a029769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldelli G, Natalucci V, Ferri Marini C, et al. A home-based lifestyle intervention program reduces the tumorigenic potential of triple-negative breast cancer cells. Sci Rep . 2024;14(1):2409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J-S, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Exercise in advanced prostate cancer elevates myokine levels and suppresses in-vitro cell growth. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2022;25(1):86&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Wilson RL, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Gray E, Newton RU. Myokine expression and tumor-suppressive effect of serum after 12 wk of exercise in prostate cancer patients on ADT. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2022;54(2):197&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM, Carter H. The effect of endurance training on parameters of aerobic fitness. Sports Med . 2000;29(6):373&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, Lazinica B, Krieger JW, Pedisic Z. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2018;48(5):1207&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glickman SG, Marn CS, Supiano MA, Dengel DR. Validity and reliability of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry for the assessment of abdominal adiposity. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2004;97(2):509&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Test-retest reliability of the one-repetition maximum (1RM) strength assessment: a systematic review. Sports Med Open . 2020;6(1):31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf6;rkman F, Ekblom-Bak E, Ekblom &#xd6;, Ekblom B. Validity of the revised Ekblom Bak cycle ergometer test in adults. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2016;116(9):1627&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekblom-Bak E, Bj&#xf6;rkman F, Hellenius ML, Ekblom B. A new submaximal cycle ergometer test for prediction of VO2max. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2014;24(2):319&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lea JWD, O&#x2019;Driscoll JM, Hulbert S, Scales J, Wiles JD. Convergent validity of ratings of perceived exertion during resistance exercise in healthy participants: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Open . 2022;8(1):2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herman L, Foster C, Maher M, Mikat RP, Porcari JP. Validity and reliability of the session RPE method for monitoring exercise training intensity. S Afr J Sports Med . 2006;18(1):14&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Byrnes RK, Cooke DM, et al. RPE vs. Percentage 1RM loading in periodized programs matched for sets and repetitions. Front Physiol . 2018;9:247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svensson P, Hellberg M, Zhou Y, Wis&#xe9;n A, Clyne N. The Borg scale is a sustainable method for prescribing and monitoring self-administered aerobic endurance exercise in patients with chronic kidney disease. Eur J Physiother . 2022;25:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kenfield SA, Hart NH, et al. Intense Exercise for Survival among Men with Metastatic Castrate-Resistant Prostate Cancer (INTERVAL-GAP4): a multicentre, randomised, controlled phase III study protocol. BMJ Open . 2018;8(5):e022899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences: routledge; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zunner BEM, Wachsmuth NB, Eckstein ML, et al. Myokines and resistance training: a narrative review. Int J Mol Sci . 2022;23(7):3501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juthani R, Punatar S, Mittra I. New light on chemotherapy toxicity and its prevention. BJC Rep . 2024;2(1):41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiuza-Luces C, Valenzuela PL, G&#xe1;lvez BG, et al. The effect of physical exercise on anticancer immunity. Nat Rev Immunol . 2024;24(4):282&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijbels K, Brocke S, Abrams JS, Steinman L. Administration of neutralizing antibodies to interleukin-6 (IL-6) reduces experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis and is associated with elevated levels of IL-6 bioactivity in central nervous system and circulation. Mol Med . 1995;1(7):795&#x2013;805.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>