<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">24072967</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1178-1998</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2013</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical interventions in aging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Interv Aging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sixteen weeks of resistance training can decrease the risk of metabolic syndrome in healthy postmenopausal women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1221</StartPage><EndPage>1228</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1221-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/CIA.S44245</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The postmenopausal phase has been considered an aggravating factor for developing metabolic syndrome. Notwithstanding, no studies have as yet investigated the effects of resistance training on metabolic syndrome in postmenopausal women. Thus, the purpose of this study was to verify whether resistance training could reduce the risk of metabolic syndrome in postmenopausal women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty postmenopausal women were randomly assigned to a resistance training protocol (n = 10, 53.40 &#xb1; 3.95 years, 64.58 &#xb1; 9.22 kg) or a control group (n = 10, 53.0 &#xb1; 5.7 years, 64.03 &#xb1; 5.03 kg). In the resistance training protocol, ten exercises were performed, with 3 &#xd7; 8-10 maximal repetitions three times per week, and the load was increased every week. Two-way analysis of variance was used to evaluate specific metabolic syndrome Z-score, high density lipoprotein cholesterol, fasting blood glucose, triglycerides, waist circumference, blood pressure, strength, and body composition. The level of statistical significance was set at P &lt; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The main results demonstrated a significant decrease of metabolic syndrome Z-score when the postmenopausal women performed resistance training (P = 0.0162). Moreover, we observed decreases in fasting blood glucose for the resistance training group (P = 0.001), and also significant improvements in lean body mass (P = 0.042, 2.46%), reduction of body fat percentage (P = 0.001, -6.75%) and noticeable increases in muscle strength after resistance training to leg press (P = 0.004, 41.29%) and bench press (P = 0.0001, 27.23%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It was concluded that resistance training performed three times a week may reduce the metabolic syndrome Z-score with concomitant decreases in fasting blood glucose, improvements in body composition, and muscle strength in postmenopausal women.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Miguel Soares</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Laboratory, School of Physical Education, State University of Campinas, Campinas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonganha</LastName><ForeName>Val&#xe9;ria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vechin</LastName><ForeName>Felipe Cassaro</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berton</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo Paes de Barros</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lixandr&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Manoel Em&#xed;lio</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nogueira</LastName><ForeName>Felipe Romano Damas</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Souza</LastName><ForeName>Giovana Verg&#xed;nia</ForeName><Initials>GV</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chacon-Mikahil</LastName><ForeName>Mara Patricia Traina</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton Augusto</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Interv Aging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101273480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1176-9092</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000886" MajorTopicYN="N">Anthropometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001938" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Brazil</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postmenopause</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040242" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Reduction Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postmenopausal women</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24072967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3783540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S44245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">cia-8-1221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dutra ES, de Carvalho KM, Miyazaki E, Hamann EM, Ito MK. Metabolic syndrome in central Brazil: prevalence and correlates in the adult population. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2012;4:20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3457864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22583910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Expert Panel on Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Cholesterol in Adults Executive Summary of the Third Report of the National Cholesterol Education Program (NCEP) Expert Panel on Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Cholesterol in Adults (Adult Treatment Panel III) JAMA. 2001;285:2486&#x2013;2497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11368702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornier MA, Dabelea D, Hernandez TL, et al. The metabolic syndrome. Endocr Rev. 2008;29:777&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18971485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer CP, Godsland IF, Stevenson JC. Is there a menopausal metabolic syndrome? Gynecol Endocrinol. 1997;11:341&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9385535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douchi T, Yamamoto S, Nakamura S, et al. The effect of menopause on regional and total body lean mass. Maturitas. 1998;29:247&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9699196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douchi T, Yamamoto S, Yoshimitsu N, Andoh T, Matsuo T, Nagata Y. Relative contribution of aging and menopause to changes in lean and fat mass in segmental regions. Maturitas. 2002;42:301&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12191853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley CJ, Lees B, Stevenson JC. Sex- and menopause-associated changes in body-fat distribution. Am J Clin Nutr. 1992;55:950&#x2013;954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1570802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svendsen OL, Hassager C, Christiansen C. Age- and menopause-associated variations in body composition and fat distribution in healthy women as measured by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry. Metabolism. 1995;44:369&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7885283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toth MJ, Tchernof A, Sites CK, Poehlman ET. Effect of menopausal status on body composition and abdominal fat distribution. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2000;24:226&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10702775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tr&#xe9;mollieres FA, Pouilles JM, Ribot CA. Relative influence of age and menopause on total and regional body composition changes in postmenopausal women. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1996;175:1594&#x2013;1600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8987946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr MC. The emergence of the metabolic syndrome with menopause. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003;88:2404&#x2013;2411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12788835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans EM, Van Pelt RE, Binder EF, Williams DB, Ehsani AA, Kohrt WM. Effects of HRT and exercise training on insulin action, glucose tolerance, and body composition in older women. J Appl Physiol. 2001;90:2033&#x2013;2040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11356762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gohlke-Barwolf C. Coronary artery disease &#x2013; is menopause a risk factor? Basic Res Cardiol. 2000;95(Suppl 1):I77&#x2013;I83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11192358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuller LH, Simkin-Silverman LR, Wing RR, Meilahn EN, Ives DG. Women&#x2019;s Healthy Lifestyle Project: a randomized clinical trial: results at 54 months. Circulation. 2001;103:32&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11136682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simkin-Silverman L, Wing RR, Hansen DH, et al. Prevention of cardiovascular risk factor elevations in healthy premenopausal women. Prev Med. 1995;24:509&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8524727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss JM, Carlson SH. Effects of hormone replacement therapy on the sympathetic nervous system and blood pressure. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2003;5:241&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12724057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho GJ, Lee JH, Park HT, et al. Postmenopausal status according to years since menopause as an independent risk factor for the metabolic syndrome. Menopause. 2008;15:524&#x2013;529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18467953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asikainen TM, Suni JH, Pasanen ME, et al. Effect of brisk walking in 1 or 2 daily bouts and moderate resistance training on lower-extremity muscle strength, balance, and walking performance in women who recently went through menopause: a randomized, controlled trial. Phys Ther. 2006;86:912&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16813472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gami AS, Witt BJ, Howard DE, et al. Metabolic syndrome and risk of incident cardiovascular events and death: a systematic review and meta-analysis of longitudinal studies. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007;49:403&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17258085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, McCarthy JP, Bamman MM. Effects of resistance training on older adults. Sports Med. 2004;34:329&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakka HM, Laaksonen DE, Lakka TA, et al. The metabolic syndrome and total and cardiovascular disease mortality in middle-aged men. JAMA. 2002;288:2709&#x2013;2716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12460094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Siebert U, Schobersberger W. Resistance training in the treatment of the metabolic syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of resistance training on metabolic clustering in patients with abnormal glucose metabolism. Sports Med. 2010;40:397&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20433212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR, et al. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1423&#x2013;1434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park MS, Chung SY, Chang Y, Kim K. Physical activity and physical fitness as predictors of all-cause mortality in Korean men. J Korean Med Sci. 2009;24:13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2650993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19270807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JL, Slentz CA, Houmard JA, et al. Exercise training amount and intensity effects on metabolic syndrome (from Studies of a Targeted Risk Reduction Intervention through Defined Exercise) Am J Cardiol. 2007;100:1759&#x2013;1766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2190779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18082522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzmarzyk PT, Leon AS, Wilmore JH, et al. Targeting the metabolic syndrome with exercise: evidence from the HERITAGE Family Study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:1703&#x2013;1709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14523308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman LA, Slentz CA, Willis LH, et al. Comparison of aerobic versus resistance exercise training effects on metabolic syndrome (from the Studies of a Targeted Risk Reduction Intervention Through Defined Exercise &#x2013; STRRIDE-AT/RT) Am J Cardiol. 2011;108:838&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3752599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21741606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, Souza GV, G&#xe1;spari AF, et al. Effects of concurrent training on interleukin-6, tumour necrosis factor-alpha and C-reactive protein in middle-aged men. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:1573&#x2013;1581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21933039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsatti FL, Nahas EA, Maesta N, Nahas-Neto J, Burini RC. Plasma hormones, muscle mass and strength in resistance-trained postmenopausal women. Maturitas. 2008;59:394&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18499368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augusto Libardi C, Bonganha V, Soares Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o M, et al. The periodized resistance training promotes similar changes in lipid profile in middle-aged men and women. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2012;52:286&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22648467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treuth MS, Hunter GR, Kekes-Szabo T, Weinsier RL, Goran MI, Berland L. Reduction in intra-abdominal adipose tissue after strength training in older women. J Appl Physiol. 1995;78:1425&#x2013;1431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7615451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florindo AA, et al. [Validation and reliability of the Baecke questionnaire for the evaluation of habitual physical activity in adult men] Valida&#xe7;&#xe3;o e reprodutibilidade do question&#xe1;rio de Baecke de avalia&#xe7;&#xe3;o da atividade f&#xed;sica habitual em homens adultos. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2003;9:121&#x2013;128. Portuguese.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML, Ward A. Generalized equations for predicting body density of women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1980;12:175&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7402053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. Body composition from fluid spaces and density: analysis of methods. 1961. Nutrition. 1993;9:480&#x2013;491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8286893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, O&#x2019;Bryant H, Garhammer J. A hypothetical model for strength training. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1981;21:342&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7339218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88:50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurca R, Lamonte MJ, Barlow CE, Kampert JB, Church TS, Blair SN. Association of muscular strength with incidence of metabolic syndrome in men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1849&#x2013;1855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16286852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijndaele K, Duvigneaud N, Matton L, et al. Muscular strength, aerobic fitness, and metabolic syndrome risk in Flemish adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:233&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternfeld B, Bhat AK, Wang H, Sharp T, Quesenberry CP., Jr Menopause, physical activity, and body composition/fat distribution in midlife women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1195&#x2013;1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16015138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston AP, De Lisio M, Parise G. Resistance training, sarcopenia, and the mitochondrial theory of aging. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33:191&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18347672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, McManus C, Smith J, Stevens V, Nixon DW. Anthropometric measurement of muscle mass: revised equations for calculating bone-free arm muscle area. Am J Clin Nutr. 1982;36:680&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7124671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapik JJ, Staab JS, Harman EA. Validity of an anthropometric estimate of thigh muscle cross-sectional area. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:1523&#x2013;1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8970148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holten MK, Zacho M, Gaster M, Juel C, Wojtaszewski JF, Dela F. Strength training increases insulin-mediated glucose uptake, GLUT4 content, and insulin signaling in skeletal muscle in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2004;53:294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattyn N, Cornelissen VA, Eshghi SR, Vanhees L. The effect of exercise on the cardiovascular risk factors constituting the metabolic syndrome: a meta-analysis of controlled trials. Sports Med. 2013;43:121&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3693431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23329606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potteiger JA, Claytor RP, Hulver MW, et al. Resistance exercise and aerobic exercise when paired with dietary energy restriction both reduce the clinical components of metabolic syndrome in previously physically inactive males. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:2035&#x2013;2044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>