<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30908365</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Different Weekly Sets-Equated Resistance Training Frequencies on Muscular Strength, Muscle Mass, and Body Fat in Older Women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2990</StartPage><EndPage>2995</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2990-2995</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003130</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pina, FLC, Nunes, JP, Schoenfeld, BJ, Nascimento, MA, Gerage, AM, Janu&#xe1;rio, RSB, Carneiro, NH, Cyrino, ES, and Oliveira, AR. Effects of different weekly sets-equated resistance training frequencies on muscular strength, muscle mass and body fat in older women. J Strength Cond Res 34(10): 2990-2995, 2020-The aim of this study was to analyze the effects of different resistance training (RT) frequencies (2 vs. 3 times per week) with an equivalent number of weekly sets performed between conditions on muscular strength and body composition in older women. Forty-seven older women (65 &#xb1; 4 years) were divided into 2 groups that performed a 12-week RT program either 2 (G2x and 3 sets) or 3 (G3x and 2 sets) times per week. The groups were evaluated before and after study on measures of body composition through dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry, and muscular strength through one repetition maximum (1RM) testing. Lean soft tissue was significantly increased in both groups (G2x = +1.7%, G3x = +1.7%), while only G3x reduced body fat after the intervention period (G2x = -0.7%, G3x = -2.9%). Similarly, significant increases were noted between conditions for 1RM scores in bench press (G2x = +11.8%, G3x = +11.9%) and knee extension (G2x = +17.4%, G3x = +10.8%). The results indicate that performing 2 or 3 RT sessions per week promotes similar improvements in muscular outcomes, while training more frequently may reduce body fat after 12 weeks of weekly sets-equated RT in untrained older women.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pina</LastName><ForeName>F&#xe1;bio L C</ForeName><Initials>FLC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, University of Northern Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Lehman College, Bronx, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nascimento</LastName><ForeName>Matheus A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paran&#xe1; State University, Paranava&#xed; Campus, Paranava&#xed;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerage</LastName><ForeName>Aline M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Sports, Federal University of Santa Catarina, Florian&#xf3;polis, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janu&#xe1;rio</LastName><ForeName>Renata S B</ForeName><Initials>RSB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, University of Northern Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carneiro</LastName><ForeName>Nelson H</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Arli R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015502" MajorTopicYN="N">Absorptiometry, Photon</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30908365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202010000-00034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM. American College of Sports Medicine Position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM. American College of Sports Medicine Position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Fontes-Villalba M, Santos-Concejero J. Total number of sets as a training volume quantification method for muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 2018. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borde R, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U. Dose-response relationships of resistance training in healthy old adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 45: 1693&#x2013;1720, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckinx F, Landi F, Cesari M, Fielding RA, Visser M, Engelke K, et al. Pitfalls in the measurement of muscle mass: A need for a reference standard. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 9: 269&#x2013;278, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM. Functional consequences of sarcopenia and dynapenia in the elderly. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 13: 271&#x2013;276, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The T-Test for Means. In: 2nd, ed. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, MI: Routledge, 1988. pp. 19&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csapo R, Alegre LM. Effects of resistance training with moderate vs heavy loads on muscle mass and strength in the elderly: A meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 26: 995&#x2013;1006, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha PM, Nunes JP, Tomeleri CM, Nascimento MA, Schoenfeld BJ, Antunes M, et al. Resistance training performed with single- and multiple-sets induces similar improvements in muscular strength, muscle mass, muscle quality, and IGF-1 in older women: A randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 2018. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Loenneke JP, Loprinzi PD. Dose-dependent association between muscle-strengthening activities and all-cause mortality: Prospective cohort study among a national sample of adults in the USA. Arch Cardiovasc Dis 109: 626&#x2013;633, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Counts BR, et al. Frequency: The overlooked resistance training variable for inducing muscle hypertrophy? Sport Med 47: 799&#x2013;805, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Dreyer HC, Pennings B, Fry CS, Dhanani S, Dillon EL, Sheffield-Moore M, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Skeletal muscle protein anabolic response to resistance exercise and essential amino acids is delayed with aging. J Appl Physiol 104: 1452&#x2013;1461, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WJ. Skeletal muscle loss: Cachexia, sarcopenia, and inactivity. Am J Clin Nutr 91: 1123S&#x2013;1127S, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti PTV, Geraldes AAR, Bottaro MF, Lima MVIC, Albuquerque RB, Fleck SJ. Effects of different resistance training frequencies on the muscle strength and functional performance of active women older than 60 years. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2225&#x2013;2234, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Lezaun E, Schumann M, M&#xe4;kinen T, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Walker S. Effects of resistance training frequency on cardiorespiratory fitness in older men and women during intervention and follow-up. Exp Gerontol 95: 44&#x2013;53, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Steele J, Smith D. Evidence-based resistance training recommendations for muscular hypertrophy. Med Sport 17: 217&#x2013;235, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, Lazinica B, Krieger JW, Pedisic Z. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 1207&#x2013;1220, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lera-Orsatti F, Nahas EAP, Maest&#xe1; N, Nahas Neto J, Lera-Orsatti C, Vannucchi Portari G, et al. Effects of resistance training frequency on body composition and metabolics and inflammatory markers in overweight postmenopausal women. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 54: 317&#x2013;325, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Cyrino ES. Comment on: &#x201c;Comparison of periodized and non-periodized resistance training on maximal strength: A meta-analysis&#x201d;. Sport Med 48: 491&#x2013;494, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Ribeiro AS, Silva AM, Schoenfeld BJ, dos Santos L, Cunha PM, et al. Improvements in phase angle are related with muscle quality index after resistance training in older women. J Aging Phys Act 2018. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilha CS, Ribeiro AS, Fleck SJ, Nascimento MA, Pina FLC, Okino AM, et al. Effect of resistance training with different frequencies and detraining on muscular strength and oxidative stress biomarkers in older women. Age (Dordr) 37: 104, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Sen A, Gordon PM. Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: A meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 249&#x2013;258, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger JW. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci 2018. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- versus high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra R, Saavedra F, Jotta B, Novaes J, Cardozo D, Alves H, et al. The influence weekly resistance training frequency on strength and body composition. Int J Sport Sci 8: 19&#x2013;24, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Duret C, Wheeler S, Marcus R. Once-weekly resistance exercise improves muscle strength and neuromuscular performance in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc 47: 1208&#x2013;1214, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomeleri CM, Souza MF, Burini RC, Cavaglieri CR, Ribeiro AS, Antunes M, et al. Resistance training reduces metabolic syndrome and inflammatory markers in older women: A randomized controlled trial. J Diabetes 10: 328&#x2013;337, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turpela M, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Haff GG, Walker S. Effects of different strength training frequencies on maximum strength, body composition and functional capacity in healthy older individuals. Exp Gerontol 98: 13&#x2013;21, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: Effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep 11: 209&#x2013;216, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Stewart KJ. Impact of strength and resistance training on cardiovascular disease risk factors and outcomes in older adults. Clin Geriatr Med 25: 703&#x2013;714, 2009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>