<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37967946</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1347-4715</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental health and preventive medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Health Prev Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute and chronic functional and traditional resistance training improve muscular fitness in young males via the AMPK/PGC-1&#x3b1;/irisin signaling pathway.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>69</StartPage><MedlinePgn>69</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">69</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1265/ehpm.23-00146</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In this study, we aimed to investigate the effects of acute and chronic resistance training of varying intensities on molecular responses and their association with muscular fitness in a cohort of young males who participated in this intervention study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Young males (19-28 years) with no prior training experience underwent a six-week program consisting of two distinct modalities of resistance training. The participants were randomly divided into a functional resistance training group (FRT; n = 9; participants performed 4-5 sets of 20 repetitions maximum (RM) at 40% 1RM) or a traditional resistance training group (TRT; n = 9; participants performed 4-5 sets of 12 RM at 70% 1RM). Both protocols entailed training three days per week for six weeks. Blood samples were obtained before, immediately after an acute bout of training, and after the six-week training program to determine alterations in molecular responses. Muscular fitness analysis and anthropometric measurements were conducted before and after the six-week training program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After the six-week training program, the lean body mass of participants in both TRT and FRT groups was significantly increased (p &lt; 0.05), whereas body fat percentage and fat mass were significantly decreased solely in the FRT group (p &lt; 0.05). All muscular fitness variables were significantly increased in both groups (p &lt; 0.01), with no difference between the two groups. Additionally, in the TRT group, serum levels of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) were significantly increased following acute training and six weeks of resistance training, whereas in the FRT group, no significant increase in serum levels of AMPK was observed. In both groups, serum levels of peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-&#x3b3; coactivator-1&#x3b1; (PGC-1&#x3b1;), irisin, and insulin-like growth factor-1 were significantly increased. Moreover, myostatin was significantly decreased following acute training and six weeks of resistance training (p &lt; 0.05), with no difference between the two groups. Furthermore, a significant correlation was observed between barbell back squat and certain molecular variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Overall, our study indicates that acute and chronic resistance training of varying intensities are effective changing molecular responses, the chronic FRT and TRT improve muscular fitness in young males through the AMPK/PGC-1&#x3b1;/irisin signaling pathway.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chinese Clinical Trial Registry: ChiCTR2200059775 (11/05/2022).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Chongwen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Air Force Medical Center of Chinese PLA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tianjin University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Chaoqun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Air Force Medical Center of Chinese PLA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Air Force Medical Center of Chinese PLA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Sports University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bo</LastName><ForeName>Shumin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education and Sports.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Health Prev Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1342-078X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.31</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D055372">AMP-Activated Protein Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005353">Fibronectins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055372" MajorTopicYN="N">AMP-Activated Protein Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005353" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibronectins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AMPK</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Irisin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscular fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PGC-1&#x3b1;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37967946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10654215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1265/ehpm.23-00146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Conley MS, Rozenek R. National Strength and Conditioning Association Position Statement. J Strength Cond. 2001;23:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakicic JM, Clark K, Coleman E, Donnelly JE, Foreyt J, Melanson E, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Appropriate intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:2145&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:1451&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel BM, Zierath JR. The Limits of Exercise Physiology: From Performance to Health. Cell Metab. 2017;25:1000&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, Skelly LE, Gibala MJ. CrossTalk proposal: Exercise training intensity is more important than volume to promote increases in human skeletal muscle mitochondrial content. J Physiol. 2019;597:4111&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31309577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soligon SD. Suspension training vs. traditional resistance training: effects on muscle mass, strength and functional performance in older adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo C, Bo S, Wang T, Zhang W. Functional and Traditional Resistance Training Are Equally Effective in Increasing Upper and Lower Limb Muscular Endurance and Performance Variables in Untrained Young Men. Front Physiol. 2022;13:868195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9471151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36117686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little JP, Safdar A, Wilkin GP, Tarnopolsky MA, Gibala MJ. A practical model of low-volume high-intensity interval training induces mitochondrial biogenesis in human skeletal muscle: potential mechanisms. J Physiol. 2010;588:1011&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2849965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20100740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia JC, Ferreira DMS, Ruas JL. Intercellular: local and systemic actions of skeletal muscle PGC-1s. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2015;26:305&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25934582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morash AJ, Vanderveken M, McClelland GB. Muscle metabolic remodeling in response to endurance exercise in salmonids. Front Physiol. 2014;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4240067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25484869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winder WW, Hardie DG. Inactivation of acetyl-CoA carboxylase and activation of AMP-activated protein kinase in muscle during exercise. Am J Physiol. 1996;270:E299&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8779952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardie DG. AMP-activated/SNF1 protein kinases: conserved guardians of cellular energy. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2007;8:774&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman NJ, Parker BL, Chaudhuri R, Fisher-Wellman KH, Kleinert M, Humphrey SJ, et al. Global Phosphoproteomic Analysis of Human Skeletal Muscle Reveals a Network of Exercise-Regulated Kinases and AMPK Substrates. Cell Metab. 2015;22:922&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4635038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26437602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabinovitch RC, Samborska B, Faubert B, Ma EH, Gravel SP, Andrzejewski S, et al. AMPK Maintains Cellular Metabolic Homeostasis through Regulation of Mitochondrial Reactive Oxygen Species. Cell Reports. 2017;21:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28978464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostr&#xf6;m P, Wu J, Jedrychowski MP, Korde A, Ye L, Lo JC, et al. A PGC1-&#x3b1;-dependent myokine that drives brown-fat-like development of white fat and thermogenesis. Nature. 2012;481:463&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3522098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22237023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Pan J. Irisin ameliorates depressive-like behaviors in rats by regulating energy metabolism. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2016;474:22&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27079240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Bostr&#xf6;m P, Sparks LM, Ye L, Choi JH, Giang AH, et al. Beige Adipocytes Are a Distinct Type of Thermogenic Fat Cell in Mouse and Human. Cell. 2012;150:366&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3402601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson HP. Irisin and FNDC5 in retrospect: An exercise hormone or a transmembrane receptor? Adipocyte. 2013;2:289&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3774709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24052909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC. The Role of Resistance Exercise Intensity on Muscle Fibre Adaptations. Sports Med. 2004;34:663&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15335243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA. Skeletal muscle adaptations consequent to long-term heavy resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20:S132&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3057312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter C, Reidy PT, Bhattarai N, Sidossis LS, Rasmussen BB. Resistance Exercise Training Alters Mitochondrial Function in Human Skeletal Muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47:1922&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4478283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25539479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvadego D, Domenis R, Lazzer S, Porcelli S, Rittweger J, Rizzo G, et al. Skeletal muscle oxidative function in vivo and ex vivo in athletes with marked hypertrophy from resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2013;114:1527&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23519233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya Y, Ando D, Takamatsu K, Goto K. Resistance exercise induces a greater irisin response than endurance exercise. Metabolism. 2015;64:1042&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26081427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Guo C, Liu S, Zhang S, Mao Y, Fang L. Eight Weeks of High-Intensity Interval Static Strength Training Improves Skeletal Muscle Atrophy and Motor Function in Aged Rats via the PGC-1&#x3b1;/FNDC5/UCP1 Pathway. Clin Interv Aging. 2021;16:811&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34040358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safdar A, Little JP, Stokl AJ, Hettinga BP, Akhtar M, Tarnopolsky MA. Exercise Increases Mitochondrial PGC-1&#x3b1; Content and Promotes Nuclear-Mitochondrial Cross-talk to Coordinate Mitochondrial Biogenesis. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:10605&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21245132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huh JY, Dincer F, Mesfum E, Mantzoros CS. Irisin stimulates muscle growth-related genes and regulates adipocyte differentiation and metabolism in humans. Int J Obes. 2014;38:1538&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24614098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG. Is irisin the new player in exercise-induced adaptations or not? A 2017 update. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2018;56:525&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29127759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37:145&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Feigenbaum MS, Franklin BA. Prescription of resistance training for healthy populations. Sports Med. 2001;31:953&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fragala MS. Personalize It: Program Design in Resistance Training. ACSM&#x2019;s Health Fit J. 2006;10:7&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neufer PD, Bamman MM, Muoio DM, Bouchard C, Cooper DM, Goodpaster BH, et al. Understanding the Cellular and Molecular Mechanisms of Physical Activity-Induced Health Benefits. Cell Metab. 2015;22:4&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26073496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo C, Bo S, Li Q, Zhang L. The Effect of Whole-Body Traditional and Functional Resistance Training on CAVI and Its Association With Muscular Fitness in Untrained Young Men. Front Physiol. 2022;13:888048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35694401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyatani M, Yang P, Thomas S, Craven BC, Oh P. Bioelectrical impedance and dual-energy X-Ray absorptiometry assessments of changes in body composition following exercise in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Obes. 2012;2012:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3457637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23029604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Damirchi A, Asadi A. Age-related hormonal adaptations, muscle circumference and strength development with 8 weeks moderate intensity resistance training. Ann Endocrinol (Paris). 2013;74:30&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23337018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine, Riebe D, Ehrman JK, Liguori G, Magal M, editors. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Tenth edition. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Asadi A, Roohi S. Enhancing muscular performance in women: compound versus complex, traditional resistance and plyometric training alone. J Musculoskelet Res. 2014;17:1450007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112:155&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiatarone MA. High-Intensity Strength Training in Nonagenarians: Effects on Skeletal Muscle. JAMA. 1990;263:3029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2342214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo C, Li Q, Zhang L, Bo S. Effects of 6-Week Traditional and Functional Resistance Training on Arterial Stiffness and Muscular Strength in Healthy Young Men. Front Physiol. 2022;13:859402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8924443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally KM, Cordero J, Good J, Brown DD, McCaw ST. Physiologic and metabolic responses to a continuous functional resistance exercise workout. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:373&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19197213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huh JY, Mougios V, Skraparlis A, Kabasakalis A, Mantzoros CS. Irisin in response to acute and chronic whole-body vibration exercise in humans. Metabolism. 2014;63:918&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24814685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Lee HJ, So B, Son JS, Yoon D, Song W. Effect of Aerobic Training and Resistance Training on Circulating Irisin Level and Their Association With Change of Body Composition in Overweight/Obese Adults: a Pilot Study. Physiol Res. 2016;271&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26447516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mat&#xe9;-Mu&#xf1;oz JL, Monroy AJA, Jodra Jim&#xe9;nez P, Garnacho-Casta&#xf1;o MV. Effects of instability versus traditional resistance training on strength, power and velocity in untrained men. J Sports Sci Med. 2014;13:460&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25177170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson K, Behm DG. Trunk muscle activity increases with unstable squat movements. Can J Appl Physiol. 2005;30:33&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asanuma H, Pavlides C. Neurobiological basis of motor learning in mammals. Neuroreport. 1997;8:R1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9141042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D. Effects of Low- vs. High-Load Resistance Training on Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy in Well-Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:2954&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzig S, Shaw RJ. AMPK: guardian of metabolism and mitochondrial homeostasis. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2018;19:121&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5780224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28974774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger S, Handschin C, St.-Pierre J, Spiegelman BM. AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) action in skeletal muscle via direct phosphorylation of PGC-1&#x3b1;. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2007;104:12017&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1924552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadalupe-Grau A, Rodr&#xed;guez-Garc&#xed;a L, Torres-Peralta R, Morales-&#xc1;lamo D, Ponce-Gonz&#xe1;lez JG, P&#xe9;rez-Suarez I, et al. Greater basal skeletal muscle AMPK&#x3b1; phosphorylation in men than in women: Associations with anaerobic performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16:455&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26305090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponce-Gonz&#xe1;lez JG, Ara I, Larsen S, Guerra B, Calbet JAL, Helge JW. Effect of regional muscle location but not adiposity on mitochondrial biogenesis-regulating proteins. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:11&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26269447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Zhu Y, Zeng F. Influence on Ratio of AMP/ATP and AMPK Activity in Rat&#x2019;s Skeletal Muscle by Different Exercise Intensity. China Sport Science and Technology. 2008;44:19&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Fujita S, Cadenas JG, Chinkes DL, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Resistance exercise increases AMPK activity and reduces 4E-BP1 phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle: AMPK, muscle protein synthesis and resistance exercise. J Physiol. 2006;576:613&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1890364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen BB, Winder WW. Effect of exercise intensity on skeletal muscle malonyl-CoA and acetyl-CoA carboxylase. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:1104&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9338417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtaszewski JF, Nielsen P, Hansen BF, Richter EA, Kiens B. Isoform-specific and exercise intensity-dependent activation of 5&#x2032;-AMP-activated protein kinase in human skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2000;528(Pt 1):221&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11018120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessen N, Pold R, Buhl ES, Jensen LS, Schmitz O, Lund S. Effects of AICAR and exercise on insulin-stimulated glucose uptake, signaling, and GLUT-4 content in rat muscles. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2003;94:1373&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12496137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooshmand-Moghadam B, Eskandari M, Golestani F, Rezae S, Mahmoudi N, Gaeini AA. The effect of 12-week resistance exercise training on serum levels of cellular aging process parameters in elderly men. Exp Gerontol. 2020;141:111090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32919015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobina T, Yoshioka K, Hirata A, Mori S, Kiyonaga A, Tanaka H. Peroxisomal proliferator-activated receptor gamma co-activator-1 alpha gene expression increases above the lactate threshold in human skeletal muscle. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2011;51:683&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22212273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Uguccioni G, Ljubicic V, Irrcher I, Iqbal S, Singh K, et al. Multiple signaling pathways regulate contractile activity-mediated PGC-1 &#x3b1; gene expression and activity in skeletal muscle cells. Physiol Rep. 2014;2:e12008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4098736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24843073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aschenbach WG, Sakamoto K, Goodyear LJ. 5&#x2032; adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase, metabolism and exercise. Sports Med. 2004;34:91&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14965188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin S, Kuloglu T, Aydin S, Kalayci M, Yilmaz M, Cakmak T, et al. A comprehensive immunohistochemical examination of the distribution of the fat-burning protein irisin in biological tissues. Peptides. 2014;61:130&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25261800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pekkala S, Wiklund PK, Hulmi JJ, Ahtiainen JP, Horttanainen M, P&#xf6;ll&#xe4;nen E, et al. Are skeletal muscle <i>FNDC5</i> gene expression and irisin release regulated by exercise and related to health?: FNDC5, irisin and exercise. J Physiol. 2013;591:5393&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3936375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24000180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W, Ju L, Wu J, Weng X. A new myokine-Irisin and exercise. J Guangzhou Sport Univ. 2016;36:87&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Fontana B, Reyes-Garc&#xed;a R, Morales-Santana S, &#xc1;vila-Rubio V, Mu&#xf1;oz-Garach A, Rozas-Moreno P, et al. Relationship between myostatin and irisin in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a compensatory mechanism to an unfavourable metabolic state? Endocrine. 2016;52:54&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26438394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hee Park K, Zaichenko L, Brinkoetter M, Thakkar B, Sahin-Efe A, Joung KE, et al. Circulating Irisin in Relation to Insulin Resistance and the Metabolic Syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;98:4899&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3849667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24057291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Dyar KA, Ciciliot S, Blaauw B, Sandri M. Mechanisms regulating skeletal muscle growth and atrophy. FEBS J. 2013;280:4294&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23517348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi C, Toyoda H, Ogata S, Okano T, Mashino S. Long-term participation in community-based group resistance exercises delays the transition from robustness to frailty in older adults: a retrospective cohort study. Environ Health Prev Med. 2021;26:105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8529757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34670491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>