<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30273288</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance Training Improves a Cellular Health Parameter in Obese Older Women: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2996</StartPage><EndPage>3002</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2996-3002</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002773</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ribeiro, AS, Schoenfeld, BJ, dos Santos, L, Nunes, JP, Tomeleri, CM, Cunha, PM, Sardinha, LB, and Cyrino, ES. Resistance training improves a cellular health parameter in obese older women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 34(10): 2996-3002, 2020-Phase angle (PhA) is a viable indicator of cellular health, with higher values reflecting better cellularity, cell membrane integrity, and cell function. Adaptive responses to resistance training (RT) on PhA may be important in obese older people. The main purpose of the present study was to investigate the effects of 8 weeks of RT on PhA in obese older women. Thirty-three obese older women (68.1 &#xb1; 5.7 years, 71.6 &#xb1; 10.1 kg, 154.5 &#xb1; 6.7 cm, 30.0 &#xb1; 4.1 kg&#xb7;m, and 45.0 &#xb1; 6.0% body fat) were randomly allocated into 1 of 2 groups: a training group that performed the RT program (TG, n = 18) or a nonexercise control group (CG, n = 15). The whole-body RT consisted of an 8-week RT program involving 8 exercises performed for 3 sets of 8-12 repetitions 3 times a week. Anthropometric, body fat and fat-free mass, PhA, total body water (TBW), intracellular water (ICW), and extracellular water compartments were performed at before and after training. After the intervention period, the TG presented greater increases (p &lt; 0.05) than CG for fat-free mass (TG = +1.3% and CG = -0.3%), TBW (TG = +2.0% and CG = -1.7%), ICW (TG = +3.1% and CG = -1.9%), and PhA (TG = +3.4% and CG = -1.4%), and lower values for percentage of body fat (TG = -1.3% and CG = +0.9%) and bioimpedance resistance (TG = -4.6% and CG = +2.3%). Our results suggest that 8 weeks of RT improves PhA-a cellular health parameter-in obese older women.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, University of Northern Parana, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science Department, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, New York, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dos Santos</LastName><ForeName>Leandro</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomeleri</LastName><ForeName>Crisieli M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cunha</LastName><ForeName>Paolo M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sardinha</LastName><ForeName>Luis B</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Health Laboratory, CIPER, Faculty of Human Kinetics, University of Lisbon, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000886" MajorTopicYN="N">Anthropometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001834" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202010000-00035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bales CW, Buhr G. Is obesity bad for older persons? A systematic review of the pros and cons of weight reduction in later life. J Am Med Direct Assoc 9: 302&#x2013;312, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa-Silva MC, Barros AJ, Post CL, Waitzberg DL, Heymsfield SB. Can bioelectrical impedance analysis identify malnutrition in preoperative nutrition assessment? Nutrition 19: 422&#x2013;426, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beberashvili I, Azar A, Sinuani I, Shapiro G, Feldman L, Stav K, et al. Bioimpedance phase angle predicts muscle function, quality of life and clinical outcome in maintenance hemodialysis patients. Eur J Clin Nutr 68: 683&#x2013;689, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosy-Westphal A, Danielzik S, Dorhofer RP, Later W, Wiese S, Muller MJ. Phase angle from bioelectrical impedance analysis: Population reference values by age, sex, and body mass index. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr 30: 309&#x2013;316, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RE, Kuk JL. Consequences of obesity and weight loss: A devil's advocate position. Obes Rev 16: 77&#x2013;87, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buffa R, Floris G, Marini E. Migration of the bioelectrical impedance vector in healthy elderly subjects. Nutrition 19: 917&#x2013;921, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JA. Power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lorenzo A, Andreoli A, Matthie J, Withers P. Predicting body cell mass with bioimpedance by using theoretical methods: A technological review. J Appl Physiol 82: 1542&#x2013;1558, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deurenberg P. Limitations of the bioelectrical impedance method for the assessment of body fat in severe obesity. Am J Clin Nutr 64: 449S&#x2013;452S, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>dos Santos L, Cyrino ES, Antunes M, Santos DA, Sardinha LB. Changes in phase angle and body composition induced by resistance training in older women. Eur J Clin Nutr 70: 1408&#x2013;1413, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda DH, Stout JR, Moon JR, Smith-Ryan AE, Kendall KL, Hoffman JR. Effects of resistance training on classic and specific bioelectrical impedance vector analysis in elderly women. Exp Gerontol 74: 9&#x2013;12, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, Franklin BA, Lamonte MJ, Lee IM, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukaski HC, Kyle UG, Kondrup J. Assessment of adult malnutrition and prognosis with bioelectrical impedance analysis: Phase angle and impedance ratio. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 20: 330&#x2013;339, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, Stobaus N, Pirlich M, Bosy-Westphal A. Bioelectrical phase angle and impedance vector analysis&#x2013;clinical relevance and applicability of impedance parameters. Clin Nutr 31: 854&#x2013;861, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, Wirth R, Neubauer M, Eckardt R, Stobaus N. The bioimpedance phase angle predicts low muscle strength, impaired quality of life, and increased mortality in old patients with cancer. J Am Med Dir Assoc 16: 173 e117&#x2013;122, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccoli A, Pastori G. BIVA Software 2002. Padova, Italy: Department of Medical and Surgical Sciences, University of Padova, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Avelar A, Dos Santos L, Silva AM, Gobbo LA, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Hypertrophy-type resistance training improves phase angle in young adult men and women. Int J Sports Med 38: 35&#x2013;40, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Souza MF, Tomeleri CM, Silva AM, Teixeira DC, et al. Resistance training prescription with different load-management methods improves phase angle in older women. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 913&#x2013;921, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saragat B, Buffa R, Mereu E, De Rui M, Coin A, Sergi G, et al. Specific bioelectrical impedance vector reference values for assessing body composition in the Italian elderly. Exp Gerontol 50: 52&#x2013;56, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardinha LB, Cyrino ES, Santos LD, Ekelund U, Santos DA. Fitness but not weight status is associated with projected physical independence in older adults. Age 38: 54, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardinha LB, Lohman TG, Teixeira PJ, Guedes DP, Going SB. Comparison of air displacement plethysmography with dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry and 3 field methods for estimating body composition in middle-aged men. Am J Clin Nutr 68: 786&#x2013;793, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza MF, Tomeleri CM, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva AM, Sardinha LB, et al. Effect of resistance training on phase angle in older women: A randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 1308&#x2013;1316, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stobaus N, Pirlich M, Valentini L, Schulzke JD, Norman K. Determinants of bioelectrical phase angle in disease. Br J Nutr 107: 1217&#x2013;1220, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilg H, Moschen AR. Adipocytokines: Mediators linking adipose tissue, inflammation and immunity. Nat Rev Immunol 6: 772&#x2013;783, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomeleri CM, Cavaglieri CR, de Souza MF, Cavalcante EF, Antunes M, Nabbuco HCG, et al. Phase angle is related with inflammatory and oxidative stress biomarkers in older women. Exp Gerontol 102: 12&#x2013;18, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomeleri CM, Cavalcante EF, Antunes M, Nabuco HCG, de Souza MF, Teixeira DC, et al. Phase angle is moderately associated with muscle quality and functional capacity, independent of age and body composition in older women. J Geriatr Phys Ther 42: 281&#x2013;286, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent HK, Innes KE, Vincent KR. Oxidative stress and potential interventions to reduce oxidative stress in overweight and obesity. Diabetes Obes Metabol 9: 813&#x2013;839, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilhelm-Leen ER, Hall YN, Horwitz RI, Chertow GM. Phase angle, frailty and mortality in older adults. J Gen Intern Med 29: 147&#x2013;154, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Xie X, Duan Y, Wang L, Cheng Z, Cheng J. A review of impedance measurements of whole cells. Biosens Bioelectron 77: 824&#x2013;836, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yerrakalva D, Mullis R, Mant J. The associations of &#x201c;fatness,&#x201d; &#x201c;fitness,&#x201d; and physical activity with all-cause mortality in older adults: A systematic review. Obesity 23: 1944&#x2013;1956, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Huo X, Wu C, Zhang C, Duan Z. A bioelectrical impedance phase angle measuring system for assessment of nutritional status. Bio-medical Mater Eng 24: 3657&#x2013;3664, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>