<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20490353</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1687-9597</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2010</Volume><PubDate><Year>2010</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obstetrics and gynecology international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obstet Gynecol Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of resistance training and soy isoflavone on body composition in postmenopausal women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>156037</StartPage><MedlinePgn>156037</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">156037</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2010/156037</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Objective. To investigate the independent and additive effects of resistance training (RT) and soy isoflavone (ISO) on body composition in postmenopausal women (PW). Method. This study used a placebo-controlled, double-blind (soy), randomized (ISO versus placebo) x (RT versus No RT) design. A total of 80 PW, aged 45-70 years, were randomly (71 completed 9-months intervention): RT + ISO (n = 15), No RT + ISO (n = 20), RT + placebo (n = 18), and No RT + placebo (n = 18). ISO received 100 mg a day of isoflavone; and to RT attended supervised resistance training sessions. At baseline and 9-months, fat and muscle mass were estimated by DXA. ANOVA and test t were used. Results. RT groups showed significantly increased muscle strength (35.2%) and muscle mass (1.4%). Exercising attenuated gains in fat trunk and % body fat (P &lt; .05). Significant decreases in muscle mass (-1.8%) and increases in fat mass of the whole-body (1.6%) and trunk (9.7%) was found in no-RT groups (P &lt; .05). In ISO groups, there were no differences in body composition and muscle strength. ISO and RT had no additive effects. Conclusion. In PW: RT improved muscle mass and strength and attenuated gain of fat mass; ISO did not alter body composition and muscle strength; there were no additive effects of RT and ISO.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orsatti</LastName><ForeName>F&#xe1;bio Lera</ForeName><Initials>FL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gynecology and Obstetrics, Botucatu Medical School, Sao Paulo State University, Rubiao Junior, Botucatu, Sao Paulo 18618-970, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nahas</LastName><ForeName>Eliana Aguiar Petri</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nahas-Neto</LastName><ForeName>Jorge</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maesta</LastName><ForeName>Nailza</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orsatti</LastName><ForeName>Cl&#xe1;udio Lera</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fernandes</LastName><ForeName>Cesar Edurado</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Obstet Gynecol Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101517078</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1687-9597</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20490353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2872758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2010/156037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sowers M, Zheng H, Tomey K, et al. Changes in body composition in women over six years at midlife: ovarian and chronological aging. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2007;92(3):895&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17192296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WJ. Effects of exercise on senescent muscle. Clinical Orthopaedics and Related Research. 2002;(403, supplement):S211&#x2013;S220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12394471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Heymsfield SB, Ross R. Low relative skeletal muscle mass (sarcopenia) in older persons is associated with functional impairment and physical disability. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 2002;50(5):889&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebrun CE, van der Schouw YT, de Jong FH, Grobbee DE, Lamberts SW. Fat mass rather than muscle strength is the major determinant of physical function and disability in postmenopausal women younger than 75 years of age. Menopause. 2006;13(3):474&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16735945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asikainen TM, Kukkonen-Harjula K, Miilunpalo S. Exercise for health for early postmenopausal women: a systematic review of randomised controlled trials. Sports Medicine. 2004;34(11):753&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15456348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toth MJ, Tchernof A, Sites CK, Poehlman ET. Effect of menopausal status on body composition and abdominal fat distribution. International Journal of Obesity. 2000;24(2):226&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10702775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirola J, Rikkonen T. Muscle performance after the menopause. Journal of the British Menopause Society. 2005;11(2):45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15970014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt WM, Bloomfield SA, Little KD, Nelson ME, Yingling VR. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand: physical activity and bone health. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2004;36(11):1985&#x2013;1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15514517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsatti FL, Nahas EA, Maesta N, Nahas-Neto J, Burini RC. Plasma hormones, muscle mass and strength in resistance-trained postmenopausal women. Maturitas. 2008;59(4):394&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18499368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maesta N, Nahas EA, Nahas-Neto J, et al. Effects of soy protein and resistance exercise on body composition and blood lipids in postmenopausal women. Maturitas. 2007;56(4):350&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17084566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Bryan DR, Wetzstein CJ, Zuckerman PA, Bamman MM. Resistance training and intra-abdominal adipose tissue in older men and women. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2002;34(6):1023&#x2013;1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12048332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwar A, McTernan PG, Anderson LA, et al. Site-specific regulation of oestrogen receptor-&#x3b1; and -&#x3b2; byoeatradiol in human adipose tissue. Diabetes, Obesity and Metabolism. 2001;3(5):338&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11703424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey R, Eden J. Phytoestrogens and the menopause. Climacteric. 1998;1(4):302&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11907938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemoine S, Granier P, Tiffoche C, Rannou-Bekono F, Thieulant ML, Delamarche P. Estrogen receptor alpha mRNA in human skeletal muscles. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2003;35(3):439&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arjmandi BH, Lucas EA, Khalil DA, et al. One year soy protein supplementation has positive effects on bone formation markers but not bone density in postmenopausal women. Nutrition Journal. 2005;4, article 8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC554088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15727682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Cornish SM. Effect of estrogenic compounds (estrogen or phytoestrogens) combined with exercise on bone and muscle mass in older individuals. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism. 2008;33(1):200&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18347673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sites CK, Cooper BC, Toth MJ, Gastaldelli A, Arabshahi A, Barnes S. Effect of a daily supplement of soy protein on body composition and insulin secretion in postmenopausal women. Fertility and Sterility. 2007;88(6):1609&#x2013;1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2200634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17412329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubertin-Leheudre M, Lord C, Khalil A, Dionne IJ. Six months of isoflavone supplement increases fat-free mass in obese-sarcopenic postmenopausal women: a randomized double-blind controlled trial. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2007;61(12):1442&#x2013;1444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17311051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moeller LE, Peterson CT, Hanson KB, et al. Isoflavone-rich soy protein prevents loss of hip lean mass but does not prevent the shift in regional fat distribution in perimenopausal women. Menopause. 2003;10(4):322&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12851515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2002;34(2):364&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Obesity: Preventing and Managing the Global Epidemic. Report of a WHO Consultation. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 2000. (WHO Technical Report Series 894).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11234459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NAMES. Management of osteoporosis in postmenopausal women: 2006 position statement of The North American Menopause Society. Menopause. 2006;13(3):340&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16735931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans EM, Racette SB, Van Pelt RE, Peterson LR, Villareal DT. Effects of soy protein isolate and moderate exercise on bone turnover and bone mineral density in postmenopausal women. Menopause. 2007;14(3, part 1):481&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2366994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17213752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asbury EA, Chandrruangphen P, Collins P. The importance of continued exercise participation in quality of life and psychological well-being in previously inactive postmenopausal women: a pilot study. Menopause. 2006;13(4):561&#x2013;567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16837877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gjesdal CG, Halse JI, Eide GE, Brun JG, Tell GS. Impact of lean mass and fat mass on bone mineral density: the Hordaland Health Study. Maturitas. 2008;59(2):191&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18221845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morito K, Hirose T, Kinjo J, et al. Interaction of phytoestrogens with estrogen receptors &#x3b1; and &#x3b2; . Biological and Pharmaceutical Bulletin. 2001;24(4):351&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11305594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumi T, Piskula MK, Osawa S, et al. Soy isoflavone aglycones are absorbed faster and in higher amounts than their glucosides in humans. Journal of Nutrition. 2000;130(7):1695&#x2013;1699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10867038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setchell KD, Brown NM, Desai P, et al. Bioavailability of pure isoflavones in healthy humans and analysis of commercial soy isoflavone supplements. Journal of Nutrition. 2001;131(4, supplement):1362S&#x2013;1375S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11285356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubik L, Meydani M. Bioavailability of soybean isoflavones from aglycone and glucoside forms in American women. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2003;77(6):1459&#x2013;1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12791624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott KJ, Sale C, Cable NT. Effects of resistance training and detraining on muscle strength and blood lipid profiles in postmenopausal women. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2002;36(5):340&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12351331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira PJ, Going SB, Houtkooper LB, et al. Resistance training in postmenopausal women with and without hormone therapy. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2003;35(4):555&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12673136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman-Gruen D, Kritz-Silverstein D. Usual dietary isoflavone intake and body composition in postmenopausal women. Menopause. 2003;10(5):427&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14501604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonaiuti D, Shea B, Iovine R, et al. Exercise for preventing and treating osteoporosis in postmenopausal women. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2002;(3) Article ID CD000333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12137611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>