<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">31913255</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of an Acute Strength and Conditioning Training Session on Dual-Energy X-Ray Absorptiometry Results.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>901</StartPage><EndPage>904</EndPage><MedlinePgn>901-904</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003504</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lytle, JR, Stanelle, ST, Kravits, DM, Ellsworth, RL, Martin, SE, Green, JS, and Crouse, SF. Effects of an acute strength and conditioning training session on dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry results. J Strength Cond Res 34(4): 901-904, 2020-The purpose of this study was to determine whether an athletic strength and conditioning (S&amp;C) session will alter body composition estimates of a dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan. Twenty-two strength-trained individuals (15 men, 7 women, 24 &#xb1; 2 years, 174.2 &#xb1; 8.5 cm, 83.5 &#xb1; 15.0 kg) volunteered to participate in the study. Each subject underwent 2 DXA scans, before and after completion of the S&amp;C session, which consisted of upper- and lower-body resistance exercises and interval running. Subjects consumed a free-living meal before the first scan, after which only ad libitum water intake was consumed until completing the second scan. Results were analyzed through sex by time repeated-measures analysis of variance. If no interaction effect was observed, results were next analyzed through correlated t-test (&#x3b1; = 0.05). Significant sex by time interactions were observed for arm total and lean mass, as well as a significant main effect of time showing a decrease in arm lean mass after the S&amp;C session. Values before and after the S&amp;C session that resulted in significant differences via correlated t-test are displayed in Table 1. Results revealed a significant decrease in total mass, arm and leg percent fat, and trunk lean mass, and an increase in leg lean mass.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lytle</LastName><ForeName>Jason R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Kinesiology, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stanelle</LastName><ForeName>Sean T</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kravits</LastName><ForeName>Danielle M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ellsworth</LastName><ForeName>Raychelle L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin</LastName><ForeName>Steven E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>John S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crouse</LastName><ForeName>Stephen F</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015502" MajorTopicYN="N">Absorptiometry, Photon</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="N">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012737" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060726" MajorTopicYN="N">Torso</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202004000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bone JL, Ross ML, Tomcik KA, et al. Manipulation of muscle creatine and glycogen changes dual x-ray absorptiometry estimates of body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49: 1029&#x2013;1035, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark RR, Sullivan JC, Bartok CJ, Carrel AL. DXA provides a valid minimum weight in wrestlers. Med Sci Sports Exerc 39: 2069&#x2013;2075, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harley JA, Hind K, O'Hara JP. Three-compartment body composition changes in elite rugby league players during a super league season, measured by dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1024&#x2013;1029, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horber FF, Thomi F, Casez JP, Fonteille J, Jaeger P. Impact of hydration status on body-composition as measured by dual energy x-ray absorptiometry in normal volunteers and patients on hemodialysis. Br J Radiol 65: 895&#x2013;900, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Shirreffs SM. Development of individual hydration strategies for athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 18: 457&#x2013;472, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLain L, Tai YL, Stavres J, et al. Forearm blood flow and reactive hyperemia in response to an acute bout of resistance exercise using free-weights. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 747&#x2013;748, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana A, Slater GJ, Hopkins WG, Burke LM. Effects of daily activities on dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry measurements of body composition in active people. Med Sci Sports Exerc 44: 180&#x2013;189, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana A, Slater GJ, Hopkins WG, Burke LM. Effects of exercise sessions on DXA measurements of body composition in active people. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 178&#x2013;185, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana A, Slater GJ, Hopkins WG, et al. Importance of standardized DXA protocol for assessing physique changes in athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 26: 259&#x2013;267, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nana A, Slater GJ, Stewart AD, Burke LM. Methodology review: Using dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) for the assessment of body composition in athletes and active people. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 25: 198&#x2013;215, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Sanchez N, Galloway SDR. Errors in dual energy x-ray absorptiometry estimation of body composition induced by hypohydration. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 25: 60&#x2013;68, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos DA, Silva AM, Matias CN, et al. Accuracy of DXA in estimating body composition changes in elite athletes using a four compartment model as the reference method. Nutr Metab 7: 9, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AM, Santos DA, Matias CN, et al. Changes in regional body composition explain increases in energy expenditure in elite junior basketball players over the season. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 2727&#x2013;2737, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smathers AM, Bemben MG, Bemben DA. Bone density comparisons in male competitive road cyclists and untrained controls. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 290&#x2013;296, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart AD, Hannan J. Sub-regional tissue morphometry in male athletes and controls using dual X-ray absorptiometry (DXA). Int J Sport Nutr 10: 157&#x2013;169, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton L, Scott M, Wallace J, Reilly T. Body composition of English premier league soccer players: Influence of playing position, international status, and ethnicity. J Sports Sci 27: 1019&#x2013;1026, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Morales E, Forsse JS, Grandjean PW. Impact of acute dietary manipulations on DXA and BIA body composition estimates. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49: 823&#x2013;832, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tschakovsky ME, Joyner MJ. Nitric oxide and muscle blood flow in exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 33: 151&#x2013;161, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent WJ, Weir JP. Statistics in Kinesiology (4th ed.). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2012. p. 165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrington G, Dolan E, McGoldrick A, et al. Chronic weight control impacts on physiological function and bone health in elite jockeys. J Sports Sci 27: 543&#x2013;550, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky ZM. Science and Practice of Strength Training. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 1995. pp. 80&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>