<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">19656392</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of 28 days of resistance exercise and consuming a commercially available pre-workout supplement, NO-Shotgun(R), on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of satellite cell activation, and clinical safety markers in males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>16</StartPage><MedlinePgn>16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-6-16</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study determined the effects of 28 days of heavy resistance exercise combined with the nutritional supplement, NO-Shotgun(R), on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of satellite cell activation, and clinical safety markers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eighteen non-resistance-trained males participated in a resistance training program (3 x 10-RM) 4 times/wk for 28 days while also ingesting 27 g/day of placebo (PL) or NO-Shotgun(R) (NO) 30 min prior to exercise. Data were analyzed with separate 2 x 2 ANOVA and t-tests (p &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Total body mass was increased in both groups (p = 0.001), but without any significant increases in total body water (p = 0.77). No significant changes occurred with fat mass (p = 0.62); however fat-free mass did increase with training (p = 0.001), and NO was significantly greater than PL (p = 0.001). Bench press strength for NO was significantly greater than PL (p = 0.003). Myofibrillar protein increased with training (p = 0.001), with NO being significantly greater than PL (p = 0.019). Serum IGF-1 (p = 0.046) and HGF (p = 0.06) were significantly increased with training and for NO HGF was greater than PL (p = 0.002). Muscle phosphorylated c-met was increased with training for both groups (p = 0.019). Total DNA was increased in both groups (p = 0.006), while NO was significantly greater than PL (p = 0.038). For DNA/protein, PL was decreased and NO was not changed (p = 0.014). All of the myogenic regulatory factors were increased with training; however, NO was shown to be significantly greater than PL for Myo-D (p = 0.008) and MRF-4 (p = 0.022). No significant differences were located for any of the whole blood and serum clinical chemistry markers (p &gt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">When combined with heavy resistance training for 28 days, NO-Shotgun(R) is not associated with any negative side effects, nor does it abnormally impact any of the clinical chemistry markers. Rather, NO-Shotgun(R) effectively increases muscle strength and mass, myofibrillar protein content, and increases the content of markers indicative of satellite cell activation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shelmadine</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance, and Recreation, Baylor University, Box 97313, Waco, TX 76798, USA. darryn_willoughby@baylor.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooke</LastName><ForeName>Matt</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buford</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hudson</LastName><ForeName>Geoffrey</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redd</LastName><ForeName>Liz</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leutholtz</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willoughby</LastName><ForeName>Darryn S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-6-16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-6-16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H, Spangenburg E, Booth FW. Control of the size of the human muscle mass. Annu Rev Physiol. 2004;66:799&#x2013;828. doi: 10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caiozzo VJ, Haddad F, Baker MJ, Baldwin KM. Influence of mechanical loading on myosin heavy-chain protein and mRNA isoform expression. J Appl Physiol. 1996;80:1503&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8727533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, Ragg KE, Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Staron RS. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88:50&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstrom DA, Penn BH, Strand A, Perry RL, Rudnicki MA, Tapscott SJ. Promoter-specific regulation of MyoD binding and signal transduction cooperate to pattern gene expression. Mol Cell. 2002;9:587&#x2013;600. doi: 10.1016/S1097-2765(02)00481-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1097-2765(02)00481-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11931766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel CS, Slade J, Mahoney E, Haddad F, Dudley GA, Adams GR. Time course of molecular responses of human skeletal muscle to acute bouts of resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98:482&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15465884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckingham M, Houzelstein D, Lyons G, Ontell M, Ott M, Sassoon D. Expression of muscle genes in the mouse embryo. Symp Soc Exp Biol. 1992;46:203&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1341037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams GR, Haddad F. The relationships among IGF-1, DNA content, and protein accumulation during skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:2509&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9018499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall ZW, Ralston E. Nuclear domains in muscle cells. Cell. 1989;59:771&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/0092-8674(89)90597-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0092-8674(89)90597-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2686838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauro A. Satellite cell of skeletal muscle fibers. J Biophys Biochem Cytol. 1961;9:493&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2225012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13768451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harridge SD. Plasticity of human skeletal muscle: gene expression to in vivo function. Exp Physiol. 2007;92:783&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1113/expphysiol.2006.036525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2006.036525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17631518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Thornell LE. Concomitant increases in myonuclear and satellite cell content in female trapezius muscle following strength training. Histochem Cell Biol. 2000;113:99&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1007/s004180050012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004180050012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10766262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Schjerling P, Andersen LL, Charifi N, Madsen JL, Christensen LR, Andersen JL. The effects of heavy resistance training and detraining on satellite cells in human skeletal muscles. J Physiol. 2004;558:1005&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2004.065904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2004.065904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1665027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15218062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawke TJ, Garry DJ. Myogenic satellite cells: physiology to molecular biology. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91:534&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florini JR, Ewton DZ, Coolican SA. Growth hormone and the insulin-like growth factor system in myogenesis. Endocr Rev. 1996;17:481&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8897022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson J. A role for nitric oxide in muscle repair: nitric oxide-mediated activation of muscle satellite cells. Mol Biol Cell. 2000;11:1859&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC14889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10793157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R, Sheehan S, Iwasaki H, Hattori A, Allen R. Mechanical stretch induces activation of skeletal muscle satellite cells in vitro. Exp Cell Res. 2001;267:107&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1006/excr.2001.5252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/excr.2001.5252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11412043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedieu S, Mazeres G, Cottin P, Brustis J. Involvement of myogenic regulator factors during fusion in the cell line C2C12. Int J Dev Biol. 2002;2:235&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11934152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak K, Kong Y, Konieczny S. The MRF4 activation domain is required to induce muscle-specific gene expression. Mol Cell Biol. 1992;12:4224&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC360357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1328851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yutzey K, Rhodes S, Konieczny S. Differential transactivation associated with the muscle regulatory factors MyoD1, myogenin, and MRF4. Mol Cell Biol. 1990;10:3934&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC360904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1695319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas N, Mira J, Gallien C, Chanoine C. Neural and hormonal control of expression of myogenic regulatory factor genes during regeneration of Xenopus fast muscles: myogenin and MRF4 mRNA accumulation are neurally regulated oppositely. Dev Dyn. 2000;218:112&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1097-0177(200005)218:1&lt;112::AID-DVDY10&gt;3.0.CO;2-D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0177(200005)218:1&lt;112::AID-DVDY10&gt;3.0.CO;2-D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10822264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psilander N, Damsgaard R, Pilegaard H. Resistance exercise alters MRF and IGF-1 mRNA content in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Phsyiol. 2003;95:1038&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12716875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D, Nelson M. Myosin heavy-chain mrna expression after a single bout session of heavy-resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:1262&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200205001-01040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200205001-01040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12165680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek D, Kim J, Petrella J, Cross J, Bamman M. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanism in young vs older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:531&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1674&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200105001-00170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200105001-00170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myogenic regulatory factor expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:769&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000065005.96298.01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000065005.96298.01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Op't Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, Urso B, Greenhaff P, Labarque V, Dymarkowski S, Van Hecke P, Richter E. Oral creatine supplementation faciltates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol. 2001;536:625&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagard P, Kadi F, Tufekovic G, Verney J, Olesen J, Suetta C, Kjaer M. Creatine supplementatin augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol. 2006;573:525&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2006.107359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2006.107359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Theisen D, Bertrand L, Hespel P, Hue L, Francaux M. Creatine enhances differentiation of myogenic C2 C12 cells by activating both p38 and Akt/PKB pathways. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2007;293:C1263&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.00162.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00162.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17652429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han B, Tong J, Zhu M, Ma C, Du M. Insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-1) and leucine activate pig myogenic satellite cells through mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway. Mol Reprod Dev. 2008;75:810&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1002/mrd.20832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mrd.20832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18033679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Koevering M, Nissen S. Oxidation of leucine and &#x3b1;-ketoisocaproate to &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate in vivo. Am J Physiol. 1992;25:E27&#x2013;E31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1733247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimomura Y, Nakai N, Nagasaki M, Harris R. Exercise promotes bcaa catabolism: Effects of bcaa supplementation on skeletal muscle during exercise. J Nutr. 2004;134:1583S&#x2013;87S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto K, Mizuno M, Mizuno T, dilling-Hansen B, Lahoz A, Bertelsen V, Munster H, Jordening H, Hamada K, Doi T. Branched-chain amino acids and arginine supplementation attenuates skeletal muscle proteolysis induced by moderate exercise in young individuals. Int J Sports Med. 2007;28:531&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-964940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-964940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17497593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford M. A rapid and senstive method for the quantification of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principle of protein-dye binding. Anal Biochem. 1976;72:248&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1016/0003-2697(76)90527-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0003-2697(76)90527-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">942051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D, Stout J, Wilborn C. Effects of resistance training and protein plus amino acid supplementation on muscle anabolism, mass, and strength. Amino Acids. 2007;32:467&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0398-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0398-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16988909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausubel F, Brent R, Kingston R, Moore D, Seidman J, Smith J, Struhl K. Short Protocols in Molecular Biology. 5. New York, NY: Wiley Publishers; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coburn JW, Housh DJ, Housh TJ, Malek MH, Beck TW, Cramer JT, Johnson GO, Donlin PE. Effects of leucine and whey protein supplementation during eight weeks of unilateral resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:284&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1519/R-17925.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-17925.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissen S, Sharp R, Ray M, Rathmacher JA, Rice D, Fuller JC, Jr, Connelly AS, Abumrad N. Effect of leucine metabolite beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate on muscle metabolism during resistance-exercise training. J Appl Phsyiol. 1996;81:2095&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8941534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawko E, Ostaszewski P, Jank M, Sacharuk J, Zieniewicz A, Wilczak J, Nissen S. Creatine and beta-hydroxy-beta-methyleburyrate (HMB) additively increase lean body mass and muscle strength during a weight-training program. Nutrition. 2001;17:558&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1016/S0899-9007(01)00540-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0899-9007(01)00540-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11448573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Kang J, Mangine G, Faigenbaum A, Stout J. Effect of creatine and beta-alanine supplementation on performance and endocrine responses in strength/power athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2006;16:430&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17136944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis M, von Beneden R, Dehoux M, Thissen J, Francaux M. Creatine increases IGF-1 and myogenic regulatory factor mRNA in C2C12 cells. FEBS Lett. 2004;557:243&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1016/S0014-5793(03)01504-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0014-5793(03)01504-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14741375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Creer A, Jemiolo B, Trappe S. Time course of myogenic and metabolic gene expression in response to acute exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98:1745&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01185.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01185.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15618316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella J, Kim J, Cross J, Kosek D, Bamman M. Efficacy of myonuclear addition may explain differential myofiber growth among resistance-trained young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291:E937&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00190.2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00190.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall G, Byrnes W, Fleck S, Dickinson A, Kraemer W. Acute and chronic hormonal responses to resistance training designed to promote muscle hypertrophy. Can J Appl Physiol. 1999;24:96&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheny W, Merritt E, Zannikos S, Farrar R, Adamo M. Serum IGF-1 deficiency does not prevent compensatory skeletal muscle hypertrophy in resistance exercise. Exp Biol Med. 2009;234:164&#x2013;70. doi: 10.3181/0808-RM-251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3181/0808-RM-251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19064939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R, Allen R. Active hepatocyte growth factor is present in skeletal muscle extracellular matrix. Muscle Nerve. 2004;30:654&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1002/mus.20114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.20114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15389661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R, Liu X, Pulido A, Morales M, Sakata T, Dial S, Hattori A, Ikeuchi Y, Allen R. Satellite cell activation in stretched skeletal muscle and the role of nitric oxide and hepatocyte growth factor. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2006;290:C1487&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.00513.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00513.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16684931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly C, McKay B, Phillips S, Tarnopolsky M, Parise G. Hepatocyte growth factor (HGF) and the satellite cell response following muscle lengthening contractions in humans. Muscle Nerve. 2008;38:1434&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1002/mus.21146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.21146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18816607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R, Hattori A, Ikeuchi Y, Anderson J, Allen R. Release of hepatocyte growth factor from mechanically stretched skeletal muscle satellite cells and role of pH and nitric oxide. Mol Biol Cell. 2002;13:2909&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1091/mbc.E02-01-0062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1091/mbc.E02-01-0062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC117951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12181355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snow MH. Satellite cell response in rat soleus muscle undergoing hypertrophy due to surgical ablation of synergists. Anat Rec. 1990;227:437&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1002/ar.1092270407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.1092270407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2393096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy R, Baldwin K, Martin T, Chimarusti S, Edgerton V. Biochemical and physiological changes in overloaded rat fast- and slow-twitch ankle extensors. J Appl Physiol. 1985;59:639&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3161859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downie D, Delday M, Maltin C, Sneddon A. Clenbuterol increases muscle fiber size and GATA-2 protein in rat skeletal muscle in utero. Mol Reprod Dev. 2008;75:785&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1002/mrd.20795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mrd.20795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17948249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockdale F, Topper Y. The role of DNA synthesis and mitosis in hormone-dependent differentiation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1966;56:1283&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1073/pnas.56.4.1283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.56.4.1283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC220059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5230153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latres E, Amini A, Amini A, Griffiths J, Martin F, Wei Y, Lin H, Yancopoulos G, Glass D. Insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-1) inversely regulates atrophy-induced genes via the phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase/akt/mammalian target of rapamycin (PI3K/Akt/mTOR) pathway. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:2737&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M407517200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M407517200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15550386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devlin J, Brodsky I, Scrimgeour A, Fuller , Rier D. Amino acid metabolism after intense exercise. Am J Physiol. 1990;258:E249&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2106267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Someren K, Edwards A, Howatson G. Supplementation with beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) and alpha-ketoisocaproic acd (KIC) reduces signs and symptoms of exercise-induced muscle damage in man. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2005;15:413&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16286672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto K, Mizuno M, Mizuno T, Dilling-Hansen B, Lahoz A, Bertelsen V, M&#xfc;nster H, Jordening H, Hamada K, Doi T. Branched-chain amino acids and arginine supplementation attenuates skeletal muscle proteolysis induced by moderate exercise in young individuals. Int J Sports Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;28:531&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17497593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persky A, Rawson E. Safety of creatine supplementation. Subcell Biochem. 2007;46:275&#x2013;89. full_text.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans J, Francaux M. Adverse effects of creatine supplementation: fact or fiction? Sports Med. 2000;30:155&#x2013;70. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200030030-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200030030-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10999421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>