<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38934517</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Changes in Metabolic and Inflammatory Markers after a Combined Exercise Program in Workers: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2156</StartPage><EndPage>2172</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2156-2172</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003510</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We investigated the effects of a 16-wk combined exercise training on body composition, and metabolic and inflammatory markers in sedentary middle-aged workers. We also assessed whether alterations in metabolic markers were associated with changes in health-related outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This randomized controlled trial involved 46 participants randomly allocated into control and exercise groups. The exercise group performed 16-wk combined aerobic and resistance training for 75 min per session, 3 times a week. Fasting blood samples were collected at baseline and after 16-wk intervention to determine lipid profile, and metabolic and inflammatory markers as primary outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 36 participants completed the intervention (53.70 &#xb1; 6.92 yr old; n = 18 in each group). Waist circumference (interaction effect: F = 7.423, P = 0.002), fat mass (interaction effect: F = 5.070, P = 0.011), and muscle mass (interaction effect: F = 5.420, P = 0.007) were improved in the exercise group compared with the control group. Fasting glucose increased after the 16-wk follow-up (time effect: F = 73.253, P &lt; 0.001), without an intergroup difference. Insulin levels were greater in the control compared with exercise group (group effect: F = 6.509, P = 0.015). The control group tended to increase the homeostatic model assessment of insulin resistance index (interaction effect: F = 3.493, P = 0.070) and to decrease the QUICKI index (interaction effect: F = 3.364, P = 0.075) to a greater extent compared with the exercise group. Exercise group reduced leptin (interaction effect: F = 11.175, P = 0.002) and adiponectin (interaction effect: F = 4.437, P = 0.043) concentrations in a greater magnitude than the control group. Interleukin (IL)-6 (time effect: F = 17.767, P &lt; 0.001) and tumor necrosis factor &#x3b1; (time effect: F = 9.781, P = 0.004) concentrations decreased after the intervention, without an intergroup difference. IL-17A levels increased in the control compared with exercise group (interaction effect: F = 5.010, P = 0.033). Effects on adiponectin, IL-6, and IL-17A levels seem to depend on baseline body mass index, age, and sex. Percentage changes in leptin correlated positively with changes in homeostatic model assessment of insulin resistance index in the exercise ( r = 0.565, P = 0.015) and control ( r = 0.670, P = 0.002) groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A combined training program can be an effective strategy to improve body composition and inflammatory markers and prevent marked reductions in insulin sensitivity among middle-aged workers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Fernanda M</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, Research Unit for Sport and Physical Activity (CIDAF), Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Coimbra, PORTUGAL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duarte-Mendes</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferreira</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, Research Unit for Sport and Physical Activity (CIDAF), Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Coimbra, PORTUGAL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Eug&#xe9;nia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monteiro</LastName><ForeName>Diogo</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Massart</LastName><ForeName>Alain</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, Research Unit for Sport and Physical Activity (CIDAF), Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Coimbra, PORTUGAL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farinha</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soares</LastName><ForeName>Carlos M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Ana M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Coimbra, Research Unit for Sport and Physical Activity (CIDAF), Faculty of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Coimbra, PORTUGAL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04868240</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020738">Leptin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D052242">Adiponectin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015850">Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014409">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008055">Lipids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020738" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leptin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="Y">Insulin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052242" MajorTopicYN="N">Adiponectin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055105" MajorTopicYN="N">Waist Circumference</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015850" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057185" MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014409" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007333" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin Resistance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008055" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38934517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202411000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Saeedi P, Karuranga S, et al. IDF Diabetes Atlas: global, regional and country-level diabetes prevalence estimates for 2021 and projections for 2045. Diabetes Res Clin Pract . 2022;183:109119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portuguese Society of Diabetology. Diabetes: Factos e N&#xfa;meros&#x2014;O Ano de 2019, 2020 e 2021&#x2014;Relat&#xf3;rio Anual do Observat&#xf3;rio Nacional da Diabetes 03/2023 . [facts and Numbers&#x2014;The Year of 2019, 2020 and 2021&#x2014;Annual Report of the National Diabetes Observatory 03/2023] . Lisboa: Letra Sol&#xfa;vel &#x2013; Publicidade e marketing, Lda; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association. 2. Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: standards of medical care in diabetes&#x2014;2019. Diabetes Care . 2019;42(Suppl 1):S13&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porta M, Curletto G, Cipullo D, et al. Estimating the delay between onset and diagnosis of type 2 diabetes from the time course of retinopathy prevalence. Diabetes Care . 2014;37(6):1668&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Qian F, Chavarro JE, et al. Modifiable risk factors and long term risk of type 2 diabetes among individuals with a history of gestational diabetes mellitus: prospective cohort study. BMJ . 2022;378:e070312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden Davies KA, Sprung VS, Norman JA, et al. Short-term decreased physical activity with increased sedentary behaviour causes metabolic derangements and altered body composition: effects in individuals with and without a first-degree relative with type 2 diabetes. Diabetologia . 2018;61(6):1282&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaribeygi H, Maleki M, Sathyapalan T, Jamialahmadi T, Sahebkar A. Pathophysiology of physical inactivity-dependent insulin resistance: a theoretical mechanistic review emphasizing clinical evidence. J Diabetes Res . 2021;2021:7796727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chait A, den Hartigh LJ. Adipose tissue distribution, inflammation and its metabolic consequences, including diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Front Cardiovasc Med . 2020;7:22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf3;dis K, Roden M. Energy metabolism of white adipose tissue and insulin resistance in humans. Eur J Clin Invest . 2018;48(11):e13017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa P, Pinho A, L&#xe1;zaro A, et al. CD8+ Treg cells play a role in the obesity-associated insulin resistance. Life Sci . 2023;336:122306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van de Vyver M. Immunology of chronic low-grade inflammation: relationship with metabolic function. J Endocrinol . 2023;257(1):e220271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho E, Jansson PA, Axelsen M, et al. Low cellular IRS 1 gene and protein expression predict insulin resistance and NIDDM. FASEB J . 1999;13(15):2173&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho E, Jansson PA, Nagaev I, Wenthzel AM, Smith U. Insulin resistance with low cellular IRS-1 expression is also associated with low GLUT4 expression and impaired insulin-stimulated glucose transport. FASEB J . 2001;15(6):1101&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding C, Chan Z, Magkos F. Lean, but not healthy: the 'metabolically obese, normal-weight' phenotype. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care . 2016;19(6):408&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TN, Park MS, Yang SJ, et al. Body size phenotypes and low muscle mass: the Korean Sarcopenic Obesity Study (KSOS). J Clin Endocrinol Metab . 2013;98(2):811&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz EC, Weber JL, Adams SH, et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness associates with blood pressure and metabolic health of children&#x2014;the Arkansas Active Kids Study. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(11):2225&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prince SA, Elliott CG, Scott K, Visintini S, Reed JL. Device-measured physical activity, sedentary behaviour and cardiometabolic health and fitness across occupational groups: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act . 2019;16(1):30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arundell L, Fletcher E, Salmon J, Veitch J, Hinkley T. A systematic review of the prevalence of sedentary behavior during the after-school period among children aged 5&#x2013;18 years. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act . 2016;13(1):93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK. Anti-inflammatory effects of exercise: role in diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Eur J Clin Invest . 2017;47(8):600&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RL, Soeters MR, W&#xfc;st RCI, Houtkooper RH. Metabolic flexibility as an adaptation to energy resources and requirements in health and disease. Endocr Rev . 2018;39(4):489&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SR, Hawley JA. Update on the effects of physical activity on insulin sensitivity in humans. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med . 2017;2(1):e000143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med . 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbouAssi H, Slentz CA, Mikus CR, et al. The effects of aerobic, resistance, and combination training on insulin sensitivity and secretion in overweight adults from STRRIDE AT/RT: a randomized trial. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2015;118(12):1474&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streb AR, Dos Santos Leonel L, Delevatti RS, Cavaglieri CR, Del Duca GF. Effects of non-periodized and linear periodized combined exercise training on insulin resistance indicators in adults with obesity: a randomized controlled trial. Sports Med Open . 2021;7(1):69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunelli DT, Chacon-Mikahil MP, G&#xe1;spari AF, et al. Combined training reduces subclinical inflammation in obese middle-age men. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2015;47(10):2207&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez A, Gonzalo-Encabo P, P&#xe9;rez-K&#xf6;hler B, Garc&#xed;a-Honduvilla N, Valad&#xe9;s D. Circulating myokines IL-6, IL-15 and FGF21 response to training is altered by exercise type but not by menopause in women with obesity. Eur J Sport Sci . 2021;22(9):1426&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva FM, Duarte-Mendes P, Carvalho E, et al. Effects of combined training during the COVID-19 pandemic on metabolic health and quality of life in sedentary workers: a randomized controlled study. Front Public Health . 2022;10:1040714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro-Gahete FJ, Ponce-Gonz&#xe1;lez JG, Corral-P&#xe9;rez J, et al. Effect of a 12-week concurrent training intervention on cardiometabolic health in obese men: a pilot study. Front Physiol . 2021;12:630831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, De Souza GV, Cavaglieri CR, Madruga VA, Chacon-Mikahil MP. Effect of resistance, endurance, and concurrent training on TNF-&#x3b1;, IL-6, and CRP. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2012;44(1):50&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streb AR, Braga PGS, de Melo RF, et al. Effects of combined physical exercise on plasma lipid variables, paraoxonase 1 activity, and inflammation parameters in adults with obesity: a randomized clinical trial. J Endocrinol Invest . 2022;45(10):1991&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. J Pharmacol Pharmacother . 2010;1(2):100&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira JP, Duarte-Mendes P, Teixeira AM, Silva FM. Effects of combined training on metabolic profile, lung function, stress and quality of life in sedentary adults: a study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. PLoS One . 2022;17(2):e0263455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gellish RL, Goslin BR, Olson RE, et al. Longitudinal modeling of the relationship between age and maximal heart rate. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2007;39(5):822&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xfc;hbeck G, Catal&#xe1;n V, Rodr&#xed;guez A, G&#xf3;mez-Ambrosi J. Adiponectin&#x2013;leptin ratio: a promising index to estimate adipose tissue dysfunction. Relation with obesity-associated cardiometabolic risk. Adipocyte . 2018;7(1):57&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews DR, Hosker JP, Rudenski AS, et al. Homeostasis model assessment: insulin resistance and beta-cell function from fasting plasma glucose and insulin concentrations in man. Diabetologia . 1985;28(7):412&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz A, Nambi SS, Mather K, et al. Quantitative insulin sensitivity check index: a simple, accurate method for assessing insulin sensitivity in humans. J Clin Endocrinol Metab . 2000;85(7):2402&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muntner P, Shimbo D, Carey RM, et al. Measurement of blood pressure in humans: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Hypertension . 2019;73(5):e35&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sykes K. Chester Step Test. Occup Med . 2018;68(1):70&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migueles JH, Cadenas-Sanchez C, Ekelund U, et al. Accelerometer data collection and processing criteria to assess physical activity and other outcomes: a systematic review and practical considerations. Sports Med . 2017;47(9):1821&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troiano RP, Berrigan D, Dodd KW, et al. Physical activity in the United States measured by accelerometer. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2008;40(1):181&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes C, Aro A, Azevedo A, Ramos E, Barros H. Intake and adipose tissue composition of fatty acids and risk of myocardial infarction in a male Portuguese community sample. J Am Diet Assoc . 2007;107(2):276&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field A. Discovering Statistics Using IBM SPSS Statistics . 5th ed. London: SAGE Publications; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences . 2nd ed. Hillsdale (NJ): Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad Rahimi GR, Bijeh N, Rashidlamir A. Effects of exercise training on serum preptin, undercarboxylated osteocalcin and high molecular weight adiponectin in adults with metabolic syndrome. Exp Physiol . 2020;105(3):449&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quesada O, Claggett B, Rodriguez F, et al. Associations of insulin resistance with systolic and diastolic blood pressure: a study from the HCHS/SOL. Hypertension . 2021;78(3):716&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mallah MH, Sakr S, Al-Qunaibet A. Cardiorespiratory fitness and cardiovascular disease prevention: an update. Curr Atheroscler Rep . 2018;20(1):1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva MAR, Baptista LC, Neves RS, et al. The effects of concurrent training combining both resistance exercise and high-intensity interval training or moderate-intensity continuous training on metabolic syndrome. Front Physiol . 2020;11:572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa P, Melnyk S, Bennuri SC, et al. Redox imbalance and methylation disturbances in early childhood obesity. Oxid Med Cell Longev . 2021;2021:2207125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perakakis N, Farr OM, Mantzoros CS. Leptin in leanness and obesity: JACC state-of-the-art review. J Am Coll Cardiol . 2021;77(6):745&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J, Fan J, Su Q, Yang Z. Cytokines and abnormal glucose and lipid metabolism. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) . 2019;10:703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Meng RW, Kunutsor SK, et al. Plasma adiponectin levels and type 2 diabetes risk: a nested case-control study in a Chinese population and an updated meta-analysis. Sci Rep . 2018;8(1):406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shokri E, Heidarianpour A, Razavi Z. Positive effect of combined exercise on adipokines levels and pubertal signs in overweight and obese girls with central precocious puberty. Lipids Health Dis . 2021;20(1):152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerosa-Neto J, Antunes BM, Campos EZ, et al. Impact of long-term high-intensity interval and moderate-intensity continuous training on subclinical inflammation in overweight/obese adults. J Exerc Rehabil . 2016;12(6):575&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez-Gutierrez A, Aguilera CM, Osuna-Prieto FJ, et al. Exercise-induced changes on exerkines that might influence brown adipose tissue metabolism in young sedentary adults. Eur J Sport Sci . 2022;23(4):625&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otu LI, Otu A. Adiponectin and the control of metabolic dysfunction: is exercise the magic bullet? Front Physiol . 2021;12:651732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senkus KE, Crowe-White KM, Bolland AC, Locher JL, Ard JD. Changes in adiponectin:leptin ratio among older adults with obesity following a 12-month exercise and diet intervention. Nutr Diabetes . 2022;12(1):30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaletel J, Barlovic DP, Prezelj J. Adiponectin&#x2013;leptin ratio: a useful estimate of insulin resistance in patients with type 2 diabetes. J Endocrinol Invest . 2010;33(8):514&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donges CE, Duffield R, Guelfi KJ, et al. Comparative effects of single-mode vs. duration-matched concurrent exercise training on body composition, low-grade inflammation, and glucose regulation in sedentary, overweight, middle-aged men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2013;38(7):779&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmerman KL, Flynn MG, Coen PM, Markofski MM, Pence BD. Exercise training-induced lowering of inflammatory (Cd14+ Cd16+) monocytes: a role in the anti-inflammatory influence of exercise? J Leukoc Biol . 2008;84(5):1271&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinha C, Ferreira JP, Serrano J, et al. The impact of aquatic exercise programs on the systemic hematological and inflammatory markers of community dwelling elderly: a randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol . 2022;13:838580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinjo T, Iwashita M, Yamashita A, et al. IL-17A synergistically enhances TNF&#x3b1;-induced IL-6 and CCL20 production in 3T3-L1 adipocytes. Biochem Biophys Res Commun . 2016;477(2):241&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagannathan-Bogdan M, McDonnell ME, Shin H, et al. Elevated proinflammatory cytokine production by a skewed T cell compartment requires monocytes and promotes inflammation in type 2 diabetes. J Immunol . 2011;186(2):1162&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandercappellen EJ, Koster A, Savelberg HHCM, et al. Sedentary behaviour and physical activity are associated with biomarkers of endothelial dysfunction and low-grade inflammation-relevance for (pre)diabetes: the Maastricht study. Diabetologia . 2022;65(5):777&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falconer CL, Cooper AR, Walhin JP, et al. Sedentary time and markers of inflammation in people with newly diagnosed type 2 diabetes. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis . 2014;24(9):956&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browning LM, Krebs JD, Jebb SA. Discrimination ratio analysis of inflammatory markers: implications for the study of inflammation in chronic disease. Metabolism . 2004;53(7):899&#x2013;903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarafidis PA, Lasaridis AN, Nilsson PM, et al. Validity and reproducibility of HOMA-IR, 1/HOMA-IR, QUICKI and McAuley&#x2019;s indices in patients with hypertension and type II diabetes. J Hum Hypertens . 2007;21(9):709&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Gebo KA, Abraham AG, et al. Dynamics of inflammatory responses after SARS-CoV-2 infection by vaccination status in the USA: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Microbe . 2023;4(9):e692&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadoff J, Gray G, Vandebosch A, et al. Safety and efficacy of single-dose Ad26.COV2.S vaccine against COVID-19. N Engl J Med . 2021;384(23):2187&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polack FP, Thomas SJ, Kitchin N, et al. Safety and efficacy of the BNT162b2 mRNA COVID-19 vaccine. N Engl J Med . 2020;383(27):2603&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski SR, S&#xf8;gaard OS, Tolstrup M, et al. Inflammation and platelet activation after COVID-19 vaccines&#x2014;possible mechanisms behind vaccine-induced immune thrombocytopenia and thrombosis. Front Immunol . 2021;12:779453.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>