<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">20019638</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance training predicts 6-yr body composition change in postmenopausal women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1286</StartPage><EndPage>1295</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1286-95</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181ca8115</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to examine the association of exercise frequency (ExFreq) and volume (total weight lifted by military press and squats (SQ)) with change in body composition among postmenopausal women participating in a progressive resistance training study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Previously, sedentary women (n = 122, age = 56.3 +/- 4.3 yr) were followed for 6 yr. At 6 yr, there were women who had been randomly assigned to resistance training at baseline (n = 65) controls that were permitted to cross over to the exercise program at 1 yr (n = 32) and 25 true controls. Exercisers and crossovers directed to perform eight core exercises for two sets of eight repetitions at 70%-80% of one-repetition maximum, three times weekly, plus progressive weight bearing, stretching, and balance. Body weight and fat were measured at baseline and annually using anthropometry and dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Average change in body weight and total body fat were 0.83 +/- 5.39 and 0.64 +/- 4.95 kg at 6 yr, respectively. In multiple linear regression, ExFreq, military press, and SQ were significantly inversely associated with change in body weight (standardized beta coefficient (SBC) = -0.22 to -0.28, P &lt; 0.01), fat (SBC = -0.25 to -0.33, P &lt; 0.01), and trunk fat (SBC = -0.20 to -0.31, P &lt; 0.03) after adjusting for age, years on hormone therapy, change in lean soft tissue, baseline body composition, and baseline habitual exercise. The lowest tertile of SQ (equivalent to 2.5% attendance) demonstrated significant gain in weight, fat, and trunk fat over 6 yr (P &lt; 0.004), whereas the highest tertile SQ (equivalent to 64% attendance) was able to maintain their weight, total, and regional fat.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We conclude that resistance training is a viable long-term method to prevent weight gain and deleterious changes in body composition in postmenopausal women.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bea</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arizona Cancer Center, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ 85724-5024, USA. jbea@azcc.arizona.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cussler</LastName><ForeName>Ellen C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Going</LastName><ForeName>Scott B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blew</LastName><ForeName>Robert M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metcalfe</LastName><ForeName>Lauve L</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lohman</LastName><ForeName>Timothy G</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AR039559</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050154" MajorTopicYN="N">Adiposity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="N">Postmenopause</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015430" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Gain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS172894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2892016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181ca8115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ainsworth BE, Haskell WL, Whitt MC, et al. Compendium of physical activities: an update of activity codes and MET intensities. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(9 Suppl):S498&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10993420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson JW, Konz EC, Frederich RC, Wood CL. Long-term weight-loss maintenance: a meta-analysis of US studies. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001;74(5):579&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11684524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN. Body composition in healthy aging. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2000;904:437&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binder EF, Yarasheski KE, Steger-May K, et al. Effects of progressive resistance training on body composition in frail older adults: results of a randomized, controlled trial. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2005;60(11):1425&#x2013;1431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair SN, Haskell WL, Ho P, et al. Assessment of habitual physical activity by a seven-day recall in a community survey and controlled experiments. Am J Epidemiol. 1985;122(5):794&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3876763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouassida A, Chamari K, Zaouali M, Feki Y, Zbidi A, Tabka Z. Review on leptin and adiponectin responses and adaptations to acute and chronic exercise. Br J Sports Med. 2008 doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2008.046151. E-pub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2008.046151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18927166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryner RW, Ullrich IH, Sauers J, et al. Effects of resistance vs. aerobic training combined with an 800 calorie liquid diet on lean body mass and resting metabolic rate. J Am Coll Nutr. 1999;18(2):115&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10204826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caspersen CJ, Pereira MA, Curran KM. Changes in physical activity patterns in the United States, by sex and cross-sectional age. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(9):1601&#x2013;1609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10994912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and Prevention Web site [Internet] Atlanta (GA): Defining overweight and obesity;  [cited 2004 May 20]. Available from:  http://www.cdc.gov/nccdphp/dnpa/obesity/defining.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Guidelines on the Identification, Evaluation, and Treatment of Overweight and Obesity in Adults--The Evidence Report. National Institutes of Health. Obes Res. 1998;6(Suppl 2):51S&#x2013;209S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9813653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cussler EC, Going SB, Houtkooper LB, et al. Exercise frequency and calcium intake predict 4-year bone changes in postmenopausal women. Osteoporos Int. 2005;16(12):2129&#x2013;2141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16283062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison KK, Ford ES, Cogswell ME, Dietz WH. Percentage of body fat and body mass index are associated with mobility limitations in people aged 70 and older from NHANES III. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50(11):1802&#x2013;1809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12410898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dela F, Mikines KJ, von Linstow M, Secher NH, Galbo H. Effect of training on insulin-mediated glucose uptake in human muscle. Am J Physiol. 1992;263(6 Pt 1):E1134&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1476187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Smith B, Jacobsen DJ, et al. The role of exercise for weight loss and maintenance. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2004;18(6):1009&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15561636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantin F, Di Francesco V, Fontana G, et al. Longitudinal body composition changes in old men and women: interrelationships with worsening disability. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2007;62(12):1375&#x2013;1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18166688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA. The role of progressive resistance training and nutrition in the preservation of lean body mass in the elderly. J Am Coll Nutr. 1995;14(6):587&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8598419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine JT, Colditz GA, Coakley EH, et al. A prospective study of weight change and health-related quality of life in women. Jama. 1999;282(22):2136&#x2013;2142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10591335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Going S, Lohman T, Houtkooper L, et al. Effects of exercise on bone mineral density in calcium-replete postmenopausal women with and without hormone replacement therapy. Osteoporos Int. 2003;14(8):637&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12844212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg JH, King AC. Physical activity and weight management across the lifespan. Annu Rev Public Health. 2007;28:145&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17168638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hills AP, Byrne NM. Exercise prescription for weight management. Proc Nutr Soc. 1998;57(1):93&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9571714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houtkooper LB, Ritenbaugh C, Aickin M, et al. Nutrients, body composition and exercise are related to change in bone mineral density in premenopausal women. J Nutr. 1995;125(5):1229&#x2013;1237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7738683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu FB, Willett WC, Li T, Stampfer MJ, Colditz GA, Manson JE. Adiposity as compared with physical activity in predicting mortality among women. N Engl J Med. 2004;351(26):2694&#x2013;2703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Byrne NM. Physical activity and muscle function but not resting energy expenditure impact on weight gain. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(1):225&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, McCarthy JP, Bamman MM. Effects of resistance training on older adults. Sports Med. 2004;34(5):329&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley BF, Roth SM. Strength training in the elderly: effects on risk factors for age- related diseases. Sports Med. 2000;30(4):249&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11048773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I. Influence of Sarcopenia on the Development of Physical Disability: The Cardiovascular Health Study. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 2006;54(1):56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16420198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Heymsfield SB, Ross R. Low relative skeletal muscle mass (sarcopenia) in older persons is associated with functional impairment and physical disability. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50(5):889&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keith SW, Redden DT, Katzmarzyk PT, et al. Putative contributors to the secular increase in obesity: exploring the roads less traveled. Int J Obes (Lond) 2006;30(11):1585&#x2013;1594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16801930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CG, Carr MC, Murdoch SJ, et al. Adipokines, inflammation, and visceral adiposity across the menopausal transition: a prospective study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009;94(4):1104&#x2013;1110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levinger I, Goodman C, Hare DL, Jerums G, Selig S. The effect of resistance training on functional capacity and quality of life in individuals with high and low numbers of metabolic risk factors. Diabetes Care. 2007;30(9):2205&#x2013;2210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17563342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman TG, Wright JA. Maintenance of long-term weight loss: future directions. Quest. 2004;56:105&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauro M, Taylor V, Wharton S, Sharma AM. Barriers to obesity treatment. European Journal of Internal Medicine. 2008;19(3):173&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArdle WD, Katch FI, Katch VL. Exercise physiology: energy, nutrition, and human performance. 6. Baltimore (MD): Lippincott, Williams, and Wilkins; 2007. pp. 198&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metcalfe L, Lohman T, Going S, et al. Postmenopausal women and exercise for the prevention of osteoporosis: The Bone Estrogen, and Strength Training (BEST) study. ACSM&#x2019;s Health and Fitness Journal. 2001;5(3):6&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson ME, Rejeski WJ, Blair SN, et al. Physical activity and public health in older adults: recommendation from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1435&#x2013;1445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols JF, Omizo DK, Peterson KK, Nelson KP. Efficacy of heavy-resistance training for active women over sixty: muscular strength, body composition, and program adherence. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1993;41(3):205&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8440838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rana JS, Li TY, Manson JE, Hu FB. Adiposity compared with physical inactivity and risk of type 2 diabetes in women. Diabetes Care. 2007;30(1):53&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17192333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan AS, Pratley RE, Elahi D, Goldberg AP. Resistive training increases fat-free mass and maintains RMR despite weight loss in postmenopausal women. J Appl Physiol. 1995;79(3):818&#x2013;823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8567523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan AS, Pratley RE, Goldberg AP, Elahi D. Resistive training increases insulin action in postmenopausal women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1996;51(5):M199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8808989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Jensen MD, Kugler KC, Jeffery RW, Leon AS. Strength training for obesity prevention in midlife women. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2003;27(3):326&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd PR, Kahn BB. Glucose transporters and insulin action--implications for insulin resistance and diabetes mellitus. N Engl J Med. 1999;341(4):248&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10413738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge M-P, Bjorntorp P. Hormonal Influences on Human Body Composition. In: Heymsfield S, Lohman T, Wang Z, Going S, editors. Human Body Composition. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2005. pp. 331&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternfeld B, Bhat AK, Wang H, Sharp T, Quesenberry CP., Jr Menopause, physical activity, and body composition/fat distribution in midlife women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(7):1195&#x2013;1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16015138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternfeld B, Wang H, Quesenberry CP, Jr, et al. Physical activity and changes in weight and waist circumference in midlife women: findings from the Study of Women&#x2019;s Health Across the Nation. Am J Epidemiol. 2004;160(9):912&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15496544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira PJ, Going SB, Houtkooper LB, et al. Resistance training in postmenopausal women with and without hormone therapy. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(4):555&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12673136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Vanheest JL, Forsythe CE. Diet and exercise for weight loss: a review of current issues. Sports Med. 2005;35(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15651909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf AM, Manson JE, Coldtz GA. The economic impact of overweight, obesity, and weight loss. In: Eckel R, editor. Obesity: Mechanisms and Clinical Management. Portland: Lippincott, Williams and Wilkens; 2002. p. 6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>