<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">25968470</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1662-4033</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obesity facts</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obes Facts</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Endurance and Endurance Strength Training on Body Composition and Physical Capacity in Women with Abdominal Obesity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>175</StartPage><EndPage>187</EndPage><MedlinePgn>175-87</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000431002</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the effects of endurance training with endurance strength training on the anthropometric, body composition, physical capacity, and circulatory parameters in obese women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">44 women with abdominal obesity were randomized into groups A and B, and asked to perform endurance (A) and endurance strength training (B) for 3 months, 3 times/week, for 60 min. Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry and Graded Exercise Test were performed before and after training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant decreases in body mass, BMI, total body fat, total body fat mass, and waist and hip circumference were observed after both types of intervention. Marked increases in total body lean and total body fat-free mass were documented in group B. In both groups, significant increases in peak oxygen uptake, time to exhaustion, maximal work rate, and work rate at ventilatory threshold were accompanied by noticeably decreased resting heart rate, resting systolic blood pressure, and resting and exercise diastolic blood pressure. No significant differences were noticed between groups for the investigated parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings demonstrate evidence for a favorable and comparable effect of 3-month endurance and endurance strength training on anthropometric parameters, body composition, physical capacity, and circulatory system function in women with abdominal obesity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2015 S. Karger GmbH, Freiburg.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skrypnik</LastName><ForeName>Damian</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Metabolic Disorders and Hypertension, University of Medical Sciences, Pozna&#x144;, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogda&#x144;ski</LastName><ForeName>Pawe&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#x105;dry</LastName><ForeName>Edyta</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karolkiewicz</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratajczak</LastName><ForeName>Marzena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kry&#x15b;ciak</LastName><ForeName>Jakub</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pupek-Musialik</LastName><ForeName>Danuta</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walkowiak</LastName><ForeName>Jaros&#x142;aw</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Obes Facts</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101469429</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1662-4025</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015502" MajorTopicYN="N">Absorptiometry, Photon</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000886" MajorTopicYN="N">Anthropometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001642" MajorTopicYN="N">Bicycling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056128" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity, Abdominal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25968470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5652894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000431002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000431002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Obesity: Preventing and Managing the Global Epidemic, WHO Technical Report Series number 894. Geneva: WHO; 2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11234459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane MM, Stevens GA, Cowan MJ, Danaei G, Lin JK, Paciorek CJ, Singh GM, Gutierrez HR, Lu Y, Bahalim AN, Farzadfar F, Riley LM, Ezzati M, Global Burden of Metabolic Risk Factors of Chronic Diseases Collaborating Group (Body Mass Index) National, regional, and global trends in body-mass index since 1980: systematic analysis of health examination surveys and epidemiological studies with 960 country-years and 9.1 million participants. Lancet. 2011;377:557&#x2013;567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4472365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21295846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge MP, Heymsfield SB. Overweight and obesity status are linked to lower life expectancy. Nutr Rev. 2003;61:313&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14552067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walls HL, Backholer K, Proietto J, McNeil JJ. Obesity and trends in life expectancy. J Obes. 2012;2012:107989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3359718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22655173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen DM, El-Serag HB. The epidemiology of obesity. Gastroenterol Clin North Am. 2010;39:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2833287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20202574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein EA, Trogdon JG, Cohen JW, Dietz W. Annual medical spending attributable to obesity: payer-and service-specific estimates. Health Aff. 2009;28:w822&#x2013;w831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19635784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein S, Burke LE, Bray GA, Blair S, Allison DB, Pi-Sunyer X, Hong Y, Eckel RH. Clinical implications of obesity with specific focus on cardiovascular disease: a statement for professionals from the American Heart Association Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism: Endorsed by the American College of Cardiology Foundation. Circulation. 2004;110:2952&#x2013;2967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15509809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing RR, Lang W, Wadden TA, Safford M, Knowler WC, Bertoni AG, Hill JO, Brancati FL, Peters A, Wagenknecht L. Benefits of modest weight loss in improving cardiovascular risk factors in overweight and obese individuals with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2011;34:1481&#x2013;1486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3120182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21593294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR, Powell KE, Blair SN, Franklin BA, Macera CA, Heath GW, Thompson PD, Bauman A. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1423&#x2013;1434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, Lavie CJ, Johannsen NM, Arena R, Earnest CP, O'Keefe JH, Milani RV, Blair SN, Church TS. Physical activity, cardiorespiratory fitness, and exercise training in primary and secondary coronary prevention. Circ J. 2013;77:281&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7027930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23328449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, Manore MM, Rankin JW, Smith BK. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:459&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church TS, Blair SN, Cocreham S, Johannsen N, Johnson W, Kramer K, Mikus CR, Myers V, Nauta M, Rodarte RQ, Sparks L, Thompson A, Earnest CP. Effects of aerobic and resistance training on hemoglobin a1c levels in patients with type 2 diabetes. JAMA. 2010;304:2253&#x2013;2262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, Earnest CP, Blair SN, Church TS. The effect of different doses of aerobic exercise training on endothelial function in postmenopausal women with elevated blood pressure: results from the DREW study. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46:753&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7065031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannsen NM, Swift DL, Lavie CJ, Earnest CP, Blair SN, Church TS. Categorical analysis of the impact of aerobic and resistance exercise training, alone and in combination, on cardiorespiratory fitness levels in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: results from the HART-D study. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:3305&#x2013;3312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3781553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23877979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus WE, Houmard JA, Duscha BD, Knetzger KJ, Wharton MB, McCartney JS, Bales CW, Henes S, Samsa GP, Otvos JD, Kulkarni KR, Slentz CA. Effects of the amount and intensity of exercise on plasma lipoproteins. N Engl J Med. 2002;347:1483&#x2013;1492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12421890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodama S, Tanaka S, Saito K, Shu M, Sone Y, Onitake F, Suzuki E, Shimano H, Yamamoto S, Kondo K, Ohashi Y, Yamada N, Sone H. Effect of aerobic exercise training on serum levels of high-density lipoprotein cholesterol: a meta-analysis. Arch Intern Med. 2007;167:999&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17533202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers VH, McVay MA, Brashear MM, Johannsen NM, Swift DL, Kramer K, Harris MN, Johnson WD, Earnest CP, Church TS. Exercise training and quality of life in individuals with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:1884&#x2013;1890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3687283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23404304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakicic JM. Exercise in the treatment of obesity. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am. 2003;32:967&#x2013;980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14711070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsigos C, Hainer V, Basdevant A, Finer N, Fried M, Mathus-Vliegen E, Micic D, Maislos M, Roman G, Schutz Y, Toplak H, Zahorska-Markiewicz B. Management of obesity in adults: European clinical practice guidelines. Obes Facts. 2008;1:106&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6452117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20054170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winett RA, Carpinelli RN. Potential health-related benefits of resistance training. Prev Med. 2001;33:503&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11676593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancia G, Fagard R, Narkiewicz K, Red&#xf3;n J, Zanchetti A, B&#xf6;hm M, Christiaens T, Cifkova R, De Backer G, Dominiczak A, Galderisi M, Grobbee DE, Jaarsma T, Kirchhof P, Kjeldsen SE, Laurent S, Manolis AJ, Nilsson PM, Ruilope LM, Schmieder RE, Sirnes PA, Sleight P, Viigimaa M, Waeber B, Zannad F, Task Force Members 2013 ESH/ESC guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension. The Task Force for the Management of Arterial Hypertension of the European Society of Hypertension (ESH) and of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) J Hypertens. 2013;31:1281&#x2013;1357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23817082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebeck J, &#xd8;sterg&#xe5;rd T, Rojek A, F&#xfc;chtbauer EM, Lund S, Nielsen S, Praetorius J. Gender-specific effect of physical training on AQP7 protein expression in human adipose tissue. Acta Diabetol. 2012;49((suppl 1)):S215&#x2013;S226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23001483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanal E, Ardic F, Kirac S. Effects of aerobic or combined aerobic resistance exercise on body composition in overweight and obese adults: gender differences. A randomized intervention study. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2013;49:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22569489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Katzmarzyk PT, Ross R. Waist circumference and not body mass index explains obesity-related health risk. Am J Clin Nutr. 2004;79:379&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14985210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis LH, Slentz CA, Bateman LA, Shields AT, Piner LW, Bales CW, Houmard JA, Kraus WE. Effects of aerobic and/or resistance training on body mass and fat mass in overweight or obese adults. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:1831&#x2013;1837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3544497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23019316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman LA, Slentz CA, Willis LH, Shields AT, Piner LW, Bales CW, Houmard JA, Kraus WE. Comparison of aerobic versus resistance exercise training effects on metabolic syndrome (from the Studies of a Targeted Risk Reduction Intervention through De&#xfb01;ned Exercise &#x2013; STRRIDE-AT/RT) Am J Cardiol. 2011;108:838&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3752599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21741606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson LE, Hudson R, Kilpatrick K, Kuk JL, McMillan K, Janiszewski PM, Lee S, Lam M, Ross R. Effects of exercise modality on insulin resistance and functional limitation in older adults: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Intern Med. 2009;169:122&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19171808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saremi A, Shavandi N, Parastesh M, Daneshmand H. Twelve-week aerobic training decreases chemerin level and improves cardiometabolic risk factors in overweight and obese men. Asian J Sports Med. 2010;1:151&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3289180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22375203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo DI, So WY, Ha S, Yoo EJ, Kim D, Singh H, Fahs CA, Rossow L, Bemben DA, Bemben MG, Kim E. Effects of 12 weeks of combined exercise training on visfatin and metabolic syndrome factors in obese middle-aged women. J Sports Sci Med. 2011;10:222&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schjerve IE, Tyldum GA, Tj&#xf8;nna AE, St&#xf8;len T, Loennechen JP, Hansen HE, Haram PM, Heinrich G, Bye A, Najjar SM, Smith GL, Sl&#xf8;rdahl SA, Kemi OJ, Wisl&#xf8;ff U. Both aerobic endurance and strength training programmes improve cardiovascular health in obese adults. Clin Sci. 2008;115:283&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18338980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghroubi S, Elleuch H, Chikh T, Kaffel N, Abid M, Elleuch MH. Physical training combined with dietary measures in the treatment of adult obesity. A comparison of two protocols. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2009;52:394&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19623684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S, Oh PI, Brooks D. Effect of combined aerobic and resistance training versus aerobic training alone in individuals with coronary artery disease: a meta-analysis. Eur J Prevent Cardiol. 2012;19:81&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21450617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulens M, Vansant G, Lysens R, Claessens AL, Muls E. Exercise capacity in lean versus obese women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2001;11:305&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11696216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie CJ, Milani RV. Effects of cardiac rehabilitation, exercise training, and weight reduction on exercise capacity, coronary risk factors, behavioral characteristics, and quality of life in obese coronary patients. Am J Cardiol. 1997;79:397&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9052338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyers DA, Goldberg AP, Bleecker ML, Coon PJ, Drinkwater DT, Bleecker ER. Relationship of obesity and physical fitness to cardiopulmonary and metabolic function in healthy older men. J Gerontol. 1991;46:57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1997574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorge ML, de Oliveira VN, Resende NM, Paraiso LF, Calixto A, Diniz AL, Resende ES, Ropelle ER, Carvalheira JB, Espindola FS, Jorge PT, Geloneze B. The effects of aerobic, resistance, and combined exercise on metabolic control, inflammatory markers, adipocytokines, and muscle insulin signaling in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Metabolism. 2011;60:1244&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Park JH, Kwon YC, Kim HS, Yoon MS, Park HT. The effect of combined aerobic and resistance exercise training on abdominal fat in obese middle-aged women. J Physiol Anthropol Appl Human Sci. 2003;22:129&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiorana A, O'Driscoll G, Cheetham C, Collis J, Goodman C, Rankin S, Taylor R, Green D. Combined aerobic and resistance exercise training improves functional capacity and strength in CHF. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:1565&#x2013;1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg SL, Reusch JE, Bauer TA, Jeffers BW, Hiatt WR, Regensteiner JG. Effects of exercise training on oxygen uptake kinetic responses in women with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 1999;22:1640&#x2013;1646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10526728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucotti P, Monti LD, Setola E, Galluccio E, Gatti R, Bosi E, Piatti P. Aerobic and resistance training effects compared to aerobic training alone in obese type 2 diabetic patients on diet treatment. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2011;94:395&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21890226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berent R, von Duvillard SP, Crouse SF, Sinzinger H, Green JS, Schmid P. Resistance training dose response in combined endurance-resistance training in patients with cardiovascular disease: a randomized trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2011;92:1527&#x2013;1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21872843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes WM, Souza PR, Pinheiro MH, Irigoyen MC, Medeiros A, Koike MK. Exercise training program based on minimum weekly frequencies: effects on blood pressure and physical fitness in elderly hypertensive patients. Rev Bras Fisioter. 2012;16:114&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22481693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braz NF, Carneiro MV, Oliveira-Ferreira F, Arrieiro AN, Amorim FT, Lima MM, Avelar NC, Lacerda AC, Peixoto MF. Influence of aerobic training on cardiovascular and metabolic parameters in elderly hypertensive women. Int J Prev Med. 2012;3:652&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23024855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro LZ, Fiani CR, Freitas MC, Zanetti ML, Foss MC. Decrease in blood pressure, body mass index and glycemia after aerobic training in elderly women with type 2 diabetes. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2010;95:563&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20922265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Park JH, Kwon YC, Yoon MS, Kim CS. The effect of long-term aerobic exercise on maximal oxygen consumption, left ventricular function and serum lipids in elderly women. J Physiol Anthropol. 2003;22:11&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12672978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, Johannsen NM, Tudor-Locke C, Earnest CP, Johnson WD, Blair SN, S&#xe9;n&#xe9;chal M, Church TS. Exercise training and habitual physical activity: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Prev Med. 2012;43:629&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3504348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23159258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seals DR, Silverman HG, Reiling MJ, Davy KP. Effect of regular aerobic exercise on elevated blood pressure in postmenopausal women. Am J Cardiol. 1997;80:49&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9205019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kargarfard M, Rouzbehani R, Basati F. Effects of exercise rehabilitation on blood pressure of patients after myocardial infarction. Int J Prev Med. 2010;1:124&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21566773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary S, Kang MK, Sandhu JS. The effects of aerobic versus resistance training on cardiovascular fitness in obese sedentary females. Asian J Sports Med. 2010;1:177&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3289184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22375205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso CG, Jr, Gomides RS, Queiroz AC, Pinto LG, da Silveira Lobo F, Mion D, Jr, de Moraes Forjaz CL. Acute and chronic effects of aerobic and resistance exercise on ambulatory blood pressure. Clinics. 2010;65:317&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20360924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>