<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16098231</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-7075</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of resistance training and protein supplementation on bone turnover in young adult women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The strength of aging bone depends on the balance between the resorption and formation phases of the remodeling process. The purpose of this study was to examine the interaction of two factors with the potential to exert opposing influences on bone turnover, resistance exercise training and high dietary protein intake. It was hypothesized that resistance training by young, healthy, untrained women with protein intakes near recommended levels (0.8 g.kg(-1).d(-1)) would promote bone formation and/or inhibit bone resorption, and that subsequent supplementation to provide 2.4 g protein.kg(-1).d(-1) would reverse these effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Bone formation was assessed with serum bone-specific alkaline phosphatase (BAP) and osteocalcin (OC), and bone resorption with urinary calcium and deoxypyridinoline (DPD). Biochemical, strength, anthropometric, dietary, and physical activity data were obtained from 24 healthy, untrained, eumenorrheic women (18-29 y) at baseline, after eight weeks of resistance training (3 d.wk(-1), approximately 1 hr.d(-1); 3 sets, 6-10 repetitions, 13 exercises, 75-85% maximum voluntary contraction), and after 12 weeks of resistance training and 10 days of protein/placebo supplementation. Subjects were randomized (double-blind) to either a high protein (HP) or training control (TC) group and, during the final 10 days, consumed either enough purified whey protein to bring daily protein intake to 2.4 g.kg(-1).d(-1), or an equivalent dose of isoenergetic, carbohydrate placebo.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Strength, lean tissue mass, and DPD increased significantly in both groups over time, while percent body fat and BAP decreased (repeated measures ANOVA, p &lt; or = 0.05, Bonferroni correction). No significant changes were observed for serum OC or urinary calcium, and no significant group (TC, HP) x time (baseline, week 8, week 12) interactions emerged for any of the biochemical measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">(1) Twelve weeks of high-intensity resistance training did not appear to enhance bone formation or inhibit bone resorption in young adult women, as assessed by biochemical markers of bone metabolism. (2) Subsequent maintenance of a high protein intake for 10 days in these regularly-training, calcium-replete women also showed no effects on bone metabolism.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mullins</LastName><ForeName>Nicole M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Performance and Exercise Science, Youngstown State University, Youngstown, OH 44555, USA. nmullins@ysu.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinning</LastName><ForeName>Wayne E</ForeName><Initials>WE</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2005</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-7075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1208950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-2-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1743-7075-2-19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Block JE, Smith R. Overview of exercise and bone mass. In: Genant HK, editor. Osteoporosis Update 1987. Berkeley, CA: University Press; 1987. pp. 267&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomfield SA. Changes in musculoskeletal structure with prolonged bed rest. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9044223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holick MF. Perspective on the impact of weightlessness on calcium and bone metabolism. Bone. 1998:105&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1016/S8756-3282(98)00014-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S8756-3282(98)00014-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9600764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimura R, Ashizawa N, Watanabe M, Mukai N, Amagai H, Fukubayashi T, Hayashi K, Tokuyama K, Suzuki M. Effect of resistance exercise training on bone formation and resorption in young male subjects assessed by biomarkers of bone metabolism. J Bone Miner Res. 1997;12:656&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9101378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson PB, Protas EJ, LeBlanc AD, Schneider VS, Evans HJ. Effects of weight lifting on bone mineral density in premenopausal women. J Bone Miner Res. 1990;5:153&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2316403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menkes A, Mazel S, Redmond RA, Koffler K, Libanti CR, Gundberg CM, Zizic TM, Hagberg JM, Pratley RE, Hurley BF. Strength training increases regional bone mineral density and bone remodeling in middle-aged and older men. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74:2478&#x2013;2484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8335581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson ME, Fiatarone MA, Morganti CM, Trice I, Greenburg RA, Evans WJ. Effects of high-intensity strength training on multiple risk factors for osteoporotic fractures: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Assoc. 1994;272:1909&#x2013;1914. doi: 10.1001/jama.272.24.1909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.272.24.1909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7990242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruitt LA, Jackson RA, Bartels RL, Lehnhard HL. Weight-training effects on bone mineral density in early postmenopausal women. J Bone Miner Res. 1992;7:179&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1570762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rockwell JC, Sorensen DM, Baker S, Leahey D, Stock JL, Michaels J, Baran DT. Weight training decreases vertebral bone density in premenopausal women: a prospective study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1990;71:988&#x2013;993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2401722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan AS, Treuth MS, Rubin MA, Miller JP, Nicklas BJ, Landis DM, Pratley RE, Libanati CR, Gundberg CM, Hurley BF. Effects of strength training on bone mineral density: hormonal and bone turnover relationships. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77:1678&#x2013;1684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7836186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman T, Going S, Pamenter R, Hall M, Boyden T, Houtkooper L, Ritenbaugh C, Bare L, Hill A, Aickin M. Effects of resistance training on regional and total bone mineral density in premenopausal women: a randomized prospective study. J Bone Miner Res. 1995;10:1015&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7484276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snow-Harter C, Bouxsein M, Lewis B, Carter D, Marcus R. Effects of resistance and endurance exercise on bone mineral status of young women: a randomized exercise intervention trial. J Bone Miner Res. 1992;7:761&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1642145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben DA, Fetters NL, Bemben MG, Navabi N, Koh ET. Musculoskeletal responses to high- and low-intensity resistance training in early postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1949&#x2013;1957. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200011000-00020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200011000-00020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braith RW, Mills RM, Welsch MA, Keller JW, Pollock ML. Resistance exercise training restores bone mineral density in heart transplant recipients. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1996;28:1471&#x2013;1477. doi: 10.1016/S0735-1097(96)00347-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0735-1097(96)00347-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8917260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Osteoporosis Foundation Osteoporosis: review of the evidence for prevention, diagnosis, and treatment and cost effective analysis. Osteoporos Int. 1998. pp. 1&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abelow BJ, Holford TR, Insogna KL. Cross-sectional association between dietary animal protein and hip fracture. Calcif Tiss Int . 1992;50:14&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1007/BF00297291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00297291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1739864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feskanich D, Willett WC, Stampfer MJ, Colditz GA. Protein consumption and bone fractures in women. Am J Epidemiol. 1996;143:472&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8610662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frassetto LA, Todd KM, Morris RC, Jr, Sebastian A. Worldwide incidence of hip fracture in elderly women: relation to consumption of animal and vegetable foods. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2000;55:M585&#x2013;M592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11034231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barr SI, Prior JC, Janelle KC, Lentle BC. Spinal bone mineral density in premenopausal vegetarian and nonvegetarian women: cross-sectional and prospective comparisons. J Am Diet Assoc. 1998;98:760&#x2013;765. doi: 10.1016/S0002-8223(98)00172-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-8223(98)00172-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9664916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau EM, Kwok T, Woo J, Ho SC. Bone mineral density in Chinese elderly female vegetarians, vegans, lacto-vegetarians and omnivores. Europ J Clin Nutr. 1998;52:60&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1600516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1600516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9481534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munger RG, Cerhan JR, Chiu BC. Prospective study of dietary protein intake and risk of hip fracture in postmenopausal women. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;69:147&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9925137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerstetter JE, Mitnick ME, Gundberg CM, Caseria DM, Ellison AF, Carpenter TO, Insogna KL. Changes in bone turnover in young women consuming different levels of dietary protein. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1999;84:1052&#x2013;1055. doi: 10.1210/jc.84.3.1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.84.3.1052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10084594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapses SA, Robins SP, Schwartz EI, Chowdhury H. Short-term changes in calcium but not protein intake alter the rate of bone resorption in healthy subjects as assessed by urinary pyridinium cross-link excretion. J Nutr. 1995;125:2814&#x2013;2821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7472661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordin BE, Need AG, Steurer T, Morris HA, Chatterton BE, Horowitz M. Nutrition, osteoporosis, and aging. Ann NY Acad Sci. 1998;854:336&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9928442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barzel US. The skeleton as an ion exchange system: implications for the role of acid-base imbalance in the genesis of osteoporosis. J Bone Miner Res. 1995;10:1431&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8686497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerstetter JE, Allen LH. Protein intake and calcium homeostasis. Adv Nutr Res. 1994;9:167&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7747665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barzel US, Massey LK. Excess dietary protein can adversely affect bone. J Nutr. 1998;128:1051&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9614169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins RC. Dr Atkins' New Diet Revolution. New York: Morrow, William and Company; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sears B, Lawren B. Enter the zone: a dietary road map. New York: Harper Collins; 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steen SN. Precontest strategies of a male bodybuilder. Int J Sport Nutr. 1991;1:69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1844404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faber M, Benade AJ. Nutrient intake and dietary supplementation in bodybuilders. S Afr Med J. 1987;72:831&#x2013;834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3424028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandjean AC. Diets of elite athletes: has the discipline of sports nutrition made an impact? J Nutr. 1997. pp. 874&#x2013;877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9164255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short SH, Short WR. Four-year study of university athletes' dietary intake. J Am Diet Assoc. 1983;82:632&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6853938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, MacDougall JD, Atkinson SA. Influence of protein intake and training status on nitrogen balance and lean body mass. J Appl Physiol. 1988;64:187&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3356636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern EB, Bielinski RN, Schutz Y. Effects of exaggerated amino acid and protein supply in man. Experientia. 1991;47:168&#x2013;172. doi: 10.1007/BF01945420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01945420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2001721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon PWR. Is increased dietary protein necessary or beneficial for individuals with a physically active lifestyle? Nutr Rev. 1996;54:S169&#x2013;S175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8700446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Maggi SP, Williams BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Increased rates of muscle protein turnover and amino acid transport after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1995;268:E514&#x2013;E520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesley A, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA, Atkinson SA, Smith K. Changes in human muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1992;73:1383&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1280254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Gibala MJ, Tarnopolsky MA, MacDonald JR, Interisano SA, Yarasheski KE. The time course for elevated muscle protein synthesis following heavy resistance exercise. C Can J Appl Physiol . 1995;20:480&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8563679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1997;273:E99&#x2013;E107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Nutrition Board, Institute of Medicine . Dietary Reference Intakes for Energy, Carbohydrate, Fiber, Fat, Fatty Acids, Cholesterol, Protein, and Amino Acids (Macronutrients) Washington DC: The National Academies Press; 2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12449285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon PWR, Tarnopolsky MA, MacDougall JD, Atkinson SA. Protein requirements and muscle mass/strength changes during intensive training in novice body builders. J Appl Physiol. 1992;73:767&#x2013;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1400008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Atkinson SA, MacDougall JD, Chesley A, Philllips S, Schwarcz HP. Evaluation of protein requirements for trained strength athletes. J Appl Physiol. 1992;73:1986&#x2013;1995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1474076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon PW. Beyond the zone: protein needs of active individuals. J Am Coll Nutr. 2000. pp. 513&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11023001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Protein requirements in strength sports. Nutrition. 2004;20:689&#x2013;695. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15212752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munro HN. Introduction to part II. In: Munro HN, Allison JB, editor. Mammalian Protein Metabolism. Vol. 2. New York: Academic Press; 1964. pp. 1&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerstetter JE, O'Brien KO, Insogna KL. Dietary protein affects intestinal calcium absorption. Am J Clin Nutr. 1998;68:859&#x2013;865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9771863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitano T, Esashi T, Azami S. Effect of protein intake on mineral (calcium magnesium, and phosphorus) balance in Japanese males. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol. 1988;34:387&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3236083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center J, Eisman J. The epidemiology and pathogenesis of osteoporosis. Baillieres Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1997;11:23&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9222485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calloway DH, Kurzer MS. Menstrual cycle and protein requirements of women. J Nutr. 1982;12:356&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7057271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zitterman A, Schwarz I, Scheld K, Sudhop T, Berthold HK, von Bergmann K, van der Ven H, Stehle P. Physiologic fluctuations of serum estradiol levels influence biochemical markers of bone resorption in young women. J Clin Endocrin Metab. 2000;85:95&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1210/jc.85.1.95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.85.1.95</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10634371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aurbach GD, Marx SJ, Spiegal AM. Metabolic bone disease. In: Wilson JD, Foster DW, editor. Williams' Textbook of Endocrinology. 8. Philadelphia: WB Saunders; 1992. pp. 1477&#x2013;1510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmas PD, Eastell R, Garnero P, Seibel MJ, Stepan J. The use of biochemical markers of bone turnover in osteoporosis. Osteoporos Int. 2000:2&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1007/s001980070002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s001980070002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11193237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis JF, Haskell W, Wood PD, Fortmann SP, Rogers T, Blair SN, Paffenbarger RS., Jr Physical activity assessment methodology in the Five-City Project. Am J Epidemiol. 1985;121:91&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3964995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML, Ward A. Generalized equations for predicting body density of women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1980;12:175&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7402053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brozek JF, Grande F, Anderson JT, Keys A. Densitometric analyses of body composition: revision of some quantitative assumptions. Ann NY Acad Sci. 1963;110:113&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14062375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman TG, Roche AF, Martorell R. Anthropometric Standardization Reference Manual. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo MS, Eyre DR, Gundberg CM. Molecular basis and clinical application of biological markers of bone turnover. Endoc Rev. 1996;17:333&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1210/er.17.4.333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/er.17.4.333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8854049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christenson RH. Biochemical markers of bone metabolism: an overview. Clin Biochem. 1997;30:573&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1016/S0009-9120(97)00113-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0009-9120(97)00113-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9455610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seibel MJ, Woitge HW. Basic principles and clinical applications of biochemical markers of bone metabolism. J Clin Densitom. 1999;2:299&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1385/JCD:2:3:299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1385/JCD:2:3:299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10548826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M, Karpovich PV. Isotonic and isometric forces of forearm flexors and extensors. J Appl Physiol. 1966;21:1435&#x2013;1437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5916693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke HH, Clarke DH. Developmental and Adapted Physical Education. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall; 1963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegsted M, Schuette SA, Zemel MB, Linkswiler HM. Urinary calcium and calcium balance in young men as affected by level of protein and phosphorus intake. J Nutr. 1981;111:553&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7205408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt WM, Bloomfield SA, Little KD, Nelson ME, Yingling VR. American College of Sports Medicine position stand: physical activity and bone health. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:1985&#x2013;1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15514517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruitt LA, Taaffe DR, Marcus R. Effects of a one-year high-intensity versus low-intensity resistance training on bone mineral density in older women. J Bone Miner Res. 1995;10:1788&#x2013;1795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8592957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akesson K, Lau KH, Johnston P, Imperio E, Baylink DJ. Effects of short-term calcium depletion and repletion on biochemical markers of bone turnover in young adult women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1998;83:1921&#x2013;1927. doi: 10.1210/jc.83.6.1921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.83.6.1921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9626120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashizawa N, Ouchi G, Fujimara R, Yoshida Y, Tokuyama K, Suzuki M. Effects of a single bout of resistance exercise on calcium and bone metabolism in untrained young males. Calcif Tiss Int. 1998;62:104&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1007/s002239900402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s002239900402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9437042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegsted M, Linkswiler HM. Long-term effects of level of protein intake on calcium metabolism in young adult women. J Nutr. 1981;111:244&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7463168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuette SA, Zemel MB, Linkswiler HM. Studies on the mechanism of protein-induced hypercalciuria in older men and women. J Nutr. 1980;110:305&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7354401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaney RP. Excess dietary protein may not adversely affect bone. J Nutr. 1998;128:1054&#x2013;1057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9614170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriguti JC, Ferriolli E, Marchnini JS. Urinary calcium loss in elderly men on a vegetable:animal (1:1) high-protein diet. Gerontology. 1999;45:274&#x2013;278. doi: 10.1159/000022101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000022101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10460989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer H, Kramer L, DeBartolo M, Norris C, Osis D. Further studies of the effect of a high protein diet as meat on calcium metabolism. Am J Clin Nutr. 1983;37:924&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6846239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz J. Calcium balance and acid-base status of women as affected by increased protein intake and by sodium bicarbonate ingestion. Am J Clin Nutr. 1984;39:281&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6320628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaney RP, Recker RR, Ryan RA. Urinary calcium in perimenopausal women: normative values. Osteoporos Int. 1999;9:13&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1007/s001980050110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s001980050110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10367024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaney RP. Utilization of calcium and its relationship to protein in ensuring bone health. 48th Annual Meeting of the American College of Sports Medicine: Baltimore. 2001.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>