<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34917272</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1984-0659</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>Spec 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sleep science (Sao Paulo, Brazil)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sleep Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of six weeks high-intensity interval training and resistance training in adults with obesity and sleep related breathing disorders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>41</StartPage><EndPage>48</EndPage><MedlinePgn>41-48</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5935/1984-0063.20200076</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The effects of high-intensity interval training (HIIT) combined with resistance training (RT) in adults with obesity and sleep-related breathing disorders (SRBDs) is limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to examine the effects of HIIT combined with RT on subjective sleep disorders in adults with obesity and SRBDs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study was a pre- and post-test design. Seventeen adults with obesity and SRBDs were recruited into the study. They received 24 minutes of HIIT and 30 minutes of RT, 3 times/week for 6 weeks. The Epworth sleepiness scale (daytime sleepiness), Berlin questionnaire (snoring and daytime sleepiness category), estimated maximum oxygen consumption (VO<sub>2</sub>max), muscle strength using 1-repetition maximum, anthropometric variables, and blood biomarkers were examined at baseline and after 6 weeks of training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The Epworth sleepiness scale, Berlin questionnaire (daytime sleepiness category), and the number of risks associated with sleep apnea using the Berlin questionnaire were significantly decreased after 6 weeks of training (all p&lt;0.01). The estimated VO<sub>2</sub>max and muscle strength were significantly increased at Week 6 (all <i>p</i>&lt;0.05). Body weight, body mass index, % body fat, and hip circumference were significantly decreased at Week 6 (all <i>p</i>&lt;0.05). No significant changes were observed in blood biomarkers, except for fasting blood glucose (p&lt;0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Six weeks of HIIT combined with RT has beneficial effects on subjective sleep disorders, estimated VO<sub>2</sub>max, muscle strength, and most anthropometric variables in adults with obesity and SRBDs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longlalerng</LastName><ForeName>Khomkrip</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walailak University, School of Allied Health Science, Department of Physical Therapy - Thasala - Nakhon Si Thammarat - Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakeaw</LastName><ForeName>Anucha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walailak University, School of Allied Health Science, Department of Physical Therapy - Thasala - Nakhon Si Thammarat - Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charawae</LastName><ForeName>Asmu-E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walailak University, School of Allied Health Science, Department of Physical Therapy - Thasala - Nakhon Si Thammarat - Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reantong</LastName><ForeName>Powpachara</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walailak University, School of Allied Health Science, Department of Physical Therapy - Thasala - Nakhon Si Thammarat - Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prangyim</LastName><ForeName>Usamawee</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walailak University, School of Allied Health Science, Department of Physical Therapy - Thasala - Nakhon Si Thammarat - Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeenduang</LastName><ForeName>Nutjaree</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Walailak University, School of Allied Health Science, Department of Medical Technology - Thasala - Nakhon Si Thammarat - Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Sleep Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101598477</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1984-0063</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-intensity Interval Training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep-related Breathing Disorders</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34917272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5935/1984-0063.20200076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McNicholas WT, Levy P. Sleep-related breathing disorders: definitions and measurements. Eur Respir J. 2000 Jun;15(6):988&#x2013;989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10885413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsara V, Amfilochiou A, Papagrigorakis MJ, Georgopoulos D, Liolios E. Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of sleep-related breathing disorders in adults and children. Definition and classification of sleep related breathing disorders in adults: different types and indications for sleep studies (Part 1) Hippokratia. 2009 Jul;13(3):187&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2765300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19918312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bananian S, Lehrman SG, Maguire G P. Cardiovascular consequences of sleep-related breathing disorders. Heart Dis. 2002 Sep/Oct;4(5):296&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12350242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirrakhimov AE, Sooronbaev T, Mirrakhimov EM. Prevalence of obstructive sleep apnea in Asian adults: a systematic review of the literature. BMC Pulm Med. 2013;13:10&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3585751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23433391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kryger MH, Roth T, Dement WC. Principles and practice of sleep medicine. Philadelphia: Saunders; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui MM, Lam DC, Ip MSM. Significance of endothelial dysfunction in sleep-related breathing disorder. Respirology. 2013 Jan;18(1):39&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22712467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng SSS, Chan RSM, Woo J, Chan TO, Cheung BHK, Sea MMM, et al. A randomized controlled study to examine the effect of a lifestyle modification program in OSA. Chest. 2015 Nov;148(5):1193&#x2013;1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25763792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrosielski DA, Papandreou C, Patil S P, Salas-Salvad&#xf3; J. Diet and exercise in the management of obstructive sleep apnoea and cardiovascular disease risk. Eur Respir Rev. 2017 Jun;26(144):160110&#x2013;160110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5559698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28659501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiello KD, Caughey WG, Nelluri B, Sharma A, Mookadam F, Mookadam M. Effect of exercise training on sleep apnea: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Respir Med. 2016 Jul;116:85&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27296826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes M, Goldsworthy UR, Cary BA, Hill CJ. A diet and exercise program to improve clinical outcomes in patients with obstructive sleep apnea--a feasibility study. J Clin Sleep Med. 2009 Oct;5(5):409&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19961023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand&#xe3;o GS, Gomes GSBF, Brand&#xe3;o GS, Callou Sampaio AA, Donner CF, Oliveira LVF, et al. Home exercise improves the quality of sleep and daytime sleepiness of elderlies: a randomized controlled trial. Multidiscip Respir Med. 2018 Jan;13:2&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5767972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bughin F, Desplan M, Mestejanot C, Picot MC, Roubille F, Jaffuel D, et al. Effects of an individualized exercise training program on severity markers of obstructive sleep apnea syndrome: a randomised controlled trial. Sleep Med. 2020 Feb;70:33&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32193052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Liu Y, Zheng H, Liu G, Mei A. Effects of 12 weeks of regular aerobic exercises on autonomic nervous system in obstructive sleep apnea syndrome patients. Sleep Breath. 2018 Dec;22(4):1189&#x2013;1195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30328014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weston KS, Wisl&#xf8;ff U, Coombes JS. High-intensity interval training in patients with lifestyle-induced cardiometabolic disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2014 Aug;48(16):1227&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24144531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos JS, Dalleck LC, Tjonna AE, Beetham KS, Coombes JS. The impact of high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training on vascular function: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015 May;45(5):679&#x2013;692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Colleage of Sports Medicine (ACSM) ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 9th. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer/ Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villareal DT, Aguirre L, Gurney AB, Waters DL, Sinacore DR, Colombo E, et al. Aerobic or resistance exercise, or both, in dieting obese older adults. N Engl J Med. 2017 May;376(20):1943&#x2013;1955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5552187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28514618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) Regional Office for the Western Pacific. The Asia-Pacific perspective: redefining obesity and its treatment. Sydney: Health Communications Australia/WHO; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsen T, Nes BM, Tj&#xf8;nna AE, Engstr&#xf8;m M, St&#xf8;ylen A, Steinshamn S. High-intensity interval training improves obstructive sleep apnoea. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2017 Feb;2(1) bmjsem-2016-000155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5875631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29616142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longlalerng K, Sonsuwan N, Uthaikhup S, Kietwatanachareon S, Kamsaiyai W, Panyasak D, et al. High-intensity interval training combined with resistance training improved apnea-hypopnea index but did not modify oxygen desaturation index and oxygen saturation nadir in obese children with obstructive sleep apnea. Sleep Breath. 2020 Jun;24(2):571&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31338769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banhiran W, Assanasen P, Nopmaneejumruslers C, Metheetrairut C. Epworth sleepiness scale in obstructive sleep disordered breathing: the reliability and validity of the Thai version. Sleep Breath. 2011 Sep;15(3):571&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20835769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suksakorn S, Rattanaumpawan P, Banhiran W, Cherakul N, Chotinaiwattarakul W. Reliability and validity of a Thai version of the Berlin questionnaire in patients with sleep disordered breathing. J Med Assoc Thai. 2014 Mar;97(Suppl 3):S46&#x2013;S56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24772580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams GM. Exercise physiology laboratory manual. 3rd. Boston: McGraw-Hill; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz C, Morris P, Richler J. Effect size estimates: current use, calculations, and interpretation. J Exp Psychol Gen. 2012 Feb;141(1):2&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21823805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline CE, Crowley EP, Ewing GB, Burch JB, Blair SN, Durstine JL, et al. The effect of exercise training on obstructive sleep apnea and sleep quality: a randomized controlled trial. Sleep. 2011 Dec;34(12):1631&#x2013;1640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3208839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22131599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman JE, Von Essen SG, Fuchs RH, McElligott M. Exercise training effect on obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Sleep Res Online. 2000;3(3):121&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11382910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi M, Guilan-Nejad TN, Pordanjani AF. Effect of yoga and aerobics exercise on sleep quality in women with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Sleep Sci. 2017 Apr/Jun;10(2):68&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5612039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28966742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengul YS, Ozalevli S, Oztura I, Itil O, Baklan B. The effect of exercise on obstructive sleep apnea: a randomized and controlled trial. Sleep Breath. 2011 Jan;15(1):49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19898884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuomilehto HPI, Sepp&#xe4; JM, Partinen MM, Peltonen M, Gylling H, Tuomilehto JOI, et al. Lifestyle intervention with weight reduction: first-line treatment in mild obstructive sleep apnea. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2009 Feb;179(4):320&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19011153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon JB, Schachter LM, O&#x2019;Brien PE. Predicting sleep apnea and excessive day sleepiness in the severely obese: indicators for polysomnography. Chest. 2003;123(4):1134&#x2013;1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie L, Vishnevsky A, Lavie P. Oxidative stress and systemic inflammation in patients with sleep apnea: role of obesity. Sleep Biol Rhythms. 2007 Mar;5(2):100&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos RVT, Tufik S, De Mello MT. Exercise, sleep and cytokines: is there a relation? Sleep Med Rev. 2007 Jun;11(3):231&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17517356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis GC, Stavrinou P, Fatouros IG, Philippou A, Chatzinikolaou A, Draganidis D, et al. Short-term high-intensity interval exercise training attenuates oxidative stress responses and improves antioxidant status in healthy humans. Food Chem Toxicol. 2013 Nov;61:171&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23747717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell DE, McGuire M, Samis L, Webb KA. General exercise training improves ventilatory and peripheral muscle strength and endurance in chronic airflow limitation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1998 May;157(5 Pt 1):1489&#x2013;1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9603128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parameswaran K, Todd DC, Soth M. Altered respiratory physiology in obesity. Can Respir J. 2006 May/Jun;13(4):203&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2683280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16779465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>