<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32973550</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of High-Intensity Resistance Training on Fitness and Fatness in Older Men With Osteosarcopenia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1014</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1014</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1014</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2020.01014</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To date, there has been no study on the long-term effects of resistance exercise on sarcopenia and obesity indices for people with sarcopenia. The present study thus aimed to determine the effect of 18 months of periodized, high-velocity/intensity/effort progressive resistance training (HIT-RT) on body composition and strength in older men with osteosarcopenia. Using a single-blind, two-group parallel design, 43 community-dwelling men, 72 years and older, with osteopenia and sarcopenia in Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg, Germany, were randomly assigned to two study arms by drawing lots: (1) an exercise group that conducted a consistently supervised periodized high-velocity/intensity/effort protocol (HIT-RT; <i>n</i> = 21) on machines twice a week for 18 months or (2) a control group (CG; <i>n</i> = 22) that maintained their physical activity/exercise habits. Both groups were supplied with protein, cholecalciferol, and calcium according to current recommendations. The study outcomes were lean body mass (LBM), total and abdominal body fat as determined by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry and maximum hip/leg extensor strength as assessed on an isokinetic leg press at baseline and after 8, 12, and 18 months of follow-up. The intention-to-treat principle and multiple imputation were applied to calculated study outcomes. After 18 months of HIT-RT, altogether five participants were lost to follow up (HIT-RT: <i>n</i> = 2, CG: <i>n</i> = 3). The attendance rates (95%) for HIT-RT were high; relevant adverse effects were not observed. Significant effects (i.e., differences between HIT-RT vs. CG) in favor of HIT-RT were determined for LBM (+1.73 kg, 95% CI: +1.13 to +2.32 kg), total body fat mass (-2.44 kg, 95% CI: -1.28 to 3.60 kg), abdominal body fat percentage (-2.68, 95% CI: -1.70 to -3.66), and maximum hip/leg extensor strength (+533 N, 95% CI: +397 to +670 N; all <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001). Even after adjusting for multiple testing, all effects remained significant. Of note, after 8 months of HIT-RT, only slight (LBM and fat indices) to moderate (maximum strength) ongoing effects were observed. Carefully introduced, continuously supervised HIT-RT is an effective, attractive, feasible, and safe method to improve body composition and muscle strength in older community-dwelling men with sarcopenia. However, even when consequently applying principles of exercise intensity progression within the RT protocol, only slight further positive changes were observed after 8 months of exercise.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Kemmler, Kohl, Fr&#xf6;hlich, Engelke, von Stengel and Schoene.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kemmler</LastName><ForeName>Wolfgang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Physics, Friedrich-Alexander University of Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg, Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kohl</LastName><ForeName>Matthias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty Medical and Life Sciences, University of Furtwangen, Villingen-Schwenningen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fr&#xf6;hlich</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science, University of Kaiserslautern, Kaiserslautern, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Engelke</LastName><ForeName>Klaus</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine III, Friedrich-Alexander University of Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg, University Hospital Erlangen, Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>von Stengel</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Physics, Friedrich-Alexander University of Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg, Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoene</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Physics, Friedrich-Alexander University of Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg, Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">older men</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32973550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.01014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acheson K. J., Blondel-Lubrano A., Oguey-Araymon S., Beaumont M., Emady-Azar S., Ammon-Zufferey C., et al. (2011). Protein choices targeting thermogenesis and metabolism. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 93, 525&#x2013;534. 10.3945/ajcn.110.005850, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.110.005850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato M. C., Guarnotta V., Giordano C. (2013). Body composition assessment for the definition of cardiometabolic risk. J. Endocrinol. Investig. 36, 537&#x2013;543. 10.3275/8943, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3275/8943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23612318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baer D. J., Stote K. S., Paul D. R., Harris G. K., Rumpler W. V., Clevidence B. A. (2011). Whey protein but not soy protein supplementation alters body weight and composition in free-living overweight and obese adults. J. Nutr. 141, 1489&#x2013;1494. 10.3945/jn.111.139840, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.111.139840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3145217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21677076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer J., Biolo G., Cederholm T., Cesari M., Cruz-Jentoft A. J., Morley J. E., et al. (2013). Evidence-based recommendations for optimal dietary protein intake in older people: a position paper from the PROT-AGE Study Group. J. Am. Med. Dir. Assoc. 14, 542&#x2013;559. 10.1016/j.jamda.2013.05.021, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2013.05.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23867520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer J. M., Cruz-Jentoft A. J., Fielding R. A., Kanis J. A., Reginster J. Y., Bruyere O., et al. (2019). Is there enough evidence for osteosarcopenic obesity as a distinct entity? A critical literature review. Calcif. Tissue Int. 105, 109&#x2013;124. 10.1007/s00223-019-00561-w, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00223-019-00561-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31098729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner R. N., Koehler K. M., Gallagher D., Romero L., Heymsfield S. B., Ross R. R., et al. (1998). Epidemiology of sarcopenia among the elderly in New Mexico. Am. J. Epidemiol. 147, 755&#x2013;763. 10.1093/oxfordjournals.aje.a009520, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.aje.a009520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9554417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckwee D., Delaere A., Aelbrecht S., Baert V., Beaudart C., Bruyere O., et al. (2019). Exercise interventions for the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia. A systematic umbrella review. J. Nutr. Health Aging 23, 494&#x2013;502. 10.1007/s12603-019-1196-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12603-019-1196-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31233069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendtsen L. Q., Lorenzen J. K., Bendsen N. T., Rasmussen C., Astrup A. (2013). Effect of dairy proteins on appetite, energy expenditure, body weight, and composition: a review of the evidence from controlled clinical trials. Adv. Nutr. 4, 418&#x2013;438. 10.3945/an.113.003723, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/an.113.003723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3941822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23858091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckinx F., Landi F., Cesari M., Fielding R. A., Visser M., Engelke K., et al. (2018). Pitfalls in the measurement of muscle mass: a need for a reference standard. J. Cachexia. Sarcopenia Muscle 9, 269&#x2013;278. 10.1002/jcsm.12268, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5879987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29349935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvani R., Joseph A. M., Adhihetty P. J., Miccheli A., Bossola M., Leeuwenburgh C., et al. (2013). Mitochondrial pathways in sarcopenia of aging and disuse muscle atrophy. Biol. Chem. 394, 393&#x2013;414. 10.1515/hsz-2012-0247, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hsz-2012-0247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3976204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23154422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson S. A., Fulton J. E., Schoenborn C. A., Loustalot F. (2010). Trend and prevalence estimates based on the 2008 physical activity guidelines for Americans. Am. J. Prev. Med. 39, 305&#x2013;313. 10.1016/j.amepre.2010.06.006, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2010.06.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20837280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chungchunlam S. M., Henare S. J., Ganesh S., Moughan P. J. (2015). Dietary whey protein influences plasma satiety-related hormones and plasma amino acids in normal-weight adult women. Eur. J. Clin. Nutr. 69, 179&#x2013;186. 10.1038/ejcn.2014.266, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejcn.2014.266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25563737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. (1988). Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Hillsdale: NJ Lawrence Earlbaum Associate.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft A. J., Baeyens J. P., Bauer J. M., Boirie Y., Cederholm T., Landi F., et al. (2010). Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: report of the European working group on sarcopenia in older people. Age Ageing 39, 412&#x2013;423. 10.1093/ageing/afq034, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afq034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csapo R., Alegre L. M. (2016). Effects of resistance training with moderate vs heavy loads on muscle mass and strength in the elderly: a meta-analysis. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 26, 995&#x2013;1006. 10.1111/sms.12536, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26302881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalle S., Rossmeislova L., Koppo K. (2017). The role of inflammation in age-related sarcopenia. Front. Physiol. 8:1045. 10.3389/fphys.2017.01045, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.01045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5733049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29311975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DESTATIS (2016). &#xc4;ltere Menschen in Deutschland und der EU. (Berlin: Statistisches Bundesamt; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donini L. M., Busetto L., Bauer J. M., Bischoff S., Boirie Y., Cederholm T., et al. (2019). Critical appraisal of definitions and diagnostic criteria for sarcopenic obesity based on a systematic review. Clin. Nutr. 39, 2368&#x2013;2388. 10.1016/j.clnu.2019.11.024, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2019.11.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31813698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DVO (2017). Prophylaxe, Diagnostik und Therapie der OSTEOPOROSE bei postmenopausalen Frauen und bei M&#xe4;nnern. Stuttgart: Schattauer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen E. F. (2010). Cellular mechanisms of bone remodeling. Rev. Endocr. Metab. Disord. 11, 219&#x2013;227. 10.1007/s11154-010-9153-1, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11154-010-9153-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3028072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21188536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentile C. L., Ward E., Holst J. J., Astrup A., Ormsbee M. J., Connelly S., et al. (2015). Resistant starch and protein intake enhances fat oxidation and feelings of fullness in lean and overweight/obese women. Nutr. J. 14:113. 10.1186/s12937-015-0104-2, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12937-015-0104-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26514213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gie&#xdf;ing J. (2008). HIT-Hochintensit&#xe4;tstraining. Arnsberg: Novagenics-Verlag.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hita-Contreras F., Bueno-Notivol J., Martinez-Amat A., Cruz-Diaz D., Hernandez A. V., Perez-Lopez F. R. (2018). Effect of exercise alone or combined with dietary supplements on anthropometric and physical performance measures in community-dwelling elderly people with sarcopenic obesity: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Maturitas 116, 24&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2018.07.007, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2018.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30244776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm S. (1979). A simple sequentially rejective multiple test procedure. Scand. J. Stat. 6, 65&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honaker J., King G., Blackwell M. (2011). Amelia II: a program for missing data. J. Stat. Softw. 45, 1&#x2013;47. 10.18637/jss.v045.i07</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v045.i07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu K. J., Liao C. D., Tsai M. W., Chen C. N. (2019). Effects of exercise and nutritional intervention on body composition, metabolic health, and physical performance in adults with sarcopenic obesity: a meta-analysis. Nutrients 11:2163. 10.3390/nu11092163, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11092163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31505890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Grimm A., Bebenek M., Kohl M., von Stengel S. (2018). Effects of combined whole-body electromyostimulation and protein supplementation on local and overall muscle/fat distribution in older men with sarcopenic obesity: the randomized controlled Franconia Sarcopenic Obesity (FranSO) study. Calcif. Tissue Int. 103, 266&#x2013;277. 10.1007/s00223-018-0424-2, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00223-018-0424-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29675640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Kohl M., Frohlich M., Jakob F., Engelke K., von Stengel S., et al. (2020a). Effects of high intensity resistance training on osteopenia and sarcopenia parameters in older men with osteosarcopenia &#x2010; @one-year results of the randomized controlled Franconian Osteopenia and Sarcopenia Trial (FrOST). J. Bone Miner. Res. 10.1002/jbmr.4027, PMID: [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbmr.4027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32270891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Lauber D., Mayhew J., Wassermann F. (eds.) (2008). Repetition to fatigue to predict 1RM performance. Looking behind the covariates. (G&#xf6;ttingen: Cuvillier Verlag; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Lauber D., Weineck J., Hensen J., Kalender W., Engelke K. (2004a). Benefits of 2 years of intense exercise on bone density, physical fitness, and blood lipids in early postmenopausal osteopenic women: results of the Erlangen Fitness Osteoporosis Prevention Study (EFOPS). Arch. Intern. Med. 164, 1084&#x2013;1091. 10.1001/archinte.164.10.1084, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.164.10.1084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Teschler M., Weissenfels A., Sieber C., Freiberger E., von Stengel S. (2017a). Prevalence of sarcopenia and sarcopenic obesity in older German men using recognized definitions: high accordance but low overlap! Osteoporos. Int. 28, 1881&#x2013;1891. 10.1007/s00198-017-3964-9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-017-3964-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28220197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., von Stengel S., Schoene D. (2019). Longitudinal changes in muscle mass and function in older men at increased risk for sarcopenia &#x2013; the FrOST-study. J. Frailty Aging 8, 57&#x2013;61. 10.14283/jfa.2019.9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14283/jfa.2019.9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30997916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Weineck J., Kalender W. A., Engelke K. (2004b). The effect of habitual physical activity, non-athletic exercise, muscle strength, and VO2max on bone mineral density is rather low in early postmenopausal osteopenic women. J. Musculoskelet. Neuronal Interact. 4, 325&#x2013;334. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15615501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Weineck M., Kohl M., von Stengel S., Giessing J., Fr&#xf6;hlich M., et al. (2020b). High intensity resistance exercise training to improve body composition and strength in older men with osteosarcopenia. Results of the randomized controlled Franconian Osteopenia and Sarcopenia Trial (FrOST). Front. Sports Act. Living 2:4. 10.3389/fspor.2020.00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2020.00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W., Weissenfels A., Teschler M., Willert S., Bebenek M., Shojaa M., et al. (2017b). Whole-body electromyostimulation and protein supplementation favorably affect sarcopenic obesity in community-dwelling older men at risk. The randomized controlled FranSO study. Clin. Interv. Aging 12, 1503&#x2013;1513. 10.2147/CIA.S137987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S137987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5624743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28989278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kob R., Bollheimer L. C., Bertsch T., Fellner C., Djukic M., Sieber C. C., et al. (2015). Sarcopenic obesity: molecular clues to a better understanding of its pathogenesis? Biogerontology 16, 15&#x2013;29. 10.1007/s10522-014-9539-7, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10522-014-9539-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25376109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W. J., Gordon S. E., Fleck S. J., Marchitelli L. J., Mello R., Dziados J. E., et al. (1991). Endogenous anabolic hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise in males and females. Int. J. Sports Med. 12, 228&#x2013;235. 10.1055/s-2007-1024673, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1024673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1860749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S., Kim Y., Kuk J. L. (2019). What is the role of resistance exercise in improving the cardiometabolic health of adolescents with obesity? J. Obes. Metab. Syndr. 28, 76&#x2013;91. 10.7570/jomes.2019.28.2.76, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7570/jomes.2019.28.2.76</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6604849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G., Taljaard M., Van den Heuvel E. R., Levine M. A., Cook D. J., Wells G. A., et al. (2017). An introduction to multiplicity issues in clinical trials: the what, why, when and how. Int. J. Epidemiol. 46, 746&#x2013;755. 10.1093/ije/dyw320, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyw320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28025257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C. D., Tsauo J. Y., Lin L. F., Huang S. W., Ku J. W., Chou L. C., et al. (2017a). Effects of elastic resistance exercise on body composition and physical capacity in older women with sarcopenic obesity: a CONSORT-compliant prospective randomized controlled trial. Medicine 96:e7115. 10.1097/md.0000000000007115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000007115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28591061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C. D., Tsauo J. Y., Wu Y. T., Cheng C. P., Chen H. C., Huang Y. C., et al. (2017b). Effects of protein supplementation combined with resistance exercise on body composition and physical function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 106, 1078&#x2013;1091. 10.3945/ajcn.116.143594, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.116.143594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichtenberg T., von Stengel S., Sieber C., Kemmler W. (2019). The favorable effects of a high-intensity resistance training on sarcopenia in older community-dwelling men with osteosarcopenia: the randomized controlled FrOST study. Clin. Interv. Aging 14, 2173&#x2013;2186. 10.2147/CIA.S225618, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S225618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6924654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31908428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C. J., Latham N. K. (2009). Progressive resistance strength training for improving physical function in older adults. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2009:CD002759. 10.1002/14651858.CD002759.pub2, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002759.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4324332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangione K. K., Miller A. H., Naughton I. V. (2010). Cochrane review: improving physical function and performance with progressive resistance strength training in older adults. Phys. Ther. 90, 1711&#x2013;1715. 10.2522/ptj.20100270, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20100270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21123213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Amat A., Aibar-Almazan A., Fabrega-Cuadros R., Cruz-Diaz D., Jimenez-Garcia J. D., Perez-Lopez F. R., et al. (2018). Exercise alone or combined with dietary supplements for sarcopenic obesity in community-dwelling older people: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Maturitas 110, 92&#x2013;103. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2018.02.005, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2018.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29563041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xe4;fer I., von Leitner E. C., Schon G., Koller D., Hansen H., Kolonko T., et al. (2010). Multimorbidity patterns in the elderly: a new approach of disease clustering identifies complex interrelations between chronic conditions. PLoS One 5:e15941. 10.1371/journal.pone.0015941, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0015941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21209965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J. (2010). The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J. Strength Cond. Res. 24, 2857&#x2013;2872. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e840f3, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e840f3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J. (2012). Does exercise-induced muscle damage play a role in skeletal muscle hypertrophy? J. Strength Cond. Res. 26, 1441&#x2013;1453. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31824f207e, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31824f207e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22344059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J. (2013). Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 43, 179&#x2013;194. 10.1007/s40279-013-0017-1, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0017-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23338987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SGB_IX (2019). &#x201c;Sozialgesetzbuch Neuntes Buch &#x2013; Rehabilitation und Teilhabe behinderter Menschen: &#xa7; 64 Erg&#xe4;nzende Leistungen&#x201d;, (ed.) B.d.J.u.f. Verbraucherschutz. (Bundesrepublik-Deutschland).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stec M. J., Thalacker-Mercer A., Mayhew D. L., Kelly N. A., Tuggle S. C., Merritt E. K., et al. (2017). Randomized, four-arm, dose-response clinical trial to optimize resistance exercise training for older adults with age-related muscle atrophy. Exp. Gerontol. 99, 98&#x2013;109. 10.1016/j.exger.2017.09.018, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2017.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5765758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28964826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J., Fisher J., Giessing J., Gentil P. (2017). Clarity in reporting terminology and definitions of set end points in resistance training. Muscle Nerve 56, 368&#x2013;374. 10.1002/mus.25557, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28044366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B., Arvandi M., Siebert U. (2012). Resistance training, visceral obesity and inflammatory response: a review of the evidence. Obes. Rev. 13, 578&#x2013;591. 10.1111/j.1467-789X.2012.00988.x, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2012.00988.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22385646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B., Schobersberger W. (2011). Evidence for resistance training as a treatment therapy in obesity. J. Obes. 2011, 1&#x2013;9. 10.1155/2011/482564, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2011/482564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan-Gunn M. J., Lewandowski P. A. (2013). Elevated hydrogen peroxide and decreased catalase and glutathione peroxidase protection are associated with aging sarcopenia. BMC Geriatr. 13:104. 10.1186/1471-2318-13-104, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2318-13-104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3853025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24093947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada T., Boule N. G., Forhan M., Prado C. M., Kenny G. P., Prud&#x2019;homme D., et al. (2017). Cardiometabolic risk factors in type 2 diabetes with high fat and low muscle mass: at baseline and in response to exercise. Obesity 25, 881&#x2013;891. 10.1002/oby.21808, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.21808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28317297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teschler M., Wassermann A., Weissenfels A., Frohlich M., Kohl M., Bebenek M., et al. (2018). Short time effect of a single session of intense whole-body electromyostimulation on energy expenditure. A contribution to fat reduction? Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 43, 528&#x2013;530. 10.1139/apnm-2017-0602, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2017-0602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29253351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlietstra L., Hendrickx W., Waters D. L. (2018). Exercise interventions in healthy older adults with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Australas. J. Ageing 37, 169&#x2013;183. 10.1111/ajag.12521, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajag.12521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29638028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO (1994). Assessment of osteoporotic fracture risk and its application to screening for postmenopausal osteoporosis. Geneva: World Health Organization.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7941614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World_Medical_Association (2013). World medical association declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA 310, 2191&#x2013;2194. 10.1001/jama.2013.281053, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.281053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos M. C., Klemp A., Dolan C., Quiles J. M., Schau K. A., Jo E., et al. (2016). Novel resistance training-specific rating of perceived exertion scale measuring repetitions in reserve. J. Strength Cond. Res. 30, 267&#x2013;275. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001049, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26049792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>