<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31885723</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1824-7490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sport sciences for health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sport Sci Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Plasma retinol-binding protein-4 and tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; are reduced in postmenopausal women after combination of different intensities of circuit resistance training and Zataria supplementation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>551</StartPage><EndPage>558</EndPage><MedlinePgn>551-558</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11332-019-00544-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE"><i>Zataria</i> is a plant with anti-inflammatory properties, which has been used for the treatment of many diseases. This study investigated the effect of different intensities of circuit resistance training and <i>Zataria</i> supplementation on plasma retinol-binding protein-4 (RBP-4) and tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; (TNF-&#x3b1;) in postmenopausal women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Seventy-two postmenopausal women were divided on randomized order into six groups: Control (McGinley and Bishop in J Appl Physiol 121(6):1290-1305, 2016), Training 35% (T35%), Training 55% (T55%), Zataria (&#xd6;zg&#xfc;nen et al. in Scand J Med Sci Sports 20:140-147, 2010), Zataria/Training 35% (ZT35%), and Zataria/Training 55% (ZT55%). Resist-ance training program included 12 exercise stations (each: 30 s, intensity: 35% and 55% of 1-RM) for 8 weeks (3 sessions/week). Daily (500 mg) <i>Zataria</i> was used after breakfast by participants in <i>ZG</i>, ZT35%, and ZT55% groups. Blood samples were taken 48 h before and after the first and last sessions of training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After the training period the percentage of body fat decreased significantly (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001) in all trained groups, whereas muscle mass increased significantly (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01) only in T55% and ZT55% groups. A significant decrease was observed for RBP-4 values (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) after training in all groups except for ZG and CG. Also, RBP-4 was significantly lower (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) in all groups as compared to CG at the post-test except for ZG. Moreover, significantly lower values (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) were found in T55%, ZT35%, and ZT55% as compared to ZG in post-intervention. TNF-&#x3b1; values decreased significantly (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) at the post-test as compared to pre-intervention in ZT35% and ZT55%. Also, TNF-&#x3b1; was significantly lower (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) in ZT55% compared to CG and T35% in post-test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results demonstrate clearly that in postmenopausal women, circuit resistance training both at low and moderate intensities cause a greater reduction in RBP-4 and TNF-&#x3b1; when <i>Zataria</i> is supplemented in the diet during training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tayebi</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Morteza</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Physical, Education and Sport Science, Allameh Tabataba'i University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeidi</LastName><ForeName>Ayoub</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biochemistry Division, Faculty of Physical, Education and Sport Science, University of Mazandaran, Babolsar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fashi</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Physical, Education and Health Sciences, Shahid Beheshti University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pouya</LastName><ForeName>Seyed</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education and Sport Science Department, Islamic, Azad University-Tabriz Branch, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khosravi</LastName><ForeName>Abedin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Science, Payame Noor University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shirvani</LastName><ForeName>Hossein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Research Center, Life Style Institute, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmadian</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Aliabad Katoul Branch, Islamic Azad University, Aliabad Katoul, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abderrahman</LastName><ForeName>Abderraouf Ben</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ISSEP Ksar Said, University of Manouba, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackney</LastName><ForeName>Anthony C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrine Section-Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Exercise and Sport Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zouhal</LastName><ForeName>Hassane</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6743-6464</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Univ Rennes, M2S (Laboratoire Mouvement, Sport, Sant&#xe9;)-EA 1274, 35000 Rennes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R03 AR055262</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Sport Sci Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101256653</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1824-7490</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Herbal supplementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retinol-binding protein-4 (RBP-4)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; (TNF-&#x3b1;)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31885723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1023510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6934256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-019-00544-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zuo H, Shi Z, Hu X, Wu M, Guo Z, Hussain A (2009) Prevalence of metabolic syndrome and factors associated with its components in Chinese adults. Metabolism 58(8):1102&#x2013;1108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19481771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanska A, Sypniewska G, Ponikowska I, Cwiklinska-Jurkowska M (2012) Association of follicle-stimulating hormone and sex hormone binding globulin with the metabolic syndrome in post-menopausal women. Clin Biochem 45(9):703&#x2013;706</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22449337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stachowiak G, Perty&#x144;ski T, Perty&#x144;ska-Marczewska M (2015) Metabolic disorders in menopause. Menopause Rev 14(1):59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4440199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26327890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider DG, Schindler K, Prager G, Bohdjalian A, Luger A, Wolzt M et al. (2007) Serum retinol-binding protein 4 is reduced after weight loss in morbidly obese subjects. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 92(3):1168&#x2013;1171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17164313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia W, Wu H, Bao Y, Lu J, Wang C, Zhu J et al. Association of Serum retinol binding protein 4 and visceral adiposity in chinese diabetes and non-diabetes subjects. Diabetes. 2007;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17550959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukovsk&#xe1; A, Ciko&#x161; &#x160;, Juh&#xe1;s &#x160;, Il&#x2019;kov&#xe1; G, Reh&#xe1;k P, Koppel J (2007) Effects of a combination of thyme and oregano essential oils on TNBS-induced colitis in mice. Med Inflamm</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2233768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18288268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawthorn WP, Sethi JK (2008) TNF-&#x3b1; and adipocyte biology. FEBS Lett 582(1):117&#x2013;131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4304634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18037376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olszanecka-Glinianowicz M, Chudek J, Koce&#x142;ak P, Szromek A, Zahorska-Markiewicz B (2011) Body fat changes and activity of tumor necrosis factor &#x3b1; system&#x2014;a 5-year follow-up study. Metabolism 60(4):531&#x2013;536</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20580040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lujan HL, DiCarlo SE (2013) Physical activity, by enhancing parasympathetic tone and activating the cholinergic anti-inflammatory pathway, is a therapeutic strategy to restrain chronic inflammation and prevent many chronic diseases. Med Hypotheses 80(5):548&#x2013;552</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23395411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saremi A, Gheraati M (2010) The Effect of resistance training on serum myostatin level and insulin resistance in obese-overweight men</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe D, Pruitt L, Pyka G, Guido D, Marcus R (1996) Comparative effects of high-and low-intensity resistance training on thigh muscle strength, fiber area, and tissue composition in elderly women. Clin Physiol 16(4):381&#x2013;392</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8842574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaarslan S, B&#xfc;y&#xfc;kyazi G, Taneli F, Ulman C, Tikiz C, G&#xdc;M&#xdc;&#x15e;ER G et al. (2010) Effects of different intensity resistance exercise programs on bone turnover markers, osteoprotegerin and receptor activator of nuclear factor kappa &#x3b2; ligand in post-menopausal women. Turkiye Klinikleri J Med Sci 30(1):123&#x2013;134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imayama I, Alfano CM, Kong A, Foster-Schubert KE, Bain CE, Xiao L et al. (2011) Dietary weight loss and exercise interventions effects on quality of life in overweight/obese postmenopausal women: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 8(1):118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3215656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22026966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi A, Gholamhoseinian A, Fallah H (2014) Zataria multiflora increases insulin sensitivity and PPAR&#x3b3; gene expression in high fructose fed insulin resistant rats. Iran J Basic Med Sci 17(4):263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4046234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24904719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anvari M, Dashti M, Zeinali F, Hosseini-Bioki S (2011) The effect of thyme (Zataria multiflora Boiss.) decoction on pregnancy in rats. J Med Plants 2(38):19&#x2013;25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodouri M, Alavi NM, Fathizadeh N, Taghizadeh M, Azarbad Z, Memarzadeh M (2013) Effects of Zataria multi-flora, Shirazi thyme, on the severity of premenstrual syndrome. Nurs Midwifery Stud 2(4):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4228904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25414880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oca&#xf1;a A, Reglero G (2012) Effects of thyme extract oils (from Thymus vulgaris, Thymus zygis, and Thymus hyemalis) on cytokine production and gene expression of oxLDL-stimulated THP-1-macrophages. J Obes</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3345235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22577523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayebi SM, Hasannezhad P, Saeidi A, Fadaei MR (2016) Intense circuit resistance training along with Zataria multiflora supple-mentation reduced plasma retinol binding protein-4 and tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; in postmenopausal females. Jundishapur J Nat Pharm Prod e38578(in press)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanbari-Niaki A, Saeidi A, Ahmadian M, Gharahcholo L, Naghavi N, Fazelzadeh M et al. (2018) The combination of exercise training and Zataria multiflora supplementation increase serum irisin levels in postmenopausal women. Integr Med Res 7(1):44&#x2013;52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5884011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29629290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGinley C, Bishop DJ (2016) Influence of training intensity on adaptations in acid/base transport proteins, muscle buffer capacity, and repeated-sprint ability in active men. J Appl Physiol 121(6):1290&#x2013;1305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27742804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zg&#xfc;nen K, Kurdak S, Maughan R, Zeren C, Korkmaz S, Yaz&#x3b9;c&#x3b9; Z et al. (2010) Effect of hot environmental conditions on physical activity patterns and temperature response of football players. Scand J Med Sci Sports 20:140&#x2013;147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saei-Dehkordi SS, Tajik H, Moradi M, Khalighi-Sigaroodi F (2010) Chemical composition of essential oils in Zataria multiflora Boiss. From different parts of Iran and their radical scavenging and antimicrobial activity. Food Chem Toxicol 48(6):1562&#x2013;1567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20332011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanbari&#x2013;Niaki A, Saeidi A, Aliakbari-Beydokhti M, Ardeshiri S, Kolahdouzi S, Chaichi MJ et al. (2015) Effects of circuit resistance training with crocus sativus (saffron) supplementation on plasma viscosity and fibrinogen. Ann Appl Sport Sci 3(2):1&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen AMW, Pedersen BK (2005) The anti-inflammatory effect of exercise. J Appl Physiol 98(4):1154&#x2013;1162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15772055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryner RW, Ullrich IH, Sauers J, Donley D, Hornsby G, Kolar M et al. (1999) Effects of resistance vs. aerobic training combined with an 800 calorie liquid diet on lean body mass and resting metabolic rate. J Am Coll Nutr 18(2):115&#x2013;121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10204826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakaran B, Dowling EA, Branch JD, Swain DP, Leutholtz BC (1999) Effect of 14 weeks of resistance training on lipid profile and body fat percentage in premenopausal women. Br J Sports Med 33(3):190&#x2013;195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10378072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahramanloo E, Midgley AW, Bentley DJ (2009) The effect of concurrent training on blood lipid profile and anthropometrical characteristics of previously untrained men. J Phys Act Health 6(6):760&#x2013;766</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souri R, Vahabi K, Shabkhiz F (2011) Effects of interval aerobic training on serum RBP4 and insulin resistance in type 2 diabetic patients. Iran J Diabetes Metabol 10(4):388&#x2013;397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi K, Kim T, Yoo H, Lee K, Cho G, Hwang T et al. (2009) Effect of exercise training on A-FABP, lipocalin-2 and RBP4 levels in obese women. Clin Endocrinol 70(4):569&#x2013;574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18710473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham TE, Yang Q, Bl&#xfc;her M, Hammarstedt A, Ciaraldi TP, Henry RR et al. (2006) Retinol-binding protein 4 and insulin resistance in lean, obese, and diabetic subjects. N Engl J Med 354(24):2552&#x2013;2563</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16775236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okazaki K, Kawazoe K, Takaishi Y (2002) Human platelet aggregation inhibitors from thyme (Thymus vulgaris L.). Phytother Res 16(4):398&#x2013;399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12112303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saghizadeh M, Ong JM, Garvey WT, Henry RR, Kern PA (1996) The expression of TNF alpha by human muscle. Relationship to insulin resistance. J Clin Investig 97(4):1111&#x2013;1116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC507159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8613535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotamisligil GS, Spiegelman BM (1994) Tumor necrosis factor &#x3b1;: a key component of the obesity-diabetes link. Diabetes 43(11):1271&#x2013;1278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7926300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouskela E (2010) Effects of resistance training on cytokines. Int J Sports Med 31:441450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20432196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiers W (1991) Tumor necrosis factor characterization at the molecular, cellular and in vivo level. FEBS Lett 285(2):199&#x2013;212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1649771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller C, Keller P, Giralt M, Hidalgo J, Pedersen BK (2004) Exercise normalises overexpression of TNF-&#x3b1; in knockout mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 321(1):179&#x2013;182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15358232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balducci S, Zanuso S, Nicolucci A, Fernando F, Cavallo S, Card-elli P et al. (2010) Anti-inflammatory effect of exercise training in subjects with type 2 diabetes and the metabolic syndrome is dependent on exercise modalities and independent of weight loss. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis 20(8):608&#x2013;617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19695853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock ML, Franklin BA, Balady GJ, Chaitman BL, Fleg JL, Fletcher B et al. (2000) Resistance exercise in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: benefits, rationale, safety, and prescription an advisory from the committee on exercise, rehabilitation, and prevention, council on clinical cardiology. Am Heart Assoc Circ 101(7):828&#x2013;833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandru Ba-E, Dr&#x103;cea N, Dragomirescu CC, Dr&#x103;gulescu E, Coldea IL, Anton L et al. (2010) Antimicrobial activity of plant essential oils against bacterial and fungal species involved in food poisoning and/or food decay. Roum Arch Microbiol Immunol 69(4):224&#x2013;230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21462837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>