<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">25084398</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6519</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in clinical nutrition and metabolic care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Combating adolescent obesity: an integrated physiological and psychological perspective.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>521</StartPage><EndPage>524</EndPage><MedlinePgn>521-4</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000099</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Optimizing the approach to combat childhood obesity, we emphasize the importance of combining both biological and psychological knowledge. In such an approach, strength exercises might be an important aspect in the treatment and prevention of childhood obesity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Recent evidence indicates plausible effects of the role of resistance exercise in combating the negative health effects of childhood obesity. When looking at body composition, overweight youngsters do not only have a higher fat mass, but also a higher muscle mass compared with their normal-weight counterparts. With that, they are also stronger and better in exercises wherein the focus is on absolute strength, making them - under the right circumstances - more motivated to engage in resistance exercise and ultimately maintain a physically active lifestyle.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">More and more children are obese, and obese children become obese adults. One reason that overweight youngsters are not physically active is that they are outperformed by normal-weight youngsters, and one reason they are overweight is because they are not physically active. To combat childhood obesity, strength exercise might be a solution to break the vicious cycle.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>ten Hoor</LastName><ForeName>Gill A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>aDepartment of Human Biology, Research School NUTRIM, Maastricht University Medical Center, Maastricht bDepartment of Work and Social Psychology, Maastricht University, Maastricht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plasqui</LastName><ForeName>Guy</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schols</LastName><ForeName>Annemie M W J</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kok</LastName><ForeName>Gerjo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804399</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1363-1950</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008019" MajorTopicYN="N">Life Style</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050177" MajorTopicYN="N">Overweight</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25084398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4189687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Seidell JC. In: Worldwide prevalence of obesity in adults. Bray GA, Bouchard C. editors. Handbook of obesity: epidemology, etiology, and physiopathology. Florida: Taylor &amp; Francis Ltd; 2014. 47&#x2013;54</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirza NM, Yanovski JA. In: Prevalence and consequences of pediatric obesity. Bray GA, Bouchard C. Handbook of obesity: epidemology, etiology, and physiopathology. Florida: Taylor &amp; Francis Ltd; 2014. 55&#x2013;74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelsey MM, Zaepfel A, Bjornstad P, Nadeau K. Age-related consequences of childhood obesity. Gerontology 2014; 60:222&#x2013;228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24434909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunger JM, Tomiyama AJ. Research letter: weight labeling and obesity: a longitudinal study of girls aged 10 to 19 years. JAMA Pediatr 2014; 168:579&#x2013;580</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24781349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan A. Global status report on noncommunicable diseases. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; 2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vienna Declaration on Nutrition and Noncommunicable Diseases in the Context of Health 2020. WHO Ministerial Conference on Nutrition and Noncommunicable Diseases in the Context of Health 2020 2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EuropeanCommission. EU Action Plan on Childhood Obesity; 2014-2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global Recommendations on Physical Activity for Health: 5-17 year olds; 2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee I-M, Shiroma EJ, Lobelo F, et al. Effect of physical inactivity on major noncommunicable diseases worldwide: an analysis of burden of disease and life expectancy. Lancet 2012; 380:219&#x2013;229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3645500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song M, Carroll DD, Fulton JE. Meeting the 2008 physical activity guidelines for americans among US youth. Am J Prevent Med 2013; 44:216&#x2013;222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23415117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wafa SW, Hamzaid H, Talib RA, Reilly JJ. Objectively measured habitual physical activity and sedentary behaviour in obese and nonobese Malaysian children. J Tropical Pediatr 2013; fmt093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24213306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kann L. Obesity and other correlates of physical activity and sedentary behaviors among US high school students. J Obes 2013; [online]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3628188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23606950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pataky Z, Armand S, M&#xfc;ller-Pinget S, et al. Effects of obesity on functional capacity. Obesity 2014; 22:56&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23794214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh M. Oversized young athletes: a weighty concern. Brit J Sports Med 2010; 44:45&#x2013;49</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19945974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok G, Bartholomew LK, Parcel GS, et al. Finding theory- and evidence-based alternatives to fear appeals: Intervention Mapping. Int J Psychol 2014; 49:98&#x2013;107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4255304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24811880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekkekakis P, Lind E. Exercise does not feel the same when you are overweight: the impact of self-selected and imposed intensity on affect and exertion. Int J Obes 2006; 30:652&#x2013;660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16130028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsyth DR. Group dynamics; 6th ed Wadsworth: Cengage Learning; 2014, p113, p346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Knippenberg A, Wilke H, De Vries N. Social comparison on two dimensions. Eur J Social Psychol 1981; 11:267&#x2013;283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogin B, Varela Silva MI. The body mass index: the good, the bad, and the horrid. Bulletin de la soci&#xe9;t&#xe9; Suisse d&#x2019;Anthropologie 2012; 18:5&#x2013;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colella D, Morano M, Robazza C, Bortoli L. Body image, perceived physical ability, and motor performance in nonoverweight and overweight Italian children. Percept Mot Skills 2009; 108:209&#x2013;218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19425462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patall EA, Sylvester BJ, Han C. The role of competence in the effects of choice on motivation. J Experiment Soc Psychol 2014; 50:27&#x2013;44</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochner CN, Barrios DM, Lee CD, Pi-Sunyer FX. Biological mechanisms that promote weight regain following weight loss in obese humans. Physiol Behav 2013; 120:106&#x2013;113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3797148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23911805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariman EC. Human biology of weight maintenance after weight loss. J Nutrigenet Nutrigenom 2012; 5:13&#x2013;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22472972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay A, Royer M, Chaput J, Doucet E. Adaptive thermogenesis can make a difference in the ability of obese individuals to lose body weight. Int J Obes 2013; 37:759&#x2013;764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22846776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Faigenbaum AD, Stone MH, et al. Position statement on youth resistance training: The 2014 International Consensus. Brit J Sports Med 2013; bjsports-2013-092952 [Accessed 17 July 2014]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Effects of exercise in the treatment of overweight and obese children and adolescents: A systematic review of meta-analyses. J Obes 2013; [online]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3886589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24455215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schranz N, Tomkinson G, Olds T. What is the effect of resistance training on the strength, body composition and psychosocial status of overweight and obese children and adolescents? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Medicine 2013; 43:893&#x2013;907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23729196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cloutier G, Forman D, Lindegger N, et al. Effects of a short-term heavy resistance training in young and older adults for strength and body composition. FASEB J 2014; 28:1028&#x2013;1031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasquez F, Diaz E, Lera L, et al. Impact of a strength training exercise program on body composition and cardiovascular risk factors in a group of obese schoolchildren by pubertal stage. Am J Sports Sci Med 2014; 2:40&#x2013;47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Moro T, Bianco A. Lift weights to fight overweight. Clin Physiol Functional Imag 2014; doi: 10.1111/cpf.1213633. [Accessed 17 July 2014]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescud M, Pettigrew S, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Factors influencing overweight children's commencement of and continuation in a resistance training program. BMC Public Health 2010; 10:709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21083936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohebbi H, Fatahi A, Faraji H, Mohseni MM. The effect of upper and lower limb resistance training on leptin in overweight men. Int J Sport Studies 2013; 3:1318&#x2013;1324</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibana R, Pereira G, Navalta J, et al. Acute effects of resistance exercise on 24-h blood pressure in middle aged overweight and obese women. Int J Sports Med 2013; 34:460&#x2013;464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23065659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schranz N, Tomkinson G, Parletta N, et al. Can resistance training change the strength, body composition and self-concept of overweight and obese adolescent males? A randomised controlled trial. Brit J Sports Med 2013; doi:10.1136/bjsports-2013-092209 [Accessed 17 July 2014]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23945035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison KK, M&#xe2;sse LC, Timperio A, et al. Physical activity parenting measurement and research: challenges, explanations, and solutions. Childhood Obes 2013; 9: S-103-S-109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23944918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>