<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39231694</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Off- and On-Bike Resistance Training in Cyclists: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>296</StartPage><EndPage>304</EndPage><MedlinePgn>296-304</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003556</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study compared the effects of off- and on-bike resistance training (RT) on endurance cycling performance as well as muscle strength, power, and structure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Well-trained male cyclists were randomly assigned to incorporate two sessions/week of off-bike (full squats, n = 12) or on-bike (all-out efforts performed against very high resistances and thus at very low cadences, n = 12) RT during 10 wk, with all RT-related variables (number of sessions, sets, and repetitions, duration of recovery periods, and relative loads [70% of one-repetition maximum]) matched between the two groups. A third, control group ( n = 13), did not receive any RT stimulus, but all groups completed a cycling training regime of the same volume and intensity. Outcomes included maximum oxygen uptake (V&#x307;O 2max ), off-bike muscle strength (full squat) and on-bike ("pedaling") muscle strength, and peak power capacity (Wingate test), dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry-determined body composition (muscle/fat mass), and muscle structure (cross-sectional area, pennation angle).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No significant within/between-group effect was found for V&#x307;O 2max . Both the off-bike (mean &#x394; = 2.6%-5.8%) and on-bike (4.5%-7.3%) RT groups increased squat and pedaling-specific strength parameters after the intervention compared with the control group (-5.8% to -3.9%) ( P &lt; 0.05) with no significant differences between them. The two RT groups also increased Wingate performance (4.1% and 4.3%, respectively, vs -4.9% in the control group, P &#x2264; 0.018), with similar results for muscle cross-sectional area (2.5% and 2.2%, vs -2.3% in the control group, P &#x2264; 0.008). No significant within/between-group effect was found for body composition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The new proposed on-bike RT could be an effective alternative to conventional off-bike RT training for improving overall and pedaling-specific muscle strength, power, and muscle mass.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barranco-Gil</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Universidad Europea de Madrid, Madrid, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance and Sports Science Laboratory, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Murcia, Murcia, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodr&#xed;guez-Rielves</LastName><ForeName>V&#xed;ctor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance and Sports Science Laboratory, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Murcia, Murcia, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iriberri</LastName><ForeName>Jon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jumbo Visma Professional Cycling Team, Den Bosch, NETHERLANDS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Cava</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buend&#xed;a-Romero</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;ngel</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GENUD Toledo Research Group, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Universidad de Castilla-La Mancha, Toledo, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alejo</LastName><ForeName>Lidia B</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franco-Lopez</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance and Sports Science Laboratory, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Murcia, Murcia, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanchez-Redondo</LastName><ForeName>Iv&#xe1;n R</ForeName><Initials>IR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Universidad Europea de Madrid, Madrid, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE Pablos</LastName><ForeName>Ra&#xfa;l</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences, Universidad Europea de Madrid, Madrid, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lucia</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valenzuela</LastName><ForeName>Pedro L</ForeName><Initials>PL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pallares</LastName><ForeName>Jes&#xfa;s G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6087-1583</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance and Sports Science Laboratory, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Murcia, Murcia, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001642" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bicycling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39231694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-00608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beattie K, Kenny IC, Lyons M, Carson BP. The effect of strength training on performance in endurance athletes. Sports Med . 2014;44(6):845&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Mujika I. Optimizing strength training for running and cycling endurance performance: a review. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2014;24(4):603&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Andersen JL, Bennekou M, et al. Effects of resistance training on endurance capacity and muscle fiber composition in young top-level cyclists. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2011;21(6):e298&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Hansen J, Hollan I, Ellefsen S. Strength training improves performance and pedaling characteristics in elite cyclists. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2015;25(1):e89&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Hansen J, Nygaard H. 10 weeks of heavy strength training improves performance-related measurements in elite cyclists. J Sports Sci . 2017;35(14):1435&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikmoen O, Ellefsen S, Tr&#xf8;en &#xd8;, et al. Strength training improves cycling performance, fractional utilization of V&#x307;O 2max and cycling economy in female cyclists. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2016;26(4):384&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koninckx E, Van Leemputte M, Hespel P. Effect of isokinetic cycling versus weight training on maximal power output and endurance performance in cycling. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2010;109(4):699&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paton CD, Hopkins WG, Cook C. Effects of low- vs. high-cadence interval training on cycling performance. J Strength Cond Res . 2009;23(6):1758&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristoffersen M, Gundersen H, Leirdal S, Iversen VV. Low cadence interval training at moderate intensity does not improve cycling performance in highly trained veteran cyclists. Front Physiol . 2014;5:34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitty AG, Murphy AJ, Coutts AJ, Watsford ML. The effect of low- vs high-cadence interval training on the freely chosen cadence and performance in endurance-trained cyclists. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2016;41(6):666&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimmerichter A, Eston R, Bachl N, Williams C. Effects of low and high cadence interval training on power output in flat and uphill cycling time-trials. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2012;112(1):69&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barranco-Gil D, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Iriberri J, et al. Relative pedaling forces are low during cycling. J Sci Med Sport . 2024;27(9):660&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gist NH, Fedewa MV, Dishman RK, Cureton KJ. Sprint interval training effects on aerobic capacity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2014;44(2):269&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloth M, Sloth D, Overgaard K, Dalgas U. Effects of sprint interval training on V&#x307;O 2max and aerobic exercise performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2013;23(6):e341&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(6):1206&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Junior RM, Barreira J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Barroso R. Muscle hypertrophy and strength gains after resistance training with different volume-matched loads: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2022;47(4):357&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currier BS, McLeod JC, Banfield L, et al. Resistance training prescription for muscle strength and hypertrophy in healthy adults: a systematic review and Bayesian network meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med . 2023;57(18):1211&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Rielves V, Barranco-Gil D, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, et al. Torque&#x2013;cadence profile and maximal dynamic force in cyclists: a novel approach. Sensors (Basel) . 2024;24(6):1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2022;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallar&#xe9;s JG, Cava AM, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R. Full squat produces greater neuromuscular and functional adaptations and lower pain than partial squats after prolonged resistance training. Eur J Sport Sci . 2020;20(1):115&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Pallar&#xe9;s J, P&#xe9;rez C, Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo J. Estimation of relative load from bar velocity in the full back squat exercise. Sports Med Int Open . 2017;1(2):E80&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Belmonte A, Courel-Ibanez J, Conesa-Ros E, Martinez-Cava A, Pallares JG. Level of effort: a reliable and practical alternative to the velocity-based approach for monitoring resistance training. J Strength Cond Res . 2022;36(11):2992&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luc&#xed;a A, Hoyos J, P&#xe9;rez M, Chicharro JL. Heart rate and performance parameters in elite cyclists: a longitudinal study. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2000;32(10):1777&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillo-Bevia JR, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Validity and reliability of the Cycleops hammer cycle ergometer. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2018;13(7):853&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Reliability of technologies to measure the barbell velocity: implications for monitoring resistance training. PLoS One . 2020;15(6):e0232465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Perez CE, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Importance of the propulsive phase in strength assessment. Int J Sports Med . 2010;31(2):123&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Velocity- and power-load relationships in the half, parallel and full back squat. J Sports Sci . 2019;37(10):1088&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallar&#xe9;s JG, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, P&#xe9;rez CE, De La Cruz-S&#xe1;nchez E, Mora-Rodriguez R. Imposing a pause between the eccentric and concentric phases increases the reliability of isoinertial strength assessments. J Sports Sci . 2014;32(12):1165&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Rielves V, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, et al. Reproducibility of the Rotor 2INpower crankset for monitoring cycling power output: a comprehensive analysis in different real-context situations. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2022;17(1):120&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga EM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on neuromuscular performance. Int J Sports Med . 2014;35(11):916&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Or O. The Wingate anaerobic test. An update on methodology, reliability and validity. Sports Med . 1987;4(6):381&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Belmonte A, Buendia-Romero A, Martinez-Cava A, Courel-Ibanez J, Mora-Rodriguez R, Pallares JG. Wingate test, when time and overdue fatigue matter: validity and sensitivity of two time-shortened versions. Appl Sci . 2020;10(22):8002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela PL, Gil-Cabrera J, Talavera E, et al. On- versus off-bike power training in professional cyclists: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2021;16(5):674&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Panoramic ultrasound requires a trained operator and specific evaluation sites to maximize its sensitivity: a comprehensive analysis of the measurement errors. Physiol Behav . 2022;248:113737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. The 2-point method: a quick, accurate, and repeatable approach to estimate ultrasound-derived quadriceps femoris cross-sectional area. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2022;17(10):1480&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarto F, Monti E, &#x160;imuni&#x10d; B, Pi&#x161;ot R, Narici MV, Franchi MV. Changes in biceps femoris long head fascicle length after 10-d bed rest assessed with different ultrasound methods. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(7):1529&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV. Distribution theory for Glass&#x2019;s estimator of effect size and related estimators. J Educ Stat . 1981;6(2):107&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Hansen EA, Raastad T. Effect of heavy strength training on thigh muscle cross-sectional area, performance determinants, and performance in well-trained cyclists. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2010;108(5):965&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordi M, Goodall S, Barratt P, Rowley N, Leeder J, Howatson G. Relation between peak power output in sprint cycling and maximum voluntary isometric torque production. J Electromyogr Kinesiol . 2017;35:95&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordi M, Parker Simpson L, Thomas K, et al. The relationship between neuromuscular function and the W&#x2019; in elite cyclists. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2021;16(11):1656&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Hansen J, Nygaard H, Lundby C. Superior performance improvements in elite cyclists following short-interval vs effort-matched long-interval training. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2020;30(5):849&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristoffersen M, Sandbakk &#xd8;, R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Gundersen H. Comparison of short-sprint and heavy strength training on cycling performance. Front Physiol . 2019;10:1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordi M, Folland JP, Goodall S, et al. Cycling-specific isometric resistance training improves peak power output in elite sprint cyclists. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2020;30(9):1594&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Pallar&#xe9;s J, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, P&#xe9;rez CE, Izquierdo-Gabarren M, Izquierdo M. Physiological effects of tapering and detraining in world-class kayakers. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2010;42(6):1209&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Hansen J, Hollan I, Spencer M, Ellefsen S. Impairment of performance variables after in-season strength-training cessation in elite cyclists. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2016;11(6):727&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Gabarren M, Gonz&#xe1;lez De Txabarri Exp&#xf3;sito R, Garc&#xed;a-pallar&#xe9;s J, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, ESS De Villarreal, Izquierdo M. Concurrent endurance and strength training not to failure optimizes performance gains. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2010;42(6):1191&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>