<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32058362</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Progressive Resistance Training Volume: Effects on Muscle Thickness, Mass, and Strength Adaptations in Resistance-Trained Individuals.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>600</StartPage><EndPage>607</EndPage><MedlinePgn>600-607</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aube, D, Wadhi, T, Rauch, J, Anand, A, Barakat, C, Pearson, J, Bradshaw, J, Zazzo, S, Ugrinowitsch, C, and De Souza, EO. Progressive resistance training volume: effects on muscle thickness, mass, and strength adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 36(3): 600-607, 2022-This study investigated the effects of 12-SET, 18-SET, and 24-SET lower-body weekly sets on muscle strength and mass accretion. Thirty-five resistance-trained individuals (one repetition maximum [1RM] squat: body mass ratio [1RM: BM] = 2.09) were randomly divided into 12-SET: n = 13, 18-SET: n = 12, and 24-SET: n = 10. Subjects underwent an 8-week resistance-training (RT) program consisting of 2 weekly sessions. Muscle strength (1RM), repetitions to failure (RTF) at 70% of 1RM, anterior thigh muscle thickness (MT), at the medial MT (MMT) and distal MT (DMT) points, as well as the sum of both sites (&#x3a3;MT), along with region of interest for fat-free mass (ROI-FFM) were measured at baseline and post-testing. For the 1RM, there was a main time effect (p &#x2264; 0.0001). However, there was a strong trend toward significance (p = 0.052) for group-by-time interaction, suggesting that 18-SET increased 1RM back squat to a greater extent compared with 24-SET (24-SET: 9.5 kg, 5.4%; 18-SET: 25.5 kg, 16.2%; 12-SET: 18.3 kg, 11.3%). For RTF, only a main time-effect (p &#x2264; 0.0003) was observed (24-SET: 5.7 reps, 33.1%; 18-SET: 2.4 reps, 14.5%; 12-SET: 5.0 reps, 34.8%). For the MMT, DMT, &#x3a3;MT, and ROI-FFM, there was only main time-effect (p &#x2264; 0.0001) (MMT: 24-SET: 0.15 cm, 2.7%; 18-SET: 0.32 cm, 5.7%; 12-SET: 0.38 cm, 6.4%-DMT: 24-SET: 0.39 cm, 13.1%; 18-SET: 0.28 cm, 8.9%; 12-SET: 0.34 cm, 9.7%-&#x3a3;MT: 24-SET: 0.54 cm, 6.1%; 18-SET: 0.60 cm, 6.7%; 12-SET: 0.72 cm, 7.7%, and ROI-FFM: 24-SET: 0.70 kg, 2.6%; 18-SET: 1.09 kg, 4.2%; 12-SET: 1.20 kg, 4.6%, respectively). Although all of the groups increased maximum strength, our results suggest that the middle dose range may optimize the gains in back squat 1RM. Our findings also support that differences in weekly set number did not impact in MT and ROI-FFM adaptations in subjects who can squat more than twice their body mass.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aube</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wadhi</LastName><ForeName>Tanuj</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rauch</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anand</LastName><ForeName>Ashmeet</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barakat</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pearson</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bradshaw</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zazzo</LastName><ForeName>Spencer</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugrinowitsch</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Adaptations to Strength Training, School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Souza</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo O</ForeName><Initials>EO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013848" MajorTopicYN="N">Thigh</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202203000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baker JS, Davies B, Cooper SM, et al. Strength and body composition changes in recreationally strength-trained individuals: Comparison of one versus three sets resistance-training programmes. Biomed Res Int 2013: 615901, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho M, Coswig VS, Steele J, et al. Evidence of a ceiling effect for training volume in muscle hypertrophy and strength in trained men&#x2014;Less is more? Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: 1&#x2013;23, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho M, Coswig VS, Steele J, et al. Evidence for an upper threshold for resistance training volume in trained women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 515&#x2013;522, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Menger E, Teodoro JL, et al. Functional and physiological adaptations following concurrent training using sets with and without concentric failure in elderly men: A randomized clinical trial. Exp Gerontol 110: 182&#x2013;190, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 50&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza EO, Tricoli V, Rauch J, et al. Different patterns in muscular strength and hypertrophy adaptations in untrained individuals undergoing nonperiodized and periodized strength regimens. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1238&#x2013;1244, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med 48: 499&#x2013;505, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3085&#x2013;3092, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Sanchez-Medina L. Movement velocity as a measure of loading intensity in resistance training. Int J Sports Med 31: 347&#x2013;352, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaselgrave SR, Blacker J, Smeuninx B, McKendry J, Breen L. Dose-response relationship of weekly resistance-training volume and frequency on muscular adaptations in trained men. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 360&#x2013;368, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennis E, Verschueren SM, Bogaerts A, et al. Long-term impact of strength training on muscle strength characteristics in older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 94: 2054&#x2013;2060, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: A meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1150&#x2013;1159, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodo L, Moreira A, Zavanela PM, et al. Is there a relationship between the total volume of load lifted in bench press exercise and the rating of perceived exertion? J Sports Med Phys Fitness 52: 483&#x2013;488, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PW, McEwen M, Robbins DW. Strength and neuromuscular adaptation following one, four, and eight sets of high intensity resistance exercise in trained males. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 3007&#x2013;3016, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson G, Ispoglou T, Bissas A. The impact of repetition mechanics on the adaptations resulting from strength-, hypertrophy- and cluster-type resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1875&#x2013;1888, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski KJ, Wilson GJ, Weatherby R, Murphy PW, Lyttle AD. The effect of weight training volume on hormonal output and muscular size and function. J Strength Cond Res 11: 148&#x2013;154, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Pistilli E, Haff GG, Hoffman EP, Gordon PM. Progression of volume load and muscular adaptation during resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 1063&#x2013;1071, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2585&#x2013;2601, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauch JT, Ugrinowitsch C, Barakat CI, et al. Auto-regulated exercise selection training regimen produces small increases in lean body mass and maximal strength adaptations in strength-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1133&#x2013;1140, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Ball SD, Burkett LN. Three sets of weight training superior to 1 set with equal intensity for eliciting strength. J Strength Cond Res 16: 525&#x2013;529, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Evidence-based guidelines for resistance training volume to maximize muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J 40: 107&#x2013;112, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 94&#x2013;103, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Krieger JW. Effect of repetition duration during resistance training on muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 45: 577&#x2013;585, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, et al. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2909&#x2013;2918, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Duthie GM, Thornton HR, Dascombe BJ. Training monitoring for resistance exercise: Theory and applications. Sports Med 46: 687&#x2013;698, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starkey DB, Pollock ML, Ishida Y, et al. Effect of resistance training volume on strength and muscle thickness. Med Sci Sports Exerc 28: 1311&#x2013;1320, 1996.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>