<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37302150</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2047-7163</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>106</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Apr-Jun</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science progress</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Prog</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of resistance training on body weight and body composition in older adults: An inter-individual response difference meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>368504231179062</StartPage><MedlinePgn>368504231179062</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">00368504231179062</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/00368504231179062</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Whether true inter-individual response differences (IIRD) occur as a result of resistance training on body weight and body composition in older adults with overweight and obesity is not known. To address this gap, data from a previous meta-analysis representing 587 men and women (333 resistance training, 254 control)&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;60 years of age nested in 15 randomized controlled trials of resistance training&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;8 weeks were included. Resistance training and control group change outcome standard deviations treated as point estimates for body weight and body composition (percent body fat, fat mass, body mass index in kg<sup>.</sup>m<sup>2</sup>, and lean body mass) were used to calculate true IIRD from each study. True IIRD as well as traditional pairwise comparisons were pooled using the inverse-variance (IVhet) model. Both 95% confidence intervals (CI) and prediction intervals (PI) were calculated. While statistically significant improvements were found for body weight and all body composition outcomes (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 for all), no statistically significant IIRD was observed for any of the outcomes (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05 for all) and all 95% PIs overlapped. Conclusions: While resistance training is associated with improvements in body weight and body composition in older adults, the lack of true IIRD suggests that factors other than training response variation (random variation, physiological responses associated with behavioral changes that are not the result of resistance training) are responsible for the observed variation in body weight and body composition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kelley</LastName><ForeName>George A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0595-4148</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Robert C. Byrd Health Sciences Center, West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kelley</LastName><ForeName>Kristi S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Instructor, School of Public Health, Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Robert C. Byrd Health Sciences Center, West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stauffer</LastName><ForeName>Brian L</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chief, Division of Cardiology, Denver Health Medical Center, Denver, CO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor, Department of Medicine, Division of Cardiology, University of Colorado at Denver, Aurora, CO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Prog</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0411361</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0036-8504</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001835" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Weight</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">older adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">overweight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37302150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10450275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00368504231179062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs Population Division. <i>World Population Ageing 2017 - Highlights</i> (ST/ESA/SER.A/397). 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Administration on Aging, Administration for Community Living and Division of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. 2020 <i>Profile of Older Americans</i>. 2021. Washington, DC.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak YE, McMillan R, McDonald EK. Trends in overweight and obesity self-awareness among adults with overweight or obesity in the United States, 1999 to 2016. Ann Intern Med 2021; 174: 721&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33253038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fryar CD, Carroll M, Afful J. Prevalence of overweight, obesity, and severe obesity among adults aged 20 and over: United States, 1960&#x2013;1962 through 2017&#x2013;2018. National Center for Health Statistics Health E-Stats 2020, 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward ZJ, Bleich SN, Long MW, et al. Association of body mass index with health care expenditures in the United States by age and sex. PLoS One 2021; 16: e0247307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7990296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33760880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chodzko-Zajko WJ, Proctor DN, Fiatarone Singh MA, et al. American College of sports medicine position stand. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2009; 41: 1510&#x2013;1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19516148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2018 Physical Activity Guidelines Advisory Committee. 2018 Physical Activity Guidelines Advisory Committee Scientific Report. 2nd ed. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med 2020; 54: 1451&#x2013;1462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the national strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res 2019; 33: 2019&#x2013;2052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Physical Activity, https://www.who.int/initiatives/behealthy/physical-activity (2022, accessed June 12, 2022 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2011; 43: 1334&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Taaffe DR, Galvao DA, et al. Resistance training effectiveness on body composition and body weight outcomes in individuals with overweight and obesity across the lifespan: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev 2022; 25: e13428, DOI: 10.1111/obr.13428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9285060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35191588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Goodpaster BH, Koch LG, et al. Precision exercise medicine: understanding exercise response variability. Br J Sports Med 2019; 53: 1141&#x2013;1153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6818669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30862704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jameson JL, Longo DL. Precision medicine&#x2013;personalized, problematic, and promising. N Engl J Med 2015; 372: 2229&#x2013;2234. 2015/05/28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26014593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Batterham AM. True and false interindividual differences in the physiological response to an intervention. Exp Physiol 2015; 100: 577&#x2013;588. 2015/05/13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25823596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecksteden A, Kraushaar J, Scharhag-Rosenberger F, et al. Individual response to exercise training - a statistical perspective. J Appl Physiol 2015; 118: 1450&#x2013;1459. 2015/02/11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25663672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Individual responses made easy. J Appl Physiol 2015; 118: 1444&#x2013;1446. 2015/02/14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25678695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila JJ, Gutierres JA, Sheehy ME, et al. Effect of moderate intensity resistance training during weight loss on body composition and physical performance in overweight older adults. Eur J Appl Physiol 2010; 109: 517&#x2013;525. 20100219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20169360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banitalebi E, Faramarzi M, Ghahfarokhi MM, et al. Osteosarcopenic obesity markers following elastic band resistance training: a randomized controlled trial. Exp Gerontol 2020; 135: 110884. 20200221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32092502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocalini DS, Lima LS, de Andrade S, et al. Effects of circuit-based exercise programs on the body composition of elderly obese women. Clin Interv Aging 2012; 7: 551&#x2013;556. 20121211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3526879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23271901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard DR, Soucy L, Senechal M, et al. Impact of resistance training with or without caloric restriction on physical capacity in obese older women. Menopause 2009; 16: 66&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18779759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante EF, Ribeiro AS, do Nascimento MA, et al. Effects of different resistance training frequencies on fat in overweight/obese older women. Int J Sports Med 2018; 39: 527&#x2013;534. 20180518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29775988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HT, Chung YC, Chen YJ, et al. Effects of different types of exercise on body composition, muscle strength, and igf-1 in the elderly with sarcopenic obesity. J Am Geriatr Soc 2017; 65: 827&#x2013;832. 20170215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28205203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson LE, Hudson R, Kilpatrick K, et al. Effects of exercise modality on insulin resistance and functional limitation in older adults: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Intern Med 2009; 169: 122&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19171808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz NB, Juesas A, Gargallo P, et al. Positive effects of a short-term intense elastic resistance training program on body composition and physical functioning in overweight older women. Biol Res Nurs 2018; 20: 321&#x2013;334. 20180211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29430940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henagan TM, Phillips MD, Cheek DJ, et al. The melanocortin 3 receptor: a novel mediator of exercise-induced inflammation reduction in postmenopausal women? J Aging Res 2011; 2011: 512593. 20110104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3022199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21253483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Ku JW, Lin LF, et al. Body composition influenced by progressive elastic band resistance exercise of sarcopenic obesity elderly women: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2017; 53: 556&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28084062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao CD, Tsauo JY, Lin LF, et al. Effects of elastic resistance exercise on body composition and physical capacity in older women with sarcopenic obesity: a CONSORT-compliant prospective randomized controlled trial. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017; 96: e7115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28591061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips MD, Patrizi RM, Cheek DJ, et al. Resistance training reduces subclinical inflammation in obese, postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2012; 44: 2099&#x2013;2110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22874536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Dos Santos L, et al. Resistance training improves a cellular health parameter in obese older women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 2020; 34: 2996&#x2013;3002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roh HT, Cho SY, So WY. A cross-sectional study evaluating the effects of resistance exercise on inflammation and neurotrophic factors in elderly women with obesity. J Clin Med 2020; 9: 842. 20200320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7141497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32244926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent HK, Bourguignon C, Vincent KR. Resistance training lowers exercise-induced oxidative stress and homocysteine levels in overweight and obese older adults. Obesity 2006; 14: 1921&#x2013;1930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17135607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner P, Hopewell S, Chandler J, et al. When and how to update systematic reviews: consensus and checklist. Br Med J 2016; 354: i3507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4955793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27443385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwet KL. Computing inter-rater reliability and its variance in the presence of high agreement. Br J Math Stat Psychol 2008; 61: 29&#x2013;48. 2008/05/17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18482474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein D. KAPPAETC: Stata module to evaluate interrater agreement. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea BJ, Reeves BC, Wells G, et al. AMSTAR 2: A critical appraisal tool for systematic reviews that include randomised or non-randomised studies of healthcare interventions, or both. Br Med J 2017; 358: j4008. 2017/09/25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28935701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovic J, Page MJ, et al. Rob 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Br Med J 2019; 366: l4898. 2019/08/30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunemann H, Brozek J, Guyatt GH, et al. <i>GRADE handbook for grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendation [updated October 2013]</i>. The GRADE Working Group 2013, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRADEpro GDT. GRADEpro Guideline Development Tool [Software]. McMaster University and Evidence Prime2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi SA, Barendregt JJ, Khan S, et al. Advances in the meta-analysis of heterogeneous clinical trials I: the inverse variance heterogeneity model. Contemp Clin Trials 2015; 45: 130&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26003435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi SAR, Furuya-Kanamori L, Thalib L, et al. Meta-analysis in evidence-based healthcare: a paradigm shift away from random effects is overdue. Int J Evid Based Healthc 2017; 15: 152&#x2013;160. 2017/11/15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29135532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, et al. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. Br Med J 2003; 327: 557&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson PJ, Atkinson G, Batterham AM. Inter-individual differences in weight change following exercise interventions: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Obes Rev 2018; 19: 960&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29701297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuya-Kanamori L, Barendregt JJ, Doi SAR. A new improved graphical and quantitative method for detecting bias in meta-analysis. Int J Evid Based Healthc 2018; 16: 195&#x2013;203. 2018/04/06.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29621038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IntHout J, Ioannidis JP, Rovers MM, et al. Plea for routinely presenting prediction intervals in meta-analysis. BMJ Open 2016; 6: e010247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4947751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27406637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson DA, Bray GA, Ryan DH. Is 5% weight loss a satisfactory criterion to define clinically significant weight loss? Obesity (Silver Spring) 2015; 23: 2319&#x2013;2320. 20151102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26523739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, et al. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2009; 41: 3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meta XL. 5.3 ed. Queensland, Australia: EpiGear International Pty Ltd, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>StataCorp. Stata Statistical Software: Release 16. 16.1 ed. College Station, TX: StataCorp LLC, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS, Pate RR. Inter-individual differences in body mass index were not observed as a result of aerobic exercise in children and adolescents with overweight and obesity. Pediatr Obes 2021; 16: e12692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32657544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS, Pate RR. Are there inter-individual differences in fat mass and percent body fat as a result of aerobic exercise training in overweight and obese children and adolescents? A meta-analytic perspective. Child Obes 2020; 16: 301&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32486838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonafiglia JT, Swinton PA, Ross R, et al. Interindividual differences in trainability and moderators of cardiorespiratory fitness, waist circumference, and body mass responses: A large-scale individual participant data meta-analysis. Sports Med 2022. DOI: 10.1007/s40279-022-01725-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01725-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35781787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinton PA, Hemingway BS, Saunders B, et al. A statistical framework to interpret individual response to intervention: paving the way for personalized nutrition and exercise prescription. Front Nutr 2018; 5: 41. 2018/06/13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5985399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29892599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills HL, Higgins JPT, Morris RW, et al. Detecting heterogeneity of intervention effects using analysis and meta-analysis of differences in variance between trial arms. Epidemiology 2021; 32: 846&#x2013;854. 2021/08/26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8478324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34432720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, et al. American College of sports medicine position stand. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2009; 41: 459&#x2013;471. 2009/01/08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genevi&#xe8;ve LD, Martani A, Shaw D, et al. Structural racism in precision medicine: leaving no one behind. BMC Med Ethics 2020; 21: 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7031946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton E, Hill AM, Pettigrew S, et al. Why do seniors leave resistance training programs? Clin Interv Aging 2017; 12: 585&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5375632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28392682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraschnewski JL, Sciamanna CN, Poger JM, et al. Is strength training associated with mortality benefits? A 15year cohort study of US older adults. Prev Med 2016; 87: 121&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26921660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merom D, Pye V, Macniven R, et al. Prevalence and correlates of participation in fall prevention exercise/physical activity by older adults. Prev Med 2012; 55: 613&#x2013;617. 20121010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office of Disease Prevention and Health Promotion. Move Your Way&#xae; Community Resources, https://health.gov/our-work/nutrition-physical-activity/move-your-way-community-resources (2021, accessed October 1, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nied RJ, Franklin B. Promoting and prescribing exercise for the elderly. Am Fam Physician 2002; 65: 419&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11858624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham C, O'Sullivan R. Healthcare professionals promotion of physical activity with older adults: a survey of knowledge and routine practice. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18: 20210604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8200063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crump C, Sundquist K, Sundquist J, et al. Exercise is medicine: primary care counseling on aerobic fitness and muscle strengthening. J Am Board Fam Med 2019; 32: 103&#x2013;107. Article.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGarrigle L, Todd C. Promotion of physical activity in older people using mHealth and eHealth technologies: rapid review of reviews. J Med Int Res 2020; 22: e22201. 20201229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33372894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Spiegelhalter DJ. A re-evaluation of random-effects meta-analysis. J R Stat Soc Series A 2009; 172: 137&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2667312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19381330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partlett C, Riley RD. Random effects meta-analysis: coverage performance of 95% confidence and prediction intervals following REML estimation. Stat Med 2017; 36: 301&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5157768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27714841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M. Common mistakes in meta-analysis and how to avoid them. Englewood, NJ: Biostat, Inc., 2019, pp.388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rucker G, Schumacher M. Simpson's paradox visualized: the example of the rosiglitazone meta-analysis. BMC Med Res Methodol 2008; 8: 34. 2008/06/03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2438436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18513392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>