<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32881839</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effect of Normobaric Hypoxia on Resistance Training Adaptations in Older Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2306</StartPage><EndPage>2312</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2306-2312</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003780</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Allsopp, GL, Hoffmann, SM, Feros, SA, Pasco, JA, Russell, AP, and Wright, CR. The effect of normobaric hypoxia on resistance training adaptations in older adults. J Strength Cond Res 36(8): 2306-2312, 2022-The effect of normobaric hypoxia on strength, body composition, and cardiovascular fitness was investigated after a resistance training intervention in older adults. A single-blinded, randomized control trial recruited 20 healthy adults aged 60-75 years for an 8-week resistance training intervention in normoxia ( n = 10) or normobaric hypoxia (14.4% O 2 ; n = 10). Subjects performed 2 sessions per week of upper-body and lower-body exercises at 70% of 1 repetition maximum (1RM). Pretraining and post-training, maximal oxygen uptake (V&#x307;O 2 max), muscular endurance (30 maximal knee flexions/extensions), and 5RM were assessed, with 5RM used to calculate 1RM. Subjects underwent whole-body dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DXA) at pretraining and post-training for fat and lean mass quantification. Significance was set at p &lt; 0.05. Subjects in both groups substantially improved their calculated 1RM strength for leg extension, pectoral fly, row, and squat (normoxia; 30, 38, 27, and 29%, hypoxia; 43, 50, 28, and 64%, respectively); however, hypoxia did not augment this response. Hypoxia did not enhance V&#x307;O 2 max or muscular endurance responses after the training intervention, with no improvements seen in either group. Fat mass and lean mass remained unchanged in both groups after the intervention. In summary, 8 weeks of resistance training in hypoxia was well tolerated in healthy older adults and increased upper-body and lower-body strength. However, the magnitude of strength and lean muscle improvements in hypoxia was no greater than normoxia; therefore, there is currently no evidence to support the use of hypoxic resistance training in older adults.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allsopp</LastName><ForeName>Giselle L</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition (IPAN), School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffmann</LastName><ForeName>Samantha M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Research, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Waurn Ponds, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feros</LastName><ForeName>Simon A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sport Research, School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Waurn Ponds, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasco</LastName><ForeName>Julie A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Epi-Center for Healthy Ageing, IMPACT SRC, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Western Health, Melbourne Medical School, the University of Melbourne, St Albans, Victoria, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barwon Health, Ryrie Street, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russell</LastName><ForeName>Aaron P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition (IPAN), School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wright</LastName><ForeName>Craig R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition (IPAN), School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000860" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoxia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202208000-00034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Batterham AM, Hopkins WG. Making meaningful inferences about magnitudes. Int J Sports Physiol 1: 50&#x2013;57, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength testing&#x2014;Predicting a one-rep max from reps-to-fatigue. J Phys Educ 64: 88&#x2013;90, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burtscher M, Pachinger O, Ehrenbourg I, et al. Intermittent hypoxia increases exercise tolerance in elderly men with and without coronary artery disease. Int J Cardiol 96: 247&#x2013;254, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP, Walker BG, Curry TB, Joyner MJ. Ageing reduces the compensatory vasodilatation during hypoxic exercise: The role of nitric oxide. J Physiol 589: 1477&#x2013;1488, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe R. Centre for Evaluation &amp; Monitoring. 2002. Available at: https://www.cem.org/effect-size-calculator . Accessed August 9, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The concepts of power analysis. In: Statistical Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: Revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing 48: 16&#x2013;31, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalleck LC, Astorino TA, Erickson RM, et al. Suitability of verification testing to confirm attainment of VO2max in middle-aged and older adults. Res Sports Med 20: 118&#x2013;128, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drouin JM, Valovich-mcLeod TC, Shultz SJ, Gansneder BM, Perrin DH. Reliability and validity of the Biodex system 3 pro isokinetic dynamometer velocity, torque and position measurements. Eur J Appl Physiol 91: 22&#x2013;29, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filopoulos D, Cormack SJ, Whyte DG. Normobaric hypoxia increases the growth hormone response to maximal resistance exercise in trained men. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 821&#x2013;829, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gail S, Rodefeld S, K&#xfc;nzell S. Reproducibility of a 5-repetition maximum strength test in older adults. Isokinet Exerc Sci 23: 291&#x2013;295, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gnimassou O, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Verdejo R, Brook M, et al. Environmental hypoxia favors myoblast differentiation and fast phenotype but blunts activation of protein synthesis after resistance exercise in human skeletal muscle. FASEB J32: 5272&#x2013;5284, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho JY, Kuo TY, Liu KL, Dong XY, Tung K. Combining normobaric hypoxia with short-term resistance training has No additive beneficial effect on muscular performance and body composition. J Strength Cond Res 28: 935&#x2013;941, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, McCarthy JP, Bamman MM. Effects of resistance training on older adults. Sports Med 34: 329&#x2013;348, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inness MW, Billaut F, Walker EJ, et al. Heavy resistance training in hypoxia enhances 1RM squat performance. Front Physiol 7: 502, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ikeda T, Homma T, et al. Effects of acute hypoxia on metabolic and hormonal responses to resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 1279&#x2013;1285, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ohiwa N, Honda A, et al. Effects of systemic hypoxia on human muscular adaptations to resistance exercise training. Physiol Rep 2: e12033, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurobe K, Huang Z, Nishiwaki M, et al. Effects of resistance training under hypoxic conditions on muscle hypertrophy and strength. Clin Physiol Funct I 35: 197&#x2013;202, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher JT, Jones LG, Hartley LH. Effects of high-altitude exposure on submaximal endurance capacity of men. J Appl Physiol 37: 895&#x2013;898, 1974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Hamlin MJ, Ross JJ, Taylor R, Manimmanakorn N. Effects of low-load resistance training combined with blood flow restriction or hypoxia on muscle function and performance in netball athletes. J Sci Med Sport 16: 337&#x2013;342, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer F, Scharhag-Rosenberger F, Carlsohn A, et al. The intensity and effects of strength training in the elderly. Dtsch Arztebl Int 108: 359&#x2013;364, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura A, Sugita M, Kato K, et al. Hypoxia increases muscle hypertrophy induced by resistance training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 5: 497&#x2013;508, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker MH. The altered fate of aging satellite cells is determined by signaling and epigenetic changes. Front Genet 6: 59, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puthon L, Bouzat P, Robach P, et al. Effect of ageing on hypoxic exercise cardiorespiratory, muscle and cerebral oxygenation responses in healthy humans. Exper Physiol 102: 436&#x2013;447, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo DJ, Mart&#xed;nez-Guardado I, Rubio-Arias JA, et al. Muscle architecture and neuromuscular changes after high-resistance circuit training in hypoxia. J Strength Cond Res 35: 3035&#x2013;3040, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ. Claims for the anabolic effects of growth hormone: A case of the emperor's new clothes? Br J Sports Med 37: 100&#x2013;105, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R. Origins and clinical relevance of sarcopenia. Can J Appl Physiol 26: 78&#x2013;89, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Slattery KM, Sculley DV, Dascombe BJ. Hypoxia during resistance exercise does not affect physical performance, perceptual responses, or neuromuscular recovery. J Strength Cond Res 32: 2174&#x2013;2182, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Slattery KM, Sculley DV, Hodson JA, Dascombe BJ. Physical performance during high-intensity resistance exercise in normoxic and hypoxic conditions. J Strength Cond Res 29: 807&#x2013;815, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shatilo VB, Korkushko OV, Ischuk VA, Downey HF, Serebrovskaya TV. Effects of intermittent hypoxia training on exercise performance, hemodynamics, and ventilation in healthy senior men. High Alt Med Biol 9: 43&#x2013;52, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanimoto Y, Watanabe M, Sun W, et al. Association between sarcopenia and higher-level functional capacity in daily living in community-dwelling elderly subjects in Japan. Arch Gerontol Geriatr 55: e9&#x2013;13, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan B, Lai X, Yi L, Wang Y, Hu Y. Effects of five-week resistance training in hypoxia on hormones and muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res 30: 184&#x2013;193, 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>