<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40765073</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2733-7545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical activity and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Act Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improving body composition and social function through combined exercise program in children with intellectual disabilities: a single-arm pre-post intervention study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>62</StartPage><EndPage>69</EndPage><MedlinePgn>62-69</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20463/pan.2025.0015</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Although children with intellectual disabilities (ID) face a heightened risk of physical inactivity, psychiatric comorbidities such as ADHD, and delayed social development -which collectively impair their physical, cognitive, and emotional well-being- and structured physical activity (PA) has been proposed as a multidimensional intervention, few studies have rigorously examined the integrated effects of a combined exercise program on the physical health, behavioral symptoms, and social functioning of this population. This study aimed to evaluate the effects of a 16-week combined exercise program -incorporating aerobic and resistance training- on body composition, ADHD-related behavioral symptoms, and social functioning in children with ID.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 30 children with mild ID (mean age: 10.4 &#xb1; 1.3 years) participated in a structured intervention comprising three 60-min exercise sessions per week over 16 weeks. The exercise intensity progressively increased across three phases (50-80% HRR). Body composition (including BMI, body fat, and muscle mass) was assessed using validated anthropometric and bioelectrical impedance methods. ADHD symptoms were evaluated using the ADHD Rating Scale-IV, and social functioning was assessed using the Social Maturity Scale, which were rated by both parents and teachers. Paired t-tests were conducted to assess pre-post differences, with significance set at p &lt; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Postintervention results revealed significant improvements in children's body composition: reductions in weight (-3.1%, p = 0.031), BMI (-3.3%, p = 0.028), body fat (-6.3%, p = 0.015), waist circumference (-2.6%, p = 0.040), hip circumference (-1.4%, p = 0.048), and WHR (-1.1%, p = 0.045), along with an increase in muscle mass (+5.9%, p = 0.022). ADHD-related symptoms significantly decreased: inattention (-20.0%, p = 0.012), hyperactivity/impulsivity (-20.5%, p = 0.014), and task incompletion (-20.7%, p = 0.010). Social indicators also improved, including reductions in both social interaction difficulties (-20.3%, p = 0.020) and repetitive behavior (-20.0%, p = 0.025).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The 16-week combined exercise program produced meaningful improvements in the physical health, attentional control, and social functioning of children with ID. These findings underscore the utility of integrated PA as a nonpharmacological, multidomain intervention to enhance the well-being of neurodiverse children. Future studies should explore the underlying neurobiological mechanisms and assess the long-term sustainability of these outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Siyeon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Art and Physical Education, Chosun University, Gwangju, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Son</LastName><ForeName>Woo-Hyeon</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Design Institute, Inje University, Gimhae, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ha</LastName><ForeName>Min-Seong</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, College of Arts and Sports, University of Seoul, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022S1A5B5A17046535</GrantID><Agency>National Research Foundation of Korea</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Act Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2733-7545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adhd symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combined exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">developmental disabilities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intellectual disability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social functioning</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40765073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12325873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2025.0015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pan.2025.0015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baten E, Vlaeminck F, Mues M, Valcke M, Desoete A, Warreyn P. The impact of school strategies and the home environment on home learning experiences during the covid-19 pandemic in children with and without developmental disorders. J Autism Dev Disord. 2023;53:1642&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8747872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35013867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang J, Kim S, Yang Y. Current trends and future direction of cognitive assessment tools in brain lesion disorder: adult occupational therapists. Society of Occupational Therapy for the Aged and Dementia. 2019;13:63&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shree A, Shukla PC. Intellectual disability: definition, classification, causes and characteristics. Learning Community-An International Journal of Educational and Social Development. 2016;7:9&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie K, Milton M, Smith G, Ouellette-Kuntz H. Systematic review of the prevalence and incidence of intellectual disabilities: current trends and issues. Curr Dev Disord Rep. 2016;3:104&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosed developmental disabilities in children aged 3-17 years: United States, 2019-2021. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melville CA, Oppewal A, Schafer Elinder L, Freiberger E, Guerra-Balic M, Hilgenkamp TIM, Einarsson I, Izquierdo-Gomez RH, Sansano-Nadal O, Rintala P, Cuesta-Vargas A, Gine-Garriga M. Definitions, measurement and prevalence of sedentary behaviour in adults with intellectual disabilities - a systematic review. Prev Med. 2017;97:62&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oviedo GR, Tamulevicius N, Guerra-Balic M. Physical activity and sedentary time in active and non-active adults with intellectual disability: a comparative study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16:1761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6571758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31109032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Einarsson IO, Olafsson A, Hinriksdottir G, Johannsson E, Daly D, Arngrimsson SA. Differences in physical activity among youth with and without intellectual disability. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47:411&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24983335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obrusnikova I, Miccinello DL. Parent perceptions of factors influencing after-school physical activity of children with autism spectrum disorders. Adapt Phys Activ Q. 2012;29:63&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22190053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward ZJ, Long MW, Resch SC, Giles CM, Cradock AL, Gortmaker SL. Simulation of growth trajectories of childhood obesity into adulthood. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:2145&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9036858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29171811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winnick JP, Short F. he Brockport physical fitness test. 2nd ed. Champaign (IL): Human Kinetics; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor E, Chadwick O, Heptinstall E, Danckaerts M. Hyperactivity and conduct problems as risk factors for adolescent development. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1996;35:1213&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8824065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekker MC, Koot HM. DSM-IV disorders in children with borderline to moderate intellectual disability. II: child and family predictors. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2003;42:923&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12874494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker A, Kay-Lambkin FJ, Richmond R, Filia S, Castle D, Williams J, Lewin TJ. Study protocol: a randomised controlled trial investigating the effect of a healthy lifestyle intervention for people with severe mental disorders. BMC Public Health. 2011;11:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21208433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraone SV, Banaschewski T, Coghill D, Zheng Y, Biederman J, Bellgrove MA, Newcorn JH, Gignac M, Al Saud NM, Manor I, Rohde LA, Yang L, Cortese S, Almagor D, Stein MA, Albatti TH, Aljoudi HF, Alqahtani MMJ, Asherson P, Atwoli L, Bolte S, Buitelaar JK, Crunelle CL, Daley D, Dalsgaard S, Dopfner M, Espinet S, Fitzgerald M, Franke B, Gerlach M, Haavik J, Hartman CA, Hartung CM, Hinshaw SP, Hoekstra PJ, Hollis C, Kollins SH, Sandra Kooij JJ, Kuntsi J, Larsson H, Li T, Liu J, Merzon E, Mattingly G, Mattos P, McCarthy S, Mikami AY, Molina BSG, Nigg JT, Purper-Ouakil D, Omigbodun OO, Polanczyk GV, Pollak Y, Poulton AS, Rajkumar RP, Reding A, Reif A, Rubia K, Rucklidge J, Romanos M, Ramos-Quiroga JA, Schellekens A, Scheres A, Schoeman R, Schweitzer JB, Shah H, Solanto MV, Sonuga-Barke E, Soutullo C, Steinhausen HC, Swanson JM, Thapar A, Tripp G, van de Glind G, van den Brink W, Van der Oord S, Venter A, Vitiello B, Walitza S, Wang Y. The world federation of ADHD international consensus statement: 208 evidence-based conclusions about the disorder. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2021;128:789&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8328933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33549739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gjervan B, Torgersen T, Nordahl HM, Rasmussen K. Functional impairment and occupational outcome in adults with ADHD. J Atten Disord. 2012;16:544&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21725028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamai H, Hasan B. Classroom behaviour and social maturity of intellectually disabled children. IAHRW International Journal of Social Sciences Review. 2019;7:1906&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok S, DaCosta B. Digital literacy of youth and young adults with intellectual disability predicted by support needs and social maturity. Assist Technol. 2017;29:123&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27057650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashi A, Dawes H, Mansoubi M, Sarlak Z. The effect of an exercise package for students with intellectual disability on motor and social development. Iran J Child Neurol. 2023;17:93&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10114272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37091473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maicas-Perez L, Hernandez-Lougedo J, Mate-Munoz JL, Villagra-Astudillo A, Garcia-Fernandez P, Suarez-Villadat B, Jimenez-Rojo B. Effect of physical activity interventions on health parameters in children and adolescents with intellectual disabilities: a systematic review. Healthcare (Basel) 2024;12:2434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11640914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39685056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fei X, Li C, Li HJ. Effectiveness of exercise on body composition for overweight and obese children and adolescents: a network meta-analysis. Chin J Sch Health. 2022;43:372&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Miyashita M, Kwon YC, Park HT, Kim EH, Park JK, Park KB, Yoon SR, Chung JW, Nakamura Y, Park SK. A 12-week after-school physical activity programme improves endothelial cell function in overweight and obese children: a randomised controlled study. BMC Pediatr. 2012;12:111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3447644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22849607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang X, Qiu H, Wang P, Sit CHP. The impacts of a combined exercise on executive function in children with ADHD: a randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32:1297&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35611615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabri S, Zhang MY, Guo L, Dang J, Mao ZX. Effectiveness of school-based physical activity programs in enhancing attention, academic performance, and social relationships among children with intellectual disabilities: evidence from Pakistani schools. Front Psychol. 2024;15:1431890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11420793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39319071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders. 4th ed. American Psychiatric Association; 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 10th ed. American College of Sports Medicine; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuPaul GJ, Power TJ, Anastopoulos AD, Reid R. ADHD Rating Scale&#x2014;IV: Checklists, norms, and clinical interpretation. New York (NY): The Guilford Press; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans EW, Must A, Anderson SE, Curtin C, Scampini R, Maslin M, Bandini L. Dietary patterns and body mass index in children with autism and typically developing children. Res Autism Spectr Disord. 2012;6:399&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3427936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22936951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Yi ES. Analysis of the relationship between physical activity and metabolic syndrome risk factors in adults with intellectual disabilities. J Exerc Rehabil. 2018;14:592&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30276179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiano C. Prevalence and risk factors of overweight and obesity among children and adolescents with intellectual disabilities. Obes Rev. 2011;12:189&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20406413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton S, Hankey CR, Miller S, Boyle S, Melville CA. A review of weight loss interventions for adults with intellectual disabilities. Obes Rev. 2007;8:339&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17578383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmahgoub SS, Calders P, Lambers S, Stegen SM, Van Laethem C, Cambier DC. The effect of combined exercise training in adolescents who are overweight or obese with intellectual disability: the role of training frequency. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:2274&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21734606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E, Park H. The effect of combined exercise program on health fitness and sociality of obese students with intellectual disability. Korean J Phys Educ. 2019;58:549&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall UA, Edin F, Pedersen A, Madsen K. Whole-body fat oxidation increases more by prior exercise than overnight fasting in elite endurance athletes. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41:430&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26988766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykens EM. Psychopathology in children with intellectual disability. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2000;41:407&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10836671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt RG, Barbaresi WJ, Colligan RC, Weaver AL, Katusic SK. Developmental dissociation, deviance, and delay: occurrence of attention-deficit-hyperactivity disorder in individuals with and without borderline-to-mild intellectual disability. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2006;48:831&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16978463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linna SL, Moilanen I, Ebeling H, Piha J, Kumpulainen K, Tamminen T, Almqvist F. Psychiatric symptoms in children with intellectual disability. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1999;8 Suppl 4:77&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10654137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehren A, Reichert M, Coghill D, Muller HHO, Braun N, Philipsen A. Physical exercise in attention deficit hyperactivity disorder - evidence and implications for the treatment of borderline personality disorder. Borderline Personal Disord Emot Dysregul. 2020;7:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31921425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerrillo-Urbina AJ, Garcia-Hermoso A, Sanchez-Lopez M, Pardo-Guijarro MJ, Santos Gomez JL, Martinez-Vizcaino V. The effects of physical exercise in children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Child Care Health Dev. 2015;41:779&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25988743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Hale BJ. Differential effects of differing intensities of acute exercise on speed and accuracy of cognition: a meta-analytical investigation. Brain Cogn. 2012;80:338&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wigal SB, Emmerson N, Gehricke JG, Galassetti P. Exercise: applications to childhood ADHD. J Atten Disord. 2013;17:279&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22863768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieb K, Zanarini MC, Schmahl C, Linehan MM, Bohus M. Borderline personality disorder. Lancet. 2004;364:453&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15288745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nater UM, Bohus M, Abbruzzese E, Ditzen B, Gaab J, Kleindienst N, Ebner-Priemer U, Mauchnik J, Ehlert U. Increased psychological and attenuated cortisol and alpha-amylase responses to acute psychosocial stress in female patients with borderline personality disorder. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2010;35:1565&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20630661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Yu M, Zhou X. Effects of physical exercise on attention deficit and other major symptoms in children with ADHD: a meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2022;311:114509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35305344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What is intellectual disability? American Psychiatric Association. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerson E. Prevalence of psychiatric disorders in children and adolescents with and without intellectual disability. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2003;47:51&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12558695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook F, Oliver C. A review of defining and measuring sociability in children with intellectual disabilities. Res Dev Disabil. 2011;32:11&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21036013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir M, Ilk&#x131;m M, Tan&#x131;r H. The effect of physical activity on social adaptation and skills development in mentally disabled individuals. Eur J Phys Educ Sport Sci. 2018;4:64&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song M, Roh H. The effect of the soccer activity on sociality of students with intellectual disability. J Intellec Disabil. 2010;12:235&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi PH, Cheung SY. Effects of an 8-week structured physical activity program on psychosocial behaviors of children with intellectual disabilities. Adapt Phys Activ Q. 2016;33:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26785496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>