<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38088883</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of L-Leucine Supplementation and Resistance Training on Adipokine Markers in Untrained Perimenopausal and Postmenopausal Women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>526</StartPage><EndPage>532</EndPage><MedlinePgn>526-532</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004661</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chapman-Lopez, TJ, Funderburk, LK, Heileson, JL, Wilburn, DT, Koutakis, P, Gallucci, AR, and Forsse, JS. Effects of L-leucine supplementation and resistance training on adipokine markers in untrained perimenopausal and postmenopausal women. J Strength Cond Res 38(3): 526-532, 2024-This study examined the effects of supplementing 5 g of leucine compared with a placebo during a 10-week resistance training program on body composition parameters and adipokine concentrations in untrained, perimenopausal and postmenopausal women. Thirty-five women were randomly assigned to 2 groups-leucine (LEU, n = 17) and placebo (PLC, n = 18)-in a double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Each group consumed the supplement or placebo every day and completed a resistance training program for 10 weeks. Using 3-day food records, a diet was assessed before the intervention and after its cessation. Body composition was assessed preintervention and postintervention using dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry. Moreover, the concentrations of adipokines, such as adiponectin, visfatin, leptin, and monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 (MCP-1), were assessed preintervention and postintervention. Both groups showed an increase in visceral adipose tissue (VAT) area ( p = 0.030) and fat-free mass (FFM; p = 0.023). There were significant group differences in concentrations of visfatin ( p = 0.020) and leptin ( p = 0.038) between the PLC and LEU groups. Visfatin displayed higher concentrations in the PLC group and leptin displayed higher concentrations in the LEU group. In addition, there were significant decreases in adiponectin concentrations for both groups (LEU: 652 &#xb1; 513 to 292 &#xb1; 447 pg&#xb7;ml -1 ; PLC: 584 &#xb1; 572 to 245 &#xb1; 356 pg&#xb7;ml -1 , p = 0.002) and MCP-1 only decreased in the PLC group (253 &#xb1; 119 to 206 &#xb1; 106 pg&#xb7;ml -1 , p = 0.004). There were significant decreases in adiponectin concentrations in both groups and a decrease in MCP-1 concentrations in the PLC group. These decreases may be due to both adipokines possible relationship with VAT area. However, it is not known whether leucine has underlying properties that hinder changes in MCP-1 concentrations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chapman-Lopez</LastName><ForeName>Tomas J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Laboratory of Exercise, Nutrition, and Renal Vascular Research, Department of Health Human Performance and Recreation, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Funderburk</LastName><ForeName>LesLee K</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Laboratory of Exercise, Nutrition, and Renal Vascular Research, Department of Health Human Performance and Recreation, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Sciences and Design, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heileson</LastName><ForeName>Jeffery L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Laboratory of Exercise, Nutrition, and Renal Vascular Research, Department of Health Human Performance and Recreation, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Services Division, Walter Reed National Military Medical Center, Bethesda, Maryland; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilburn</LastName><ForeName>Dylan T</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Laboratory of Exercise, Nutrition, and Renal Vascular Research, Department of Health Human Performance and Recreation, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koutakis</LastName><ForeName>Panagiotis</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Muscle Biology Lab, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gallucci</LastName><ForeName>Andrew R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Laboratory of Exercise, Nutrition, and Renal Vascular Research, Department of Health Human Performance and Recreation, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forsse</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8326-5132</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrated Laboratory of Exercise, Nutrition, and Renal Vascular Research, Department of Health Human Performance and Recreation, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D054392">Adipokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D052242">Adiponectin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020738">Leptin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>GMW67QNF9C</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007930">Leucine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.4.2.12</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D054409">Nicotinamide Phosphoribosyltransferase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054392" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipokines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052242" MajorTopicYN="N">Adiponectin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020738" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leptin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007930" MajorTopicYN="N">Leucine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054409" MajorTopicYN="N">Nicotinamide Phosphoribosyltransferase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D047648" MajorTopicYN="N">Perimenopause</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="N">Postmenopause</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38088883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202403000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adamopoulos S, Parissis J, Kroupis C, et al. Physical training reduces peripheral markers of inflammation in patients with chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J 22: 791&#x2013;797, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh M, Shahrbanian S, Hackney AC. Comparison of the effects of 12 weeks of three types of resistance training (traditional, circular and interval) on the levels of neuregulin 4, adiponectin and leptin in non-athletic men with obesity. Arch Med Deporte 38: 389&#x2013;396, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. Preexercise evaluation and health-related physical fitness testing and interpretation. In: ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription (11th ed.). Philadelphia, PA: Wolters Kluwer, 2022. pp. 28&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beavers KM, Ambrosius WT, Rejeski WJ, et al. Effect of exercise type during intentional weight loss on body composition in older adults with obesity: Exercise type, weight loss, and body composition. Obesity 25: 1823&#x2013;1829, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruunsgaard H. Physical activity and modulation of systemic low-level inflammation. J Leukoc Biol 78: 819&#x2013;835, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman-Lopez T, Wilburn D, Fletcher E, et al. The influence of resistance training on adipokines in post-menopausal women: A brief review. Sports Med Health Sci 4: 219&#x2013;224, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi KM, Kim JH, Cho GJ, et al. Effect of exercise training on plasma visfatin and eotaxin levels. Eur J Endocrinol 157: 437&#x2013;442, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christen T, Trompet S, Noordam R, et al. Sex differences in body fat distribution are related to sex differences in serum leptin and adiponectin. Peptides 107: 25&#x2013;31, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cnop M, Havel PJ, Utzschneider KM, et al. Relationship of adiponectin to body fat distribution, insulin sensitivity and plasma lipoproteins: Evidence for independent roles of age and sex. Diabetologia 46: 459&#x2013;469, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford PB, Obarzanek E, Morrison J, Sabry ZI. Comparative advantage of 3-day food records over 24-hour recall and 5-day food frequency validated by observation of 9- and 10-year-old girls. J Am Diet Assoc 94: 626&#x2013;630, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis KE. Postmenopausal women and the health consequences of obesity. J Obstet Gynecol Neonatal Nurs 36: 511&#x2013;517, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donges CE, Duffield R, Drinkwater EJ. Effects of resistance or aerobic exercise training on interleukin-6, C-reactive protein, and body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 304&#x2013;313, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubnov G, Brzezinski A, Berry EM. Weight control and the management of obesity after menopause: The role of physical activity. Maturitas 44: 89&#x2013;101, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantuzzi G. Adipose tissue, adipokines, and inflammation. J Allergy Clin Immunol 115: 911&#x2013;919, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher G, Hyatt TC, Hunter GR, et al. Effect of diet with and without exercise training on markers of inflammation and fat distribution in overweight women. Obesity 19: 1131&#x2013;1136, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman EW, Sammel MD, Lin H, Gracia CR. Obesity and reproductive hormone levels in the transition to menopause. Menopause 17: 718&#x2013;726, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funderburk LK, Beretich KN, Chen MD, Willoughby DS. Efficacy of L-leucine supplementation coupled with resistance training in untrained midlife women. J Am Coll Nutr 39: 316&#x2013;324, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Ceballos-Ceballos RJM, Poblete-Aro CE, et al. Exercise, adipokines and pediatric obesity: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Obes 41: 475&#x2013;482, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo YJ, Choi S-E, Jeon JY, et al. Visfatin induces inflammation and insulin resistance via the NF-&#x3ba;B and STAT3 signaling pathways in hepatocytes. J Diabetes Res 2019: 4021623, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Izquierdo M, Mart&#xed;nez-Labari C, et al. Resistance training improves cardiovascular risk factors in obese women despite a significative decrease in serum adiponectin levels. Obesity 18: 535&#x2013;541, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail I, Keating SE, Baker MK, Johnson NA. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of aerobic vs. resistance exercise training on visceral fat. Obes Rev 13: 68&#x2013;91, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanda H, Tateya S, Tamori Y, et al. MCP-1 contributes to macrophage infiltration into adipose tissue, insulin resistance, and hepatic steatosis in obesity. J Clin Invest 116: 1494&#x2013;1505, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landecho MF, Tuero C, Valent&#xed; V, et al. Relevance of leptin and other adipokines in obesity-associated cardiovascular risk. Nutrients 11: 2664, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau PWC, Kong Z, Choi C, et al. Effects of short-term resistance training on serum leptin levels in obese adolescents. J Exerc Sci Fitness 8: 54&#x2013;60, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lihn AS, Pedersen SB, Richelsen B. Adiponectin: Action, regulation and association to insulin sensitivity. Obes Rev 6: 13&#x2013;21, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, Devries MC, Phillips SM. Skeletal muscle and resistance exercise training; the role of protein synthesis in recovery and remodeling. J Appl Physiol 122: 541&#x2013;548, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njerve IU, Byrkjeland R, Arnesen H, et al. Effects of long-term exercise training on adipose tissue expression of fractalkine and MCP-1 in patients with type 2 diabetes and stable coronary artery disease: A substudy of a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes 9: 55&#x2013;62, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedroso JAB, Nishimura LS, de Matos-Neto EM, Donato J, Tirapegui J. Leucine improves protein nutritional status and regulates hepatic lipid metabolism in calorie-restricted rats. Cell Biochem Funct 32: 326&#x2013;332, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perks CM, Holly JMP. Hormonal mechanisms underlying the relationship between obesity and breast cancer. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 40: 485&#x2013;507, 2011, vii.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu X, Chen D. Targeting adipokines in obesity-related tumors. Front Oncol 11: 3099, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rollins BJ. Chemokines. Blood 90: 909&#x2013;928, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savary-Auzeloux I, Magne H, Mign&#xe9; C, et al. A dietary supplementation with leucine and antioxidants is capable to accelerate muscle mass recovery after immobilization in adult rats. PLoS One 8: e81495, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der H, Covas MI, Marrugat J, et al. Use of a three-day estimated food record, a 72-hour recall and a food-frequency questionnaire for dietary assessment in a Mediterranean Spanish population. Clin Nutr 20: 429&#x2013;437, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson KA, Singh MAF. Effects of exercise on adiponectin: A systematic review. Obesity 16: 241&#x2013;256, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Anshita D, Ravichandiran V. MCP-1: Function, regulation, and involvement in disease. Int Immunopharmacol 101: 107598, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurston RC, Chang Y, Mancuso P, Matthews KA. Adipokines, adiposity, and vasomotor symptoms during the menopause transition: Findings from the study of women's health across the nation. Fertil Steril 100: 793&#x2013;800, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabal J, Forga M, Leyes P, et al. Effects of free leucine supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and functional status in older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Clin Interv Aging 10: 713&#x2013;723, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tr&#xf8;seid M, Lappeg&#xe5;rd KT, et al. Exercise reduces plasma levels of the chemokines MCP-1 and IL-8 in subjects with the metabolic syndrome. Eur Heart J 25: 349&#x2013;355, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villareal DT, Aguirre L, Gurney AB, et al. Aerobic or resistance exercise, or both, in dieting obese older adults. N Engl J Med 376: 1943&#x2013;1955, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinheimer EM, Sands LP, Campbell WW. A systematic review of the separate and combined effects of energy restriction and exercise on fat-free mass in middle-aged and older adults: Implications for sarcopenic obesity. Nutr Rev 68: 375&#x2013;388, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YJ, Kim MK, Hwang SH, et al. Relative validities of 3-day food records and the food frequency questionnaire. Nutr Res Pract 4: 142&#x2013;148, 2010.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>