<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32777917</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2713-4148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impacts of exercise on pediatric obesity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>196</StartPage><EndPage>207</EndPage><MedlinePgn>196-207</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3345/cep.2020.00997</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Over the last few decades, the rates of pediatric obesity have more than doubled regardless of sociodemographic categorization, and despite these rates plateauing in recent years there continues to be an increase in the severity of obesity in children and adolescents. This review will discuss the pediatric obesity mediated cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk factors such as attenuated levels of satiety and energy metabolism hormones, insulin resistance, vascular endothelial dysfunction, and arterial stiffness. Additionally, early intervention to combat pediatric obesity is critical as obesity has been suggested to track into adulthood, and these obese children and adolescents are at an increased risk of early mortality. Current suggested strategies to combat pediatric obesity are modifying diet, limiting sedentary behavior, and increasing physical activity. The effects of exercise intervention on metabolic hormones such as leptin and adiponectin, insulin sensitivity/resistance, and body fat in obese children and adolescents will be discussed along with the exercise modality, intensity, and duration. Specifically, this review will focus on the differential effects of aerobic exercise, resistance training, and combined exercise on the cardiovascular risks in pediatric obesity. This review outlines the evidence that exercise intervention is a beneficial therapeutic strategy to reduce the risk factors for CVD and the ideal exercise prescription to combat pediatric obesity should contain both muscle strengthening and aerobic components with an emphasis on fat mass reduction and long-term adherence.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Headid Iii</LastName><ForeName>Ronald J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Kinesiology, University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, NE, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Song-Young</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Kinesiology, University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, NE, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101761234</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2713-4148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric obesity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32777917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8103043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3345/cep.2020.00997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">cep.2020.00997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ng M, Fleming T, Robinson M, Thomson B, Graetz N, Margono C, et al. Global, regional, and national prevalence of overweight and obesity in children and adults during 1980-2013: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2013. Lancet. 2014;384:766&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4624264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24880830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2015 Obesity Collaborators. Afshin A, Forouzanfar MH, Reitsma MB, Sur P, Estep K, et al. Health effects of overweight and obesity in 195 countries over 25 years. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:13&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregg EW, Shaw JE. Global health effects of overweight and obesity. N Engl J Med. 2017;377:80&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogden CL, Carroll MD, Kit BK, Flegal KM. Prevalence of childhood and adult obesity in the United States, 2011-2012. JAMA. 2014;311:806&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4770258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24570244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner AC, Skelton JA. Prevalence and trends in obesity and severe obesity among children in the United States, 1999-2012. JAMA Pediatr. 2014;168:561&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24710576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plourde G. Preventing and managing pediatric obesity. Recommendations for family physicians. Can Fam Physician. 2006;52:322&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1479709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16572577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JC, Lawlor DA, Kimm SY. Childhood obesity. Lancet. 2010;375:1737&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3073855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20451244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir D, Bektas M. The effect of childrens' eating behaviors and parental feeding style on childhood obesity. Eat Behav. 2017;26:137&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson SE, Keim SA. Parent-child interaction, self-regulation, and obesity prevention in early childhood. Curr Obes Rep. 2016;5:192&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4856567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27037572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paeratakul S, Ferdinand DP, Champagne CM, Ryan DH, Bray GA. Fastfood consumption among US adults and children: dietary and nutrient intake profile. J Am Diet Assoc. 2003;103:1332&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14520253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig DS, Peterson KE, Gortmaker SL. Relation between consumption of sugar-sweetened drinks and childhood obesity: a prospective, observational analysis. Lancet. 2001;357:505&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11229668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EY, Kang B, Yang Y, Yang HK, Kim HS, Lim SY, et al. Study time after school and habitual eating are associated with risk for obesity among overweight korean children: a prospective study. Obes Facts. 2018;11:46&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5869488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29408816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JO, Birch LL. Eating in the absence of hunger and overweight in girls from 5 to 7 y of age. Am J Clin Nutr. 2002;76:226&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2604807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12081839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez B, Gortmaker SL, Colditz GA, Peterson KE, Laird NM, Parra-Cabrera S. Association of obesity with physical activity, television programs and other forms of video viewing among children in Mexico city. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1999;23:845&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10490786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arluk SL, Branch JD, Swain DP, Dowling EA. Childhood obesity's relationship to time spent in sedentary behavior. Mil Med. 2003;168:583&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12901472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicente-Rodr&#xed;guez G, Rey-L&#xf3;pez JP, Mart&#xed;n-Matillas M, Moreno LA, W&#xe4;rnberg J, Redondo C, et al. Television watching, videogames, and excess of body fat in Spanish adolescents: the AVENA study. Nutrition. 2008;24:654&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18472399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen RE, Crespo CJ, Bartlett SJ, Cheskin LJ, Pratt M. Relationship of physical activity and television watching with body weight and level of fatness among children: results from the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. JAMA. 1998;279:938&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9544768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner AC, Perrin EM, Moss LA, Skelton JA. Cardiometabolic risks and severity of obesity in children and young adults. N Engl J Med. 2015;373:1307&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26422721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly JJ, Kelly J. Long-term impact of overweight and obesity in childhood and adolescence on morbidity and premature mortality in adulthood: systematic review. Int J Obes (Lond) 2011;35:891&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20975725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venn AJ, Thomson RJ, Schmidt MD, Cleland VJ, Curry BA, Gennat HC, et al. Overweight and obesity from childhood to adulthood: a follow-up of participants in the 1985 Australian Schools Health and Fitness Survey. Med J Aust. 2007;186:458&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17484707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmonds M, Burch J, Llewellyn A, Griffiths C, Yang H, Owen C, et al. The use of measures of obesity in childhood for predicting obesity and the development of obesity-related diseases in adulthood: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Health Technol Assess. 2015;19:1&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4781104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26108433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietz WH. Critical periods in childhood for the development of obesity. Am J Clin Nutr. 1994;59:955&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8172099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyfault JP, Krogh-Madsen R. Metabolic disruptions induced by reduced ambulatory activity in free-living humans. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2011;111:1218&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21636564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyfault JP, Booth FW. Lack of regular physical exercise or too much inactivity. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2011;14:374&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21519238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirico F, Bianco A, D'Alicandro G, Castaldo C, Montagnani S, Spera R, et al. Effects of physical exercise on adiponectin, leptin, and inflammatory markers in childhood obesity: systematic review and meta-analysis. Child Obes. 2018;14:207&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5994661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29762052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whooten R, Kerem L, Stanley T. Physical activity in adolescents and children and relationship to metabolic health. Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes. 2019;26:25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6522241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30507695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento H, Alves AI, Medeiros AF, Coimbra S, Catarino C, Bronzeda-Rocha E, et al. Impact of a school-based intervention protocol ACORDA Project - on adipokines in an overweight and obese pediatric population. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2016;28:407&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27176449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balagopal P, George D, Yarandi H, Funanage V, Bayne E. Reversal of obesity-related hypoadiponectinemia by lifestyle intervention: a controlled, randomized study in obese adolescents. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90:6192&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16131584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray RG, Hackney AC. Interactions of metabolic hormones, adipose tissue and exercise. Sports Med. 2005;35:393&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15896089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grundy SM, Cleeman JI, Daniels SR, Donato KA, Eckel RH, Franklin BA, et al. Diagnosis and management of the metabolic syndrome: an American Heart Association/National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute Scientific Statement. Circulation. 2005;112:2735&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16157765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicklas TA, von Duvillard SP, Berenson GS. Tracking of serum lipids and lipoproteins from childhood to dyslipidemia in adults: the Bogalusa Heart Study. Int J Sports Med. 2002;23 Suppl 1:S39&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12012261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juhola J, Magnussen CG, Viikari JS, K&#xe4;h&#xf6;nen M, Hutri-K&#xe4;h&#xf6;nen N, Jula A, et al. Tracking of serum lipid levels, blood pressure, and body mass index from childhood to adulthood: the Cardiovascular Risk in Young Finns Study. J Pediatr. 2011;159:584&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21514597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronti T, Lupattelli G, Mannarino E. The endocrine function of adipose tissue: an update. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2006;64:355&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16584505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kershaw EE, Flier JS. Adipose tissue as an endocrine organ. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89:2548&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15181022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havel PJ. Control of energy homeostasis and insulin action by adipocyte hormones: leptin, acylation stimulating protein, and adiponectin. Curr Opin Lipidol. 2002;13:51&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11790963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Ceballos-Ceballos RJ, Poblete-Aro CE, Hackney AC, Mota J, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R. Exercise, adipokines and pediatric obesity: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Obes (Lond) 2017;41:475&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5382285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28017965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha R, Fisch G, Teague B, Tamborlane WV, Banyas B, Allen K, et al. Prevalence of impaired glucose tolerance among children and adolescents with marked obesity. N Engl J Med. 2002;346:802&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11893791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golbidi S, Laher I. Exercise induced adipokine changes and the metabolic syndrome. J Diabetes Res. 2014;2014:726861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3915640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24563869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruige JB, Dekker JM, Blum WF, Stehouwer CD, Nijpels G, Mooy J, et al. Leptin and variables of body adiposity, energy balance, and insulin resistance in a population-based study. The Hoorn Study. Diabetes Care. 1999;22:1097&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10388974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon JY, Han J, Kim HJ, Park MS, Seo DY, Kwak YS. The combined effects of physical exercise training and detraining on adiponectin in overweight and obese children. Integr Med Res. 2013;2:145&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5481692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28664066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes WA, Leite N, da Silva LR, Brunelli DT, G&#xe1;spari AF, Radominski RB, et al. Effects of 12 weeks of combined training without caloric restriction on inflammatory markers in overweight girls. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:190212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26852885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son WM, Sung KD, Bharath LP, Choi KJ, Park SY. Combined exercise training reduces blood pressure, arterial stiffness, and insulin resistance in obese prehypertensive adolescent girls. Clin Exp Hypertens. 2017;39:546&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28590143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonds SE, Pryor JT, Ravussin E, Greenway FL, Dileone R, Allen AM, et al. Leptin mediates the increase in blood pressure associated with obesity. Cell. 2014;159:1404&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4259491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25480301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trayhurn P, Beattie JH. Physiological role of adipose tissue: white adipose tissue as an endocrine and secretory organ. Proc Nutr Soc. 2001;60:32939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11681807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantzoros CS, Magkos F, Brinkoetter M, Sienkiewicz E, Dardeno TA, Kim SY, et al. Leptin in human physiology and pathophysiology. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;301:E567&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21791620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouchi N, Parker JL, Lugus JJ, Walsh K. Adipokines in inflammation and metabolic disease. Nat Rev Immunol. 2011;11:85&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3518031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21252989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Considine RV, Sinha MK, Heiman ML, Kriauciunas A, Stephens TW, Nyce MR, et al. Serum immunoreactive-leptin concentrations in normalweight and obese humans. N Engl J Med. 1996;334:292&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8532024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Liu R, Arguelles L, Wang G, Zhang J, Shen X, et al. Adiposity trajectory and its associations with plasma adipokine levels in children and adolescents-A prospective cohort study. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2016;24:408&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26704698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani RM, Rocha NP, Magalh&#xe3;es DM, Barbosa IG, Teixeira AL, Sim&#xf5;es E Silva AC. Early changes in adipokines from overweight to obesity in children and adolescents. J Pediatr (Rio J) 2016;92:624&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27504976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly AS, Steinberger J, Olson TP, Dengel DR. In the absence of weight loss, exercise training does not improve adipokines or oxidative stress in overweight children. Metabolism. 2007;56:1005&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17570265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconcellos F, Seabra A, Cunha F, Montenegro R, Penha J, Bouskela E, et al. Health markers in obese adolescents improved by a 12-week recreational soccer program: a randomised controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:564&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26208409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karacabey K. The effect of exercise on leptin, insulin, cortisol and lipid profiles in obese children. J Int Med Res. 2009;37:1472&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19930853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balagopal PB, Gidding SS, Buckloh LM, Yarandi HN, Sylvester JE, George DE, et al. Changes in circulating satiety hormones in obese children: a randomized controlled physical activity-based intervention study. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2010;18:1747&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20094040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shultz SP, Dahiya R, Leong GM, Rowlands DS, Hills AP, Byrne NM. Muscular strength, aerobic capacity, and adipocytokines in obese youth after resistance training: a pilot study. Australas Med J. 2015;8:113&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4422951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26045721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racil G, Zouhal H, Elmontassar W, Ben Abderrahmane A, De Sousa MV, Chamari K, et al. Plyometric exercise combined with high-intensity interval training improves metabolic abnormalities in young obese females more so than interval training alone. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41:103&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26701117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe2;maso AR, da Silveira Campos RM, Caranti DA, de Piano A, Fisberg M, Foschini D, et al. Aerobic plus resistance training was more effective in improving the visceral adiposity, metabolic profile and inflammatory markers than aerobic training in obese adolescents. J Sports Sci. 2014;32:1435&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24730354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seabra A, Katzmarzyk P, Carvalho MJ, Seabra A, Coelho-E-Silva M, Abreu S, et al. Effects of 6-month soccer and traditional physical activity programmes on body composition, cardiometabolic risk factors, inflammatory, oxidative stress markers and cardiorespiratory fitness in obese boys. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:1822&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26890580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park TG, Hong HR, Lee J, Kang HS. Lifestyle plus exercise intervention improves metabolic syndrome markers without change in adiponectin in obese girls. Ann Nutr Metab. 2007;51:197&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17587789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouwens DM, Bekaert M, Lapauw B, Van Nieuwenhove Y, Lehr S, Hartwig S, et al. Chemerin as biomarker for insulin sensitivity in males without typical characteristics of metabolic syndrome. Arch Physiol Biochem. 2012;118:135&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22335466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuzawa Y, Funahashi T, Kihara S, Shimomura I. Adiponectin and metabolic syndrome. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2004;24:29&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14551151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim ES, Im JA, Kim KC, Park JH, Suh SH, Kang ES, et al. Improved insulin sensitivity and adiponectin level after exercise training in obese Korean youth. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2007;15:3023&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18198311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A, Sanchez-Gonzalez MA, Son WM, Kwak YS, Park SY. The effects of a 12-week combined exercise training program on arterial stiffness, vasoactive substances, inflammatory markers, metabolic profile, and body composition in obese adolescent girls. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2018;30:480&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30193554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racil G, Ben Ounis O, Hammouda O, Kallel A, Zouhal H, Chamari K, et al. Effects of high vs. moderate exercise intensity during interval training on lipids and adiponectin levels in obese young females. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:2531&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23824463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xydakis AM, Case CC, Jones PH, Hoogeveen RC, Liu MY, Smith EO, et al. Adiponectin, inflammation, and the expression of the metabolic syndrome in obese individuals: the impact of rapid weight loss through caloric restriction. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89:2697&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15181044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassis GP, Papantakou K, Skenderi K, Triandafillopoulou M, Kavouras SA, Yannakoulia M, et al. Aerobic exercise training improves insulin sensitivity without changes in body weight, body fat, adiponectin, and inflammatory markers in overweight and obese girls. Metabolism. 2005;54:1472&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16253636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts CK, Hevener AL, Barnard RJ. Metabolic syndrome and insulin resistance: underlying causes and modification by exercise training. Compr Physiol. 2013;3:1&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23720280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Ding Y, Tanaka Y, Zhang W. Risk factors contributing to type 2 diabetes and recent advances in the treatment and prevention. Int J Med Sci. 2014;11:1185&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4166864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Magliano DJ, Zimmet PZ. The worldwide epidemiology of type 2 diabetes mellitus--present and future perspectives. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2011;8:228&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22064493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbloom AL, Silverstein JH, Amemiya S, Zeitler P, Klingensmith GJ, International Society for Pediatric et al. ISPAD clinical practice consensus guidelines 2006-2007. Type 2 diabetes mellitus in the child and adolescent. Pediatr Diabetes. 2008;9:512&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18694453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Son WM, Headid RJ, Pekas EJ, Noble JM, Park SY. Corrigendum to: the effects of a 12-week jump rope exercise program on body composition, insulin sensitivity, and academic self-efficacy in obese adolescent girls. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2020;33:681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaibi GQ, Cruz ML, Ball GD, Weigensberg MJ, Salem GJ, Crespo NC, et al. Effects of resistance training on insulin sensitivity in overweight Latino adolescent males. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:1208&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16826016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Heijden GJ, Wang ZJ, Chu Z, Toffolo G, Manesso E, Sauer PJ, et al. Strength exercise improves muscle mass and hepatic insulin sensitivity in obese youth. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1973&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2944907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20351587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo DY, Lee S, Figueroa A, Kim HK, Baek YH, Kwak YS, et al. Yoga training improves metabolic parameters in obese boys. Korean J Physiol Pharmacol. 2012;16:175&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3394919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22802698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marson EC, Delevatti RS, Prado AK, Netto N, Kruel LF. Effects of aerobic, resistance, and combined exercise training on insulin resistance markers in overweight or obese children and adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Prev Med. 2016;93:211&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27773709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho SS, Dhaliwal SS, Hills AP, Pal S. The effect of 12 weeks of aerobic, resistance or combination exercise training on cardiovascular risk factors in the overweight and obese in a randomized trial. BMC Public Health. 2012;12:704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3487794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23006411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharath LP, Choi WW, Cho JM, Skobodzinski AA, Wong A, Sweeney TE, et al. Combined resistance and aerobic exercise training reduces insulin resistance and central adiposity in adolescent girls who are obese: randomized clinical trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118:1653&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29846794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung ST, Onuzuruike AU, Magge SN. Cardiometabolic risk in obese children. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2018;1411:166&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5931397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29377201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strong JP, Malcom GT, McMahan CA, Tracy RE, Newman WP 3rd, Herderick EE, et al. Prevalence and extent of atherosclerosis in adolescents and young adults: implications for prevention from the Pathobiological Determinants of Atherosclerosis in Youth Study. JAMA. 1999;281:727&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10052443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGill HC, Jr, McMahan CA, Zieske AW, Sloop GD, Walcott JV, Troxclair DA, et al. Associations of coronary heart disease risk factors with the intermediate lesion of atherosclerosis in youth. The Pathobiological Determinants of Atherosclerosis in Youth (PDAY) Research Group. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2000;20:1998&#x2013;2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10938023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinehr T, Kiess W, de Sousa G, Stoffel-Wagner B, Wunsch R. Intima media thickness in childhood obesity: relations to inflammatory marker, glucose metabolism, and blood pressure. Metabolism. 2006;55:113&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16324929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabarsky G, Beek C, Hagman E, Pierpont B, Caprio S, Weiss R. Impact of severe obesity on cardiovascular risk factors in youth. J Pediatr. 2018;192:105&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9338402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29246331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barseghian A, Gawande D, Bajaj M. Adiponectin and vulnerable atherosclerotic plaques. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;57:761&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21310310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabbatini AR, Fontana V, Laurent S, Moreno H. An update on the role of adipokines in arterial stiffness and hypertension. J Hypertens. 2015;33:435&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25502905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulcelik NE, Usman A, G&#xfc;rlek A. Role of adipocytokines in predicting the development of diabetes and its late complications. Endocrine. 2009;36:397&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19779867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McTernan PG, Kusminski CM, Kumar S. Resistin. Curr Opin Lipidol. 2006;17:170&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16531754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels SR. Complications of obesity in children and adolescents. Int J Obes (Lond) 2009;33 Suppl 1:S60&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19363511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagman E, Danielsson P, Brandt L, Ekbom A, Marcus C. Association between impaired fasting glycaemia in pediatric obesity and type 2 diabetes in young adulthood. Nutr Diabetes. 2016;6:e227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5022148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27548712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts K, Beye P, Siafarikas A, O'Driscoll G, Jones TW, Davis EA, et al. Effects of exercise training on vascular function in obese children. J Pediatr. 2004;144:620&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15126996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts K, Beye P, Siafarikas A, Davis EA, Jones TW, O'Driscoll G, et al. Exercise training normalizes vascular dysfunction and improves central adiposity in obese adolescents. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;43:1823&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15145107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangner N, Scheuermann K, Winzer E, Wagner I, Hoellriegel R, Sandri M, et al. Childhood obesity: impact on cardiac geometry and function. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2014;7:1198&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25306542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimbrone MA, Jr, Garc&#xed;a-Carde&#xf1;a G. Endothelial Cell Dysfunction and the Pathobiology of Atherosclerosis. Circ Res. 2016;118:620&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4762052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TODAY Study Group Lipid and inflammatory cardiovascular risk worsens over 3 years in youth with type 2 diabetes: the TODAY clinical trial. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:1758&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3661790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23704675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cote AT, Phillips AA, Harris KC, Sandor GG, Panagiotopoulos C, Devlin AM. Obesity and arterial stiffness in children: systematic review and meta-analysis. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2015;35:1038&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25633314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northcott JM, Yeganeh A, Taylor CG, Zahradka P, Wigle JT. Adipokines and the cardiovascular system: mechanisms mediating health and disease. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2012;90:1029&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22646022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Jiang J, L&#xfc; JM, Chai H, Wang X, Lin PH, et al. Resistin decreases expression of endothelial nitric oxide synthase through oxidative stress in human coronary artery endothelial cells. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2010;299:H193&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2904138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20435848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vita JA, Keaney JF., Jr Endothelial function: a barometer for cardiovascular risk? Circulation. 2002;106:640&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12163419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inaba Y, Chen JA, Bergmann SR. Prediction of future cardiovascular outcomes by flow-mediated vasodilatation of brachial artery: a metaanalysis. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2010;26:631&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20339920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Jones H, Thijssen D, Cable NT, Atkinson G. Flow-mediated dilation and cardiovascular event prediction: does nitric oxide matter? Hypertension. 2011;57:363&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21263128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ras RT, Streppel MT, Draijer R, Zock PL. Flow-mediated dilation and cardiovascular risk prediction: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2013;168:344&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23041097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumura K, Imamura A, Murakami R, Numaguchi Y, Matsui H, Toyoaki M. Endothelial function and early atherosclerotic changes. Future Cardiol. 2005;1:501&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19804151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi Y, Kihara Y, Noma K. Endothelial dysfunction and hypertension in aging. Hypertens Res. 2012;35:1039&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22972557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiorana A, O'Driscoll G, Dembo L, Cheetham C, Goodman C, Taylor R, et al. Effect of aerobic and resistance exercise training on vascular function in heart failure. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2000;279:H1999&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11009490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hambrecht R, Wolf A, Gielen S, Linke A, Hofer J, Erbs S, et al. Effect of exercise on coronary endothelial function in patients with coronary artery disease. N Engl J Med. 2000;342:454&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10675425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiorana A, O'Driscoll G, Cheetham C, Dembo L, Stanton K, Goodman C, et al. The effect of combined aerobic and resistance exercise training on vascular function in type 2 diabetes. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2001;38:860&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11527646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versari D, Daghini E, Virdis A, Ghiadoni L, Taddei S. Endothelial dysfunction as a target for prevention of cardiovascular disease. Diabetes Care. 2009;32 Suppl 2(Suppl 2):S314&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19875572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celermajer DS, Sorensen KE, Georgakopoulos D, Bull C, Thomas O, Robinson J, et al. Cigarette smoking is associated with dose-related and potentially reversible impairment of endothelium-dependent dilation in healthy young adults. Circulation. 1993;88(5 Pt 1):2149&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8222109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celermajer DS, Sorensen K, Ryalls M, Robinson J, Thomas O, Leonard JV, et al. Impaired endothelial function occurs in the systemic arteries of children with homozygous homocystinuria but not in their heterozygous parents. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1993;22:854&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8354824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorensen KE, Celermajer DS, Georgakopoulos D, Hatcher G, Betteridge DJ, Deanfield JE. Impairment of endothelium-dependent dilation is an early event in children with familial hypercholesterolemia and is related to the lipoprotein(a) level. J Clin Invest. 1994;93:50&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC293724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8282821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tounian P, Aggoun Y, Dubern B, Varille V, Guy-Grand B, Sidi D, et al. Presence of increased stiffness of the common carotid artery and endothelial dysfunction in severely obese children: a prospective study. Lancet. 2001;358:1400&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11705484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farpour-Lambert NJ, Aggoun Y, Marchand LM, Martin XE, Herrmann FR, Beghetti M. Physical activity reduces systemic blood pressure and improves early markers of atherosclerosis in pre-pubertal obese children. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;54:2396&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20082930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias KA, Green DJ, Ingul CB, Pavey TG, Coombes JS. Exercise and vascular function in child obesity: a meta-analysis. Pediatrics. 2015;136:e648&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26260721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Walsh JH, Maiorana A, Best MJ, Taylor RR, O'Driscoll JG. Exercise-induced improvement in endothelial dysfunction is not mediated by changes in CV risk factors: pooled analysis of diverse patient populations. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2003;285:H267987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12933344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niebauer J, Cooke JP. Cardiovascular effects of exercise: role of endothelial shear stress. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1996;28:1652&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8962548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinken TM, Thijssen DH, Hopkins N, Dawson EA, Cable NT, Green DJ. Shear stress mediates endothelial adaptations to exercise training in humans. Hypertension. 2010;55:312&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cecelja M, Chowienczyk P. Role of arterial stiffness in cardiovascular disease. JRSM Cardiovasc Dis. 2012;1:cvd.2012.012016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24175067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashina A, Tomiyama H, Takeda K, Tsuda H, Arai T, Hirose K, et al. Validity, reproducibility, and clinical significance of noninvasive brachialankle pulse wave velocity measurement. Hypertens Res. 2002;25:35964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12135313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent S, Cockcroft J, Van Bortel L, Boutouyrie P, Giannattasio C, Hayoz D, et al. Expert consensus document on arterial stiffness: methodological issues and clinical applications. Eur Heart J. 2006;27:2588605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17000623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira T, Correia C, Cardoso J. Novel methods for pulse wave velocity measurement. J Med Biol Eng. 2015;35:555&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4609308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26500469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acree LS, Montgomery PS, Gardner AW. The influence of obesity on arterial compliance in adult men and women. Vasc Med. 2007;12:183&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17848474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charakida M, Jones A, Falaschetti E, Khan T, Finer N, Sattar N, et al. Childhood obesity and vascular phenotypes: a population study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2012;60:2643&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23177297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czippelova B, Turianikova Z, Krohova J, Wiszt R, Lazarova Z, Pozorciakova K, et al. Arterial stiffness and endothelial function in young obese patients - vascular resistance matters. J Atheroscler Thromb. 2019;26:1015&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6845697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mestanik M, Jurko A, Spronck B, Avolio AP, Butlin M, Jurko T, et al. Improved assessment of arterial stiffness using corrected cardio-ankle vascular index (CAVI0) in overweight adolescents with white-coat and essential hypertension. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2017;77:665&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29103321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagayama D, Imamura H, Sato Y, Yamaguchi T, Ban N, Kawana H, et al. Inverse relationship of cardioankle vascular index with BMI in healthy Japanese subjects: a cross-sectional study. Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2016;13:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5189698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28053538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlachopoulos C, Aznaouridis K, Stefanadis C. Prediction of cardiovascular events and all-cause mortality with arterial stiffness: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010;55:1318&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20338492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashor AW, Lara J, Siervo M, Celis-Morales C, Mathers JC. Effects of exercise modalities on arterial stiffness and wave reflection: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS One. 2014;9:e110034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4198209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25333969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Parker JR, LaRocca TJ, Seals DR. Aerobic exercise and other healthy lifestyle factors that influence vascular aging. Adv Physiol Educ. 2014;38:296&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25434012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HY, Oh BH. Aging and arterial stiffness. Circ J. 2010;74:2257&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante JL, Lima JA, Redheuil A, Al-Mallah MH. Aortic stiffness: current understanding and future directions. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;57:1511&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21453829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinken TM, Thijssen DH, Black MA, Cable NT, Green DJ. Time course of change in vasodilator function and capacity in response to exercise training in humans. J Physiol. 2008;586:5003&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2614057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18755749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison KK, Birch LL. Childhood overweight: a contextual model and recommendations for future research. Obes Rev. 2001;2:159&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2530932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12120101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson PM, Butcher KE. Childhood obesity: trends and potential causes. Future Child. 2006;16:19&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16532657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obarzanek E, Schreiber GB, Crawford PB, Goldman SR, Barrier PM, Frederick MM, et al. Energy intake and physical activity in relation to indexes of body fat: the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute Growth and Health Study. Am J Clin Nutr. 1994;60:15&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8017331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goran MI, Hunter G, Nagy TR, Johnson R. Physical activity related energy expenditure and fat mass in young children. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1997;21:171&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9080254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogelholm M, Nuutinen O, Pasanen M, My&#xf6;h&#xe4;nen E, S&#xe4;&#xe4;tel&#xe4; T. Parentchild relationship of physical activity patterns and obesity. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1999;23:1262&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10643682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Saavedra JM, Escalante Y, S&#xe1;nchez-L&#xf3;pez M, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. Endocrinology and Adolescence: aerobic exercise reduces insulin resistance markers in obese youth: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur J Endocrinol. 2014;171:R163&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24920290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamurtas AZ, Stavropoulos-Kalinoglou A, Koutsias S, Koutedakis Y, Fatouros I. Adiponectin, resistin, and visfatin in childhood obesity and exercise. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2015;27:454&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25902558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twig G, Yaniv G, Levine H, Leiba A, Goldberger N, Derazne E, et al. Body-mass index in 2.3 million adolescents and cardiovascular death in adulthood. N Engl J Med. 2016;374:2430&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27074389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry VW, Baruth M, Beets MW, Durstine JL, Liu J, Blair SN. Fitness vs. fatness on all-cause mortality: a meta-analysis. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2014;56:382&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Effects of aerobic exercise on non-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol in children and adolescents: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Prog Cardiovasc Nurs. 2008;23:128&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2596632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19039893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Aerobic exercise and lipids and lipoproteins in children and adolescents: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Atherosclerosis. 2007;191:447&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2447165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16806228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KJ, Shin YA, Lee KY, Jun TW, Song W. Aerobic exercise traininginduced decrease in plasma visfatin and insulin resistance in obese female adolescents. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20:275&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung KD, Pekas EJ, Scott SD, Son WM, Park SY. Correction to: the effects of a 12-week jump rope exercise program on abdominal adiposity, vasoactive substances, inflammation, and vascular function in adolescent girls with prehypertension. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120:1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32193661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor WC, Yancey AK, Leslie J, Murray NG, Cummings SS, Sharkey SA, et al. Physical activity among African American and Latino middle school girls: consistent beliefs, expectations, and experiences across two sites. Women Health. 1999;30:67&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10881759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins LB, Pender NJ, Kazanis AS. Barriers to physical activity perceived by adolescent girls. J Midwifery Womens Health. 2003;48:206&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12764306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matos N, Winsley RJ. Trainability of young athletes and overtraining. J Sports Sci Med. 2007;6:353&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3787286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis LH, Slentz CA, Bateman LA, Shields AT, Piner LW, Bales CW, et al. Effects of aerobic and/or resistance training on body mass and fat mass in overweight or obese adults. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2012;113:1831&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3544497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23019316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Meo S, Iossa S, Venditti P. Improvement of obesity-linked skeletal muscle insulin resistance by strength and endurance training. J Endocrinol. 2017;234:R159&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28778962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Bacha F, Hannon T, Kuk JL, Boesch C, Arslanian S. Effects of aerobic versus resistance exercise without caloric restriction on abdominal fat, intrahepatic lipid, and insulin sensitivity in obese adolescent boys: a randomized, controlled trial. Diabetes. 2012;61:2787&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3478522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22751691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Deldin AR, White D, Kim Y, Libman I, Rivera-Vega M, et al. Aerobic exercise but not resistance exercise reduces intrahepatic lipid content and visceral fat and improves insulin sensitivity in obese adolescent girls: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2013;305:E1222&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3840217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24045865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Kim Y, Kuk JL. What is the role of resistance exercise in improving the cardiometabolic health of adolescents with obesity? J Obes Metab Syndr. 2019;28:76&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6604849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piercy KL, Troiano RP, Ballard RM, Carlson SA, Fulton JE, Galuska DA, et al. The physical activity guidelines for Americans. JAMA. 2018;320:2020&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9582631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30418471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Sui X, Lobelo F, Morrow JR, Jr, Jackson AW, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, et al. Association between muscular strength and mortality in men: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2008;337:a439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2453303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Sui X, Lobelo F, Lee DC, Morrow JR, Jr, Jackson AW, et al. Muscular strength and adiposity as predictors of adulthood cancer mortality in men. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2009;18:146876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3762582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19366909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos AP, Marinho DA, Costa AM, Izquierdo M, Marques MC. The effects of concurrent resistance and endurance training follow a detraining period in elementary school students. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:1708&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21912296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Dias S, Strasser B, Hoffmann G. Impact of different training modalities on anthropometric and metabolic characteristics in overweight/obese subjects: a systematic review and network metaanalysis. PLoS One. 2013;8:e82853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3866267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24358230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Missbach B, Dias S, K&#xf6;nig J, Hoffmann G. Impact of different training modalities on glycaemic control and blood lipids in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and network metaanalysis. Diabetologia. 2014;57:1789&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24996616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, Peterson MD, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. Concurrent aerobic plus resistance exercise versus aerobic exercise alone to improve health outcomes in paediatric obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:161&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Libman I, Hughan K, Kuk JL, Jeong JH, Zhang D, et al. Effects of exercise modality on insulin resistance and ectopic fat in adolescents with overweight and obesity: a randomized clinical trial. J Pediatr. 2019;206:91&#x2013;8.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7193538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galan-Lopez P, Ries F. Motives for exercising and associations with body composition in icelandic adolescents. Sports (Basel) 2019;7:149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6628225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31226864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>