<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36036301</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Plyometric Jump Training on Measures of Physical Fitness and Sport-Specific Performance of Water Sports Athletes: A Systematic Review with Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">108</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-022-00502-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">A growing body of literature is available regarding the effects of plyometric jump training (PJT) on measures of physical fitness (PF) and sport-specific performance (SSP) in-water sports athletes (WSA, i.e. those competing in sports that are practiced on [e.g. rowing] or in [e.g. swimming; water polo] water). Indeed, incoherent findings have been observed across individual studies making it difficult to provide the scientific community and coaches with consistent evidence. As such, a comprehensive systematic literature search should be conducted to clarify the existent evidence, identify the major gaps in the literature, and offer recommendations for future studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine the effects of PJT compared with active/specific-active controls on the PF (one-repetition maximum back squat strength, squat jump height, countermovement jump height, horizontal jump distance, body mass, fat mass, thigh girth) and SSP (in-water vertical jump, in-water agility, time trial) outcomes in WSA, through a systematic review with meta-analysis of randomized and non-randomized controlled studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The electronic databases PubMed, Scopus, and Web of Science were searched up to January 2022. According to the PICOS approach, the eligibility criteria were: (population) healthy WSA; (intervention) PJT interventions involving unilateral and/or bilateral jumps, and a minimal duration of&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;3&#xa0;weeks; (comparator) active (i.e. standard sports training) or specific-active (i.e. alternative training intervention) control group(s); (outcome) at least one measure of PF (e.g. jump height) and/or SSP (e.g. time trial) before and after training; and (study design) multi-groups randomized and non-randomized controlled trials. The Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) scale was used to assess the methodological quality of the included studies. The DerSimonian and Laird random-effects model was used to compute the meta-analyses, reporting effect sizes (ES, i.e. Hedges' g) with 95% confidence intervals (95% CIs). Statistical significance was set at p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.05. Certainty or confidence in the body of evidence for each outcome was assessed using Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE), considering its five dimensions: risk of bias in studies, indirectness, inconsistency, imprecision, and risk of publication bias.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 11,028 studies were identified with 26 considered eligible for inclusion. The median PEDro score across the included studies was 5.5 (moderate-to-high methodological quality). The included studies involved a total of 618 WSA of both sexes (330 participants in the intervention groups [31 groups] and 288 participants in the control groups [26 groups]), aged between 10 and 26&#xa0;years, and from different sports disciplines such as swimming, triathlon, rowing, artistic swimming, and water polo. The duration of the training programmes in the intervention and control groups ranged from 4 to 36&#xa0;weeks. The results of the meta-analysis indicated no effects of PJT compared to control conditions (including specific-active controls) for in-water vertical jump or agility (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.15 to 0.03; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.477 to 0.899), or for body mass, fat mass, and thigh girth (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.06 to 0.15; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.452 to 0.841). In terms of measures of PF, moderate-to-large effects were noted in favour of the PJT groups compared to the control groups (including specific-active control groups) for one-repetition maximum back squat strength, horizontal jump distance, squat jump height, and countermovement jump height (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.67 to 1.47; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.041 to&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), in addition to a small effect noted in favour of the PJT for SSP time-trial speed (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.42; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005). Certainty of evidence across the included studies varied from very low-to-moderate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PJT is more effective to improve measures of PF and SSP in WSA compared to control conditions involving traditional sport-specific training as well as alternative training interventions (e.g. resistance training). It is worth noting that the present findings are derived from 26 studies of moderate-to-high methodological quality, low-to-moderate impact of heterogeneity, and very low-to-moderate certainty of evidence based on GRADE. Trial registration The protocol for this systematic review with meta-analysis was published in the Open Science platform (OSF) on January 23, 2022, under the registration doi https://doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/NWHS3 (internet archive link: https://archive.org/details/osf-registrations-nwhs3-v1 ).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramirez-Campillo</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Rehabilitation Sciences Laboratory, School of Physical Therapy, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perez-Castilla</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, 18011, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thapa</LastName><ForeName>Rohit K</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Rashtriya Raksha University, Gandhinagar, 382305, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afonso</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research, Education, Innovation, and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), Faculty of Sport of the University of Porto, Rua Dr. Pl&#xe1;cido Costa, 91, 4200-450, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clemente</LastName><ForeName>Filipe Manuel</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Escola Superior Desporto e Lazer, Instituto Polit&#xe9;cnico de Viana do Castelo, Rua Escola Industrial e Comercial de Nun'&#xc1;lvares, 4900-347, Viana do Castelo, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center in Sports Performance, Recreation, Innovation and Technology (SPRINT), Melga&#xe7;o, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Telecomunica&#xe7;&#xf5;es, Delega&#xe7;&#xe3;o da Covilh&#xe3;, 1049-001, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colado</LastName><ForeName>Juan C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group in Prevention and Health in Exercise and Sport (PHES), University of Valencia, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Villarreal</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo Sa&#xe9;z</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Performance Sports Research Center (PPSRC), Universidad Pablo de Olavide, Seville, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaabene</LastName><ForeName>Helmi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7812-7931</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports and Health Sciences, Faculty of Human Sciences, University of Potsdam, 14469, Potsdam, Germany. chaabene@uni-potsdam.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human physical conditioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Movement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal and neural physiological phenomena</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plyometric exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Rodrigo Ramirez-Campillo, Alejandro Perez-Castilla, Rohit K. Thapa, Jos&#xe9; Afonso, Filipe Manuel Clemente, Juan C. Colado, Eduardo Sa&#xe9;z de Villarreal and Helmi Chaabene declare that they have no conflicts of interest relevant to the content of this review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9424421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00502-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-022-00502-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>United States National Library of Medicine N. Medical subject headings, MeSH. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/?term=water+sport. 2021. Date of acces: 1st Jan 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dictionary OAA. Water sports. https://www.oxfordlearnersdictionaries.com/definition/american_english/water-sports. Access date: 5th Jan 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FINA. 2021. Available from http://www.fina.org. Accessed 1st Jan 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IOC. Access date: 1st Jan 2021. https://olympics.com/en/sports/. 2021;International Olympic Committee.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troup JP. The physiology and biomechanics of competitive swimming. Clin Sports Med. 1999;18(2):267&#x2013;285. doi: 10.1016/S0278-5919(05)70143-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0278-5919(05)70143-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10230563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arce-&#xc1;lvarez A, Veliz C, Vazquez-Mu&#xf1;oz M, von Igel M, Alvares C, Ramirez-Campillo R, et al. Hypoxic respiratory chemoreflex control in young trained swimmers. Front Physiol. 2021;12:632603. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.632603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.632603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7953139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagerman FC. Applied physiology of rowing. Sports Med. 1984;1(4):303&#x2013;326. doi: 10.2165/00007256-198401040-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-198401040-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6390606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavoie JM, Montpetit RR. Applied physiology of swimming. Sports Med. 1986;3(3):165&#x2013;189. doi: 10.2165/00007256-198603030-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-198603030-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3520747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Toole ML, Douglas PS. Applied physiology of triathlon. Sports Med. 1995;19(4):251&#x2013;267. doi: 10.2165/00007256-199519040-00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199519040-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7604198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guellich A, Seiler S, Emrich E. Training methods and intensity distribution of young world-class rowers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2009;4(4):448&#x2013;460. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.4.4.448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.4.4.448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20029096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiskerstrand A, Seiler KS. Training and performance characteristics among Norwegian international rowers 1970&#x2013;2001. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2004;14(5):303&#x2013;310. doi: 10.1046/j.1600-0838.2003.370.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1600-0838.2003.370.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15387804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Morris T, Whyte G. The specificity of training prescription and physiological assessment: a review. J Sports Sci. 2009;27(6):575&#x2013;589. doi: 10.1080/02640410902729741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410902729741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19340630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arellano R, S&#xe1;nchez J, Valdivielso F, Aymerich J. Analysis of 100-m backstroke, breastroke, butterfly and freestyle swimmers at the 2001 European youth Olympic days; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan MI, Thapa RK, Kumar G, Bishop C, Chaabene H, Ramirez-Campillo R. Inter-limb jump asymmetries and their association with sport-specific performance in young male and female swimmers. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(14):7324. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18147324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18147324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8307746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maciejewski H, Rahmani A, Chorin F, Lardy J, Samozino P, Ratel S. Methodological considerations on the relationship between the 1500-m rowing ergometer performance and vertical jump in national-level adolescent rowers. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(11):3000&#x2013;3007. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29533359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Barbosa AC, Nocentini RK, Pereira LA, Kobal R, Kitamura K, et al. A correlational analysis of tethered swimming, swim sprint performance and dry-land power assessments. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37(3):211&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26669251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido N, Marinho DA, Barbosa TM, Costa AM, Silva AJ, P&#xe9;rez-Turpin JA, et al. Relationships between dry land strength, power variables and short sprint performance in young competitive swimmers. J Hum Sport Exerc II. 2010;5(2):10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinho DA, Neiva HP, Branquinho L, Ferraz R. Anthropometric characterization and muscle strength parameters in young female swimmers at national level: the relationship with performance in the 50 m freestyle. J Hum Sport Exerc. 2021;16(2proc):S295&#x2013;S306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alf&#x151;ldi Z, Borys&#x142;awski K, Ihasz F, So&#xf3;s I, Podstawski R. Differences in the anthropometric and physiological profiles of hungarian male rowers of various age categories, rankings and career lengths: selection problems. Front Physiol. 2021;12:747781. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.747781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.747781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8548758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34721071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Siati F, Laffaye G, Gatta G, Dello Iacono A, Ardig&#xf2; LP, Padulo J. Neuromuscular and technical abilities related to age in water-polo players. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(15):1466&#x2013;1472. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2015.1119298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1119298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26643977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan D, Zhong B, Guo W, Xu Y. Physical fitness characteristics and performance in single-handed dinghy and 470 classes sailors. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2022;20(1):9&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.jesf.2021.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2021.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8605227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34868325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove MJ, Wilson J, Watt D, Grant SF. The relationship between selected physiological variables of rowers and rowing performance as determined by a 2000 m ergometer test. J Sports Sci. 1999;17(11):845&#x2013;852. doi: 10.1080/026404199365407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404199365407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10585164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maciejewski H, Rahmani A, Chorin F, Lardy J, Giroux C, Ratel S. The 1,500-m rowing performance is highly dependent on modified wingate anaerobic test performance in national-level adolescent rowers. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2016;28(4):572&#x2013;579. doi: 10.1123/pes.2015-0283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.2015-0283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27633491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Crowley E. Strength training for swimmers. In: Schumann M, R&#xf8;nnestad BR, editors. Concurrent aerobic and strength training: scientific basics and practical applications. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2019. pp. 369&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa MJ, Bragada JA, Marinho DA, Silva AJ, Barbosa TM. Longitudinal interventions in elite swimming: a systematic review based on energetics, biomechanics, and performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(7):2006&#x2013;2016. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318257807f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318257807f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22531620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugent F, Comyns T, Nevill A, Warrington GD. The effects of low-volume, high-intensity training on performance parameters in competitive youth swimmers. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(2):203&#x2013;208. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2018-0110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30039991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner KJ, Pyne DB, P&#xe9;riard JD, Rice AJ. High-intensity interval training and sprint-interval training in national-level rowers. Front Physiol. 2021;12:803430. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.803430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.803430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8712637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34970160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botonis PG, Malliaros I, Arsoniadis GG, Platanou TI, Toubekis AG. High-intensity training in water polo: swimming versus ball drills. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;15:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31188693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G, Mikulic P. Neuro-musculoskeletal and performance adaptations to lower-extremity plyometric training. Sports Med. 2010;40(10):859&#x2013;895. doi: 10.2165/11318370-000000000-00000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11318370-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20836583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, Nikolaidis TP, Clemente F, Gentil P, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A. Body composition adaptations to lower-body plyometric training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Biol Sport. 2021;39:273&#x2013;287. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2022.104916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2022.104916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Cree J, Read P, Chavda S, Edwards M, Turner A. Strength and conditioning for sprint swimming. Strength Cond J. 2013;35(6):1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Mikulic P. Effects of plyometric versus resistance training on skeletal muscle hypertrophy: a review. J Sport Health Sci. 2020;6:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32579911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Andrade DC, Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, Negra Y, Boullosa D, Moran J. Effects of jump training on physical fitness and athletic performance in endurance runners: a meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2021;6:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33956587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Andrade DC, Nikolaidis PT, Moran J, Clemente FM, Chaabene H, et al. Effects of plyometric jump training on vertical jump height of volleyball players: a systematic review with meta-analysis of randomized-controlled trial. J Sport Sci Med. 2020;19:489&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Castillo D, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Moran J, de Villarreal ES, Lloyd RS. Effects of plyometric jump training on jump and sprint performance in young male soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(12):2125&#x2013;2143. doi: 10.1007/s40279-020-01337-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01337-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Gentil P, Negra Y, Grgic J, Girard O. Effects of plyometric jump training on repeated sprint ability in athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51(10):2165&#x2013;2179. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01479-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01479-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E, Requena B, Newton RU. Does plyometric training improve strength performance? A meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(5):513&#x2013;522. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2009.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2009.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19897415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic G. Does plyometric training improve vertical jump height? A meta-analytical review. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41(6):349&#x2013;355. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2007.035113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2007.035113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17347316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Alvarez C, Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, Sanchez-Sanchez J, Yanci J, Castillo D, et al. Optimal reactive strength index: is it an accurate variable to optimize plyometric training effects on measures of physical fitness in young soccer players? J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(4):885&#x2013;893. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29389692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Moran J, Drury B, Williams M, Keogh JW, Chaabene H, et al. Effects of equal volume but different plyometric jump training intensities on components of physical fitness in physically active young males. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(7):1916&#x2013;1923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30741877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobbert MF. Drop jumping as a training method for jumping ability. Sports Med. 1990;9(1):7&#x2013;22. doi: 10.2165/00007256-199009010-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199009010-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2408119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Moran J, Chaabene H, Granacher U, Behm DG, Garcia-Hermoso A, et al. Methodological characteristics and future directions for plyometric jump training research: a scoping review update. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(6):983&#x2013;997. doi: 10.1111/sms.13633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32034819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louder TJ, Bressel E, Nardoni C, Dolny DG. Biomechanical comparison of loaded countermovement jumps performed on land and in water. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(1):25&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29194184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louder T, Dolny D, Bressel E. Biomechanical comparison of countermovement jumps performed on land and in water: age effects. J Sport Rehabil. 2018;27(3):249&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1123/jsr.2016-0225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2016-0225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28513324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triplett NT, Colado JC, Benavent J, Alakhdar Y, Madera J, Gonzalez LM, et al. Concentric and impact forces of single-leg jumps in an aquatic environment versus on land. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(9):1790&#x2013;1796. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a252b7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a252b7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19657290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Garcia-Masso X, Gonz&#xe1;lez LM, Triplett NT, Mayo C, Merce J. Two-leg squat jumps in water: an effective alternative to dry land jumps. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31(2):118&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1055/s-0029-1242814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0029-1242814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20222004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martel GF, Harmer ML, Logan JM, Parker CB. Aquatic plyometric training increases vertical jump in female volleyball players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(10):1814&#x2013;1819. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000184289.87574.60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000184289.87574.60</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullenax PM, Johnson QR, Trevino MA, Smith DB, Jacobson BH, Dawes JJ. The impact of aquatic based plyometric training on jump performance: a critical review. Int J Exerc Sci. 2021;14(6):815&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8439703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34567378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson LE, Devor ST, Merrick MA, Buckworth J. The effects of land versus aquatic plyometrics on power, torque, velocity, and muscle soreness in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(1):84&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stemm JD, Jacobson BH. Comparison of land- and aquatic-based plyometric training on vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):568&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louder TJ, Searle CJ, Bressel E. Mechanical parameters and flight phase characteristics in aquatic plyometric jumping. Sports Biomech. 2016;15(3):342&#x2013;356. doi: 10.1080/14763141.2016.1162840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2016.1162840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27125295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermosilla F, Sanders R, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Moh&#xed;no F, Yustres I, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Rave JM. Effects of dry-land training programs on swimming turn performance: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(17):9340. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18179340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18179340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8431432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro NM, Morou&#xe7;o PG, Marques MC, Batalha N, Neiva H, Marinho DA. A systematic review on dry-land strength and conditioning training on swimming performance. Sci Sports. 2019;34(1):e1&#x2013;e14. doi: 10.1016/j.scispo.2018.07.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2018.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willems TM, Cornelis JA, De Deurwaerder LE, Roelandt F, De Mits S. The effect of ankle muscle strength and flexibility on dolphin kick performance in competitive swimmers. Hum Mov Sci. 2014;36:167&#x2013;176. doi: 10.1016/j.humov.2014.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2014.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24984154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sole S, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, Andrade DC, Sanchez-Sanchez J. Plyometric jump training effects on the physical fitness of individual-sport athletes: a systematic review with meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2021;9:e11004e. doi: 10.7717/peerj.11004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.11004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7931718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33717707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlachopoulos D, Barker AR, Ubago-Guisado E, Williams CA, Gracia-Marco L. The effect of a high-impact jumping intervention on bone mass, bone stiffness and fitness parameters in adolescent athletes. Arch Osteoporosis. 2018;13(1):128. doi: 10.1007/s11657-018-0543-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11657-018-0543-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6244891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30446875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racil G, Jlid MC, Bouzid MS, Sioud R, Khalifa R, Amri M, et al. Effects of flexibility combined with plyometric exercises versus isolated plyometric or flexibility mode in adolescent male hurdlers. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2020;60(1):45&#x2013;52. doi: 10.23736/S0022-4707.19.09906-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.19.09906-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31640314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radwan NL, Mahmoud WS, Mohamed RA, Ibrahim MM. Effect of adding plyometric training to physical education sessions on specific biomechanical parameters in primary school girls. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2021;21(2):237&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8185267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34059568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AF, Clemente FM, Lima R, Nikolaidis PT, Rosemann T, Knechtle B. The effect of plyometric training in volleyball players: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(16):2960. doi: 10.3390/ijerph16162960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16162960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31426481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Clemente FM, Nakamura FY, Morou&#xe7;o P, Sarmento H, Inman RA, et al. The effectiveness of post-exercise stretching in short-term and delayed recovery of strength, range of motion and delayed onset muscle soreness: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Physiol. 2021;12:677581. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.677581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.677581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8133317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34025459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Ramirez-Campillo R, Mosc&#xe3;o J, Rocha T, Zacca R, Martins A, et al. Strength training versus stretching for improving range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Healthcare (Basel, Switzerland). 2021;9(4):427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Claudino JG, Fonseca H, Moreira-Gon&#xe7;alves D, Ferreira V, Almeida JM, et al. Stretching for recovery from groin pain or injury in athletes: a critical and systematic review. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2021;6(3):73. doi: 10.3390/jfmk6030073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk6030073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8482255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34564192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Rocha-Rodrigues S, Clemente FM, Aquino M, Nikolaidis PT, Sarmento H, et al. The hamstrings: anatomic and physiologic variations and their potential relationships with injury risk. Front Physiol. 2021;12:694604. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.694604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.694604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8294189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34305648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croisier JL, Forthomme B, Namurois MH, Vanderthommen M, Crielaard JM. Hamstring muscle strain recurrence and strength performance disorders. Am J Sports Med. 2002;30(2):199&#x2013;203. doi: 10.1177/03635465020300020901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465020300020901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11912088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abt G, Boreham C, Davison G, Jackson R, Nevill A, Wallace E, et al. Power, precision, and sample size estimation in sport and exercise science research. J Sports Sci. 2020;38(17):1933&#x2013;1935. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1776002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1776002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32558628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cossor JM, Blanksby BA, Elliott BC. The influence of plyometric training on the freestyle tumble turn. J Sci Med Sport. 1999;2(2):106&#x2013;116. doi: 10.1016/S1440-2440(99)80190-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1440-2440(99)80190-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10476974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fone L, van den Tillaar R. Effect of different types of strength training on swimming performance in competitive swimmers: a systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2022;8(1):19. doi: 10.1186/s40798-022-00410-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00410-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8804114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35099631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiele D, Prieske O, Chaabene H, Granacher U. Effects of strength training on physical fitness and sport-specific performance in recreational, sub-elite, and elite rowers: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2020;38(10):1186&#x2013;1195. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1745502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1745502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32216524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murad MH, Asi N, Alsawas M, Alahdab F. New evidence pyramid. Evid Based Med. 2016;21(4):125&#x2013;127. doi: 10.1136/ebmed-2016-110401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ebmed-2016-110401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4975798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27339128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Ioannidis JPA, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate healthcare interventions: explanation and elaboration. BMJ. 2009;339:b2700. doi: 10.1136/bmj.b2700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.b2700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;29(372):n71. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Alvarez C, Garcia-Hermoso A, Ramirez-Velez R, Gentil P, Asadi A, et al. Methodological characteristics and future directions for plyometric jump training research: a scoping review. Sports Med. 2018;48(5):1059&#x2013;1081. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0870-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0870-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Abdelkrim N, El Fazaa S, El Ati J. Time-motion analysis and physiological data of elite under-19-year-old basketball players during competition. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41(2):69&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2006.032318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2006.032318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2658931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17138630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delextrat A, Cohen D. Physiological testing of basketball players: toward a standard evaluation of anaerobic fitness. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(4):1066&#x2013;1072. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181739d9b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181739d9b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Alonso-Mart&#xed;nez AM, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, P&#xe9;rez-Sousa M, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, Izquierdo M. Association of physical education with improvement of health-related physical fitness outcomes and fundamental motor skills among youths: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Pediatr. 2020;174(6):e200223. doi: 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.0223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.0223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7136862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32250414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Hermoso A, Ramirez-Campillo R, Izquierdo M. Is muscular fitness associated with future health benefits in children and adolescents? A systematic review and meta-analysis of longitudinal studies. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):1079&#x2013;1094. doi: 10.1007/s40279-019-01098-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01098-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30953308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Hermoso A, Ramirez-Velez R, Ramirez-Campillo R, Peterson MD, Martinez-Vizcaino V. Concurrent aerobic plus resistance exercise versus aerobic exercise alone to improve health outcomes in paediatric obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(3):161&#x2013;166. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T, Bangsbo J, Franks A. Anthropometric and physiological predispositions for elite soccer. J Sports Sci. 2000;18(9):669&#x2013;683. doi: 10.1080/02640410050120050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410050120050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11043893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slinde F, Suber C, Suber L, Edwen CE, Svantesson U. Test&#x2013;retest reliability of three different countermovement jumping tests. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(2):640&#x2013;644. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181660475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181660475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann S, Ringhof S, Neumann R, Woll A, Rumpf MC. Validity and reliability of speed tests used in soccer: a systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(8):e0220982. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0220982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0220982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Test&#x2013;retest reliability of the one-repetition maximum (1RM) strength testassessment: a systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2020;6:1&#x2013;16. 10.1186/s40798-020-00260-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia FM, Krustrup P. The Yo&#x2013;Yo intermittent recovery test : a useful tool for evaluation of physical performance in intermittent sports. Sports Med. 2008;38(1):37&#x2013;51. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200838010-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200838010-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18081366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drevon D, Fursa SR, Malcolm AL. Intercoder reliability and validity of WebPlotDigitizer in extracting graphed data. Behav Modif. 2016;41(2):323&#x2013;339. doi: 10.1177/0145445516673998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0145445516673998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27760807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Morton NA. The PEDro scale is a valid measure of the methodological quality of clinical trials: a demographic study. Aust J Physiother. 2009;55(2):129&#x2013;133. doi: 10.1016/S0004-9514(09)70043-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0004-9514(09)70043-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19463084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2003;83(8):713&#x2013;721. doi: 10.1093/ptj/83.8.713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/83.8.713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamato TP, Maher C, Koes B, Moseley A. The PEDro scale had acceptably high convergent validity, construct validity, and interrater reliability in evaluating methodological quality of pharmaceutical trials. J Clin Epidemiol. 2017;86:176&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.03.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stojanovi&#x107; E, Risti&#x107; V, McMaster DT, Milanovi&#x107; Z. Effect of plyometric training on vertical jump performance in female athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(5):975&#x2013;986. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0634-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0634-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27704484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi A, Arazi H, Young WB, Saez de Villarreal E. The effects of plyometric training on change-of-direction ability: a meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(5):563&#x2013;573. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2015-0694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27139591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashin AG, McAuley JH. Clinimetrics: physiotherapy evidence database (PEDro) scale. J Physiother. 2020;66(1):59. doi: 10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2019.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31521549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Sanchez-Sanchez J, Romero-Moraleda B, Yanci J, Garcia-Hermoso A, Manuel CF. Effects of plyometric jump training in female soccer player's vertical jump height: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2020;38(13):1475&#x2013;1487. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2020.1745503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1745503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32255389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentine JC, Pigott TD, Rothstein HR. How many studies do you need?: a primer on statistical power for meta-analysis. J Educ Behav Stat. 2010;35(2):215&#x2013;247. doi: 10.3102/1076998609346961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/1076998609346961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigott T. Advances in meta-analysis. New York: Springer; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett MG, Lutz B. Effects of rope-jump training on the os calcis stiffness index of postpubescent girls. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(12):1913&#x2013;1919. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200212000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200212000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12471296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Ramirez-Campillo R, Granacher U. Effects of jumping exercise on muscular power in older adults: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(12):2843&#x2013;2857. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-1002-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-1002-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30341594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG. Analysing data and undertaking meta-analyses. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions: the Cochrane collaboration. Chichester: Wiley; 2008. pp. 243&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontopantelis E, Springate DA, Reeves D. A re-analysis of the Cochrane Library data: the dangers of unobserved heterogeneity in meta-analyses. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(7):e69930. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0069930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0069930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3724681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23922860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818cb278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Special topics in statistics. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions: the Cochrane collaboration. Chichester: Wiley; 2008. pp. 481&#x2013;529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1539&#x2013;1558. doi: 10.1002/sim.1186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.1186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Assessing risk of bias due to missing results in a synthesis. In: Higgins J, Green S, et al., editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. 2. Chichester: Wiley; 2019. p. 365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JPA, Terrin N, Jones DR, Lau J, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d4002. doi: 10.1136/bmj.d4002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d4002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315(7109):629&#x2013;634. doi: 10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot-based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56(2):455&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1111/j.0006-341X.2000.00455.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0006-341X.2000.00455.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L, Lin L. The trim-and-fill method for publication bias: practical guidelines and recommendations based on a large database of meta-analyses. Medicine. 2019;98(23):e15987. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000015987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000015987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6571372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31169736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Clark CCT, Ramirez-Campillo R, Davies MJ, Drury B. A meta-analysis of plyometric training in female youth: its efficacy and shortcomings in the literature. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:1996&#x2013;2008. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002768</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30052601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Sandercock G, Ramirez-Campillo R, Clark CCT, Fernandes JFT, Drury B. A meta-analysis of resistance training in female youth: its effect on muscular strength, and shortcomings in the literature. Sports Med. 2018;48:1661&#x2013;1671. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0914-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0914-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29626334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Sandercock GR, Ramirez-Campillo R, Meylan C, Collison J, Parry DA. A meta-analysis of maturation-related variation in adolescent boy athletes' adaptations to short-term resistance training. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1041&#x2013;1051. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2016.1209306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1209306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27454545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Akl EA, Kunz R, Vist G, Brozek J, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction-GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(4):383&#x2013;394. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Alonso-Coello P, Guyatt GH, Yepes-Nu&#xf1;ez JJ, Akl EA, Hazlewood G, et al. GRADE Guidelines: 19. Assessing the certainty of evidence in the importance of outcomes or values and preferences&#x2014;risk of bias and indirectness. J Clin Epidemiol. 2019;111:94&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.01.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.01.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29452223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Coello PA, Guyatt GH, Yepes-Nu&#xf1;ez JJ, Akl EA, Hazlewood G, et al. GRADE guidelines: 20. Assessing the certainty of evidence in the importance of outcomes or values and preferences&#x2014;inconsistency, imprecision, and other domains. J Clin Epidemiol. 2019;111:83&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.05.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29800687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Kunz R, Brozek J, Alonso-Coello P, Rind D, et al. Corrigendum to GRADE guidelines 6. Rating the quality of evidence-imprecision. J Clin Epidemiol 2011;64:1283&#x2013;1293. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;137:265. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2021.04.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2021.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34174652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez de Villarreal E, Suarez-Arrones L, Requena B, Haff GG, Ramos Veliz R. Enhancing performance in professional water polo players: dryland training, in-water training, and combined training. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(4):1089&#x2013;1097. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25259469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez de Villarreal ES, Suarez-Arrones L, Requena B, Haff GG, Ramos-Veliz R. Effects of dry-land versus in-water specific strength training on professional male water polo players' performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(11):3179&#x2013;3187. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24818541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escriv&#xe1;-Sell&#xe9;s FR, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effect of two periods of power training on performance in the thrust, barracuda and boost exercises in synchronised swimming. Apunts Ed Fis Deport. 2020;142:35&#x2013;45. doi: 10.5672/apunts.2014-0983.es.(2020/4).142.05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5672/apunts.2014-0983.es.(2020/4).142.05</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamandulis S, Snieckus A, Venckunas T, Aagaard P, Masiulis N, Skurvydas A. Rapid increase in training load affects markers of skeletal muscle damage and mechanical performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(11):2953&#x2013;2961. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318243ff21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318243ff21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyttle AD, Wilson GJ, Ostrowski KJ. Enhancing performance: maximal power versus combined weights and plyometrics training. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10(3):173&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques MC, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, Marinho DA, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D. In-season strength training in elite junior swimmers: the role of the low-volume, high-velocity training on swimming performance. J Hum Kinet. 2020;74(1):71&#x2013;84. doi: 10.2478/hukin-2020-0015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polhemus R, Burkhardt E. The effects of plyometric training with ankle and vest weights on conventional weight training programs for mess and women. Nat Strength Coach Assoc J. 1980;2(1):13&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1519/0199-610X(1980)002&lt;0013:TEOPTW&gt;2.3.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/0199-610X(1980)002&lt;0013:TEOPTW&gt;2.3.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejman M, Bilewski M, Szczepan S, Klarowicz A, Rudnik D, Mackala K. Assessing the impact of a targeted plyometric training on changes in selected kinematic parameters of the swimming start. Acta Bioeng Biomech. 2017;19(2):149&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28869635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zwaard S, Koppens TFP, Weide G, Levels K, Hofmijster MJ, de Koning JJ, et al. Training-induced muscle adaptations during competitive preparation in elite female rowers. Front Sports Active Liv. 2021;3:781942. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2021.781942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.781942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8692787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34957399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro NM, Marinho DA, Marques MC, Batalha NP, Morou&#xe7;o PG. Effects of dry-land strength and conditioning programs in age group swimmers. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(9):2447&#x2013;2454. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28825604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aurell-Badenas V, Murias-Lozano R, Rodr&#xed;guez-L&#xf3;pez ES, Garc&#xed;a-Gim&#xe9;nez A. Efficacy of plyometrics in the neuromuscular fatigue during triathlon: a pilot study. Rev Int Med Cienc Act Fis Dep. 2020;20(79):551&#x2013;566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellver M, Drobnic F, Jovell E, Ferrer-Roca V, Abalos X, Del Rio L, et al. Jumping rope and whole-body vibration program effects on bone values in Olympic artistic swimmers. J Bone Miner Metab. 2021;39(5):858&#x2013;867. doi: 10.1007/s00774-021-01224-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00774-021-01224-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop DC, Smith RJ, Smith MF, Rigby HE. Effect of plyometric training on swimming block start performance in adolescents. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(7):2137&#x2013;2143. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b866d0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b866d0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonacci J, Green D, Saunders PU, Franettovich M, Blanch P, Vicenzino B. Plyometric training as an intervention to correct altered neuromotor control during running after cycling in triathletes: a preliminary randomised controlled trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2011;12(1):15&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.ptsp.2010.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2010.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21256445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Born DP, St&#xf6;ggl T, Petrov A, Burkhardt D, L&#xfc;thy F, Romann M. Analysis of freestyle swimming sprint start performance after maximal strength or vertical jump training in competitive female and male junior swimmers. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(2):323&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31985714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breed RV, Young WB. The effect of a resistance training programme on the grab, track and swing starts in swimming. J Sports Sci. 2003;21(3):213&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1080/0264041031000071047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0264041031000071047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12703850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ca&#xf1;as-Jamett R, Figueroa-Puig J, Ramirez-Campillo R, Tuesta M. Plyometric training improves swimming performance in recreationally-trained swimmers. Rev Brasil Med Esport. 2020;26(5):436&#x2013;440. doi: 10.1590/1517-8692202026052019_0052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-8692202026052019_0052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan-Shuttler JD, Edmonds R, Eddy C, O&#x2019;Neill V, Ives SJ. The Effect of concurrent plyometric training versus submaximal aerobic cycling on rowing economy, peak power, and performance in male high school rowers. Sports Med Open. 2017;3(1):1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1186/s40798-017-0075-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-017-0075-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5288420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28150178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan-Shuttler JD, Edmonds R, Eddy C, O'Neill V, Ives SJ. Beyond peak, a simple approach to assess rowing power and the impact of training: a technical report. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(6):233&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6355124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30761208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido N, Marinho DA, Reis VM, van den Tillaar R, Costa AM, Silva AJ, et al. Does combined dry land strength and aerobic training inhibit performance of young competitive swimmers? J Sports Sci Med. 2010;9(2):300&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones JV, Pyne DB, Haff GG, Newton RU. Comparison of ballistic and strength training on swimming turn and dry-land leg extensor characteristics in elite swimmers. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2018;13(2):262&#x2013;269. doi: 10.1177/1747954117726017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747954117726017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JF, Morrow A, Leger A. Changes in rowing ergometer, weight-lifting, vertical jump and isokinetic performance in response to standard and standard plus phytometric training-programs. Intern J Sports Med. 1993;14(8):449&#x2013;454. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1021209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1021209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8300271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin MS, Pareja Blanco F, De Villarreal ES. Effects of different in-season strength training methods on strength gains and water polo performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16(4):591&#x2013;600. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33508780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk DJ, Robinson TL, Switaj ZJ, Drinkwater EJ. Comparison of the hang high pull and loaded jump squat for the development of vertical jump and isometric force-time characteristics. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(1):17&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28426514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potdevin FJ, Alberty ME, Chevutschi A, Pelayo P, Sidney MC. Effects of a 6-week plyometric training program on performances in pubescent swimmers. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(1):80&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181fef720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181fef720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21157388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupi&#x161;ov&#xe1; Z, Pupi&#x161; M, S&#xfd;kora J, Br&#x171;nn D, Gini&#x10d;ov&#xe1; J, Pavlovi&#x107; R. The impact of a specific training programme on the selected parameters of swimming turns. Turk J Kinesiol. 2019;5:36&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Veliz R, Requena B, Suarez-Arrones L, Newton RU, Saez de Villarreal E. Effects of 18-week in-season heavy-resistance and power training on throwing velocity, strength, jumping, and maximal sprint swim performance of elite male water polo players. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(4):1007&#x2013;1014. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24077370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebutini VZ, Pereira G, Bohrer RC, Ugrinowitsch C, Rodacki AL. Plyometric long jump training with progressive loading improves kinetic and kinematic swimming start parameters. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(9):2392&#x2013;2398. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24531431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sammoud S, Negra Y, Bouguezzi R, Hachana Y, Granacher U, Chaabene H. The effects of plyometric jump training on jump and sport-specific performances in prepubertal female swimmers. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2021;19(1):25&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1016/j.jesf.2020.07.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2020.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7475125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sammoud S, Negra Y, Chaabene H, Bouguezzi R, Moran J, Granacher U. The effects of plyometric jump training on jumping and swimming performances in prepubertal male swimmers. J Sports Sci Med. 2019;18(4):805&#x2013;811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6873130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31827366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veliz RR, Suarez-Arrones L, Requena B, Haff GG, Feito J, Saez de Villarreal E. Effects of in-competitive season power-oriented and heavy resistance lower-body training on performance of elite female water polo players. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(2):458&#x2013;465. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Alvarez C, Garc&#xed;a-Pinillos F, Gentil P, Moran J, Pereira LA, et al. Plyometric training in young male soccer players: potential effect of jump height. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2019;31(3):306&#x2013;313. doi: 10.1123/pes.2018-0207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.2018-0207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30736711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Pereira LA, Kobal R, Zanetti V, Kitamura K, Abad CCC, et al. Transference effect of vertical and horizontal plyometrics on sprint performance of high-level U-20 soccer players. J Sports Sci. 2015;33(20):2182&#x2013;2191. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2015.1081394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1081394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26390150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Tricoli V, Roschel H, Nakamura FY, Cal Abad CC, Kobal R, et al. Transference of traditional versus complex strength and power training to sprint performance. J Hum Kinet. 2014;28(41):265&#x2013;273. doi: 10.2478/hukin-2014-0054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4120461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25114753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malisoux L, Francaux M, Nielens H, Renard P, Lebacq J, Theisen D. Calcium sensitivity of human single muscle fibers following plyometric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(11):1901&#x2013;1908. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000232022.21361.47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000232022.21361.47</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malisoux L, Francaux M, Nielens H, Theisen D. Stretch-shortening cycle exercises: an effective training paradigm to enhance power output of human single muscle fibers. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2006;100(3):771&#x2013;779. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01027.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01027.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16322375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malisoux L, Francaux M, Theisen D. Effect Of plyometric training on mechanical properties of human single muscle fibres. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2005;37:S288-S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran J, Liew B, Ramirez-Campillo R, Granacher U, Negra Y, Chaabene H. The effects of plyometric jump training on lower-limb stiffness in healthy individuals: a meta-analytical comparison. J Sport Health Sci. 2021;5&#x2013;24. 10.1016/j.jshs.2021.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10105022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DJ, Owen NJ, Cunningham DJ, Cook CJ, Kilduff LP. Strength and power predictors of swimming starts in international sprint swimmers. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(4):950&#x2013;955. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c8656f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c8656f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow JWC, Hay JG, Wilson BD, Imel C. Turning techniques of elite swimmers. J Sports Sci. 1984;2(3):241&#x2013;255. doi: 10.1080/02640418408729720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640418408729720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aspenes S, Kjendlie PL, Hoff J, Helgerud J. Combined strength and endurance training in competitive swimmers. J Sports Sci Med. 2009;8(3):357&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3763280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido N, Marinho D, Barbosa T, Costa A, Silva A, P&#xe9;rez-Turpin J, et al. Relationships between dry land strength, power variables and short sprint performance in young competitive swimmers. J Human Sport Exerc. 2010;5(2):240&#x2013;249. doi: 10.4100/jhse.2010.52.12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4100/jhse.2010.52.12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Pinillos F, Camara-Perez JC, Soto-Hermoso VM, Latorre-Roman PA. A high intensity interval training (HIIT)-based running plan improves athletic performance by improving muscle power. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(1):146&#x2013;153. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27172268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourgoulis V, Boli A, Aggeloussis N, Toubekis A, Antoniou P, Kasimatis P, et al. The effect of leg kick on sprint front crawl swimming. J Sports Sci. 2014;32(3):278&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2013.823224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2013.823224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24016316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morais JE, Marinho DA, Arellano R, Barbosa TM. Start and turn performances of elite sprinters at the 2016 European Championships in swimming. Sports Biomech. 2019;18(1):100&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1080/14763141.2018.1435713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2018.1435713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29578384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20(5 Suppl):S135&#x2013;S145. doi: 10.1249/00005768-198810001-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-198810001-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3057313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducrocq GP, Hureau TJ, Meste O, Blain GM. Similar cardioventilatory but greater neuromuscular stimuli with interval drop jump than with interval running. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;17:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31188680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons TS, Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Arnett SW, Schafer MA, Igaune L. Evaluation of repetitive jumping intensity on the digi-jump machine. Int J Exerc Sci. 2020;13(2):818&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E, Kellis E, Kraemer WJ, Izquierdo M. Determining variables of plyometric training for improving vertical jump height performance: a meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(2):495&#x2013;506. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318196b7c6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318196b7c6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19197203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E, Requena B, Cronin JB. The effects of plyometric training on sprint performance: a meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(2):575&#x2013;584. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318220fd03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318220fd03</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22240550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Cronin JB, Faigenbaum AD, Haff GG, Howard R, Kraemer WJ, et al. National strength and conditioning association position statement on long-term athletic development. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(6):1491&#x2013;1509. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26933920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RS, Oliver JL, Faigenbaum AD, Howard R, De Ste Croix MB, Williams CA, et al. Long-term athletic development, part 2: barriers to success and potential solutions. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(5):1451&#x2013;1464. doi: 10.1519/01.JSC.0000465424.75389.56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/01.JSC.0000465424.75389.56</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25909962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossler R, Donath L, Verhagen E, Junge A, Schweizer T, Faude O. Exercise-based injury prevention in child and adolescent sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2014;44(12):1733&#x2013;1748. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0234-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0234-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25129698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Carroll RM, Simenz CJ. Strength and conditioning practices of National Hockey League strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(4):889&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Hintz MJ, Simenz CJ. Strength and conditioning practices of Major League Baseball strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(3):538&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weldon A, Duncan MJ, Turner A, Sampaio J, Noon M, Wong D, et al. Contemporary practices of strength and conditioning coaches in professional soccer. Biol Sport. 2021;38(3):377&#x2013;390. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2021.99328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.99328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8329977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34475621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Moran J, Oliver JL, Pedley JS, Lloyd RS, Granacher U. Programming plyometric-jump training in soccer: a review. Sports. 2022;10(6):94. doi: 10.3390/sports10060094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports10060094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9230747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35736834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Fauth ML, Garceau LR, Petushek EJ. Kinetic quantification of plyometric exercise intensity. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(12):3288&#x2013;3298. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31821656a3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31821656a3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22080319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebben WP, Simenz C, Jensen RL. Evaluation of plyometric intensity using electromyography. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(3):861&#x2013;868. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a834b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a834b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Andrade DC, Izquierdo M. Effects of plyometric training volume and training surface on explosive strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(10):2714&#x2013;2722. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318280c9e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318280c9e9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23254550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurado-Lavanant A, Alvero-Cruz JR, Pareja-Blanco F, Melero-Romero C, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Fernandez-Garcia JC. The effects of aquatic plyometric training on repeated jumps, drop jumps and muscle damage. Int J Sports Med. 2018;39(10):764&#x2013;772. doi: 10.1055/s-0034-1398574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0034-1398574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26393814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heywood SE, Mentiplay BF, Rahmann AE, McClelland JA, Geigle PR, Bower KJ, et al. The effectiveness of aquatic plyometric training in improving strength, jumping, and sprinting: a systematic review. J Sport Rehabil. 2022;31(1):85&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1123/jsr.2020-0432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2020-0432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34564070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held NJ, Perrotta AS, Buschmann LK, Bredin SSD, Warburton DER. A systematic review of the efficacy of lower body aquatic plyometric training: the development of evidence-based recommendations for practitioners. Health Fit J Canada. 2019;12(1):17&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Pereira LA, Andrade D, M&#xe9;ndez-Rebolledo G, de la Fuente CI, Castro-Sepulveda M, et al. Tapering strategies applied to plyometric jump training: a systematic review with meta-analysis of randomized-controlled trials. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2021;1:53&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32674540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosquet L, Montpetit J, Arvisais D, Mujika I. Effects of tapering on performance: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1358&#x2013;1365. doi: 10.1249/mss.0b013e31806010e0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e31806010e0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I. The influence of training characteristics and tapering on the adaptation in highly trained individuals: a review. Int J Sports Med. 1998;19(7):439&#x2013;446. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-971942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-971942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9839839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I. Tapering and peaking for optimal performance. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>