<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">29927884</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hormonal Contraceptive Use Does Not Affect Strength, Endurance, or Body Composition Adaptations to Combined Strength and Endurance Training in Women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>449</StartPage><EndPage>457</EndPage><MedlinePgn>449-457</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002713</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Myllyaho, MM, Ihalainen, JK, Hackney, AC, Valtonen, M, Nummela, A, Vaara, E, H&#xe4;kkinen, K, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen, H, and Taipale, RS. Hormonal contraceptive use does not affect strength, endurance, or body composition adaptations to combined strength and endurance training in women. J Strength Cond Res 35(2): 449-457, 2021-This study examined the effects of a 10-week period of high-intensity combined strength and endurance training on strength, endurance, body composition, and serum hormone concentrations in physically active women using hormonal contraceptives (HCs, n = 9) compared with those who had never used hormonal contraceptives (NHCs, n = 9). Training consisted of 2 strength training sessions and 2 high-intensity running interval sessions per week. Maximal bilateral isometric leg press (Isom), maximal bilateral dynamic leg press (one repetition maximum [1RM]), countermovement jump (CMJ), a 3,000-m running test (3,000 m), body composition, and serum hormone levels were measured before and after training between days 1-5 of each subject's menstrual cycle. Both groups increased 1RM and CMJ: HC = 13.2% (p &lt; 0.001) and 9.6% (p &lt; 0.05), and NHC = 8.3% (p &lt; 0.01) and 8.5% (p &lt; 0.001). Hormonal contraceptive improved 3,000 m by 3.5% (p &lt; 0.05) and NHC by 1% (n.s.). Never used hormonal contraceptive increased lean mass by 2.1% (p &lt; 0.001), whereas body fat percentage decreased from 23.9 &#xb1; 6.7 to 22.4 &#xb1; 6.0 (-6.0%, p &lt; 0.05). No significant changes were observed in body composition in HC. No significant between-group differences were observed in any of the performance variables. Luteinizing hormone concentrations decreased significantly (p &lt; 0.05) over 10 weeks in NHC, whereas other hormone levels remained statistically unaltered in both groups. It seems that the present training is equally appropriate for improving strength, endurance, and body composition in women using HC as those not using HC without disrupting hypothalamic-pituitary-gonadal axis function.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2018 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Myllyaho</LastName><ForeName>Moona M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology of Physical Activity, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ihalainen</LastName><ForeName>Johanna K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology of Physical Activity, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackney</LastName><ForeName>Anthony C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise &amp; Sport Science, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valtonen</LastName><ForeName>Maarit</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Olympic Sport, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nummela</LastName><ForeName>Ari</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Olympic Sport, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaara</LastName><ForeName>Elina</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>JAMK University of Applied Sciences, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xe4;kkinen</LastName><ForeName>Keijo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology of Physical Activity, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen</LastName><ForeName>Heikki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biology of Physical Activity, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taipale</LastName><ForeName>Ritva S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kajaani University of Applied Sciences, Kajaani, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003270">Contraceptive Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003270" MajorTopicYN="N">Contraceptive Agents</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endurance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29927884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202102000-00022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ashley CD, Kramer ML, Bishop P. Estrogen and substrate metabolism: A review of contradictory research. Sports Med 29: 221&#x2013;227, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachmann G, Bancroft J, Braunstein G, Burger H, Davis S, Dennerstein L, et al. Androgen insufficiency: the Princeton consensus statement on definition, classification, and assessment. Fertil Steril 77: 660&#x2013;665, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell GJ, Syrotuik D, Martin TP, Burnham R, Quinney HA. Effect of concurrent strength and endurance training on skeletal muscle properties and hormone concentrations in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol 81: 418&#x2013;427, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrows M, Peters CE. The influence of oral contraceptives on athletic performance in female athletes. Sports Med 37: 557&#x2013;574, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casazza GA, Suh SH, Miller BF, Navazio FM, Brooks GA. Effects of oral contraceptives on peak exercise capacity. J Appl Physiol (1985) 93: 1698&#x2013;1702, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casazza GA, Jacobs KA, Suh SH, Miller BF, Horning MA, Brooks GA. Menstrual cycle phase and oral contraceptive effects on triglyceride mobilization during exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 97: 302&#x2013;309, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Hawley JA. The molecular bases of training adaptation. Sports Med 37: 737&#x2013;763, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences 2. Hilsdale, NJ: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 25&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consitt LA, Copeland JL, Tremblay MS. Endogenous anabolic hormone responses to endurance versus resistance exercise and training in women. Sports Med 32: 1&#x2013;22, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello JT, Bieuzen F, Bleakley CM. Where are all the female participants in sports and exercise medicine research? Eur J Sport Sci 14: 847&#x2013;851, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis KM, Tepper NK, Jatlaoui TC, Berry-Bibee E, Horton LG, Zapata LB, et al. U.S. medical eligibility criteria for contraceptive use, 2016. MMWR Recomm Rep 65: 1&#x2013;103, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis AR, Westhoff CL. Primary dysmenorrhea in adolescent girls and treatment with oral contraceptives. J Pediatr Adolesc Gynecol 14: 3&#x2013;8, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edge J, Bishop D, Goodman C. The effects of training intensity on muscle buffer capacity in females. Eur J Appl Physiol 96: 97&#x2013;105, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott K, Cable N, Reilly T. Does oral contraceptive use affect maximum force production in women? Br J Sports Med 39: 15&#x2013;19, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackney A. Influence of oestrogen on muscle glycogen utilization during exercise. Acta Physiol Scand 167: 273&#x2013;274, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Kallinen M. Neuromuscular adaptations and serum hormones in women during short-term intensive strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 64: 106&#x2013;111, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Cheng S, Kim DH, Komi PV. Neuromuscular adaptations and serum hormones in females during prolonged power training. Int J Sports Med 11: 91&#x2013;98, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA. Molecular responses to strength and endurance training: Are they incompatible? Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 34: 355&#x2013;361, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helgerud J, Hoydal K, Wang E, Karlsen T, Berg P, Bjerkaas M, et al. Aerobic high-intensity intervals improve VO2max more than moderate training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 39: 665&#x2013;671, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hessemer V, Bruck K. Influence of menstrual cycle on shivering, skin blood flow, and sweating responses measured at night. J Appl Physiol (1985) 59: 1902&#x2013;1910, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson R. Interference of strength development by simultaneously training for strength and endurance. Eur J Appl Physiol 45: 255&#x2013;263, 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce S, Sabapathy S, Bulmer A, Minahan C. Effect of long-term oral contraceptive use on determinants of endurance performance. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1891&#x2013;1896, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebrun CM, Petit MA, McKenzie DC, Taunton JE, Prior JC. Decreased maximal aerobic capacity with use of a triphasic oral contraceptive in highly active women: A randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med 37: 315&#x2013;320, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkola J, Vesterinen V, Taipale R, Capostagno B, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Nummela A. Effect of resistance training regimens on treadmill running and neuromuscular performance in recreational endurance runners. J Sports Sc 29: 1359&#x2013;1371, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran VH, Leathard HL, Coley J. Cardiovascular functioning during the menstrual cycle. Clin Physiol 20: 496&#x2013;504, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pivarnik JM, Marichal CJ, Spillman T, Morrow JR Jr. Menstrual cycle phase affects temperature regulation during endurance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 72: 543&#x2013;548, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman LM, Scroop GC, Norman RJ. Impact of menstrual cycle phase on the exercise status of young, sedentary women. Eur J Appl Physiol 90: 505&#x2013;513, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res 18: 918&#x2013;920, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickenlund A, Carlstrom K, Ekblom B, Brismar TB, Von Schoultz B, Hirschberg AL. Effects of oral contraceptives on body composition and physical performance in female athletes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 89: 4364&#x2013;4370, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarwar R, Niclos BB, Rutherford O. Changes in muscle strength, relaxation rate and fatiguability during the human menstrual cycle. J Physiol 493: 267&#x2013;272, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillanpaa E, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Laaksonen DE, Karavirta L, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Serum basal hormone concentrations, nutrition and physical fitness during strength and/or endurance training in 39-64-year-old women. Int J Sports Med 31: 110&#x2013;117, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E, Laaksonen DE, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Karavirta L, Jensen B, Kraemer WJ, et al. Body composition, fitness, and metabolic health during strength and endurance training and their combination in middle-aged and older women. Eur J Appl Physiol 106: 285&#x2013;296, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipila S, Finni T, Kovanen V. Estrogen influences on neuromuscular function in postmenopausal women. Calcif Tissue Int 96: 222&#x2013;233, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh SH, Casazza GA, Horning MA, Miller BF, Brooks GA. Effects of oral contraceptives on glucose flux and substrate oxidation rates during rest and exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 94: 285&#x2013;294, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taipale RS, Mikkola J, Salo T, Hokka L, Vesterinen V, Kraemer WJ, et al. Mixed maximal and explosive strength training in recreational endurance runners. J Strength Cond Res 28: 689&#x2013;699, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaiksaar S, Jurimae J, Maestu J, Purge P, Kalytka S, Shakhlina L, et al. No effect of menstrual cycle phase and oral contraceptive use on endurance performance in rowers. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1571&#x2013;1578, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiegratz I, Kutschera E, Lee JH, Moore C, Mellinger U, Winkler UH, et al. Effect of four different oral contraceptives on various sex hormones and serum-binding globulins. Contraception 67: 25&#x2013;32, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin JP, Rhea MR, Wilson SMC, Loenneke JP, Anderson JC. Concurrent training: A meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2293&#x2013;2307, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman Y, Eijkemans MJ, Coelingh Bennink HJ, Blankenstein MA, Fauser BC. The effect of combined oral contraception on testosterone levels in healthy women: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Reprod Update 20: 76&#x2013;105, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>