<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31803464</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2042-0188</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Therapeutic advances in endocrinology and metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Endocrinol Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reduced physical activity in young and older adults: metabolic and musculoskeletal implications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2042018819888824</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2042018819888824</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2042018819888824</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/2042018819888824</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Although the health benefits of regular physical activity and exercise are well established and have been incorporated into national public health recommendations, there is a relative lack of understanding pertaining to the harmful effects of <i>physical inactivity</i>. Experimental paradigms including complete immobilization and bed rest are not physiologically representative of sedentary living. A useful 'real-world' approach to contextualize the physiology of societal downward shifts in physical activity patterns is that of short-term daily <i>step reduction</i>.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Step-reduction studies have largely focused on musculoskeletal and metabolic health parameters, providing relevant disease models for metabolic syndrome, type 2 diabetes (T2D), nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD), sarcopenia and osteopenia/osteoporosis. In untrained individuals, even a short-term reduction in physical activity has a significant impact on skeletal muscle protein and carbohydrate metabolism, causing anabolic resistance and peripheral insulin resistance, respectively. From a metabolic perspective, short-term inactivity-induced peripheral insulin resistance in skeletal muscle and adipose tissue, with consequent liver triglyceride accumulation, leads to hepatic insulin resistance and a characteristic dyslipidaemia. Concomitantly, various inactivity-related factors contribute to a decline in <i>function</i>; a reduction in cardiorespiratory fitness, muscle mass and muscle strength.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Physical inactivity maybe particularly deleterious in certain patient populations, such as those at high risk of T2D or in the elderly, considering concomitant sarcopenia or osteoporosis. The effects of short-term physical inactivity (with step reduction) are reversible on resumption of habitual physical activity in younger people, but less so in older adults. Nutritional interventions and resistance training offer potential strategies to prevent these deleterious metabolic and musculoskeletal effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPACT" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Individuals at high risk of/with cardiometabolic disease and older adults may be more prone to these acute periods of inactivity due to acute illness or hospitalization. Understanding the risks is paramount to implementing countermeasures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2019.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowden Davies</LastName><ForeName>Kelly A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9448-0732</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical, Nutritional and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Medical Sciences, Newcastle University, Catherine Cookson Building M1.038, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE2 4HH, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pickles</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Ageing and Chronic Disease, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sprung</LastName><ForeName>Victoria S</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Science, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kemp</LastName><ForeName>Graham J</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Ageing and Chronic Disease, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alam</LastName><ForeName>Uazman</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Ageing and Chronic Disease, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Daniel R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology and Physical Education, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tahrani</LastName><ForeName>Abd A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Metabolism and Systems Research, College of Medical and Dental Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuthbertson</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Ageing and Chronic Disease, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ther Adv Endocrinol Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532143</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2042-0188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anabolic resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liver fat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical inactivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest statement: The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31803464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2042018819888824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_2042018819888824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tremblay MS, Aubert S, Barnes JD, et al. Sedentary Behavior Research Network (SBRN): Terminology Consensus Project process and outcome. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 2017; 14: 75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28599680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth FW, Roberts CK, Thyfault JP, et al. Role of inactivity in chronic diseases: evolutionary insight and pathophysiological mechanisms. Physiol Rev 2017; 97: 1351&#x2013;1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6347102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alibegovic AC, Sonne MP, Hojbjerre L, et al. Insulin resistance induced by physical inactivity is associated with multiple transcriptional changes in skeletal muscle in young men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 2010; 299: E752&#x2013;E763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abadi A, Glover EI, Isfort RJ, et al. Limb immobilization induces a coordinate down-regulation of mitochondrial and other metabolic pathways in men and women. PLoS One 2009; 4: e6518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2716517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19654872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King DS, Dalsky GP, Clutter WE, et al. Effects of lack of exercise on insulin secretion and action in trained subjects. Am J Physiol 1988; 254: E537&#x2013;E542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3284381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer E, Shook RP, Thomas DM, et al. 45-year trends in women&#x2019;s use of time and household management energy expenditure. PLoS One 2013; 8: e56620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3577846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris JN, Heady JA, Raffle PA, et al. Coronary heart-disease and physical activity of work. Lancet 1953; 265: 1111&#x2013;1120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13110075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vina J, Sanchis-Gomar F, Martinez-Bello V, et al. Exercise acts as a drug; the pharmacological benefits of exercise. Br J Pharmacol 2012; 167: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22486393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair SN, Kohl HW, 3rd, Paffenbarger RS, Jr, et al. Physical fitness and all-cause mortality: a prospective study of healthy men and women. JAMA 1989; 262: 2395&#x2013;2401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2795824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikander R, Sievanen H, Heinonen A, et al. Targeted exercise against osteoporosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis for optimising bone strength throughout life. BMC Med 2010; 8: 47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zampieri S, Pietrangelo L, Loefler S, et al. Lifelong physical exercise delays age-associated skeletal muscle decline. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2015; 70: 163&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warburton DE, Nicol CW, Bredin SS. Health benefits of physical activity: the evidence. CMAJ 2006; 174: 801&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1402378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16534088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee IM, Shiroma EJ, Lobelo F, et al. Effect of physical inactivity on major non-communicable diseases worldwide: an analysis of burden of disease and life expectancy. Lancet 2012; 380: 219&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3645500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding D, Lawson KD, Kolbe-Alexander TL, et al. The economic burden of physical inactivity: a global analysis of major non-communicable diseases. Lancet 2016; 388: 1311&#x2013;1324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27475266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker JM, Welk GJ, Beyler NK. Physical activity in US adults: compliance with the physical activity guidelines for Americans. Am J Prev Med 2011; 40: 454&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21406280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarborough P, Bhatnagar P, Wickramasinghe KK, et al. The economic burden of ill health due to diet, physical inactivity, smoking, alcohol and obesity in the UK: an update to 2006&#x2013;07 NHS costs. J Public Health 2011; 33: 527&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21562029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church TS, Thomas DM, Tudor-Locke C, et al. Trends over 5 decades in U.S. occupation-related physical activity and their associations with obesity. PLoS One 2011; 6: e19657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Althoff T, Sosic R, Hicks JL, et al. Large-scale physical activity data reveal worldwide activity inequality. Nature 2017; 547: 336&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5774986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28693034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen N, Healy GN, Matthews CE, et al. Too much sitting: the population-health science of sedentary behavior. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 2010; 38: 105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20577058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen N, Salmon J, Koohsari MJ, et al. Sedentary behaviour and health: mapping environmental and social contexts to underpin chronic disease prevention. Br J Sports Med 2014; 48: 174&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24415410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakrania K, Edwardson CL, Bodicoat DH, et al. Associations of mutually exclusive categories of physical activity and sedentary time with markers of cardiometabolic health in English adults: a cross-sectional analysis of the Health Survey for England. BMC Public Health 2016; 16: 25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4709945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26753523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas A, Oh PI, Faulkner GE, et al. Sedentary time and its association with risk for disease incidence, mortality, and hospitalization in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Intern Med 2015; 162: 123&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25599350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henson J, Yates T, Biddle SJ, et al. Associations of objectively measured sedentary behaviour and physical activity with markers of cardiometabolic health. Diabetologia 2013; 56: 1012&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23456209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henson J, Edwardson CL, Morgan B, et al. Associations of sedentary time with fat distribution in a high-risk population. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2015; 47: 1727&#x2013;1734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith L, Thomas EL, Bell JD, et al. The association between objectively measured sitting and standing with body composition: a pilot study using MRI. BMJ Open 2014; 4: e005476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4067859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24916091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knudsen SH, Hansen LS, Pedersen M, et al. Changes in insulin sensitivity precede changes in body composition during 14 days of step reduction combined with overfeeding in healthy young men. J Appl Physiol 2012; 113: 7&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22556394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhin JP, Richardson JD, Betts JA, et al. Exercise counteracts the effects of short-term overfeeding and reduced physical activity independent of energy imbalance in healthy young men. J Physiol 2013; 591: 6231&#x2013;6243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3892474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24167223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden Davies KA, Sprung VS, Norman JA, et al. Short-term decreased physical activity with increased sedentary behaviour causes metabolic derangements and altered body composition: effects in individuals with and without a first-degree relative with type 2 diabetes. Diabetologia 2018; 61: 1282&#x2013;1294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krogh-Madsen R, Thyfault JP, Broholm C, et al. A 2-wk reduction of ambulatory activity attenuates peripheral insulin sensitivity. J Appl Physiol 2010; 108: 1034&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen RH, Krogh-Madsen R, Thomsen C, et al. Metabolic responses to reduced daily steps in healthy nonexercising men. Chicago, IL: American Medical Association, 2008, pp.1261&#x2013;1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18349087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon NC, Hurst TL, Talbot DC, et al. Effect of short-term reduced physical activity on cardiovascular risk factors in active lean and overweight middle-aged men. Metabolism 2013; 62: 361&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22995864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikus CR, Oberlin DJ, Libla JL, et al. Lowering physical activity impairs glycemic control in healthy volunteers. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2012; 44: 225&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4551428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21716152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebovitz HE, Banerji MA. Point: visceral adiposity is causally related to insulin resistance. Diabetes Care 2005; 28: 2322&#x2013;2325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16123512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart CA, Shangraw RE, Prince MJ, et al. Bed-rest-induced insulin resistance occurs primarily in muscle. Metabolism 1988; 37: 802&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3043146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabol R, Petersen KF, Dufour S, et al. Reversal of muscle insulin resistance with exercise reduces postprandial hepatic de novo lipogenesis in insulin resistant individuals. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2011; 108: 13705&#x2013;13709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3158147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21808028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen KF, Dufour S, Savage DB, et al. The role of skeletal muscle insulin resistance in the pathogenesis of the metabolic syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2007; 104: 12587&#x2013;12594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1924794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17640906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFronzo RA, Tripathy D. Skeletal muscle insulin resistance is the primary defect in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care 2009; 32(Suppl. 2): S157&#x2013;S163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19875544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tieland M, Trouwborst I, Clark BC. Skeletal muscle performance and ageing. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2018; 9: 3&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5803609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer J, Biolo G, Cederholm T, et al. Evidence-based recommendations for optimal dietary protein intake in older people: a position paper from the PROT-AGE Study Group. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2013; 14: 542&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23867520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Tang JE, Moore DR, et al. Exercise training and protein metabolism: influences of contraction, protein intake, and sex-based differences. J Appl Physiol 2009; 106: 1692&#x2013;1701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19036897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell WK, Atherton PJ, Williams J, et al. Sarcopenia, dynapenia, and the impact of advancing age on human skeletal muscle size and strength; a quantitative review. Front Physiol 2012; 3: 260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3429036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22934016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Fielding RA. Skeletal muscle power: a critical determinant of physical functioning in older adults. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 2012; 40: 4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3245773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22016147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, von Allmen MT, Stokes T, et al. Failed recovery of glycemic control and myofibrillar protein synthesis with 2 wk of physical inactivity in overweight, prediabetic older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2018; 73: 1070&#x2013;1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6037059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29095970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verlaan S, Aspray TJ, Bauer JM, et al. Nutritional status, body composition, and quality of life in community-dwelling sarcopenic and non-sarcopenic older adults: a case&#x2013;control study. Clin Nutr 2017; 36: 267&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN, Koehler KM, Gallagher D, et al. Epidemiology of sarcopenia among the elderly in New Mexico. Am J Epidemiol 1998; 147: 755&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9554417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao L, Morley JE. Sarcopenia is recognized as an independent condition by an international classification of disease, tenth revision, clinical modification (ICD-10-CM) code. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2016; 17: 675&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27470918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>English KL, Paddon-Jones D. Protecting muscle mass and function in older adults during bed rest. Current opinion in clinical nutrition and metabolic care 2010; 13: 34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3276215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19898232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkin OJ, Travers RL, Gonzalez JT, et al. Exercise strategies to protect against the impact of short-term reduced physical activity on muscle function and markers of health in older men: study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials 2016; 17: 381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4969660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27484001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson D, Smith K, Babraj J, et al. Anabolic signaling deficits underlie amino acid resistance of wasting, aging muscle. FASEB J 2005; 19: 422&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Glover EI, Rennie MJ. Alterations of protein turnover underlying disuse atrophy in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol 2009; 107: 645&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D, Sheffield-Moore M, Urban RJ, et al. Essential amino acid and carbohydrate supplementation ameliorates muscle protein loss in humans during 28 days bedrest. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2004; 89: 4351&#x2013;4358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15356032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kortebein P, Ferrando A, Lombeida J, et al. Effect of 10 days of bed rest on skeletal muscle in healthy older adults. JAMA 2007; 297: 1769&#x2013;1774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17456818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkin O, McGuigan P, Thompson D, et al. A reduced activity model: a relevant tool for the study of ageing muscle. Biogerontology 2016; 17: 435&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4889637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26506931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tudor-Locke C, Craig CL, Aoyagi Y, et al. How many steps/day are enough? For older adults and special populations. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 2011; 8: 80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3169444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21798044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, McGlory C. CrossTalk proposal: the dominant mechanism causing disuse muscle atrophy is decreased protein synthesis. J Physiol 2014; 592: 5341&#x2013;5343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4270495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25512435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen L, Stokes KA, Churchward-Venne TA, et al. Two weeks of reduced activity decreases leg lean mass and induces &#x2018;anabolic resistance&#x2019; of myofibrillar protein synthesis in healthy elderly. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2013; 98: 2604&#x2013;2612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23589526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devries MC, Breen L, Von Allmen M, et al. Low-load resistance training during step-reduction attenuates declines in muscle mass and strength and enhances anabolic sensitivity in older men. Physiol Rep 2015; 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26265753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Rasmussen BB, Cadenas JG, et al. Aerobic exercise overcomes the age-related insulin resistance of muscle protein metabolism by improving endothelial function and Akt/mammalian target of rapamycin signaling. Diabetes 2007; 56: 1615&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2740742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17351147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, et al. Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis &#x2013; report of the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People. Age Ageing 2010; 39: 412&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batsis JA, Villareal DT. Sarcopenic obesity in older adults: aetiology, epidemiology and treatment strategies. Nat Rev Endocrinol 2018; 14: 513&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6241236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30065268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beals JW, Sukiennik RA, Nallabelli J, et al. Anabolic sensitivity of postprandial muscle protein synthesis to the ingestion of a protein-dense food is reduced in overweight and obese young adults. Am J Clin Nutr 2016; 104: 1014&#x2013;1022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27604771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beals JW, Mackenzie RWA, van Vliet S, et al. Protein-rich food ingestion stimulates mitochondrial protein synthesis in sedentary young adults of different BMIs. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2017; 102: 3415&#x2013;3424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28911136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smeuninx B, McKendry J, Wilson D, et al. Age-related anabolic resistance of myofibrillar protein synthesis is exacerbated in obese inactive individuals. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2017; 102: 3535&#x2013;3545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5587073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28911148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, von Allmen MT, Stokes T, et al. Failed recovery of glycemic control and myofibrillar protein synthesis with two weeks of physical inactivity in overweight, pre-diabetic older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. Epub ahead of print 31 October 2017. DOI: 10.1093/gerona/glx203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glx203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6037059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29095970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Current concepts and unresolved questions in dietary protein requirements and supplements in adults. Front Nutr 2017; 4: 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5420553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28534027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy CH, Saddler NI, Devries MC, et al. Leucine supplementation enhances integrative myofibrillar protein synthesis in free-living older men consuming lower- and higher-protein diets: a parallel-group crossover study. Am J Clin Nutr 2016; 104: 1594&#x2013;1606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27935521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komar B, Schwingshackl L, Hoffmann G. Effects of leucine-rich protein supplements on anthropometric parameter and muscle strength in the elderly: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Nutr Health Aging 2015; 19: 437&#x2013;446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25809808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng H, Kong J, Underwood C, et al. Systematic review and meta-analysis of the effect of protein and amino acid supplements in older adults with acute or chronic conditions. Br J Nutr 2018; 119: 527&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29508691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tieland M, Franssen R, Dullemeijer C, et al. The impact of dietary protein or amino acid supplementation on muscle mass and strength in elderly people: individual participant data and meta-analysis of RCT&#x2019;s. J Nutr Health Aging 2017; 21: 994&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29083440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR. Keeping older muscle &#x2018;young&#x2019; through dietary protein and physical activity. Adv Nutr 2014; 5: 599s&#x2013;607s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4188243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25469405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Kelly RP, Devries MC, et al. Low-load resistance exercise during inactivity is associated with greater fibre area and satellite cell expression in older skeletal muscle. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2018; 9: 747&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6104111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29761654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Winett RA. Uncomplicated resistance training and health-related outcomes: evidence for a public health mandate. Curr Sports Med Rep 2010; 9: 208&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4086449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Cotie LM, MacDonald MJ, et al. Citrulline does not enhance blood flow, microvascular circulation, or myofibrillar protein synthesis in elderly men at rest or following exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 2014; 307: E71&#x2013;E83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24824653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher SR, Goodwin JS, Protas EJ, et al. Ambulatory activity of older adults hospitalized with acute medical illness. J Am Geriatr Soc 2011; 59: 91&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3133455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21158744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MJ, Slentz CA, Kraus WE. Metabolic deterioration of the sedentary control group in clinical trials. J Appl Physiol 2011; 111: 1211&#x2013;1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21778417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loprinzi PD, Cardinal BJ. Association between objectively-measured physical activity and sleep, NHANES 2005&#x2013;2006. Ment Health Phys Act 2011; 4: 65&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Sanchez J, Recio-Rodriguez JI, Gomez-Marcos MA, et al. Relationship between the presence of insomnia and walking physical activity and diet quality: a cross-sectional study in a sample of Spanish adults. Med Clin 2019; 152: 339&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30220466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>