<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31156747</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Low-Volume Resistance Training on Muscle Strength and Functionality of People with Parkinson's Disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>567</StartPage><EndPage>580</EndPage><MedlinePgn>567-580</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Parkinson's disease (PD) is a progressive, neurodegenerative disorder of the central nervous system that affects the elderly and results in a decrease of functional capacity, motor control, and muscle strength. Resistance training (RT) has been shown to be a non-drug alternative in both elderly and parkinsonian patients in increasing functional capacity and muscle strength. The present study aimed to verify the effects of low-volume RT in people with PD in relation to muscular strength, body composition, anthropometry and functional capacity. Fifteen elderly patients with idiopathic PD were divided into two groups: 7 in the resistance-training group (RTG): RT twice a week for 12 weeks, and 8 in the control group (CG): No exercise. Before the training period, the subjects performed maximum strength (1-RM), body composition (Bioimpedance), anthropometry, and functional capacity (GDLAM protocol) tests. The endpoints were analyzed by the Generalized Estimates (GEE) with post hoc Bonferroni, being adopted for the analyses &#x3b1; &lt; 0.05. The results showed that the RTG had muscle strength gains: Bench Press 113.33%, Lat Pull Down 71.83% and Leg press 45&#xba; 94.48%, (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001), functional capacity (IG: -10.47%), and lean mass: 11.98%, (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001), while the GC presented significant changes before and after functional capacity only (GI: -1.61%) (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001). In addition, the RTG obtained reductions in the percentage of body fat (-2.30%) and in the waist-hip ratio (-2.22) without changes indicated in the CG. RT was efficient in improving muscle strength, functional capacity, body composition and anthropometric health indicators in individuals with PD.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbalho</LastName><ForeName>Matheus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and Dance, Federal University of Goi&#xe1;s, Goi&#xe2;nia, GO, BR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monteiro</LastName><ForeName>Elren P</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosciences and Rehabilitation Laboratory, Federal University of Health Sciences of Porto Alegre, Porto Alegre, RS, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and Dance, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, BR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Rochelle R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and Dance, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, BR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raiol</LastName><ForeName>Rodolfo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biological and Health Sciences Center, University Center of State of Par&#xe1;, Bel&#xe9;m, PA, BR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elderly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">volume training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6533097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/IJTI8994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrahin O, Rodrigues RP, Nascimento VC, Silva-Grigoletto ME, Sousa EC, Mar&#xe7;al A. Single- and multiple-set resistance training improves skeletal and respiratory muscle strength in elderly women. Clin Interv Aging. 2014;9:1775&#x2013;1782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4205116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25342896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(7):1510&#x2013;1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19516148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila JJ, Gutierres JA, Sheehy ME, Lofgren IE, Delmonico MJ. Effect of moderate intensity resistance training during weight loss on body composition and physical performance in overweight older adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(9):517&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20169360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballinger GA. Using generalized estimating equations for longitudinal data analysis. Organ Res Methods. 2004;7(2):127&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho MSM, Gentil P, Izquierdo M, Fisher J, Steele J, Raiol RA. There are no no-responders to low or high resistance training volumes among older women. Exp Gerontol. 2017;99:18&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28918362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brienesse LA, Emerson MN. Effects of resistance training for people with parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2013;14(4):236&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23318666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannon J, Marino FE. Early-phase neuromuscular adaptations to high- and low-volume resistance training in untrained young and older women. J Sports Sci. 2010;28(14):1505&#x2013;1514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21058165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro KV, Alves CH, Sauaia BA, et al. Effects of low intensity resistance training on the risk of falls and functional autonomy in the elderly. JEPonline. 2016;19(1):33&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cottell KE, Dorfman LR, Straight CR, Delmonico MJ, Lofgren IE. The effects of diet education plus light resistance training on coronary heart disease risk factors in community-dwelling older adults. J Nutr Heal Aging. 2011;15(9):762&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croft JB, Keenan NL, Sheridan DP, Wheeler FC, Speers MA. Waist-to-hip ratio in a biracial population: Measurement, implications, and cautions for using guidelines to define high risk for cardiovascular disease. J Am Diet Assoc. 1995;95(1):60&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7798582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falvo MJ, Schilling BK, Earhart GM. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and resistive exercise : Rationale, review, and recommendations. Mov Disord. 2008;23(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17894327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. High- and low-load resistance training: interpretation and practical application of current research findings. Sports Med. 2017;47(3):393&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27480764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Steele J, Gentil P, Giessing J, Westcott WL. A minimal dose approach to resistance training for the older adult; the prophylactic for aging. Exp Gerontol. 2017;99:80&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28962853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank P, Andersson E, Pont&#xe9;n M, Ekblom B, Ekblom M, Sahlin K. Strength training improves muscle aerobic capacity and glucose tolerance in elderly. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2016;26(7):764&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26271931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frazzitta G, Ferrazzoli D, Maestri R, et al. Differences in muscle strength in parkinsonian patients affected on the right and left side. PLoS One. 2015;10(3):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4373899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25806509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Bottaro M. Effects of training attendance on muscle strength of young men after 11 weeks of resistance training. Asian J Sports Med. 2013;4(2):101&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Ferreira-Junior JB, Bemben MG, Ferreira D, Bottaro M. The effects of resistance training on lower and upper body strength gains in young women. Int J Kines Sports Sci. 2015;3(3):18&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Buckley TA, Pitsikoulis C, Barthelemy EJ. Gait &amp; posture progressive resistance training improves gait initiation in individuals with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Gait Posture. 2012;35(4):669&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22266107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch MA, Farley BG. Exercise and neuroplasticity in persons living with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2009;45(2):215&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19532109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes AJ, Daniel SE, Kilford L, Lees AJ. Accuracy of clinical diagnosis of idiopathic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease : A clinico-pathological study of 100 cases. J Neurol Neurosurg, Psychiatry. 1992;55(3):181&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1014720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1564476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inkster LM, Eng JJ, Macintyre DL, Jon A. Leg muscle strength is reduced in PD and relates to the ability to rise from a chair. Mov Disord. 2012;18(2):157&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3471985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Iba&#xf1;ez J, Hakkinen K, Kraemer WJ, Larri&#xf3;n JL, Gorostiaga EM. Once weekly combined resistance and cardiovascular training in healthy older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(3):435&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15076785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakinuma S, Nogaki H, Pramanik B, Morimatsu M. Muscle weakness in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease : Isokinetic study of the limbs. Eur Neurol. 1998;39(4):218&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9635472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leahy S, Leahy S, Neill CO, Jakeman P. A comparison of dual energy X-ray absorptiometry and bioelectrical impedance analysis to measure total and segmental body composition in healthy young adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(2):589&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21614505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang KY, Zeger SL. Longitudinal data analysis using generalized linear models. Biometrika. 1986;73(1):13&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W, Lee L, Chen C, et al. Optimal cut-off values for obesity: using simple anthropometric indices to predict cardiovascular risk factors in Taiwan. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2002;26(9):1232&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12187401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Wei L, Zhang J. Review of guidelines and literature for handling missing data in longitudinal clinical trials with a case study. Pharm Stat. 2006;5(1):7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17080924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou J, Benice T, Kearns G, Sexton G, Nutt J. Levodopa normalizes exercise related cortico-motoneuron excitability abnormalities in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Clin Neurophysiol. 2013;114(5):930&#x2013;937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12738440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsden CD. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neurol Neurosurg, Psychiatry. 1994;57(6):672&#x2013;681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1072968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7755681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcbride JM, Blaak JB, Triplett-mcbride T. Effect of resistance exercise volume and complexity on EMG, strength, and regional body composition. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;90(5&#x2013;6):626&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12923645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro EP, Wild LB, Martinez FG, Pagnussat AS, Peyr&#xe9;-Tartaruga L. Biomechanical aspects of locomotion people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: Review study. Rev Bras Ci&#xea;nc Esporte. 2017;39(4):450&#x2013;457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris ME. Movement disorders in people with Parkinson disease: A model for physical therapy. Phys Ther. 2000;80(6):578&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10842411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Botton CE, Wilhelm EN, et al. Time course of low- and high-volume strength training on neuromuscular adaptations and muscle quality in older women. Age (Dordr) 2014;36(2):881&#x2013;892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4039257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24414336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rikli RE, Jones CJ. Development and validation of criterion-referenced clinically relevant fitness standards for maintaining physical independence in later years. Gerontologist. 2013;53(2):255&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22613940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Sui X, Lobelo F, et al. Association between muscular strength and mortality in men: Prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2008;337:a439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2453303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scandalis TA, Bosak A, Berliner J, Helman LL, Wells MR. Resistance training and gait function in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2001;80(1):38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11138953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schenkman ML, Clark K, Xie T, Kuchibhatla M, Shinberg M, Ray L. Spinal movement and performance of a standing reach task in participants with and without Parkinson disease. Phys Ther. 2001;81(8):1400&#x2013;1411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schilling BK, Pfeiffer RF, Ledoux MS, Karlage RE, Bloomer RJ, Falvo MJ. Effects of moderate-volume, high-load lower-body resistance training on strength and function in persons with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A pilot study. Parkinsons Dis. 2010;16:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20976096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethi KD. Clinical aspects of Parkinson disease. Mov Disord. 2002;15(4):457&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12151843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shulman LM, Katzel LI, Ivey F, et al. Randomized clinical trial of 3 types of physical exercise for patients with Parkinson disease. JAMA Neurol. 2015;70(2):183&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4574905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23128427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulzer D, Surmeier DJ. Neuronal vulnerability, pathogenesis and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2014;28(1):41&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22791686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suresh KP. An overview of randomization techniques: An unbiased assessment of outcome in clinical research. J Hum Reprod Sci. 2011;4(1):8&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3136079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21772732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toole T, Hirsch MA, Forkink A. The effects of a balance and strength training program on equilibrium in Parkinsonism: A preliminary study. NeuroRehabilitation. 2000;14(3):165&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11455079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trost S, Owen N, Brown WJ, et al. Correlates of adults&#x2019; participation in physical activity: Review and update. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;34(12):1996&#x2013;2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12471307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams TD, Tolusso DV, Fedewa MV, Esco MR. Comparison of periodized and non-periodized resistance training on maximal strength: A meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(10):2083&#x2013;2100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28497285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Obesity: Preventing and managing the global epidemic. 2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11234459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni M, Signorile JF. High-speed resistance training modifies load-velocity and load-power relationships in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(10):2866&#x2013;2875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27893480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerhan JR, Moore SC, Jacobs EJ, Kitahara CM, Rosenberg PS, Adami HO, et al. A pooled analysis of waist circumference and mortality in adults. Mayo Clin Proc. 2014;89(3):335&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4104704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24582192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Pacelli F, Bargossi AM, Marcolin G, Guzzinati S, Neri M, et al. Effects of three distinct protocols of fitness training on body composition, strength and blood lactate. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2010;50(1):43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20308971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>