<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37095566</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-activation effects of accommodating resistance and different rest intervals on vertical jump performance in strength trained males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>65</StartPage><MedlinePgn>65</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">65</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-023-00670-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Post-activation potentiation performance (PAPE) is a physiological phenomenon that has been studied numerously but the researchers are still seeking for the optimal application methods. The accommodating resistance was found to be an effective training method to acutely enhance subsequent explosive performance. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the effects of performing a trap bar deadlift with accommodating resistance on squat jump (SJ) performance with different rest intervals (90, 120, 150s).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study had a cross-over design and fifteen strength-trained males (age 22.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.1 years; body height 182&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.5&#xa0;cm; body mass: 80.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;9.8&#xa0;kg; body fat 15.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;7.0%; BMI 24.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.8; lean body mass 67.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;8.8&#xa0;kg) participated in one familiarization, three experimental and three control sessions within three weeks. The conditioning activity (CA) used in the study was a single set of 3 repetitions of a trap bar deadlift at 80% 1RM with approximately 15% 1RM of an elastic band. The SJ measurements were performed at the baseline and post-CA after 90 or 120 or 150s.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The 90s experimental protocol significantly improved (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05, effect size 0.34) acute SJ performance whereas 120 and 150&#xa0;s experimental protocols did not significantly improve performance. The following tendency was observed - the longer the rest interval, the smaller the potentiation effect; p value for 90s (0.046), 120s (0.166), 150s (0.745).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A trap bar deadlift with accommodating resistance and 90s rest interval can be used to acutely enhance jump performance. A 90s rest interval was found to be optimal to enhance subsequent SJ performance, but the potential rest interval extension to 120s could also be taken by strength and conditioning coaches as the PAPE effect is highly individual. However, exceeding the rest interval to more than 120s may not be effective in optimising the PAPE effect.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masel</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Biochemistry, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, University of Physical Education in Krak&#xf3;w, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland. sebastian.masel@doctoral.awf.krakow.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maciejczyk</LastName><ForeName>Marcin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Biochemistry, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, University of Physical Education in Krak&#xf3;w, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-activation performance enhancement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trap bar deadlift</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Variable resistance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10123974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-023-00670-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-023-00670-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Babault N. Post-activation potentiation versus post-activation performance enhancement in humans: historical perspective, underlying mechanisms, and current issues. Front Physiol. 2019 doi: 10.3389/fphys.2019.01359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.01359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31736781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Duncan NM, Marin PJ, Brown LE, Loenneke JP, Wilson SM, et al. Meta-analysis of postactivation potentiation and power: effects of conditioning activity, volume, gender, rest periods, and training status. J Strength Cond Res. 2013 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825c2bdb.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825c2bdb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22580978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobbs WC, Tolusso DV, Fedewa MV, Esco MR. Effect of postactivation potentiation on explosive vertical jump: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2019 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Bishop D. Factors modulating post-activation potentiation and its effect on performance of subsequent explosive activities. Sports Med. 2009 doi: 10.2165/00007256-200939020-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200939020-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19203135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, Haff GG. Factors modulating post-activation potentiation of jump, sprint, throw, and upper-body ballistic performances: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016 doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0415-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0415-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26508319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio F, Chapman M, Larumbe-Zabala E, Massey B, Neil A, Triplett TN. Effects of three different conditioning activity volumes on the optimal recovery time for potentiation in college athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2015 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25719916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, de Villarreal ES, Haff GG. The temporal profile of postactivation potentiation is related to strength level. J Strength Cond Res. 2014 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182a73ea3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182a73ea3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23965945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Fern&#xe1;ndez F, Gay A, Ruiz-Navarro J, Morales-Ortiz E, L&#xf3;pez-Contreras G, Arellano R. Swimming performance after an eccentric Post-Activation Training Protocol. Apunts Edu F&#xed;s Deportes. 202010.5672/apunts.2014-0983.es.(2020/2).140.07.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Wilk M, Golas A, Lockie RG, Maszczyk A, Zajac A. Does eccentric-only and concentric-only activation increase power output? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020 doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31425385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Wilk M, Lockie RG, Bogdanis GC. Postactivation Performance Enhancement of Concentric Bench Press throw after eccentric-only Conditioning Exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2022 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rixon KP, Lamont HS, Bemben MG. Influence of type of muscle contraction, gender, and lifting experience on Postactivation Potentiation performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2007 doi: 10.1519/R-18855.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-18855.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arabatzi F, Patikas D, Zafeiridis A, Giavroudis K, Kannas T, Gourgoulis V, Kotzamanidis CM. The Post-Activation Potentiation Effect on Squat Jump performance: age and sex effect. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2014 doi: 10.1123/pes.2013-0052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.2013-0052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24225048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis GC, Tsoukos A, Veligekas P, Tsolakis C, Terzis G. Effects of muscle action type with Equal Impulse of Conditioning Activity on Postactivation Potentiation. J Strength Cond Res. 2014 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24584048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spieszny M, Trybulski R, Biel P, Zaj&#x105;c A, Krzysztofik M. Post-isometric back squat performance enhancement of Squat and Countermovement Jump. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022 doi: 10.3390/ijerph191912720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191912720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9565011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36232019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrich G, Parstorfer M. Effects of Plyometric Versus Concentric and Eccentric Conditioning Contractions on Upper-Body Postactivation Potentiation. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017 doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2016-0278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2016-0278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27736266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Sato K, DeWeese BH, Ebben WP, Stone MH. Potentiation Effects of Half-Squats Performed in a ballistic or nonballistic manner. J Strength Cond Res. 2016 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26544089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca-Fern&#xe1;ndez F, L&#xf3;pez-Contreras G, Mour&#xe3;o L, de Jesus K, de Jesus K, Zacca R, Vilas-Boas JP, Fernandes RJ, Arellano R. Eccentric flywheel post-activation potentiation influences swimming start performance kinetics. J Sports Sci. 2019 doi: 10.1080/02640414.2018.1505183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2018.1505183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30070620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S, Bautista I, Rivera F. Post-activation performance enhancement (PAPE) after a single-bout of high-intensity flywheel resistance training. Biology of Sport. 2020 doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2020.96318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.96318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. Increases in jump squat peak external power output when combined with accommodating resistance box squats during contrasting resistance complex training with short rest periods. J Aust Strength Cond. 2008;6:10&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. Increases in bench throw power output when combined with heavier bench press plus accommodating chains resistance during complex training. J Aust Strength Cond. 2009;16:10&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyland TP, Van Dorin JD, Reyes GFC. Postactivation potentation effects from accommodating resistance combined with heavy back squats on short sprint performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2015 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25968229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strokosch A, Louit L, Seitz L, Clarke R, Hughes JD. Impact of accommodating resistance in potentiating horizontal-jump performance in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol. 2018 doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29688093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mina MA, Blazevich AJ, Tsatalas T, Giakas G, Seitz LB, Kay AD. Variable, but not free-weight, resistance back squat exercise potentiates jump performance following a comprehensive task&#x2010;specific warm&#x2010;up. Scand J Med Sci Spor. 2019 doi: 10.1111/sms.13341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30468526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#x10d;m&#xe1;r M, Kr&#x10d;m&#xe1;rov&#xe1; B, Baka&#x13e;&#xe1;r I, &#x160;imonek J. Acute Performance Enhancement following Squats Combined with Elastic bands on short Sprint and Vertical Jump Height in female athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2020 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33337702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popp Marin D, Anthony Astorino T, Silva Serafim AI, Bertoldo Urtado C, Prestes J, Tubagi Polito LF, Otton R. Comparison between traditional resistance exercise and variable resistance with elastic bands in acute vertical jump performance. Hum Mov. 2021 doi: 10.5114/hm.2021.103287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/hm.2021.103287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybulski R, Makar P, Alexe DI, Stanciu S, Piwowar R, Wilk M, Krzysztofik M. Post-Activation Performance Enhancement: Save Time with active Intra-Complex Recovery Intervals. Front Physiol. 2022 doi: 10.3389/fphys.2022.840722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.840722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9298750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, Haff GG. Application of methods of inducing postactivation potentiation during the preparation of rugby players. Strength Cond J. 2015 doi: 10.1519/ssc.0000000000000116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijem RM, Coburn JW, Brown LE, Lynn SK, Ciccone AB. Electromyographic and force plate analysis of the deadlift performed with and without chains. J Strength Cond Res. 2016 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26840441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinton PA, Stewart A, Agouris I, Keogh JW, Lloyd R. A biomechanical analysis of straight and hexagonal barbell deadlifts using submaximal loads. J Strength Cond Res. 2011 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e73f87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e73f87</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21659894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leyva WD, Archer D, Munger CN, Galpin AJ, Coburn JW, Brown LE. Comparison of hex bar deadlift vs. back squat postactivation potentiation on vertical jump.2015. Conference: American College of Sports Medicine &#x2013; Southwest Regional Meeting. Available at: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/292445693_Comparison_of_hex_bar_deadlift_vs_back_squat_postactivation_potentiation_on_vertical_jump</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chmiel J, Carillo J, Cerone D, Phillips J, Swensen T, Kaye M, Post Activation Potentiation of Back Squat and Trap Bar Deadlift on Acute Sprint Performance. 2016. Int J Exe Sci.: Conference Proceedings (Vol.&#xa0;9, No. 4, p.&#xa0;31). Available at: https://digitalcommons.wku.edu/ijesab/vol9/iss4/31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott DJ, Ditroilo M, Marshall PA. Complex training: the effect of exercise selection and training status on postactivation potentiation in rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res. 2017 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28930932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott DJ, Ditroilo M, Marshall P. Effect of accommodating resistance on the postactivation potentiation response in rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res. 2018 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29401203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masel S, Maciejczyk M. Effects of Post-Activation Performance Enhancement on Jump Performance in Elite Volleyball Players. Appl Sci. 2022 doi: 10.3390/app12189054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12189054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11178877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38877057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustino V, Messina G, Patti A, Padua E, Zangla D, Drid P, Battaglia G, Palma A, Bianco A. Effects of a postural Exercise Program on Vertical Jump Height in Young Female Volleyball players with knee Valgus. Int J Enviton Res Public Health. 2022 doi: 10.3390/ijerph19073953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19073953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8997520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35409635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glatthorn JF, Gouge S, Nussbaumer S, Stauffacher S, Impellizzeri FM, Maffiuletti NA. Validity and reliability of Optojump Photoelectric cells for estimating Vertical Jump Height. J Strength Cond Res. 2011 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ccb18d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ccb18d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Routledge Academic: New York, NY, USA, 1988. ISBN 9780203771587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace B, Bergstrom HC. Muscular bases and mechanisms of variable resistance training efficacy. Int J Sports Sci Coa. 2018 doi: 10.1177/1747954118810240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747954118810240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>