<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">19450935</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-2777</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>73</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical hypotheses</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Hypotheses</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nutrigenomic targeting of carbohydrate craving behavior: can we manage obesity and aberrant craving behaviors with neurochemical pathway manipulation by Immunological Compatible Substances (nutrients) using a Genetic Positioning System (GPS) Map?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>427</StartPage><EndPage>434</EndPage><MedlinePgn>427-34</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.mehy.2009.02.037</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Genetic mediated physiological processes that rely on both pharmacological and nutritional principles hold great promise for the successful therapeutic targeting of reduced carbohydrate craving, body-friendly fat loss, healthy body recomposition, and overall wellness. By integrating an assembly of scientific knowledge on inheritable characteristics and environmental mediators of gene expression, we review the relationship of genes, hormones, neurotransmitters, and nutrients as they correct unwanted weight gain coupled with unhappiness. In contrast to a simple one-locus, one-mechanism focus on pharmaceuticals alone, we hypothesize that the use of nutrigenomic treatment targeting multi-physiological neurological, immunological, and metabolic pathways will enable clinicians to intercede in the process of lipogenesis by promoting lipolysis while attenuating aberrant glucose cravings. In turn, this approach will enhance wellness in a safe and predictable manner through the use of a Genetic Positioning System (GPS) Map. The GPS Map, while presently incomplete, ultimately will serve not only as a blueprint for personalized medicine in the treatment of obesity, but also for the development of strategies for reducing many harmful addictive behaviors and promoting optimal health by using substances compatible with the body's immune system.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Downs</LastName><ForeName>B William</ForeName><Initials>BW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrigenomics and Personalized Medicine, LifeGen, Inc., La Jolla, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Amanda L C</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Thomas J H</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waite</LastName><ForeName>Roger L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braverman</LastName><ForeName>Eric R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerner</LastName><ForeName>Mallory</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braverman</LastName><ForeName>Dasha</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rhoades</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prihoda</LastName><ForeName>Thomas J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palomo</LastName><ForeName>Tomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oscar-Berman</LastName><ForeName>Marlene</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reinking</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blum</LastName><ForeName>Seth H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DiNubile</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>H H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blum</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K05 AA000219</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AA007112</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01-AA07112</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K05-AA00219</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Hypotheses</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505668</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0306-9877</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004040">Dietary Carbohydrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002874" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromosome Mapping</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004040" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Carbohydrates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005247" MajorTopicYN="Y">Feeding Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001068" MajorTopicYN="N">Feeding and Eating Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018390" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Targeting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015316" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest</b>. Kenneth Blum, B. William Downs, Roger L. Waite own stock in LifeGen, Inc. the exclusive distributors of patents related to Synaptamine complex&#x2122; and other variants. There are no other conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2009</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19450935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS469598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3758908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2009.02.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0306-9877(09)00225-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen AL, Chen TJ, Braverman ER, Blum SH, Cassel K, et al. Activation instead of blocking mesolimbic dopaminergic reward circuitry is a preferred modality in the long term treatment of reward deficiency syndrome (RDS): a commentary. Theor Biol Med Model. 2008;5:24. [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19014506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen TJH, Downs BW, Meshkin B, Blum SH, Martinez-Pons M, et al. Synaptamine (Sg8839): an amino-acid enkephalinase inhibition nutraceutical improves recovery of alcoholics, a subtype of Reward Deficiency Syndrome (RDS) Trends Appl Sci Res. 2007;2:132&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CY, Mao X, Wei L. Genes and (common) pathways underlying drug addiction. PLoS Comput Biol. 2008;4(1):e2. [Epub 2007 Nov 20]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2174978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18179280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boundy VA, Pacheco MA, Guan W, Molinoff PB. Agonists and antagonists differentially regulate the high affinity state of the D2L receptor in human embryonic kidney 293 cells. Mol Pharmacol. 1995;48:956&#x2013;964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7476927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boundy VA, Lu L, Molinoff PB. Differential coupling of rat D2 dopamine receptor isoforms expressed in Spodoptera frugiperda insect cells. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1996;276:784&#x2013;794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8632351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble EP, Blum K, Ritchie T, Montgomery A, Sheridan PJ. Allelic association of the D2 dopamine receptor gene with receptor-binding characteristics in alcoholism. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1991;48:648&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2069496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferr&#xe9; S, Quiroz C, Woods AS, Cunha R, Popoli P, Ciruela F, et al. An update on adenosine A2A&#x2013;dopamine D2 receptor interactions: implications for the function of G protein-coupled receptors. Curr Pharm Des. 2008;14:1468&#x2013;1474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2424285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18537670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsch P, Reuter M, Mier D, Lonsdorf T, Stark R, Gallhofer B, et al. Imaging gene-substance interactions: the effect of the DRD2 Taql A polymorphism and the dopamine agonist bromocriptine on the brain activation during the anticipation of reward. Neurosci Lett. 2006;405:196&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16901644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawford BR, Young RM, Rowell JA, Qualichefski J, Fletcher BH, Syndulko K, et al. Bromocriptine in the treatment of alcoholics with the D2 dopamine receptor Al allele. Nat Med. 1995;1:337&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7585063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen TJ, Meshkin B, Waite RL, Downs BW, Blum SH, et al. Manipulation of catechol-O-methyl-transferase (COMT) activity to influence the attenuation of substance seeking behavior, a subtype of Reward Deficiency Syndrome (RDS), is dependent upon gene polymorphisms: a hypothesis. Med Hypotheses. 2007;69:1054&#x2013;1060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17467918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen AL, Chen TJ, Rhoades P, Prihoda TJ, Downs BW, et al. LG839: anti-obesity effects and polymorphic gene correlates of reward deficiency syndrome. Adv Ther. 2008;25:894&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18781289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen ALC, Chen TLC, Rhoades P, Prihoda P, Downs BW, et al. Dopamine D2 Receptor Taq A1 allele predicts treatment compliance of LG839 in a subset analysis of a pilot study in The Netherlands. Gene Therapy Mol Biol. 2008;12:129&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen TJH, Williams L, Chen ALC, Downs BW, Waite RL, et al. A short term pilot open label study to evaluate efficacy and safety of LG839, a customized DNA directed nutraceutical in obesity: exploring nutrigenomics. Gene Ther Mol Biol. 2008:112. Chen.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen TJH, Meshkin B, Downs BW, Gordon CA, Blum SH, et al. Reward Deficiency Syndrome in obesity: a preliminary cross-sectional trial with a genotrim variant. Adv Ther. 2006;23:1040&#x2013;1051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17276971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TJ, Blum K, Payte JT, Schoolfield J, Hopper D, Stanford M. Narcotic antagonists in drug dependence: pilot study showing enhancement of compliance with SYN-10, amino-acid precursors and enkephalinase inhibition therapy. Med Hypotheses. 2004;63:538&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15288384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanos PK, Volkow ND, Freimuth P, Umegaki H, Ikari H, Roth G, et al. Overexpression of dopamine D2 receptors reduces alcohol self-administration. J Neurochem. 2001;78:1094&#x2013;1103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11553683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meshkin B, Chen TJH, Chen ALC, Prihoda TJH, Morrisette H, Braverman ER, et al. Health economics of nutrigenomics in weight management. Gene Ther Mol Biol. 2008;12:25&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comings DE, Blum K. Reward deficiency syndrome: genetic aspects of behavioral disorders. Prog Brain Res. 2000;126:325&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11105655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ALC, Blum K, Chen TJH, Rhinking J, Waite RL, Downs BW, et al. The impact of biomics technology and DNA directed anti-obesity targeting of the brain reward circuitry. Gene Therapy Mol Biol. 2008;12:45&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowirrat A, Oscar-Berman M. Relationship between dopaminergic neurotransmission, alcoholism, and Reward Deficiency Syndrome. Am J Med Genet B Neuropsychiatr Genet. 2005;132B(1):29&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15457501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein LH, Temple JL, Neaderhiser BJ, Salis RJ, Erbe RW. Food reinforcement, the dopamine D2 receptor genotype, and energy intake in obese and nonobese humans. Behav Neurosci. 2007;121:877&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2213752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17907820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maes HH, Neale Mc, Eaves IJ. Genetic and environmental factors in relative body weight and human adiposity. Behav Gen. 1997;27:325&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9519560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Braverman ER, Holder JM, Lubar JF, Monastra VJ, Miller D, et al. Reward deficiency syndrome: a biogenetic model for the diagnosis and treatment of impulsive, addictive, and compulsive behaviors. J Psychoactive Drugs. 2000;32(Suppl.):1&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11280926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TJH, Blum K, Kaats G, Braverman E, Pullin D, Downs BW, et al. Reviewing the role of putative candidate genes in &#x201c;Neurobesigenics&#x201d; a clinical subtype of Reward Deficiency Syndrome (RDS) Gene Ther Mol Biol. 2007;11:61&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Cull JG, Chen TJH, Garcia-Swan S, Holder JM, Wood RC, et al. Clinical evidence for effectiveness of PhenCal in maintaining weight loss in an open-label, controlled, 2 year study. Curr Ther Res. 1997;58:745&#x2013;763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Meshkin B, Downs BW. DNA based customized nutraceutical &#x201c;&#x201c;gene therapy&#x201d; utilizing a genoscore: a hypothesized paradigm shift of a novel approach to the diagnosis, stratification, prognosis and treatment of inflammatory processes in the human. Med Hypotheses. 2006;66:1008&#x2013;1018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16403602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corth&#xe9;sy-Theulaz I, den Dunnen JT, Ferr&#xe9; P, Geurts JM, M&#xfc;ller M, Van Belzen N. Nutrigenomics: the impact of biomics technology on nutrition research. Ann Nutr Metab. 2005;49:355&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16179781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crombag HS, Bossert JM, Koya E, Shaham Y. Context-induced relapse to drug seeking: a review. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci. 2008;36:3233&#x2013;3243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2607323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18640922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice AM, Rayco-Solon P, Moore SE. Insights from the developing world: thrifty genotypes and thrifty phenotypes. Proc Nutr Soc. 2005;64:153&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15960860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum K, Chen TJH, Blum SH, Downs BW, Braverman ER, Mengucci JF, et al. Nutrigenomics and pharmacogenomics: a scientific wonderland. Biol Social Life (Social Sci Inform) 2006;45:35&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin R. The role of law in the control of obesity in England: looking at the contribution of law to a healthy food culture. Aust New Zealand Health Policy. 2008;5:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18854038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownell KD, Warner KE. The perils of ignoring history: m big tobacco played dirty and millions died: how similar is big Food? The Milbank Quarterly. 2009;87:259&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2879177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19298423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kathiresan S, Willer CJ, Peloso GM, Demissie S, Musunuru K, Schadt EE, et al. Common variants at 30 loci contribute to polygenic dyslipidemia. Nat Genet. 2009;41(1):56&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19060906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oben JE, Ngondi JL, Blum K. Inhibition of Irvingia gabonensis seed extract (OB131) on adipogenesis as mediated via down regulation of the PPARgamma and Leptin genes and up-regulation of the adiponectin gene. Lipids Health Dis. 2008;7:4450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2588592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19014517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkow ND, Wang GJ, Telang F, Fowler JS, Thanos PK, Logan J, et al. Low dopamine striatal D2 receptors are associated with prefrontal metabolism in obese subjects: possible contributing factors. Neuroimage. 2008;42:1537&#x2013;1543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2659013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18598772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnard ND, Noble EP, Ritchie T, Cohen J, Jenkins DJ, Turner-McGrievy G, et al. D2 dopamine receptor Taq1A polymorphism, body weight, and dietary intake in type 2 diabetes. Nutrition. 2009;25:58&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18834717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray MS, Hagberg JM, P&#xe9;russe L, Rankinen T, Roth SM, Wolfarth B, et al. The human gene map for performance and health-related fitness phenotypes: the 2006&#x2013;2007 update. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:35&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19123262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stice E, Spoor S, Bohan C, Small DM. Relation between Obesity and blunted striatal response to food is moderated by Taq A1 allele. Science. 2008;322:449&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2681095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18927395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geiger BM, Behr GG, Frank LE, Caldera-Siu AD, Beinfeld MC, Kokkotou EG, et al. Evidence for defective mesolimbic dopamine exocytosis in obesity-prone rats. FASEB J. 2008;22(8):2740&#x2013;2746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18477764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comings DE, Gade R, MacMurray JP, Muhleman D, Peters WR. Genetic variants of the human obesity (OB) gene: association with psychiatric symptoms and body mass index in young women, and interaction with the dopamine D2 receptor (DRD2) gene. Mol Psychiatry. 1996;1:325&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9118359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponce G, Jimenez-Arriero MA, Rubio G, Hoenicka J, Ampuero I, Ramos JA, et al. The A1 allele of the DRD2 gene (TaqI A polymorphisms) is associated with antisocial personality in a sample of alcohol-dependent patients. Eur Psychiatry. 2003;18:356&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14643564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis CA, Levitan RD, Reid C, Carter JC, Kaplan AS, Patte AS, et al. Dopamine for &#x201c;Wanting&#x201d; and Opioids for &#x201c;Liking&#x201d;: A comparison of Obese adults with and without Binge &#x201c;Eating&#x201d;. Obesity. 2009 in press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19282821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rada P, Avena NM, Hoebel BG. Daily bingeing on sugar repeatedly releases dopamine in the accumbens. Neuroscience. 2005;134:737&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15987666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang GO, Gaysinskaya V, Karatayev O, Leibowitz SF. Maternal high-fat diet and fetal programming: increased proliferation of Hypothalmic pepetide-producing neurons that increase risk for overeating and obesity. J Neurosci. 2008;28:12107&#x2013;12119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2752048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19005075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blass EM. Biological and Environmental determinants of childhood obesity. Nutr Clin Care. 2003;6:13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12841426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgkins CC, CaHill KS, Seraphine AE, Frost-Pineda K, Gold MS. Adolescent drug addiction treatment and weight gain. J Addict Dis. 2004:55&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15256344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm JW, Osincup D, Wells B, Manaois M, Fyall A, Buse C, et al. Environmental enrichment attenuates cue-induced reinforcement of sucrose seeking in rats. Behav Pharmacol. 2008;19:777&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19020412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenoir M, Serre F, Cantin L, Ahmed SH. Intense sweetness surpasses cocaine reward. Plos One. 2007;2(8):e698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1931610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17668074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gearhardt AN, Corbin WR, Brownell KD. Preliminary validation of the Yale Food Addiction Scale. Appetite. 2009;52:439&#x2013;446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19121351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>