<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36374564</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reporting Attendance and Resistance Exercise Compliance in Men with Localized Prostate Cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>354</StartPage><EndPage>364</EndPage><MedlinePgn>354-364</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003069</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">Resistance exercise is a well-established intervention to counteract musculoskeletal and metabolic toxicities from prostate cancer treatment. In this study, we reported resistance exercise attendance and compliance, and examined if these variables can influence changes in outcomes of interest in men with localized or locally advanced prostate cancer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 83 prostate cancer patients (age, 68.2 &#xb1; 7.0 yr; body mass index, 27.7 &#xb1; 3.8 kg&#xb7;m -2 ) who had undergone 6 months of resistance-based exercise and had data available on exercise training from logbook records were examined. Attendance outcomes such as missed sessions, interruptions and permanent discontinuation, and metrics such as dosage completed (sessions &#xd7; number of exercises &#xd7; sets &#xd7; repetitions &#xd7; external load), compliance, tolerance, reductions, and escalations were assessed. Outcomes assessed were body composition, physical function, and muscle strength.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Median resistance exercise attendance was 80.6%, with a median resistance exercise compliance of 88.5% (interquartile range [IQR], 61.1%-107.1%) per participant. A median of 11 (IQR, 1-26) and 0 (IQR, 0-2) sessions were escalated or reduced, respectively. Significant improvements were observed in whole-body lean mass, 400-m walk, repeated chair rise, leg press, and chest press strength after 6 months of intervention ( P &lt; 0.05) regardless of resistance exercise compliance ( Ptrend = 0.199-0.950). Participants with higher levels of resistance exercise compliance presented greater improvements in trunk fat mass ( Ptrend = 0.026) and appendicular lean mass ( Ptrend = 0.047).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">A higher resistance exercise compliance led to greater improvements in regional fat and lean mass, whereas physical function and muscle strength improvements were achieved with lower compliance. In addition, patients experienced a high number of dose escalations during the intervention. These findings are important to improve the reproducibility/precision of exercise medicine prescription.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopez</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taaffe</LastName><ForeName>Dennis R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton</LastName><ForeName>Robert U</ForeName><Initials>RU</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spry</LastName><ForeName>Nigel</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joseph</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Colin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buffart</LastName><ForeName>Laurien M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galv&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Daniel A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011471" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prostatic Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36374564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202303000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin . 2021;71(3):209&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Amico AV, Chen MH, Renshaw AA, Loffredo M, Kantoff PW. Androgen suppression and radiation vs radiation alone for prostate cancer: a randomized trial. JAMA . 2008;299(3):289&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunner C, Gulamhusein A, Rosario DJ. The modern role of androgen deprivation therapy in the management of localised and locally advanced prostate cancer. J Clin Urol . 2016;9(2 Suppl):24&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvao DA, Spry NA, Taaffe DR, et al. Changes in muscle, fat and bone mass after 36 weeks of maximal androgen blockade for prostate cancer. BJU Int . 2008;102(1):44&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvao DA, Taaffe DR, Spry N, Joseph D, Turner D, Newton RU. Reduced muscle strength and functional performance in men with prostate cancer undergoing androgen suppression: a comprehensive cross-sectional investigation. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2009;12(2):198&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o DA, Taaffe DR, Spry N, Joseph D, Newton RU. Cardiovascular and metabolic complications during androgen deprivation: exercise as a potential countermeasure. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2009;12(3):233&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MR, Saad F, Egerdie B, et al. Sarcopenia during androgen-deprivation therapy for prostate cancer. J Clin Oncol . 2012;30(26):3271&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenfield SA, Stampfer MJ, Giovannucci E, Chan JM. Physical activity and survival after prostate cancer diagnosis in the health professionals follow-up study. J Clin Oncol . 2011;29(6):726&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM, Wang Q, Neilson HK, Kopciuk KA, McGregor SE, Courneya KS. Physical activity and survival after prostate cancer. Eur Urol . 2016;70(4):576&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Newton RU, Taaffe DR, et al. Associations of fat and muscle mass with overall survival in men with prostate cancer: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2022;25(4):615&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal RJ, Reid RD, Courneya KS, et al. Resistance exercise in men receiving androgen deprivation therapy for prostate cancer. J Clin Oncol . 2003;21(9):1653&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal RJ, Reid RD, Courneya KS, et al. Randomized controlled trial of resistance or aerobic exercise in men receiving radiation therapy for prostate cancer. J Clin Oncol . 2009;27(3):344&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o DA, Taaffe DR, Spry N, Joseph D, Newton RU. Combined resistance and aerobic exercise program reverses muscle loss in men undergoing androgen suppression therapy for prostate cancer without bone metastases: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Oncol . 2010;28(2):340&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourke L, Gilbert S, Hooper R, et al. Lifestyle changes for improving disease-specific quality of life in sedentary men on long-term androgen-deprivation therapy for advanced prostate cancer: a randomised controlled trial. Eur Urol . 2014;65(5):865&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o DA, Spry N, Denham J, et al. A multicentre year-long randomised controlled trial of exercise training targeting physical functioning in men with prostate cancer previously treated with androgen suppression and radiation from TROG 03.04 RADAR. Eur Urol . 2014;65(5):856&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Spry N, et al. Can supervised exercise prevent treatment toxicity in patients with prostate cancer initiating androgen-deprivation therapy: a randomised controlled trial. BJU Int . 2015;115(2):256&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsen TS, Raastad T, Skovlund E, et al. Effects of strength training on body composition, physical functioning, and quality of life in prostate cancer patients during androgen deprivation therapy. Acta Oncol . 2015;54(10):1805&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Spry N, et al. Exercise mode specificity for preserving spine and hip bone mineral density in prostate cancer patients. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2019;51(4):607&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Spry N, et al. Immediate versus delayed exercise in men initiating androgen deprivation: effects on bone density and soft tissue composition. BJU Int . 2019;123(2):261&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigaran A, Zopf E, Gardner J, et al. The effect of exercise training on cardiometabolic health in men with prostate cancer receiving androgen deprivation therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2021;24(1):35&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Buffart LM, Galvao DA. What is the minimal dose for resistance exercise effectiveness in prostate cancer patients? Systematic review and meta-analysis on patient-reported outcomes. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2021;24(2):465&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Galvao DA. Resistance exercise dosage in men with prostate cancer: systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(3):459&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Newton RU, Taaffe DR, et al. Interventions for improving body composition in men with prostate cancer: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2022;54(5):728&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasso JP, Eves ND, Christensen JF, Koelwyn GJ, Scott J, Jones LW. A framework for prescription in exercise-oncology research. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle . 2015;6(2):115&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neil-Sztramko SE, Medysky ME, Campbell KL, Bland KA, Winters-Stone KM. Attention to the principles of exercise training in exercise studies on prostate cancer survivors: a systematic review. BMC Cancer . 2019;19(1):321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet Oncology. Exercise and cancer treatment: balancing patient needs. Lancet Oncol . 2018;19(6):715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyengar NM, Jones LW. Development of exercise as interception therapy for cancer: a review. JAMA Oncol . 2019;5(11):1620&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairman CM, Nilsen TS, Newton RU, et al. Reporting of resistance training dose, adherence, and tolerance in exercise oncology. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2020;52(2):315&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel DA, O&#x2019;Neil ME, Richards TB, Dowling NF, Weir HK. Prostate cancer incidence and survival, by stage and race/ethnicity&#x2014;United States, 2001&#x2013;2017. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep . 2020;69(41):1473&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Taaffe DR, Spry N, et al. Can exercise ameliorate treatment toxicity during the initial phase of testosterone deprivation in prostate cancer patients? Is this more effective than delayed rehabilitation? BMC Cancer . 2012;12:432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Spry N, et al. Timing of exercise for muscle strength and physical function in men initiating ADT for prostate cancer. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis . 2020;23(3):457&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen PL, Alibhai SM, Basaria S, et al. Adverse effects of androgen deprivation therapy and strategies to mitigate them. Eur Urol . 2015;67(5):825&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairman CM, Zourdos MC, Helms ER, Focht BC. A scientific rationale to improve resistance training prescription in exercise oncology. Sports Med . 2017;47(8):1457&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsen TS, Scott JM, Michalski M, et al. Novel methods for reporting of exercise dose and adherence: an exploratory analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2018;50(6):1134&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1982;14(5):377&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godin G, Shephard RJ. A simple method to assess exercise behavior in the community. Can J Appl Sport Sci . 1985;10(3):141&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galv&#xe3;o DA, Taaffe DR. Resistance exercise dosage in older adults: single- versus multiset effects on physical performance and body composition. J Am Geriatr Soc . 2005;53(12):2090&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Botton CE, Wilhelm EN, et al. Time course of low- and high-volume strength training on neuromuscular adaptations and muscle quality in older women. Age (Dordr) . 2014;36(2):881&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha PM, Nunes JP, Tomeleri CM, et al. Resistance training performed with single and multiple sets induces similar improvements in muscular strength, muscle mass, muscle quality, and IGF-1 in older women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res . 2020;34(4):1008&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Simonsick EM, Naydeck BL, et al. Association of long-distance corridor walk performance with mortality, cardiovascular disease, mobility limitation, and disability. JAMA . 2006;295(17):2018&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzatvar Y, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, S&#xe1;ez de Asteasu ML, et al. Physical function and all-cause mortality in older adults diagnosed with cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci . 2021;76(8):1447&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Courneya KS, Matthews C, et al. American College of Sports Medicine roundtable on exercise guidelines for cancer survivors. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2010;42(7):1409&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone KM, Wiskemann J, et al. Exercise guidelines for cancer survivors: consensus statement from international multidisciplinary roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2019;51(11):2375&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Resistance training effectiveness on body composition and body weight outcomes in individuals with overweight and obesity across the lifespan: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev . 2022;23(5):e13428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J. Physiological Aspects of Sport Training and Performance . Champaign (IL): Human Kinetics; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsen TS, Johansen SH, Thorsen L, Fairman CM, Wisl&#xf8;ff T, Raastad T. Does androgen deprivation for prostate cancer affect normal adaptation to resistance exercise? Int J Environ Res Public Health . 2022;19(7):3820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos E, Gillen J, Moore D, et al. High-intensity interval training or resistance training versus usual care in men with prostate cancer on active surveillance: a 3-arm feasibility randomized controlled trial. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2021;46(12):1535&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes SC, Newton RU, Spence RR, Galvao DA. The exercise and sports science Australia position statement: exercise medicine in cancer management. J Sci Med Sport . 2019;22(11):1175&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kenfield SA, Hart NH, et al. Intense exercise for survival among men with metastatic castrate-resistant prostate cancer (INTERVAL-GAP4): a multicentre, randomised, controlled phase III study protocol. BMJ Open . 2018;8(5):e022899.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>