<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17908338</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of protein source and resistance training on body composition and sex hormones.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Evidence suggests an inverse relationship between soy protein intake and serum concentrations of male sex hormones. Anecdotal evidence indicates that these alterations in serum sex hormones may attenuate changes in lean body mass following resistance training. However, little empirical data exists regarding the effects of soy and milk-based proteins on circulating androgens and exercise induced body composition changes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">For 12 weeks 20 subjects were supplemented with 50 g per day of one of four different protein sources (Soy concentrate; Soy isolate; Soy isolate and whey blend, and Whey blend only) in combination with a resistance-training program. Body composition, testosterone, estradiol and sex hormone binding globulin (SHBG) were measured at baseline and week 12.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Protein supplementation resulted in a significant increase in lean body mass independent of protein source (0.5 +/- 1.1 and 0.9 +/- 1.4 kg, p = 0.006, p = 0.007). No significant differences were observed between groups for total and free testosterone, SHBG, percentage body fat, BMI or body weight. The Testosterone/Estradiol ratio increased across all groups (+13.4, p = 0.005) and estradiol decreased (p = 0.002). Within group analysis showed significant increases in the Testosterone/Estradiol ratio in soy isolate + whey blend group (+16.3, p = 0.030). Estradiol was significantly lower in the whey blend group (-9.1 +/- 8.7 pg/ml, p = 0.033).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This investigation shows that 12 week supplementation with soy protein does not decrease serum testosterone or inhibit lean body mass changes in subjects engaged in a resistance exercise program.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalman</LastName><ForeName>Douglas</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Miami Research Associates, Nutrition/Endocrinology Division, Miami, Florida, USA. dkalman@miamiresearch.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feldman</LastName><ForeName>Samantha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinez</LastName><ForeName>Michele</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krieger</LastName><ForeName>Diane R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tallon</LastName><ForeName>Mark J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2007</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2007</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1997115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-4-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-4-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Protein requirements and supplementation in strength sports. Nutrition. 2004;20:689&#x2013;695. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15212752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H, Spangenburg EE, Booth FW. Control of the size of the human muscle mass. Annu Rev Physiol. 2004;66:799&#x2013;828. doi: 10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudichon C, Mahe S, Benamouzig R, Luengo C, Fouillet H, Dare S, Van Oycke M, Ferriere F, Rautureau J, Tome D. Net postprandial utilization of [15N]-labeled milk protein nitrogen is influenced by diet composition in humans. J Nutr. 1999;129:890&#x2013;895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10203566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makela S, Poutanen M, Kostian ML, Lehtimaki N, Strauss L, Santti R, Vihko R. Inhibition of 17beta-hydroxysteroid oxidoreductase by flavonoids in breast and prostate cancer cells. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med. 1998;217:310&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9492340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum JI, O'Connor JC, Seyler JE, Anthony TG, Freund GG, Layman DK. Leucine reduces the duration of insulin-induced PI 3-kinase activity in rat skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288:E86&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00272.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00272.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15339747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bos C, Metges CC, Gaudichon C, Petzke KJ, Pueyo ME, Morens C, Everwand J, Benamouzig R, Tome D. Postprandial kinetics of dietary amino acids are the main determinant of their metabolism after soy or milk protein ingestion in humans. J Nutr. 2003;133:1308&#x2013;1315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12730415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boza JJ, Martinez-Augustin O, Baro L, Suarez MD, Gil A. Protein v. enzymic protein hydrolysates. Nitrogen utilization in starved rats. Br J Nutr. 1995;73:65&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7857916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman M, Brandon DL. Nutritional and health benefits of soy proteins. J Agric Food Chem. 2001;49:1069&#x2013;1086. doi: 10.1021/jf0009246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf0009246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11312815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Eliasson J, Karlsson HK, Kohnke R. Branched-chain amino acids activate key enzymes in protein synthesis after physical exercise. J Nutr. 2006. pp. 269&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimball SR, Jefferson LS. Signaling pathways and molecular mechanisms through which branched-chain amino acids mediate translational control of protein synthesis. J Nutr. 2006. pp. 227&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton LE, Layman DK. Leucine regulates translation initiation of protein synthesis in skeletal muscle after exercise. J Nutr. 2006. pp. 533&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dillingham BL, McVeigh BL, Lampe JW, Duncan AM. Soy protein isolates of varying isoflavone content exert minor effects on serum reproductive hormones in healthy young men. J Nutr. 2005;135:584&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morito K, Hirose T, Kinjo J, Hirakawa T, Okawa M, Nohara T, Ogawa S, Inoue S, Muramatsu M, Masamune Y. Interaction of phytoestrogens with estrogen receptors alpha and beta. Biol Pharm Bull. 2001;24:351&#x2013;356. doi: 10.1248/bpb.24.351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.24.351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11305594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner-Thorpe D, O'Hagen C, Young I, Lewis SJ. Dietary supplements of soya flour lower serum testosterone concentrations and improve markers of oxidative stress in men. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2003;57:100&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12548304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey R, Ekangaki A, Eden JA. The effects of soy protein in women and men with elevated plasma lipids. Biofactors. 2000;12:251&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11216493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata C, Takatsuka N, Shimizu H, Hayashi H, Akamatsu T, Murase K. Effect of soymilk consumption on serum estrogen and androgen concentrations in Japanese men. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2001;10:179&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11303585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habito RC, Montalto J, Leslie E, Ball MJ. Effects of replacing meat with soyabean in the diet on sex hormone concentrations in healthy adult males. Br J Nutr. 2000;84:557&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11103227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi K, Abata S, Iwamoto N, Ogura M, Yamashita T, Ishikawa O, Ohslzu F, Nakamura H. Effects of soy protein on levels of remnant-like particles cholesterol and vitamin E in healthy men. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol. 2001;47:283&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11767208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis JG, Morris JC, Clark BM, Elder PA. The effect of isoflavone extract ingestion, as Trinovin, on plasma steroids in normal men. Steroids. 2002;67:25&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1016/S0039-128X(01)00129-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0039-128X(01)00129-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11728518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teede HJ, Dalais FS, Kotsopoulos D, Liang YL, Davis S, McGrath BP. Dietary soy has both beneficial and potentially adverse cardiovascular effects: a placebo-controlled study in men and postmenopausal women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2001;86:3053&#x2013;3060. doi: 10.1210/jc.86.7.3053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.86.7.3053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11443167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, Hakkinen K. Muscle hypertrophy, hormonal adaptations and strength development during strength training in strength-trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89:555&#x2013;563. doi: 10.1007/s00421-003-0833-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-003-0833-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luiking YC, Deutz NE, Jakel M, Soeters PB. Casein and soy protein meals differentially affect whole-body and splanchnic protein metabolism in healthy humans. J Nutr. 2005;135:1080&#x2013;1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15867285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, co-workers American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand on Progression Models in Resistance Training for Healthy Adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:364&#x2013;380. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200205001-00389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200205001-00389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conway JM, Ingwersen LA, Moshfegh AJ. Accuracy of dietary recall using the USDA five-step multiple-pass method in men: an observational validation study. J Am Diet Assoc. 2004;104:595&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1016/j.jada.2004.01.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jada.2004.01.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15054345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown EC, DiSilvestro RA, Babaknia A, Devor ST. Soy versus whey protein bars: effects on exercise training impact on lean body mass and antioxidant status. Nutr J. 2004;8;3:22. doi: 10.1186/1475-2891-3-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2891-3-22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC539287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15588291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dangin M, Boirie Y, Guillet C, Beaufrere B. Influence of the protein digestion rate on protein turnover in young and elderly subjects. J Nutr. 2002;132:3228S&#x2013;3233S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12368423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H, Wang HW, Sum HY, Hao NJ. The structure-activity relationships of flavonoids as inhibitors of cytochrome P-450 enzymes in rat liver microsomes and the mutagenicity of 2-amino-3-methylyl-imidazo [4,5-f] quinoline. Mutagenesis. 1994;9:101&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1093/mutage/9.2.101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/mutage/9.2.101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8201941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adlercreutz H, Bannwart C, Wahala K, Makela T, Brunow G, Hase T, Arosemena PJ, Kellis JT, Vickery LE. Inhibition of human aromatase by mammalian lignans and isoflavonoid phytoestrogens. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 1993;44:147&#x2013;153. doi: 10.1016/0960-0760(93)90022-O.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0960-0760(93)90022-O</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8382517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata C, Takatsuka N, Inaba S, Kawakami N, Shimizu H. Effects of soymilk consumption on serum estrogen concentrations in premenopausal Japanese women. J Natl Cancer Inst. 1998;90:1830&#x2013;1835. doi: 10.1093/jnci/90.23.1830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/90.23.1830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9839524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu AM, Fukamachi K, Krausz KW, Cheung C, Gonzalez FJ. Potential role for human cytochrome P450 3A4 in estradiol homeostasis. Endocrinology. 2005;146:2911&#x2013;2919. doi: 10.1210/en.2004-1248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/en.2004-1248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen NE, Appleby PN, Davey GK, Key TJ. Soy milk intake in relation to serum sex hormone levels in British men. Nutr Cancer. 2001;41:41&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1207/S15327914NC41-1&amp;2_5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15327914NC41-1&amp;2_5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12094627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JH, Cawood E, Kinniburgh D, Provan A, Collins AR, Irvine DS. Effect of a phytoestrogen food supplement on reproductive health in normal males. Clin Sci (Lond) 2001;100:613&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11352776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata C, Inaba S, Kawakami N, Kakizoe T, Shimizu H. The inverse association of soy product intake with serum androgen and estrogen concentrations in Japanese men. Nutr Cancer. 2000;36:14&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1207/S15327914NC3601_3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15327914NC3601_3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10798211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Volek JS, Selanne H, Mero AA. Protein ingestion prior to strength exercise affects blood hormones and metabolism. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1990&#x2013;1997. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000175912.64126.f9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000175912.64126.f9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16286871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin JW, Goldman LP, Puglisi MJ, Nickols-Richardson SM, Earthman CP, Gwazdauskas FC. Effect of post-exercise supplement consumption on adaptations to resistance training. J Am Coll Nutr. 2004;23:322&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15310736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DC. Sex-hormone-binding globulin. Clin Endocrinol. 1974;3:69&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4134992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke CW, Anderson DC. Sex-hormone-binding globulin is an oestrogen amplifier. Nature. 1972;3:38&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1038/240038a0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/240038a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4120573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn JF, Nisula BC, Rodbard D. Transport of steroid hormones: binding of 21 endogenous steroids to both testosterone-binding globulin and corticosteroid-binding globulin in human plasma. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1981;53:58&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7195404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson KE, Rosner W, Khan MS, New MI, Pang SY, Wissel PS, Kappas A. Diet-hormone interactions: protein/carbohydrate ratio alters reciprocally the plasma levels of testosterone and cortisol and their respective binding globulins in man. Life Sci. 1987;40:1761&#x2013;1768. doi: 10.1016/0024-3205(87)90086-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0024-3205(87)90086-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3573976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Key TJ, Roe L, Thorogood M, Moore JW, Clark GM, Wang DY. Testosterone, sex hormone-binding globulin, calculated free testosterone, and oestradiol in male vegans and omnivores. Br J Nutr. 1990;64:111&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1079/BJN19900014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/BJN19900014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2400756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed MJ, Cheng RW, Simmonds M, Richmond W, James VH. Dietary lipids: an additional regulator of plasma levels of sex hormone binding globulin. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1987;64:1083&#x2013;1085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3558725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gates JR, Parpia B, Campbell TC, Junshi C. Association of dietary factors and selected plasma variables with sex hormone-binding globulin in rural Chinese women. Am J Clin Nutr. 1996;63:22&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8604665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingham SA. Limitations of the various methods for collecting dietary intake data. Ann Nutr Metab. 1991;35:117&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1952811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rider AA, Calkins BM, Arthur RS, Nair PP. Diet, nutrition intake, and metabolism in populations at high and low risk for colon cancer: Concordance of nutrient information obtained by different methods. Am J Clin Nutr. 1984;40:906&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6548334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jozsi AC, Campbell WW, Joseph L, Davey SL, Evans WJ. Changes in power with resistance training in older and younger men and women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1999;54:M591&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10619323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratley R, Nicklas B, Rubin M, Miller J, Smith A, Smith M, Hurley B, Goldberg A. Strength training increases resting metabolic rate and norepinephrine levels in healthy 50- to 65-yr-old men. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76:133&#x2013;137. doi: 10.1063/1.357118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.357118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8175496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Kruskall LJ, Evans WJ. Lower body versus whole body resistive exercise training and energy requirements of older men and women. Metabolism. 2002;51:989&#x2013;997. doi: 10.1053/meta.2002.34018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2002.34018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12145771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charette SL, McEvoy L, Pyka G, Snow-Harter C, Guido D, Wiswell RA, Marcus R. Muscle hypertrophy response to resistance training in older women. J Appl Physiol. 1991;70:1912&#x2013;1916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1864770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focht BC, Koltyn KF. Influence of resistance exercise of different intensities on state anxiety and blood pressure. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:456&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199903000-00016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199903000-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10188752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casini ML, Marelli G, Papaleo E, Ferrari A, D'Ambrosio F, Unfer V. Psychological assessment of the effects of treatment with phytoestrogens on postmenopausal women: a randomized, double-blind, crossover, placebo-controlled study. Fertil Steril. 2006;85:972&#x2013;978. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2005.09.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2005.09.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16580383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antignac JP, Cariou R, Le Bizec B, Cravedi JP, Andre F. Identification of phytoestrogens in bovine milk using liquid chromatography/electrospray tandem mass spectrometry. Rapid Commun Mass Spectrom. 2003;17:1256&#x2013;1264. doi: 10.1002/rcm.1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rcm.1052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12811748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankenfeld CL, Atkinson C, Thomas WK, Goode EL, Gonzalez A, Jokela T, Wahala K, Schwartz SM, Li SS, Lampe JW. Familial correlations, segregation analysis, and nongenetic correlates of soy isoflavone-metabolizing phenotypes. Exp Biol Med. 2004;229:902&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15388885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNair DM, Lorr M, Droppleman LF. Manual for the Profile of Mood States. San Diego, CA: Educational and Industrial Testing Services; 1971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariotti F, Mahe S, Benamouzig R, Luengo C, Dare S, Gaudichon C, Tome D. Nutritional value of [15N]-soy protein isolate assessed from ileal digestibility and postprandial protein utilization in humans. J Nutr. 1999;129:1992&#x2013;1997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10539774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Hartman JW, Wilkinson SB. Dietary protein to support anabolism with resistance exercise in young men. J Am Coll Nutr. 2005;24:134S&#x2013;139S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15798080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>