<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20205751</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Moderate energy restriction with high protein diet results in healthier outcome in women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-7-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The present study compares two different weight reduction regimens both with a moderately high protein intake on body composition, serum hormone concentration and strength performance in non-competitive female athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Fifteen normal weighted women involved in recreational resistance training and aerobic training were recruited for the study (age 28.5 +/- 6.3 yr, height 167.0 +/- 7.0 cm, body mass 66.3 +/- 4.2 kg, body mass index 23.8 +/- 1.8, mean +/- SD). They were randomized into two groups. The 1 KG group (n = 8; energy deficit 1100 kcal/day) was supervised to reduce body weight by 1 kg per week and the 0.5 KG group (n = 7; energy deficit 550 kcal/day) by 0.5 kg per week, respectively. In both groups protein intake was kept at least 1.4 g/kg body weight/day and the weight reduction lasted four weeks. At the beginning of the study the energy need was calculated using food and training diaries. The same measurements were done before and after the 4-week weight reduction period including total body composition (DXA), serum hormone concentrations, jumping ability and strength measurements</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">During the 4-week weight reduction period there were no changes in lean body mass and bone mass, but total body mass, fat mass and fat percentage decreased significantly in both groups. The changes were greater in the 1 KG group than in the 0.5 KG group in total body mass (p &lt; 0.001), fat mass (p &lt; 0.001) and fat percentage (p &lt; 0.01). Serum testosterone concentration decreased significantly from 1.8 +/- 1.0 to 1.4 +/- 0.9 nmol/l (p &lt; 0.01) in 1 KG and the change was greater in 1 KG (30%, p &lt; 0.001) than in 0.5 KG (3%). On the other hand, SHBG increased significantly in 1 KG from 63.4 +/- 17.7 to 82.4 +/- 33.0 nmol/l (p &lt; 0.05) during the weight reducing regimen. After the 4-week period there were no changes in strength performance in 0.5 KG group, however in 1 KG maximal strength in bench press decreased (p &lt; 0.05) while endurance strength in squat and counter movement jump improved (p &lt; 0.05)</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It is concluded that a weight reduction by 0.5 kg per week with ~1.4 g protein/kg body weight/day can be recommended to normal weighted, physically active women instead of a larger (e.g. 1 kg per week) weight reduction because the latter may lead to a catabolic state. Vertical jumping performance is improved when fat mass and body weight decrease. Thus a moderate weight reduction prior to a major event could be considered beneficial for normal built athletes in jumping events.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mero</LastName><ForeName>Antti A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology of Physical Activity, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland. antti.a.mero@jyu.fi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huovinen</LastName><ForeName>Heikki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matintupa</LastName><ForeName>Olle</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hulmi</LastName><ForeName>Juha J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puurtinen</LastName><ForeName>Risto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hohtari</LastName><ForeName>Hannele</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karila</LastName><ForeName>Tuomo Am</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2822830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-7-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Saris WHM, Astrup A, Prentice AM, Zunft HJF, Formiguera X, Venne WPHG Verboeket-van de, Raben A, Poppitt SD, Seppelt B, Johnston S, Vasilaras TH, Keogh GF. Randomized controlled trial of changes in dietary carbohydrate/fat ratio and simple vs complex carbohydrates on body weight and blood lipids: The CARMEN study. Int J Obes. 2000;24(10):1310&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0801451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0801451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11093293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poppitt SD, Keogh GF, Prentice AM, Williams DEM, Sonnemans HMW, Valk EEJ, Robinson E, Wareham NJ. Long-term effects of ad libitum low-fat, high-carbohydrate diets on body weight and serum lipids in overweight subjects with metabolic syndrome. Am J Clin Nutr. 2002;75(1):11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11756055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass JN, Miller WC, Szymanski LM, Fernhall B, Durstine JL. Physiological responses to weight-loss intervention in inactive obese African-American and Caucasian women. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2002;42(1):56&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11832875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karila TAM, Sarkkinen P, Marttinen M, Sepp&#xe4;l&#xe4; T, Mero A, Tallroth K. Rapid weight loss decreases serum testosterone. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1055/s-2008-1038604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1038604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18516767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates GW, Whitworth NS. Effect of body weight reduction on plasma androgens in obese infertile women. Fertil Steril. 1982;38(4):406&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6811336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquali E, Antenucci D, Casimirri F, Venturoli S, Paradisi R, Fabbri R, Belestra V, Melchionda N, Barbara L. Clinical and hormonal characteristics of obese amenorrheic hyperandrogenic women before and after weight loss. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 1989;68:173&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2642485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Evans E, Baum JI, Seyler J, Erickson DJ, Boileau RA. Dietary protein and exercise have additive effects on body composition during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2005;135:1903&#x2013;1910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16046715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Jeor ST, Howard BV, Prewitt TE, Bovee V, Bazzarre T, Eckel RH. Dietary protein and weight reduction: a statement for healthcare professionals from the Nutrition Committee of the Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism of the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2001;104(15):1869&#x2013;1874. doi: 10.1161/hc4001.096152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/hc4001.096152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11591629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jonge L, Bray GA. The thermic effect of food and obesity: a critical review. Obesity Research. 1997;5(6):622&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9449148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair KS, Halliday D, Garrow JS. Thermic response to isoenergetic protein, carbohydrate or fat meals in lean and obese subjects. Clin Sci. 1983;65(3):307&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6347500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jequier E. Pathways to obesity. Int J Obes. 2002;26:S12&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0802123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0802123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12174324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siervo M, Boschi V, Falconi C. Which REE prediction equation should we use in normal-weight, overweight and obese women? Clinical Nutrition. 2003;22(4):426. doi: 10.1016/S0261-5614(03)00095-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0261-5614(03)00095-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12706138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankenfield D, Roth-Yousev L, Compher C. Comparison of predictive equations for resting metabolic rate in healthy non-obese and obese adults: a systematic review. Journal of the American Dietetic Association. 2005;105(5):775&#x2013;789. doi: 10.1016/j.jada.2005.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jada.2005.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiebzak G, Leamy L, Pierson R, Nord Z, Zhang. Measurement precision of body composition variables using the Lunar DPX-L densitometer. Journal of Clinical Densiometry. 2000;3(1):35&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1385/JCD:3:1:035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1385/JCD:3:1:035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10745300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen A, Verdonck L, Kaufman JM. A critical evaluation of simple methods for the estimation of free testosterone in serum. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1999;84:3666&#x2013;3672. doi: 10.1210/jc.84.10.3666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.84.10.3666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10523012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Ahtiainen JP, Selanne H, Volek JS, Hakkinen K, Kovanen V, Mero AA. Androgen receptors and testosterone in men--effects of protein ingestion, resistance exercise and fiber type. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2008;110:130&#x2013;137. doi: 10.1016/j.jsbmb.2008.03.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsbmb.2008.03.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18455389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi PV, Bosco C. Utilization of stored elastic energy in leg extensor muscles by men and women. Medicine and Science in Sport. 1987;10(4):261&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">750844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remer T. Influence of nutrition on acid-base balance - metabolic aspects. Eur J Nutr. 2001;40:214&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1007/s394-001-8348-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s394-001-8348-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11842946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaszquez JA, Adibi SA. Protein sparing during treatment of obesity: ketogenic versus nonketogenic very low caloric diet. Metabolism. 1992;41:406&#x2013;414. doi: 10.1016/0026-0495(92)90076-M.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0026-0495(92)90076-M</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1556948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell JD, Margen S, Calloway DH. Ketosis, weight loss, uric acid, and nitrogen balance in obese women fed single nutrients at low caloric levels. Metabolism. 1969;18:193&#x2013;208. doi: 10.1016/0026-0495(69)90039-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0026-0495(69)90039-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4887615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadoyannakis NJ, Stefanidis CJ, McGeown M. The effect of correction of metabolic acidosis on nitrogen and potassium balance of patients with chronic renal failure. Am J Clin Nutr. 1984;40:623&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6089541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gougeon-Reyburn R, Lariviere F, Marliss EB. Effects of bicarbonate supplementation on urinary mineral excretion during very low energy diets. Am J Med Sci. 1991;302:67&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1097/00000441-199108000-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000441-199108000-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1897560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson-Hughes B, Harris SS, Ceglia L. Alkaline diets favor lean tissue mass in older adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2008;87:662&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2597402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18326605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Due A, Toubro S, Skov AR, Astrup A. Effect of normal-fat diets, either medium or high in protein, on body weight in overweight subjects: a randomized 1-year trial. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2004;28:1283&#x2013;1290. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0802767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0802767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15303109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skov AR, Toubro S, Ronn B, Holm L, Astrup A. Randomized trial on protein vs. carbohydrate in ad libitum fat reduced diet for the treatment of obesity. International Journal of Obesity Related Metabolic Disorders. 1999;23:528&#x2013;536. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0800867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0800867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10375057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerterp-Plantenga MS. The significance of protein in food intake and body weight regulation. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab care. 2003;6:635&#x2013;638. doi: 10.1097/00075197-200311000-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00075197-200311000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14557793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerterp-Plantenga MS, Lejeune MP, Nijs I, van Ooijen M, Kovacs EM. High protein intake sustains weight maintenance after body weight loss in humans. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2004;28:57&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0802461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0802461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14710168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lejeune MP, Kovacs EM, Westerterp-Plantenga MS. Additional protein intake limits weight regain after weight loss in humans. Br J Nutr. 2005;93:281&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1079/BJN20041305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/BJN20041305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lejeune MP, Westerterp KR, Adam TC, Luscombe-Marsh ND, Westerterp-Plantenga MS. Ghrelin and glucagon-like peptide 1 concentrations, 24-h satiety, and energy and substrate metabolism during a high-protein diet and measured in a respiration chamber. Am J Clin MNutr. 2006;83:89&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16400055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weigle DS, Breen PA, Matthys CC, Callahan HS, Meeuws KE, Burden VR. A high-protein diet induces sustained reductions in appetite, ad libitum caloric intake, and body weight despite compensatory changes in diurnal plasma leptin and ghrelin concentrations. Am J Clin Nutr. 2005;82:41&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claessens M, van Baak MA, Monsheimer S, Saris WHM. The effect of a low-fat, high-protein or high-carbohydrate ad libitum diet on weight loss maintenance and metabolic risk factors. Int J Obes. 2009;33:296&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1038/ijo.2008.278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2008.278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen NE, Appleby PN, Davey GK, Key TJ. Lifestyle and nutritional determinants of bioavailable androgens and related hormones in British men. Cancer Causes Control. 2002;13:353&#x2013;363. doi: 10.1023/A:1015238102830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1015238102830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12074505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen A. Physiology of the testosterone-binding globulin in man. Ann NYAcad Sci. 1988;538:103&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1111/j.1749-6632.1988.tb48855.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.1988.tb48855.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3056178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wabtisch M, Hauner H, Heinze E, B&#xf6;ckmann A, Benz R, Mayer H, Teller W. Body fat distribution and steroid hormone concentrations in obese adolescent girls before and after weight reduction. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism. 1995;80:3469&#x2013;3475. doi: 10.1210/jc.80.12.3469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.80.12.3469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8530585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bootwood N, Hamilton-Fairley D, Kiddy D, Robinson S, Franks S. Sex hormone-binding globulin and female reproductive function. J Steroid Biochem Molec Biology. 1995;53(1-6):529&#x2013;531. doi: 10.1016/0960-0760(95)00108-C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0960-0760(95)00108-C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7626505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisset AS, Blouin K, Tchernof A. Impact of diet and adiposity on circulating levels of sex hormone-binding globulin and androgens. Nutrition Reviews. 2008;66(9):506&#x2013;516. doi: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2008.00083.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1753-4887.2008.00083.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18752474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viitasalo JT, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Bosco C, Alen M. Effects of rapid weight reduction on force production and vertical jumping height. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 1987;8(4):281&#x2013;285. doi: 10.1055/s-2008-1025670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1025670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3667026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryan J, Triggermann M. The effect of weight-loss dieting on cognitive performance and physiological well-being in overweight women. Appetite. 2001;36:147&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1006/appe.2000.0389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/appe.2000.0389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11237350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>