<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36767015</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2227-9032</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Healthcare (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Healthcare (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intensity Differences of Resistance Training for Type 2 Diabetic Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">440</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/healthcare11030440</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Resistance training is used as adjunctive therapy for type 2 diabetes (T2DM), and the aim of this study was to investigate the differences in the treatment effects of different intensities of resistance training in terms of glycemia, lipids, blood pressure, adaptations, and body measurements. A comprehensive search was conducted in the PubMed, EMBASE (Excerpta Medica dataBASE), EBSCO (Elton B. Stephens Company) host, Cochrane Library, WOS (Web of Science), and Scopus databases with a cut-off date of April 2022, and reference lists of relevant reviews were also consulted. The literature screening and data extraction were performed independently by two researchers. RoB2 (Risk of bias 2) tools were used for the literature quality assessment, the exercise intensity was categorized as medium-low intensity and high intensity, and the meta subgroup analysis was performed using R Version. A fixed or random effects model was selected for within-group analysis based on the heterogeneity test, and a random effects model was used for the analysis of differences between subgroups. A total of 36 randomized controlled trials were included, with a total of 1491 participants. It was found that resistance training significantly improved HbA1c (glycated hemoglobin), fasting blood glucose, TG (triglycerides), TC (total cholesterol), and LDL (low-density lipoprotein cholesterol) levels in patients with T2DM and caused a significant reduction in systolic blood pressure, percent of fat mass, and HOMA-IR (homeostatic model assessment for insulin resistance) indexes. The effects of high and medium-low intensity resistance training on T2DM patients were different in terms of HOMA-IR, maximal oxygen consumption, weight, waist-to-hip ratio, and body mass indexes. Only medium-low intensity resistance training resulted in a decrease in HOMA-IR. In addition to weight (MD = 4.25, 95% CI: [0.27, 8.22], <i>I</i><sup>2</sup> = 0%, <i>p</i> = 0.04; MD = -0.33, 95% CI: [-2.05, 1.39], <i>I</i><sup>2</sup> = 0%, <i>p</i> = 0.76; between groups <i>p</i> = 0.03) and HOMA-IR (MD = 0.11, 95% CI: [-0.40, -0.63], <i>I</i><sup>2</sup> = 0%, <i>p</i> = 0.85; MD = -1.09, 95% CI: [-1.83, -0.36], <i>I</i><sup>2</sup> = 87%, <i>p</i> = &lt; 0.01; between groups <i>p</i> = 0.0085), other indicators did not reach statistical significance in the level of difference within the two subgroups of high intensity and medium-low intensity. The treatment effects (merger effect values) of high intensity resistance training were superior to those of medium-low intensity resistance training in terms of HbA1c, TG, TC, LDL levels and diastolic blood pressure, resting heart rate, waist circumference, fat mass, and percentage of fat mass. Therefore, high intensity resistance training can be considered to be a better option to assist in the treatment of T2DM and reduce the risk of diabetic complications compared to medium-low intensity resistance training. Only one study reported an adverse event (skeletal muscle injury) associated with resistance training. Although results reflecting the difference in treatment effect between intensity levels reached no statistical significance, the practical importance of the study cannot be ignored.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Tenglong</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Keimyung University, Daegu 42601, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Man-Hsu</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Marketing, Keimyung University, Daegu 42601, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Kijin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3724-7758</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Keimyung University, Daegu 42601, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Healthcare (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101666525</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2227-9032</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood glucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36767015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9914423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11030440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">healthcare11030440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dagenais G.R., Gerstein H.C., Zhang X., McQueen M., Lear S., Lopez-Jaramillo P., Mohan V., Mony P., Gupta R., Kutty V.R. Variations in diabetes prevalence in low-, middle-, and high-income countries: Results from the prospective urban and rural epidemiological study. Diabetes Care. 2016;39:780&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26965719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 Coronavirus Pandemic.  [(accessed on 28 July 2022)].  Available online:  https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S., Hirsch J.S., Narasimhan M., Crawford J.M., McGinn T., Davidson K.W., Barnaby D.P., Becker L.B., Chelico J.D., Cohen S.L. Presenting characteristics, comorbidities, and outcomes among 5700 patients hospitalized with COVID-19 in the New York City area. JAMA. 2020;323:2052&#x2013;2059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F., Yu T., Du R., Fan G., Liu Y., Liu Z., Xiang J., Wang Y., Song B., Gu X. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: A retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395:1054&#x2013;1062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7270627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32171076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W.-J., Liang W.-H., Zhao Y., Liang H.-R., Chen Z.-S., Li Y.-M., Liu X.-Q., Chen R.-C., Tang C.-L., Wang T. Comorbidity and its impact on 1590 patients with COVID-19 in China: A nationwide analysis. Eur. Respir. J. 2020;55:2000547. doi: 10.1183/13993003.00547-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00547-2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan W.-J., Ni Z.-Y., Hu Y., Liang W.-H., Ou C.-Q., He J.-X., Liu L., Shan H., Lei C.-L., Hui D.S. Clinical characteristics of coronavirus disease 2019 in China. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;382:1708&#x2013;1720. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2002032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2002032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32109013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers J., Atwood J.E., Froelicher V. Active lifestyle and diabetes. Am. Heart Assoc. 2003;107:2392&#x2013;2394. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.0000067882.00596.FC.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.0000067882.00596.FC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12756188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chudyk A., Petrella R.J. Effects of exercise on cardiovascular risk factors in type 2 diabetes: A meta-analysis. Diabetes Care. 2011;34:1228&#x2013;1237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3114506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas D., Elliott E.J., Naughton G.A. Exercise for type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2006;2006:CD002968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Ye W., Chen Q., Zhang Y., Kuo C.-H., Korivi M. Resistance exercise intensity is correlated with attenuation of HbA1c and insulin in patients with type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2019;16:140. doi: 10.3390/ijerph16010140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16010140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6339182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30621076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiguro H., Kodama S., Horikawa C., Fujihara K., Hirose A.S., Hirasawa R., Yachi Y., Ohara N., Shimano H., Hanyu O. In search of the ideal resistance training program to improve glycemic control and its indication for patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sport. Med. 2016;46:67&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0379-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0379-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26604100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano T. Pathophysiology of diabetic dyslipidemia. J. Atheroscler. Thromb. 2018;25:RV17023. doi: 10.5551/jat.RV17023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5551/jat.RV17023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6143775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29998913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Scott C.A., Mao C., Tang J., Farmer A.J. Resistance exercise versus aerobic exercise for type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sport. Med. 2014;44:487&#x2013;499. doi: 10.1007/s40279-013-0128-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0128-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24297743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reaven G.M., Greenfield M.S. Diabetic hypertriglyceridemia: Evidence for three clinical syndromes. Diabetes. 1981;30:66&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7028540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N. ACSM&#x2019;s Foundations of Strength Training and Conditioning. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; Philadelphia, PA, USA: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>One Rep Max Calculator.  [(accessed on 30 July 2022)].  Available online:  https://strengthlevel.com/one-rep-max-calculator.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannsen N.M., Swift D.L., Lavie C.J., Earnest C.P., Blair S.N., Church T.S. Categorical analysis of the impact of aerobic and resistance exercise training, alone and in combination, on cardiorespiratory fitness levels in patients with type 2 diabetes: Results from the HART-D study. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:3305&#x2013;3312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3781553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23877979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotnikoff R., Eves N., Jung M., Sigal R., Padwal R., Karunamuni N. Multicomponent, home-based resistance training for obese adults with type 2 diabetes: A randomized controlled trial. Int. J. Obes. 2010;34:1733&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20531348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavros Y., Kay S., Anderberg K.A., Baker M.K., Wang Y., Zhao R., Meiklejohn J., Climstein M., O&#x2019;Sullivan A., De Vos N. Changes in insulin resistance and HbA1c are related to exercise-mediated changes in body composition in older adults with type 2 diabetes: Interim outcomes from the GREAT2DO trial. Diabetes Care. 2013;36:2372&#x2013;2379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3714491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23474589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church T.S., Blair S.N., Cocreham S., Johannsen N., Johnson W., Kramer K., Mikus C.R., Myers V., Nauta M., Rodarte R.Q. Effects of aerobic and resistance training on hemoglobin A1c levels in patients with type 2 diabetes: A randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2010;304:2253&#x2013;2262. doi: 10.1001/jama.2010.1710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2010.1710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran S., Paul J., Sundaram M., Varalakshmi S., Sudhakar S. Effects of whole-body Vibration therapy among Type II Diabetes Mellitus-A Pilot single blind randomized clinical trial. Res. J. Pharm. Technol. 2021;14:1465&#x2013;1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabouri M., Hatami E., Pournemati P., Shabkhiz F. Inflammatory, antioxidant and glycemic status to different mode of high-intensity training in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Mol. Biol. Rep. 2021;48:5291&#x2013;5304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34228273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranasinghe C., Devage S., Constantine G.R., Katulanda P., Hills A.P., King N.A. Glycemic and cardiometabolic effects of exercise in South Asian Sri Lankans with type 2 diabetes mellitus: A randomized controlled trial Sri Lanka diabetes aerobic and resistance training study (SL-DARTS) Diabetes Metab. Syndr. Clin. Res. Rev. 2021;15:77&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1016/j.dsx.2020.12.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2020.12.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33310265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholami F., Khaki R., Mirzaei B., Howatson G. Resistance training improves nerve conduction and arterial stiffness in older adults with diabetic distal symmetrical polyneuropathy: A randomized controlled trial. Exp. Gerontol. 2021;153:111481. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2021.111481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2021.111481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34280509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaeeshirazi R. Aerobic versus resistance training: Leptin and metabolic parameters improvement in type 2 diabetes obese men. Res. Q. Exerc. Sport. 2021;93:537&#x2013;547. doi: 10.1080/02701367.2021.1875111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2021.1875111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34383632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rad M.M., Bijeh N., Hosseini S.R.A., Saeb A.R. The effect of two concurrent exercise modalities on serum concentrations of FGF21, irisin, follistatin, and myostatin in men with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Arch. Physiol. Biochem. 2020:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1080/13813455.2020.1829649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13813455.2020.1829649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto Y., Nagai Y., Kawanabe S., Hishida Y., Hiraki K., Sone M., Tanaka Y. Effects of resistance training using elastic bands on muscle strength with or without a leucine supplement for 48 weeks in elderly patients with type 2 diabetes. Endocr. J. 2021;68:291&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33071273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogharnasi M., TajiTabas A., Tashakorizadeh M., Nayebifar S. The Effects of resistance and endurance training on levels of nesfatin-1, HSP70, insulin resistance and body composition in women with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Sci. Sport. 2019;34:e15&#x2013;e23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh P.-L., Tseng C.-H., Tseng Y.J., Yang W.-S. Resistance training improves muscle function and cardiometabolic risks but not quality of life in older people with type 2 diabetes mellitus: A randomized controlled trial. J. Geriatr. Phys. Ther. 2018;41:65&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1519/JPT.0000000000000107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27893563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botton C.E., Umpierre D., Rech A., Pfeifer L.O., Machado C.L., Teodoro J.L., Dias A.S., Pinto R.S. Effects of resistance training on neuromuscular parameters in elderly with type 2 diabetes mellitus: A randomized clinical trial. Exp. Gerontol. 2018;113:141&#x2013;149. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2018.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2018.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30296453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AminiLari Z., Fararouei M., Amanat S., Sinaei E., Dianatinasab S., AminiLari M., Daneshi N., Dianatinasab M. The effect of 12 weeks aerobic, resistance, and combined exercises on omentin-1 levels and insulin resistance among type 2 diabetic middle-aged women. Diabetes Metab. J. 2017;41:205. doi: 10.4093/dmj.2017.41.3.205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4093/dmj.2017.41.3.205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5489501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28537059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabani R., Nazari M., Dalili S., Rad A.H. Effect of circuit resistance training on glycemic control of females with diabetes Type II. Int. J. Prev. Med. 2015;6:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4410441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25949784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdirejei H.A., Abadei S.F.R., Seidi A.A., Gorji N.E., Kafshgari H.R., Pour M.E., Khalili H.B., Hajeizad F., Khayeri M. Effects of an eight-week resistance training on plasma vaspin concentrations, metabolic parameters levels and physical fitness in patients with type 2 diabetes. Cell J. 2014;16:367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4204186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24611142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou N., Fotiadis G., Kapelouzou A., Kostakis A., Liapis C., Vrabas I. The differential anti-inflammatory effects of exercise modalities and their association with early carotid atherosclerosis progression in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabet. Med. 2013;30:e41&#x2013;e50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23078531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira V.N.D., Bessa A., Jorge M.L.M.P., Oliveira R.J.D.S., de Mello M.T., De Agostini G.G., Jorge P.T., Espindola F.S. The effect of different training programs on antioxidant status, oxidative stress, and metabolic control in type 2 diabetes. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 2012;37:334&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22458821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou N.P., Fotiadis G., Athanasiadou Z., Vitta I., Lampropoulos S., Vrabas I.S. The effects of resistance training on ApoB/ApoA-I ratio, Lp (a) and inflammatory markers in patients with type 2 diabetes. Endocrine. 2012;42:561&#x2013;569. doi: 10.1007/s12020-012-9650-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-012-9650-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22407494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed U.A., Manzar D., Raza S., Shareef M.Y., Hussain M.E. Resistance training leads to clinically meaningful improvements in control of glycemia and muscular strength in untrained middle-aged patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. N. Am. J. Med. Sci. 2012;4:336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3421911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22912941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavari A., Najafipoor F., Aliasgarzadeh A., Niafar M., Mobasseri M. Effect of aerobic exercise, resistance training or combined training on glycaemic control and cardio-vascular risk factors in patients with type 2 diabetes. Biol. Sport. 2012;29:135&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorge M.L.M.P., de Oliveira V.N., Resende N.M., Paraiso L.F., Calixto A., Diniz A.L.D., Resende E.S., Ropelle E.R., Carvalheira J.B., Espindola F.S. The effects of aerobic, resistance, and combined exercise on metabolic control, inflammatory markers, adipocytokines, and muscle insulin signaling in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Metabolism. 2011;60:1244&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larose J., Sigal R.J., Khandwala F., Prud&#x2019;homme D., Boul&#xe9; N., Kenny G.P. Associations between physical fitness and HbA1c in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetologia. 2011;54:93&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20953579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon H.R., Min K.W., Ahn H.J., Seok H.G., Lee J.H., Park G.S., Han K.A. Effects of aerobic exercise vs. resistance training on endothelial function in women with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Metab. J. 2011;35:364&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3178697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21977456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazley L., Ingle L., Tsakirides C., Carroll S., Nagi D. Impact of a short-term, moderate intensity, lower volume circuit resistance training programme on metabolic risk factors in overweight/obese type 2 diabetics. Res. Sport. Med. 2010;18:251&#x2013;262. doi: 10.1080/15438627.2010.510049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2010.510049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21058210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku Y., Han K., Ahn H., Kwon H., Koo B., Kim H., Min K. Resistance exercise did not alter intramuscular adipose tissue but reduced retinol-binding protein-4 concentration in individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus. J. Int. Med. Res. 2010;38:782&#x2013;791. doi: 10.1177/147323001003800305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/147323001003800305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20819415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin C., Sigal R.J., Cousins M., Menard M.L., Atkinson M., Khandwala F., Kenny G.P., Proctor S., Ooi T.C. Resistance exercise but not aerobic exercise lowers remnant-like lipoprotein particle cholesterol in type 2 diabetes: A randomized controlled trial. Atherosclerosis. 2010;213:552&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20870234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wycherley T.P., Noakes M., Clifton P.M., Cleanthous X., Keogh J.B., Brinkworth G.D. A high-protein diet with resistance exercise training improves weight loss and body composition in overweight and obese patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2010;33:969&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2858200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora E., Shenoy S., Sandhu J. Effects of resistance training on metabolic profile of adults with type 2 diabetes. Indian J. Med. Res. 2009;129:515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung N., Cinnadaio N., Russo M., Marek S. A pilot randomised controlled trial of resistance exercise bands in the management of sedentary subjects with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Res. Clin. Pract. 2009;83:e68&#x2013;e71. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2008.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2008.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19157617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larose J. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. University of Ottawa; Ottawa, ON, Canada: 2009. The Effect of Exercise Training on Physical Fitness in type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenoy S., Arora E., Jaspal S. Effects of progressive resistance training and aerobic exercise on type 2 diabetics in Indian population. Int. J. Diabetes Metab. 2009;17:27&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal R.J., Kenny G.P., Boul&#xe9; N.G., Wells G.A., Prud&#x2019;homme D., Fortier M., Reid R.D., Tulloch H., Coyle D., Phillips P. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: A randomized trial. Ann. Intern. Med. 2007;147:357&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17876019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum K., Votteler T., Schiab J. Efficiency of vibration exercise for glycemic control in type 2 diabetes patients. Int. J. Med. Sci. 2007;4:159. doi: 10.7150/ijms.4.159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.4.159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1885552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17554399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks N., Layne J.E., Gordon P.L., Roubenoff R., Nelson M.E., Castaneda-Sceppa C. Strength training improves muscle quality and insulin sensitivity in Hispanic older adults with type 2 diabetes. Int. J. Med. Sci. 2007;4:19. doi: 10.7150/ijms.4.19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.4.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1752232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda C., Layne J.E., Munoz-Orians L., Gordon P.L., Walsmith J., Foldvari M., Roubenoff R., Tucker K.L., Nelson M.E. A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise training to improve glycemic control in older adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25:2335&#x2013;2341. doi: 10.2337/diacare.25.12.2335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.25.12.2335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan D.W., Puddey I.B., Beilin L.J., Burke V., Morton A.R., Stanton K. Effects of a short-term circuit weight training program on glycaemic control in NIDDM. Diabetes Res. Clin. Pract. 1998;40:53&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9699091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii T., Yamakita T., Sato T., Tanaka S., Fujii S. Resistance training improves insulin sensitivity in NIDDM subjects without altering maximal oxygen uptake. Diabetes Care. 1998;21:1353&#x2013;1355. doi: 10.2337/diacare.21.8.1353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.21.8.1353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9702447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honkola A., Forsen T., Eriksson J. Resistance training improves the metabolic profile in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Acta Diabetol. 1997;34:245&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9451466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid R., Tulloch H., Sigal R., Kenny G., Fortier M., McDonnell L., Wells G., Boule N., Phillips P., Coyle D. Effects of aerobic exercise, resistance exercise or both, on patient-reported health status and well-being in type 2 diabetes mellitus: A randomised trial. Diabetologia. 2010;53:632&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20012857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon P., Vannier E., Hamada K., Layne J., Hurley B., Roubenoff R., Castaneda-Sceppa C. Resistance training alters cytokine gene expression in skeletal muscle of adults with type 2 diabetes. Int. J. Immunopathol. Pharmacol. 2006;19:739&#x2013;749. doi: 10.1177/039463200601900404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/039463200601900404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17166396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holten M.K., Zacho M., Gaster M., Juel C., Wojtaszewski J.F., Dela F. Strength training increases insulin-mediated glucose uptake, GLUT4 content, and insulin signaling in skeletal muscle in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2004;53:294&#x2013;305. doi: 10.2337/diabetes.53.2.294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diabetes.53.2.294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L. Genetic and Dietary Effects on Physical Properties, Assembly and Secretion of apoB-Containing Lipoproteins. Texas A&amp;M University; College Station, TX, USA: 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastor-Barriuso R., Banegas J.R., Damin J., Appel L.J., Guallar E. Systolic blood pressure, diastolic blood pressure, and pulse pressure: An evaluation of their joint effect on mortality. Ann. Intern. Med. 2003;139:731&#x2013;739. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-139-9-200311040-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-139-9-200311040-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14597457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>