<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25414756</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oxygen uptake and heart rate kinetics after different types of resistance exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>235</StartPage><EndPage>244</EndPage><MedlinePgn>235-44</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2014-0077</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Oxygen uptake (VO2) and heart rate (HR) kinetics after exercise are important indicators of fitness and cardiovascular health. However, these variables have been little investigated in resistance exercise (RE). The current study compared post-exercise kinetics of VO2 and the HR among different types of REs. The study included 14 males (age: 26.5&#xb1;5.4 years, body mass: 80.1&#xb1;11.4 kg, body height: 1.77&#xb1;0.07 m, fat content: 11.3&#xb1;4.6%) with RE experience. Dynamic muscle strength was measured using one repetition maximum (1RM) with regard to the half-squat, bench press, pull-down, and triceps pushdown exercises. The participants performed a maximum number of repetitions at 80% of 1RM for each exercise, separated by a recovery period of 60 minutes. VO2 was measured using ergospirometry. VO2 and HR kinetics were assessed using the time constant of the recovery curves, and excess oxygen consumption (EPOC) was calculated afterward. Significant differences were not observed across the exercises with regard to VO2 kinetics. However, the half-squat exercise elicited a greater EPOC than the bench press and triceps pushdown exercises (p&lt;.05). HR kinetics was slower for the half-squat exercise than for the other exercises (p&lt;.05). These findings confirm that the type of RE influences both the cardiac autonomic response post-exercise and EPOC, but not VO2 kinetics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vianna</LastName><ForeName>Jeferson M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Motor Evaluation Laboratory, Faculty of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF) - Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Werneck</LastName><ForeName>Francisco Z</ForeName><Initials>FZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Motor Evaluation Laboratory, Faculty of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF) - Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coelho</LastName><ForeName>Emerson F</ForeName><Initials>EF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Ouro Preto (UFOP) - Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Damasceno</LastName><ForeName>Vinicius O</ForeName><Initials>VO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Pernambuco (UFPE) - Department Physical Education, Pernambuco, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reis</LastName><ForeName>Victor M</ForeName><Initials>VM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Centre for Sport, Health and Human Development, University of Tras-os-Montes and Alto Douro (UTAD) - Vila Real, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy expenditure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxygen uptake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25414756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jhk-42-235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida APV, Coertjens M, Cadore EL, Geremia JM, Silva AEL, Kruel LFM. Recovery oxygen uptake in response to two resistance training sessions at different intensities. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2011;17(2):132&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer RJ. Energy Cost of Moderate-Duration Resistance and Aerobic Exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(4):878&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M, Laursen PB, Ahmaidi S. Parasympathetic reactivation after repeated sprint exercise. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2007;293:H133&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17337589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buitrago S, Wirtz N, Yue Z, Kleinoder H, Mester J. Effects of load and training modes on physiological and metabolic responses in resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;117(7):2739&#x2013;2748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castinheiras Neto AG, Silva NL, Farinatti PTV. Influence of resistance training variables on post-exercise oxygen consumption: a systematic review. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2009;15(1):70&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen-Solal A, Laperche T, Morvan D, Geneves M, Caviezel B, Gourgon R. Prolonged kinetics of recovery of oxygen consumption after maximal graded exercise in patients with chronic heart failure. Analysis with gas exchange measurements and NMR spectroscopy. Circulation. 1995;91:2924&#x2013;2932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7796502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole CR, Blackstone EH, Pashkow FJ, Snader CE, Lauer MS. Heart-rate recovery immediately after exercise as a predictor of mortality. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:1351&#x2013;1357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10536127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins MA, Cureton KJ, Hill DW, Ray CA. Relationship of heart rate to oxygen uptake during weight lifting exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1991;23(5):636&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2072844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaesser GA, Brooks GA. Metabolic bases of excess post-exercise oxygen consumption: a review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1984;16(1):29&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6369064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan KS, Kelly EE, Collier SR, Fernhall B. Cardiac autonomic modulation during recovery from acute endurance versus resistance exercise. Eur J Cardiov Prev R. 2006;13:80&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16449868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai K, Sato H, Hori M, Kusuoka H, Ozaki H, Yokoyama H, Takeda H, Inoue M, Kamada T. Vagally mediated heart rate recovery after exercise is accelerated in athletes but blunted in patients with chronic heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1994;24:1529&#x2013;1535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7930286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Generalized equations for predicting body density of men. Brit J Nutr. 1978;40:497&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">718832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM, Burnley M. Effect of exercise modality on VO2 kinetics. In: Jones AM, Poole DC, editors. Oxygen uptake kinetics in sport, exercise and medicine. Routledge; London: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM, Poole DC. Oxygen uptake kinetics in sport, exercise and medicine. Routledge; London: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A, Strazar K. Frequent low-load ischemic resistance exercise to failure enhances muscle oxygen delivery and endurance capacity. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21(6):231&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koga S, Barstow TJ, Shiojiri T, Takaishi T, Fukuba Y, Kondo N, Shibasaki M, Poole DC. Effect of muscle mass on VO2 kinetics at the onset work. J Appl Physiol. 2001;90:461&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppo K, Bouckaert J, Jones AM. Effects of training status and exercise intensity on phase II VO2 kinetics. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(2):225&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14767244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima AHRD, Forjaz CLD, Silva GQD, Meneses AL, Silva AJMR, Ritti-Dias RM. Acute Effect of Resistance Exercise Intensity in Cardiac Autonomic Modulation After Exercise. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2011;96(6):498&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21503389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Ray S, MacCartney N, Sale D, Lee P, Garner S. Substrate utilization during weighlifting. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20:S66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meirelles CDM, Gomes PSC. Acute effects of resistance exercise on energy expenditure: revisiting the impact of the training variables. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2004;10:122&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips WT, Ziuraitis JR. Energy Cost of the ACSM Single-set Resistance Training Protocol. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(2):350&#x2013;3555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto RS, Lupi R, Brentano MA. Metabolic responses to strength training: an emphasis on energy expenditure. Rev Bras Cineantropom Desempenho Hum. 2011;13(2):150&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robergs RA, Gordon T, Reynolds J, Walker TB. Energy Expenditure During Bench Press and Squat Exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(1):123&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuenke MD, Mikat RP, McBride JM. Effect of an acute period of resistance exercise on excess post-exercise oxygen consumption: implications for body mass management. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;86(5):411&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11882927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short KR, Sedlock DA. Excess postexercise oxygen consumption and recovery rate in trained and untrained participants. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83(1):153&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9216958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sietsema KE, Daly JA, Wasserman K. Early dynamics of O2 uptake and heart rate as affected by exercise work rate. J Appl Physiol. 1989;67(6):2535&#x2013;2541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2606862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton MK, Potteiger JA. Effects of resistance exercise bouts of different intensities but equal work on EPOC. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(4):715&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vianna JM, Lima JP, Saavedra FJ, Reis VM. Aerobic and anaerobic energy during resistance exercise at 80% 1RM. J Hum Kinet. 2011;29A:75&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu F, Rhodes EC. Oxygen uptake kinetics during exercise. Sports Med. 1999;27(5):313&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10368878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>