<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40734253</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1643-3750</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical science monitor : international medical journal of experimental and clinical research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Monit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Study of the Rehabilitation Exercise 5R System and Aerobic Exercise on Postpartum Recovery: Impacts on Muscle Function and Metabolic Health.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e947877</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e947877</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e947877</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12659/MSM.947877</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BACKGROUND This study evaluated the effectiveness of a postpartum rehabilitation exercise using rehabilitative ultrasound imaging (RUSI) compared to an aerobic exercise and routine daily activities over a 12-week period. MATERIAL AND METHODS We randomly assigned 56 postpartum women to 3 groups: Group 1 (5R system), Group 2 (aerobic exercise), and Group 3 (control). Groups 1 and 2 engaged in supervised exercise sessions twice per week over a 12-week intervention period. Outcomes included inter-rectus distance (IRD), muscle thickness, muscle strength, body composition, fasting blood glucose (FBG), and postpartum depression. RESULTS No significant group-by-time interaction effects were observed for IRD (p&gt;0.05). For rectus abdominis thickness (RAT), quadriceps thickness (QT), and gluteus maximus thickness (GMT), significant group-by-time interaction effects were observed during contraction and relaxation (p&lt;0.05). Significant group-by-time interaction effects were observed for muscle strength, including knee extension (KE), hip flexion (HF), trunk flexion (TF), and trunk extension (TE) (p&lt;0.05). Body weight and body mass index (BMI) decreased significantly in all groups (p&lt;0.001). Abdominal fat percentage (AFP) and FBG levels decreased only in Group 1, with a statistically significant interaction effect observed (p&lt;0.05). No significant differences were found in the Korean version of the Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale (K-EPDS) scores (p&gt;0.05). CONCLUSIONS Systematic rehabilitation exercise is important for facilitating rapid postpartum recovery. Integrating core-strengthening exercises with resistance training has been shown to be more effective than aerobic exercise alone in improving muscle thickness, muscle strength, AFP and FBG.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Byeon</LastName><ForeName>Na-Eun</ForeName><Initials>NE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Applied Physical Therapy Lab, Future Convergence University, Sahmyook University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Jang-Hoon</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, School of Health and Medical Science, Kyungbok University, Namyangju, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>So-Jung</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fitness Center for Pregnant Women, Momsbodycare Center, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Woo-Sung</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fitness Center for Pregnant Women, Momsbodycare Center, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Wan-Hee</ForeName><Initials>WH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Applied Physical Therapy Lab, Future Convergence University, Sahmyook University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Monit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9609063</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1234-1010</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049590" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postpartum Period</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019052" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression, Postpartum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest:</b> None declared</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40734253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12320554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.947877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">947877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Choo HJ, Hwang SK, Hynes CK. Musculoskeletal issues and care for pregnant and postpartum women. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep. 2020;8:493&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutke A, &#xd6;stgaard HC, &#xd6;berg B. Association between muscle function and low back pain in relation to pregnancy. J Rehabil Med. 2008;40(4):304&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18382827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goossens N, Geraerts I, Vandenplas L, et al. Body perception disturbances in women with pregnancy-related lumbopelvic pain and their role in the persistence of pain postpartum. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2021;21:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7977601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33736613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Gu Y, Gu Y, et al. Diastasis recti abdominis in adult women based on abdominal computed tomography imaging: Prevalence, risk factors and its impact on life. J Clin Nurs. 2021;30(3&#x2013;4):518&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33207011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelli E. Accelerating uterine involution: the role of postpartum exercise in primary care settings. Open Access Indonesian Journal of Medical Reviews. 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(24):1451&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Critchley CJC. Physical therapy is an important component of postpartum care in the fourth trimester. Phys Ther. 2022;102(5):pzac021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35225339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beamish NF, Davenport MH, Ali MU, et al. Impact of postpartum exercise on pelvic floor disorders and diastasis recti abdominis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59(8):562&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12013572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39694630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter T, Bastounis A, Guo B, Jane Morrell C. The effectiveness of exercise-based interventions for preventing or treating postpartum depression: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Womens Mental Health. 2019;22:37&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29882074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaik A, Khan S, Shaik A, Shaik KK, Khan MS. Advancements in postpartum rehabilitation: A systematic review. Cureus. 2024;16(8):e66165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11372501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39233964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed H, Slayman T, Thoma KD. ACOG committee opinion no. 804: Physical activity and exercise during pregnancy and the postpartum period. Obstet Gynecol. 2021;137(2):375&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33481513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin C, Rokibullah R, Sofinia H. The physiological changes in the postpartum period after childbirth. Asian Journal of Social and Humanities. 2022;1(03):105&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourladani A, Zafrakas M, Chatzigiannis B, et al. The effect of physical exercise on postpartum fitness, hormone and lipid levels: A randomized controlled trial in primiparous, lactating women. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2015;291:525&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25138123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schauberger CW, Rooney BL, Goldsmith L, et al. Peripheral joint laxity increases in pregnancy but does not correlate with serum relaxin levels. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1996;174(2):667&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8623804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selman R, Early K, Battles B, et al. Maximizing recovery in the postpartum period: A Timeline for rehabilitation from pregnancy through return to sport. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2022;17(6):1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9528725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taglione E, Catitti P, D&#x2019;Angelo M, et al. Proprioceptive and motor training using the high performance robotic device Hunova: Protocol of a randomized, controlled trial in patients with lower limb post-traumatic conditions. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;61:e497&#x2013;e98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCheminant J, Hinman T, Pratt K, et al. Effect of resistance training on body composition, self-efficacy, depression, and activity in postpartum women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(2):414&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22738284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S, Zhu B, Zheng Y, et al. Effect of real-time ultrasound imaging for biofeedback on trunk muscle contraction in healthy subjects: A preliminary study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2021;22:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaCross J, Proulx L, Brizzolara K, Humphrey J. Effect of rehabilitative ultrasound imaging (RUSI) biofeedback on improving pelvic floor muscle function in individuals with stress urinary incontinence: A systematic review. The Journal of Women&#x2019;s &amp; Pelvic Health Physical Therapy. 2021;45(4):174&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H-J, Ha H-G, Hahn J, et al. Intra-and inter-rater reliabilities for novel muscle thickness assessment during Co-contraction with dual-rehabilitative ultrasound imaging. Phys Ther Sport. 2018;32:109&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29778826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byeon N-e, Shin J-h, Lee W-h. Reliability and validity of dual probe-fixing frame for rehabilitative ultrasound imaging for exercises with visual feedback. Physical Therapy Rehabilitation Science. 2023;12(3):259&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chidi-Ogbolu N, Baar K. Effect of estrogen on musculoskeletal performance and injury risk. Front Physiol. 2019;9:421933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6341375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30697162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodete CS, Thuraka B, Pasupuleti V, Malisetty S. Hormonal influences on skeletal muscle function in women across Life stages: A systematic review. Muscles. 2024;3(3):271&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linek P, Saulicz E, Wolny T, My&#x15b;liwiec A. Intra-rater reliability of B-mode ultrasound imaging of the abdominal muscles in healthy adolescents during the active straight leg raise test. PM R. 2015;7(1):53&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25088316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab AM, Rasouli O, Amiri M, Tahan N. Reliability of ultrasound measurement of automatic activity of the abdominal muscle in participants with and without chronic low back pain. Chiropr Man Therap. 2013;21:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4029582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24479859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaw L-J, Hsu M-J, Liao C-F, et al. The relationships between inter-recti distance measured by ultrasound imaging and abdominal muscle function in postpartum women: A 6-month follow-up study. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2011;41(6):435&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly CR, Mourtzakis M, Furberg H, et al. Rectus Abdominis muscle thickness is a valid measure of cross-sectional area: Implications for Ultrasound. Acad Radiol. 2022;29(3):382&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9447478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34253439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hides JA, Miokovic T, Belav&#xfd; DL, et al. Ultrasound imaging assessment of abdominal muscle function during drawing-in of the abdominal wall: An intrarater reliability study. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2007;37(8):480&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17877284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardo E, El Behi H, Boizeau P, et al. Reliability of ultrasound measurements of quadriceps muscle thickness in critically ill patients. BMC Anesthesiol. 2018;18(1):205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6309087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30591032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong J-R, Lee S-J, Lee W-H. Reliability of rehabilitative ultrasound imaging for measuring the gluteus maximus muscle at rest and during contraction. Physical Therapy Rehabilitation Science. 2017;6(1):7&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baschung Pfister P, de Bruin ED, Sterkele I, et al. Manual muscle testing and hand-held dynamometry in people with inflammatory myopathy: An intra-and interrater reliability and validity study. PLoS One. 2018;13(3):e0194531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5875759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29596450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW. Considerations and practical options for measuring muscle strength: A narrative review. Biomed Res Int. 2019;2019:8194537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30792998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maayah MF, Al-Jarrah MD, El Zahrani SS, et al. Test-retest strength reliability of the Electronic Push/Pull Dynamometer (EPPD) in the measurement of the quadriceps and hamstring muscles on a new chair. Open Journal of Internal Medicine. 2012;2(02):123&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma&#x144;ka J, Bobowik P, Jaskulski K, et al. The influence of three different test positions and thigh asymmetry on measurements of isometric hip flexion strength in men and women. Acta Bioeng Biomech. 2022;24(4):49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37341044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seko T, Mori M, Ohnishi H, et al. Reliability and validity of seated hip extensor strength measurement by handheld dynamometer in older adults. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2019;42(4):E39&#x2013;E44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Blaiser C, De Ridder R, Willems T, et al. Reliability and validity of trunk flexor and trunk extensor strength measurements using handheld dynamometry in a healthy athletic population. Phys Ther Sport. 2018;34:180&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30366246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vla&#x17e;n&#xe1; D, Krko&#x161;ka P, Kuhn M, et al. Assessment of lumbar extensor muscles in the context of trunk function, a pilot study in healthy individuals. Applied Sciences. 2021;11(20):9518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhatt GS, Agarwal MM, Othman Y, Nair SC. Performance of the Roche Accu-Chek active glucose meter to screen for gestational diabetes mellitus using fasting capillary blood. Diabetes Technol Ther. 2011;13(12):1229&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21864017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLester CN, Nickerson BS, Kliszczewicz BM, McLester JR. Reliability and agreement of various InBody body composition analyzers as compared to dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry in healthy men and women. J Clin Densitom. 2020;23(3):443&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30472111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh EA, Walton L, Said S, et al. The association between Diastasis recti abdominis and pelvic floor dysfunction, sacroiliac joint dysfunction, and quality of life among postpartum women after Cesarean delivery. Physikalische Medizin, Rehabilitationsmedizin, Kurortmedizin. 2024;34(1):18&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S, Zhu B, Zheng Y, et al. Effect of RUSI-based core stability exercise on chronic non-specific low back pain patients: Study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2021;11(12):e047317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8671944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34907039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zielonka-Pycka K, Szczygie&#x142; E, Golec E. The influence of physiotherapy on motor control re-education among patients after ischemic stroke. Medical Rehabilitation. 2018;22:4&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyake Y, Nakamura S, Nakajima M. The effect of trunk coordination exercise on dynamic postural control using a Core Noodle. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2014;18(4):519&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25440201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A, Casolo A, Negro F, et al. The increase in muscle force after 4 weeks of strength training is mediated by adaptations in motor unit recruitment and rate coding. J Physiol. 2019;597(7):1873&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6441907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30727028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doba N, Nishiwaki K, Hinohara S. Studies On the target heart rate (thr) in exercise prescription &#x2013; usefulness of the Karvonen&#x2019;s formula. Japanese Journal of Physical Fitness and Sports Medicine. 1988;37(3):245&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedliar I. Calculation of the intensity of health improving aerobic loads. Scientific Journal of Drahomanov Ukrainian State University. Series 15. Scientific and Pedagogical Problems of Physical Culture (Physical Culture And Sports) 2020;5(125):135&#x2013;39. [in Ukrainian]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: A practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol. 2013;4:863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3840331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuominen R, Jahkola T, Mikkonen J, et al. Low back pain and motor control dysfunction after pregnancy: The possible role of rectus diastasis. International Journal of Abdominal Wall and Hernia Surgery. 2023;6(1):30&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell BS, Dhaher YY, Szleifer IG. Review of the multiscale effects of female sex hormones on matrix metalloproteinase &#x2013; mediated collagen degradation. Crit Rev Biomed Eng. 2015;43(5&#x2013;6):401&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27480583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franz MG. The role of stem cells in abdominal wall repair. 2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsia M, Jones S. Natural resolution of rectus abdominis diastasis. Two single case studies. Aust J Physiother. 2000;46(4):301&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11676815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Gleeson BG, Jonkers RAM, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance training is accompanied by a fiber type-specific increase in satellite cell content in elderly men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2009;64(3):332&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Longo S, Mallinson J, et al. Muscle thickness correlates to muscle cross-sectional area in the assessment of strength training-induced hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28(3):846&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5873262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker JL, Stokes M. Ultrasound imaging and muscle function. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2011;41(8):572&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21654098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, DeVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 1979;58(3):115&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">453338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S, editor. Impacts of muscle strength and flexibility on joints. International Conference on Biological Engineering and Medical Science; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K. Neuromuscular and hormonal adaptations during strength and power training. A review. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1989;29(1):9&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2671501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalmers G. Strength training: Do Golgi tendon organs really inhibit muscle activity at high force levels to save muscles from injury, and adapt with strength training? Sports Biomech. 2002;1(2):239&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14658379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loon LJV, Murphy R, Oosterlaar AM, et al. Creatine supplementation increases glycogen storage but not GLUT-4 expression in human skeletal muscle. Clin Sci. 2004;106(1):99&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14507259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC. The role of resistance exercise intensity on muscle fibre adaptations. Sports Med. 2004;34:663&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15335243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadal A, Alonso-Magdalena P, Soriano S, et al. The role of oestrogens in the adaptation of islets to insulin resistance. J Physiol. 2009;587(Pt 21):5031&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19687125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SR, Hawley JA. Update on the effects of physical activity on insulin sensitivity in humans. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2017;2(1):e000143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5569266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28879026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden Davies KA, Sprung VS, Norman JA, et al. Short-term decreased physical activity with increased sedentary behaviour causes metabolic derangements and altered body composition: Effects in individuals with and without a first-degree relative with type 2 diabetes. Diabetologia. 2018;61:1282&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>