<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28515835</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effect of Acute Hyperglycemia on Muscular Strength, Power and Endurance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>390</StartPage><EndPage>396</EndPage><MedlinePgn>390-396</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this study was to elucidate the impact of acute hyperglycemia on skeletal muscle strength, power, and endurance. Ten male collegiate athletes (age 21.5 &#xb1; 1.5 years, height 186 &#xb1; 2.03 cm, body mass 108.8 &#xb1; 7.6 kg) participated in 2 testing sessions, separated by 7 days and randomized for either high glucose (HG) or control (C) treatment conditions. HG consumed a high glucose drink (2 g glucose/kg body weight) while controls consumed an isocaloric nutrition bar (40% protein, 30% fat, and 30% carbohydrate). Blood glucose (BC) levels for HG and C were tested at 0 (basal) and 30, 60, 90, and 120 minutes (mins) post consumption. At 30 mins post consumption, HG and C muscular strength was assessed by a 1RM bench press (BP) test followed by lower body power at 60 mins via vertical jump test. Muscular endurance was examined with a 3-set-to-failure BP test at 90 mins. HG exhibited significantly greater BC values (p&lt;0.05) at the 30, 60, 90, and 120 minute time points. HG glucose area under the curve was significantly greater (p&lt;0.05) than C and was positively correlated with %body fat, a finding that trended towards significance, r = 0.587, n= 10, p = 0.074. There were no between group differences in maximal strength, power or muscular endurance. Although performance measures were unaffected by acute hyperglycemia, acute hyperglycemia can be induced and maintained in healthy, active and young subjects. Despite regular physical activity, excess body fat negatively impacts glucose metabolism.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lime-Ma</LastName><ForeName>Franklin</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance and Athletics, Linfield College, McMinnville, OR, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cotter</LastName><ForeName>Joshua A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, California State University, Long Beach, Long Beach, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schick</LastName><ForeName>Evan E</ForeName><Initials>EE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, California State University, Long Beach, Long Beach, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glycemic control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28515835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5421977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/SDBW3813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association. Standards of Medical Care in Diabetes-2016: Summary of Revisions. Diabetes care. 2016;39(Suppl 1):S4&#x2013;S5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26696680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen H, Schmitz O, Nielsen S. Decreased isometric muscle strength after acute hyperglycaemia in Type 1 diabetic patients. Diabetic Med. 2005;22(10):1401&#x2013;1407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16176203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boor P, Celec P, Behuliak M, Grancic P, Kebis A, Kukan M, Pronayova N, Liptaj T, Ostendorf T, Sebekova K. Regular moderate exercise reduces advanced glycation and ameliorates early diabetic nephropathy in obese Zucker rats. Metab Clin Exp. 2009;58(11):1669&#x2013;1677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buell JL, Calland D, Hanks F, Johnston B, Pester B, Sweeney R, Thorne R. Presence of metabolic syndrome in football linemen. J Athl Train. 2008;43(6):608&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2582553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19030139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chansky ME, Corbett JG, Cohen E. Hyperglycemic emergencies in athletes. Clin Sports Med. 2009;28(3):469&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19505627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook S, Weitzman M, Auinger P, Nguyen M, Dietz WH. Prevalence of a metabolic syndrome phenotype in adolescents: findings from the third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, 1988&#x2013;1994. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2003;157(8):821&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12912790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earle RW, Baechle TR. NSCA&#x2019;s Essentials of Personal Training. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurca R, Lamonte MJ, Church TS, Earnest CP, Fitzgerald SJ, Barlow CE, Jordan AN, Kampert JB, Blair SN. Associations of muscle strength and fitness with metabolic syndrome in men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(8):1301&#x2013;1307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyani RR, Metter EJ, Egan J, Golden SH, Ferrucci L. Hyperglycemia predicts persistently lower muscle strength with aging. Diabetes Care. 2015;38(1):82&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4274779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25392294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyani RR, Tra Y, Yeh HC, Egan JM, Ferrucci L, Brancati FL. Quadriceps strength, quadriceps power, and gait speed in older U.S. adults with diabetes mellitus: results from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, 1999&#x2013;2002. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2013;61(5):769&#x2013;775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3725774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23617584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonborg J, Vejlstrup N, Kelbaek H, Nepper-Christensen L, Jorgensen E, Helqvist S, Holmvang L, Saunamaki K, Botker HE, Kim WY, Clemmensen P, Treiman M, Engstrom T. Impact of acute hyperglycemia on myocardial infarct size, area at risk, and salvage in patients with STEMI and the association with exenatide treatment: results from a randomized study. Diabetes. 2014;63(7):2474&#x2013;2485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24584550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macias-Cervantes MH, Rodriguez-Soto JM, Uribarri J, Diaz-Cisneros FJ, Cai W, Garay-Sevilla ME. Effect of an advanced glycation end product-restricted diet and exercise on metabolic parameters in adult overweight men. Nutrition. 2015;31(3):446&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25701333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metter EJ, Talbot LA, Schrager M, Conwit R. Skeletal muscle strength as a predictor of all-cause mortality in healthy men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57(10):B359&#x2013;B365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12242311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukaka MM. Statistics corner: A guide to appropriate use of correlation coefficient in medical research. Malawi Med J. 2012;24(3):69&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3576830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23638278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Kupelian V, Visser M, Simonsick EM, Goodpaster BH, Kritchevsky SB, Tylavsky FA, Rubin SM, Harris TB. Strength, but not muscle mass, is associated with mortality in the health, aging and body composition study cohort. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61(1):72&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SW, Goodpaster BH, Strotmeyer ES, Kuller LH, Broudeau R, Kammerer C, de Rekeneire N, Harris TB, Schwartz AV, Tylavsky FA, Cho YW, Newman AB, Health A Body Composition S. Accelerated loss of skeletal muscle strength in older adults with type 2 diabetes: the health, aging, and body composition study. Diabetes Care. 2007;30(6):1507&#x2013;1512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17363749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinders I, Murphy RA, Brouwer IA, Visser M, Launer L, Siggeirsdottir K, Eiriksdottir G, Gudnason V, Jonsson PV, Lang TF, Harris TB, Age GESRS. Muscle Quality and Myosteatosis: Novel Associations With Mortality Risk: The Age, Gene/Environment Susceptibility (AGES)-Reykjavik Study. Am J Epidemiol. 2016;183(1):53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5006223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26643983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddell M, Perkins BA. Exercise and glucose metabolism in persons with diabetes mellitus: perspectives on the role for continuous glucose monitoring. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2009;3(4):914&#x2013;923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2769951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20144341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steffes GD, Megura AE, Adams J, Claytor RP, Ward RM, Horn TS, Potteiger JA. Prevalence of metabolic syndrome risk factors in high school and NCAA division I football players. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(7):1749&#x2013;1757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22996023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright KJ, Thomas MM, Betik AC, Belke D, Hepple RT. Exercise training initiated in late middle age attenuates cardiac fibrosis and advanced glycation end-product accumulation in senescent rats. Exp Gerontol. 2014;50:9&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24280067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>