<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27274674</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1303-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sports science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relationship between Leg Mass, Leg Composition and Foot Velocity on Kicking Accuracy in Australian Football.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>344</StartPage><EndPage>351</EndPage><MedlinePgn>344-51</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Kicking a ball accurately over a desired distance to an intended target is arguably the most important skill to acquire in Australian Football. Therefore, understanding the potential mechanisms which underpin kicking accuracy is warranted. The aim of this study was to examine the relationship between leg mass, leg composition and foot velocity on kicking accuracy in Australian Football. Thirty-one Australian Footballers (n = 31; age: 22.1 &#xb1; 2.8 years; height: 1.81 &#xb1; 0.07 m; weight: 85.1 &#xb1; 13.0 kg; BMI: 25.9 &#xb1; 3.2) each performed ten drop punt kicks over twenty metres to a player target. Athletes were separated into accurate (n = 15) and inaccurate (n = 16) kicking groups. Leg mass characteristics were assessed using whole body DXA scans. Foot velocity was determined using a ten-camera optoelectronic, three-dimensional motion capture system. Interactions between leg mass and foot velocity evident within accurate kickers only (r = -0.670 to -0.701). Relative lean mass was positively correlated with kicking accuracy (r = 0.631), while no relationship between foot velocity and kicking accuracy was evident in isolation (r = -0.047 to -0.083). Given the evident importance of lean mass, and its interaction with foot velocity for accurate kickers; future research should explore speed-accuracy, impulse-variability, limb co-ordination and foot-ball interaction constructs in kicking using controlled with-in subject studies to examine the effects of resistance training and skill acquisition programs on the development of kicking accuracy. Key pointsAccurate kickers expressed a very strong inverse relationship between leg mass and foot velocity. Inaccurate kickers were unable to replicate this, with greater volatility in their performance, indicating an ability of accurate kickers to mediate foot velocity to compensate for leg mass in order to deliver the ball over the required distance.Accurate kickers exhibited larger quantities of relative lean mass and lower quantities of relative fat mass in their kicking leg. Higher relative lean mass reduces the relative muscular impulses required to produce a given action, allowing greater limb control with proportionately reduced volitional effort.Kicking accuracy was unable to be explained by either foot velocity or leg mass in isolation; rather, it was the co-contribution and interrelation of these characteristics which were the discriminatory factors between accurate and inaccurate kickers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hart</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas H</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University, Perth, W.A., Australia; Fremantle Dockers Football Club, Perth, W.A., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nimphius</LastName><ForeName>Sophia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Exercise and Sport Science Research, Edith Cowan University , Perth, W.A., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spiteri</LastName><ForeName>Tania</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Science, University of Notre Dame , Perth, W.A., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cochrane</LastName><ForeName>Jodie L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Exercise and Sport Science Research, Edith Cowan University , Perth, W.A., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton</LastName><ForeName>Robert U</ForeName><Initials>RU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University , Perth, W.A., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1303-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coordination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impulse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">relative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">variability</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27274674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amiri-Khorasani M., Osman N., Yusof A. (2010) Kinematics analysis: number of trials necessary to achieve performance stability during soccer instep kicking. Journal of Human Kinetics 23, 15-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen T.B., Dorge H.C., Thomsen F.I. (1999) Collisions in soccer kicking. Sports Engineering 2, 121-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baktash S., Hy A., Muir S., Walton T., Zhang Y. (2009) The effects of different instep foot positions on ball velocity in place kicking. International Journal of Sports Science and Engineering 3(2), 85-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball K. (2007a) Use of weighted balls for improving kicking for distance. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 6(S10), 44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball K. (2007b) Foot-ball interaction in Australian Rules football. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 6(Suppl. 10), 46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball K. (2008) Biomechanical considerations of distance kicking in Australian Rules football. Sports Biomechanics 7(1), 10-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18341133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beilock S., Bertenthal B.I., Hoerger M., Carr T.H. (2008) When does haste make waste? Speed-accuracy trade-off, skill level, and the tools of the trade. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Applied 14(4), 340-352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19102617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besier T.F., LLoyd D.G., Cochrane J.L., Ackland T.R. (2001) External loading of the knee joint during running and cutting maneuvers. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 33(7), 1168-1175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop D. (2008) An applied research model for the sports sciences. Sports Medicine 38(3), 253-263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18278985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron M., Adams R. (2003) Kicking footedness and movement discrimination by elite Australian Rules footballers. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport 6(3), 266-274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14609143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cauraugh J. H., Gabert T. E. White J. J. (1990) Tennis serving velocity and accuracy. Perceptual and Motor Skills 70, 719-722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chelly M.S., Hermassi S., Shephard R.J. (2010) Relationships between power and strength of the upper and lower limb muscles and throwing velocity in male handball players. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 24(6), 1480-1487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20508448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davids K., Lees A., Burwitz L. (2000) Understanding and measuring coordination and control in kicking skills in soccer: implications for talent identification and skill acquisition. Journal of Sports Sciences 18(9), 703-714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11043896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean M., Wu S.W., Maloney L.T. (2007) Trading off speed and accuracy in rapid, goal-directed movements. Journal of Vision 7(5), 1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dichiera A., Webster K.E., Kuilboer L., Morris M.E., Bach T.M., Feller J.A. (2006) Kinematic patterns associated with accuracy of the drop punt kick in Australian Football. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport 9(4), 292-298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16854625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart N.H., Nimphius S., Cochrane J.L., Newton R.U. (2013) Leg mass characteristics of accurate and inaccurate kickers - an Australian Football perspective. Journal of Sports Science 31(15), 1647-1655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23687978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart N.H., Nimphius S., Spiteri T., Newton R.U. (2014) Leg strength and lean mass symmetry influences kicking performance in Australian Football. Journal of Sport Science and Medicine 13(1), 157-165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24570620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart N.H., Nimphius S., Spiteri T., Cochrane J.L., Newton R.U. (2015) Segmental musculoskeletal examinations using dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA): Positioning and analysis considerations. Journal of Sport Science and Medicine 14(3), 620-626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4541127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26336349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hologic. (2004) QDR for Windows XP Reference Manual. Hologic Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W. (2002) A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics. Avaliable from URL: http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/effectmag.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janelle C.M. (2002) Anxiety, arousal and visual attention: a mechanistic account of performance variability. Journal of Sports Sciences 20, 237-251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11999479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E., Katis A. (2007) Biomechanical characteristics and determinants of instep soccer kick. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 6, 154-165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3786235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landlinger J., Stoggl T., Lindlinger S., Wagner H., Muller E. (2012) Differences in ball speed and accuracy of tennis groundstrokes between elite and high-performance players. European Journal of Sport Science 12(4), 301-308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lees A., Nolan L. (1998) The biomechanics of soccer: a review. Journal of Sports Sciences 16(3), 211-234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9596356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levanon J., Dapena J. (1998) Comparison of the kinematics of the full-instep and pass kicks in soccer. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 30(6), 917-927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9624652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magill R. (2008) Motor Learning and Control: Concepts and applications. 8th edition New York, NY: McGraw-Hill.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manolopoulos E., Papadopoulos C., Kellis E. (2006) Effects of combined strength and kick coordination training on soccer kick biomechanics in amateur players. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports 16, 102-110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16533348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagengast A.J., Braun D.A., Wolpert D.M. (2011) Risk sensitivity in a motor task with speed-accuracy trade-off. Journal of Neurophysiology 105(6), 2668-2674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21430284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiffer J.J., Galvao D.A., Gibbs Z., Smith K., Turner D., Foster J., Martin R., Newton R.U. (2010) Strength and functional characteristics of men and women 65 years and older. Rejuvenation Research 13(1), 75-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20230281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips E., Portus M., Davids K., Renshaw I. (2012) Performance accuracy and functional variability in elite and developing fast bowlers. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport 15(2), 182-188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21907618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt R., Lee T. (2005) Motor Control and Learning: A behavioural emphasis (4th ed.). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schorer J., Fath F., Baker J., Jaitner T. (2007) Identification of interindividual and intraindividual movement patterns in handball players of varying expertise levels. Journal of Motor Behavior 39(5), 409-421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17827117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiteri T., Hart N. H., Nimphius S. (2014) Offensive and defensive agility: a sex comparison of lower body kinematics and ground reaction forces. Journal of Applied Biomechanics 30(4), 514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24615296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterzing T., Hennig E.M. (2008) The influence of soccer shoes on kicking velocity in full-instep kicks. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews 36(2), 91-97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18362691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbin M.A., Stodden D.F., Fischman M.G., Weimar W.H. (2011) Impulse-variability theory: implications for ballistic, multijoint motor skill performance. Journal of Motor Behavior 43(3), 275-283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21598159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R., Ettema G. (2003) Instructions emphasizing velocity, accuracy, or both in performance and kinematics of overarm throwing by experienced team handball players. Perceptual and Motor Skills 97(3 Pt 1), 731-742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14738333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner H., Pfusterschmied J., Klous M., von Duvillard S.P., Muller E. (2012) Movement variability and skill level of various throwing techniques. Human Movement Science 31(1), 79-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21835479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams A.M., Ericsson K.A. (2005) Perceptual-cognitive expertise in sport: some considerations when applying the expert performance approach. Human Movement Science 24(3), 283-307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson C., Simpson S.E., van Emmerik R.E., Hamill J. (2008) Coordination variability and skill development in expert triple jumpers. Sports Biomechanics 7(1), 2-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18341132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young W., Gulli R., Rath D., Russell A., O'Brien B., Harvey J. (2010) Acute effect of exercise on kicking accuracy in elite Australian football players. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport 13(1), 85-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18768357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young W. B., Rath D. A. (2011) Enhancing Foot Velocity in Football Kicking: The Role of Strength Training. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 25(2), 561-566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20375741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>