<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34767655</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of concurrent strength and endurance training on run performance and biomechanics: A randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>543</StartPage><EndPage>558</EndPage><MedlinePgn>543-558</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.14092</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This parallel-group randomized controlled trial investigated the effect of concurrent strength and endurance (CSE) training on running performance, biomechanics, and muscle activity during overground running. Thirty moderately trained distance runners were randomly assigned to 10-week CSE training (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;15; 33.1&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;7.5&#xa0;years) or a control group (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;15; 34.2&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;8.2&#xa0;years). Participants ran &#x2265;30&#xa0;km per week and had no experience with strength training. The primary outcome measure was 2-km run time. Secondary outcome measures included lower limb sagittal plane biomechanics and muscle activity during running (3.89&#xa0;m&#xa0;s<sup>-1</sup> and maximal sprinting); maximal aerobic capacity (V&#x307;O<sub>2</sub> max); running economy; and body composition. CSE training improved 2-km run time (mean difference (MD): -11.3&#xa0;s [95% CI -3.7, -19.0]; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.006) and time to exhaustion during the V&#x307;O<sub>2</sub> max running test (MD 59.1&#xa0;s [95% CI 8.58, 109.62]; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.024). The CSE training group also reduced total body fat (MD: -1.05&#xa0;kg [95% CI -0.21, -1.88]; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.016) while total body mass and lean body mass were unchanged. Hip joint angular velocity during the early swing phase of running at 3.89&#xa0;m&#xa0;s<sup>-1</sup> was the only biomechanical or muscle activity variable that significantly changed following CSE training. CSE training is beneficial for running performance, but changes in running biomechanics and muscle activity may not be contributing factors to the performance improvement. Future research should consider other possible mechanisms and the effect of CSE training on biomechanics and muscle activity during prolonged running under fatigued conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trowell</LastName><ForeName>Danielle</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4578-9952</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sport Research, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Movement Science, Australian Institute of Sport, Canberra, Australian Capital Territory, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fox</LastName><ForeName>Aaron</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5639-6388</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sport Research, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saunders</LastName><ForeName>Natalie</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9177-5896</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sport Research, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vicenzino</LastName><ForeName>Bill</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0253-5933</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonacci</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4333-3214</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sport Research, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Deakin University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Australian Institute of Sport PhD Program Stipend</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endurance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plyometrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">running economy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">statistical parametric mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training adaptations</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Saunders PU, Pyne DB, Telford RD, Hawley JA. Factors affecting running economy in trained distance runners. Sports Med. 2004;34(7):465-485. doi:10.2165/00007256-200434070-00005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Prampero PE, Capelli C, Pagliaro P, et al. Energetics of best performances in middle-distance running. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74(5):2318-2324. doi:10.2165/00007256-200434070-00005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcaraz-Iba&#xf1;ez M, Rodr&#xed;guez-P&#xe9;rez M. Effects of resistance training on performance in previously trained endurance runners: a systematic review. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(6):613-629. doi:10.1080/02640414.2017.1326618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagrove RC, Howatson G, Hayes PR. Effects of strength training on the physiological determinants of middle- and long-distance running performance: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2017;48(5):1117-1149. doi:10.1007/s40279-017-0835-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston RE, Quinn TJ, Kertzer R, Vroman NB. Strength training in female distance runners: impact on running economy. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(4):224-229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedano S, Mar&#xed;n PJ, Cuadrado G, Redondo JC. Concurrent training in elite male runners: the influence of strength versus muscular endurance training on performance outcomes. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(9):2433-2443. doi:10.1519/JSC.0b013e318280cc26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, &#xc1;lvarez C, Henr&#xed;quez-Olgu&#xed;n C, et al. Effects of plyometric training on endurance and explosive strength performance in competitive middle- and long-distance runners. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(1):97-104. doi:10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182a1f44c</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly CM, Burnett AF, Newton MJ. The effect of strength training on three-kilometer performance in recreational women endurance runners. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(2):396-403. doi:10.1519/JSC.0b013e318163534a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders PU, Telford RD, Pyne DB, et al. Short-term plyometric training improves running economy in highly trained middle and long distance runners. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(4):947-954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trowell D, Vicenzino B, Saunders N, Fox A, Bonacci J. Effect of strength training on biomechanical and neuromuscular variables in distance runners: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;50(1):133-150. doi:10.1007/s40279-019-01184-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrauti A, Bergermann M, Fernandez-Fernandez J. Effects of a concurrent strength and endurance training on running performance and running economy in recreational marathon runners. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2770-2778. doi:10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d64e9c</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paavolainen L, H&#xe4;kkinen K, H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen I, Nummela A, Rusko H. Explosive-strength training improves 5-km running time by improving running economy and muscle power. J Appl Physiol. 1999a;86(5):1527-1533. doi:10.1152/jappl.1999.86.5.1527</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteve-Lanao J, Rhea MR, Fleck SJ, Lucia A. Running-specific, periodized strength training attenuates loss of stride length during intense endurance running. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(4):1176-1183. doi:10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a861f</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorn TW, Schache AG, Pandy MG. Muscular strategy shift in human running: dependence of running speed on hip and ankle muscle performance. J Exp Biol. 2012;215(11):1944-1956. doi:10.1242/jeb.064527</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrino J, Ruby BC, Dumke CL. Effect of plyometrics on the energy cost of running and MHC and titin isoforms. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(1):49-56. doi:10.1249/MSS.0000000000000747</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N, Alvar B, Evetoch T, Housh T, Kibler W, Kraemer W. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults [ACSM position stand]. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Hewson DJ. Variability of competitive performance of distance runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(9):1588-1592. doi:10.1097/00005768-200109000-00023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders PU, Telford RD, Pyne DB, et al. Improved running economy in elite runners after 20 days of simulated moderate-altitude exposure. J Appl Physiol. 2004;96(3):931-937. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00725.2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kipp S, Byrnes WC, Kram R. Calculating metabolic energy expenditure across a wide range of exercise intensities: the equation matters. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(6):639-642. doi:10.1139/apnm-2017-0781</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howley ET, Bassett DR, Welch HG. Criteria for maximal oxygen uptake: review and commentary. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27:1292-1301. doi:10.1249/00005768-199509000-00009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai AK, Arnold AS, Wakeling JM. Why are antagonist muscles co-activated in my simulation? A musculoskeletal model for analysing human locomotor tasks. Ann Biomed Eng. 2017;45(12):2762-2774. doi:10.1007/s10439-017-1920-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coren S. The lateral preference inventory for measurement of handedness, footedness, eyedness, and earedness: norms for young adults. Psychon Bull Rev. 1993;31(1):1-3. doi:10.3758/BF03334122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Merletti R, et al. European recommendations for surface electromyography, Vol. 8. Roessingh Research and Development; 1999:13-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter DA. Biomechanics and motor control of human movement, Vol. 41. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2009:164 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges L, Olkin I. Statistical models for meta-analysis, Vol. 86. Academic Press; 1985:110 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics. In: A new view of statistics. newstats.org/effectmag.html. Accessed January 16, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pataky TC. Generalized n-dimensional biomechanical field analysis using statistical parametric mapping. J Biomech. 2010;43(10):1976-1982. doi:10.1016/j.jbiomech.2010.03.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung AP. The impact of resistance training on distance running performance. Sports Med. 2003;33(7):539-552. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200333070-00005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Santos-Concejero J, Grivas GV. Effects of strength training on running economy in highly trained runners: a systematic review with meta-analysis of controlled trials. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(8):2361-2368. doi:10.1519/JSC.0000000000001316</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher JR, MacIntosh BR. Running economy from a muscle energetics perspective. Front Physiol. 2017;8:433. doi:10.3389/fphys.2017.00433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willy RW, Davis IS. The effect of a hip-strengthening program on mechanics during running and during a single-leg squat. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2011;41(9):625-632. doi:10.2519/jospt.2011.3470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis IS, Futrell E. Gait retraining: altering the fingerprint of gait. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am. 2016;27(1):339-355. doi:10.1016/j.pmr.2015.09.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novacheck TF. The biomechanics of running. Gait Posture. 1998;7(1):77-95. doi:10.1016/S0966-6362(97)00038-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schache AG, Blanch PD, Dorn TW, Brown NA, Rosemond D, Pandy MG. Effect of running speed on lower limb joint kinetics. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1260-1271. doi:10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182084929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damasceno MV, Lima-Silva AE, Pasqua LA, et al. Effects of resistance training on neuromuscular characteristics and pacing during 10-km running time trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(7):1513-1522. doi:10.1007/s00421-015-3130-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes PR, Bowen SJ, Davies EJ. The relationships between local muscular endurance and kinematic changes during a run to exhaustion at vVO2max. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(4):898-903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas E, De Bie J, Vanfleteren R, Hoogkamer W, Vanwanseele B. Novice runners show greater changes in kinematics with fatigue compared with competitive runners. Sports Biomech. 2018;17(3):350-360. doi:10.1080/14763141.2017.1347193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodson-Tole E, Lai A. Ultrasound-derived changes in thickness of human ankle plantar flexor muscles during walking and running are not homogeneous along the muscle mid-belly region. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):1-11. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-51510-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald KA, Honert EC, Cook OS, Zelik KE. Unholey shoes: experimental considerations when estimating ankle joint complex power during walking and running. J Biomech. 2019;92:61-66. doi:10.1016/j.jbiomech.2019.05.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judson LJ, Churchill SM, Barnes A, Stone JA, Brookes IG, Wheat J. Horizontal force production and multi-segment foot kinematics during the acceleration phase of bend sprinting. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29(10):1563-1571. doi:10.1111/sms.13486</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>