<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38500043</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2318</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC geriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Geriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of oral oligopeptide preparation and exercise intervention in older people with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>260</StartPage><MedlinePgn>260</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">260</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12877-024-04860-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Nutrition and exercise are important interventions for sarcopenia. There were few studies on oral oligopeptide nutrition preparations combined with exercise to intervene in the older people with sarcopenia. The aim of this study was to verify the effectiveness of oligopeptide nutrition preparation combined with exercise intervention on the older people with sarcopenia in community.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 219 subjects aged 65 years or older with sarcopenia were randomly divided into 4 groups. The nutrition group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;58) was given individualized nutrition education and oral oligopeptide nutrition preparation. The exercise group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;50) received exercise intervention. The combined group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;52) received both oral nutrition preparation and exercise interventions. The control group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;59) only received individualized nutrition education. The nutrition preparation can provide energy 185kcal and protein 24.2g per day. The exercise intervention including warm-up exercise, resistance exercise and aerobic exercise, the training time was 60min for 5 times every week. The intervention lasted for 16&#xa0;weeks. Hand grip strength, gait speed, body composition and hematology parameters were measured before and after intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 159 subjects completed the study. Compared with baseline, the left grip strength and 6-m walking speed of the subjects in nutrition group increased significantly after the intervention, and the grip strength of both hands in exercise group and combined group increased significantly. The body weight of the subjects in nutrition group, exercise group and combined group increased significantly after intervention, but no increase in soft lean mass (SLM) and skeletal muscle mass (SMM) was observed in any of the four groups. The fat-free mass (FFM) of the legs of the control group, exercise group and nutrition group decreased after intervention, and only the FFM of the legs of the combined group maintained the level before the intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Both oral peptide nutrition and exercise interventions can improve the muscle strength or function of the older people with sarcopenia. However, there were no increases in muscle mass observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">ChiCTR, ChiCTR2100052135. Registered 20 October 2021, https://www.chictr.org.cn/showproj.html?proj=135743.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Xinyi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Nutrition, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan Province, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatrics, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Daomei</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Chengdu Medical College, Sichuan Province, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jingjing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Nutrition, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan Province, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhengxing Community Health Service Center of Tianfu New District, Sichuan Province, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Suqiong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shibantan Community Health Service Center of Xindu District, Sichuan Province, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jing</LastName><ForeName>Xiaofan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Nutrition, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan Province, Chengdu, China. stephy1024@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Nutrition, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan Province, Chengdu, China. 271927115@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ChiCTR</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>2100052135</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Z20191013</GrantID><Agency>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatrics, West China Hospital, Sichuan University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Z20191013</GrantID><Agency>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatrics, West China Hospital, Sichuan University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Z20191013</GrantID><Agency>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatrics, West China Hospital, Sichuan University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CNS-FF2019A23</GrantID><Agency>Chinese Nutrition Society</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CNS-FF2019A23</GrantID><Agency>Chinese Nutrition Society</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Geriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968548</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2318</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009842">Oligopeptides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009842" MajorTopicYN="N">Oligopeptides</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older people</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Peptide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38500043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10946144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-024-04860-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12877-024-04860-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen L-K, Liu L-K, Woo J, Assantachai P, Auyeung T-W, Bahyah KS, Chou M-Y, Chen L-Y, Hsu P-S, Krairit O, et al. Sarcopenia in Asia: Consensus Report of the Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2014;15(2):95&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24461239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L-K, Woo J, Assantachai P, Auyeung T-W, Chou M-Y, Iijima K, Jang HC, Kang L, Kim M, Kim S, et al. Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia: 2019 Consensus Update on Sarcopenia Diagnosis and Treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21(3):300&#x2013;307.e302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Li WY, Ho M, Chau PH. The Prevalence of Sarcopenia in Chinese Older Adults: Meta-Analysis and Meta-Regression. Nutrients. 2021;13(5):1441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu S, Umapathysivam K, Visvanathan R. Sarcopenia in older people. Int J Evid Based Healthc. 2014;12(4):227&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25478672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juan L, Qingqing D, Baiyu Z, Xiang L, Jingmin L, Yongming L, Guoxian D, Cuntai Z, Jianye W, Pulin Y. Chinese expert consensus on diagnosis and treatment for elderly with sarcopenia(2021) J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13(3):1653&#x2013;1672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang L, Gao Y, Liu X, Liang Y, Chen Y, Liang Y, Zhang L, Chen W, Pang H, Peng L-N. Effects of whey protein nutritional supplement on muscle function among community-dwelling frail older people: A multicenter study in China. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2019;83:7&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30921603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morteza T, Irandoust K, Moddaberi S. The effects of weight-bearing exercise on postural control and fatigue index of elderly males. Int Arch Health Sci. 2019;6(4):122&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizia S, Cristiellem R, Lucas G, Rodrigo V, Douglas S, Claudio L, Marilia A, Beat K, Pantelis N, Meiry O, et al. Motivation for Brazilian older adult women to join a community physical activity program before COVID-19 pandemic. Int J Sport Studies Health. 2022;5(1):e128560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok TC, Bai X, Li JC, Ho FK, Lee TM. Effectiveness of cognitive training in Chinese older people with subjective cognitive complaints: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2013;28:208&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22528470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshimura Y, Wakabayashi H, Yamada M, Kim H, Harada A, Arai H. Interventions for Treating Sarcopenia: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Studies. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2017;18(6):553.e551&#x2013;553.e516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28549707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negm AM, Lee J, Hamidian R, Jones CA, Khadaroo RG. Management of Sarcopenia: A Network Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2022;23(5):707&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35183490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, He Y, Jin N, Li H, Liu X. Effects of protein supplementation and exercise on delaying sarcopenia in healthy older individuals in Asian and non-Asian countries: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Food Chem X. 2022;13:100210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8808080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H, Wang Z, Wu J, Liu Y, Zheng J, Xiao W, He P, Zhou Y, Wang J, Yu P, et al. Chinese expert consensus on prevention and intervention for elderly with sarcopenia (2023) Aging Med (Milton) 2023;6(2):104&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10242264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37287669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloom I, Shand C, Cooper C, Robinson S, Baird J. Diet Quality and Sarcopenia in Older Adults: A Systematic Review. Nutrients. 2018;10(3):308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5872726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29510572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessier A-J, Chevalier S. An Update on Protein, Leucine, Omega-3 Fatty Acids, and Vitamin D in the Prevention and Treatment of Sarcopenia and Functional Decline. Nutrients. 2018;10(8):1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6116139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30115829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho-Junior HJ, Calvani R, Azzolino D, Picca A, Tosato M, Landi F, Cesari M, Marzetti E. Protein Intake and Sarcopenia in Older Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(14):8718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9320473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35886571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smeuninx B, Greig CA, Breen L. Amount, Source and Pattern of Dietary Protein Intake Across the Adult Lifespan: A Cross-Sectional Study. Front Nutr. 2020;7:25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32232047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutz NE, Wolfe RR. Is there a maximal anabolic response to protein intake with a meal? Clin Nutr. 2013;32(2):309&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3595342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23260197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo Y, Liu C, Ji Z, Yang R, An Q, Zhang X, You J, Duan D, Sun Y, Zhu Y, et al. A high whey protein, vitamin D and E supplement preserves muscle mass, strength, and quality of life in sarcopenic older adults: A double-blind randomized controlled trial. Clin Nutr. 2019;38(1):159&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29395372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanach NI, McCullough F, Avery A. The impact of dairy protein intake on muscle mass, muscle strength, and physical performance in middle-aged to older adults with or without existing sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Adv Nutr. 2019;10(1):59&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30624580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W, Kohl M, Jakob F, Engelke K, von Stengel S. Effects of high intensity dynamic resistance exercise and whey protein supplements on Osteosarcopenia in older men with low bone and muscle mass final results of the randomized controlled frost study. Nutrients. 2020;12(8):2341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7468852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32764397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C-D, Liao Y-H, Liou T-H, Hsieh C-Y, Kuo Y-C, Chen H-C. Effects of protein-rich nutritional composition supplementation on sarcopenia indices and physical activity during resistance exercise training in older women with knee Osteoarthritis. Nutrients. 2021;13(8):2487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8399515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson MI, Mikhail A, Lan L, Di Carlo A, Hamilton B, Barnard K, Hettinga BP, Hatcher E, Tarnopolsky MG, Nederveen JP, et al. A five-ingredient nutritional supplement and home-based resistance exercise improve lean mass and strength in free-living elderly. Nutrients. 2020;12(8):2391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7468764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32785021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C-D, Chen H-C, Huang S-W, Liou T-H. The role of muscle mass gain following protein supplementation plus exercise therapy in older adults with sarcopenia and frailty risks: A systematic review and meta-regression analysis of randomized trials. Nutrients. 2019;11(8):1713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31349606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, Boirie Y, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Cederholm T, Cooper C, Landi F, Rolland Y, Sayer AA, et al. Sarcopenia: Revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48(1):16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabuco H, Tomeleri C, Sugihara Junior P, Fernandes R, Cavalcante E, Antunes M, Ribeiro A, Teixeira D, Silva A, Sardinha L, et al. Effects of whey protein supplementation pre- or post-resistance training on muscle mass, muscular strength, and functional capacity in pre-conditioned older women: a randomized clinical trial. Nutrients. 2018;10(5):563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5986443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29751507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Arnau FM, Fonfr&#xed;a-Vivas R, Buigues C, Castillo Y, Molina P, Hoogland AJ, van Doesburg F, Pruimboom L, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Garrido J, Cauli O. Effects of Leucine administration in Sarcopenia: a randomized and placebo-controlled clinical trial. Nutrients. 2020;12(4):932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7230494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32230954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caballero-Garc&#xed;a A, Pascual-Fern&#xe1;ndez J, Noriega-Gonz&#xe1;lez DC, Bello HJ, Pons-Biescas A, Roche E, C&#xf3;rdova-Mart&#xed;nez A. L-Citrulline Supplementation and Exercise in the Management of Sarcopenia. Nutrients. 2021;13(9):3133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8465698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34579009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi M, Kim H, Bae J. Does the combination of resistance training and a nutritional intervention have a synergic effect on muscle mass, strength, and physical function in older adults? A systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2021;21(1):639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8588667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu KJ, Liao CD, Tsai MW, Chen CN. Effects of exercise and nutritional intervention on body composition, metabolic health, and physical performance in adults with Sarcopenic obesity: a meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2019;11(9):2163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31505890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu P-Y, Huang K-S, Chen K-M, Chou C-P, Tu Y-K. Exercise, nutrition, and combined exercise and nutrition in older adults with Sarcopenia: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Maturitas. 2021;145:38&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33541561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudart C, Dawson A, Shaw SC, Harvey NC, Kanis JA, Binkley N, Reginster JY, Chapurlat R, Chan DC, Bruy&#xe8;re O, et al. Nutrition and physical activity in the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia: systematic review. Osteoporos Int. 2017;28(6):1817&#x2013;1833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5457808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yan J, Zhou Z, Guo J, Wei Y, Jing X, Liao X, Hu W. Effect of corn oligopeptide on dexamethasone-induced muscle atrophy. West Chin Med J. 2023;38(3):429&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaiping C, Mingliang L, Jing L, Miao X, Ke L, Jiuming Y, et al. Effects of wheat oligopeptides and its combination with soybean oligopeptides and pea oligopeptides on protein expression in C2C12 skeletal muscle cells stimulated by TNF-&#x3b1; in vitro. Food and Fermentation Industries. 2023;50(02):153&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdzieblik D, Oesser S, Baumstark MW, Gollhofer A, Konig D. Collagen peptide supplementation in combination with resistance training improves body composition and increases muscle strength in elderly sarcopenic men: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Nutr. 2015;114(8):1237&#x2013;1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26353786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pao YC, Chen CY, Chang CI, Chen CY, Tsai JS. Self-reported exhaustion, physical activity, and grip strength predict frailty transitions in older outpatients with chronic diseases. Medicine (Baltimore) 2018;97(23):e10933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5999477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29879035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung CHC, Au Yeung SL, Fong SSM, Schooling CM. Lean mass, grip strength and risk of type 2 diabetes: a bi-directional Mendelian randomisation study. Diabetologia. 2019;62(5):789&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30798333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parra-Soto S, Pell JP, Celis-Morales C, Ho FK. Absolute and relative grip strength as predictors of cancer: prospective cohort study of 445552 participants in UK Biobank. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13(1):325&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34953058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon JH, Kim YJ, Oh YH, Kong MH, Kim HJ. Association between Colorectal Adenoma and Hand Grip Strength in the Elderly. J Bone Metab. 2019;26(3):161&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6746666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31555613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern&#xe4;ng O, Reynolds CA, Finkel D, Ernsth-Bravell M, Pedersen NL, Dahl Aslan AK. Grip strength and cognitive abilities: associations in old Age. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2016;71(5):841&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6433432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25787083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua KY, Lim WS, Lin X, Yuan JM, Koh WP. Handgrip strength and timed Up-and-Go (TUG) test are predictors of short-term mortality among elderly in a population-based cohort in Singapore. J Nutr Health Aging. 2020;24(4):371&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32242204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheerman K, Meskers CGM, Verlaan S, Maier AB. Sarcopenia, Low Handgrip Strength, and Low Absolute Muscle Mass Predict Long-Term Mortality in Older Hospitalized Patients: An Observational Inception Cohort Study. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2021;22(4):816&#x2013;820.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33453174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granic A, Davies K, Jagger C, Dodds RM, Kirkwood TBL, Sayer AA. Initial level and rate of change in grip strength predict all-cause mortality in very old adults. Age Ageing. 2017;46(6):970&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5860048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28541466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck Jepsen D, Robinson K, Ogliari G, Montero-Odasso M, Kamkar N, Ryg J, Freiberger E, Masud T. Predicting falls in older adults: an umbrella review of instruments assessing gait, balance, and functional mobility. BMC Geriatr. 2022;22(1):615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35879666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marengoni A, Bandinelli S, Maietti E, Guralnik J, Zuliani G, Ferrucci L, Volpato S. Combining Gait speed and recall memory to predict survival in late life: population-based study. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2017;65(3):614&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5682559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28029688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders JB, Bremmer MA, Comijs HC, van de Ven PM, Deeg DJH, Beekman ATF. Gait Speed and Processing Speed as Clinical Markers for Geriatric Health Outcomes. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2017;25(4):374&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28063852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CC, Shih MH, Chen CD, Yeh SL. Effects of adequate dietary protein with whey protein, leucine, and vitamin D supplementation on sarcopenia in older adults: An open-label, parallel-group study. Clin Nutr. 2021;40(3):1323&#x2013;1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32928579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo M-W, Jung S-W, Kim S-W, Lee J-M, Jung HC, Song J-K. Effects of 16 weeks of resistance training on muscle quality and muscle growth factors in older adult women with Sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(13):6762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34201810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuka Y, Yamada Y, Maeda A, Izumo T, Rogi T, Shibata H, Fukuda M, Arimitsu T, Miyamoto N, Hashimoto T. Effects of resistance training intensity on muscle quantity/quality in middle-aged and older people: a randomized controlled trial. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13(2):894&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8977953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35187867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Landi F, Schneider SM, Zuniga C, Arai H, Boirie Y, Chen LK, Fielding RA, Martin FC, Michel JP, et al. Prevalence of and interventions for sarcopenia in ageing adults a systematic review report of the international Sarcopenia initiative (EWGSOP and IWGS) Age Ageing. 2014;43(6):748&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4204661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25241753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Hai S, Cao L, Zhou J, Liu P, Dong BR. Estimation of prevalence of sarcopenia by using a new bioelectrical impedance analysis in Chinese community-dwelling elderly people. BMC Geriatr. 2016;16(1):216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5198494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28031025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurt RT, Ebbert JO, Croghan I, Nanda S, Schroeder DR, Teigen LM, Velapati SR, Mundi MS. The Comparison of segmental multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis and dual-Energy X-ray Absorptiometry for estimating fat free mass and percentage body fat in an ambulatory population. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2021;45(6):1231&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32794583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Mao L, Feng Y, Ainsworth BE, Liu Y, Chen N. Effects of different exercise training modes on muscle strength and physical performance in older people with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2021;21(1):708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu LY, Chan R, Kwok T, Cheng KC, Ha A, Woo J. Effects of exercise and nutrition supplementation in community-dwelling older Chinese people with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. Age Ageing. 2019;48(2):220&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>