<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35640016</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Low-Intensity Resistance Training Improves Flow-Mediated Dilation in Young Hispanic Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>298</StartPage><EndPage>304</EndPage><MedlinePgn>298-304</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004273</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brice&#xf1;o-Torres, JM, Carpio-Rivera, E, Solera-Herrera, A, Forsse, J, Grandjean, PW, and Moncada-Jim&#xe9;nez, J. Low-intensity resistance training improves flow-mediated dilation in young hispanic adults. J Strength Cond Res 37(2): 298-304, 2023-The purpose of this study was to compare the effects of 2 resistance exercise training (RET) intensities on brachial artery flow-mediated dilatation (FMD) in sedentary males. Thirty-four men (age = 20.6 &#xb1; 1.8 years, height = 171.3 &#xb1; 5.2 cm, body mass = 65.2 &#xb1; 10.6 kg, and DXA fat mass = 22.3 &#xb1; 7.4%) were randomly assigned to a control group (no exercise CTRL, n = 12), RET at 50% of 1 repetition maximum (1RM) (RET50%, n = 12), and RET at 80% 1RM (RET80%, n = 10). The RET program was performed twice per week for 8 weeks; subjects performed the same RET exercises at similar total workloads (1920 arbitrary units [AUs] for the RET80% and 1950 AUs for the RET50%). The FMD% was measured before and after 8 weeks by ultrasound. Mixed factorial analysis of variance (3 groups &#xd7; 2 measurements), effect size (ES), and 95% confidence intervals (95% CIs) were computed for FMD%. The level of significance was set at p &#x2264; 0.05. A significant increase ( p = 0.001) was found on post-test FMD% in RET50% (mean = 9.9 &#xb1; 3.7%, ES = 1.9, and 95% CIs = 2.8-0.9) compared with CTRL (mean = 5.7 &#xb1; 1.7%, ES = 0.2, and 95% CIs = -0.4 to 0.8), and there were no significant differences found between RET50% and RET80% and between RET80% and CTRL. Results support the concept of training specificity and provide preliminary evidence that lower resistance and higher repetition RET elicit greater short-term reduced endothelium dysfunction than higher intensity RET at similar training volume.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brice&#xf1;o-Torres</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, College of Education, University of Costa Rica, San Jos&#xe9;, Costa Rica.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carpio-Rivera</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, College of Education, University of Costa Rica, San Jos&#xe9;, Costa Rica.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solera-Herrera</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, College of Education, University of Costa Rica, San Jos&#xe9;, Costa Rica.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forsse</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation, Robbins College of Health and Human Sciences, Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grandjean</LastName><ForeName>Peter W</ForeName><Initials>PW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise Science, and Recreation Management, School of Applied Sciences, University of Mississippi, Oxford, Mississippi; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moncada-Jim&#xe9;nez</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9807-5163</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, College of Education, University of Costa Rica, San Jos&#xe9;, Costa Rica.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Movement Sciences Research Center (CIMOHU), School of Physical Education and Sports, College of Education, University of Costa Rica, San Jos&#xe9;, Costa Rica.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004106" MajorTopicYN="N">Dilatation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006630" MajorTopicYN="N">Hispanic or Latino</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35640016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202302000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashor AW, Lara J, Siervo M, Celis-Morales C, Mathers JC. Effects of exercise modalities on arterial stiffness and wave reflection: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS One 9: 1&#x2013;15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashor AW, Lara J, Siervo M, et al. Exercise modalities and endothelial function: A systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Med 45: 279&#x2013;296, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barquera S, Pedroza-Tob&#xed;as A, Medina C, et al. Global overview of the epidemiology of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. Arch Med Res 46: 328&#x2013;338, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer AM, Zinkevich N, Miller B, et al. Transition in the mechanism of flow-mediated dilation with aging and development of coronary artery disease. Basic Res Cardiol 1125: 1&#x2013;12, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeno FP, Farinha JB, Ramis TR, et al. Effects of a single session of high- and moderate-intensity resistance exercise on endothelial function of middle-aged sedentary men. Front Physiol 10: 1&#x2013;8, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowles DK, Laughlin MH. Mechanism of beneficial effects of physical activity on atherosclerosis and coronary heart disease. J Appl Physiol (1985) 111: 308&#x2013;310, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP, Beck DT, Braith RW. Progressive resistance training without volume increases does not alter arterial stiffness and aortic wave reflection. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 232: 1228&#x2013;1235, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP, Pierce GL, Howe KS, Mering MC, Braith RW. Effect of resistance training on arterial wave reflection and brachial artery reactivity in normotensive postmenopausal women. Eur J Appl Physiol 100: 403&#x2013;408, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Fagard RH, Coeckelberghs E, Vanhees L. Impact of resistance training on blood pressure and other cardiovascular risk factors: A meta-analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Hypertension 58: 950&#x2013;958, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early KS, Stewart A, Johannsen N, et al. The effects of exercise training on brachial artery flow-mediated dilation: A meta-analysis. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev 37: 77&#x2013;89, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al.; American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Dawson EA, Groenewoud HM, Jones H, Thijssen DH. Is flow-mediated dilation nitric oxide mediated?: A meta-analysis. Hypertens 63: 376&#x2013;382, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Jones H, Thijssen D, Cable NT, Atkinson G. Flow-mediated dilation and cardiovascular event prediction: Does nitric oxide matter? Hypertens 57: 363&#x2013;369, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV. Distribution theory for Glass's estimator of effect size and related estimators. J Educ Stat 6: 107&#x2013;128, 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howlett N, Trivedi D, Troop NA, Chater AM. Are physical activity interventions for healthy inactive adults effective in promoting behavior change and maintenance, and which behavior change techniques are effective? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Transl Behav Med 9: 147&#x2013;157, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaime SJ, Maharaj A, Alvarez-Alvarado S, Figueroa A. Impact of low-intensity resistance and whole-body vibration training on aortic hemodynamics and vascular function in postmenopausal women. Hypertens Res 42: 1979&#x2013;1988, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HR, Min KW, Ahn HJ, et al. Effects of aerobic exercise vs. resistance training on endothelial function in women with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Metab J 35: 364&#x2013;373, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Effects of low-intensity resistance training with slow lifting and lowering on vascular function. J Hum Hypertens 22: 509&#x2013;511, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Effects of muscle contraction timing during resistance training on vascular function. J Hum Hypertens 23: 470&#x2013;478, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Effect of low-intensity resistance training on arterial function. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 743&#x2013;748, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Low-intensity resistance training after high-intensity resistance training can prevent the increase of central arterial stiffness. Int J Sports Med 34: 385&#x2013;390, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Min S, Sakamaki-Sunaga M. Arterial compliance and stiffness following low-intensity resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 235&#x2013;241, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilla J, Leary E, Limberg JK. Identifying responders versus non-responders: Incorporation of controls is required for sound statistical inference. Exp Physiol 106: 375&#x2013;376, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan American Health Organization, World Health Organization. Socioeconomic indicators. In: Communicable Diseases and Health Analysis/Health Information and Analysis: Health Situation in the Americas: Basic Indicators 2017. World Health Organization (WHO), Geneva, 2017. p. 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen BA, Hastings B, Gottschall JS. Low load, high repetition resistance training program increases bone mineral density in untrained adults. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 57: 70&#x2013;76, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakobowchuk M, McGowan CL, de Groot PC, et al. Endothelial function of young healthy males following whole body resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 98: 2185&#x2013;2190, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos JS, Dalleck LC, Tjonna AE, Beetham KS, Coombes JS. The impact of high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training on vascular function: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 45: 679&#x2013;692, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo DI, Kim E, Fahs CA, et al. Reliability of the one-repetition maximum test based on muscle group and gender. J Sports Sci Med 11: 221&#x2013;225, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stensvold D, Tj&#xf8;nna AE, Skaug EA, et al. Strength training versus aerobic interval training to modify risk factors of metabolic syndrome. J Appl Physiol (1985) 108: 804&#x2013;810, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Monahan KD, Seals DR. Age-predicted maximal heart rate revisited. J Am Coll Cardiol 37: 153&#x2013;156, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thijssen DH, Black MA, Pyke KE, et al. Assessment of flow-mediated dilation in humans: A methodological and physiological guideline. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 300: H2&#x2013;H12, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widlansky ME, Gokce N, Keaney JF, Vita JA. The clinical implications of endothelial dysfunction. J Am Coll Cardiol 42: 1149&#x2013;1160, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodman RJ, Playford DA, Watts GF, et al. Improved analysis of brachial artery ultrasound using a novel edge-detection software system. J Appl Physiol (1985) 91: 929&#x2013;937, 2001.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>