<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38085621</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Minimal-Equipment Resistance Training and Blood Flow Restriction on Military-Relevant Performance Outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>55</StartPage><EndPage>65</EndPage><MedlinePgn>55-65</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004596</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cintineo, HP, Chandler, AJ, Mastrofini, GF, Lints, BS, McFadden, BA, and Arent, SM. Effects of minimal-equipment resistance training and blood flow restriction on military-relevant performance outcomes. J Strength Cond Res 38(1): 55-65, 2024-This study compared minimal-equipment resistance training (RT) with and without blood flow restriction (BFR) to traditional-equipment RT on performance and body composition changes over 6 weeks. Reserve officers' training corps cadets and midshipmen (N = 54, 40.7% female) were randomized into traditional-equipment RT (TRAD), minimal-equipment RT (MIN), or minimal-equipment RT with BFR (MIN + BFR). Performance and body composition were assessed pretraining and post-training, and measures of intensity and workload were evaluated throughout. Performance assessments included the army combat fitness test (ACFT), countermovement vertical jump, 3RM bench press, and V&#x307;O2max; body composition measures included body fat percentage, fat-free mass, and muscle and tendon thickness. All groups trained 4 days per week after a full-body routine. Data were analyzed by mixed-effects models (&#x3b1; = 0.05). Group-by-time interactions for 3RM deadlift and 3RM bench press (p &lt; 0.004) showed larger improvements for TRAD compared with MIN and MIN + BFR. Time main effects for all other performance variables, body fat percentage, fat-free mass, and muscle thickness (p &#x2264; 0.035) indicated improvements in all groups. A group-by-time interaction for blood lactate (p &lt; 0.001) and group main effects for heart rate (p &lt; 0.001) and workload variables (p &lt; 0.008) indicated higher intensity and workload for MIN and MIN + BFR compared with TRAD. A sex-by-time interaction for 3RM deadlift (p = 0.008) and sex-by-group-by-time interaction for 3RM bench press (p = 0.018) were also found. Minimal-equipment RT improved performance and body composition, although strength improvements were greater with traditional equipment. Minimal-equipment RT and minimal-equipment RT with BFR exhibited higher exertion levels than TRAD, although adaptations were similar. Overall, individuals can improve performance and body composition using portable, field-expedient RT equipment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cintineo</LastName><ForeName>Harry P</ForeName><Initials>HP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8707-1842</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, University of South Carolina, Columbia, South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandler</LastName><ForeName>Alexa J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mastrofini</LastName><ForeName>Gianna F</ForeName><Initials>GF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lints</LastName><ForeName>Blaine S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McFadden</LastName><ForeName>Bridget A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arent</LastName><ForeName>Shawn M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0647-0591</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05003778</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006439" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008889" MajorTopicYN="Y">Military Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38085621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202401000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arent SM, Senso M, Golem DL, McKeever KH. The effects of theaflavin-enriched black tea extract on muscle soreness, oxidative stress, inflammation, and endocrine responses to acute anaerobic interval training: A randomized, double-blind, crossover study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 7: 11, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker BM, Walker SC. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. J Stat Softw 67: 1 &#x2013;48, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Shachar M, L&#xfc;decke D, Makowski D. Estimation of effect size indices and standardized parameters. J Open Source Softw 5: 2815, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop P, Cureton K, Collins M. Sex difference in muscular strength in equally-trained men and women. Ergonomics 30: 675&#x2013;687, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornsen T, Wernbom M, Kirketeig A, et al. Type 1 muscle fiber hypertrophy after blood flow-restricted training in powerlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 288&#x2013;298, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Coleman DR, Horne S, Cannavan D. Anatomical predictors of maximum isometric and concentric knee extensor moment. Eur J Appl Physiol 105: 869&#x2013;878, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Administration of the Borg scales. In: Borg's Perceived Exertion and Pain Scales. , Borg G, ed. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 1998. pp. 44&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadegiani FA, Kater CE. Hormonal aspects of overtraining syndrome: A systematic review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 9: 14, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 50&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Kilduff LP, Beaven CM. Improving strength and power in trained athletes with 3 weeks of occlusion training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 9: 166&#x2013;172, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Perceptual and arterial occlusion responses to very low load blood flow restricted exercise performed to volitional failure. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 39: 29&#x2013;34, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early KS, Rockhill M, Bryan A, et al. Effect of blood flow restriction training on muscular performance, pain and vascular function. Int J Sports Phys Ther 15: 892&#x2013;900, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards S. Appendix A: List of heart rate formulas. In: Heart Rate Monitor Book. Edwards S, ed. San Francisco, CA: Polar Electro, Inc, 1993. pp. 153&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, et al. Muscular adaptations to fatiguing exercise with and without blood flow restriction. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 167&#x2013;176, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Lundberg TR, Alvarez-Alvarez L, de Paz JA. Muscle damage responses and adaptations to eccentric-overload resistance exercise in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 1075&#x2013;1084, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Hoffman JR, Townsend JR, et al. Intramuscular anabolic signaling and endocrine response following high volume and high intensity resistance exercise protocols in trained men. Physiol Rep 3: e12466, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronfeldt BM, Lindberg Nielsen J, Mieritz RM, Lund H, Aagaard P. Effect of blood-flow restricted vs heavy-load strength training on muscle strength: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports 30: 837&#x2013;848, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad M, Stylianides G, Djaoui L, Dellal A, Chamari K. Session-RPE method for training load monitoring: Validity, ecological usefulness, and influencing factors. Front Neurosci 11: 612, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harman E, Frykman P, Palmer C, et al. Effects of a Specifically Designed Physical Conditioning Program on the Load Carriage and Lifting Performance of Female Soldiers. Natick, MA: U.S. Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harman EA, Gutekunst DJ, Frykman PN, et al. Effects of two different eight-week training programs on military physical performance. J Strength Cond Res 22: 524&#x2013;534, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl RD, Chen TC, Nosaka K. Mechanisms and Mediators of the skeletal muscle repeated bout effect. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 45: 24&#x2013;33, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Ibanez J, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, et al. Differential effects of strength training leading to failure versus not to failure on hormonal responses, strength, and muscle power gains. J Appl Physiol 100: 1647&#x2013;1656, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapik JJ. The influence of physical fitness training on the manual material handling capability of women. Appl Ergon 28: 339&#x2013;345, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korkmaz E, Donmez G, Uzuner K, et al. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscle strength and architecture. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1396&#x2013;1403, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Mazzetti SA, Nindl BC, et al. Effect of resistance training on women's strength/power and occupational performances. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 1011&#x2013;1025, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EC, Fragala MS, Kavouras SA, et al. Biomarkers in sports and exercise: Tracking health, performance, and recovery in athletes. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2920&#x2013;2937, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenth R. emmeans: Estimated Marginal Means, Aka Least-Squares Means. R Package Version 1.4.7, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 361&#x2013;378, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino G, et al. Effects of exercise intensity and occlusion pressure after 12 weeks of resistance training with blood-flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 2471&#x2013;2480, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Balapur A, Thrower AD, Barnes JT, Pujol TJ. The perceptual responses to occluded exercise. Int J Sports Med 32: 181&#x2013;184, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Main L, Grove JR. A multi-component assessment model for monitoring training distress among athletes. Eur J Sport Sci 9: 195&#x2013;202, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Fleck SJ, Dickinson A, Kraemer WJ. Acute and chronic hormonal responses to resistance training designed to promote muscle hypertrophy. Can J Appl Physiol 24: 96&#x2013;107, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory MA, Gomez TD, Bernauer EM, Mole PA. Evaluation of a new air displacement plethysmograph for measuring human body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc 27: 1686&#x2013;1691, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFadden BA, Walker AJ, Bozzini BN, et al. Psychological and physiological changes in response to the cumulative demands of a women's Division I collegiate soccer season. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1373&#x2013;1382, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Loftin M, Abe T. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci 4: 217&#x2013;220, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol 10: 533, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce JR, Clark BC, Ploutz-Snyder LL, Kanaley JA. Growth hormone and muscle function responses to skeletal muscle ischemia. J Appl Physiol 101: 1588&#x2013;1595, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, de Freitas MC, Zanchi NE, Lira FS, Cholewa JM. The role of inflammation and immune cells in blood flow restriction training adaptation: A review. Front Physiol 9: 1376, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Triplett NT. Program design for resistance training. In: Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Haff GG, Triplett NT, eds. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Morita N, et al. Intramuscular metabolism during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol (1985) 106: 1119&#x2013;1124, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber C, Bellon C, Abbott H, Bingham GE. Roles of maximal strength and rate of force development in maximizing muscular power. Strength Cond J 38: 71&#x2013;78, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team RC. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DQ, Lumpp SA, Schreiber JA, Keith JA. Physical fitness profile of army ROTC cadets. J Strength Cond Res 18: 904&#x2013;907, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umbel JD, Hoffman RL, Dearth DJ, et al. Delayed-onset muscle soreness induced by low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 107: 687&#x2013;695, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 126: 30&#x2013;43, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker AJ, McFadden BA, Sanders DJ, et al. Workload, energy expenditure, and biomarker differences in Division I male and female soccer players. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49: 571, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki M, et al. Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 2525&#x2013;2533, 2011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>