<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29761054</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2167-8359</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>6</Volume><PubDate><Year>2018</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PeerJ</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Is high-intensity interval cycling feasible and more beneficial than continuous cycling for knee osteoarthritic patients? Results of a randomised control feasibility trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e4738</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e4738</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e4738</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.4738</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Knee osteoarthritis (OA) patients often suffer joint pain and stiffness, which contributes to negative changes in body composition, strength, physical performance (function), physical activity and health-related quality of life. To reduce these symptoms and side effects of knee OA, moderate-intensity continuous training (MICT) cycling is often recommended. While resistance training is considered the optimal form of training to improve sarcopenic outcomes, it imposes higher joint loads and requires supervision, either initially or continuously by trained exercise professionals. Therefore, this pilot study sought to gain some insight into the feasibility and potential benefits of high-intensity interval training (HIIT) cycling as an alternative exercise option to MICT cycling for individuals with knee OA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-seven middle-aged and older adults with knee OA were randomly allocated to either MICT or HIIT, with both programs involving four unsupervised home-based cycling sessions (&#x223c;25 min per session) each week for eight weeks. Feasibility was assessed by enrolment rate, withdrawal rate, exercise adherence and number of adverse effects. Efficacy was assessed by health-related quality of life (Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Osteoarthritis Index (WOMAC) and Lequesne index), physical function (Timed Up and Go (TUG), Sit to Stand (STS) and preferred gait speed) and body composition (body mass, BMI, body fat percentage and muscle mass).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-seven of the interested 50 potential participants (54%) enrolled in the study, with 17 of the 27 participants completing the trial (withdrawal rate of 37%); with the primary withdrawal reasons being unrelated injuries or illness or family related issues. Of the 17 participants who completed the trial, exercise adherence was very high (HIIT 94%; MICT 88%). While only three individuals (one in the MICT and two in the HIIT group) reported adverse events, a total of 28 adverse events were reported, with 24 of these attributed to one HIIT participant. Pre-post-test analyses indicated both groups significantly improved their WOMAC scores, with the HIIT group also significantly improving in the TUG and STS. The only significant between-group difference was observed in the TUG, whereby the HIIT group improved significantly more than the MICT group. No significant changes were observed in the Lequesne index, gait speed or body composition for either group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">An unsupervised home-based HIIT cycle program appears somewhat feasible for middle-aged and older adults with knee OA and may produce similar improvements in health-related quality of life but greater improvements in physical function than MICT. These results need to be confirmed in larger randomised controlled trials to better elucidate the potential for HIIT to improve outcomes for those with knee OA. Additional research needs to identify and modify the potential barriers affecting the initiation and adherence to home-based HIIT cycling exercise programs by individuals with knee OA.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keogh</LastName><ForeName>Justin W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9851-1068</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Medicine, Bond University, Gold Coast, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Potential Centre, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cluster for Health Improvement, Faculty of Science, Health, Education and Engineering, University of the Sunshine Coast, Sunshine Coast, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grigg</LastName><ForeName>Josephine</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Medicine, Bond University, Gold Coast, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vertullo</LastName><ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8447-8399</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences and Medicine, Bond University, Gold Coast, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Knee Research Australia, Gold Coast, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cycling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High intensity interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Home-based exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal conditions</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Justin W. Keogh is an Academic Editor for PeerJ.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29761054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5949056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.4738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">4738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aamot IL, Forbord SH, Gustad K, Lockra V, Stensen A, Berg AT, Dalen H, Karlsen T, Stoylen A. Home-based versus hospital-based high-intensity interval training in cardiac rehabilitation: a randomized study. European Journal of Preventive Cardiology. 2014;21(9):1070&#x2013;1078. doi: 10.1177/2047487313488299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2047487313488299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23613224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghadir A, Anwer S, Brism&#xe9;e J-M. The reliability and minimal detectable change of Timed Up and Go test in individuals with grade 1&#x2013;3 knee osteoarthritis. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders. 2015;16(1):174. doi: 10.1186/s12891-015-0637-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-015-0637-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4520098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26223312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkatan M, Baker JR, Machin DR, Park W, Akkari AS, Pasha EP, Tanaka H. Improved function and reduced pain after swimming and cycling training in patients with osteoarthritis. Journal of Rheumatology. 2016;43(3):666&#x2013;672. doi: 10.3899/jrheum.151110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.151110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26773104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez C, Ramirez-Campillo R, Ramirez-Velez R, Izquierdo M. Prevalence of non-responders for glucose control markers after 10 weeks of high-intensity interval training in adult women with higher and lower insulin resistance. Frontiers in Physiology. 2017;8:479. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2017.00479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5498508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28729841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthritis Foundation . Arthritis Foundation; [20 February 2015]. Your exercise solution&#x2014;biking.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellamy N. Pain assessment in osteoarthritis: experience with the WOMAC osteoarthritis index. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism. 1989;18(4 Suppl. 2):14&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1016/0049-0172(89)90010-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0049-0172(89)90010-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2786253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellamy N, Buchanan WW, Goldsmith CH, Campbell J, Stitt LW. Validation study of WOMAC: a health status instrument for measuring clinically important patient relevant outcomes to antirheumatic drug therapy in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip or knee. Journal of Rheumatology. 1988;15(12):1833&#x2013;1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3068365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossers WJR, Scherder EJA, Boersma F, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, van der Woude LHV, van Heuvelen MJG. Feasibility of a combined aerobic and strength training program and its effects on cognitive and physical function in institutionalized dementia patients. A pilot study. PLOS ONE. 2014;9(5):e97577. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0097577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0097577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4028210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24844772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C, Blair SN, Church TS, Earnest CP, Hagberg JM, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Jenkins NT, Karavirta L, Kraus WE, Leon AS, Rao DC, Sarzynski MA, Skinner JS, Slentz CA, Rankinen T. Adverse metabolic response to regular exercise: is it a rare or common occurrence? PLOS ONE. 2012;7(5):e37887. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0037887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0037887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3364277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22666405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutcher SH, Park Y, Dunn SL, Boutcher YN. The relationship between cardiac autonomic function and maximal oxygen uptake response to high-intensity intermittent-exercise training. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2013;31(9):1024&#x2013;1029. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2012.762984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.762984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23362808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema BS, Davies TB, Stewart M, Papalia S, Atlantis E. The feasibility and effectiveness of high-intensity boxing training versus moderate-intensity brisk walking in adults with abdominal obesity: a pilot study. BMC Sports Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation. 2015;7(1):3. doi: 10.1186/2052-1847-7-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2052-1847-7-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4429464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25973207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross M, Smith E, Hoy D, Nolte S, Ackerman I, Fransen M, Bridgett L, Williams S, Guillemin F, Hill CL, Laslett LL, Jones G, Cicuttini F, Osborne R, Vos T, Buchbinder R, Woolf A, March L. The global burden of hip and knee osteoarthritis: estimates from the Global Burden of Disease 2010 study. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases. 2014;73(7):1323&#x2013;1330. doi: 10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-204763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-204763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24553908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, Boirie Y, Cederholm T, Landi F, Martin FC, Michel JP, Rolland Y, Schneider SM, Topinkova E, Vandewoude M, Zamboni M. Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: report of the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in older people. Age and Ageing. 2010;39(4):412&#x2013;423. doi: 10.1093/ageing/afq034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afq034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunlop DD, Song J, Semanik PA, Chang RW, Sharma L, Bathon JM, Eaton CB, Hochberg MC, Jackson RD, Kwoh CK, Mysiw WJ, Nevitt MC, Hootman JM. Objective physical activity measurement in the osteoarthritis initiative: are guidelines being met? Arthritis &amp; Rheumatism. 2011;63(11):3372&#x2013;3382. doi: 10.1002/art.30562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.30562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3205278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21792835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldridge SM, Lancaster GA, Campbell MJ, Thabane L, Hopewell S, Coleman CL, Bond CM. Defining feasibility and pilot studies in preparation for randomised controlled trials: development of a conceptual framework. PLOS ONE. 2016;11(3):e0150205. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0150205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0150205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26978655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fien S, Henwood T, Climstein M, Keogh JWL. Feasibility and benefits of group-based exercise in residential aged care adults: a pilot study for the GrACE programme. PeerJ. 2016;4:e2018. doi: 10.7717/peerj.2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4878364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27231652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisken A, Keogh JWL, Waters D, Hing W. Perceived benefits, motives, and barriers to aqua-based exercise among older adults with and without osteoarthritis. Journal of Applied Gerontology. 2015;34(3):377&#x2013;396. doi: 10.1177/0733464812463431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0733464812463431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25765822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisken A, Waters D, Hing W, Keogh JWL. Perception and responses to different forms of aqua-based exercise among older adults with osteoarthritis. International Journal of Aquatic Research and Education. 2014;8(1):32&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1123/ijare.2013-0007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijare.2013-0007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flores RH, Hochberg MC. Definition and classification of osteoarthritis. In: Brandt KD, Dohert M, Lohmander LS, editors. Osteoarthritis. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 1988. pp. 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francois ME, Little JP. Effectiveness and safety of high-intensity interval training in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Spectrum. 2015;28(1):39&#x2013;44. doi: 10.2337/diaspect.28.1.39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diaspect.28.1.39</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4334091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25717277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fransen M, McConnell S, Harmer AR, Van der Esch M, Simic M, Bennell KL. Exercise for osteoarthritis of the knee. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2015;1:CD004376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10094004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25569281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill S, McBurney H. Reliability of performance-based measures in people awaiting joint replacement surgery of the hip or knee. Physiotherapy Research International. 2008;13(3):141&#x2013;152. doi: 10.1002/pri.411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18697226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall M, Boyer ER, Gillette JC, Mirka GA. Medial knee joint loading during stair ambulation and walking while carrying loads. Gait Posture. 2013;37(3):460&#x2013;462. doi: 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2012.08.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2012.08.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22963827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawker GA, Wright JG, Coyte PC, Williams JI, Harvey B, Glazier R, Badley EM. Differences between men and women in the rate of use of hip and knee arthroplasty. New England Journal of Medicine. 2000;342(14):1016&#x2013;1022. doi: 10.1056/nejm200004063421405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejm200004063421405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10749964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heino Brechter J, Powers CM. Patellofemoral stress during walking in persons with and without patellofemoral pain. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise. 2002;34(10):1582&#x2013;1593. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200210000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200210000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12370559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hootman JM, Macera CA, Ham SA, Helmick CG, Sniezek JE. Physical activity levels among the general US adult population and in adults with and without arthritis. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatism. 2003;49(1):129&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1002/art.10911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.10911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12579604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia D, Cai M, Xi Y, Du S, Tian Z. Interval exercise training increases LIF expression and prevents myocardial infarction-induced skeletal muscle atrophy in rats. Life Sciences. 2018;193:77&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1016/j.lfs.2017.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2017.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29223542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keogh JW, Grigg J, Vertullo CJ. Is home-based, high-intensity interval training cycling feasible and safe for patients with knee osteoarthritis: study protocol for a randomised pilot study? Orthopedic Journal of Sports Medicine. 2017;5(3):2325967117694334. doi: 10.1177/2325967117694334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2325967117694334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5400173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28451599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kressig RW, Beauchet O. Guidelines for clinical applications of spatio-temporal gait analysis in older adults. Aging Clinical and Experimental Research. 2006;18(2):174&#x2013;176. doi: 10.1007/bf03327437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf03327437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16702791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutzner I, Heinlein B, Graichen F, Bender A, Rohlmann A, Halder A, Beier A, Bergmann G. Loading of the knee joint during activities of daily living measured in vivo in five subjects. Journal of Biomechanics. 2010;43(11):2164&#x2013;2173. doi: 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2010.03.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2010.03.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20537336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutzner I, Heinlein B, Graichen F, Rohlmann A, Halder AM, Beier A, Bergmann G. Loading of the knee joint during ergometer cycling: telemetric in vivo data. Journal of Orthopaedic &amp; Sports Physical Therapy. 2012;42(12):1032&#x2013;1038. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2012.4001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.4001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23346556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landi F, Marzetti E, Martone AM, Bernabei R, Onder G. Exercise as a remedy for sarcopenia. Current Opinion in Clinical Nutrition &amp; Metabolic Care. 2014;17(1):25&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1097/MCO.0000000000000018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24310054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lequesne M. Indices of severity and disease activity for osteoarthritis. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism. 1991;20(6 Suppl. 2):48&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1016/0049-0172(91)90027-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0049-0172(91)90027-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1866630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lequesne MG. The algofunctional indices for hip and knee osteoarthritis. Journal of Rheumatology. 1997;24(4):779&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9101517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liou K, Ho S, Fildes J, Ooi SY. High intensity interval versus moderate intensity continuous training in patients with coronary artery disease: a meta-analysis of physiological and clinical parameters. Heart, Lung and Circulation. 2016;25(2):166&#x2013;174. doi: 10.1016/j.hlc.2015.06.828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hlc.2015.06.828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26375499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loew L, Brosseau L, Kenny GP, Durand-Bush N, Poitras S, De Angelis G, Wells GA. An evidence-based walking program among older people with knee osteoarthritis: the PEP (participant exercise preference) pilot randomized controlled trial. Clinical Rheumatology. 2017;36(7):1607&#x2013;1616. doi: 10.1007/s10067-017-3606-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-017-3606-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lord SR, Murray SM, Chapman K, Munro B, Tiedemann A. Sit-to-stand performance depends on sensation, speed, balance, and psychological status in addition to strength in older people. Journal of Gerontology Series A. 2002;57(8):M539&#x2013;M543. doi: 10.1093/gerona/57.8.m539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/57.8.m539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12145369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, Gibala MJ. Physiological adaptations to interval training and the role of exercise intensity. Journal of Physiology. 2017;595(9):2915&#x2013;2930. doi: 10.1113/jp273196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jp273196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27748956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangione KK, McCully K, Gloviak A, Lefebvre I, Hofmann M, Craik R. The effects of high-intensity and low-intensity cycle ergometry in older adults with knee osteoarthritis. Journal of Gerontology Series A. 1999;54(4):M184&#x2013;M190. doi: 10.1093/gerona/54.4.m184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/54.4.m184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10219009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsiadlo D, Richardson S. The timed &#x201c;Up &amp; Go&#x201d;: a test of basic functional mobility for frail elderly persons. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 1991;39(2):142&#x2013;148. doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.1991.tb01616.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.1991.tb01616.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1991946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers CM, Ho KY, Chen YJ, Souza RB, Farrokhi S. Patellofemoral joint stress during weight-bearing and non-weight-bearing quadriceps exercises. Journal of Orthopaedic &amp; Sports Physical Therapy. 2014;44(5):320&#x2013;327. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2014.4936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2014.4936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24673446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragini B, Aishwarya SR, Tamil Selvan M, Pillai A, Mariamichael A. Prediction of body fat using segmental body composition by bioelectrical impedance in the evaluation of obesity. Journal of Engineering and Applied Sciences. 2015;10(8):3627&#x2013;3634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos JS, Dalleck LC, Tjonna AE, Beetham KS, Coombes JS. The impact of high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training on vascular function: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Medicine. 2015;45(5):679&#x2013;692. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0321-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0321-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rewald S, Mesters I, Emans PJ, Arts JJ, Lenssen AF, de Bie RA. Aquatic circuit training including aqua-cycling in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a feasibility study. Journal of Rehabilitation Medicine. 2015;47(4):376&#x2013;381. doi: 10.2340/16501977-1937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-1937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25655490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rognmo O, Moholdt T, Bakken H, Hole T, Molstad P, Myhr NE, Grimsmo J, Wisloff U. Cardiovascular risk of high- versus moderate-intensity aerobic exercise in coronary heart disease patients. Circulation. 2012;126(12):1436&#x2013;1440. doi: 10.1161/circulationaha.112.123117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.112.123117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosano C, Aizenstein H, Brach J, Longenberger A, Studenski S, Newman AB. Gait measures indicate underlying focal gray matter atrophy in the brain of older adults. Journals of Gerontology Series A. 2008;63(12):1380&#x2013;1388. doi: 10.1093/gerona/63.12.1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/63.12.1380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2648808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R. Sarcopenic obesity: does muscle loss cause fat gain? Lessons from rheumatoid arthritis and osteoarthritis. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences. 2000;904(1):553&#x2013;557. doi: 10.1111/j.1749-6632.2000.tb06515.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.2000.tb06515.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salacinski AJ, Krohn K, Lewis SF, Holland ML, Ireland K, Marchetti G. The effects of group cycling on gait and pain-related disability in individuals with mild-to-moderate knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Orthopaedic &amp; Sports Physical Therapy. 2012;42(12):985&#x2013;995. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2012.3813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.3813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22951360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstad J, Stensvold D, Hoff M, Nes BM, Arbo I, Bye A. The effects of high intensity interval training in women with rheumatic disease: a pilot study. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2015;115(10):2081&#x2013;2089. doi: 10.1007/s00421-015-3186-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3186-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26013051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senior HE, Henwood TR, Beller EM, Mitchell GK, Keogh JWL. Prevalence and risk factors of sarcopenia among adults living in nursing homes. Maturitas. 2015;82(4):418&#x2013;423. doi: 10.1016/j.maturitas.2015.08.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2015.08.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26341045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraev T, Barclay G. Evidence based exercise clinical benefits of high intensity interval training. Australian Family Physician. 2012;41(12):960&#x2013;962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23210120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka R, Ozawa J, Kito N, Moriyama H. Does exercise therapy improve the health-related quality of life of people with knee osteoarthritis? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Journal of Physical Therapy Science. 2015;27(10):3309&#x2013;3314. doi: 10.1589/jpts.27.3309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.27.3309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4668190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26644699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trehan SK, Wolff AL, Gibbons M, Hillstrom HJ, Daluiski A. The effect of simulated elbow contracture on temporal and distance gait parameters. Gait &amp; Posture. 2015;41(3):791&#x2013;794. doi: 10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.02.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25759282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tubach F, Ravaud P, Baron G, Falissard B, Logeart I, Bellamy N, Bombardier C, Felson D, Hochberg M, van der Heijde D, Dougados M. Evaluation of clinically relevant changes in patient reported outcomes in knee and hip osteoarthritis: the minimal clinically important improvement. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases. 2005;64(1):29&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1136/ard.2004.022905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2004.022905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1755212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15208174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthman OA, van der Windt DA, Jordan JL, Dziedzic KS, Healey EL, Peat GM, Foster NE. Exercise for lower limb osteoarthritis: systematic review incorporating trial sequential analysis and network meta-analysis. British Medical Journal. 2013;347:f5555. doi: 10.1136/bmj.f5555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.f5555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellsandt E, Golightly Y. Exercise in the management of knee and hip osteoarthritis. Current Opinion in Rheumatology. 2018;30(2):151&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29251659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshimura N, Muraki S, Oka H, Tanaka S, Kawaguchi H, Nakamura K, Akune T. Accumulation of metabolic risk factors such as overweight, hypertension, dyslipidaemia, and impaired glucose tolerance raises the risk of occurrence and progression of knee osteoarthritis: a 3-year follow-up of the ROAD study. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2012;20(11):1217&#x2013;1226. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2012.06.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2012.06.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>