<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">30365470</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cold-Water Immersion Has No Effect on Muscle Stiffness After Exercise-Induced Muscle Damage.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>533</StartPage><EndPage>538</EndPage><MedlinePgn>533-538</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000682</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To analyze the effect of cryotherapy on muscle stiffness after exercise-induced muscle damage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">A leg-to-leg comparison model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING">University research laboratory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS">Thirty (30) untrained men (21.1 &#xb1; 1.6 years, 177.6 &#xb1; 6.4 cm, 75.9 &#xb1; 10.0 kg, and 15.9 &#xb1; 2.9% fat mass) with no history of lower-limb injury and no experience in resistance training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTION">All participants underwent a plyometric exercise program to induce muscle damage; however, randomly, one leg was assigned to a treatment condition and subjected twice to cold-water immersion of the lower limb at 10&#xb0;C (&#xb1;1&#xb0;C) for 10 minutes, while the other leg was assigned to control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES MEASURES">Longitudinal stiffness and passive transverse stiffness were evaluated on the soleus and gastrocnemius muscles at 4 moments: pre-exercise, immediately after exercise, 24 hours, and 72 hours after the damage protocol. Furthermore, pressure pain threshold (PPT) and maximal voluntary isometric contraction (MVIC) were also assessed in the same periods.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">No significant differences between control and cryotherapy were observed in regard to MVIC (P = 0.529), passive longitudinal stiffness (P = 0.315), and passive transverse stiffness (P = 0.218). Only a significant decrease was observed in PPT on the soleus muscle in the cryotherapy compared with the control leg immediately after exercise (P = 0.040).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The results show that cryotherapy had no influence on muscle stiffness. However, cryotherapy had a positive effect on PPT immediately after exercise.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CESPU, Department of Physiotherapy, North Polytechnic Institute of Health, Paredes, Portugal; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocha</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CESPU, Department of Physiotherapy, North Polytechnic Institute of Health, Paredes, Portugal; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CESPU, Department of Physiotherapy, North Polytechnic Institute of Health, Paredes, Portugal; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CEMAH, Activity and Human Movement Study Center, Polytechnic Institute of Oporto, Oporto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017679" MajorTopicYN="N">Cryotherapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007101" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immersion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009129" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Tonus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="Y">injuries</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017288" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Threshold</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059385" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plyometric Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30365470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-202011000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Komi PV, Golhofer A. Stretch reflexes can have an important role in force enhancement during stretch-shorten cycle exercise. J Biomech. 1997;13:451&#x2013;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers C, Noakes TD, Lambert EV, et al. Time course of recovery of vertical jump height and heart rate versus running speed after a 90-km foot race. J Sports Sci. 1998;16:645&#x2013;651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB, Warren GL, Warren GA. Mechanisms of exercise-induced fibre injury. Sports Med. 1991;12:184&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friden J, Sjostrom M, Ekblom B. Myofibrillar damage following intense eccentric exercise in man. Int J Sports Med. 1983;4:170&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan DL, Proske U. Popping sarcomere hypothesis explains stretch-induced muscle damage. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2004;31:541&#x2013;545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friden J, Lieber RL. Eccentric exercise-induced injuries to contractile and cytoskeletal muscle fibre components. Acta Physiol Scand. 2001;171:321&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung K, Hume PA, Maxwell L. Delayed onset muscle soreness: treatment strategies and performance factors. Sports Med. 2003;33:145&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres R, Pinho F, Duarte J, et al. Effect of single bout versus repeated bouts of stretching on muscle recovery following eccentric exercise. J Sci Med Sport. 2013;16:583&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schleip R, Naylor I, Ursu D, et al. Passive muscle stiffness may be influenced by active contractility of intramuscular connective tissue. Med Hypotheses. 2006;66:66&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knudson D, Magnusson P, McHugh M. Current issues in flexibility fitness. Res Dig. 2000;3:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chino K, Takahashi H. Association of gastrocnemius muscle stiffness with passive ankle joint stiffness and sex- related difference in the joint stiffness. J Appl Biomech. 2017;15:1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aird L, Samuel D, Stokes M. Quadriceps muscle tone, elasticity and stiffness in older males: reliability and symmetry using the MyotonPRO. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2012;55:31&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algafly A, George K. The effect of cryotherapy on nerve conduction velocity, pain threshold and pain tolerance. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41:365&#x2013;369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB. Initial events in exercise-induce muscular injury. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1990;22:429&#x2013;435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren GL, Ingalls CP, Lowe DA, et al. What mechanisms contribute to the strength loss that occurs during and in the recovery from skeletal muscle injury? J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2002;32:58&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson MP, Gleichmann M, Cheng A. Mitochondria in neuroplasticity and neurological disorders. Neuron. 2008;60:748&#x2013;766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bieuzen F, Bleakley CM, Costello JT. Contrast water therapy and exercise induced muscle damage: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2013;8:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres R, Ribeiro F, Alberto Duarte J, et al. Evidence of the physiotherapeutic interventions used currently after exercise-induced muscle damage: systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Ther Sport. 2012;13:101&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eston R, Peters D. Effects of cold water immersion on the symptoms of exercise-induced muscle damage. J Sports Sci. 1999;17:231&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrick MA, Rankin JM, Andres FA, et al. A preliminary examination of cryotherapy and secondary injury in skeletal muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:1516&#x2013;1521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washington LL, Gibson SJ, Helme RD. Age-related differences in the endogenous analgesic response to repeated cold water immersion in human volunteers. Pain. 2000;89:89&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaile J, O'Hagan C, Stefanovic B, et al. Effect of cold water immersion on repeated cycling performance and limb blood flow. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:825&#x2013;829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcock IM, Cronin JB, Hing WA. Physiological response to water immersion: a method for sport recovery? Sports Med. 2006;36:747&#x2013;765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohenauer E, Taeymans J, Baeyens JP, et al. The effect of post-exercise cryotherapy on recovery characteristics: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2015;10:1&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakeman JR, Macrae R, Eston R. A single 10-min bout of cold-water immersion therapy after strenuous plyometric exercise has no beneficial effect on recovery from the symptoms of exercise-induced muscle damage. Ergonomics. 2009;52:456&#x2013;460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellwood KL, Brukner P, Williams D. Ice-water immersion and delayed-onset muscle soreness: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41:392&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum D, Tan F, Pang J, et al. Effects of intermittent sprint and plyometric training on endurance running performance. J Sport Health Sci. 2019;8:471&#x2013;477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muraoka T, Omuro K, Wakahara T, et al. Effects of muscle cooling on the stiffness of the human gastrocnemius muscle in vivo. Cells Tissues Organs. 2008;187:152&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustalampi S, Ylinen J, Kautiainen H, et al. Acute effects of cold pack on mechanical properties of the quadriceps muscle in healthy subjects. Phys Ther Sport. 2012;13:265&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP, Cosgrave CH. To stretch or not to stretch: the role of stretching in injury prevention and performance. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:169&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo deSC, Vicente RC, Cesario MD, et al. Cold-water immersion alters muscle recruitment and balance of basketball players during vertical jump landing. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:348&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G, Goodall S, van Someren KA. The influence of cold water immersions on adaptation following a single bout of damaging exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;105:615&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twist C, Eston R. The effects of exercise-induced muscle damage on maximal intensity intermittent exercise performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;94:652&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versey NG, Halson SL, Dawson BT. Water immersion recovery for athletes: effect on exercise performance and practical recommendations. Sports Med. 2013;43:1101&#x2013;1130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, et al. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10:361&#x2013;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wylde V, Palmer S, Learmonth ID, et al. Test&#x2013;retest reliability of quantitative sensory testing in knee osteoarthritis and healthy participants. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2011;19:655&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fryer G, Carub J, Mclver S. The effect of manipulation and mobilisation on pressure pain thresholds in the thoracic spine. Int J Osteopath Med. 2004;7:8&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aird L, Samuel D, Stokes M. Quadriceps muscle tone, elasticity and stiffness in older males: reliability and symmetry using the MyotonPRO. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2012;55:e31&#x2013;e39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregson W, Black M, Jones H, et al. Influence of cold water immersion on limb and cutaneous blood flow at rest. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39:1316&#x2013;1323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcock IM, Cronin JB, Hing WA. Water immersion: does it enhance recovery from exercise? J Sports Physiol Perform. 2006;1:95&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Point M, Guilhem G, Hug F, et al. Cryotherapy induces an increase in muscle stiffness. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;28:260&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall S, Howatson G. The effects of multiple cold water immersions on indices of muscle damage. J Sports Sci Med. 2008;7:235&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ascensao A, Leite M, Rebelo AN, et al. Effects of cold water immersion on the recovery of physical performance and muscle damage following a one-off soccer match. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:217&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey DM, Erith SJ, Griffin PJ, et al. Influence of cold-water immersion on indices of muscle damage following prolonged intermittent shuttle running. J Sports Sci. 2007;25:1163&#x2013;1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulick DT, Kimura IF, Sitler M, et al. Various treatment techniques on signs and symptoms of delayed onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train. 1996;31:145&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denegar CR, Perrin DH. Effect of transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation, cold, and a combination treatment on pain, decreased range of motion, and strength loss associated with delayed onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train. 1992;27:200&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Lievens P. The use of cryotherapy in sports injuries. Sports Med. 1986;3:398&#x2013;414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkpatrick DR, McEntire DM, Hambsch ZJ, et al. Therapeutic basis of clinical pain modulation. Clin Trans Sci. 2015;8:848&#x2013;856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melzack R, Wall P. Pain mechanisms: a new theory. Science. 1965;150:971&#x2013;978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill ND, Beaven CM, Cook C. Effectiveness of post-match recovery strategies in rugby players. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40:260&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janecki D, Jarocka E, Jaskolska A, et al. Muscle passive stiffness increases less after the second bout of eccentric exercise compared to the first bout. J Sci Med Sport. 2011;14:338&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaskolski A, Andrzejewska R, Marusiak J, et al. Similar response of agonist and antagonist muscles after eccentric exercise revealed by electromyography and mechanomyography. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2007;17:568&#x2013;577.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>