<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39021741</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research Hotspots and Trends of Interventions for Sarcopenic Obesity: A Bibliometric Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e64687</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e64687</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e64687</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.64687</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sarcopenic obesity, characterized by both obesity and sarcopenia, significantly impacts health and independence of affected individuals. There is an urgent need to explore effective strategies for addressing or preventing sarcopenic obesity. An initial critical step is to promptly assess the impact of academic research in this field, considering factors such as geographical regions, authors, journals, and institutions. It is also essential to analyze current trends and identify potential areas that may inspire future researchers to conduct further studies, ultimately improving public health outcomes for individuals with sarcopenic obesity. To achieve this, bibliometric research was conducted using the Web of Science Core Collection database to identify English language articles and reviews focusing on sarcopenic obesity interventions published between January 1, 2004, and June 15, 2024, followed by a literature review. A total of 929 English-language articles were collected, consisting of 645 research articles and 284 reviews. Research output in the field has shown significant growth since 2017, reaching a peak of 139 papers in 2022. The United States leads in publication output with 234 papers and a total of 13,971 citations, highlighting substantial international collaboration. Both the United States and Europe are recognized as key academic hubs for sarcopenic obesity intervention research, characterized by robust academic interactions. Moreover, there has been a notable increase in publication volume from China, South Korea, and Japan. Noteworthy authors in this field include Boirie Y from Universit&#xe9; Clermont Auvergne in France, Prado CM from the University of Alberta in Canada, Cruz-Jentoft AJ from Hospital Universitario Ramon y Cajal in Spain, and Prado CM from the University of Alberta, known for their high citation count. The University of Alberta leads in the number of publications, while the University of Verona in Italy leads in citation frequency. Journals with higher publication volumes in sarcopenic obesity intervention include Nutrients, Clinical Nutrition, and Journal of Cachexia Sarcopenia and Muscle. Among the top 20 keywords, the most relevant interventions for sarcopenic obesity are exercise, nutrition, resistance training, physical activity, and muscle strength.&#xa0;The primary evidence currently available suggests that resistance training is the most effective method for enhancing muscle strength in sarcopenic obesity patients. Additionally, combining protein supplementation with resistance exercise has shown encouraging results in reducing fat mass in these individuals. To progress in this field, it is crucial to foster collaboration among countries, regions, and academic institutions, promoting multidisciplinary partnerships.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Zhang et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ning</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, CHN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Jiarong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hemodialysis, Gansu Provincial People's Hospital, Lanzhou, CHN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, CHN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, CHN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bibliometric analyses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multimodal intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenic obesity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: This study was supported by the National High Level Hospital Clinical Research Funding (2022-PUMCH-B129). Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39021741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11252088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.64687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Association of low muscle mass index and sarcopenic obesity with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Wu Q, Xu Z, Ma X, et al. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2024;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11123550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38775452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity and sarcopenic obesity: definition, assessment, prevalence and mechanism. Lee DC, Shook RP, Drenowatz C, Blair SN. Future Sci OA. 2016;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5137918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28031974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of sarcopenic obesity and sarcopenic overweight in the general population: the lifelines cohort study. Wagenaar CA, Dekker LH, Navis GJ. Clin Nutr. 2021;40:4422&#x2013;4429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33485705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenic obesity: epidemiologic evidence, pathophysiology, and therapeutic perspectives. Koliaki C, Liatis S, Dalamaga M, Kokkinos A. Curr Obes Rep. 2019;8:458&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31654335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prevalence of low muscle mass associated with obesity in the USA. Murdock DJ, Wu N, Grimsby JS, et al. Skelet Muscle. 2022;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36539856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Associations between sarcopenic obesity and cognitive impairment in elderly Chinese community-dwelling individuals. Wang H, Hai S, Liu YX, et al. J Nutr Health Aging. 2019;23:14&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30569063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenic obesity in older adults: a clinical overview. Prado CM, Batsis JA, Donini LM, Gonzalez MC, Siervo M. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2024;20:261&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38321142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mapping knowledge landscapes and emerging trends of sarcopenic obesity in older adults: a bibliometric analysis from 2004 to 2023. Zhang N, Qu X, Zhou H, Kang L. Cureus. 2024;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11170931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38873392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The journal coverage of Web of Science, Scopus and Dimensions: a comparative analysis. Singh VK, Singh P, Karmakar M, Leta J, Mayr P. Scientometrics. 2021;126:5113&#x2013;5142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibliometric analysis: augmented reality-based physics laboratory with VOSviewer software. Putri CR, Soleh SM, Saregar A, Anugrah A, Endah N. J Phys Conf Ser. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibliometric analysis of tuberculosis molecular epidemiology based on CiteSpace. Zheng MQ, Li XX, Xu R, Liu S, Rui ZY, Guo ZY, Chen D. Front Public Health. 2022;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9723223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36483245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: Report of the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People. Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, et al. Age Ageing. 2010;39:412&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and clinical implications of sarcopenic obesity in patients with solid tumours of the respiratory and gastrointestinal tracts: a population-based study. Prado CM, Lieffers JR, McCargar LJ, Reiman T, Sawyer MB, Martin L, Baracos VE. Lancet Oncol. 2008;9:629&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18539529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ESPEN guidelines on definitions and terminology of clinical nutrition. Cederholm T, Barazzoni R, Austin P, et al. Clin Nutr. 2017;36:49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27642056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Age-related and disease-related muscle loss: the effect of diabetes, obesity, and other diseases. Kalyani RR, Corriere M, Ferrucci L. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2014;2:819&#x2013;829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4156923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24731660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenic obesity in older adults: aetiology, epidemiology and treatment strategies. Batsis JA, Villareal DT. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2018;14:513&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6241236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30065268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenic obesity: a new category of obesity in the elderly. Zamboni M, Mazzali G, Fantin F, Rossi A, Di Francesco V. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2008;18:388&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health consequences of obesity in the elderly: a review of four unresolved questions. Zamboni M, Mazzali G, Zoico E, et al. Int J Obes (Lond) 2005;29:1011&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15925957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenia exacerbates obesity-associated insulin resistance and dysglycemia: findings from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey III. Srikanthan P, Hevener AL, Karlamangla AS. PLOS One. 2010;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3279294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenia in older adults. Walston JD. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2012;24:623&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4066461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22955023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarcopenic obesity: a critical appraisal of the current evidence. Prado CM, Wells JC, Smith SR, Stephan BC, Siervo M. Clin Nutr. 2012;31:583&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22809635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lean tissue imaging: a new era for nutritional assessment and intervention. Prado CM, Heymsfield SB. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2014;38:940&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4361695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25239112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measuring adiposity in patients: the utility of body mass index (BMI), percent body fat, and leptin. Shah NR, Braverman ER. PLOS One. 2012;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3317663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22485140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerobic or resistance exercise, or both, in dieting obese older adults. Villareal DT, Aguirre L, Gurney AB, et al. N Engl J Med. 2017;376:1943&#x2013;1955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5552187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28514618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insulin resistance and sarcopenia: mechanistic links between common co-morbidities. Cleasby ME, Jamieson PM, Atherton PJ. J Endocrinol. 2016;229:67&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26931135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutrition, frailty, and sarcopenia. Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Kiesswetter E, Drey M, Sieber CC. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2017;29:43&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28155181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Definition and diagnostic criteria for sarcopenic obesity: ESPEN and EASO consensus statement. Donini LM, Busetto L, Bischoff SC, et al. Clin Nutr. 2022;41:990&#x2013;1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35227529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietary behaviour change intervention for managing sarcopenic obesity among community-dwelling older people: a pilot randomised controlled trial. Yin YH, Liu JY, V&#xe4;lim&#xe4;ki M. BMC Geriatr. 2023;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10521482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37752447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutritional and exercise interventions in individuals with sarcopenic obesity around retirement age: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eglseer D, Traxler M, Schoufour JD, et al. Nutr Rev. 2023;81:1077&#x2013;1090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10413430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36882046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of nutrition and exercise interventions on persons with sarcopenic obesity: an umbrella review of meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. Reiter L, Bauer S, Traxler M, et al. Curr Obes Rep. 2023;12:250&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10482763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37249818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weight loss, exercise, or both and physical function in obese older adults. Villareal DT, Chode S, Parimi N, et al. N Engl J Med. 2011;364:1218&#x2013;1229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3114602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21449785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of bariatric surgery on sarcopenic obesity outcomes: a one-year prospective study in middle-aged women. Rodrigues PS, Mendon&#xe7;a FM, Neves JS, et al. Obes Surg. 2024;34:1674&#x2013;1683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38523172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>