<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30557175</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of 2 Types of Resistance Training Models on Obese Adolescents' Body Composition, Cardiometabolic Risk, and Physical Fitness.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2672</StartPage><EndPage>2682</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2672-2682</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002877</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Magnani Branco, BH, Carvalho, IZ, Garcia de Oliveira, H, Fanhani, AP, Machado dos Santos, MC, Pestillo de Oliveira, L, Macente, SB, and Nelson, NJ. Effects of 2 types of resistance training models on obese adolescents' body composition, cardiometabolic risk, and physical fitness. J Strength Cond Res 34(9): 2672-2682, 2020-The main objective of this study was to investigate the effects of 2 types of resistance training (RT) models in conjunction with interdisciplinary interventions by other health professionals to reduce the body fat and cardiometabolic risk of obese adolescents while improving their general health-related physical fitness. The 12-week analyses involved 18 male adolescents who were split into 2 groups (weight lifting: n = 9 and functional: n = 9), with equalization according to the primary muscle group (whenever possible), the effort:pause ratio, and intensity. The results showed reductions in fat mass and body fat, as well as in waist and hip circumferences (p &lt; 0.05) after the intervention period. However, no significant differences were observed in terms of the body mass, body mass index, neck circumference, systolic and diastolic blood pressures, and for lean mass (p &gt; 0.05) after the respective period. Maximal isometric strength, abdominal strength resistance, flexibility, and maximal oxygen consumption all produced significant increases after the interventions (p &lt; 0.05). There were reductions in low-density lipoproteins and triglyceride levels after the intervention period (p &lt; 0.05). For fasting glycemia, high-density lipoproteins, and alanine aminotransferase, no differences were observed (p &gt; 0.05). In addition, no differences were observed in rating of perceived recovery, internal training load, or caloric intake (p &gt; 0.05). With the results presented, it is concluded that both RT methods were effective at reducing both fat mass and body fat, thus improving health-related physical fitness components and decreasing cardiometabolic risk.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Magnani Branco</LastName><ForeName>Braulio Henrique</ForeName><Initials>BH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Maringa (UniCesumar), Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Health Promotion, UniCesumar, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education, Physiotherapy, Sports, Nutrition and Performance Study Group (GEFFEND), UniCesumar, Parana, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle Zanquetta</ForeName><Initials>IZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Maringa (UniCesumar), Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education, Physiotherapy, Sports, Nutrition and Performance Study Group (GEFFEND), UniCesumar, Parana, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garcia de Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Humberto</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Maringa (UniCesumar), Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education, Physiotherapy, Sports, Nutrition and Performance Study Group (GEFFEND), UniCesumar, Parana, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fanhani</LastName><ForeName>Ana Paula</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Maringa (UniCesumar), Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education, Physiotherapy, Sports, Nutrition and Performance Study Group (GEFFEND), UniCesumar, Parana, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Machado Dos Santos</LastName><ForeName>Michelle Cardoso</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Maringa (UniCesumar), Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education, Physiotherapy, Sports, Nutrition and Performance Study Group (GEFFEND), UniCesumar, Parana, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pestillo de Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Maringa (UniCesumar), Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Health Promotion, UniCesumar, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macente Boni</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Maringa (UniCesumar), Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nardo</LastName><ForeName>Nelson</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Suffix>Junior</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State University of Maringa, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008055">Lipids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000082742" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Disease Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008055" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30557175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202009000-00032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andreato LV, Branco BHM, Esteves JV. Comment on: &#x201c;Effect of high-intensity interval training on total, abdominal and visceral fat mass: A meta-analysis&#x201d;. Sports Med 48: 1513&#x2013;1514, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA. Crescent pyramid and drop-set systems do not promote greater strength gains, muscle hypertrophy, and changes on muscle architecture compared with traditional resistance training in well-trained men. Eur J Appl Phsysiol 117: 359&#x2013;369, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antunes BMM, Monteiro PA, Silveira LS, Cayres SU, Silva CB, J&#xfa;nior IF. Effect of concurrent training on risk and hepatic steatosis in obese adolescents. Rev Paul Pediatr 31: 371&#x2013;376, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchini JAA, Da Silva DF, Hintze LJ, Antonini VDS, Lopera CA, McNeil J, et al. Obese adolescents who gained/maintained or lost weight had similar body composition and cardiometabolic risk factors following a multidisciplinary intervention. J Exerc Sci Fit 12: 38&#x2013;45, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchini JAA, Da Silva DF, Dada RF, Lopera CA, McNeil J, Nardo-Junior N. Improvements in self-reported and parent-proxy perceptions of adolescents' health-related quality of life following a multidisciplinary obesity treatment program. Sport Sci Health 13: 131&#x2013;137, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazil. Ministry of Sa&#xfa;de, Secretariat of Surveillance in Sa&#xfa;de, Vigitel Brasil, 2017: Surveillance of Risk Factors and Protection for Chronic Illnesses by Phone Inqu&#xe9;rito. Bras&#xed;lia: Ministry of Sa&#xfa;de, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell SC, Moffatt RJ, Kushnick MR. Continuous and intermittent walking alters HDL2-C and LCATa. Atherosclerosis 218: 524&#x2013;529, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carnier J, De Mello MT, Ackel-DElia C, Corgosinho FC, Campos RMS, Sanches PL, et al. Aerobic training (AT) is more effective than aerobic plus resistance training (AT + RT) to improve anorexigenic/orexigenic factors in obese adolescents. Appetite 69: 168&#x2013;173, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catapano AL, Graham I, De Backer G, Wiklund O, Chapman J, Drexel H, et al. 2016 ESC/EAS guidelines for the management of dyslipidaemias: The task force for the management of dyslipidaemias of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and European Atherosclerosis Society (EAS). Atherosclerosis 253: 282&#x2013;344, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The concepts of power analysis. In: Statistical Power Analysis for Behavioural Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erbaum, 1988. pp. 1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole TJ, Lobstein T. Extended international (IOTF) body mass index cut-offs for thinness, overweight and obesity. Pediatr Obes 7: 284&#x2013;294, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vreede PL, Samson MM, Meeterren NLU, Duursma SA, Verhaar HJJ. Functional-task exercise versus resistance strength exercise to improve daily function in older women: A randomized, controlled trial. J Am Geriatr Soc 53: 2&#x2013;10, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisberg RM, Marchioni DML, Colucci ACA. Avalia&#xe7;&#xe3;o do consumo alimentar e da ingest&#xe3;o de nutrientes na pr&#xe1;tica cl&#xed;nica. Arq Bras Endocrinol Metab 53: 617&#x2013;624, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, Gottschall L, Hrovatin LA, Parker S, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise testing. J Strength Cond Res 15: 109&#x2013;115, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Cerrillo-Urbina AJ, Herrera-Valenzuela T, Cristi-Montero C, Saavedra JM, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. Is high-intensity interval training more effective on improving cardiometabolic risk and aerobic capacity than other forms of exercise in overweight and obese youth? A meta-analysis. Obes Rev 6: 531&#x2013;540, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedes DP, Lopes CC, Guedes JERP. Reproducibility and validity of the International Physical Activity Questionnaire in adolescents. Rev Bras Med Esporte 11: 151&#x2013;158, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyward V. ASEP methods recommendation: Body composition assessment. J Exerc Physiol Online 4: 1&#x2013;12, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad M, Stylianides G, Djaoui L, Dellal A, Chamari K. Session-RPE method for training load monitoring: Validity, ecological usefulness, and influencing factors. Front Neurosci 11: 1&#x2013;14, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoor GAT, Plasqui G, Ruiter RAC, Kremers SPJ, Rutten GM, Schols AMWJ, et al. A new direction in psychology and health: Resistance exercise training for obese children and adolescents. Psychol Health 31: 1&#x2013;8, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebbe M, Damanhoury S, Browne N, Dyson MP, McHugh TLF, Ball GDC. Barriers to and enablers of healthy lifestyle behaviours in adolescents with obesity: A scoping review and stakeholder consultation. Obes Rev 18: 1439&#x2013;1453, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim WR, Flamm SL, Di Bisceglie AM, Henry CB. Serum activity of alanine aminotransferase (ALT) as an indicator of health and disease. Hepatology 47: 1363&#x2013;1370, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent CM, Green JM, Bishop PA, Sj&#xf6;kvist J, Schumacker RE, Richardson MT, et al. A practical approach to monitoring recovery: Development of a perceived recovery status scale. J Strength Cond Res 25: 620&#x2013;628, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeMura LM, Duvillard SPV, Andreacci J, Klebez JM, Chelland SR, Russo J. Lipid and lipoprotein profiles, cardiovascular fitness, body composition, and diet during and after resistance, aerobic and combination training in young women. Eur J Appl Physiol 82: 451&#x2013;458, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohne-Seiler H, Torstvet MK, Anderssen SM. Traditional versus functional strength training: Effects on muscle strength and power in the elderly. J Aging Phys Act 21: 51&#x2013;70, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopera CA, Da Silva DF, Bianchini JA, Locateli JC, Moreira AC, Dada RP, et al. Effect of water- versus land-based exercise training as a component of a multidisciplinary intervention program for overweight and obese adolescents. Physiol Behav 165: 365&#x2013;373, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machado AF, Baker JS, Figueira-Junior AJ, Bocalini DS. High-intensity interval training using whole-body exercises: Training recommendations and methodological overview. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 39: 378&#x2013;383, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackinnon DP, Elliot DL, Thoemmes F, Kuehl KS, Moe EL, Goldenberg L, et al. Long-term effects of a worksite health promotion program for firefighters. Am J Health Behav 6: 695&#x2013;706, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuo AR, Da Silva DF, Bianchini JAA, Hintze LJ, Antonini VDS, Lopera CA, et al. Differences between obese and severely obese adolescents in relation to the effects of a multidisciplinary intervention on hypertriglyceridemic waist phenotype. J Exerc Physiol Online 19: 68&#x2013;75, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morano M, Rutigliano I, Rago AMA, Pettoello-Mantovani M, Camanozzi A. A multicomponent, school-initiated obesity intervention to promote healthy lifestyles in children. Nutrition 32: 1075&#x2013;1080, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura FY, Moreira A, Aoki MS. Monitoring the load of training: the subjective perception of the effort of the session is a reliable method? R da Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica/UEM 21: 1&#x2013;11, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardo N Jr, Silva DAS, De Moraes GLF, Petroski EL, Pacheco RL, Martins PC, et al. Results from Brazil's 2016 report card on physical activity for children and youth. J Phys Act Health 13: S104&#x2013;S109, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardo-Junior N, Bianchini JAA, Da Silva DF, Ferraro ZM, Lopera CA, Antonini VDS. Building a response criterion for pediatric multidisciplinary obesity intervention success based on combined benefits. Eur J Pediatr 1: 1&#x2013;12, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordestgaard BG, Chapman J, Humphries SE, Ginsberg HN, Masana L, Descamps OS, et al. Familial hypercholesterolaemia is underdiagnosed and undertreated in the general population: Guidance for clinicians to prevent coronary heart disease: Consensus statement of the European Atherosclerosis Society. Eur Heart J 45: 3478&#x2013;3490, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ory MG, Smith ML, Mier N, Wernicke MM. The science of sustaining health behavior change: The health maintenance consortium. Am J Health Behav 6: 647&#x2013;659, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Moro T, Marcolin G, Neri M, Bianco A, Palma A, et al. High-intensity interval resistance training (HIRT) influences resting energy expenditure and respiratory ration in non-dieting individuals. J Transl Med 237: 1&#x2013;8, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt ML, Duncan BB, Silva GA, Menezes AM, Monteiro CA, Barreto SM, et al. New non-communicable diseases in Brazil: Current burden and challenges. Lancet 377: 1949&#x2013;1961, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seventh Brazilian directive on arterial hypertension. Arq Bras Cardiol 107: 01&#x2013;103, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Grigoletto ME, Brito CJ, Heredia JR. Functional training: Functional for what and for whom? Rev Bras Cineantropom Desempenho Hum 16: 714&#x2013;719, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva DFO, Lyra CO, Lima SCVC. Dietary patterns of adolescents and associations with cardiovascular risk factors: A systematic review [in Portuguese]. Ci&#xea;nc Sa&#xfa;de Coletiva 21: 1181&#x2013;1195, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater B, Philippi ST, Fisberg RM, Latorre MR. Validation of a semiquantitative adolescent food frequency questionnaire applied at a public school in S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil. Eur J Clin Nutr 57: 629&#x2013;635, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Xu D. Effects of aerobic exercise on lipids and Lipoproteins. Lipids Health Dis 16: 1&#x2013;8, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts K, Jones TW, Davis EA, Green D. Exercise training in obese children and adolescents: Current concepts. Sports Med 35: 375&#x2013;392, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willett WC, Lenart E. Reproducibility and Validity of Food-Frequency Questionnaires. Nutritional Epidemiology. New York, NY; Oxford, United Kingdom: Oxford University Press, 2012. pp. 96&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>