<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32826634</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Studies of Twin Responses to Understand Exercise Therapy (STRUETH): Body Composition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>58</StartPage><EndPage>67</EndPage><MedlinePgn>58-67</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002461</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">We studied individual variability in exercise responses in twins. We hypothesized that 1) endurance (END) training would reduce fat mass whereas resistance (RES) training would increase lean mass, 2) individuals who did not respond to one modality would respond to the other, and 3) cross-sectional heritability estimates would be higher than estimates based on training responses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">DXA was undertaken in 84 same-sex untrained twins (30 monozygotic [MZ], 12 dizygotic [DZ]). Participants underwent 3 months of END and RES training, separated by 3 months washout. Twins trained in pairs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">RES (P &lt; 0.001) and END (P = 0.002) increased lean mass, with a greater change in RES (P &lt; 0.001). Similarly, RES (P = 0.04) and END (P = 0.006) decreased fat mass. Eighty-four percent of subjects responded positively to RES for lean mass and 58% to END (P &lt; 0.001). For fat mass, RES and END induced 56% and 66% responder rates, respectively (P = 0.28). Cross-sectional intraclass correlations, used to assess the similarity in twin responses, were higher for MZ than DZ pairs for all variables. Following training, only MZ pairs were significantly correlated (P &lt; 0.001) for change in lean mass to RES.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">To our knowledge, this study is the first to report individual responsiveness in body composition to both RES and END in the same subjects. Although RES and END induced favorable changes in fat mass, RES was superior for lean mass. The frequency of lean mass responders to RES exceeded that for END, whereas response rates for fat mass were similar. Cross-sectional heritability estimates were higher than training response estimates, and shared environment had the largest influence on changes in body composition. This study suggests that exercise professionals should consider modality and environmental factors when optimizing exercise interventions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Hannah J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences, Exercise and Sport Science, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marsh</LastName><ForeName>Channa E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences, Exercise and Sport Science, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maslen</LastName><ForeName>Barbara A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences, Exercise and Sport Science, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scurrah</LastName><ForeName>Katrina J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Twins Research Australia, Centre for Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Melbourne School of Population and Global Health, The University of Melbourne, Victoria, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naylor</LastName><ForeName>Louise H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences, Exercise and Sport Science, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences, Exercise and Sport Science, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015502" MajorTopicYN="N">Absorptiometry, Photon</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050218" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Fat Distribution</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002149" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Intake</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004777" MajorTopicYN="N">Environment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014429" MajorTopicYN="Y">Twins, Dizygotic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014430" MajorTopicYN="Y">Twins, Monozygotic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202101000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;russe L, Rice T, Province MA, et al. Familial aggregation of amount and distribution of subcutaneous fat and their responses to exercise training in the HERITAGE family study. Obes Res . 2000;8(2):140&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Landi F, Schneider SM, et al. Prevalence of and interventions for sarcopenia in ageing adults: a systematic review. Report of the International Sarcopenia Initiative (EWGSOP and IWGS). Age Ageing . 2014;43(6):748&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley JE, Anker SD, von Haehling S. Prevalence, Incidence, and Clinical Impact of Sarcopenia: Facts, Numbers, and Epidemiology&#x2014;Update 2014 . Springer; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Maiorana AJ. Why exercise is an important component of risk reduction in obesity management. Med J Aust . 2012;196(3):165&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ. Is body mass index really the best measure of obesity in individuals? J Am Coll Cardiol . 2009;53(6):526&#x2013;526; author reply 528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Nyman K, et al. Body composition and fitness during strength and/or endurance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2008;40(5):950&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonafiglia JT, Rotundo MP, Whittall JP, Scribbans TD, Graham RB, Gurd BJ. Inter-individual variability in the adaptive responses to endurance and sprint interval training: a randomized crossover study. PloS One . 2016;11(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C, Rankinen T. Individual differences in response to regular physical activity. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2001;33(6 Suppl):S446&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hautala AJ, Kiviniemi AM, M&#xe4;kikallio TH, et al. Individual differences in the responses to endurance and resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2006;96(5):535&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner MJ, Lundby C. Concepts about V&#x2d9;O 2max and trainability are context dependent. Exerc Sport Sci Rev . 2018;46(3):138&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu FC, Lenchik L, Nicklas BJ, et al. Heritability of body composition measured by DXA in the diabetes heart study. Obes Res . 2005;13(2):312&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hind K, Oldroyd B, Truscott J. In vivo precision of the GE Lunar iDXA densitometer for the measurement of total body composition and fat distribution in adults. Eur J Clin Nutr . 2011;65(1):140&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arden NK, Spector TD. Genetic influences on muscle strength, lean body mass, and bone mineral density: a twin study. J Bone Miner Res . 1997;12(12):2076&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee I-M, Pate RR, et al. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2007;39(8):1423&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay MS, Warburton DE, Janssen I, et al. New Canadian physical activity guidelines. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2011;36(1):36&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Global Recommendations on Physical Activity for Health . World Health Organization; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh CE, Thomas HJ, Naylor LH, Scurrah KJ, Green DJ. Exploring human trainability: design and rationale of Studies of Twin Responses to Understand Exercise as a Therapy (STRUETH) study. Contemp Clin Trials Commun . 2020;19:100584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy K, Lam J, Cutler T, et al. Twins research Australia: a new paradigm for driving twin research. Twin Res Hum Genet . 2019;22:438&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maia JA, Thomis M, Beunen G. Genetic factors in physical activity levels: a twin study. Am J Prev Med . 2002;23(2 Suppl):87&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neale M, Cardon L. NATO ASI series D: Behavioural and Social Sciences, Vol. 67. Methodology for Genetic Studies of Twins and Families . New York (NY): Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-94-015-8018-2 ; 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson K, Norgate S. The equal environments assumption of classical twin studies may not hold. Br J Educ Psychol . 2005;75(3):339&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominicus A, Skrondal A, Gjessing HK, Pedersen NL, Palmgren J. Likelihood ratio tests in behavioral genetics: problems and solutions. Behav Genet . 2006;36(2):331&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C. Human Adaptability May Have a Genetic Basis. Health Risk Estimation, Risk Reduction and Health Promotion Proceedings of the 18th Annual Meeting of the Society of Prospective Medicine . Ottawa: Canadian Public Health Association; 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H. Exercise nonresponders: genetic curse, poor compliance, or improper prescription? Exerc Sport Sci Rev . 2018;46(3):137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Goodpaster BH, Koch LG, et al. Precision exercise medicine: understanding exercise response variability. Br J Sports Med . 2019;53(18):1141&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidsen PK, Gallagher IJ, Hartman JW, et al. High responders to resistance exercise training demonstrate differential regulation of skeletal muscle microRNA expression. J Appl Physiol . 2011;110(2):309&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, et al. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2005;37(6):964&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Petrella JK, Kim JS, Mayhew DL, Cross JM. Cluster analysis tests the importance of myogenic gene expression during myofiber hypertrophy in humans. J Appl Physiol . 2007;102(6):2232&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, de Lannoy L, Stotz PJ. Separate effects of intensity and amount of exercise on interindividual cardiorespiratory fitness response. Mayo Clin Proc . 2015;90(11):1506&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sisson SB, Katzmarzyk PT, Earnest CP, Bouchard C, Blair SN, Church TS. Volume of exercise and fitness non-response in sedentary, post-menopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2009;41(3):539&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houtkooper LB, Going SB, Sproul J, Blew RM, Lohman TG. Comparison of methods for assessing body-composition changes over 1 y in postmenopausal women. Am J Clin Nutr . 2000;72(2):401&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins ND, Stratton G, Cable NT, Tinken TM, Graves LE, Green DJ. Impact of exercise training on endothelial function and body composition in young people: a study of mono- and di-zygotic twins. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2012;112(2):421&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elks CE, den Hoed M, Zhao JH, et al. Variability in the heritability of body mass index: a systematic review and meta-regression. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) . 2012;3:29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luczak ED, Leinwand LA. Sex-based cardiac physiology. Annu Rev Physiol . 2009;71:1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>