<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32376815</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2093-758X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Korean Academy of Nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Korean Acad Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Effect of Resistance Exercise Program for Middle-Aged Women with Myofascial Pain Syndrome on Shoulder Pain, Angle of Shoulder Range of Motion, and Body Composition Randomized Controlled Trial, RCT].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>286</StartPage><EndPage>297</EndPage><MedlinePgn>286-297</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4040/jkan.2020.50.2.286</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to identify the effects of myofascial pain syndrome on shoulder pain, range of motion, and body composition around the shoulder in middle-aged women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 72 women participated in the randomized controlled trial. The subjects were grouped into an experimental group (n=39) and a control group (n=33). The experimental group received a resistance exercise program using an elastic band for 8 weeks, 3 days a week. The control group followed a normal daily for 8 weeks. Measurements were conducted three times; before the experimental treatment (pre-test), the 2nd and 8th weeks after treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Regarding the general characteristics and homogeneity of the dependent variables, there were no significant differences between the two groups, except for the thickness of the left and right muscles and the left fat. After treatment, shoulder pain was significantly different between the two groups (F=18.54, <i>p</i>&lt;.001) and the range of shoulder motion was significantly different (left, F=86.70, <i>p</i>&lt;.001; right, F=98.66, <i>p</i>&lt;.001). Furthermore, there were a significant differences in the thickness of muscles between the two groups (left, F=40.20, <i>p</i>&lt;.001; right, F=29.57, <i>p</i>&lt;.001); however, the thickness of fat was not significantly different.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The resistance exercise program reduces shoulder pain and improves the range of motion of the shoulder joint and increases muscle mass on around the shoulder. It suggests to conduct a study to confirm the long-term exercise effect.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Korean Society of Nursing Science.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>WonJong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5586-1762</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Eulji University, Daejeon, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hur</LastName><ForeName>Myung Haeng</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0523-8926</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Eulji University, Daejeon, Korea. mhhur@eulji.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>kor</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2018R1C1B5045374</GrantID><Acronym>NRF</Acronym><Agency>National Research Foundation of Korea</Agency><Country>Korea</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Korean Acad Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101488689</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2005-3673</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009209" MajorTopicYN="N">Myofascial Pain Syndromes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="N">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012782" MajorTopicYN="N">Shoulder</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020069" MajorTopicYN="N">Shoulder Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myofascial Pain Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Range of Motion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32376815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4040/jkan.2020.50.2.286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">50.286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Koh KB. In: Stress &amp; psychosomatic medicine. 2nd ed. Seoul: Ilchokak; 2011. pp. 1-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics Korea. Life tables for Korea, 2016 [Internet]. Daejeon: Statistics Korea; c2017 [cited 2017 Dec 5]. Available from: http://kostat.go.kr/portal/eng/pressReleases/8/6/index.board?bmode=read&amp;bSeq=&amp;aSeq=366185&amp;pageNo=1&amp;rowNum=10&amp;navCount=10&amp;currPg=&amp;searchInfo=&amp;sTarget=title&amp;sTxt=.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min ES. Relationship between stress, depression, and resilience of middle-aged women. Journal of the Korea Entertainment Industry Association 2017;11(4):199&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong WK, Lim YR. The effect of walking exercise frequency on the blood lipid, blood pressure, musculoskeletal pain, and health related quality of life in middle aged women. The Korea Journal of Sports Science 2018;27(3):1105&#x2013;1114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MI, Kim MS, Joo JH. In: Women's medicine encyclopedia. Seoul: S&amp;D; 2008. pp. 1-257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharan D. Myofascial pain syndrome: Diagnosis and management. Indian Journal of Rheumatology 2014;9 Suppl 2:S22&#x2013;S25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travell JG, Simons DG. In: Myofascial pain and dysfunction: The trigger point manual. Baltimore (MD): Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 1983. pp. 1-713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pott H, Baeumler P, Irnich D. Diagnosis of myofascial pain syndrome in chronic pain patients in daily clinical practice. Journal of Acupuncture and Meridian Studies 2018;11(4):259&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manolopoulos L, Vlastarakos PV, Georgiou L, Giotakis I, Loizos A, Nikolopoulos TP. Myofascial pain syndromes in the maxillofacial area: A common but underdiagnosed cause of head and neck pain. International Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery 2008;37(11):975&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18632254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernon H, Schneider M. Chiropractic management of myofascial trigger points and myofascial pain syndrome: A systematic review of the literature. Journal of Manipulative and Physiological Therapeutics 2009;32(1):14&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19121461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partanen JV, Ojala TA, Arokoski JP. Myofascial syndrome and pain: A neurophysiological approach. Pathophysiology 2010;17(1):19&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19500953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Hwang Bo Y, Hong ES, Ohn JH, Kim CH, Kim HW, et al. Investigation of sarcopenia and its association with cardiometabolic risk factors in elderly subjects. Journal of the Korean Geriatrics Society 2010;14(3):121&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley LV. In: Yoo JH, Park ES, Kim MG, Lee TJ, Kim SH, Lee SH, et al.Essentials of human disease. 1st Engl. Ed. Seoul: Fornursebook; c2013. pp. 1-549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisoli A Jr, Chaves PH, Ingham SJ, Fried LP. Severe osteopenia and osteoporosis, sarcopenia, and frailty status in community-dwelling older women: Results from the women's health and aging study (WHAS) II. Bone 2011;48(4):952&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Korean Geriatrics Society. Textbook of geriatric medicine. 3rd ed. Seoul: PanMun Education; 2015. pp. 1-868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dail NW, Agnew TA, Floyd RT. In: Lee WH, Kim BW, Kim HD, Park JH, Bae WS, Lee GC, et al.Kinesiology for manual therapies with muscle cards. 1st Engl. Ed. Seoul: Jungdam Media; c2013. pp. 1-539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Korean Society of Anesthesiologists. Anesthesiology and pain medicine. 3rd ed. Seoul: Ryo Moon Gak.P.Co,; c2014. pp. 1-1276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JL. Travell and Simons': Myofascial pain and dysfunction the trigger point manual, volume 1. Upper half of body, second edition. Regional Anesthesia and Pain Medicine. 1999;24(4):378&#x2013;379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons DG, Travell JG, Simons LS. In: Myofascial pain and dysfunction: The trigger point manual, vol 1. Upper half of body. 2nd ed. Baltimore (MD): Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 1998. pp. 11-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2006;101(2):531&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiidus PM. In: Lee JH, Kim JY, Park JH, Sung DJ, Song W, Lee HS, et al., editors. Skeletal muscle damage and repair. 1st Engl. Ed. Seoul: Life Science; c2015. pp. 1-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson A. In: Goo BO, Kim HS, Nam KW, Park MC, Sim JM, Jung SJ, et al.Effective management of musculoskeletal injury: Clinical ergonomics approach to prevention, treatment and rehabilitation. 1st Engl. Ed. Seoul: Hyunmoon; c2010. pp. 1-331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YG, Lim SK, Hong JG, Kim KH, Kim JG, Park JS, et al. In: Sports injury and rehabilitation. Seoul: Hanmibook; c2015. pp. 1-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SH. Effects of elastic-band exercise on physical fitness for activities of daily living, muscle mass and pain in elderly women. Journal of Coaching Development 2012;14(1):67&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D. Effects of rhythm exercise training on body composition and arterial compliance in elderly females. Journal of the Korea Academia-Industrial cooperation Society 2016;17(5):243&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son IH. In: The effect of 12 weeks elastic band and sports massage therapy on ROM and muscular endurance pain scale in patients with frozen shoulder [master's thesis]. Ulsan: University of Ulsan; 2013. pp. 1-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KH. Sample size calculations with dropouts in clinical trials. Communications for Statistical Applications and Methods 2008;15(3):353&#x2013;365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MW. Advances in pain research and therapy, volume 19. Deafferentation pain syndromes pathophysiology and treatment: Blaine S. Nashold, Jr. and Janice Ovelmen-Levitt, eds. 367 pages. $98.00. New York, NY: Raven Press, 1992. ISBN: 0-88167-823-6. Surgical Neurology 1993;39(5):409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JW, Kwon YJ, Jang TW, Lee JH, Kim IS, Ryu SC, et al. The effect of a stretching exercise on myofascial pain syndrome patients in small and medium sized industries. Korean Journal of Occupational and Environmental Medicine 2010;22(4):307&#x2013;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraishi Y. In: Chung HJ, Chung JP, Lee G, Lee KR, Bae SJ, Kim HJ, et al.The orthopaedic medicine. 1st Japanese. Ed. Seoul: Medianbooks Publication; c2017. pp. 1-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG, Murphy RE. Age related neural adaptation following short term resistance training in women. Journal of Sports Medicine and Physical Fitness 2001;41(3):291&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11533557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoch MC, Andreatta RD, Mullineaux DR, English RA, Medina McKeon JM, Mattacola CG, et al. Two-week joint mobilization intervention improves self-reported function, range of motion, and dynamic balance in those with chronic ankle instability. Journal of Orthopaedic Research 2012;30(11):1798&#x2013;1804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22610971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Eta-squared and partial eta-squared in fixed factor ANOVA designs. Educational and Psychological Measurement 1973;33(1):107&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim JO. Effects of resistance exercise using elastic band on range of motion, function and shoulder pain among patients with rotator cuff repair. Korean Journal of Adult Nursing 2016;28(5):491&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin HS, Lee KS. Effects of combined resistance exercise on range of motion (ROM), grip strength and pain in middle-aged women with shoulder disorder. The Korean Journal of Sports Science 2006;15(1):569&#x2013;577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D. Effects of Theraband exercise programs on strength, balance and proprioception in elderly. Journal of The Korean Society of Integrative Medicine 2014;2(4):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo HN, Kim YK, Kang MA, Shin JS. Effects of elastic band exercise on pain, range of motion, and fear of falling in patients with total knee replacement. Journal of Korean Clinical Nursing Research 2015;21(2):266&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila JJ, Gutierres JA, Sheehy ME, Lofgren IE, Delmonico MJ. Effect of moderate intensity resistance training during weight loss on body composition and physical performance in overweight older adults. European Journal of Applied Physiology 2010;109(3):517&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20169360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korean Society of Exercise Physiology. Exercise physiology. 2nd ed. Seoul: Hanmibook; 2014. pp. 1-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Progressive resistance strength training for improving physical function in older adults (2009). Australasian Journal on Ageing 2010;29(2):98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YJ, Yoon MN, Han SS. Effects of Thera-Band(R) resistance training including isometric exercise in total knee replacement patients. Korean Journal of Health Promotion 2011;11(2):82&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo DI, So WY, Chang HK. Low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction for improving the skeletal muscle. The Official Journal of the Korean Academy of Kinesiology 2012;14(3):37&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong JY, Oak JS. Effects of 12 weeks aerobic&#xb7;anaerobic combined exercise training on fitness, body composition, skeletal muscle index and blood lipid profiles in obese elderly women. The Korean Journal of Obesity 2013;22(1):30&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So WY, Song M, Cho BL, Park YH, Kim YS, Lim JY, et al. The effect of elastic band exercise training and detraining on body composition and fitness in the elderly. Journal of the Korean Gerontological Society 2009;29(4):1247&#x2013;1259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So WY, Jun TW, Seo DI, Chang H, Seo HK, Eom WS, et al. Effects of 12 weeks elastic band exercise on body composition, cardiorespiratory function and physical fitness of middle-aged obese women. The Korean Journal of Obesity 2008;17(3):132&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao Y, Bing C, Hunter L, Jenkins JR, Wabitsch M, Trayhurn P. Zinc-&#x3b1;2-glycoprotein,a lipid mobilizing factor, is expressed and secreted by human (SGBS) adipocytes. FEBSLetters 2005;579(1):41&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HS. Effects of low caroic diet plus exercise on visceral fat in obesity women. Exercise Science 2006;15(1):17&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HS, Chung SM, Cho JH, Choi HS. Effects of exercise program on body fat distribution for obese women. The Korean Journal of Sports Medicine 2001;19(2):260&#x2013;268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DH, Lee SH, An K, Moon JY, Kim SH, Choi YJ, et al. Effects of 6 weeks of lifestyle modification including combined exercise program on the risk of metabolic parameters and macrovascular complications in Type 2 diabetic patients. The Korean Journal of Obesity 2011;20(3):147&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HK, Lee YG, Lee BG, Lee KR, Kim KK, Kang HC, et al. Change of body composition in obese women with short-term low calory diets. Journal of the Korean Academy of Family Medicine 2004;25(1):21&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>