<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22050827</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-7075</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of 28 days of resistance exercise while consuming commercially available pre- and post-workout supplements, NO-Shotgun&#xae; and NO-Synthesize&#xae; on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of protein synthesis, and clinical safety markers in males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>78</StartPage><MedlinePgn>78</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1743-7075-8-78</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The effects of 28 days of heavy resistance training while ingesting the pre- and post-workout supplements, NO-Shotgun&#xae; and NO-Synthesize&#xae; were determined on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of protein synthesis, and clinical safety markers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nineteen non-resistance-trained males participated in a resistance training program 4 times/week for 28 days while either ingesting 27 g/day of carbohydrate (CARB) or NO-Shotgun&#xae; 30 min pre-exercise and 27 g/day of carbohydrate or NO- Synthesize&#xae; 30 min post-exercise (NOSS). Data were analyzed with separate 2 &#xd7; 2 ANOVA (p &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Total body mass was increased in both groups (p = 0.001), but not different between groups. Fat mass was unchanged with CARB, but NOSS decreased fat mass (p = 0.026). Both groups increased fat-free mass (p = 0.001); however, the increases were greater with NOSS (p = 0.023). NOSS underwent greater increases in upper-body (p = 0.023) and lower-body (p = 0.035) strength than CARB. Myofibrillar protein significantly increased in both groups (p = 0.041), with NOSS being greater than CARB (p = 0.049). All of the MHC isoforms were significantly increased in both groups; however, NOSS was greater than CARB for MHC 1 (p = 0.013) and MHC 2A (p = 0.046). All of the myogenic regulatory factors were significantly increased in both groups; however, NOSS was greater than CARB for Myo-D (p = 0.038) and MRF-4 (p = 0.001). For the whole blood and serum clinical chemistry markers, all variables remained within normal clinical ranges.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Heavy resistance training for 28 days, with NO-Shotgun&#xae; and NO-Synthesize&#xae; ingested before and after exercise, respectively, significantly improved body composition and increased muscle mass and performance without abnormally impacting any of the clinical chemistry markers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spillane</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance, and Recreation, Baylor University, Box 97313, Waco, TX76798, USA. darryn_willoughby@baylor.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwarz</LastName><ForeName>Neil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leddy</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Correa</LastName><ForeName>Tracie</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minter</LastName><ForeName>Melodie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longoria</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willoughby</LastName><ForeName>Darryn S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-7075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22050827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3226541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-8-78</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1743-7075-8-78</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rennie M, Wackerhage H, Spangenburg E, Booth F. Control of the size of the human muscle mass. Annu Rev Physiol. 2004;66:799&#x2013;828. doi: 10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caiozzo V, Haddad F, Baker M, Baldwin K. Influence of mechanical loading on myosin heavy-chain protein and mRNA isoform expression. J Appl Physiol. 1996;80:1503&#x2013;1512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8727533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos G, Luecke T, Wendeln H, Toma K, Hagerman F, Murray T, Ragg K, Ratamess N, Kraemer W, Staron R. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88:50&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstrom D, Penn B, Strand A, Perry R, Rudnicki M, Tapscott S. Promoter-specific regulation of MyoD binding and signal transduction cooperate to pattern gene expression. Mol Cell. 2002;9:587&#x2013;600. doi: 10.1016/S1097-2765(02)00481-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1097-2765(02)00481-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11931766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel S, Slade J, Mahoney E, Haddad F, Dudley G, Adams G. Time course of molecular responses of human skeletal muscle to acute bouts of resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98:482&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15465884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckingham M, Houzelstein D, Lyons G, Ontell M, Ott M, Sassoon D. Expression of muscle genes in the mouse embryo. Symp Soc Exp Biol. 1992;46:203&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1341037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Tranchina P, Rashti L, Kang J, Faigenbaum A. Effect of protein-supplement timing on strength, power, and body-composition changes in resistance-trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19:172&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke D, Chilibeck P, Davidson K, Candow D, Farthing J, Smith-Palmer T. The effect of whey protein supplementation with and without creatine monohydrate combined with resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscle strength. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2001;11:349&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11591884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagard P, Kadi F, Tufekovic G, Verney J, Olesen J, Suetta C, Kjaer M. Creatine supplementatin augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol. 2006;573:525&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2006.107359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2006.107359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin J, Goldman L, Puglisi M, Nickols-Richardson S, Earthman C, Gwazdauskas F. Effect of post-exercise supplement consumption on adaptations to resistance training. J Am Coll Nutr. 2004;23:322&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15310736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb P, Williams A, Hayes A. A creatine-protein-carbohydrate supplement enhances responses to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1960&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1249/mss.0b013e31814fb52a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e31814fb52a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17986903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck T, Housh T, Johnson G, Coburn J, Malek M, Cramer J. Effects of a drink containing creatine, amino acids, and protein combined with ten weeks of resistance training on body composition, strength, and anaerobic performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:100&#x2013;04.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D, Stout J, Wilborn C. Effects of resistance training and protein plus amino acid supplementation on muscle anabolism, mass, and strength. Amino Acids. 2007;32:467&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0398-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0398-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16988909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb P, Hayes A. Effects of supplement timing and resistance exercise on skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:1918&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelmadine B, Cooke M, Buford T, Hudson G, Redd L, Leutholtz B, Willoughby D. Effects of 28 days of resistance exercise and consuming a commercially available pre-workout supplement, NO-Shotgun, on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of satellite cell activation, and clinical safety markers in males. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;5:6&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff G, Lehmkuhl J, McCoy B, Stone H. Carbohydrate supplementation and resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:187&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beelen M, Tieland M, Gijsen A, Vandereyt H, Kies A, Kuipers H, Saris W, Koopman R, van Loon L. Coingestion of carbohydrate and protein hydrolysate stimulates muscle protein synthesis during exercise in young men, with no further increase during subsequent overnight recovery. J Nutr. 2008;138:2198&#x2013;204. doi: 10.3945/jn.108.092924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.108.092924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18936219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieillevoye S, Poortmans J, Duchateau J, Carpentier A. Effects of a combined essential amino acids/carbohydrate supplementation on muscle mass, architecture and maximal strength following heavy-load training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110:479&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1007/s00421-010-1520-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1520-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20521064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1674&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella J, Kim J, Cross J, Kosek D, Bamman M. Efficacy of myonuclear addition may explain differential myofiber growth among resistance-trained young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291:E937&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00190.2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00190.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall G, Byrnes W, Fleck S, Dickinson A, Kraemer W. Acute and chronic hormonal responses to resistance training designed to promote muscle hypertrophy. Can J Appl Physiol. 1999;24:96&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1139/h99-009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h99-009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheny R, Merritt E, Zannikos S, Farrar R, Adamo M. Serum IGF-I-deficiency does not prevent compensatory skeletal muscle hypertrophy in resistance exercise. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 2009;234:164&#x2013;70. doi: 10.3181/0808-RM-251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3181/0808-RM-251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19064939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek D, Kim J, Petrella J, Cross J, Bamman M. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanism in young vs older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:531&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florini J, Ewton D, Coolican S. Growth hormone and the insulin-like growth factor system in myogenesis. Endocr Rev. 1996;17:481&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8897022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Creer A, Jemiolo B, Trappe S. Time course of myogenic and metabolic gene expression in response to acute exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98:1745&#x2013;1752. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01185.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01185.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15618316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak K, Kong Y, Konieczny S. The MRF4 activation domain is required to induce muscle-specific gene expression. Mol Cell Biol. 1992;12:4224&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC360357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1328851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yutzey K, Rhodes S, Konieczny S. Differential transactivation associated with the muscle regulatory factors MyoD1, myogenin, and MRF4. Mol Cell Biol. 1990;10:3934&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC360904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1695319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas N, Mira J, Gallien C, Chanoine C. Neural and hormonal control of expression of myogenic regulatory factor genes during regeneration of Xenopus fast muscles: myogenin and MRF4 mRNA accumulation are neurally regulated oppositely. Dev Dyn. 2000;218:112&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1097-0177(200005)218:1&lt;112::AID-DVDY10&gt;3.0.CO;2-D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0177(200005)218:1&lt;112::AID-DVDY10&gt;3.0.CO;2-D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10822264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myogenic regulatory factor expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:769&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000065005.96298.01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000065005.96298.01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Op't Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, Urso B, Greenhaff P, Labarque V, Dymarkowski S, Van Hecke P, Richter E. Oral creatine supplementation faciltates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol. 2001;536:625&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>