<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39995478</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of circuit hydraulic weight interval training on body composition and progression of resistance in recreationally exercising pre- and postmenopausal women: an 18-week quasi-experimental study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1540983</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1540983</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1540983</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2025.1540983</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The lack of physical activity, stress, and unhealthy eating habits contribute to body mass disorders, which form the basis of most civilization diseases. Mature women are increasingly turning to fitness clubs to improve their physique and protect themselves from diseases and the progressive aging process. The multitude of training systems proposed to women by fitness clubs leads to the search for solutions that will bring positive health results. The response to an exercise stimulus may depend on the menopausal status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This quasi-experimental study aimed to determine the effects of 6, 12, and 18&#xa0;weeks of circuit hydraulic weight interval training (CHWIT) on anthropometric indices, body composition estimated by the bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA), and muscle performance in inactive pre- and post-menopausal women from an urban population. A total of 100 women aged between 35 and 69 (mean 51.5 &#xb1; 9.61) years with a mean body mass index (BMI) of 27.3 (&#xb1;5.4&#xa0;kg/m<sup>2</sup>) were divided by menopausal status and assigned to the training CHWIT group (25 pre- and 25 postmenopausal women) and the control group (25 pre- and 25 postmenopausal women). Each participant from the CHWIT group took part in a total of 54 training sessions, developed for the Mrs.Sporty network, under the constant supervision of a qualified trainer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After 18&#xa0;weeks of training in both intervention groups, ANCOVA demonstrated statistically significant (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05) decreased body fat (%), reduced thigh and arm circumference, and increased muscle component (kg) as the main part of fat-free body mass. Additionally, premenopausal women decreased their body mass, BMI, and waist and hip circumferences. A significant increase in the muscle component was noticed after 6&#xa0;weeks of CHWIT in pre-menopausal women and only after 18&#xa0;weeks in postmenopausal women. Significant progression of resistance (amount of repetitions on hydraulic machines) was observed after 6&#xa0;weeks and at each subsequent stage of CHWIT in both intervention groups (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001). No significant differences were found in the controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">CHWIT is an effective form of training, improving body composition and physical functions in inactive pre- and postmenopausal women. Changes in the muscle component require a longer intervention of physical effort in women after menopause.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Socha, &#x106;wiel&#x105;g and Andrzejewski.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Socha</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#x142;gorzata</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Biology, Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences, Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x106;wiel&#x105;g</LastName><ForeName>Paulina</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Biology, Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences, Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andrzejewski</LastName><ForeName>Waldemar</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fundamentals of Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Wroclaw University of Health and Sport Sciences, Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body fat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">circuit training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydraulic resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interval training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39995478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11847869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1540983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1540983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achamrah N., Colange G., Delay J., Rimbert A., Folope V., Petit A., et al. (2018). Comparison of body composition assessment by DXA and BIA according to the body mass index: a retrospective study on 3655 measures. PLoS One 13, e0200465. 10.1371/journal.pone.0200465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0200465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6042744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30001381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson L. J., Erceg D. N., Schroeder E. T. (2012). Utility of multifrequency bioelectrical impedance compared with dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry for assessment of total and regional body composition varies between men and women. Nutr. Res. 32, 479&#x2013;485. 10.1016/j.nutres.2012.05.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2012.05.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22901555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J., Kenyon M., Ellerbroek A., Carson C., Burgess V., Tyler-Palmer D., et al. (2019). Comparison of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) versus a multi-frequency bioelectrical impedance (InBody 770) device for body composition assessment after a 4-week hypoenergetic diet. J. Funct. Morphol. Kinesiol. 4, 23. 10.3390/jfmk4020023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk4020023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Fatouros I. G. (2022). Psychological adaptations to high-intensity interval training in overweight and obese adults: a topical review. Sports 10, 64. 10.3390/sports10050064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports10050064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9148041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Fatouros I. G., Chatzinikolaou A., Draganidis D., Georgakouli K., Papanikolaou K., et al. (2019). Dose-response effects of high-intensity interval neuromuscular exercise training on weight loss, performance, health and quality of life in inactive obese adults: study rationale, design and methods of the DoIT trial. Contemp. Clin. Trials Commun. 23 (15), 100386. 10.1016/j.conctc.2019.100386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conctc.2019.100386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31193901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Jamurtas A. Z., Draganidis D., Georgakouli K., Tsimeas P., Poulios A., et al. (2021b). Hybrid neuromuscular training improves cardiometabolic health and alters redox status in inactive overweight and obese women: a randomized controlled trial. Antioxidants 10, 1601. 10.3390/antiox10101601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox10101601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8533161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34679738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Jamurtas A. Z., Fatouros I. G. (2021a). High-Intensity interval training in metabolic diseases: physiological adaptations. ACSMS Health Fit. J. 25, 54&#x2013;59. 10.1249/FIT.0000000000000703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/FIT.0000000000000703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Jamurtas A. Z., Georgakouli K., Draganidis D., Deli C. K., Papanikolaou K., et al. (2018). High intensity, circuit-type integrated neuromuscular training alters energy balance and reduces body mass and fat in obese women: a 10-month training-detraining randomized controlled trial. PLoS One 13, e0202390. 10.1371/journal.pone.0202390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0202390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6107179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Jamurtas A. Z., Metsios G. S., Perivoliotis K., Liguori G., Feito Y., et al. (2022). Comparative efficacy of 5 exercise types on cardiometabolic health in overweight and obese adults: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of 81 randomized controlled trials. Circ. Cardiovasc. Qual. Outcomes 15, E008243. 10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.121.008243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.121.008243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Jamurtas A. Z., Tsimeas P., Poulios A., Perivoliotis K., Syrou N., et al. (2023). Hybrid-type, multicomponent interval training upregulates musculoskeletal fitness of adults with overweight and obesity in a volume-dependent manner: a 1-year dose-response randomised controlled trial. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 23, 432&#x2013;443. 10.1080/17461391.2021.2025434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2021.2025434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34974824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Loules G., Georgakouli K., Tsimeas P., Draganidis D., Chatzinikolaou A., et al. (2020a). High-intensity interval neuromuscular training promotes exercise behavioral regulation, adherence and weight loss in inactive obese women. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 20, 783&#x2013;792. 10.1080/17461391.2019.1663270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2019.1663270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31478436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batrakoulis A., Tsimeas P., Deli C. K., Vlachopoulos D., Ubago-Guisado E., Poulios A., et al. (2020b). Hybrid neuromuscular training promotes musculoskeletal adaptations in inactive overweight and obese women: a training-detraining randomized controlled trial. J. Sports Sci. 39, 503&#x2013;512. 10.1080/02640414.2020.1830543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2020.1830543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Beck T. W. (2013). The importance of <i>a priori</i> sample size estimation in strength and conditioning research. J. Strength. Cond. Res.
27, 2323&#x2013;2337. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318278eea0

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318278eea0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23880657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito P. J., G&#xf3;mez-Candela C., Caba&#xf1;as M. D., Szendrei B., Castro E. A. (2019). Comparison between different methods for measuring body fat after a weight loss program. Rev. Bras. Med. Esporte 25, 474&#x2013;479. 10.1590/1517-869220192506149743</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-869220192506149743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buch A., Carmeli E., Boker L. K., Marcus Y., Shefer G., Kis O., et al. (2016). Muscle function and fat content in relation to sarcopenia, obesity and frailty of old age-an overview. Exp. Gerontol. 76, 25&#x2013;32. 10.1016/j.exger.2016.01.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2016.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26785313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. (1998). Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. New York: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooney M. M., Walker J. B. (1986). Hydraulic resistance exercise benefits cardiovascular fitness of spinal cord injured. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 18, 522&#x2013;525. 10.1249/00005768-198610000-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-198610000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3773668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz Rivera P. N., Goldstein R. L., Polak M., Lazzari A. A., Moy M. L., Wan E. S. (2022). Performance of bioelectrical impedance analysis compared to dual X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) in Veterans with COPD. Sci. Rep. 12, 1946. 10.1038/s41598-022-05887-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-05887-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8816927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csapo R., Alegre L. M. (2016). Effects of resistance training with moderate vs heavy loads on muscle mass and strength in the elderly: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 26, 995&#x2013;1006. 10.1111/sms.12536</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26302881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mendon&#xe7;a R. M. S. C., de Ara&#xfa;jo J&#xfa;nior A. T., de Sousa M. D. S. C., Fernandes H. M. (2014). The effects of different exercise programmes on female body composition. J. Hum. Kinet. 43, 67&#x2013;78. 10.2478/hukin-2014-0091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4332186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan E., Swinton P., McCoy S., Carver P. (2015). The impact of a self-regulated pneumatic resistance intervention on variables related to balance, gait and lower extremity muscle function in community dwelling older adults. Prog. Health Sci. 5, 120&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuit M., Rance M., More C., Bouillon P., Boscaro A., Martin V., et al. (2021). Effect of concurrent training on body composition and gut microbiota in postmenopausal women with overweight or obesity. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 54, 517&#x2013;529. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34628447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x17c;ygad&#x142;o B., &#x141;epecka-Klusek C., Pilewski B. (2012). Use of bioelectrical impedance analysis in prevention and treatment of overweight and obesity. Probl. Hig. Epidemiol. 93, 274&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone P. H., Tai C. Y., Carson L. R., Joy J. M., Mosman M. M., McCann T. R., et al. (2015). Caloric expenditure of aerobic, resistance, or combined high-intensity interval training using a hydraulic resistance system in healthy men. J. Strength Cond. Res. 29, 779&#x2013;785. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000661</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25162652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C., Armstrong M. (2018). What types of physical activities are effective in developing muscle and bone strength and balance. J. Frailty Sarcopenia Falls 3, 58&#x2013;65. 10.22540/JFSF-03-058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22540/JFSF-03-058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala M. S., Cadore E. L., Dorgo S., Izquierdo M., Kraemer W. J., Peterson M. D., et al. (2019). Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J. Strength. Cond. Res. 33, 2019&#x2013;2052. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel D. A. (1991). Fatigue patterns for accommodating hydraulic resistance exercise. J. Appl. Sport Sci. Res. 5, 6&#x2013;10. 10.1519/1533-4287(1991)005&lt;0006:fpfahr&gt;2.3.co;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(1991)005&lt;0006:fpfahr&gt;2.3.co;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadelha A. B., Paiva F. M. L., Gauche R., de Oliveira R. J., Lima R. M. (2016). Effects of resistance training on sarcopenic obesity index in older women: a randomized controlled trial. Arch. Gerontol. Geriatr. 65, 168&#x2013;173. 10.1016/j.archger.2016.03.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2016.03.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27057600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gafner S., Bastiaenen C. H. G., Terrier P., Put I., Ferrari S., Gold G., et al. (2017). Evaluation of hip abductor and adductor strength in the elderly: a reliability study. Eur. Rev. Aging Phys. Act. 14, 5. 10.1186/s11556-017-0174-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11556-017-0174-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5404282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28450961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gafner S. C., Bastiaenen C. H. G., Biver E., Ferrari S., Allet L. (2021). Reliability and validity of an adapted hip abductor strength measure as a potential new fall risk assessment for older persons: a study protocol. BMC Geriatr. 21, 110. 10.1186/s12877-021-02048-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-021-02048-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7866761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi B. B., Rodrigues B., Feriani D. J., de Jesus Furtado Almeida F., Sauaia B. A., Schwingel P. A., et al. (2016). Effects of resistance training of moderate intensity on heart rate variability, body composition, and muscle strength in healthy elderly women. Sport. Sci. Health 12, 389&#x2013;395. 10.1007/s11332-016-0303-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-016-0303-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobbo L. A., Cyrino E. S. (2021). &#x201c;&#x201c;Effects of resistance training programs on body composition in older adults,&#x201d; in Bioelectrical Impedance Analysis of Body Composition,&#x201d; in Applications in sports science. Editors Marini E., Toselli S. (Italy: Cagliari, Italy: Unica Press; ), 165&#x2013;176. 10.13125/unicapress.978-88-3312-033-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13125/unicapress.978-88-3312-033-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha C. H., Swearingin B., Jeon Y. K., Lee M. (2015). Effects of combined exercise on HOMA-IR, HOMA &#x3b2;-cell and atherogenic index in Korean obese female. Sport Sci. Health 11, 49&#x2013;55. 10.1007/s11332-014-0208-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-014-0208-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes C. J., Racette S. B. (2021). The utility of body composition assessment in nutrition and clinical practice: an overview of current methodology. Nutrients 13, 2493. 10.3390/nu13082493</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13082493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8399582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34444653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu W. H., Hsu R. W. W., Lin Z. R., Fan C. H. (2015). Effects of circuit exercise and tai chi on body composition in middle-aged and older women. Geriatr. Gerontol. Int. 15, 282&#x2013;288. 10.1111/ggi.12270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ggi.12270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24597918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter G. R., McCarthy J. P., Bamman M. M. (2004). Effects of resistance training on older adults. Sports Med. 34, 329&#x2013;348. 10.2165/00007256-200434050-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200434050-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaenada-Carrilero E., Vicente-Mampel J., Baraja-Vegas L., Thorborg K., Valero-Merlos E., Blanco-G&#xed;menez P., et al. (2024). Hip adduction and abduction strength profiles in elite and sub-elite female soccer players according to players level and leg limb-dominance. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabil. 16, 53. 10.1186/s13102-024-00838-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-024-00838-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10882891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38383450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karatrantou K., Gerodimos V., Katsareli E., Manouras N., Ioakimidis P., Famisis K. (2019). Strength profile of hip abductor and adductor muscles in youth elite soccer players. J. Hum. Kinet. 66, 31&#x2013;41. 10.2478/hukin-2018-0069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2018-0069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6458577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30988838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami T., Imagama T., Matsuki Y., Okazaki T., Kaneoka T., Yamazaki K., et al. (2024). Preoperative abductor muscle strength on the healthy side affects the Timed up and Go test after total hip arthroplasty in women. BMC Musculoskelet. Disord. 25, 881. 10.1186/s12891-024-08008-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-024-08008-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11536871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39501288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly J. S., Metcalfe J. (2012). Validity and reliability of body composition analysis using the Tanita BC418-MA. J. Exerc. Physiol. Online 15, 74&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp J. L., Schache A. G., Makdissi M., Sims K. J., Crossley K. M. (2013). Greater understanding of normal hip physical function may guide clinicians in providing targeted rehabilitation programmes. J. Sci. Med. Sport. 16, 292&#x2013;296. 10.1016/j.jsams.2012.11.887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2012.11.887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23266242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick C., Thomas A., Campbell B., Taylor L., Wilborn C., Marcello B., et al. (2009). Effects of a popular exercise and weight loss program on weight loss, body composition, energy expenditure and health in obese women. Nutr. Metab. (Lond.) 6, 23&#x2013;17. 10.1186/1743-7075-6-23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-6-23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19442301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr Z. Y., Comstock R. D. (2010). Epidemiology of weight training-related injuries presenting to United States emergency departments, 1990-2007. Am. J. Sport. Med. 38, 765&#x2013;771. 10.1177/0363546509351</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546509351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klika B., Jordan C. (2013). High-intensity circuit training using body weight: maximum results with minimal investment. ACSMs. Health Fit. J. 17, 8&#x2013;13. 10.1249/FIT.0b013e31828cb1e8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/FIT.0b013e31828cb1e8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kravitz L. (1996). The fitness professional&#x2019;s complete guide to circuits and intervals. IDEA Today 14 (1), 32&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S., Islam M. M., Rogers M. E., Kusunoki M., Okada A., Takeshima N. (2011). Effects of hydraulic-resistance exercise on strength and power in untrained healthy older adults. J. Strength Cond. Res. 25, 1089&#x2013;1097. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c69ea1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c69ea1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehnert M., Stastny P., Sigmund M., Xaverova Z., Hubnerova B., Kostrzewa M. (2015). The effect of combined machine and body weight circuit training for women on muscle strength and body composition. J. Phys. Educ. Sport 15, 561&#x2013;568. 10.7752/jpes.2015.03084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7752/jpes.2015.03084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maillard F., Pereira B., Boisseau N. (2018). Effect of high-intensity interval training on total, abdominal and visceral fat mass: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 48, 269&#x2013;288. 10.1007/s40279-017-0807-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0807-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29127602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltais M. L., Desroches J., Dionne I. J. (2009). Changes in muscle mass and strength after menopause. J. Musculoskelet. Neuronal Interact. 9, 186&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19949277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcos-Pardo P. J., Orquin-Castrill&#xf3;n F. J., Gea-Garc&#xed;a G. M., Menayo-Ant&#xfa;nez R., Gonz&#xe1;lez-G&#xe1;lvez N., Vale R. G. D. S., et al. (2019). Effects of a moderate-to-high intensity resistance circuit training on fat mass, functional capacity, muscular strength, and quality of life in elderly: a randomized controlled trial. Sci. Rep. 9, 7830. 10.1038/s41598-019-44329-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-44329-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6534570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31127163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitka M. (2013). Do flawed data on caloric intake from NHANES present problems for researchers and policy makers? Jama 310, 2137&#x2013;2138. 10.1001/jama.2013.281865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.281865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24281443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan A., Noguchi K. S., Tang A., Heisz J., Thabane L., Richardson J. (2023). Physical and cognitive effects of high-intensity interval or circuit-based strength training for community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review. J. Aging Phys. Act. 1 (aop), 1051&#x2013;1074. 10.1123/japa.2022-0425</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/japa.2022-0425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37652435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadler S. F., DePrince M. L., Hauesien N., Malanga G. A., Stitik T. P., Price E. (2000). Portable dynamometer anchoring station for measuring strength of the hip extensors and abductors. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 81, 1072&#x2013;1076. 10.1053/apmr.2000.7165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/apmr.2000.7165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10943757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman A. B., Kupelian V., Visser M., Simonsick E. M., Goodpaster B. H., Kritchevsky S. B., et al. (2006). Strength, but not muscle mass, is associated with mortality in the health, aging and body composition study cohort. J. Gerontol. A. Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 61, 72&#x2013;77. 10.1093/gerona/61.1.72</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/61.1.72</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newsome A. M., Batrakoulis A., Camhi S., McAvoy C., Sansone J., Rachelle M. S. (2024). 2025 ACSM worldwide fitness trends: future directions of the health and fitness industry. J. 28, 11&#x2013;25. 10.1249/FIT.0000000000001017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/FIT.0000000000001017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson S., Hammar M., West J., Borga M., Thorell S., Spetz Holm A. C. (2023). Resistance training decreased abdominal adiposity in postmenopausal women. Maturitas 176, 107794. 10.1016/j.maturitas.2023.107794</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2023.107794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37421844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira-Junior S. A., Boullosa D., Mendon&#xe7;a M. L. M., Vieira L. F. C., Mattos W. W., Amaral B. O. C., et al. (2021). Effects of circuit weight-interval training on physical fitness, cardiac autonomic control, and quality of life in sedentary workers. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public. Health. 18, 4606. 10.3390/ijerph18094606</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18094606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33925277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A., Pacelli F., Bargossi A. M., Marcolin G., Guzzinati S., Neri M., et al. (2010). Effects of three distinct protocols of fitness training on body composition, strength and blood lactate. J. Sports Med. Phys. Fit. 50, 43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20308971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Physical Activity Council (2019). Physical activity council&#x2019;s overview report on U.S. Participation. Available at: https://www.physicalactivitycouncil.com/pdfs/current.pdf (Accessed December 15, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichon C., Hunter G., Morris M., Bond R., Metz J. (1996). Blood pressure and heart rate response and metabolic cost of circuit versus traditional weight training. J. Strength. Cond. Res. 10, 153&#x2013;156. 10.1519/00124278-199608000-00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-199608000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Arenas S., Blazevich A. J., Mart&#xed;nez-Pascual M., P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J., Luque A. J., L&#xf3;pez-Rom&#xe1;n F. J., et al. (2013). Effects of high-resistance circuit training in an elderly population. Exp. Gerontol. 48 (3), 334&#x2013;340. 10.1016/j.exger.2013.01.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2013.01.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23352954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B., Dawes J. (2009). High-intensity interval training: applications for general fitness training. Strength. Cond. J. 31, 44&#x2013;46. 10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181c2a844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181c2a844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw B. S., Gouveia M., McIntyre S., Shaw I. (2016). Anthropometric and cardiovascular responses to hypertrophic resistance training in postmenopausal women. Menopause 23, 1176&#x2013;1181. 10.1097/GME.0000000000000687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GME.0000000000000687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skidmore B. L., Jones M. T., Blegen M., Matthews T. D. (2012). Acute effects of three different circuit weight training protocols on blood lactate, heart rate, and rating of perceived exertion in recreationally active women. J. Sports Sci. Med. 11, 660&#x2013;668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3763312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24150076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socha M., Fr&#x105;czak P., Jonak W., Sobiech K. A. (2016). Effect of resistance training with elements of stretching on body composition and quality of life in postmenopausal women. Prz. Menopauzalny 15, 26&#x2013;31. 10.5114/pm.2016.58770</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/pm.2016.58770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4828505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27095955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiegler P., Cunliffe A. (2006). The role of diet and exercise for the maintenance of fat-free mass and resting metabolic rate during weight loss. Sports Med. 36, 239&#x2013;262. 10.2165/00007256-200636030-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636030-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16526835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B., Schobersberger W. (2011). Evidence for resistance training as a treatment therapy in obesity. J. Obes. 11, 482564. 10.1155/2011/482564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2011/482564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suomi R., Surburg P. R., Lecius P. (1995). Effects of hydraulic resistance strength training on isokinetic measures of leg strength in men with mental retardation. Adapt. Phys. Act. Q. 12, 377&#x2013;387. 10.1123/apaq.12.4.377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/apaq.12.4.377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeshima N., Rogers M. E., Watanabe E., Brechue W. F., Okada A., Yamada T., et al. (2002). Water-based exercise improves health-related aspects of fitness in older women. Med. Sci. Sports. Exerc. 34, 544&#x2013;551. 10.1097/00005768-200203000-00024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200203000-00024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teede H. J., Lombard C., Deeks A. A. (2010). Obesity, metabolic complications and the menopause: an opportunity for prevention. Climacteric 13, 203&#x2013;209. 10.3109/13697130903296909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/13697130903296909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19863456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapp E. G., Chisholm D. J., Fruend J., Bouthcher S. H. (2008). The effects of high-intensity intermittent exercise training on fat loss and fasting insulin levels of young women. Int. J. Obes. 32, 684&#x2013;691. 10.1038/sj.ijo.0803781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0803781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18197184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconcelos K. S., Dias J., Ara&#xfa;jo M. C., Pinheiro A. C., Moreira B. S., Dias R. C. (2016). Effects of a progressive resistance exercise program with high-speed component on the physical function of older women with sarcopenic obesity: a randomized controlled trial. Braz. J. Phys. Ther. 20, 432&#x2013;440. 10.1590/bjpt-rbf.2014.0174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/bjpt-rbf.2014.0174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5123261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27410162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weltman A., Janney C., Rians C. B., Strand K., Berg B., Tippitt S., et al. (1986). The effects of hydraulic resistance strength training in pre-pubertal males. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 18, 629&#x2013;638. 10.1249/00005768-198612000-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-198612000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2946921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wewege M., van den Berg R., Ward R. E., Keech A. (2017). The effects of high-intensity interval training vs. moderate-intensity continuous training on body composition in overweight and obese adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes. Rev. 18, 635&#x2013;646. 10.1111/obr.12532</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28401638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y. (2018). Muscle mass, quality, and composition changes during atrophy and sarcopenia. In: Adv. Exp. Med. Biol. 1088. 47, 72. 10.1007/978-981-13-1435-3_3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-13-1435-3_3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30390247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young K. C. (2007). The effects of hydraulic resistance circuit training on whole body bone mineral density in postmenopausal women. PhD Thesis: Wichita State University.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>