<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37417618</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>27</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The efficacy of different interventions in the treatment of sarcopenia in middle-aged and elderly people: A network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e34254</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e34254</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e34254</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000034254</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In this study, a meta-analysis system was used to evaluate the effects of 7 methods of treating sarcopenia, including resistance exercise, aerobic exercise, mixed exercise, nutrition, resistance combined with nutrition, mixed exercise combined with nutrition, and electric stimulation combined with nutrition, and their effects on physical function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">According to the PRISMA guidelines, PubMed, Web of Science, Embase, and other foreign databases, as well as Chinese databases such as China National Knowledge Infrastructure and Wan Fang, the literatures of randomized controlled trials with different intervention measures were searched. ADDIS software was used to compare and rank the results of the network meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 2485 patients were included in the 30 randomized controlled trial items. According to the clinical manifestations of sarcopenia, 7 different forms of exercise and nutrition interventions can improve muscle strength, muscle mass, and physical function; in terms of improving muscle strength, resistance exercise has the most significant effect on improving grip strength (MD = 2.58, 95% confidence interval [CI] [1.06-4.07]); resistance exercise combined with nutrition lifting performed best in chair standing test (MD = -2.37, 95% CI [-4.73 to -0.33]). For muscle mass gains, resistance training increased appendicular skeletal muscle mass significantly (MD = 0.90, 95% CI [0.11-1.73]), while resistance exercise combined with nutrition significantly increased fat-free mass (MD = 5.15, 95% CI [0.91-9.43]). For physical activity, resistance training improved walk speed best (MD = 0.28, 95% CI [0.15-0.41]), and resistance exercise combined with nutrition in the best results were seen in the timed up and go test (MD = -2.31, 95% CI [-4.26 to -0.38]).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Compared with aerobic exercise, mixed exercise, nutrition, resistance combined with nutrition, mixed exercise combined with nutrition, and electric stimulation combined with nutrition, resistance exercise has more advantages in improving muscle mass, strength, and physical function performance. The clinical treatment of sarcopenia with resistance exercise intervention has a better curative effect.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0721-7611</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Haiting</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Naval Aviation University, Yantai, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Liming</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qinghai Normal University, Qinghai, Xining, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Hongwen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Shilun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000099094">Network Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013996" MajorTopicYN="N">Time and Motion Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009135" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscular Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37417618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10328700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000034254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202307070-00029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Petermann-Rocha F, Balntzi V, Gray SR, et al. Global prevalence of sarcopenia and severe sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:86&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34816624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nations, United. World Population Prospects 2019: Highlights. United Nations: 2019. Available at: https://www.un-ilibrary.org/content/books/9789210042352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LK, Woo J, Assantachai P, et al. Asian working group for sarcopenia: 2019 consensus update on sarcopenia diagnosis and treatment. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:300&#x2013;307.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostini F, Bernetti A, Di Giacomo G, et al. Rehabilitative good practices in the treatment of sarcopenia: a narrative review. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;100:280&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33595941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederholm T, Barazzoni R, Austin P, et al. ESPEN guidelines on definitions and terminology of clinical nutrition. Clin Nutr. 2017;36:49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27642056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahat G, Ilhan B. Sarcopenia and the cardiometabolic syndrome: a narrative review. Eur Geriatr Med. 2016;7:220&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bone AE, Hepgul N, Kon S, et al. Sarcopenia and frailty in chronic respiratory disease: lessons from gerontology. Chron Respir Dis. 2017;14:85&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5720213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27923981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennison EM, Sayer AA, Cooper C. Epidemiology of sarcopenia and insight into possible therapeutic targets. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2017;13:340&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5444517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker SD, Morley JE, von Haehling S. Welcome to the ICD-10 code for sarcopenia. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2016;7:512&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5114626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27891296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijnarends DM, Koster A, Schols JM, et al. Physical activity and incidence of sarcopenia: the population-based AGES &#x2013; reykjavik study. Age Ageing. 2016;45:614&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5027639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaap LA, van Schoor NM, Lips P, et al. Associations of sarcopenia definitions, and their components, with the incidence of recurrent falling and fractures: the longitudinal aging study Amsterdam. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2018;73:1199&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29300839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Piasecki M, Atherton PJ. The age-related loss of skeletal muscle mass and function: measurement and physiology of muscle fibre atrophy and muscle fibre loss in humans. Ageing Res Rev. 2018;47:123&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6202460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung SSY, Reijnierse EM, Pham VK, et al. Sarcopenia and its association with falls and fractures in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2019;10:485&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6596401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30993881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohashi K, Ishikawa T, Imai M, et al. Relationship between pre-sarcopenia and quality of life in patients with chronic liver disease: a cross-sectional study. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;31:1408&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30964810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2018;48:16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, Otten L. Financial impact of sarcopenia or low muscle mass &#x2013; a short review. Clin Nutr. 2019;38:1489&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30316536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudart C, Zaaria M, Pasleau F, et al. Health outcomes of sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0169548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5240970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28095426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawthon PM, Lui LY, Taylor BC, et al. Clinical definitions of sarcopenia and risk of hospitalization in community-dwelling older men: the osteoporotic fractures in men study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2017;72:1383&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5861971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28329087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmstrom TK, Miller DK, Simonsick EM, et al. SARC-F: a symptom score to predict persons with sarcopenia at risk for poor functional outcomes. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2016;7:28&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4799853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27066316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartee GD, Hepple RT, Bamman MM, et al. Exercise promotes healthy aging of skeletal muscle. Cell Metab. 2016;23:1034&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5045036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27304505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudart C, Dawson A, Shaw SC, et al. Nutrition and physical activity in the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia: systematic review. Osteoporos Int. 2017;28:1817&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5457808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson SM, Reginster JY, Rizzoli R, et al. Does nutrition play a role in the prevention and management of sarcopenia? Clin Nutr. 2018;37:1121&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5796643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28927897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan T, Chang L, Mn R, et al. Comparative efficacy of interventional therapies for early-stage hepatocellular carcinoma: a prisma-compliant systematic review and network meta-analysis. Medicine (Baltimore). 2016;95:e3185&#x2013;e3185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4839802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27082558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x8c37;&#x9e3f;&#x79cb;; &#x738b;&#x6768;; &#x674e;&#x536b;, Cochrane&#x504f;&#x501a;&#x98ce;&#x9669;&#x8bc4;&#x4f30;&#x5de5;&#x5177;&#x5728;&#x968f;&#x673a;&#x5bf9;&#x7167;&#x7814;&#x7a76;Meta&#x5206;&#x6790;&#x4e2d;&#x7684;&#x5e94;&#x7528;. &#x4e2d;&#x56fd;&#x5faa;&#x73af;&#x6742;&#x5fd7; 2014;29:147&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HK, Suzuki T, Saito K, et al. Effects of exercise and amino acid supplementation on body composition and physical function in community-dwelling elderly Japanese sarcopenic women: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2012;60:16&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22142410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Kim M, Kojima N, et al. Exercise and nutritional supplementation on community-dwelling elderly Japanese women with sarcopenic obesity: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2016;17:1011&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27544583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Suzuki T, Saito K, et al. Effects of exercise and tea catechins on muscle mass, strength and walking ability in community-dwelling elderly Japanese sarcopenic women: a randomized controlled trial. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2013;13:458&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22935006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao CD, Tsauo JY, Lin LF, et al. Effects of elastic resistance exercise on body composition and physical capacity in older women with sarcopenic obesity: a CONSORT-compliant prospective randomized controlled trial. Medicine (Baltim). 2017;96:e7115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5466239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28591061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cebria IIMA, Balasch-Bernat M, Tortosa-Chulia MA, et al. Effects of resistance training of peripheral muscles versus respiratory muscles in older adults with sarcopenia who are institutionalized: a randomized controlled trial. J Aging Phys Act. 2018;26:637&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29431561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HT, Chung YC, Chen YJ, et al. Effects of different types of exercise on body composition, muscle strength, and IGF-1 in the elderly with sarcopenic obesity. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2017;65:827&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28205203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltais ML, Ladouceur JP, Dionne IJ. The effect of resistance training and different sources of postexercise protein supplementation on muscle mass and physical capacity in sarcopenic elderly men. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:1680&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada M, Kimura Y, Ishiyama D, et al. Synergistic effect of bodyweight resistance exercise and protein supplementation on skeletal muscle in sarcopenic or dynapenic older adults. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2019;19:429&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30864254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Kwon Y, Park H. Effects of 24-week aerobic and resistance training on carotid artery intima-media thickness and flow velocity in elderly women with sarcopenic obesity. J Atheroscler Thromb. 2017;24:1117&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason C, Xiao L, Imayama I, et al. Influence of diet, exercise, and serum vitamin d on sarcopenia in postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:607&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3594522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23190588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong ZJ, Zhang HL, Yin LX. Effects of intradialytic resistance exercise on systemic inflammation in maintenance hemodialysis patients with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. Int Urol Nephrol. 2019;51:1415&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6660503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31270740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Hajj C, Fares S, Chardigny JM, et al. Vitamin D supplementation and muscle strength in pre-sarcopenic elderly Lebanese people: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Osteoporos. 2018;14:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30569340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu LY, Chan R, Kwok T, et al. Effects of exercise and nutrition supplementation in community-dwelling older Chinese people with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. Age Ageing. 2019;48:220&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdzieblik D, Oesser S, Baumstark MW, et al. Collagen peptide supplementation in combination with resistance training improves body composition and increases muscle strength in elderly sarcopenic men: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Nutr. 2015;114:1237&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26353786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikberg S, Sorlen N, Branden L, et al. Effects of resistance training on functional strength and muscle mass in 70-year-old individuals with pre-sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2019;20:28&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsekoura M, Billis E, Tsepis E, et al. The effects of group and home-based exercise programs in elderly with sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Med. 2018;7:480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30486262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piastra G, Perasso L, Lucarini S, et al. Effects of two types of 9-month adapted physical activity program on muscle mass, muscle strength, and balance in moderate sarcopenic older women. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:5095673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6211206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30420965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson JK, Dorff TB, Todd Schroeder E, et al. Impact of resistance training on body composition and metabolic syndrome variables during androgen deprivation therapy for prostate cancer: a pilot randomized controlled trial. BMC Cancer. 2018;18:368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5883585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29614993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HT, Wu HJ, Chen YJ, et al. Effects of 8-week kettlebell training on body composition, muscle strength, pulmonary function, and chronic low-grade inflammation in elderly women with sarcopenia. Exp Gerontol. 2018;112:112&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30243898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aleman-Mateo H, Carreon VR, Macias L, et al. Nutrient-rich dairy proteins improve appendicular skeletal muscle mass and physical performance, and attenuate the loss of muscle strength in older men and women subjects: a single-blind randomized clinical trial. Clin Interv Aging. 2014;9:1517&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4172033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25258523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubertin-Leheudre M, Lord C, Khalil A, et al. Six months of isoflavone supplement increases fat-free mass in obese-sarcopenic postmenopausal women: a randomized double-blind controlled trial. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2007;61:1442&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17311051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer JM, Verlaan S, Bautmans I, et al. Effects of a vitamin D and leucine-enriched whey protein nutritional supplement on measures of sarcopenia in older adults, the PROVIDE study: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2015;16:740&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26170041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny AM, Kleppinger A, Wang Y, et al. Effects of ultra-low-dose estrogen therapy on muscle and physical function in older women. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53:1973&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16274381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malafarina V, Uriz-Otano F, Malafarina C, et al. Effectiveness of nutritional supplementation on sarcopenia and recovery in hip fracture patients. A multi-centre randomized trial. Maturitas. 2017;101:42&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28539168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo Y, Liu C, Ji Z, et al. A high whey protein, vitamin D and E supplement preserves muscle mass, strength, and quality of life in sarcopenic older adults: a double-blind randomized controlled trial. Clin Nutr. 2019;38:159&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29395372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi I, Yoshimura Y, Shimazu S, et al. Effects of branched-chain amino acids and vitamin D supplementation on physical function, muscle mass and strength, and nutritional status in sarcopenic older adults undergoing hospital-based rehabilitation: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2019;19:12&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30358032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Negro RW, Aquilani R, Bertacco S, et al. Comprehensive effects of supplemented essential amino acids in patients with severe COPD and sarcopenia. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2010;73:25&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20499791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sammarco R, Marra M, Di Guglielmo ML, et al. Evaluation of hypocaloric diet with protein supplementation in middle-aged sarcopenic obese women: a pilot study. Obes Facts. 2017;10:160&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28528340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabuco HCG, Tomeleri CM, Fernandes RR, et al. Effect of whey protein supplementation combined with resistance training on body composition, muscular strength, functional capacity, and plasma-metabolism biomarkers in older women with sarcopenic obesity: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2019;32:88&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W, Grimm A, Bebenek M, et al. Effects of combined whole-body electromyostimulation and protein supplementation on local and overall muscle/fat distribution in older men with sarcopenic obesity: the randomized controlled franconia sarcopenic obesity (FranSO) study. Calcif Tissue Int. 2018;103:266&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29675640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x66fe;&#x5baa;&#x6d9b;; &#x5f20;&#x8d85;; &#x675c;&#x4eae;, &#x5e94;&#x7528;ADDIS&#x8f6f;&#x4ef6;&#x5b9e;&#x73b0;&#x7f51;&#x72b6;Meta&#x5206;&#x6790;. &#x4e2d;&#x56fd;&#x5faa;&#x8bc1;&#x533b;&#x5b66;&#x6742;&#x5fd7; 2013;13:1508&#x2013;1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodds RM, Syddall HE, Cooper R, et al. Global variation in grip strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis of normative data. Age Ageing. 2016;45:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4776623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26790455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Alley DE, Shardell MD, et al. Comparison of handgrip and leg extension strength in predicting slow gait speed in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2016;64:144&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5490244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26782864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshiko A, Ogawa M, Shimizu K, et al. Chair sit-to-stand performance is associated with diagnostic features of sarcopenia in older men and women. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2021;96:104463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34218157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg IH. Summary comments. Am J Clin Nutr. 1989;50:1231&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayer AA, Syddall H, Martin H, et al. The developmental origins of sarcopenia. J Nutr Health Aging. 2008;12:427&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2652119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18615224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caan BJ, Meyerhardt JA, Kroenke CH, et al. Explaining the obesity paradox: the association between body composition and colorectal cancer survival (C-SCANS Study). Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2017;26:1008&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5647152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28506965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Sayer AA. Sarcopenia. Lancet. 2019;393:2636&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31171417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J, Qian Z, Chen Y, et al. MicroRNA regulatory networks in the pathogenesis of sarcopenia. J Cell Mol Med. 2020;24:4900&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32281300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, Vellas B, Evans WJ, et al. Sarcopenia: an undiagnosed condition in older adults. Current consensus definition: prevalence, etiology, and consequences. International working group on sarcopenia. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2011;12:249&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3377163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Taylor CC, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M. What is the cause of the ageing atrophy? total number, size and proportion of different fiber types studied in whole vastus lateralis muscle from 15- to 83-year-old men. J Neurol Sci. 1988;84:275&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3379447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon RJ, Hasni S. Pathogenesis and management of sarcopenia. Clin Geriatr Med. 2017;33:17&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5127276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27886695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalle S, Rossmeislova L, Koppo K. The role of inflammation in age-related sarcopenia. Front Physiol. 2017;8:1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5733049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29311975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson S, Cooper C, Aihie Sayer A. Nutrition and sarcopenia: a review of the evidence and implications for preventive strategies. J Aging Res. 2012;2012:510801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3312288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22506112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall BT, Gorissen SH, Pennings B, et al. Aging is accompanied by a blunted muscle protein synthetic response to protein ingestion. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0140903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26536130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abate M, Di Iorio A, Di Renzo D, et al. Frailty in the elderly: the physical dimension. Eura Medicophys. 2007;43:407&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17117147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YH, Kim KI, Paik NJ, et al. Muscle strength: a better index of low physical performance than muscle mass in older adults. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2016;16:577&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26017097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth S, Ferrell R, Hurley B. Strength training for the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia. J Nutr Health Aging. 2000;4:143&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10936901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidler RD, Bernard JA, Burutolu TB, et al. Motor control and aging: links to age-related brain structural, functional, and biochemical effects. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2010;34:721&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19850077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the national strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2019&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petriz BA, Gomes CP, Almeida JA, et al. The effects of acute and chronic exercise on skeletal muscle proteome. J Cell Physiol. 2017;232:257&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27381298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira ML, Sherrington C, Smith K, et al. Physical activity improves strength, balance and endurance in adults aged 40-65 years: a systematic review. J Physiother. 2012;58:145&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22884181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Garofolini A, Orazem J, et al. Effects of resistance training on muscle size and strength in very elderly adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Med. 2020;50:1983&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32740889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckw&#xe9;e D, Delaere A, Aelbrecht S, et al. Exercise interventions for the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia. a systematic umbrella review. J Nutr Health Aging. 2019;23:494&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31233069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JW, Kim R, Choi H, et al. Understanding of sarcopenia: from definition to therapeutic strategies. Arch Pharm Res. 2021;44:876&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gielen E, Beckw&#xe9;e D, Delaere A, et al. Nutritional interventions to improve muscle mass, muscle strength, and physical performance in older people: an umbrella review of systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Nutr Rev. 2021;79:121&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32483625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remelli F, Vitali A, Zurlo A, et al. Vitamin D deficiency and sarcopenia in older persons. Nutrients. 2019;11:2861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6950416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31766576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Studenski SA, Peters KW, Alley DE, et al. The FNIH sarcopenia project: rationale, study description, conference recommendations, and final estimates. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2014;69:547&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3991146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24737557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>