<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24707449</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2161-105X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>Suppl 9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pulmonary &amp; respiratory medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pulm Respir Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Upper-Body Resistance Training and Self-Efficacy Enhancement in COPD.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>001</StartPage><MedlinePgn>001</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Loss of skeletal muscle strength is commonly seen with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). The study aim was to determine the effects of comprehensive upper-body resistance training (8 different lifts) and a self-efficacy enhancing intervention in COPD with respect to muscle strength, symptoms, functional status and exercise adherence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This randomized trial had 3 groups: upper-body resistance training with an intervention to enhance self-efficacy (UBR + SE), upper-body resistance training and health education (UBR + HE), gentle chair exercises and health education (CE + HE). Subjects performed 16 weeks of supervised training, then 12 months of long-term maintenance at home. Outcomes were: muscle strength, dyspnea, functional status, self-efficacy, and adherence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Sixty-four subjects completed 16 wks of training: age 71 &#xb1; 8 yr, fat-free mass index 19 &#xb1; 3 kg/m<sup>2</sup>, forced expiratory volume in one second 58 &#xb1; 18 percent predicted. The UBR + SE intervention produced a 46% increase in strength compared to a 36% increase in the UBR + HE group (<i>P</i> = 0.054). The combined UBR + SE and UBR + HE groups produced a 41% increase in strength compared to an 11% increase in the CE+HE (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). The combined UBR groups also demonstrated increases in lean arm mass (<i>P</i> = 0.003) and a trend toward decreased dyspnea (<i>P</i> = 0.053). There were no group differences in attrition, attendance and training progression. Fifty subjects completed long-term maintenance and the UBR + SE and UBR + HE groups retained some gains in muscle strength, 24% and 21% respectively, and the CE + HE group lost 3% of muscle strength from baseline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study provides strong evidence that comprehensive resistance training increased strength and lean arm mass and that strength can be partially maintained through a simple home program using hand weights. It provides limited evidence that upper-body resistance training improved dyspnea and that the exercise-specific self-efficacy enhancing intervention was beneficial.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Covey</LastName><ForeName>Margaret K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biobehavioral Health Science, College of Nursing, University of Illinois at Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McAuley</LastName><ForeName>Edward</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Community Health, College of Applied Health Sciences, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kapella</LastName><ForeName>Mary C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biobehavioral Health Science, College of Nursing, University of Illinois at Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Collins</LastName><ForeName>Eileen G</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biobehavioral Health Science, College of Nursing, University of Illinois at Chicago, USA ; Department of Research and Development, Edward Hines Jr Veterans Administration Hospital, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alex</LastName><ForeName>Charles G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research and Development, Edward Hines Jr Veterans Administration Hospital, Chicago, USA ; Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Stritch School of Medicine, Loyola University, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berbaum</LastName><ForeName>Michael L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health Research and Policy, University of Illinois at Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larson</LastName><ForeName>Janet L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biobehavioral Health Science, College of Nursing, University of Illinois at Chicago, USA ; Acute, Critical and Long-Term Care Programs, School of Nursing, University of Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>M01 RR013987</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NR008037</GrantID><Acronym>NR</Acronym><Agency>NINR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Pulm Respir Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101598003</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dyspnea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24707449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS426340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3975911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2161-105X.S9-001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Shea SD, Taylor NF, Paratz JD. Progressive resistance exercise improves muscle strength and may improve elements of performance of daily activities for people with COPD: a systematic review. Chest. 2009;136:1269&#x2013;1283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19734323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries AL, Bauldoff GS, Carlin BW, Casaburi R, Emery CF, et al. Pulmonary Rehabilitation: Joint ACCP/AACVPR Evidence-Based Clinical Practice Guidelines. Chest. 2007;131:4S&#x2013;42S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda EF, Malaguti C, Corso SD. Peripheral muscle dysfunction in COPD: lower limbs versus upper limbs. J Bras Pneumol. 2011;37:380&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21755195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breslin EH. Dyspnea-limited response in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: reduced unsupported arm activities. Rehabil Nurs. 1992;17:12&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1535920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Shea SD, Taylor NF, Paratz JD. Qualitative outcomes of progressive resistance exercise for people with COPD. Chron Respir Dis. 2007;4:135&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17711912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houchen L, Steiner MC, Singh SJ. How sustainable is strength training in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease? Physiotherapy. 2009;95:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19627679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nici L, Donner C, Wouters E, Zuwallack R, Ambrosino N, et al. American Thoracic Society/European Respiratory Society statement on pulmonary rehabilitation. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2006;173:1390&#x2013;1413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16760357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E, Courneya KS, Rudolph DL, Lox CL. Enhancing exercise adherence in middle-aged males and females. Prev Med. 1994;23:498&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7971878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E, Blissmer B. Self-efficacy determinants and consequences of physical activity. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2000;28:85&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10902091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E. The role of efficacy cognitions in the prediction of exercise behavior in middle-aged adults. J Behav Med. 1992;15:65&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1583674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease. Global Strategy for the Diagnosis, Management, and Prevention of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1983;67:361&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6880820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efron B. Forcing a sequential experiment to be balanced. Biometrika. 1971;58:403&#x2013;417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Borg&#x2019;s Perceived Exertion and Pain Scale. Human Kinetics; Champaign, IL: 1998. pp. 1&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Switkes B. Safe and Enjoyable Workouts for All Ages. CC-M Productions Inc; 1994. Armchair Fitness: Gentle Exercise. [DVD]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-Efficacy: The Exercise of Control. W.H. Freeman and Co; New York, NY: 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E, Katula J, Mihalko SL, Blissmer B, Duncan TE, et al. Mode of physical activity and self-efficacy in older adults: a latent growth curve analysis. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 1999;54:283&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10542821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson JL, Covey MK, Wirtz SE, Berry JK, Alex CG, et al. Cycle ergometer and inspiratory muscle training in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1999;160:500&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10430720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black LF, Hyatt RE. Maximal respiratory pressures: normal values and relationship to age and sex. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1969;99:696&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5772056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Berman LB, Townsend M, Pugsley SO, Chambers LW. A measure of quality of life for clinical trials in chronic lung disease. Thorax. 1987;42:773&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC460950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3321537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leidy NK. Psychometric properties of the functional performance inventory in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Nurs Res. 1999;48:20&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E, Mihalko SL. In: Advances in Sport and Exercise Psychology Measurement. Duda JL, editor. Fitness Information Technology; Morgantown, W. Va: 1998. pp. 371&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanger J, Clausen JL, Coates A, Pedersen OF, Brusasco V, et al. Standardisation of the measurement of lung volumes. Eur Respir J. 2005;26:511&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16135736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyle UG, Genton L, Gremion G, Slosman DO, Pichard C. Aging, physical activity and height-normalized body composition parameters. Clin Nutr. 2004;23:79&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14757396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautmans I, Njemini R, Vasseur S, Chabert H, Moens L, et al. Biochemical changes in response to intensive resistance exercise training in the elderly. Gerontology. 2005;51:253&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15980654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janaudis-Ferreira T, Hill K, Goldstein RS, Robles-Ribeiro P, Beauchamp MK, et al. Resistance arm training in patients with COPD: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Chest. 2011;139:151&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20724740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega F, Toral J, Cejudo P, Villagomez R, S&#xe1;nchez H, et al. Comparison of effects of strength and endurance training in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;166:669&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12204863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson K, Killian K, McCartney N, Stubbing DG, Jones NL. Randomised controlled trial of weightlifting exercise in patients with chronic airflow limitation. Thorax. 1992;47:70&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC463573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1549826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruit MA, Gosselink R, Troosters T, De Paepe K, Decramer M. Resistance versus endurance training in patients with COPD and peripheral muscle weakness. Eur Respir J. 2002;19:1072&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12108859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casaburi R, Bhasin S, Cosentino L, Porszasz J, Somfay A, et al. Effects of testosterone and resistance training in men with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2004;170:870&#x2013;878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15271690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongsgaard M, Backer V, J&#xf8;rgensen K, Kjaer M, Beyer N. Heavy resistance training increases muscle size, strength and physical function in elderly male COPD-patients--a pilot study. Respir Med. 2004;98:1000&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15481277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracy BL, Ivey FM, Hurlbut D, Martel GF, Lemmer JT, et al. Muscle quality. II. Effects of strength training in 65- to 75-yr-old men and women. J Appl Physiol. 1999;86:195&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9887131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Shea SD, Taylor NF, Paratz JD. A predominantly home-based progressive resistance exercise program increases knee extensor strength in the short-term in people with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomised controlled trial. Aust J Physiother. 2007;53:229&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18047457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troosters T, Gosselink R, Decramer M. Short- and long-term effects of outpatient rehabilitation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomized trial. Am J Med. 2000;109:207&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10974183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Shea SD, Taylor NF, Paratz JD. But watch out for the weather: factors affecting adherence to progressive resistance exercise for persons with COPD. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2007;27:166&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17558200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E, Mailey EL, Mullen SP, Szabo AN, W&#xf3;jcicki TR, et al. Growth trajectories of exercise self-efficacy in older adults: influence of measures and initial status. Health Psychol. 2011;30:75&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3521039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21038962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cress ME, Buchner DM, Prohaska T, Rimmer J, Brown M, et al. Best practices for physical activity programs and behavior counseling in older adult populations. J Aging Phys Act. 2005;13:61&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15677836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obesity: preventing and managing the global epidemic. Report of a WHO consultation. World Health Organ Tech Rep Ser. 2000;894:1&#x2013;253. [No authors listed]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11234459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>