<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40403187</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute Glucose Tolerance in Response to Lower- and Higher-Load Resistance Exercise in Postmenopausal Women: Contribution of Aerobic Capacity and Body Composition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e749</StartPage><EndPage>e757</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e749-e757</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005096</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Paquin, J, St-Martin, P, Lord, S-E, Gendron, P, Brochu, M, and Dionne, IJ. Acute glucose tolerance in response to lower- and higher-load resistance exercise in postmenopausal women: Contribution of aerobic capacity and body composition. J Strength Cond Res 39(6): e749-e757, 2025-Glucose tolerance (GT), fat-free mass (FFM), and V&#x307;o2peak are known to decline after menopause. Exercise recommendations advise ageing adults to perform heavy weights and low repetitions (HWLR) resistance exercise (RE). However, the most efficient RE parameters to improve acute GT in postmenopausal women (PMW) are unclear. Our aim was to determine how acute GT is influenced by 2 RE sessions of different loads (HWLR vs. low-weight and higher repetitions, LWHR), compared with a control condition, and examine potential contributors. After measuring baseline oral glucose tolerance (OGTT), FFM (DXA), and V&#x307;o2peak (metabolic cart), 12 PMW underwent additional OGTTs (area under the curve-AUC; 2-h glucose) after 3 randomized experimental conditions (control, HWLR, and LWHR). Session volume was defined as the total weight lifted. The Cederholm's index was calculated to derive insulin sensitivity. There was a significant effect of RE on glucose AUC (1,109 &#xb1; 234 vs. 954 &#xb1; 149 and 974 &#xb1; 194 mmol/L &#xd7; 120 minutes for control, HWLR, and LWHR; p &lt; 0.005) and 2-h glucose (8.8 &#xb1; 2.5 vs. 7.0 &#xb1; 1.6 and 7.4 &#xb1; 2.0 mmol/L for control, HWLR, and LWHR; p &lt; 0.04) with no difference between HWLR and LWHR. A greater volume was achieved with LWHR (4,292.1 &#xb1; 1,143.4 vs. 3,888.1 &#xb1; 1,042.1 kg, p &lt; 0.05), although it was not significantly associated with post-RE GT. Fat-free mass was significantly associated with Cederholm's index at baseline only (r = 0.6, p &lt; 0.05). Significant correlations were also found between V&#x307;o2peak and glucose AUC for all conditions (all r &#x2264; -0.6 to 0.8; p &lt; 0.05). We conclude that HWLR and LWHR both acutely improve GT in PMW, whereas V&#x307;o2peak may be a stronger contributor than FFM.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paquin</LastName><ForeName>Jasmine</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, de L'Universit&#xe9;, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Aging, CIUSSS de L'Estrie-CHUS, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>St-Martin</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, de L'Universit&#xe9;, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Aging, CIUSSS de L'Estrie-CHUS, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Strasbourg, Center National de La Recherche Scientifique, Institut Pluridisciplinaire Hubert Curien, Strasbourg, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lord</LastName><ForeName>Sarah-&#xc8;ve</ForeName><Initials>S&#xc8;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, de L'Universit&#xe9;, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Aging, CIUSSS de L'Estrie-CHUS, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gendron</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, de L'Universit&#xe9;, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Aging, CIUSSS de L'Estrie-CHUS, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brochu</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, de L'Universit&#xe9;, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Aging, CIUSSS de L'Estrie-CHUS, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dionne</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle J</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Activity Sciences, Universit&#xe9; de Sherbrooke, de L'Universit&#xe9;, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center on Aging, CIUSSS de L'Estrie-CHUS, Sherbrooke, QC, Canada ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Chaire de recherche sur un vieillissement en sant&#xc3;&#xa9; - Fondation B. Breton et J.-L. Gravel</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postmenopause</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005951" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose Tolerance Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin sensitivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle mass</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40403187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202506000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barbat-Artigas S, Rolland Y, Vellas B, et al. Muscle quantity is not synonymous with muscle quality. J Am Med Dir Assoc 14: 852.e1&#x2013;852.e7, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Befroy DE, Petersen KF, Dufour S, et al. Impaired mitochondrial substrate oxidation in muscle of insulin-resistant offspring of type 2 diabetic patients. Diabetes 56:1376&#x2013;1381, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben DA, Fetters NL, Bemben MG, et al. Musculoskeletal responses to high-and low-intensity resistance training in early postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 1949&#x2013;1957, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binzen CA, Swan PD, Manore MM. Postexercise oxygen consumption and substrate use after resistance exercise in women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 932&#x2013;938, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black LE, Swan PD, Alvar BA. Effects of intensity and volume on insulin sensitivity during acute bouts of resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1109&#x2013;1116, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeno FP, Farinha JB, Ramis TR, et al. Effects of a single session of high-and moderate-intensity resistance exercise on endothelial function of middle-aged sedentary men. Front Physiol 10: 777, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondarev D, Laakkonen EK, Finni T, et al. Physical performance in relation to menopause status and physical activity. Menopause 25: 1432&#x2013;1441, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botero JP, Shiguemoto GE, Prestes J, et al. Effects of long-term periodized resistance training on body composition, leptin, resistin and muscle strength in elderly post-menopausal women. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 53: 289&#x2013;294, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength testing&#x2014;predicting a one-rep max from reps-to-fatigue. J Phys Educ Recreat Dance 64: 88&#x2013;90, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Andrews RJ, West DWD, et al. Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub&#x2010;fractional synthetic responses in men. J Physiol 590: 351&#x2013;362, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DWD, Staples AW, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS One 5: e12033, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnley M, Vanhatalo A, Jones AM. Distinct profiles of neuromuscular fatigue during muscle contractions below and above the critical torque in humans. J Appl Physiol 113: 215&#x2013;223, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Castro JM. The time of day of food intake influences overall intake in humans J Nutrition 134: 104&#x2013;111, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederholm J, Wibell L. Insulin release and peripheral sensitivity at the oral glucose tolerance test. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 10: 167&#x2013;175, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coen PM, Jubrias SA, Distefano G, et al. Skeletal muscle mitochondrial energetics are associated with maximal aerobic capacity and walking speed in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 68: 447&#x2013;455, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig JC, Vanhatalo A, Burnley M, et al. Critical power: Possibly the most important fatigue threshold in exercise physiology. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 2320&#x2013;2334, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimenna FJ, Arad AD. The acute vs. chronic effect of exercise on insulin sensitivity: Nothing lasts forever. Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab 10:149, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitriadis GD, Maratou E, Kountouri A, et al. Regulation of postabsorptive and postprandial glucose metabolism by insulin-dependent and insulin-independent mechanisms: An integrative approach. Nutrients 13: 159, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwan K, Li T, Altman DG, Elbourne D. CONSORT 2010 statement: Extension to randomised crossover trials. BMJ 366: l4378, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edinburgh RM, Hengist A, Smith HA, et al. Preexercise breakfast ingestion versus extended overnight fasting increases postprandial glucose flux after exercise in healthy men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 315: 1062&#x2013;1074, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: Position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2019&#x2013;2052, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Fukuda DH, Stout JR, et al. Muscle quality index improves with resistance exercise training in older adults. Exp Gerontol 53:1&#x2013;6, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghachem A, Lagac&#xe9; JC, Brochu M, et al. Fat-free mass and glucose homeostasis: Is greater fat-free mass an independent predictor of insulin resistance? Aging Clin Exp Res 31: 447&#x2013;454, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glouzon BKJ, Barsalani R, Lagace JC, et al. Muscle mass and insulin sensitivity in postmenopausal women after 6-month exercise training. Climacteric 18: 846&#x2013;851, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassi B, Rossiter HB, Zoladz JA. Skeletal muscle fatigue and decreased efficiency: Two sides of the same coin? Exerc Sport Sci Rev 43: 75&#x2013;783, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ. Are the hypertrophic adaptations to high and low-load resistance training muscle fiber type specific? Front Physiol 9: 402, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groennebaek T, Vissing K. Impact of resistance training on skeletal muscle mitochondrial biogenesis, content, and function. Front Physiol 8: 713, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houzelle A, J&#xf6;rgensen JA, Schaart G, et al. Human skeletal muscle mitochondrial dynamics in relation to oxidative capacity and insulin sensitivity. Diabetologia 64: 424&#x2013;436, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs RA, Lundby C. Mitochondria express enhanced quality as well as quantity in association with aerobic fitness across recreationally active individuals up to elite athletes. J Appl Physiol 114: 344&#x2013;350, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanaley JA, Colberg SR, Corcoran MH, et al. Exercise/physical activity in individuals with type 2 diabetes: A consensus statement from the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc 54: 353&#x2013;368, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley D, Mitrakou A, Marsh H, et al. Skeletal muscle glycolysis, oxidation, and storage of an oral glucose load. J Clin Investig 81: 1563&#x2013;1571, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadilkar SS. Musculoskeletal disorders and menopause. The J Obstet Gynecol India 69: 99&#x2013;103, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuiman P, Hopman MTE, Mensink M. Glycogen availability and skeletal muscle adaptations with endurance and resistance exercise. Nutr Metab 12: 1&#x2013;11, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambrinoudaki I, Paschou SA, Armeni E, et al. The interplay between diabetes mellitus and menopause: Clinical implications. Nat Rev Endocrinol 18: 608&#x2013;622, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeSuer DA, McCormick JH, Mayhew JL, et al. The accuracy of prediction equations for estimating 1-RM performance in the bench press, squat, and deadlift. J Strength Cond Res 11: 211&#x2013;213, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C, Kim HJ, Morton RW, et al. Resistance exercise-induced changes in muscle phenotype are load dependent. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 2578&#x2013;2585, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;hrmann PM, Herbert BM, Gaster C, et al. Validation of a self-administered 3-day estimated dietary record for use in the elderly. Eur J Nutr 38: 235&#x2013;240, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manco M, Nolfe G, Calvani M, et al. Menopause, insulin resistance, and risk factors for cardiovascular disease. Menopause 13: 809&#x2013;817, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauger AR, Sculthorpe N. A new VO2max protocol allowing self-pacing in maximal incremental exercise. Br J Sports Med 46, 59&#x2013;63, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olver TD, Laughlin MH. Endurance, interval sprint, and resistance exercise training: Impact on microvascular dysfunction in type 2 diabetes. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 310: 337&#x2013;350, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuki M, Kasayama S, Morita S, et al. Menopause, but not age, is an independent risk factor for fasting plasma glucose levels in nondiabetic women. Menopause 14: 404&#x2013;407, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paquin J, Lagac&#xe9; JC, Brochu M, et al. Exercising for insulin sensitivity&#x2013;is there a mechanistic relationship with quantitative changes in skeletal muscle mass? Front Physiol 12: 635, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry HA, Roberts MD, Kavazis AN. Human skeletal muscle mitochondrial adaptations following resistance exercise training. Int J Sports Med 41: 349&#x2013;359, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick J, Winter SL, Burnley M. Loss of knee extensor torque complexity during fatiguing isometric muscle contractions occurs exclusively above the critical torque. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 310: 1144&#x2013;1153, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pich&#xe9; M&#xc8;, Lemieux S, Corneau L, et al. Measuring insulin sensitivity in postmenopausal women covering a range of glucose tolerance: Comparison of indices derived from the oral glucose tolerance test with the euglycemic-hyperinsulinemic clamp. Metabolism 56, 1159&#x2013;1166, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polotsky H, Polotsky A. Metabolic implications of menopause. Semin Reprod Med 28: 426&#x2013;434, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior SJ, Blumenthal JB, Katzel LI, et al. Increased skeletal muscle capillarization after aerobic exercise training and weight loss improves insulin sensitivity in adults with IGT. Diabetes Care 37: 1469&#x2013;1475, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed ME, Ben-Ezra V, Biggerstaff KD, et al. The effects of two bouts of high- and low-volume resistance exercise on glucose tolerance in normoglycemic women. J Strength Cond Res 26: 251&#x2013;260, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Y, Zhang M, Liu Y, et al. Association of menopause and type 2 diabetes mellitus. Menopause 26: 325&#x2013;330, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Hargreaves M. Exercise, GLUT4, and skeletal muscle glucose uptake. Physiol Rev 93: 993&#x2013;1017, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvadego D, Domenis R, Lazzer S, et al. Skeletal muscle oxidative function in vivo and ex vivo in athletes with marked hypertrophy from resistance training. J Appl Physiol 114:1527&#x2013;1535, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd SO, Cocks M, Tipton KD, et al. Resistance training increases skeletal muscle oxidative capacity and net intramuscular triglyceride breakdown in type I and II fibres of sedentary males. Exp Physiol 99: 894&#x2013;908, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade SC, Dionne CE, Underwood M, Buchbinder R. Consensus on exercise reporting template (CERT): Explanation and elaboration statement. Br J Sports Med 50: 1428&#x2013;1437, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sligar J, DeBruin DA, Saner NJ, et al. The importance of mitochondrial quality control for maintaining skeletal muscle function across health span. Am J Physiol-Cell Physiol 322: 461&#x2013;467, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stannard SR, Buckley AJ, Edge JA, et al. Adaptations to skeletal muscle with endurance exercise training in the acutely fed versus overnight-fasted state. J Sci Med Sport 13: 465&#x2013;469, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor R, Price TB, Katz LD, et al. Direct measurement of change in muscle glycogen concentration after a mixed meal in normal subjects. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 265: 224&#x2013;229, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams N. The Borg rating of perceived exertion (RPE) scale. Occup Med 67: 404&#x2013;405, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaribeygi H, Atkin SL, Simental-Mend&#xed;a LE, et al. Molecular mechanisms by which aerobic exercise induces insulin sensitivity. J Cell Physiol 234: 12385&#x2013;12392, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaspelkis II. Resistance training improves insulin signaling and action in skeletal muscle. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 34:42&#x2013;46, 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>