<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27293507</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oxygen Consumption and Substrate Utilization During and After Resistance Exercises Performed with Different Muscle Mass.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>77</StartPage><EndPage>88</EndPage><MedlinePgn>77-88</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigated the energy expenditure (EE) and substrate utilization reflected by the respiratory-exchange ratio (RER) during and after resistance exercises performed with different muscle mass. Ten male volunteers (mean&#xb1;SD; 26&#xb1;4yr, 179&#xb1;6cm, 77&#xb1;8kg) performed multiple sets of the horizontal leg press (LP) and chest fly (CF) (5 sets of 10 repetitions with 15 repetition-maximum, 1-minute between-set intervals) in a counterbalanced design. Oxygen uptake and carbon dioxide production were measured during 40 minutes of resting; resistance exercise protocols (sets and intervals); 90 minutes of post-exercise recovery. Total fat and carbohydrate oxidation rates were calculated according to the non-protein respiratory quotient. Both exercise conditions elicited net excess post-exercise oxygen consumption (EPOC) of similar duration (approximately 40min). The EPOC magnitude at 40 minutes was greater after LP than after CF (7.36&#xb1;1.10L <i>vs</i>. 4.73&#xb1;0.99L; <i>P</i>&lt;0.001). The RER was higher in LP (1.30&#xb1;0.04) than CF (1.16&#xb1;0.05, <i>P</i>=0.0003) during exercise. During recovery the RER was similar in LP and CF (<i>P</i>&gt;0.05) and lower than pre-exercise (Pre-exercise=0.78&#xb1;0.04 <i>vs</i>. CF<sub>40min</sub>=0.74&#xb1;0.04; CF<sub>90min</sub>=0.68&#xb1;0.02 and LP<sub>50min</sub>=0.73&#xb1;0.06; LP<sub>90min</sub>=0.65&#xb1;0.04, <i>P</i>&lt;0.05). However, fat oxidation after LP was greater than CF between 30-90 minutes of recovery (mean total fat oxidation: LP=10.9 g <i>vs</i>. CF=8.4 g; <i>P</i>&lt;0.01). The increases of EE and fat oxidation during post-exercise recovery were greater after multiple sets of resistance exercises performed with larger muscle mass than smaller muscle mass. This finding has practical implications for resistance training designed as part of weight management programs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farinatti</LastName><ForeName>Paulo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Physical Activity and Health Promotion/ State University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil; Salgado de Oliveira University, Niteroi, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castinheiras Neto</LastName><ForeName>Antonio G</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Salgado de Oliveira University, Niteroi, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amorim</LastName><ForeName>Paulo R S</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education Department /Vi&#xe7;osa Federal University, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise physiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rate of respiratory ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27293507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4882463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/AKBM3973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Benton MJ, Swan PD. Effect of protein ingestion on energy expenditure and substrate utilization after exercise in middle-aged women. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(6):544&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18156660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binzen CA, Swan PD, Manore MM. Postexercise oxygen consumption and substrate use after resistance exercise in women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(6):932&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11404658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burleson MA, O&#x2019;Bryant HS, Stone MH, Collins MA, Triplett-McBride T. Effect of weight training exercise and treadmill exercise on post-exercise oxygen consumption. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30(4):518&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9565932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compher C, Frankenfield D, Keim N, Roth-Yousey L. Best practice methods to apply to measurement of resting metabolic rate in adults: a systematic review. J Am Diet Assoc. 2006;106(6):881&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16720129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, Manore MM, Rankin JW, Smith BK. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(2):459&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Bois D, Du Bois EF. A formula to estimate the approximate surface area if height and weight be known. Archives of Internal Medicine. 1916;17:863&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2520314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti P, Castinheiras Neto AG, da Silva NL. Influence of Resistance Training Variables on Excess Postexercise Oxygen Consumption: A Systematic Review. ISRN Physiology. 2013;2013:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti PT, Castinheiras Neto AG. The effect of between-set rest intervals on the oxygen uptake during and after resistance exercise sessions performed with large- and small-muscle mass. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(11):3181&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21993043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillette CA, Bullough RC, Melby CL. Postexercise energy expenditure in response to acute aerobic or resistive exercise. Int J Sport Nutr. 1994;4(4):347&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7874151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory S, Wood R, Matthews T, Vanlangen D, Sawyer J, Headley S. Substrate Utilization is Influenced by Acute Dietary Carbohydrate Intake in Active, Healthy Females. J Sports Sci Med. 2011;10(1):59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddock BL, Wilkin LD. Resistance training volume and post exercise energy expenditure. Int J Sports Med. 2006;27(2):143&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16475061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heden T, Lox C, Rose P, Reid S, Kirk EP. One-set resistance training elevates energy expenditure for 72 h similar to three sets. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(3):477&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20886227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JO, Melby C, Johnson SL, Peters JC. Physical activity and energy requirements. Am J Clin Nutr. 1995;62(5 Suppl):1059S&#x2013;66S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7484922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Generalized equations for predicting body density of men. Br J Nutr. 1978;40(3):497&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">718832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamurtas AZ, Koutedakis Y, Paschalis V, Tofas T, Yfanti C, Tsiokanos A, Koukoulis G, Kouretas D, Loupos D. The effects of a single bout of exercise on resting energy expenditure and respiratory exchange ratio. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92(4&#x2013;5):393&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeacocke NA, Burke LM. Methods to standardize dietary intake before performance testing. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20(2):87&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanaley JA, Mottram CD, Scanlon PD, Jensen MD. Fatty acid kinetic responses to running above or below lactate threshold. J Appl Physiol. 1985;1995;79(2):439&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7592200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk EP, Donnelly JE, Smith BK, Honas J, Lecheminant JD, Bailey BW, Jacobsen DJ, Washburn RA. Minimal resistance training improves daily energy expenditure and fat oxidation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(5):1122&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2862249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons S, Richardson M, Bishop P, Smith J, Heath H, Giesen J. Excess post-exercise oxygen consumption in untrained men following exercise of equal energy expenditure: comparisons of upper and lower body exercise. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2007;9(6):889&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17924871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melanson EL, Sharp TA, Seagle HM, Donahoo WT, Grunwald GK, Peters JC, Hamilton JT, Hill JO. Resistance and aerobic exercise have similar effects on 24-h nutrient oxidation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(11):1793&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12439085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melanson EL, Sharp TA, Seagle HM, Donahoo WT, Grunwald GK, Peters JC, Hamilton JT, Hill JO. Twenty-four-hour metabolic responses to resistance exercise in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(1):61&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melby C, Scholl C, Edwards G, Bullough R. Effect of acute resistance exercise on postexercise energy expenditure and resting metabolic rate. J Appl Physiol. 1985;1993;75(4):1847&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8282641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academy of Sciences. Dietary Reference Intakes for Energy, Carbohydrate, Fiber, Fat, Fatty Acids, Cholesterol, Protein, and Amino Acids (Macronutrients): A Report of the Panel on Macronutrients, Subcommittees on Upper Reference Levels of Nutrients and Interpretation and Uses of Dietary Reference Intakes, and the Standing Committee on the Scientific Evaluation of Dietary Reference Intakes. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Diet, Nutrition, and Prevention of Chronic Disease. Geneve: World Health Organization; 2003. (Technical Report Series 916).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12768890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormsbee MJ, Thyfault JP, Johnson EA, Kraus RM, Choi MD, Hickner RC. Fat metabolism and acute resistance exercise in trained men. J Appl Physiol. 1985;2007;102(5):1767&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17234805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osterberg KL, Melby CL. Effect of acute resistance exercise on postexercise oxygen consumption and resting metabolic rate in young women. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2000;10(1):71&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10939877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascoe DD, Costill DL, Fink WJ, Robergs RA, Zachwieja JJ. Glycogen resynthesis in skeletal muscle following resistive exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1993;25(3):349&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8455450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peronnet F, Massicotte D. Table of nonprotein respiratory quotient: an update. Can J Sport Sci. 1991;16(1):23&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1645211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Falvo MJ, Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Faigenbaum AD, Kang J. The effect of rest interval length on metabolic responses to the bench press exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100(1):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17237951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robergs RA, Gordon T, Reynolds J, Walker TB. Energy expenditure during bench press and squat exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(1):123&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romijn JA, Coyle EF, Hibbert J, Wolfe RR. Comparison of indirect calorimetry and a new breath 13C/12C ratio method during strenuous exercise. Am J Physiol. 1992;263(1 Pt 1):E64&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1636700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. Body composition from fluid space and density. In: Brozek J, Henschel A, editors. Techniques for measuring body composition. Washington, DC: National Academy of Science; 1961. pp. 223&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton MK, Potteiger JA. Effects of resistance exercise bouts of different intensities but equal work on EPOC. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(4):715&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>