<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37607390</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Female Soccer Periodization on Anaerobic Power/Capacity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2405</StartPage><EndPage>2410</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2405-2410</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004555</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Purdom, TM, Levers, KS, Ryan, GA, Brown, L, Giles, J, and McPherson, C. Female soccer periodization on anaerobic power/capacity. J Strength Cond Res 37(12): 2405-2410, 2023-The purpose of this study was to observe changes in anaerobic power and capacity (resistance to fatigue) over an annual training cycle (ATC) in 14 Division I female soccer athletes (19.4 &#xb1; 1.0 years, 60.8 &#xb1; 5.4 kg, 164.9 &#xb1; 6.2 cm, 19.5 &#xb1; 3.2% body fat, and 48.9 &#xb1; 3.9 kg fat free mass). All subjects were evaluated across the ATC at 5 testing blocks (B1-B5) representing seasonal transitions: postcompetition I (B1), prespring (B2), postspring training (B3), precompetition (B4), and postcompetition II (B5) using 3 tests: countermovement vertical jump to measure peak vertical power (PVP), 40-yard sprint to measure peak horizontal power (PHP), and 35-m running anaerobic sprint test to measure anaerobic capacity via fatigue index (FI). Repeated measures analysis of variance was used with the Bonferroni post hoc test when relevant along with Cohen's d to evaluate effect size. Data are represented as mean &#xb1; SD ; significance set to p &lt; 0.05. Significant performance increases were observed from postseason I to spring season training (B1-B3) in PVP (6.61 &#xb1; 3.18 and 7.71 &#xb1; 3.20; p &lt; 0.01, d = 1.12) while changes occurred from prespring season to postspring season (B2-B3) in PVP (6.84 &#xb1; 3.15 and 7.71 &#xb1; 3.20; p = 0.03, d = 0.93) and PHP (6.65 &#xb1; 0.97 and 7.55 &#xb1; 1.26; p &lt; 0.01, d = 1.06) with no change in body composition. No other significant changes were observed across the ATC ( p &gt; 0.05). Increases in PHP and PVP occurred with directed training after B3 and then declined remaining so across the competitive season. Peak horizontal power and PVP may be more sensitive to coaching style and seasonal transition compared with FI and body composition changes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purdom</LastName><ForeName>Troy M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, North Carolina Agriculture and Technical State University, Greensboro, North Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levers</LastName><ForeName>Kyle S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, The George Washington University, Washington, District of Columbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ryan</LastName><ForeName>Gregory A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, College of Nursing and Health Sciences, Piedmont University, Demorest, Georgia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Lindsey</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Athletic Training, Recreation, and Kinesiology, Longwood University, Farmville, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giles</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Athletic Training, Recreation, and Kinesiology, Longwood University, Farmville, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McPherson</LastName><ForeName>Chase</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Athletic Training, Recreation, and Kinesiology, Longwood University, Farmville, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000693" MajorTopicYN="N">Anaerobiosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37607390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202312000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alves RN, Oliveira L, Costa P, Samulski DM. Monitoring and prevention of overtraining in athletes. Rev Bras Med 12: 262&#x2013;266, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Philadelphia, PA: Lippencott Willimas &amp; Wilkins, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson AG, Lavallee D. Applying the theories of reasoned action and planned behavior to athlete training adherence behavior. Appl Psychol 57: 304&#x2013;312, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bro&#x17e;ek J, Grande F, Anderson JT, Keys A. Densitometric analysis of body composition: Revision of some quantitative assumptions. Ann N Y Acad Sci 110: 113&#x2013;140, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell BP, Peters DM. Seasonal variation in physiological fitness of a semiprofessional soccer team. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1370&#x2013;1377, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canavan PK, Vescovi JD. Evaluation of power prediction equations: Peak vertical jumping power in women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 1589&#x2013;1593, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtara M, Chamari K, Chaouachi M, et al. Effects of intra-session concurrent endurance and strength training sequence on aerobic performance and capacity. Br J Sports Med 39: 555&#x2013;560, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dambroz F, Clemente FM, Teoldo I. The effect of physical fatigue on the performance of soccer players: A systematic review. PLoS One 17: e0270099, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datson N, Drust B, Weston M, et al. Match physical performance of elite female soccer players during international competition. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2379&#x2013;2387, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datson N, Hulton A, Andersson H, et al. Applied physiology of female soccer: An update. Sports Med 44: 1225&#x2013;1240, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper N, Whyte G. Here's a new running based test of anaerobic performance for which you need only a stopwatch and a calculator. Peak Perform 96: 3&#x2013;5, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmonds S, Nicholson G, Begg C, Jones B, Bissas A. Importance of physical qualities for speed and change of direction ability in elite female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1669&#x2013;1677, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. The training-injury prevention paradox: Should athletes be training smarter and harder? Br J Sports Med 50: 273&#x2013;280, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harman EA, Rosenstein MT, Frykman PN, Rosenstein RM, Kraemer WJ. Estimation of human power output from vertical jump. J Strength Cond Res 5: 116&#x2013;120, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann H, Wirth K, Keiner M, et al. Short-term periodization models: Effects on strength and speed-strength performance. Sports Med 45: 1373&#x2013;1386, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics: A new view of statistics. 2002. Available at: http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/effectmag.html . Accessed June 30, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, French DN, Paxton NJ, et al. Changes in exercise performance and hormonal concentrations over a big ten soccer season in starters and nonstarters. J Strength Cond Res 18: 121&#x2013;128, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann JB, Ivey PJ, Brechue WF, Mayhew JL. Validity and reliability of hand and electronic timing for 40-yd sprint in college football players. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1509&#x2013;1514, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Duclos M, Foster C, et al. Prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of the overtraining syndrome: Joint consensus statement of the European college of sport science and the American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 186&#x2013;205, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller TA, Thierry-Aguilera R, Congleton JJ, et al. Seasonal changes in VO2max among Division 1A collegiate women soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 21: 48&#x2013;51, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobari H, Tubagi Polito LF, Clemente FM, et al. Relationships between training workload parameters with variations in anaerobic power and change of direction status in elite youth soccer players. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 7934, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peart AN, Nicks CR, Mangum MM, Tyo BM. Evaluation of seasonal changes in fitness, anthropometrics, and body composition in collegiate Division II female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 32: 2010&#x2013;2017, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdom TM, Levers KS, Giles J, et al. Accumulative competitive season training stress affects neuromuscular function and increases injury risk in uninjured D1 female athletes. Front Sports Act Living 2: 610475, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdom TM, Levers KS, McPherson CS, Giles J, Brown L. A longitudinal prospective study: The effect of annual seasonal transition and coaching influence on aerobic capacity and body composition in Division I female soccer players. Sports 8: 107, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe6;ther SA, Aspvik NP. Seasonal variation in objectively assessed physical activity among young Norwegian talented soccer players: A description of daily physical activity level. J Sports Sci Med 13: 964&#x2013;968, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JR, Brito J, Akenhead R, Nassis GP. The transition period in soccer: A window of opportunity. Sports Med 46: 305&#x2013;313, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;nnessen E, Hem E, Leirstein S, Haugen T, Seiler S. Maximal aerobic power characteristics of male professional soccer players, 1989&#x2013;2012. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 8: 323&#x2013;329, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, et al. Concurrent training: A meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2293&#x2013;2307, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagatto AM, Beck WR, Gobatto CA. Validity of the running anaerobic sprint test for assessing anaerobic power and predicting short-distance performances. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1820&#x2013;1827, 2009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>