<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39271931</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5497</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of obesity (2005)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Obes (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health-enhancing physical activity in obesity management: the need to (seriously) go beyond weight loss.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>211</StartPage><EndPage>213</EndPage><MedlinePgn>211-213</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41366-024-01632-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There are many false hopes around the impact of physical activity and exercise in obesity management, especially regarding weight loss. Narrowly focusing on weight loss only leads to disappointment for patients and practitioners. Indeed, in persons with overweight or obesity, exercise training, specifically aerobic (i.e. endurance) training, is associated with significant additional weight and fat loss compared to the absence of training. However the magnitude of this effect remains modest, amounting to only 2-3&#x2009;kg additional weight or fat loss on average. We therefore argue that this conversation needs to be re-oriented towards the many potential health benefits of physical activity that can be seen beyond weight loss. Exercise training has been shown to improve the cardiometabolic risk profile by effects including decreasing abdominal visceral fat and improving insulin sensitivity. Aerobic, as well as combined aerobic and resistance (i.e. strength) training, increase cardiorespiratory fitness, a major risk factor for ill health. Resistance training improves muscle strength, another major component of physical fitness, even in the absence of a significant change in muscle mass. Beyond body mass loss, recognizing the broad value of physical activity/exercise in improving health and quality of life of people with obesity is a crucial perspective shift.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oppert</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Michel</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0324-4820</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re Hospital, Assistance Publique-H&#xf4;pitaux de Paris (AP-HP), Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, CRNH-Ile de France, F-75013, Paris, France. jean-michel.oppert@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Sorbonne Paris Nord and Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, INSERM, INRAE, CNAM, Center of Research in Epidemiology and StatisticS (CRESS), Nutritional Epidemiology Research Team (EREN), F-93017, Bobigny, France. jean-michel.oppert@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciangura</LastName><ForeName>C&#xe9;cile</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Piti&#xe9;-Salp&#xea;tri&#xe8;re Hospital, Assistance Publique-H&#xf4;pitaux de Paris (AP-HP), Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, CRNH-Ile de France, F-75013, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellicha</LastName><ForeName>Alice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5572-487X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Sorbonne Paris Nord and Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, INSERM, INRAE, CNAM, Center of Research in Epidemiology and StatisticS (CRESS), Nutritional Epidemiology Research Team (EREN), F-93017, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Obes (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101256108</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0307-0565</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073319" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity Management</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Loss</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39271931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41366-024-01632-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41366-024-01632-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title/><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO Guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behavior. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2020. WHO Physical activity guidelines 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppert J-M, Bellicha A, van Baak MA, Battista F, Beaulieu K, Blundell JE, et al. Exercise training in the management of overweight and obesity in adults: Synthesis of the evidence and recommendations from the European Association for the Study of Obesity Physical Activity Working Group. Obes Rev. 2021;22:e13273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34076949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8365734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellicha A, van Baak MA, Battista F, Beaulieu K, Blundell JE, Busetto L, et al. Effect of exercise training on weight loss, body composition changes, and weight maintenance in adults with overweight or obesity: An overview of 12 systematic reviews and 149 studies. Obes Rev. 2021;22:e13256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33955140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8365736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellicha A, van Baak MA, Battista F, Beaulieu K, Blundell JE, Busetto L, et al. Effect of exercise training before and after bariatric surgery: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2021;22:e13296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8365633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allison DB, Bier DM, Locher JL. Measurement rigor is not a substitute for design rigor in causal inference: increased physical activity does cause (modest) weight loss. Int J Obes. 2023;47:3&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41366-022-01234-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pontzer H. Exercise is essential for health but a poor tool for weight loss: a reply to Allison and colleagues. Int J Obes (Lond). 2023;47:98&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41366-022-01248-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36526732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DM, Bouchard C, Church T, Slentz C, Kraus WE, Redman LM, et al. Why do individuals not lose more weight from an exercise intervention at a defined dose? An energy balance analysis. Obes Rev. 2012;13:835&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2012.01012.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22681398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3771367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Guardia L, Shin AC. Obesity-induced tissue alterations resist weight loss: A mechanistic review. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2024;26:3045&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.15637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38720199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su L, Fu J, Sun S, Zhao G, Cheng W, Dou C, et al. Effects of HIIT and MICT on cardiovascular risk factors in adults with overweight and/or obesity: A meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0210644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0210644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30689632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6349321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhurandhar EJ, Kaiser KA, Dawson JA, Alcorn AS, Keating KD, Allison DB. Predicting adult weight change in the real world: a systematic review and meta-analysis accounting for compensatory changes in energy intake or expenditure. Int J Obes. 2015;39:1181&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2014.184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stubbs RJ, Sepp A, Hughes DA, Johnstone AM, King N, Horgan G, et al. The effect of graded levels of exercise on energy intake and balance in free-living women. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2002;26:866&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0801874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12037658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu K, Hopkins M, Blundell J, Finlayson G. Homeostatic and non-homeostatic appetite control along the spectrum of physical activity levels: An updated perspective. Physiol Behav. 2018;192:23&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2017.12.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29289613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Careau V, Halsey LG, Pontzer H, Ainslie PN, Andersen LF, Anderson LJ, et al. Energy compensation and adiposity in humans. Curr Biol. 2021;31:4659&#x2013;66. e2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cub.2021.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34453886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8551017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King NA, Hopkins M, Caudwell P, Stubbs RJ, Blundell JE. Individual variability following 12 weeks of supervised exercise: identification and characterization of compensation for exercise-induced weight loss. Int J Obes (Lond). 2008;32:177&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0803712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17848941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gepner Y, Shelef I, Schwarzfuchs D, Zelicha H, Tene L, Yaskolka Meir A, et al. Effect of distinct lifestyle interventions on mobilization of fat storage pools: CENTRAL Magnetic Resonance Imaging Randomized Controlled Trial. Circulation. 2018;137:1143&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.117.030501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29142011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battista F, Ermolao A, van Baak MA, Beaulieu K, Blundell JE, Busetto L, et al. Effect of exercise on cardiometabolic health of adults with overweight or obesity: Focus on blood pressure, insulin resistance, and intrahepatic fat-A systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2021;22:e13269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33960110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8365642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laaksonen DE, Lindstr&#xf6;m J, Lakka TA, Eriksson JG, Niskanen L, Wikstr&#xf6;m K, et al. Physical activity in the prevention of type 2 diabetes: the Finnish. diabetes Prev study Diabetes 2005;54:158&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PAGAC. Physical Activity Guidelines Advisory Comittee Report. Washington, DC: US Department of Health and Human Services; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers J, Prakash M, Froelicher V, Do D, Partington S, Atwood JE. Exercise capacity and mortality among men referred for exercise testing. N. Engl J Med. 2002;346:793&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa011858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11893790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenholm S, Mehta NK, Elo IT, Heli&#xf6;vaara M, Koskinen S, Aromaa A. Obesity and muscle strength as long-term determinants of all-cause mortality&#x2013;a 33-year follow-up of the Mini-Finland Health Examination Survey. Int J Obes (Lond). 2014;38:1126&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2013.214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24232499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Baak MA, Pramono A, Battista F, Beaulieu K, Blundell JE, Busetto L, et al. Effect of different types of regular exercise on physical fitness in adults with overweight or obesity: Systematic review and meta-analyses. Obes Rev. 2021;22:e13239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33939229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8365680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis ME, Blake C, Perrotta C, Cunningham C, O&#x2019;Donoghue G. Impact of training modes on fitness and body composition in women with obesity: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Obesity. 2022;30:300&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.23305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35088563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppert JM, Ciangura C, Bellicha A. Physical activity and exercise for weight loss and maintenance in people living with obesity. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2023;24:937&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11154-023-09805-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37142892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>