<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21899736</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-7075</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leucine supplementation improves adiponectin and total cholesterol concentrations despite the lack of changes in adiposity or glucose homeostasis in rats previously exposed to a high-fat diet.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>62</StartPage><MedlinePgn>62</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1743-7075-8-62</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Studies suggest that leucine supplementation (LS) has a therapeutic potential to prevent obesity and to promote glucose homeostasis. Furthermore, regular physical exercise is a widely accepted strategy for body weight maintenance and also for the prevention of obesity. The aim of this study was to determine the effect of chronic LS alone or combined with endurance training (ET) as potential approaches for reversing the insulin resistance and obesity induced by a high-fat diet (HFD) in rats.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty-seven rats were randomly divided into two groups. Animals were fed a control diet-low fat (n = 10) or HFD (n = 37). After 15 weeks on HFD, all rats received the control diet-low fat and were randomly divided according to treatment: reference (REF), LS, ET, and LS+ET (n = 7-8 rats per group). After 6 weeks of treatment, the animals were sacrificed and body composition, fat cell volume, and serum concentrations of total cholesterol, HDL-cholesterol, triacylglycerol, glucose, adiponectin, leptin and tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-&#x3b1;) were analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At the end of the sixth week of treatment, there was no significant difference in body weight between the REF, LS, ET and LS+ET groups. However, ET increased lean body mass in rats (P = 0.019). In addition, ET was more effective than LS in reducing adiposity (P = 0.019), serum insulin (P = 0.022) and TNF-&#x3b1; (P = 0.044). Conversely, LS increased serum adiponectin (P = 0.021) levels and reduced serum total cholesterol concentration (P = 0.042).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results showed that LS had no beneficial effects on insulin sensitivity or adiposity in previously obese rats. On the other hand, LS was effective in increasing adiponectin levels and in reducing total cholesterol concentration.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres-Leal</LastName><ForeName>Francisco L</ForeName><Initials>FL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Experimental Nutrition, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil. torresleal@usp.br.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fonseca-Alaniz</LastName><ForeName>Miriam H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teodoro</LastName><ForeName>Gabriela Fr</ForeName><Initials>GF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Capitani</LastName><ForeName>Mariana D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vianna</LastName><ForeName>Daiana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pantale&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Lucas C</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matos-Neto</LastName><ForeName>Emidio M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rogero</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donato</LastName><ForeName>Jose</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tirapegui</LastName><ForeName>Julio</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-7075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21899736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3184043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-8-62</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1743-7075-8-62</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arcari DP, Bartchewsky W, dos Santos TW, Oliveira KA, Funck A, Pedrazzoli J, de Souza MF, Saad MJ, Bastos DH, Gambero A. et al. Antiobesity effects of yerba mate extract (Ilex paraguariensis) in high-fat diet-induced obese mice. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009;17:2127&#x2013;2133. doi: 10.1038/oby.2009.158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2009.158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19444227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prada PO, Hirabara SM, de Souza CT, Schenka AA, Zecchin HG, Vassallo J, Velloso LA, Carneiro E, Carvalheira JB, Curi R, Saad MJ. L-glutamine supplementation induces insulin resistance in adipose tissue and improves insulin signalling in liver and muscle of rats with diet-induced obesity. Diabetologia. 2007;50:1949&#x2013;1959. doi: 10.1007/s00125-007-0723-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-007-0723-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17604977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotamisligil GS. Inflammation and metabolic disorders. Nature. 2006;444:860&#x2013;867. doi: 10.1038/nature05485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature05485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donato J, Pedrosa RG, de Araujo JA, Pires IS, Tirapegui J. Effects of leucine and phenylalanine supplementation during intermittent periods of food restriction and refeeding in adult rats. Life Sci. 2007;81:31&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1016/j.lfs.2007.04.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2007.04.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17512018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donato J, Pedrosa RG, Cruzat VF, Pires IS, Tirapegui J. Effects of leucine supplementation on the body composition and protein status of rats submitted to food restriction. Nutrition. 2006;22:520&#x2013;527. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2005.12.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2005.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16600817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halton TL, Hu FB. The effects of high protein diets on thermogenesis, satiety and weight loss: a critical review. J Am Coll Nutr. 2004;23:373&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15466943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK. The role of leucine in weight loss diets and glucose homeostasis. J Nutr. 2003;133:261S&#x2013;267S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12514305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Guo K, LeBlanc RE, Loh D, Schwartz GJ, Yu YH. Increasing dietary leucine intake reduces diet-induced obesity and improves glucose and cholesterol metabolism in mice via multimechanisms. Diabetes. 2007;56:1647&#x2013;1654. doi: 10.2337/db07-0123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db07-0123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17360978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nairizi A, She P, Vary TC, Lynch CJ. Leucine supplementation of drinking water does not alter susceptibility to diet-induced obesity in mice. J Nutr. 2009;139:715&#x2013;719. doi: 10.3945/jn.108.100081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.108.100081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2666366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19244380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cota D, Proulx K, Smith KA, Kozma SC, Thomas G, Woods SC, Seeley RJ. Hypothalamic mTOR signaling regulates food intake. Science. 2006;312:927&#x2013;930. doi: 10.1126/science.1124147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1124147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16690869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch CJ, Gern B, Lloyd C, Hutson SM, Eicher R, Vary TC. Leucine in food mediates some of the postprandial rise in plasma leptin concentrations. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291:E621&#x2013;630. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00462.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00462.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16638821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumer RM, van Roomen CP, Meijer AJ, Houben-Weerts JH, Sauerwein HP, Dubbelhuis PF. Regulation of adiponectin secretion by insulin and amino acids in 3T3-L1 adipocytes. Metabolism. 2008;57:1655&#x2013;1662. doi: 10.1016/j.metabol.2008.07.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2008.07.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19013287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Zemel MB. Leucine and calcium regulate fat metabolism and energy partitioning in murine adipocytes and muscle cells. Lipids. 2007;42:297&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1007/s11745-007-3029-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11745-007-3029-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17406924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakicic JM. The effect of physical activity on body weight. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009;17 Suppl 3:S34&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, Manore MM, Rankin JW, Smith BK. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:459&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloan RP, Shapiro PA, Demeersman RE, McKinley PS, Tracey KJ, Slavov I, Fang Y, Flood PD. Aerobic exercise attenuates inducible TNF production in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103:1007&#x2013;1011. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00147.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00147.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17626836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pischon T, Hankinson SE, Hotamisligil GS, Rifai N, Rimm EB. Leisure-time physical activity and reduced plasma levels of obesity-related inflammatory markers. Obes Res. 2003;11:1055&#x2013;1064. doi: 10.1038/oby.2003.145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2003.145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12972675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim S, Choi SH, Jeong IK, Kim JH, Moon MK, Park KS, Lee HK, Kim YB, Jang HC. Insulin-sensitizing effects of exercise on adiponectin and retinol-binding protein-4 concentrations in young and middle-aged women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2008;93:2263&#x2013;2268. doi: 10.1210/jc.2007-2028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2007-2028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18334592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo T, Kobayashi I, Murakami M. Effect of exercise on circulating adipokine levels in obese young women. Endocr J. 2006;53:189&#x2013;195. doi: 10.1507/endocrj.53.189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1507/endocrj.53.189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16618976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Evans E, Baum JI, Seyler J, Erickson DJ, Boileau RA. Dietary protein and exercise have additive effects on body composition during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2005;135:1903&#x2013;1910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16046715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves PG, Nielsen FH, Fahey GC Jr. AIN-93 purified diets for laboratory rodents: final report of the American Institute of Nutrition ad hoc writing committee on the reformulation of the AIN-76A rodent diet. J Nutr. 1993;123:1939&#x2013;1951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8229312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsubuku S, Hatayama K, Katsumata T, Nishimura N, Mawatari K, Smriga M, Kimura T. Thirteen-week oral toxicity study of branched-chain amino acids in rats. Int J Toxicol. 2004;23:119&#x2013;126. doi: 10.1080/10915810490444424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10915810490444424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15204732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeanandin G, Balage M, Schneider SM, Dupont J, Hebuterne X, Mothe-Satney I, Dardevet D. Differential effect of long-term leucine supplementation on skeletal muscle and adipose tissue in old rats: an insulin signaling pathway approach. Age (Dordr) 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3312629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21472380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Araujo JA, Falavigna G, Rogero MM, Pires IS, Pedrosa RG, Castro IA, Donato J, Tirapegui J. Effect of chronic supplementation with branched-chain amino acids on the performance and hepatic and muscle glycogen content in trained rats. Life Sci. 2006;79:1343&#x2013;1348. doi: 10.1016/j.lfs.2006.03.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2006.03.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16698042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogero MM, Tirapegui J, Pedrosa RG, Castro IA, Pires IS. Effect of alanyl-glutamine supplementation on plasma and tissue glutamine concentrations in rats submitted to exhaustive exercise. Nutrition. 2006;22:564&#x2013;571. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2005.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2005.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16472983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodbell M. Metabolism of Isolated Fat Cells. I. Effects of Hormones on Glucose Metabolism and Lipolysis. J Biol Chem. 1964;239:375&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14169133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine JB, DiGirolamo M. A simple method to predict cellular density in adipocyte metabolic incubations. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1997;21:764&#x2013;768. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0800469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0800469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9376888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White JA, Hart RJ, Fry JC. An evaluation of the Waters Pico-Tag system for the amino-acid analysis of food materials. J Automat Chem. 1986;8:170&#x2013;177. doi: 10.1155/S1463924686000330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/S1463924686000330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2547673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18925132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagen SR, Frost B, Augustin J. Precolumn phenylisothiocyanate derivatization and liquid chromatography of amino acids in food. J Assoc Off Anal Chem. 1989;72:912&#x2013;916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2592313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Boileau RA, Erickson DJ, Painter JE, Shiue H, Sather C, Christou DD. A reduced ratio of dietary carbohydrate to protein improves body composition and blood lipid profiles during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2003;133:411&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12566476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Walker DA. Potential importance of leucine in treatment of obesity and the metabolic syndrome. J Nutr. 2006;136:319S&#x2013;323S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourier A, Bigard AX, de Kerviler E, Roger B, Legrand H, Guezennec CY. Combined effects of caloric restriction and branched-chain amino acid supplementation on body composition and exercise performance in elite wrestlers. Int J Sports Med. 1997;18:47&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-972594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-972594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9059905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa RG, Donato J, Pires IS, Tirapegui J. Leucine supplementation favors liver protein status but does not reduce body fat in rats during 1 week of food restriction. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2010;35:180&#x2013;183. doi: 10.1139/H09-132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/H09-132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Filho MA, Ropelle ER, Pauli RJ, Cintra DE, Tsukumo DM, Silveira LR, Curi R, Carvalheira JB, Velloso LA, Saad MJ. Aspirin attenuates insulin resistance in muscle of diet-induced obese rats by inhibiting inducible nitric oxide synthase production and S-nitrosylation of IRbeta/IRS-1 and Akt. Diabetologia. 2009;52:2425&#x2013;2434. doi: 10.1007/s00125-009-1498-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-009-1498-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19730809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanski M, Degasperi G, Coope A, Morari J, Denis R, Cintra DE, Tsukumo DM, Anhe G, Amaral ME, Takahashi HK. et al. Saturated fatty acids produce an inflammatory response predominantly through the activation of TLR4 signaling in hypothalamus: implications for the pathogenesis of obesity. J Neurosci. 2009;29:359&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6664935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19144836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrabarti P, English T, Shi J, Smas CM, Kandror KV. Mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 suppresses lipolysis, stimulates lipogenesis, and promotes fat storage. Diabetes. 2010;59:775&#x2013;781. doi: 10.2337/db09-1602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db09-1602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2844824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20068142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polak P, Cybulski N, Feige JN, Auwerx J, Ruegg MA, Hall MN. Adipose-specific knockout of raptor results in lean mice with enhanced mitochondrial respiration. Cell Metab. 2008;8:399&#x2013;410. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2008.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2008.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19046571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshiro N, Yoshino K, Hidayat S, Tokunaga C, Hara K, Eguchi S, Avruch J, Yonezawa K. Dissociation of raptor from mTOR is a mechanism of rapamycin-induced inhibition of mTOR function. Genes Cells. 2004;9:359&#x2013;366. doi: 10.1111/j.1356-9597.2004.00727.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1356-9597.2004.00727.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15066126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinault C, Mothe-Satney I, Gautier N, Lawrence JC, Van Obberghen E. Amino acids and leucine allow insulin activation of the PKB/mTOR pathway in normal adipocytes treated with wortmannin and in adipocytes from db/db mice. FASEB J. 2004;18:1894&#x2013;1896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15479767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley RL, Jeon JY, Liu FF, Maratos-Flier E. Voluntary exercise improves insulin sensitivity and adipose tissue inflammation in diet-induced obese mice. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295:E586&#x2013;594. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00309.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00309.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2536732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HH, Huang J, Duvel K, Boback B, Wu S, Squillace RM, Wu CL, Manning BD. Insulin stimulates adipogenesis through the Akt-TSC2-mTORC1 pathway. PLoS One. 2009;4:e6189. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0006189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0006189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2703782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19593385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Leal FL, Fonseca-Alaniz MH, Rogero MM, Tirapegui J. The role of inflamed adipose tissue in the insulin resistance. Cell Biochem Funct. 2010;28:623&#x2013;631. doi: 10.1002/cbf.1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbf.1706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21104928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajvani UB, Du X, Combs TP, Berg AH, Rajala MW, Schulthess T, Engel J, Brownlee M, Scherer PE. Structure-function studies of the adipocyte-secreted hormone Acrp30/adiponectin. Implications for metabolic regulation and bioactivity. J Biol Chem. 2003;278:9073&#x2013;9085. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M207198200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M207198200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12496257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ropelle ER, Pauli JR, Fernandes MF, Rocco SA, Marin RM, Morari J, Souza KK, Dias MM, Gomes-Marcondes MC, Gontijo JA. et al. A central role for neuronal AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) and mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) in high-protein diet-induced weight loss. Diabetes. 2008;57:594&#x2013;605. doi: 10.2337/db07-0573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db07-0573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>