<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37442370</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-9649</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>90</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ageing research reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ageing Res Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids in sarcopenia management: A network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102014</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102014</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.arr.2023.102014</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1568-1637(23)00173-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sarcopenia frequently occurs with aging and leads to major adverse impacts on activities of daily living and quality of life in elderly individuals. Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acid (omega-3 PUFAs) supplements are considered promising therapeutic agents for sarcopenia management; however, the evidence remains inconsistent. We reviewed randomized controlled trials (RCTs) about omega-3 PUFA supplementation in patients with sarcopenia or in those at high risk for sarcopenia. Network meta-analysis (NMA) procedures were conducted using a frequentist model. The primary outcomes were (1) upper-extremity muscle strength and (2) lower-extremity physical function. The NMA of 16 RCTs showed that the high-dose (more than 2.5&#xa0;g/day omega-3 PUFAs) group yielded the greatest improvement in both upper-extremity muscle strength and lower-extremity physical function [compared to placebo/standard care groups, standardized mean difference (SMD)=&#xa0;1.68, 95% confidence interval (95%CI)=&#xa0;0.03-3.33, and SMD=&#xa0;0.73, 95%CI=&#xa0;0.16-1.30, respectively], and the effects were reaffirmed in subgroup analyses of placebo-controlled RCTs or those excluding concurrent resistance training programs. None of the investigated omega-3 PUFAs supplementation was associated with significantly increased skeletal muscle mass, fat mass, or overall body weight. Our findings provide a basis for future large-scale RCTs to investigate the dose effects and clinical application of omega-3 PUFA supplementation in sarcopenia management. TRIAL REGISTRATION: The current study was approved by the Institutional Review Board of the Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan (TSGHIRB No. B-109-29) and registered in PROSPERO (CRD42022347161).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tseng</LastName><ForeName>Ping-Tao</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; Department of Psychology, College of Medical and Health Science, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan; Prospect Clinic for Otorhinolaryngology &amp; Neurology, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; Institute of Precision Medicine, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Bing-Yan</ForeName><Initials>BY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; Department of Internal Medicine, E-Da Dachang Hospital, I-Shou University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Bing-Syuan</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, E-Da Cancer Hospital, I-Shou University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; Institute of Biomedical Sciences, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Chi</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, College of Medical and Health Science, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan; Clinical Psychology Center, Asia University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan; Center for Prevention and Treatment of Internet Addiction, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stubbs</LastName><ForeName>Brendon</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological Medicine, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK; Physiotherapy Department, South London and Maudsley NHS Foundation Trust, London, UK; Faculty of Health, Social Care Medicine and Education, Anglia Ruskin University, Chelmsford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>John S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience and Brain Disease Center, China Medical University,Taichung, Taiwan; Graduate Institute of Biomedical Sciences, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Cheuk-Kwan</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, E-Da Dachang Hospital, I-Shou University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; School of Medicine for International Students, I-Shou University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Shian</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; Department of Psychiatry, Tsyr-Huey Mental Hospital, Kaohsiung Jen-Ai's Home, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yen-Wen</ForeName><Initials>YW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prospect Clinic for Otorhinolaryngology &amp; Neurology, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Tien-Yu</ForeName><Initials>TY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan; Department of Psychiatry, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan; Institute of Brain Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei 112, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Kang</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Epidemiology &amp; Preventive Medicine, College of Public Health, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan; Department of Dentistry, National Taiwan University Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Pao-Yen</ForeName><Initials>PY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Kaohsiung Chang Gung Memorial Hospital and Chang Gung University College of Medicine, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; Institute for Translational Research in Biomedical Sciences, Kaohsiung Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Wei</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Kaohsiung Chang Gung Memorial Hospital and Chang Gung University College of Medicine, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Dian-Jeng</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Addiction Science, Kaohsiung Municipal Kai-Syuan Psychiatric Hospital, Kaohsiung City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Sung</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan; Department of Psychiatry, Beitou Branch, Tri-Service General Hospital, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan; Graduate Institute of Medical Sciences, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suen</LastName><ForeName>Mein-Woei</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, College of Medical and Health Science, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan; Gender Equality Education and Research Center, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan; Department of Medical Research, Asia University Hospital, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan; Department of Medical Research, China Medical University Hospital, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Landseed International Hospital, Taoyuan, Taiwan. Electronic address: Keanu.firefox@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiue</LastName><ForeName>Yow-Ling</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan; Institute of Precision Medicine, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung City, Taiwan. Electronic address: shirley@imst.nsysu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Pin</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological Medicine, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK; Mind-Body Interface Research Center (MBI-Lab), China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan; College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan; An-Nan Hospital, China Medical University, Tainan, Taiwan. Electronic address: cobolsu@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000099094">Network Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ageing Res Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101128963</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1568-1637</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015525">Fatty Acids, Omega-3</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015525" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fatty Acids, Omega-3</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frailty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Omega-3 fatty acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polyunsaturated fatty acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors report no financial interests or potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37442370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2023.102014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1568-1637(23)00173-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>