<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">17912368</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2008</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Creatine monohydrate and conjugated linoleic acid improve strength and body composition following resistance exercise in older adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e991</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e991</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e991</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aging is associated with lower muscle mass and an increase in body fat. We examined whether creatine monohydrate (CrM) and conjugated linoleic acid (CLA) could enhance strength gains and improve body composition (i.e., increase fat-free mass (FFM); decrease body fat) following resistance exercise training in older adults (&gt;65 y). Men (N = 19) and women (N = 20) completed six months of resistance exercise training with CrM (5g/d)+CLA (6g/d) or placebo with randomized, double blind, allocation. Outcomes included: strength and muscular endurance, functional tasks, body composition (DEXA scan), blood tests (lipids, liver function, CK, glucose, systemic inflammation markers (IL-6, C-reactive protein)), urinary markers of compliance (creatine/creatinine), oxidative stress (8-OH-2dG, 8-isoP) and bone resorption (Nu-telopeptides). Exercise training improved all measurements of functional capacity (P&lt;0.05) and strength (P&lt;0.001), with greater improvement for the CrM+CLA group in most measurements of muscular endurance, isokinetic knee extension strength, FFM, and lower fat mass (P&lt;0.05). Plasma creatinine (P&lt;0.05), but not creatinine clearance, increased for CrM+CLA, with no changes in serum CK activity or liver function tests. Together, this data confirms that supervised resistance exercise training is safe and effective for increasing strength in older adults and that a combination of CrM and CLA can enhance some of the beneficial effects of training over a six-month period. Trial Registration. ClinicalTrials.gov NCT00473902.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarnopolsky</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Medicine, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada. tarnopol@mcmaster.ca</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zimmer</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paikin</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Safdar</LastName><ForeName>Adeel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aboud</LastName><ForeName>Alissa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pearce</LastName><ForeName>Erin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doherty</LastName><ForeName>Timothy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT00473902</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9KJL21T0QJ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019787">Linoleic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>MU72812GK0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003401">Creatine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000375" MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003401" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019787" MajorTopicYN="N">Linoleic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009132" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052756" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Sciences</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>Dr. Tarnopolsky has received an investigator initiated grant to evaluate the absorption characteristics of a new form of creatine (creatine ascorbate) as compared with creatine monohydrate from Avicena (2006). The current submitted study was completed in 2005 and Avicena did not contribute any money to the current study, but did supply product. Dr. Tarnopolsky has not received any personal money or sponsored talks for either Avicena or Pharmanutrients.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2007</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2008</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17912368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1994592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0000991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Castillo EM, Goodman-Gruen D, Kritz-Silverstein D, Morton DJ, Wingard DL, et al. Sarcopenia in elderly men and women: the Rancho Bernardo study. Am J Prev Med. 2003;25:226&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14507529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillette-Guyonnet S, Nourhashemi F, Andrieu S, Cantet C, Albarede JL, et al. Body composition in French women 75+years of age: the EPIDOS study. Mech Ageing Dev. 2003;124:311&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12663128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau EM, Lynn HS, Woo JW, Kwok TC, Melton LJ, 3rd Prevalence of and risk factors for sarcopenia in elderly Chinese men and women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2005;60:213&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15814865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charette SL, McEvoy L, Pyka G, Snow-Harter C, Guido D, et al. Muscle hypertrophy response to resistance training in older women. J Appl Physiol. 1991;70:1912&#x2013;1916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1864770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Duret C, Wheeler S, Marcus R. Once-weekly resistance exercise improves muscle strength and neuromuscular performance in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1999;47:1208&#x2013;1214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10522954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiatarone MA, O'Neill EF, Ryan ND, Clements KM, Solares GR, et al. Exercise training and nutritional supplementation for physical frailty in very elderly people. N Engl J Med. 1994;330:1769&#x2013;1775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8190152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelton DA, Young A, Greig CA, Malbut KE. Effects of resistance training on strength, power, and selected functional abilities of women aged 75 and older. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1995;43:1081&#x2013;1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7560695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borst SE. Interventions for sarcopenia and muscle weakness in older people. Age Ageing. 2004;33:548&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert CP, Sullivan DH, Freeling SA, Lindquist DM, Evans WJ. Effects of testosterone replacement and/or resistance exercise on the composition of megestrol acetate stimulated weight gain in elderly men: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2002;87:2100&#x2013;2106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Kupelian V, Visser M, Simonsick E, Goodpaster B, et al. Sarcopenia: alternative definitions and associations with lower extremity function. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2003;51:1602&#x2013;1609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Ferreira M, Wilson M, Grindstaff P, Plisk S, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on body composition, strength, and sprint performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30:73&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, Staron RS, Putukian M, et al. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:1147&#x2013;1156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrusch MJ, Chilibeck PD, Chad KE, Davison KS, Burke DG. Creatine supplementation combined with resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:2111&#x2013;2117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Parise G, Yardley NJ, Ballantyne CS, Olatinji S, et al. Creatine-dextrose and protein-dextrose induce similar strength gains during training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:2044&#x2013;2052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brose A, Parise G, Tarnopolsky MA. Creatine supplementation enhances isometric strength and body composition improvements following strength exercise training in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2003;58:11&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12560406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Op't Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, Urso B, Greenhaff PL, et al. Oral creatine supplementation facilitates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol. 2001;536:625&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagaard P, Kadi F, Tufekovic G, Verney J, et al. Creatine supplementation augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol. 2006;573:525&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vierck JL, Icenoggle DL, Bucci L, Dodson MV. The effects of ergogenic compounds on myogenic satellite cells. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:769&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12750586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dangott B, Schultz E, Mozdziak PE. Dietary creatine monohydrate supplementation increases satellite cell mitotic activity during compensatory hypertrophy. Int J Sports Med. 2000;21:13&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, Mihic S, MacLennan D, Yarasheski KE, Tarnopolsky MA. Effects of acute creatine monohydrate supplementation on leucine kinetics and mixed-muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91:1041&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1674&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermon S, Venembre P, Sachet C, Valour S, Dolisi C. Effects of creatine monohydrate ingestion in sedentary and weight-trained older adults. Acta Physiol Scand. 1998;164:147&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9805101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eijnde BO, Van Leemputte M, Goris M, Labarque V, Taes Y, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation and exercise training on fitness in men 55-75 yr old. J Appl Physiol. 2003;95:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricon S, Burdge GC, Williams CM, Calder PC, Yaqoob P. The effects of conjugated linoleic acid on human health-related outcomes. Proc Nutr Soc. 2005;64:171&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15960862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belury MA. Dietary conjugated linoleic acid in health: physiological effects and mechanisms of action. Annu Rev Nutr. 2002;22:505&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12055356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendel AA, Belury MA. Effects of conjugated linoleic acid and troglitazone on lipid accumulation and composition in lean and Zucker diabetic fatty (fa/fa) rats. Lipids. 2006;41:241&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16711598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Storkson J, Kim S, Sugimoto K, Park Y, et al. Short-term intake of conjugated linoleic acid inhibits lipoprotein lipase and glucose metabolism but does not enhance lipolysis in mouse adipose tissue. J Nutr. 2003;133:663&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12612134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebedio JL, Angioni E, Chardigny JM, Gregoire S, Juaneda P, et al. The effect of conjugated linoleic acid isomers on fatty acid profiles of liver and adipose tissues and their conversion to isomers of 16&#x2236;2 and 18&#x2236;3 conjugated fatty acids in rats. Lipids. 2001;36:575&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11485160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaullier JM, Halse J, Hoye K, Kristiansen K, Fagertun H, et al. Supplementation with conjugated linoleic acid for 24 months is well tolerated by and reduces body fat mass in healthy, overweight humans. J Nutr. 2005;135:778&#x2013;784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15795434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blankson H, Stakkestad JA, Fagertun H, Thom E, Wadstein J, et al. Conjugated linoleic acid reduces body fat mass in overweight and obese humans. J Nutr. 2000;130:2943&#x2013;2948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11110851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaullier JM, Halse J, Hoye K, Kristiansen K, Fagertun H, et al. Conjugated linoleic acid supplementation for 1 y reduces body fat mass in healthy overweight humans. Am J Clin Nutr. 2004;79:1118&#x2013;1125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Ferreira MP, Greenwood M, Wilson M, Almada AL. Effects of conjugated linoleic acid supplementation during resistance training on body composition, bone density, strength, and selected hematological markers. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16:325&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12173945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riserus U, Basu S, Jovinge S, Fredrikson GN, Arnlov J, et al. Supplementation with conjugated linoleic acid causes isomer-dependent oxidative stress and elevated C-reactive protein: a potential link to fatty acid-induced insulin resistance. Circulation. 2002;106:1925&#x2013;1929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12370214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu S, Riserus U, Turpeinen A, Vessby B. Conjugated linoleic acid induces lipid peroxidation in men with abdominal obesity. Clin Sci (Lond) 2000;99:511&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11099394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley DS, Bartolini GL, Warren JM, Simon VA, Mackey BE, et al. Contrasting effects of t10,c12- and c9,t11-conjugated linoleic acid isomers on the fatty acid profiles of mouse liver lipids. Lipids. 2004;39:135&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15134140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HK, Kim SR, Ahn JY, Cho IJ, Yoon CS, et al. Dietary conjugated linoleic acid reduces lipid peroxidation by increasing oxidative stability in rats. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo) 2005;51:8&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15915662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Mallika V, Goswami B. Metabolic syndrome: Diagnosis, potential markers and management-an update. Clin Chim Acta 2006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG, Tournis S, Leontsini D, Jamurtas AZ, Sxina M, et al. Leptin and adiponectin responses in overweight inactive elderly following resistance training and detraining are intensity related. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90:5970&#x2013;5977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16091494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Roy BD, MacDonald JR. A randomized, controlled trial of creatine monohydrate in patients with mitochondrial cytopathies. Muscle Nerve. 1997;20:1502&#x2013;1509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez MC, Macdonald JR, Mahoney DJ, Parise G, Beal MF, et al. Beneficial effects of creatine, CoQ(10), and lipoic acid in mitochondrial disorders. Muscle Nerve 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17080429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey AL, Esmarck B, Kadi F, Koskinen SO, Kongsgaard M, et al. Enhanced satellite cell proliferation with resistance training in elderly men and women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2007;17:34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17305939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Blanco CE, Sattler FR, Schroeder ET, Wiswell RA. Satellite cell numbers in young and older men 24 hours after eccentric exercise. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33:242&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16315322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukinen H, Koski K, Laippala P, Kivela SL. Factors predicting fractures during falling impacts among home-dwelling older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1997;45:1302&#x2013;1309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9361654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturnieks DL, Tiedemann A, Chapman K, Munro B, Murray SM, et al. Physiological risk factors for falls in older people with lower limb arthritis. J Rheumatol. 2004;31:2272&#x2013;2279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15517643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whigham LD, O'Shea M, Mohede IC, Walaski HP, Atkinson RL. Safety profile of conjugated linoleic acid in a 12-month trial in obese humans. Food Chem Toxicol. 2004;42:1701&#x2013;1709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15354322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi Y, Kushiro M, Shinohara K, Ide T. Activity and mRNA levels of enzymes involved in hepatic fatty acid synthesis and oxidation in mice fed conjugated linoleic acid. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2003;1631:265&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12668178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YW, Jones PJ. Conjugated linoleic acid and obesity control: efficacy and mechanisms. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2004;28:941&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onat A, Avci GS, Barlan MM, Uyarel H, Uzunlar B, et al. Measures of abdominal obesity assessed for visceral adiposity and relation to coronary risk. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2004;28:1018&#x2013;1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15197408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busetto L. Visceral obesity and the metabolic syndrome: effects of weight loss. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2001;11:195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11590996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcell TJ, McAuley KA, Traustadottir T, Reaven PD. Exercise training is not associated with improved levels of C-reactive protein or adiponectin. Metabolism. 2005;54:533&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15798963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short KR, Vittone JL, Bigelow ML, Proctor DN, Rizza RA, et al. Impact of aerobic exercise training on age-related changes in insulin sensitivity and muscle oxidative capacity. Diabetes. 2003;52:1888&#x2013;1896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Leary VB, Marchetti CM, Krishnan RK, Stetzer BP, Gonzalez F, et al. Exercise-induced reversal of insulin resistance in obese elderly is associated with reduced visceral fat. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:1584&#x2013;1589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7037693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadid S, Stehouwer CD, Jensen MD. Diet/Exercise versus pioglitazone: effects of insulin sensitization with decreasing or increasing fat mass on adipokines and inflammatory markers. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91:3418&#x2013;3425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16804048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monzillo LU, Hamdy O, Horton ES, Ledbury S, Mullooly C, et al. Effect of lifestyle modification on adipokine levels in obese subjects with insulin resistance. Obes Res. 2003;11:1048&#x2013;1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12972674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruun JM, Helge JW, Richelsen B, Stallknecht B. Diet and exercise reduce low-grade inflammation and macrophage infiltration in adipose tissue but not in skeletal muscle in severely obese subjects. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;290:E961&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16352667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bluher M, Bullen JW, Jr, Lee JH, Kralisch S, Fasshauer M, et al. Circulating adiponectin and expression of adiponectin receptors in human skeletal muscle: associations with metabolic parameters and insulin resistance and regulation by physical training. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91:2310&#x2013;2316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16551730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Daly RM, Owen N, Jolley D, De Courten M, et al. High-intensity resistance training improves glycemic control in older patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25:1729&#x2013;1736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12351469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda C, Layne JE, Munoz-Orians L, Gordon PL, Walsmith J, et al. A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise training to improve glycemic control in older adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25:2335&#x2013;2341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riserus U, Vessby B, Arnlov J, Basu S. Effects of cis-9,trans-11 conjugated linoleic acid supplementation on insulin sensitivity, lipid peroxidation, and proinflammatory markers in obese men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2004;80:279&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15277146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, Brose AN, Tarnopolsky MA. Resistance exercise training decreases oxidative damage to DNA and increases cytochrome oxidase activity in older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2005;40:173&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15763394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, Phillips SM, Kaczor JJ, Tarnopolsky MA. Antioxidant enzyme activity is up-regulated after unilateral resistance exercise training in older adults. Free Radic Biol Med. 2005;39:289&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15964520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAnulty SR, McAnulty LS, Nieman DC, Morrow JD, Utter AC, et al. Effect of resistance exercise and carbohydrate ingestion on oxidative stress. Free Radic Res. 2005;39:1219&#x2013;1224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16298748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson TA, MacDonald-Wicks LK, Garg ML. Oxidative stress and antioxidants in athletes undertaking regular exercise training. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2005;15:131&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16089272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halbert JA, Silagy CA, Finucane P, Withers RT, Hamdorf PA. Exercise training and blood lipids in hyperlipidemic and normolipidemic adults: a meta-analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Eur J Clin Nutr. 1999;53:514&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10452405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilund KR, Ferrell RE, Phares DA, Goldberg AP, Hagberg JM. Changes in high-density lipoprotein-cholesterol subfractions with exercise training may be dependent on cholesteryl ester transfer protein (CETP) genotype. Metabolism. 2002;51:774&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12037734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banz WJ, Maher MA, Thompson WG, Bassett DR, Moore W, et al. Effects of resistance versus aerobic training on coronary artery disease risk factors. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 2003;228:434&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12671188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyden TW, Pamenter RW, Going SB, Lohman TG, Hall MC, et al. Resistance exercise training is associated with decreases in serum low-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels in premenopausal women. Arch Intern Med. 1993;153:97&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8422204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JS, Stanforth PR, Rankinen T, Leon AS, Rao Dc D, et al. The effects of exercise training on abdominal visceral fat, body composition, and indicators of the metabolic syndrome in postmenopausal women with and without estrogen replacement therapy: the HERITAGE family study. Metabolism. 2004;53:1192&#x2013;1196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15334383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartorio A, Lafortuna C, Capodaglio P, Vangeli V, Narici MV, et al. Effects of a 16-week progressive high-intensity strength training (HIST) on indexes of bone turnover in men over 65 years: a randomized controlled study. J Endocrinol Invest. 2001;24:882&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11817713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent KR, Braith RW. Resistance exercise and bone turnover in elderly men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullins NM, Sinning WE. Effects of resistance training and protein supplementation on bone turnover in young adult women. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2005;2:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1208950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohrt WM. Aging and the osteogenic response to mechanical loading. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2001;11(Suppl):S137&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11915912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber I, ap Gwynn I, Alini M, Wallimann T. Stimulatory effects of creatine on metabolic activity, differentiation and mineralization of primary osteoblast-like cells in monolayer and micromass cell cultures. Eur Cell Mater. 2005;10:8&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16025431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Mahoney DJ, Vajsar J, Rodriguez C, Doherty TJ, et al. Creatine monohydrate enhances strength and body composition in Duchenne muscular dystrophy. Neurology. 2004;62:1771&#x2013;1777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis M, Lebacq J, Poortmans JR, Belpaire-Dethiou MC, Devogelaer JP, et al. Beneficial effects of creatine supplementation in dystrophic patients. Muscle Nerve. 2003;27:604&#x2013;610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12707981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Davison KS, Whiting SJ, Suzuki Y, Janzen CL, et al. The effect of strength training combined with bisphosphonate (etidronate) therapy on bone mineral, lean tissue, and fat mass in postmenopausal women. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2002;80:941&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12450060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihic S, MacDonald JR, McKenzie S, Tarnopolsky MA. Acute creatine loading increases fat-free mass, but does not affect blood pressure, plasma creatinine, or CK activity in men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:291&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans JR, Auquier H, Renaut V, Durussel A, Saugy M, et al. Effect of short-term creatine supplementation on renal responses in men. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1997;76:566&#x2013;567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9404870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans JR, Francaux M. Long-term oral creatine supplementation does not impair renal function in healthy athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:1108&#x2013;1110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>