<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23259853</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of creatine supplementation on oxidative stress profile of athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>56</StartPage><MedlinePgn>56</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-9-56</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Creatine (Cr) supplementation has been widely used among athletes and physically active individuals. Secondary to its performance-enhancing ability, an increase in oxidative stress may occur, thus prompting concern about its use. The purpose of this study is to investigate the effects of Cr monohydrate supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and oxidative stress profile in healthy athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled method was used to assess twenty-six male elite Brazilian handball players divided into 3 groups: Cr monohydrate supplemented group (GC, N = 9), placebo group (GP, N = 9), no treatment group (COT, N = 8) for 32 days. All subjects underwent a resistance training program. Blood samples were drawn on 0 and 32 days post Cr supplementation to analyze the oxidative stress markers, thiobarbituric acid reactive species (TBARS), total antioxidant status (TAS), and uric acid. Creatine phosphokinase, urea, and creatinine were also analyzed, as well. Fitness tests (1 repetition maximum - 1RM and muscle endurance) were performed on the bench press. Body weight and height, body fat percentage (by measuring skin folds) and upper muscular area were also evaluated. Statistical analysis was performed using ANOVA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Only GC group showed increase in 1RM (54 &#xb1; 9 vs. 63 &#xb1; 10 kg; p = 0.0356) and uric acid (4.6 &#xb1; 1.0 vs. 7.4 &#xb1; 1.6 mg/dl; p = 0.025), with a decrease in TAS (1.11 &#xb1; 0.34 vs. 0.60 &#xb1; 0.19 mmol/l; p = 0.001). No differences (pre- vs. post-training) in TBARS, creatine phosphokinase, urea, creatinine, body weight and height, body fat percentage, or upper muscular area were observed in any group. When compared to COT, GC group showed greater decrease in TAS (-0.51 &#xb1; 0.36 vs. -0.02 &#xb1; 0.50 mmol/l; p = 0.0268), higher increase in 1RM (8.30 &#xb1; 2.26 vs. 5.29 &#xb1; 2.36 kg; p = 0.0209) and uric acid (2.77 &#xb1; 1.70 vs. 1.00 &#xb1; 1.03 mg/dl; p = 0.0276).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We conclude that Cr monohydrate supplementation associated with a specific resistance program promoted a meaningful increase in muscle strength without inducing changes in body composition. The observed significant increase in uric acid and the decrease in TAS suggest that creatine supplementation, despite promoting acute effects on muscle strength improvement, might induce oxidative stress and decreases total antioxidant status of subjects.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perc&#xe1;rio</LastName><ForeName>Sandro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biological Sciences Institute, Federal University of Par&#xe1;, Bel&#xe9;m, PA, Brazil. percario@ufpa.br.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Domingues</LastName><ForeName>S&#xe9;rgio Paulo de Tarso</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Luiz Felipe Milano</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vieira</LastName><ForeName>Jose Luiz Fernandes</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Vasconcelos</LastName><ForeName>Flavio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciarrocchi</LastName><ForeName>Daiane Marques</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almeida</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo Dias</ForeName><Initials>ED</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conte</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23259853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-9-56</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-9-56</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Terjung RL, Clarkson ER, Eichner P, Greenhaff PL, HAspel PJ, Israel RG, Kraemer WJ, Meyer RA, Spriet LL, Tarnopolsky MA, Wangenmakers AJ, Willians MH. The physiological health effects of oral creatine supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(3):706&#x2013;717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford TW, Kreider RB, Stout JR, Greenwood M, Campbell B, Spano M, Ziegenfuss T, Lopez H, Landis J, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: creatine supplementation and exercise. Int J Sport Nutr. 2007;4(6):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2048496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Lond) 1992;83(3):367&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karolkiewicz J, Szczesniak L, Deskur-Smielecka E, Nowak A, Steplewski R, Szeklicki R. Oxidative stress and antioxidant defense system in healthy, elderly men: relationship to physical activity. Aging Male. 2003;6(2):100&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Wilborn CD, Taylor L, Campbell B, Almada AL, Collins R, Cooke M, Earnest CP, Greenwood M, Kalman DS, Kerksick CM, Kleiner SM, Leutholtz B, Lopez H, Lowery LM, Mendel R, Smith A, Spano M, Wildman R, Willoughby DS, Ziegenfuss TN, Antonio J. ISSN exercise &amp; sport nutrition review: research &amp; recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:7. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-7-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kante M. Free radicals, exercise and antioxidant supplementation. Proc Nutr Soc. 1998;57:9&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1079/PNS19980004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/PNS19980004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9571703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams AK, Best TM. The role of antioxidants in exercise and disease prevention. Phys Sportsmed. 2002;30(5):37&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20086526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijer EP, Goris AHC, Van Dongen JLJ, Bast A, Westerherp KR. Exercise-induced oxidative stress in older adults as a function of habitual activity level. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50(2):349&#x2013;353. doi: 10.1046/j.1532-5415.2002.50069.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1532-5415.2002.50069.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers SK, Howley ET. Exercise physiology: theory and application to conditioning and performance. S&#xe3;o Paulo (SP): Manole; 2006. p. 598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarro A, Del Pino MJS, G&#xf3;mez C, Peralta JL, Boveris A. Behavioral dysfunction, brain oxidative stress, and impaired mitochondrial electron transfer in aging mice. Am J Physiol Regulatory Integrative Comp Physiol. 2002;282(4):R985&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11893601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen CK. Oxidants and antioxidants in exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1995;79(3):675&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8567503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCartney N. Acute responses to resistance training and safety. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(1):31&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199901000-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199901000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9927007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride JM, Kraemer WJ, Triplett-McBride T, Sebastianelli W. Effect of resistance exercise on free radical production. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30(2):67&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi R. Creatine supplementation decreases oxidative DNA damage and lipid peroxidation induced by a single bout of resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(12):3448&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182162f2b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182162f2b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22080314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley M, Cunningham D, Mason L, Kilduff LP, McEneny J. Role of creatine supplementation on exercise-induced cardiovascular function and oxidative stress. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2009;2(4):247&#x2013;54. doi: 10.4161/oxim.2.4.9415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/oxim.2.4.9415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20716911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eijnde BO, Hespel P. Short-term creatine supplementation does not alter the hormonal response to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(3):449&#x2013;453. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200103000-00018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200103000-00018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11252073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Ferreira M, Wilson M, Grindstaff P, Plisk S, Reinardy J, Cantler E, Almada AL. Effects of creatine supplementation on body composition, strength, and sprint performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30(1):73&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199801000-00011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199801000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson WS, Dudley GA. Dietary creatine supplementation and muscular adaptation to resistive overload. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(8):1304&#x2013;1310. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200108000-00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200108000-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11474331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, Staron RS, Putukian M, Gomez AL, Pearson DR, Fink WJ, Kraemer WJ. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(8):1147&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, Lima C, Frollini A, Donatto F, Conte M. Comparison of linear and reverse linear periodization effects on maxima strength and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(1):266&#x2013;274. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181874bf3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181874bf3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports and Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perc&#xe1;rio S, Vital ACC, Jablonka F. Dosagem do malondialdeido. Newslab. 1994;2(6):46&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Re R, Pellegrini R, Proteggente A, Pannala A, Yang M, Rice-Evans C. Antioxidant activity applying an improved ABTS radical cation decolorization assay. Free Rad Biol Med. 1999;26:1231&#x2013;1237. doi: 10.1016/S0891-5849(98)00315-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0891-5849(98)00315-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10381194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedes DP. Body composition: principles, techniques and applications. Londrina (PR): APEF; 1994. p. 124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisancho AR. New standarts of weight and body compostion by frame size and height for assessment of nutritional status of adults and the elderly. Am J Clin Nutr. 1984;40(4):808&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6486088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx JO, Ratames NA, Nindl BC, Gotshalk LA, Volek JS, Dohi K, Bush JA, Gomez AL, Mazzetti SA, Fleck SJ, Hakkinen K, Newton RU, Kraemer WJ. Low-volume circuit versus high-volume periodized resistance training in women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(4):635&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11283441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Van Hecke P, Van Leemputte M, Vanstapel F, Hespel P. Phosphocreatine resynthesis is not affected by creatine loading. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(2):236&#x2013;242. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199902000-00006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199902000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10063812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldron JE. Concurrent creatine monohydrate supplementation and resistance training does not affect markers of hepatic function in trained weightlifters. J Exerc Physiol. 2002;5(1):57&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M, Schoch R, Cooke R, Harvey T, Greenwood M, Kreider R, Willoughby DS. The effects of creatine ethyl ester supplementation combined with heavy resistance training on body composition, muscle performance, and serum and muscle creatine levels. Int J Sport Nutr. 2009;6(6):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2649889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Triplett-Mcbride NT, Fry AC, Koziris LP, Ratamess NA, Bauer JE, Volek JS, McConnell T, Newton RU, Gordon SE, Cummings D, Hauth J, Pullo F, Lynch JM, Fleck SJ, Mazzetti SA, Knuttgen HG. Physiological changes with periodized resistance training in women tennis players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(1):157&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200301000-00024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200301000-00024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12544650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schilling BK. Creatine supplementation and health variables: a retrospective study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(2):183&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11224803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans JR, Kumps A, Duez P, Fofonka A, Carpentier A, Francaux M. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on urinary methylamine, formaldehyde, and formate. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(10):1717&#x2013;1720. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000176398.64189.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000176398.64189.e6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans JR, Francaux M. Long-term oral creatine supplementation does not impair renal function in healthy athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(8):1108&#x2013;1110. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199908000-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199908000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold GN. Muscle glycogen supercompensation is enhanced by prior creatine supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(7):1096&#x2013;1100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guezennec CY, Abdelmalki A, Serrurier B, Merino D, Bigard X, Berthelot M, Pierard C, Peres M. Effects of prolonged exercise on brain ammonia and amino acids. Int J Sports Med. 1998;19:323&#x2013;327. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-971925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-971925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9721055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza Junior TP, Pereira B. Creatina: aux&#xed;lio ergog&#xea;nico com potencial antioxidante? Rev Nutr. 2008;21(3):349&#x2013;353.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>