<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22032491</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strength and hypertrophy responses to constant and decreasing rest intervals in trained men using creatine supplementation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-8-17</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The purpose of the current study was to compare strength and hypertrophy responses to resistance training programs that instituted constant rest intervals (CI) and decreasing rest intervals (DI) between sets over the course of eight weeks by trained men who supplemented with creatine monohydrate (CR).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-two recreationally trained men were randomly assigned to a CI group (n = 11; 22.3 &#xb1; 1 years; 77.7 &#xb1; 5.4 kg; 180 &#xb1; 2.2 cm) or a DI group (n = 11; 22 &#xb1; 2.5 years; 75.8 &#xb1; 4.9 kg; 178.8 &#xb1; 3.4 cm). Subjects in both groups supplemented with CR; the only difference between groups was the rest interval instituted between sets; the CI group used 2 minutes rest intervals between sets and exercises for the entire 8-weeks of training, while the DI group started with a 2 minute rest interval the first two weeks; after which the rest interval between sets was decreased 15 seconds per week (i.e. 2 minutes decreasing to 30 seconds between sets). Pre- and post-intervention maximal strength for the free weight back squat and bench press exercises and isokinetic peak torque were assessed for the knee extensors and flexors. Additionally, muscle cross-sectional area (CSA) of the right thigh and upper arm was measured using magnetic resonance imaging.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both groups demonstrated significant increases in back squat and bench press maximal strength, knee extensor and flexor isokinetic peak torque, and upper arm and right thigh CSA from pre- to post-training (p &#x2264; 0.0001); however, there were no significant differences between groups for any of these variables. The total volume for the bench press and back squat were significantly greater for CI group versus the DI group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We report that the combination of CR supplementation and resistance training can increase muscular strength, isokinetic peak torque, and muscle CSA, irrespective of the rest interval length between sets. Because the volume of training was greater for the CI group versus the DI group, yet strength gains were similar, the creatine supplementation appeared to bolster adaptations for the DI group, even in the presence of significantly less volume. However, further research is needed with the inclusion of a control group not receiving supplementation combined and resistance training with decreasing rest intervals to further elucidate such hypotheses.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souza-Junior</LastName><ForeName>T&#xe1;cito P</ForeName><Initials>TP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Parana, Curitiba, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil. tacitojr@ufpr.br.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willardson</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bloomer</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leite</LastName><ForeName>Richard D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleck</LastName><ForeName>Steven J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Paulo R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sim&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Roberto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22032491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3215636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-8-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-8-17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Op't Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, Urso B, Greenhaff PL, Labarque V, Dymarkowski S, Van Hecke P, Richter EA. Oral creatine supplementation facilitates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol. 2001;536:625&#x2013;633. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, Staron RS, Putukian M, Gomez AL, Pearson DR, Fink WJ, Kraemer WJ. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:1147&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branch JD. Effect of creatine supplementation on body composition and performance: a meta-analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2003;13:198&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12945830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford TW, Kreider RB, Stout JR, Greenwood M, Campbell B, Spano M, Ziegenfuss T, Lopez H, Landis J, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: creatine supplementation and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-4-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-4-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2048496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB. Dietary supplements and the promotion of muscle growth with resistance exercise. Sports Med. 1999;27:97&#x2013;110. doi: 10.2165/00007256-199927020-00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199927020-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10091274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Volek JS. Effects of creatine supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and weightlifting performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:822&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA. Improving muscle mass: response of muscle metabolism to exercise, nutrition and anabolic agents. Essays Biochem. 2008;44:85&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1042/BSE0440085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/BSE0440085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18384284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilduff LP, Pitsiladis YP, Tasker L, Attwood J, Hyslop P, Dailly A, Dickson I, Grant S. Effects of creatine on body composition and strength gains after 4 weeks of resistance training in previously nonresistance-trained humans. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2003;13:504&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14967873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson KD, Smodic B, Hill R. The effects of creatine monohydrate supplementation on muscular power and work. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;29:S251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huso ME, Hampl JS, Johnston CS, Swan PD. Creatine supplementation influences substrate utilization at rest. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:2018&#x2013;2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demant TW, Rhodes FC. Effects of creatine supplementation on exercise performance. Sports Med. 1999;28:46&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10461712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terjung RL, Clarkson P, Eichner ER, Greenhaff PL, Hespel PJ, Israel RG, Kraemer WJ, Meyer RA, Spriet LL, Tarnopolsky MA, Wagenmakers AJ, Williams MH. American College of Sports Medicine roundtable. The physiological and health effects of oral creatine supplementation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:706&#x2013;717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yquel RJ, Arsac LM, Thiaudi&#xe8;re E, Canioni P, Manier G. Effect of creatine supplementation on phosphocreatine resynthesis, inorganic phosphate accumulation and pH during intermittent maximal exercise. J Sports Sci. 2002;20:427&#x2013;437. doi: 10.1080/026404102317366681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404102317366681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12043832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG, Lamont HS. Creatine supplementation and exercise performance: Recent findings. Sports Med. 2005;35:107&#x2013;125. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200535020-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535020-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15707376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza Junior TP, Fleck SJ, Sim&#xe3;o R, Dubas JP, Pereira B, Pacheco EMB, Silva AC, Oliveira PR. Comparison between constant and decreasing rest intervals: influence on maximal strength and hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:1843&#x2013;1850. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ddae4a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ddae4a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias I, de Salles BF, Novaes J, Costa P, Sim&#xe3;o R. Influence of exercise order on maximum strength in untrained young men. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13:65&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2008.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2008.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19243993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cybex 6000. Testing and rehabilitation user's guide. Ronkonkoma, NY: Cybex, Division of Lumex; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Sim&#xe3;o R, Miranda F, Novaes JS, Lemos A, Willardson JM. Rest interval between sets in strength training: review article. Sports Med. 2009;39:765&#x2013;777. doi: 10.2165/11315230-000000000-00000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11315230-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19691365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. Position stand on progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. Position stand: Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:364&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becque MD, Lochmann JD, Melrose DR. Effects of oral creatine supplementation on muscular strength and body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:654&#x2013;658. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200003000-00016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200003000-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG, Bemben DA, Loftiss DD, Knehans AW. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in college football athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1667&#x2013;1673. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branch JD, Schwarz WD, Van Lunen B. Effect of creatine supplementation on cycle ergometer exercise in a hyperthermic environment. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:57&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200702000-00011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200702000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey A, Greenhaff PL. Does dietary creatine supplementation play a role in skeletal muscle metabolism and performance? Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72:607S&#x2013;617S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10919967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson-Meyer DE, Hunt GR, Trowbridge CA, Turk JC, Ernest JM, Torman SL, Harbin PA. The effect of creatine supplementation on muscle strength and body composition during off-season training in female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14:434&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Goris M, Van Hecke P, Van Leeputte M, Vanderven L, Hespel P. Long-term creatine intake is beneficial to muscle performance during resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:2055&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AM, Atter T, Georg KP. Oral creatine supplementation improves multiple sprint performance in elite ice-hockey players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1999;39:189&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10573659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Sanborn K, Smith LL, O'Bryant HS, Hoke T, Utter AC, Johnson RL, Boros R, Hruby J, Pierce KC, Stone ME, Garner B. Effects of in-season (5 weeks) creatine and pyruvate supplementation on anaerobic performance and body composition in American football players. Int J Sport Nutr. 1999;9:146&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10362452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Almada AL, Antonio J, Broeder C, Earnest C, Greenwood M, Incledon T, Kalman DS, Kleiner SM, Leutholtz B, Lowery LM, Mendel R, Stout JR, Willoughby DS, Ziegenfuss TN. Exercise and sport nutrition review: research and recommendations. Sport Nutr Rev J. 2004;1:1&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene JM. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myogenic regulatory factor expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:923&#x2013;929. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000069746.05241.F0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000069746.05241.F0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene JM. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1674&#x2013;1681. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB. Effects of creatine supplementation on performance and training adaptations. Mol Cell Biochem. 2003;244:89&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1023/A:1022465203458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022465203458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12701815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Hannibal NS, Nindl BC, Gentile CL, Hamed J, Vukovich MD. Comparison of creatine ingestion and resistance training on energy expenditure and limb blood flow. Metabolism. 2001;50:1429&#x2013;1434. doi: 10.1053/meta.2001.28159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2001.28159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syrotuik DG, Bell GJ, Burnham R, Sim LL, Calvert RA, Maclean IM. Absolute and relative strength performance following creatine monohydrate supplementation combined with periodized resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14:182&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JM, Stone MH, Johnson RL, Penland CM, Warren BJ, Lewis RD. Effects of different weight training exercise/rest intervals on strength, power, and high intensity exercise endurance. J Strength Cond Res. 1995;9:216&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. A comparison of 3 different rest intervals on the exercise volume completed during a workout. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19:23&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. The effect of rest interval length on bench press performance with heavy vs. light load. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:396&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. The effect of rest interval length on the sustainability of squat and bench press repetitions. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:400&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Noble BJ, Clark MJ, Culver BW. Physiologic responses to heavy-resistance exercise with very short rest periods. Int J Sports Med. 1987;8:247&#x2013;252. doi: 10.1055/s-2008-1025663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1025663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3667019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Fleck SJ, Dickinson A, Kraemer WJ. Acute and chronic hormonal responses to resistance training designed to promote muscle hypertrophy. Can J Appl Physiol. 1999;24:96&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1139/h99-009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h99-009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincivero DM, Lephart SM, Karunakara RG. Effects of rest interval on isokinetic strength and functional performance after short-term high intensity training. Br J Sports Med. 1997;31:229&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.31.3.229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.31.3.229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1332526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9298559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. The effect of different rest intervals between sets on volume components and strength gains. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:146&#x2013;152. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31815f912d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31815f912d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Short vs. long rest period between the sets in hypertrophic resistance training: Influence on muscle strength, size, and hormonal adaptations in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19:572&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buresh R, Berg K, French J. The effect of resistive exercise rest interval on hormonal response, strength, and hypertrophy with training. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:62&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318185f14a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318185f14a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19077743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>