<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24864135</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2014</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evidence-based recommendations for natural bodybuilding contest preparation: nutrition and supplementation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-11-20</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The popularity of natural bodybuilding is increasing; however, evidence-based recommendations for it are lacking. This paper reviewed the scientific literature relevant to competition preparation on nutrition and supplementation, resulting in the following recommendations. Caloric intake should be set at a level that results in bodyweight losses of approximately 0.5 to 1%/wk to maximize muscle retention. Within this caloric intake, most but not all bodybuilders will respond best to consuming 2.3-3.1&#xa0;g/kg of lean body mass per day of protein, 15-30% of calories from fat, and the reminder of calories from carbohydrate. Eating three to six meals per day with a meal containing 0.4-0.5&#xa0;g/kg bodyweight of protein prior and subsequent to resistance training likely maximizes any theoretical benefits of nutrient timing and frequency. However, alterations in nutrient timing and frequency appear to have little effect on fat loss or lean mass retention. Among popular supplements, creatine monohydrate, caffeine and beta-alanine appear to have beneficial effects relevant to contest preparation, however others do not or warrant further study. The practice of dehydration and electrolyte manipulation in the final days and hours prior to competition can be dangerous, and may not improve appearance. Increasing carbohydrate intake at the end of preparation has a theoretical rationale to improve appearance, however it is understudied. Thus, if carbohydrate loading is pursued it should be practiced prior to competition and its benefit assessed individually. Finally, competitors should be aware of the increased risk of developing eating and body image disorders in aesthetic sport and therefore should have access to the appropriate mental health professionals.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helms</LastName><ForeName>Eric R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research in New Zealand (SPRINZ) at AUT Millennium Institute, AUT University, 17 Antares Place, Mairangi Bay, Auckland 0632, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aragon</LastName><ForeName>Alan A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>California State University, Northridge, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fitschen</LastName><ForeName>Peter J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nutritional Sciences, University of Illinois, Urbana, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body fat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calories</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Competition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frequency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrient</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24864135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4033492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-11-20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-11-20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Lockie RG, Knight TJ, Clark AC, De Jonge XAKJ. A comparison of methods to quantify the in-season training load of professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2013;8:195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23428492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleiner SM, Bazzarre TL, Litchford MD. Metabolic profiles, diet, and health practices of championship male and female bodybuilders. J Am Diet Assoc. 1990;90:962&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2365938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandoval WM, Heyward VH. Food selection patterns of bodybuilders. Int J Sport Nutr. 1991;1:61&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1844403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Hunter GR, Newton LE, Roney RK, Khaled MA. Changes in body composition, diet, and strength of bodybuilders during the 12&#xa0;weeks prior to competition. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1993;33:383&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8035587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert CP, Frank LL, Evans WJ. Macronutrient considerations for the sport of bodybuilding. Sports Med. 2004;34:317&#x2013;327. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200434050-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200434050-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestu J, Eliakim A, Jurimae J, Valter I, Jurimae T. Anabolic and catabolic hormones and energy balance of the male bodybuilders during the preparation for the competition. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:1074&#x2013;1081. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cb6fd3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cb6fd3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall KD. What is the required energy deficit per unit weight loss? Int J Obes. 2007;32:573&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2376744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17848938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLean PS, Bergouignan A, Cornier M-A, Jackman MR. Biology's response to dieting: the impetus for weight regain. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2011;301:R581&#x2013;R600. doi: 10.1152/ajpregu.00755.2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00755.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21677272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camps SG, Verhoef SP, Westerterp KR. Weight loss, weight maintenance, and adaptive thermogenesis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2013;97:990&#x2013;994. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.112.050310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.112.050310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannsen DL, Knuth ND, Huizenga R, Rood JC, Ravussin E, Hall KD. Metabolic slowing with massive weight loss despite preservation of fat-free mass. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012;97:2489&#x2013;2496. doi: 10.1210/jc.2012-1444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2012-1444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3387402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22535969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keys A, University of Minnesota. Laboratory of Physiological Hygiene. The Biology Of Human Starvation. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press; 1950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trexler E, Smith-Ryan A, Norton L. Metabolic adaptation to weight loss: implications for the athlete. J Int Soc Sport Nutr. 2014;11:7. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-11-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-11-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garthe I, Raastad T, Refsnes PE, Koivisto A, Sundgot-Borgen J. Effect of two different weight-loss rates on body composition and strength and power-related performance in elite athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2011;21:97&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21558571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes GB. Body fat content influences the body composition response to nutrition and exercise. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2000;904:359&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall KD. Body fat and fat-free mass inter-relationships: Forbes's theory revisited. Br J Nutr. 2007;97:1059&#x2013;1063. doi: 10.1017/S0007114507691946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114507691946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2376748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17367567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero AA, Huovinen H, Matintupa O, Hulmi JJ, Puurtinen R, Hohtari H, Karila T. Moderate energy restriction with high protein diet results in healthier outcome in women. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:4. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-7-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2822830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandoval WM, Heyward VH, Lyons TM. Comparison of body composition, exercise and nutritional profiles of female and male body builders at competition. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1989;29:63&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2770270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walberg-Rankin J, Edmonds CE, Gwazdauskas FC. Diet and weight changes of female bodybuilders before and after competition. Int J Sport Nutr. 1993;3:87&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8499941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Withers RT, Noell CJ, Whittingham NO, Chatterton BE, Schultz CG, Keeves JP. Body composition changes in elite male bodybuilders during preparation for competition. Aust J Sci Med Sport. 1997;29:11&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9127683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Ploeg GE, Brooks AG, Withers RT, Dollman J, Leaney F, Chatterton BE. Body composition changes in female bodybuilders during preparation for competition. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2001;55:268&#x2013;277. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11360131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton LE, Hunter GR, Bammon M, Roney RK. Changes in psychological state and self-reported diet during various phases of training in competitive bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res. 1993;7:153&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butterfield GE. Whole-body protein utilization in humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1987;19:S157&#x2013;S165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3316915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon PW. Beyond the zone: protein needs of active individuals. J Am Coll Nutr. 2000;19:513S&#x2013;521S. doi: 10.1080/07315724.2000.10718974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.2000.10718974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11023001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Dietary protein for athletes: from requirements to metabolic advantage. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2006;31:647&#x2013;654. doi: 10.1139/h06-035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h06-035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17213878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Moore DR, Tang JE. A critical examination of dietary protein requirements, benefits, and excesses in athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(Suppl):S58&#x2013;S76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater G, Phillips SM. Nutrition guidelines for strength sports: sprinting, weightlifting, throwing events, and bodybuilding. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:S67&#x2013;S77. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2011.574722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2011.574722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21660839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Protein and amino acids for athletes. J Sports Sci. 2004;22:65&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1080/0264041031000140554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0264041031000140554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Van Loon LJ. Dietary protein for athletes: from requirements to optimum adaptation. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(Suppl 1):S29&#x2013;S38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22150425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mettler S, Mitchell N, Tipton KD. Increased protein intake reduces lean body mass loss during weight loss in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:326&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millward DJ. Macronutrient intakes as determinants of dietary protein and amino acid adequacy. J Nutr. 2004;134:1588S&#x2013;1596S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiegler P, Cunliffe A. The role of diet and exercise for the maintenance of fat-free mass and resting metabolic rate during weight loss. Sports Med. 2006;36:239&#x2013;262. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200636030-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636030-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16526835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walberg JL, Leidy MK, Sturgill DJ, Hinkle DE, Ritchey SJ, Sebolt DR. Macronutrient content of a hypoenergy diet affects nitrogen retention and muscle function in weight lifters. Int J Sports Med. 1988;9:261&#x2013;266. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1025018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1025018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3182156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Zinn C, Rowlands DS, Brown SR. A systematic review of dietary protein during caloric restriction in resistance trained lean athletes: a case for higher intakes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013. Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24092765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia M, Stubbs RJ, Henry CJ. Differences in fat, carbohydrate, and protein metabolism between lean and obese subjects undergoing total starvation. Obes Res. 1999;7:597&#x2013;604. doi: 10.1002/j.1550-8528.1999.tb00720.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.1550-8528.1999.tb00720.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10574520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Protein requirements and supplementation in strength sports. Nutrition. 2004;20:689&#x2013;695. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15212752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Building muscle: nutrition to maximize bulk and strength adaptations to resistance exercise training. Eur J Sport Sci. 2008;8:67&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1080/17461390801919128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461390801919128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD. Protein for adaptations to exercise training. Eur J Sport Sci. 2008;8:107&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1080/17461390801919102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461390801919102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J, Wilson GJ. Contemporary issues in protein requirements and consumption for resistance trained athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2006;3:7&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-3-1-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-3-1-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2129150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18500966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celejowa I, Homa M. Food intake, nitrogen and energy balance in Polish weight lifters, during a training camp. Nutr Metab. 1970;12:259&#x2013;274. doi: 10.1159/000175300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000175300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5510411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Cao JJ, Margolis LM, Sauter ER, Whigham LD, McClung JP, Rood JC, Carbone JW, Combs GF Jr, Young AJ. Effects of high-protein diets on fat-free mass and muscle protein synthesis following weight loss: a randomized controlled trial. FASEB J. 2013;27:3837&#x2013;3847. doi: 10.1096/fj.13-230227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.13-230227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23739654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leveritt M, Abernethy PJ. Effects of carbohydrate restriction on strength performance. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13:52&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Koch AJ, Potteiger JA, Kuphal KE, Magee LM, Green SB, Jakicic JJ. Carbohydrate supplementation attenuates muscle glycogen loss during acute bouts of resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2000;10:326&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10997956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Ray S, Sale DG, McCartney N, Lee P, Garner S. Muscle substrate utilization and lactate production. Can J Appl Physiol. 1999;24:209&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1139/h99-017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h99-017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10364416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Boileau RA, Erickson DJ, Painter JE, Shiue H, Sather C, Christou DD. A reduced ratio of dietary carbohydrate to protein improves body composition and blood lipid profiles during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2003;133:411&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12566476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Baum JI. Dietary protein impact on glycemic control during weight loss. J Nutr. 2004;134:968S&#x2013;973S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15051856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halton TL, Hu FB. The effects of high protein diets on thermogenesis, satiety and weight loss: a critical review. J Am Coll Nutr. 2004;23:373&#x2013;385. doi: 10.1080/07315724.2004.10719381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.2004.10719381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15466943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldhorst M, Smeets A, Soenen S, Hochstenbach-Waelen A, Hursel R, Diepvens K, Lejeune M, Luscombe-Marsh N, Westerterp-Plantenga M. Protein-induced satiety: effects and mechanisms of different proteins. Physiol Behav. 2008;94:300&#x2013;307. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2008.01.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2008.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18282589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerterp-Plantenga MS. Protein intake and energy balance. Regul Pept. 2008;149:67&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1016/j.regpep.2007.08.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.regpep.2007.08.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18448177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smeets AJ, Soenen S, Luscombe-Marsh ND, Ueland O, Westerterp-Plantenga MS. Energy expenditure, satiety, and plasma ghrelin, glucagon-like peptide 1, and peptide tyrosine-tyrosine concentrations following a single high-protein lunch. J Nutr. 2008;138:698&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18356323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CM, Haub MD. Low-carbohydrate diets and performance. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2007;6:225&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17617997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Kraemer WJ, Bush JA, Incledon T, Boetes M. Testosterone and cortisol in relationship to dietary nutrients and resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1997;82:49&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1063/1.365847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.365847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9029197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallinen J, Pakarinen A, Ahtiainen J, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Relationship between diet and serum anabolic hormone responses to heavy-resistance exercise in men. Int J Sports Med. 2004;25:627&#x2013;633. doi: 10.1055/s-2004-815818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2004-815818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15532008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen EK, Adlercreutz H, Puska P, Pietinen P. Decrease of serum total and free testosterone during a low-fat high-fibre diet. J Steroid Biochem. 1983;18:369&#x2013;370. doi: 10.1016/0022-4731(83)90117-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-4731(83)90117-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6298507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorgan JF, Judd JT, Longcope C, Brown C, Schatzkin A, Clevidence BA, Campbell WS, Nair PP, Franz C, Kahle L, Taylor PR. Effects of dietary fat and fiber on plasma and urine androgens and estrogens in men: a controlled feeding study. Am J Clin Nutr. 1996;64:850&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8942407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen EK, Adlercreutz H, Puska P, Pietinen P. Diet and serum sex hormones in healthy men. J Steroid Biochem. 1984;20:459&#x2013;464. doi: 10.1016/0022-4731(84)90254-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-4731(84)90254-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6538617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryanarayana BV, Kent JR, Meister L, Parlow AF. Pituitary-gonadal axis during prolonged total starvation in obese men. Am J Clin Nutr. 1969;22:767&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5789477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossow LM, Fukuda DH, Fahs CA, Loenneke JP, Stout JR. Natural bodybuilding competition preparation and recovery: a 12-month case study. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2013;8:582&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23412685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucks AB, Verdun M, Heath EM. Low energy availability, not stress of exercise, alters LH pulsatility in exercising women. J Appl Physiol. 1998;84:37&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9451615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP. Strength nutrition: maximizing your anabolic potential. Strength Cond J. 2010;32:80&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181d5284e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e3181d5284e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shephard RJ. Electrolyte manipulation in female body-builders. Br J Sports Med. 1994;28:60&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1332163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8044499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Too D, Wakayama EJ, Locati LL, Landwer GE. Effect of a precompetition bodybuilding diet and training regimen on body composition and blood chemistry. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1998;38:245&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9830833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawyer JC, Wood RJ, Davidson PW, Collins SM, Matthews TD, Gregory SM, Paolone VJ. Effects of a short-term carbohydrate-restricted diet on strength and power performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:2255&#x2013;2262. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31827da314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31827da314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23774282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soenen S, Bonomi AG, Lemmens SGT, Scholte J, Thijssen MAMA, van Berkum F, Westerterp-Plantenga MS. Relatively high-protein or &#x2018;low-carb&#x2019; energy-restricted diets for body weight loss and body weight maintenance? Physiol Behav. 2012;107:374&#x2013;380. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2012.08.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2012.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22935440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Grimaldi K, D'Agostino D, Cenci L, Moro T, Bianco A, Palma A. Ketogenic diet does not affect strength performance in elite artistic gymnasts. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9:34. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-9-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-9-34</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22835211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essen-Gustavsson B, Tesch PA. Glycogen and triglyceride utilization in relation to muscle metabolic characteristics in men performing heavy-resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1990;61:5&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1007/BF00236686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00236686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2289498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goedecke JH, Gibson ASC, Grobler L, Collins M, Noakes TD, Lambert EV. Determinants of the variability in respiratory exchange ratio at rest and during exercise in trained athletes. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2000;279:E1325&#x2013;E1334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11093921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornier MA, Donahoo WT, Pereira R, Gurevich I, Westergren R, Enerback S, Eckel PJ, Goalstone ML, Hill JO, Eckel RH, Draznin B. Insulin sensitivity determines the effectiveness of dietary macronutrient composition on weight loss in obese women. Obes Res. 2005;13:703&#x2013;709. doi: 10.1038/oby.2005.79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2005.79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15897479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pendergast DR, Leddy JJ, Venkatraman JT. A perspective on fat intake in athletes. J Am Coll Nutr. 2000;19:345&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1080/07315724.2000.10718930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.2000.10718930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10872896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turocy PS, DePalma BF, Horswill CA, Laquale KM, Martin TJ, Perry AC, Somova MJ, Utter AC. National athletic trainers' association position statement: safe weight loss and maintenance practices in sport and exercise. J Athl Train. 2011;46:322&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3419563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21669104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy JL, Katz AL, Cutler CL, Sherman WM, Coyle EF. Muscle glycogen synthesis after exercise: effect of time of carbohydrate ingestion. J Appl Physiol. 1988;64:1480&#x2013;1485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3132449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jentjens R, Jeukendrup A. Determinants of post-exercise glycogen synthesis during short-term recovery. Sports Med. 2003;33:117&#x2013;144. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200333020-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200333020-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robergs RA, Pearson DR, Costill DL, Fink WJ, Pascoe DD, Benedict MA, Lambert CP, Zachweija JJ. Muscle glycogenolysis during differing intensities of weight-resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1991;70:1700&#x2013;1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2055849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy BD, Tarnopolsky MA. Influence of differing macronutrient intakes on muscle glycogen resynthesis after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1998;84:890&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9480948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Dreyer HC, Drummond MJ, Glynn EL, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion before resistance exercise does not enhance postexercise muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:1730&#x2013;1739. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.90395.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.90395.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2681328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18535123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baty JJ, Hwang H, Ding Z, Bernard JR, Wang B, Kwon B, Ivy JL. The effect of a carbohydrate and protein supplement on resistance exercise performance, hormonal response, and muscle damage. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:321&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Elliott TA, Cree MG, Aarsland AA, Sanford AP, Wolfe RR. Stimulation of net muscle protein synthesis by whey protein ingestion before and after exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007;292:E71&#x2013;E76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16896166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Liquid carbohydrate/essential amino acid ingestion during a short-term bout of resistance exercise suppresses myofibrillar protein degradation. Metabolism. 2006;55:570&#x2013;577. doi: 10.1016/j.metabol.2005.11.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2005.11.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16631431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levenhagen DK, Gresham JD, Carlson MG, Maron DJ, Borel MJ, Flakoll PJ. Postexercise nutrient intake timing in humans is critical to recovery of leg glucose and protein homeostasis. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2001;280:E982&#x2013;E993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11350780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Rasmussen BB, Miller SL, Wolf SE, Owens-Stovall SK, Petrini BE, Wolfe RR. Timing of amino acid-carbohydrate ingestion alters anabolic response of muscle to resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2001;281:E197&#x2013;E206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11440894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb PJ, Hayes A. Effects of supplement timing and resistance exercise on skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:1918&#x2013;1925. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmarck B, Andersen JL, Olsen S, Richter EA, Mizuno M, Kjaer M. Timing of postexercise protein intake is important for muscle hypertrophy with resistance training in elderly humans. J Physiol. 2001;535:301&#x2013;311. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00301.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00301.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11507179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burk A, Timpmann S, Medijainen L, Vahi M, Oopik V. Time-divided ingestion pattern of casein-based protein supplement stimulates an increase in fat-free body mass during resistance training in young untrained men. Nutr Res. 2009;29:405&#x2013;413. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2009.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2009.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19628107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Tranchina CP, Rashti SL, Kang J, Faigenbaum AD. Effect of protein-supplement timing on strength, power, and body-composition changes in resistance-trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19:172&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wycherley TP, Noakes M, Clifton PM, Cleanthous X, Keogh JB, Brinkworth GD. Timing of protein ingestion relative to resistance exercise training does not influence body composition, energy expenditure, glycaemic control or cardiometabolic risk factors in a hypocaloric, high protein diet in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2010;12:1097&#x2013;1105. doi: 10.1111/j.1463-1326.2010.01307.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1463-1326.2010.01307.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20977582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisgarber KD, Candow DG, Vogt ES. Whey protein before and during resistance exercise has no effect on muscle mass and strength in untrained young adults. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2012;22:463&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22806076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Stout JR, Wilborn CD. Effects of resistance training and protein plus amino acid supplementation on muscle anabolism, mass, and strength. Amino Acids. 2007;32:467&#x2013;477. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0398-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0398-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16988909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Kovanen V, Selanne H, Kraemer WJ, Hakkinen K, Mero AA. Acute and long-term effects of resistance exercise with or without protein ingestion on muscle hypertrophy and gene expression. Amino Acids. 2009;37:297&#x2013;308. doi: 10.1007/s00726-008-0150-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-008-0150-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18661258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Jonkers RA, Gleeson BG, Beelen M, Meijer K, Savelberg HH, Wodzig WK, Dendale P, van Loon LJ. Protein supplementation before and after exercise does not further augment skeletal muscle hypertrophy after resistance training in elderly men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89:608&#x2013;616. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.2008.26626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2008.26626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19106243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Fletcher G, Hanson B, Folland JP. Whey protein does not enhance the adaptations to elbow flexor resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:1791&#x2013;1800. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318256c48d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318256c48d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22460474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Moore DR, Atherton PJ, Staples AW, Prior T, Tang JE, Rennie MJ, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Enhanced amino acid sensitivity of myofibrillar protein synthesis persists for up to 24&#xa0;h after resistance exercise in young men. J Nutr. 2011;141:568&#x2013;573. doi: 10.3945/jn.110.135038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.110.135038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, De Bock K, Maris M, Ramaekers M, Nielens H, Francaux M, Hespel P. Increased p70s6k phosphorylation during intake of a protein-carbohydrate drink following resistance exercise in the fasted state. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:791&#x2013;800. doi: 10.1007/s00421-009-1289-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1289-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20187284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Robinson MJ, Fry JL, Tang JE, Glover EI, Wilkinson SB, Prior T, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89:161&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Breen L, Burd NA, Hector AJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Josse AR, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise enhances myofibrillar protein synthesis with graded intakes of whey protein in older men. Br J Nutr. 2012;108:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1017/S0007114511005204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114511005204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22313809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamer HM, Wall BT, Kiskini A, de Lange A, Groen BB, Bakker JA, Gijsen AP, Verdijk LB, van Loon LJ. Carbohydrate co-ingestion with protein does not further augment post-prandial muscle protein accretion in older men. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2013;10:15. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-10-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-10-15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3585863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23351781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staples AW, Burd NA, West DW, Currie KD, Atherton PJ, Moore DR, Rennie MJ, Macdonald MJ, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Carbohydrate does not augment exercise-induced protein accretion versus protein alone. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1154&#x2013;1161. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820751cb.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820751cb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Karagounis LG, Peirce N, Simpson EJ, Hazell M, Layfield R, Wackerhage H, Smith K, Atherton P, Selby A, Rennie MJ. Disassociation between the effects of amino acids and insulin on signaling, ubiquitin ligases, and protein turnover in human muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295:E595&#x2013;E604. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.90411.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.90411.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2536736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Beelen M, Stellingwerff T, Pennings B, Saris WH, Kies AK, Kuipers H, van Loon LJ. Coingestion of carbohydrate with protein does not further augment postexercise muscle protein synthesis. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007;293:E833&#x2013;E842. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00135.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00135.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick C, Harvey T, Stout J, Campbell B, Wilborn C, Kreider R, Kalman D, Ziegenfuss T, Lopez H, Landis J, Ivy JL, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: nutrient timing. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2008;5:17. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-5-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-5-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2575187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18834505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aragon AA, Schoenfeld BJ. Nutrient timing revisited: is there a post-exercise anabolic window? J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10:5. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-10-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3577439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23360586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor MA, Garrow JS. Compared with nibbling, neither gorging nor a morning fast affect short-term energy balance in obese patients in a chamber calorimeter. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2001;25:519&#x2013;528. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0801572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0801572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11319656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Venne WP V-v, Westerterp KR. Influence of the feeding frequency on nutrient utilization in man: consequences for energy metabolism. Eur J Clin Nutr. 1991;45:161&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1905998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farshchi HR, Taylor MA, Macdonald IA. Decreased thermic effect of food after an irregular compared with a regular meal pattern in healthy lean women. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2004;28:653&#x2013;660. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0802616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0802616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15085170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farshchi HR, Taylor MA, Macdonald IA. Regular meal frequency creates more appropriate insulin sensitivity and lipid profiles compared with irregular meal frequency in healthy lean women. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2004;58:1071&#x2013;1077. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15220950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvie MN, Pegington M, Mattson MP, Frystyk J, Dillon B, Evans G, Cuzick J, Jebb SA, Martin B, Cutler RG, Son TG, Maudsley S, Carlson OD, Egan JM, Flyvbjerg A, Howell A. The effects of intermittent or continuous energy restriction on weight loss and metabolic disease risk markers: a randomized trial in young overweight women. Int J Obes. 2011;35:714&#x2013;727. doi: 10.1038/ijo.2010.171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2010.171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3017674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20921964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soeters MR, Lammers NM, Dubbelhuis PF, Ackermans M, Jonkers-Schuitema CF, Fliers E, Sauerwein HP, Aerts JM, Serlie MJ. Intermittent fasting does not affect whole-body glucose, lipid, or protein metabolism. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;90:1244&#x2013;1251. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.2008.27327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2008.27327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnal MA, Mosoni L, Boirie Y, Houlier ML, Morin L, Verdier E, Ritz P, Antoine JM, Prugnaud J, Beaufrere B, Mirand PP. Protein feeding pattern does not affect protein retention in young women. J Nutr. 2000;130:1700&#x2013;1704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10867039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnal MA, Mosoni L, Boirie Y, Houlier ML, Morin L, Verdier E, Ritz P, Antoine JM, Prugnaud J, Beaufrere B, Mirand PP. Protein pulse feeding improves protein retention in elderly women. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;69:1202&#x2013;1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10357740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Bounty PM, Campbell BI, Wilson J, Galvan E, Berardi J, Kleiner SM, Kreider RB, Stout JR, Ziegenfuss T, Spano M, Smith A, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: meal frequency. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2011;8:4. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-8-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-8-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3070624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21410984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varady KA. Intermittent versus daily calorie restriction: which diet regimen is more effective for weight loss? Obes Rev. 2011;12:e593&#x2013;e601. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-789X.2011.00873.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2011.00873.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21410865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosy-Westphal A, Later W, Hitze B, Sato T, Kossel E, Gluer CC, Heller M, Muller MJ. Accuracy of bioelectrical impedance consumer devices for measurement of body composition in comparison to whole body magnetic resonance imaging and dual X-ray absorptiometry. Obes Facts. 2008;1:319&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6452160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20054195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pateyjohns IR, Brinkworth GD, Buckley JD, Noakes M, Clifton PM. Comparison of three bioelectrical impedance methods with DXA in overweight and obese men. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2006;14:2064&#x2013;2070. doi: 10.1038/oby.2006.241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2006.241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17135624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neovius M, Hemmingsson E, Freyschuss B, Udden J. Bioelectrical impedance underestimates total and truncal fatness in abdominally obese women. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2006;14:1731&#x2013;1738. doi: 10.1038/oby.2006.199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2006.199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17062802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stote KS, Baer DJ, Spears K, Paul DR, Harris GK, Rumpler WV, Strycula P, Najjar SS, Ferrucci L, Ingram DK, Longo DL, Mattson MP. A controlled trial of reduced meal frequency without caloric restriction in healthy, normal-weight, middle-aged adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;85:981&#x2013;988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2645638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17413096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwao S, Mori K, Sato Y. Effects of meal frequency on body composition during weight control in boxers. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 1996;6:265&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8960647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benardot D, Martin DE, Thompson WR, Roman SB. Between-meal energy intake effects on body composition, performance, and totol caloric consumption in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:S339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton LE, Wilson GJ. Optimal protein intake to maximize muscle protein synthesis: examinations of optimal meal protein intake. Agro Food Industry Hi-Tech. 2009;20:54&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohe J, Low JF, Wolfe RR, Rennie MJ. Latency and duration of stimulation of human muscle protein synthesis during continuous infusion of amino acids. J Physiol. 2001;532:575&#x2013;579. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0575f.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0575f.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11306673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton PJ, Etheridge T, Watt PW, Wilkinson D, Selby A, Rankin D, Smith K, Rennie MJ. Muscle full effect after oral protein: time-dependent concordance and discordance between human muscle protein synthesis and mTORC1 signaling. Am J Clin Nutr. 2010;92:1080&#x2013;1088. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.2010.29819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2010.29819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20844073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munsters MJ, Saris WH. Effects of meal frequency on metabolic profiles and substrate partitioning in lean healthy males. PLoS One. 2012;7:e38632. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0038632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0038632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22719910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmstrup M, Owens CM, Fairchild TJ, Kanaley JA. Effect of meal freqnency on glucose and insulin excursions over the course of a day. Eur e-J Clin Nutr Metab. 2010;5:277&#x2013;280. doi: 10.1016/j.eclnm.2010.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclnm.2010.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leidy HJ, Armstrong CL, Tang M, Mattes RD, Campbell WW. The influence of higher protein intake and greater eating frequency on appetite control in overweight and obese men. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2010;18:1725&#x2013;1732. doi: 10.1038/oby.2010.45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2010.45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4034047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20339363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Ormsbee MJ, Gentile CL, Nindl BC, Brestoff JR, Ruby M. Increased protein intake and meal frequency reduces abdominal fat during energy balance and energy deficit. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2013;21:1357&#x2013;1366. doi: 10.1002/oby.20296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.20296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23703835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adechian S, Balage M, Remond D, Migne C, Quignard-Boulange A, Marset-Baglieri A, Rousset S, Boirie Y, Gaudichon C, Dardevet D, Mosoni L. Protein feeding pattern, casein feeding or milk soluble protein feeding did not change the evolution of body composition during a short-term weight loss program. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;303:E973&#x2013;E982. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00285.2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00285.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22895782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Areta J, Coffey VG, Stellingwerff T, Phillips SM, Burke LM, Cleroux M, Godin JP, Hawley JA. Daytime pattern of post-exercise protein intake affects whole-body protein turnover in resistance-trained males. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2012;9:91. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-9-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-9-91</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23067428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta JL, Burke LM, Ross ML, Camera DM, West DW, Broad EM, Jeacocke NA, Moore DR, Stellingwerff T, Phillips SM, Hawley JA, Coffey VG. Timing and distribution of protein ingestion during prolonged recovery from resistance exercise alters myofibrillar protein synthesis. J Physiol. 2013;591:2319&#x2013;2331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OCB/NANBF/IFPA Drug Testing Guidelines.  [ http://www.thenaturalmusclenetwork.com/OCB/forms/DrugTestingGuidelines.pdf]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell B, Kreider RB, Ziegenfuss T, La Bounty P, Roberts M, Burke D, Landis J, Lopez H, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: protein and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:8. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-4-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-4-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford TW, Kreider RB, Stout JR, Greenwood M, Campbell B, Spano M, Ziegenfuss T, Lopez H, Landis J, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition position stand: creatine supplementation and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:6. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-4-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-4-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2048496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Kim C, Carpentier A, Poortmans J. Studies on the safety of creatine supplementation. Amino Acids. 2011;40:1409&#x2013;1418. doi: 10.1007/s00726-011-0878-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-011-0878-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21399917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becque MD, Lochmann JD, Melrose DR. Effects of oral creatine supplementation on muscular strength and body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:654&#x2013;658. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200003000-00016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200003000-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, Staron RS, Putukian M, Gomez AL, Pearson DR, Fink WJ, Kraemer WJ. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:1147&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1674&#x2013;1681. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Goris M, Van Hecke P, Van Leemputte M, Vangerven L, Hespel P. Long-term creatine intake is beneficial to muscle performance during resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:2055&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Sanborn K, Smith LL, O'Bryant HS, Hoke T, Utter AC, Johnson RL, Boros R, Hruby J, Pierce KC, Stone ME, Garner B. Effects of in-season (5&#xa0;weeks) creatine and pyruvate supplementation on anaerobic performance and body composition in American football players. Int J Sport Nutr. 1999;9:146&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10362452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persky AM, Brazeau GA. Clinical pharmacology of the dietary supplement creatine monohydrate. Pharmacol Rev. 2001;53:161&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11356982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Soderlund K, Timmons JA, Cederblad G, Greenhaff PL. Muscle creatine loading in men. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:232&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8828669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallon MJ, Child R. Book Kre-alkalyn suppplementation has no beneficial effect on creatine-to-creatinine conversion rates. City; 2007. Kre-alkalyn suppplementation has no beneficial effect on creatine-to-creatinine conversion rates.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Child RT MJ. Creatine ethyl ester rapidly degrades to creatinine in stomach acid. Book Creatine ethyl ester rapidly degrades to creatinine in stomach acid. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M, Schoch R, Cooke M, Harvey T, Greenwood M, Kreider R, Willoughby DS. The effects of creatine ethyl ester supplementation combined with heavy resistance training on body composition, muscle performance, and serum and muscle creatine levels. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:6. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-6-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-6-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2649889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Oliver JM, Sanchez A, Galvan E, Fluckey J, Riechman S, Greenwood M, Kelly K, Meininger C, Rasmussen C, Kreider RB. A buffered form of creatine does not promote greater changes in muscle creatine content, body composition, or training adaptations than creatine monohydrate. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9:43. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-9-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-9-43</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3479057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22971354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli GG, Gualano B, Smith A, Stout J, Lancha AH Jr. Role of beta-alanine supplementation on muscle carnosine and exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1162&#x2013;1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Tallon MJ, Dunnett M, Boobis L, Coakley J, Kim HJ, Fallowfield JL, Hill CA, Sale C, Wise JA. The absorption of orally supplied beta-alanine and its effect on muscle carnosine synthesis in human vastus lateralis. Amino Acids. 2006;30:279&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0299-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0299-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16554972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derave W, Ozdemir MS, Harris RC, Pottier A, Reyngoudt H, Koppo K, Wise JA, Achten E. beta-Alanine supplementation augments muscle carnosine content and attenuates fatigue during repeated isokinetic contraction bouts in trained sprinters. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103:1736&#x2013;1743. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00397.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00397.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17690198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill CA, Harris RC, Kim HJ, Harris BD, Sale C, Boobis LH, Kim CK, Wise JA. Influence of beta-alanine supplementation on skeletal muscle carnosine concentrations and high intensity cycling capacity. Amino Acids. 2007;32:225&#x2013;233. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0364-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0364-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16868650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Thienen R, Van Proeyen K, Vanden Eynde P, Puype J, Lefere T, Hespel P. Beta-alanine improves sprint performance in endurance cycling. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:898&#x2013;903. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818db708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31818db708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale C, Saunders B, Hudson S, Wise JA, Harris RC, Sunderland CD. Effect of beta-alanine plus sodium bicarbonate on high-intensity cycling capacity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1972&#x2013;1978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21407127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AE, Walter AA, Graef JL, Kendall KL, Moon JR, Lockwood CM, Fukuda DH, Beck TW, Cramer JT, Stout JR. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation and high-intensity interval training on endurance performance and body composition in men; a double-blind trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:5. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-6-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-6-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2649036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19210788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Cramer JT, Zoeller RF, Torok D, Costa P, Hoffman JR, Harris RC, O'Kroy J. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on the onset of neuromuscular fatigue and ventilatory threshold in women. Amino Acids. 2007;32:381&#x2013;386. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0474-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0474-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17136505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess NA, Ross R, Kang J, Magrelli J, Neese K, Faigenbaum AD, Wise JA. Beta-alanine and the hormonal response to exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2008;29:952&#x2013;958. doi: 10.1055/s-2008-1038678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1038678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18548362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Faigenbaum AD, Ross R, Kang J, Stout JR, Wise JA. Short-duration beta-alanine supplementation increases training volume and reduces subjective feelings of fatigue in college football players. Nutr Res. 2008;28:31&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2007.11.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2007.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoeller RF, Stout JR, O'Kroy JA, Torok DJ, Mielke M. Effects of 28&#xa0;days of beta-alanine and creatine monohydrate supplementation on aerobic power, ventilatory and lactate thresholds, and time to exhaustion. Amino Acids. 2007;33:505&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1007/s00726-006-0399-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-006-0399-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16953366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Kang J, Mangine G, Faigenbaum A, Stout J. Effect of creatine and beta-alanine supplementation on performance and endocrine responses in strength/power athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2006;16:430&#x2013;446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17136944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendrick IP, Harris RC, Kim HJ, Kim CK, Dang VH, Lam TQ, Bui TT, Smith M, Wise JA. The effects of 10&#xa0;weeks of resistance training combined with beta-alanine supplementation on whole body strength, force production, muscular endurance and body composition. Amino Acids. 2008;34:547&#x2013;554. doi: 10.1007/s00726-007-0008-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-007-0008-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18175046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeney KM, Wright GA, Glenn Brice A, Doberstein ST. The effect of beta-alanine supplementation on power performance during repeated sprint activity. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:79&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c63bd5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c63bd5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19935102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobson RM, Saunders B, Ball G, Harris RC, Sale C. Effects of beta-alanine supplementation on exercise performance: a meta-analysis. . Amino Acids. 2012;43:25&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1007/s00726-011-1200-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-011-1200-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22270875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu P, Xu W, Sturman JA. Dietary beta-alanine results in taurine depletion and cerebellar damage in adult cats. J Neurosci Res. 1996;43:112&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1002/jnr.490430115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jnr.490430115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8838582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith HJ, Mukerji P, Tisdale MJ. Attenuation of proteasome-induced proteolysis in skeletal muscle by {beta}-hydroxy-{beta}-methylbutyrate in cancer-induced muscle loss. Cancer Res. 2005;65:277&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15665304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eley HL, Russell ST, Baxter JH, Mukerji P, Tisdale MJ. Signaling pathways initiated by beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate to attenuate the depression of protein synthesis in skeletal muscle in response to cachectic stimuli. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007;293:E923&#x2013;E931. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00314.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00314.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathmacher JA, Nissen S, Panton L, Clark RH, Eubanks May P, Barber AE, D'Olimpio J, Abumrad NN. Supplementation with a combination of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB), arginine, and glutamine is safe and could improve hematological parameters. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2004;28:65&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1177/014860710402800265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/014860710402800265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15080599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissen S, Sharp RL, Panton L, Vukovich M, Trappe S, Fuller JC Jr. beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) supplementation in humans is safe and may decrease cardiovascular risk factors. J Nutr. 2000;130:1937&#x2013;1945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10917905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher PM, Carrithers JA, Godard MP, Schulze KE, Trappe SW. Beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate ingestion, part II: effects on hematology, hepatic and renal function. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:2116&#x2013;2119. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200012000-00023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200012000-00023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11128860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitschen PJ, Wilson GJ, Wilson JM, Wilund KR. Efficacy of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate supplementation in elderly and clinical populations. Nutrition. 2013;29:29&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2012.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2012.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23085015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Wilson JM, Manninen AH. Effects of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) on exercise performance and body composition across varying levels of age, sex, and training experience: a review. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2008;5:1. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-5-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-5-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2245953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18173841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J, Fitschen P, Campbell B, Wilson G, Zanchi N, Taylor L, Wilborn C, Kalman D, Stout J, Hoffman J, Ziegenfuss T, Lopez H, Kreider R, Smith-Ryan A, Antonio J. International Society of Sports Nutrition Position Stand: beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10:6. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-10-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23374455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimomura Y, Yamamoto Y, Bajotto G, Sato J, Murakami T, Shimomura N, Kobayashi H, Mawatari K. Nutraceutical effects of branched-chain amino acids on skeletal muscle. J Nutr. 2006;136:529S&#x2013;532S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garlick PJ, Grant I. Amino acid infusion increases the sensitivity of muscle protein synthesis in vivo to insulin. Effect of branched-chain amino acids. Biochem J. 1988;254:579&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1135117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3052439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balage M, Dardevet D. Long-term effects of leucine supplementation on body composition. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2010;13:265&#x2013;270. doi: 10.1097/MCO.0b013e328336f6b8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0b013e328336f6b8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20110810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pencharz PB, Elango R, Ball RO. Determination of the tolerable upper intake level of leucine in adult men. J Nutr. 2012;142:2220S&#x2013;2224S. doi: 10.3945/jn.112.160259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.112.160259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23077191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Tipton KD, Klein S, Wolfe RR. An abundant supply of amino acids enhances the metabolic effect of exercise on muscle protein. Am J Physiol. 1997;273:E122&#x2013;E129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Phillips SM, Doyle D Jr, Wolfe RR. Postexercise net protein synthesis in human muscle from orally administered amino acids. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E628&#x2013;E634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louard RJ, Barrett EJ, Gelfand RA. Effect of infused branched-chain amino acids on muscle and whole-body amino acid metabolism in man. Clin Sci. 1990;79:457&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2174312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsheim E, Tipton KD, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Essential amino acids and muscle protein recovery from resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2002;283:E648&#x2013;E657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12217881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoppani J, Scheett T, Pena J, Rudolph C, Charlebois D. Consuming a supplement containing branched-chain amino acids during a resistance-traning program increases lean mass, muscle strength, and fat loss. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:P1. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-6-S1-P1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-6-S1-P1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3313152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19660093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Layman DK, Moulton CJ, Norton LE, Anthony TG, Proud CG, Rupassara SI, Garlick PJ. Leucine or carbohydrate supplementation reduces AMPK and eEF2 phosphorylation and extends postprandial muscle protein synthesis in rats. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;301:E1236&#x2013;E1242. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00242.2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00242.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4395871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21917636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryawan A, Hawes JW, Harris RA, Shimomura Y, Jenkins AE, Hutson SM. A molecular model of human branched-chain amino acid metabolism. Am J Clin Nutr. 1998;68:72&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Heffernan KS, Fernhall B. Hemodynamic and vascular response to resistance exercise with L-arginine. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:773&#x2013;779. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181909d9d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181909d9d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Lysecki PJ, Manolakos JJ, MacDonald MJ, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Bolus arginine supplementation affects neither muscle blood flow nor muscle protein synthesis in young men at rest or after resistance exercise. J Nutr. 2011;141:195&#x2013;200. doi: 10.3945/jn.110.130138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.110.130138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21191143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpi E, Kobayashi H, Sheffield-Moore M, Mittendorfer B, Wolfe RR. Essential amino acids are primarily responsible for the amino acid stimulation of muscle protein anabolism in healthy elderly adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2003;78:250&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12885705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvares TS, Meirelles CM, Bhambhani YN, Paschoalin VM, Gomes PS. L-Arginine as a potential ergogenic aid in healthy subjects. Sports Med. 2011;41:233&#x2013;248. doi: 10.2165/11538590-000000000-00000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11538590-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21395365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer BK, Jones BT. Acute arginine supplementation fails to improve muscle endurance or affect blood pressure responses to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:1789&#x2013;1794. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e07569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e07569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21399536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConell GK. Effects of L-arginine supplementation on exercise metabolism. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2007;10:46&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1097/MCO.0b013e32801162fa.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0b013e32801162fa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17143054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao A, Hathcock JN. Risk assessment for the amino acids taurine, L-glutamine and L-arginine. Regul Toxicol Pharmacol. 2008;50:376&#x2013;399. doi: 10.1016/j.yrtph.2008.01.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yrtph.2008.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18325648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Guisado J, Jakeman PM. Citrulline malate enhances athletic anaerobic performance and relieves muscle soreness. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:1215&#x2013;1222. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cb28e0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181cb28e0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendahan D, Mattei JP, Ghattas B, Confort-Gouny S, Le Guern ME, Cozzone PJ. Citrulline/malate promotes aerobic energy production in human exercising muscle. Br J Sports Med. 2002;36:282&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.36.4.282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.36.4.282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12145119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sureda A, Cordova A, Ferrer MD, Perez G, Tur JA, Pons A. L-citrulline-malate influence over branched chain amino acid utilization during exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110:341&#x2013;351. doi: 10.1007/s00421-010-1509-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1509-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20499249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickner RC, Tanner CJ, Evans CA, Clark PD, Haddock A, Fortune C, Geddis H, Waugh W, McCammon M. L-citrulline reduces time to exhaustion and insulin response to a graded exercise test. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:660&#x2013;666. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000210197.02576.da.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000210197.02576.da</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M. Dosing and efficacy of glutamine supplementation in human exercise and sport training. J Nutr. 2008;138:2045S&#x2013;2049S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18806122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Sanders MS, Kalman D, Woodgate D, Street C. The effects of high-dose glutamine ingestion on weightlifting performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16:157&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haub MD, Potteiger JA, Nau KL, Webster MJ, Zebas CJ. Acute L-glutamine ingestion does not improve maximal effort exercise. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1998;38:240&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9830832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colker CM, Swain MA, Fabrucini B, Shi Q, Kalman DS. Effects of supplemental protein on body composition and muscular strength in healthy athletic male adults. Curr Ther Res. 2000;61:19&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/S0011-393X(00)88492-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0011-393X(00)88492-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Burke DG, Davison KS, Smith-Palmer T. Effect of glutamine supplementation combined with resistance training in young adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;86:142&#x2013;149. doi: 10.1007/s00421-001-0523-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-001-0523-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11822473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri M, Madsen K, Spiller R, Van Meerveld BG, Verne GN. Intestinal barrier function in health and gastrointestinal disease. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2012;24:503&#x2013;512. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2982.2012.01921.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2982.2012.01921.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5595063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22583600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy JL, Kammer L, Ding Z, Wang B, Bernard JR, Liao YH, Hwang J. Improved cycling time-trial performance after ingestion of a caffeine energy drink. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19:61&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton LR, Lovell RJ, Siegler J, Midgley AW, Moore L, Bentley DJ. The effects of caffeine ingestion on time trial cycling performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2008;3:157&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19208924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr A, Dawson B, Schneiker K, Goodman C, Lay B. Effect of caffeine supplementation on repeated sprint running performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2008;48:472&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M, Howatson G, Abraham CS, Lockey RA, Goodwin JE, Foley P, McInnes G. Caffeine supplementation and multiple sprint running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1835&#x2013;1840. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31817a8ad2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31817a8ad2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green JM, Wickwire PJ, McLester JR, Gendle S, Hudson G, Pritchett RC, Laurent CM. Effects of caffeine on repetitions to failure and ratings of perceived exertion during resistance training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2007;2:250&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19168925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolf K, Bidwell WK, Carlson AG. The effect of caffeine as an ergogenic aid in anaerobic exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18:412&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18708685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan MJ, Oxford SW. The effect of caffeine ingestion on mood state and bench press performance to failure. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:178&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318201bddb.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318201bddb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21157384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AD, Cribb PJ, Cooke MB, Hayes A. The effect of ephedra and caffeine on maximal strength and power in resistance-trained athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:464&#x2013;470. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181660320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181660320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrix CR, Housh TJ, Mielke M, Zuniga JM, Camic CL, Johnson GO, Schmidt RJ, Housh DJ. Acute effects of a caffeine-containing supplement on bench press and leg extension strength and time to exhaustion during cycle ergometry. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:859&#x2013;865. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ae7976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ae7976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19834348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawrot P, Jordan S, Eastwood J, Rotstein J, Hugenholtz A, Feeley M. Effects of caffeine on human health. Food Addit Contam. 2003;20:1&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12519715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Atkinson SA, MacDougall JD, Sale DG, Sutton JR. Physiological responses to caffeine during endurance running in habitual caffeine users. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1989;21:418&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2674593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzarre TL, Kleiner SM, Litchford MD. Nutrient intake, body fat, and lipid profiles of competitive male and female bodybuilders. J Am Coll Nutr. 1990;9:136&#x2013;142. doi: 10.1080/07315724.1990.10720362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.1990.10720362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2338462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleiner SM, Bazzarre TL, Ainsworth BE. Nutritional status of nationally ranked elite bodybuilders. Int J Sport Nutr. 1994;4:54&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8167655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson JF Jr, Johnson TE, Lee W, Sidor RJ. Nutrition and the precontest preparations of a male bodybuilder. J Am Diet Assoc. 1990;90:264&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2303663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen RE, Barlett SJ, Morgan GD, Brownell KD. Weight loss, psychological, and nutritional patterns in competitive male body builders. Int J Eat Disord. 1995;18:49&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1002/1098-108X(199507)18:1&lt;49::AID-EAT2260180106&gt;3.0.CO;2-C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1098-108X(199507)18:1&lt;49::AID-EAT2260180106&gt;3.0.CO;2-C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7670443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balon TW, Horowitz JF, Fitzsimmons KM. Effects of carbohydrate loading and weight-lifting on muscle girth. Int J Sport Nutr. 1992;2:328&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1299502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costill DL, Cote R, Fink W. Muscle water and electrolytes following varied levels of dehydration in man. J Appl Physiol. 1976;40:6&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1248983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfield GS, Blouin AG, Woodside DB. Body image, binge eating, and bulimia nervosa in male bodybuilders. Can J Psychiatry. 2006;51:160&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16618007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangweth B, Pope HG Jr, Kemmler G, Ebenbichler C, Hausmann A, De Col C, Kreutner B, Kinzl J, Biebl W. Body image and psychopathology in male bodybuilders. Psychother Psychosom. 2001;70:38&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1159/000056223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000056223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11150937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baghurst T, Lirgg C. Characteristics of muscle dysmorphia in male football, weight training, and competitive natural and non-natural bodybuilding samples. Body Image. 2009;6:221&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1016/j.bodyim.2009.03.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bodyim.2009.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19410526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickett TC, Lewis RJ, Cash TF. Men, muscles, and body image: comparisons of competitive bodybuilders, weight trainers, and athletically active controls. Br J Sports Med. 2005;39:217&#x2013;222. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2004.012013. discussion 217&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2004.012013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1725169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15793091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankauskiene R, Kardelis K, Pajaujiene S. Muscle size satisfaction and predisposition for a health harmful practice in bodybuilders and recreational gymnasium users. Medicina (Kaunas) 2007;43:338&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17485962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walberg JL, Johnston CS. Menstrual function and eating behavior in female recreational weight lifters and competitive body builders. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1991;23:30&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1997810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundgot-Borgen J, Garthe I. Elite athletes in aesthetic and Olympic weight-class sports and the challenge of body weight and body compositions. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(Suppl 1):S101&#x2013;S114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21500080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>