<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23487491</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>33</Volume><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of multi-ingredient supplementation on resistance training in young males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>91</StartPage><EndPage>101</EndPage><MedlinePgn>91-101</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/v10078-012-0048-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Muscle strength and fatigue resistance increases with resistance training. Resistance training adaptations can be enhanced with single-ingredient or dual-ingredient supplementation but less is known about resistance training adaptations by multi-ingredient supplementation. We examined the effects of a commercial multi-ingredient supplement on resistance training adaptations for training-specific and non-training-specific tasks in young males. Male participants (n = 16, age 21&#xb1;2 years, body mass 74.5&#xb1;5.9 kg, body height 177&#xb1;5 cm) had at least 1 year experience with resistance training exercises. Training (7 muscle groups, 4 sessions/week, weekly adjustments) consisted of two 6 weeks blocks with 4 weeks between blocks. During training, participants consumed placebo (i.e. maltodextrin, n = 7) or the sports nutritional supplement Cyclone (Maximuscle Ltd, UK, n = 9) (main ingredients creatine monohydrate, whey protein, glutamine and HMB) twice daily with one intake &lt;15 min following a training session. Unpaired Student's t-test was used for placebo and Cyclone group comparison of percentage changes with p &lt; 0.05. Effect sizes (Cohen's d) were calculated for the Cyclone group. Cyclone did not enhance maximal voluntary isometric force (MVIF) (p = 0.56), time to fatigue at 70% MVIF (p = 0.41) and peak concentric strength (60&#xb0;&#xb7;s(-1)) (p = 0.66) of m.quadriceps femoris (i.e. the non-specific training tasks). For the specific-training tasks, Cyclone did not enhance one-repetition maximum (1-RM) of lateral pull (p = 0.48) but there was a trend and large effect size for 1-RM of bench press (p = 0.07, d = 0.98) and 45&#xb0; leg press (p = 0.07, d = 1.41). Cyclone resulted in an increase in number of repetitions for 80% pre-training 1-RM for lateral pull (p = 0.02, d = 1.30), bench press (p = 0.03, d = 1.20) with a trend for 45&#xb0; leg press (p = 0.08, d = 0.96). Cyclone during resistance training enhanced the performance of 1-RM and number of repetitions at 80% of pre-training 1RM of some training-specific tasks, all with large effect sizes. Our observations suggest that Cyclone during resistance training substantially improves the ability to perform training-related tasks.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willems</LastName><ForeName>Mark Et</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chichester, Department of Sport and Exercise Sciences, College Lane, Chichester, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sallis</LastName><ForeName>Chris W</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haskell</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cyclone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports nutrition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/v10078-012-0048-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jhk-33-91</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Trolle M, Bangsbo J, Klausen K. Effects of different strength training regimes on moment and power generation during dynamic knee extensions. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69:382&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7875132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW, Housh TJ, Johnson GO, Coburn JW, Malek MH, Cramer JT. Effects of a drink containing creatine, amino acids, and protein combined with ten weeks of resistance training on body composition, strength, and anaerobic performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:100&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, MacNeil LG, Roy BD, Tarnopolsky MA, Ziegenfuss T. Effect of creatine supplementation and resistance-exercise training on muscle insulin-like growth factor in young adults. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18:389&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18708688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Chilibeck PD, Davison KS, Candow DG, Farthing J, Smith-Palmer T. The effect of whey protein supplementation with and without creatine monohydrate combined with resistance training on lean tissue mass and muscle strength. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2001;11:349&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11591884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Burke DG, Davison KS, Smith-Palmer T. Effect of glutamine supplementation combined with resistance training in young adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;86:142&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11822473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, Ragg KE, Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Staron RS. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88:50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey A, Contatin-Teodosiu D, Howell S, Hultman E, Greenhaff PL. Creatine ingestion favourably affects performance and muscle metabolism during maximal exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1996;271:E31&#x2013;E37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8760078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chromiak JA, Smedley B, Carpenter W, Brown R, Koh YS, Lamberth JG, Joe LA, Abadie BR, Altorfer G. Effect of a 10-week strength training program and recovery drink on body composition, muscular strength and endurance, and anaerobic power and capacity. Nutrition. 2004;20:420&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15105028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes MR, Kraemer WJ. Performance and physiologic adaptations to resistance training. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;81(11 Suppl):S3&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12409807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolezal BA, Potteiger JA. Concurrent resistance and endurance training influence basal metabolic rate in nondieting individuals. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85:695&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Snell PG, Rodgiguez R, Almada AL, Mitchell TL. The effect of creatine monohydrate ingestion on power indices, muscular strength and body composition. Acta Physiol Scand. 1995;153:207&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7778463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Jones DA, Maffulli N, Williams AG, Stewart CE, Degens H. What causes in vivo muscle specific tension to increase following resistance training? Exp Physiol. 2011;96:145&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20889606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goreham C, Green HJ, Ball-Burnett M, Ranney D. High-resistance training and muscle metabolism during prolonged exercise. Am J Physiol. 1999;276(3 Pt 1):E489&#x2013;E496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10070015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman JW, Moore DR, Phillips SM. Resistance training reduces whole-body protein turnover and improves net protein retention in untrained young males. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2006;31:557&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17111010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Tranchina CP, Rashti SL, Kang J, Faigenbaum AD. Effect of a proprietary protein supplement on recovery indices following resistance exercise in strength/power athletes. Amino Acids. 2010;38:771&#x2013;778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19347247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Kovanen V, Sel&#xe4;nne H, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Mero AA. Acute and long-term effects of resistance exercise with or without protein ingestion on muscle hypertrophy and gene expression. Amino Acids. 2009;37:297&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18661258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Rasmussen CJ, Lancaster SL, Magu B, Smith P, Melton C, Greenwood M, Almada AL, Earnest CP, Kreider RB. The effects of protein and amino acid supplementation on performance and training adaptions during ten weeks of resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:643&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Rasmussen CJ, Lancaster SL, Starks M, Smith P, Melton C, Greenwood M, Almada A, Kreider R. Impact of differing protein sources and a creatine containing nutritional formula after 12 weeks resistance training. Nutrition. 2007;23:647&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17679046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Hatfield DL, Spiering BA, Vingren JL, Fragala MS, Ho JY, Volek JS, Anderson JM, Maresh CM. Effects of a multi-nutrient supplement on exercise performance and hormonal responses to resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101:637&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17701421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB. Dietary supplements and the promotion of muscle growth with resistance exercise. Sports Med. 1999;27:97&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10091274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider R, Ferreira M, Wilson M. Effects of calcium &#x3b2;- HMB supplementation with or without creatine during training on body composition alterations (abstract) FASEB J. 1997;11:A374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubukeli ZN, Noakes TD, Dennis SC. Training techniques to improve endurance exercise performances. Sports Med. 2002;32:489&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12076176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maganaris CN, Maughan RJ. Creatine supplementation enhances maximum voluntary isometric force and endurance capacity in resistance trained men. Acta Physiol Scand. 1998;163:279&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9715740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew DL, Kim JS, Cross JM, Ferrando AA, Bamman MM. Translational signaling responses preceding resistance training-mediated myofiber hypertrophy in young and old humans. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:1655&#x2013;1662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagaard P, Kadi F, Tufekovic G, Verney J, Olesen JL, Suetta C, Kjaer M. Creatine supplementation augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol. 2006;573(Pt 2):525&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panton LB, Rathmacher JA, Baier S, Nissen S. Nutritional supplementation of the leucine metabolite beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (hmb) during resistance training. Nutrition. 2000;16:734&#x2013;739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10978853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennings B, Boirie Y, Senden JM, Gijsen AP, Kuipers H, van Loon LJC. Whey protein stimulates postprandial muscle protein accretion more effectively than do casein and casein hydrolysate in older men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2011;93:997&#x2013;1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21367943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips GC. Glutamine: The nonessential amino acid for performance enhancement. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2007;6:265&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17618004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price M, Moss P, Rance S. Effects of sodium bicarbonate ingestion on prolonged intermittent exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:1303&#x2013;1308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Iosia M, Kerksick CM, Taylor LW, Campbell B, Wilborn CD, Harvey T, Cooke M, Rasmussen C, Greenwood M, Wilson R, Jitomir J, Willoughby D, Kreider RB. Effects of arachidonic acid supplementation on training adaptations in resistance-trained males. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007;4:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2217562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18045476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Volek JS. Effects of creatine supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and weight lifting performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:822&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford OM, Jones DA. The role of learning and coordination in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1986;55:100&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz SM, Hofheins JE, Lemieux R. Nine weeks of supplementation with a multi-nutrient product augments gains in lean mass, strength, and muscular performance in resistance trained men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3016253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21162744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelmadine B, Cooke M, Buford T, Hudson G, Redd L, Leutholtz B, Willoughby DS. Effects of 28 days of resistance exercise and consuming a commercially available pre-workout supplement, NO-Shotgun(R), on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of satellite cell activation, and clinical safety markers in males. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater GJ, Jenkins D. &#x3b2;-Hydroxy &#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (HMB) supplementation and the promotion of muscle growth and strength. Sports Med. 2000;30:105&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syrotuik DG, Bell GJ, Burnham R, Sim LL, Calvert RA, Maclean IM. Absolute and relative strength performance following creatine monohydrate supplementation combined with periodized resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14:182&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Goris M, Van Hecke P, Van Leemputte M, Vangerven L, Hespel P. Long-term creatine intake is beneficial to muscle performance during resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:2055&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Loon LJC. Application of protein or protein hydrolysates to improve post exercise recovery. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17:S104&#x2013;S117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Kraemer WJ. Creatine supplementation: Its effect on human muscular performance and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10:200&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter AA, Herda TJ, Ryan ED, Costa PB, Hoge KM, Beck TW, Stout JR, Cramer JT. Acute effects of a thermogenic nutritional supplement on cycling time to exhaustion and muscular strength in college-aged men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19594929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Wilson JM, Manninen AH. Effects of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) on exercise performance and body composition across varying levels of age, sex, and training experience: A review. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2008;5:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2245953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18173841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>