<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">12937471</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-162X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2003</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of athletic training</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Athl Train</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Creatine Supplementation Increases Total Body Water Without Altering Fluid Distribution.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>44</StartPage><EndPage>50</EndPage><MedlinePgn>44-50</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>OBJECTIVE: To examine the effects of oral creatine (Cr) monohydrate supplementation on muscle Cr concentration, body mass, and total body water (TBW), extracellular water (ECW), and intracellular water (ICW) volumes. DESIGN AND SETTING: After an overnight fast, urinary Cr and creatinine concentrations, muscle Cr concentration, body mass, TBW, ECW, and ICW were measured, and subjects were randomly assigned to either a Cr or a placebo (P) group. The Cr group ingested 25 g/d of Cr for 7 days (loading phase) and 5 g/d for the remaining 21 days (maintenance phase), whereas the P group ingested a sucrose P using the same protocol. All the measures were reassessed immediately after the loading and maintenance phases. SUBJECTS: Sixteen men (age = 22.8 +/- 3.01 years, height = 179.8 +/- 7.1 cm, body mass = 84.8 +/- 11.2 kg) and 16 women (age = 21.8 +/- 2.51 years, height = 163.4 +/- 5.9 cm, body mass = 63.6 +/- 14.0 kg) involved in resistance training volunteered to participate in this study. MEASUREMENTS: Muscle Cr concentration was determined from the vastus lateralis muscle using a percutaneous needle-biopsy technique. Total body water, ECW, and ICW volumes were assessed using deuterium oxide and sodium bromide dilution analyses. RESULTS: The Cr group experienced a significant increase in muscle Cr concentration, body mass, and TBW. The P group experienced a small but significant increase in TBW only. CONCLUSIONS: The Cr supplementation protocol was effective for increasing muscle Cr concentrations, body mass, and TBW; however, fluid distribution was not changed.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Powers</LastName><ForeName>Michael E.</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida, Gainesville, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arnold</LastName><ForeName>Brent L.</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weltman</LastName><ForeName>Arthur L.</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perrin</LastName><ForeName>David H.</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mistry</LastName><ForeName>Dilawaar</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kahler</LastName><ForeName>David M.</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kraemer</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Volek</LastName><ForeName>Jeff</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>M01 RR000847</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Athl Train</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9301647</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1062-6050</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2003</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2003</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2003</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2003</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC155510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Lond) 1992;83:367&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Soderlund K, Timmons JA, Cederblad G, Greenhaff PL. Muscle creatine loading in men. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:231&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8828669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna MJ, Morton J, Selig SE, Snow RJ. Creatine supplementation increases muscle total creatine but not maximal intermittent exercise performance. J Appl Physiol. 1999;87:2244&#x2013;2252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preen D, Dawson B, Goodman C, Lawrence S, Beilby J, Ching S. Effect of creatine loading on long term sprint exercise performance and metabolism. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:814&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11323554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becque MD, Lochmann JD, Melrose DR. Effects of oral creatine supplementation on muscular strength and body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;31:654&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Snell PG, Rodriguez R, Almada AL, Mitchell TL. The effect of creatine monohydrate ingestion on anaerobic power indices, muscular strength and body composition. Acta Physiol Scand. 1995;153:207&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7778463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly VG, Jenkins DG. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on near-maximal strength and repeated sets of high-intensity bench press exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 1998;12:109&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Kraemer WJ, Bush JA, et al. Creatine supplementation enhances muscular performance during high intensity resistance exercise. J Am Diet Assoc. 1997;97:765&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9216554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafe GG, Kirksey KB, Stone MH. The effect of 6 weeks of creatine monohydrate supplementation on dynamic rate of force development. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14:426&#x2013;433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirksey B, Stone MH, Warren BJ, et al. The effects of 6 weeks of creatine monohydrate supplementation on performance measures and body composition in collegiate track and field athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13:148&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Mazzetti SA, Farquhar WB, Barnes BR, Gomez AL, Kraemer WJ. Physiological responses to short-term exercise in the heat after creatine loading. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1101&#x2013;1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindstaff PD, Kreider R, Bishop R, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on repetitive sprint performance and body composition in competitive swimmers. Int J Sport Nutr. 1997;7:330&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9407259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsom PD, Ekblom B, Soderlund K, Sjodin B, Hultman E. Creatine supplementation and dynamic high-intensity intermittent exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 1993;3:143&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout J, Eckerson J, Ebersole K, et al. Effect of creatine loading on neuromuscular fatigue threshold. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:109&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilliam JD, Hohzorn C, Martin D, Trimble MH. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on isokinetic torque production. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;31:993&#x2013;996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10795791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Chatard JC, Lacoste L, Barale F, Geyssant A. Creatine supplementation does not improve sprint performance in competitive swimmers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:1435&#x2013;1441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8933496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG, Bemben DA, Loftiss DD, Knehans AW. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in college football athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1667&#x2013;1673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Ferreira M, Wilson M, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on body composition, strength, and sprint performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30:73&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francaux M, Poortman JR. Effects of training and creatine supplement on muscle strength and body mass. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1999;80:165&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10408330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Hultman E, Nordesjo LO. Glycogen, glycolytic intermediates and high energy phosphates determined in biopsy samples of muscular quadriceps femoris of man at rest: methods and variance of values. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1974;33:109&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4852173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measurement of body composition using deuterium oxide. Technical Paper 913. Nashua, NH: Metabolic Solutions Inc; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans EM, Saunders MJ, Spano MA, Arngrimsson SA, Lewis RD, Cureton KJ. Body composition changes with diet and exercise in obese women: a comparison of estimates from clinical methods and a 4-component model. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;70:5&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10393132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukaski HC, Johnson PE. A simple, inexpensive method of determining total body water using a tracer dose of D2O and infrared absorption of biological fluids. Am J Clin Nutr. 1985;41:363&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2982253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penman AD, Wright IA. Determination of deuterium level in biological fluids by isotope ratio mass spectrometry. Biomed Environ Mass Spectrom. 1987;14:339&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2959342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Extracellular water measurements with sodium bromide. Technical Paper 920. Nashua, NH: Metabolic Solutions Inc; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller ME, Cosgriff JM, Forbes GB. Bromide space determination using anion-exchange chromatography for measurement of bromide. Am J Clin Nutr. 1989;50:168&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2750689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Marken Lichtenbelt WD, Snel YEM, Brummer RJM, Koppeschaar HPF. Deuterium and bromide dilution, and bioimpedance spectrometry independently show that growth hormone-deficient adults have an enlarged extracellular water compartment related to intracellular water. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1997;82:907&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9062505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL. Creatine supplementation: recent developments. Br J Sports Med. 1996;30:276&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1332404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9015583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett C, Hinds M, Jenkins DG. Effects of oral creatine supplementation on multiple sprint cycle performance. Aust J Sci Med Sport. 1996;28:35&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8742865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Eckerson JM, Housh TJ, Ebersole KT. The effects of creatine supplementation on anaerobic working capacity. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13:135&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1674&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Klesges R, Harmon K, et al. Effects of ingesting supplements designed to promote lean tissue accretion on body composition during resistance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr. 1996;6:234&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8876343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN. Electrical impedance and total body electrical conductivity. In: Roche A, editor. Human Body Composition. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1996. pp. 79&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoeller DA. Hydrometry. In: Roche A, editor. Human Body Composition. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1996. pp. 25&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Kenefick RW, Castellani JW, et al. Bioimpedance spectroscopy technique: intra-, extracellular, and total body water. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:1657&#x2013;1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9432101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haussinger D, Lang F, Gerok W. Regulation of cell function by the cellular hydration state. Am J Physiol. 1994;267(3 Pt 1):E343&#x2013;E355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7943214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haussinger D. The role of cell hydration in the regulation of cell function. Biochem J. 1996;313(Pt 3):697&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1216967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8611144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modlesky CM, Cureton KJ, Lewis RD, Prior BM, Sloniger MA, Rowe DA. Density of the fat-free mass and estimates of body composition in male weight trainers. J Appl Physiol. 1996;80:2085&#x2013;2096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8806917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Crim MC, Young VR, Evans WJ. Increased energy requirements and changes in body composition with resistance training in older adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 1994;60:167&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8030593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>