<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15173863</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-162X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2004</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of athletic training</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Athl Train</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Pre-Exercise Muscle Temperature on Responses to Eccentric Exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>132</StartPage><EndPage>137</EndPage><MedlinePgn>132-137</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>OBJECTIVE: We tested the hypothesis that altering the pre-exercise muscle temperature would influence the magnitude of muscle damage induced by eccentric exercise. SUBJECTS: Female students who had no experience in resistance training were placed into either a microwave treatment group (n = 10) or an icing treatment group (n = 10). DESIGN AND SETTING: Subjects in each group performed 12 maximal eccentric actions of the forearm flexors of each arm on 2 separate occasions separated by 4 weeks. Before testing, the exercise arm was subjected to either passive warming (microwave) or control for the microwave treatment group or cooling (icing) or control for the icing treatment group. The control arm performed the same exercise protocol without treatment. Limbs were randomized for treatment or control and order of testing. Deep muscle temperature increased by approximately 3 degrees C after the microwave treatment and decreased approximately 5 degrees C after the icing treatment. MEASUREMENTS: We evaluated changes in maximal isometric force and indirect markers of muscle damage, including range of motion, upper arm circumference, muscle soreness, and plasma creatine kinase activity, in the microwave and control and icing and control groups using a 2-way, repeated-measures analysis of variance. RESULTS: All measures changed significantly (P &lt;.01) after exercise, but neither of the treatments demonstrated significant effects on most of the variables compared with the control. CONCLUSIONS: These results suggest that pre-exercise cooling does not affect the magnitude of muscle damage in response to eccentric exercise. Similarly, pre-exercise passive muscle warming did not prove beneficial in attenuating indicators of muscle damage. Thus, any beneficial effects of warm-up exercise cannot be attributed to the effects of increased muscle temperature.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nosaka</LastName><ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Western Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakamoto</LastName><ForeName>Kei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sacco</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Athl Train</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9301647</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1062-6050</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2004</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2004</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2004</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2004</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC419506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Nosaka K, Braun B. Muscle function after exercise-induced muscle damage and rapid adaptation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24:512&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1569847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell JN, Chleboun G, Conatser R. Muscle stiffness, strength loss, swelling and soreness following exercise-induced injury in humans. J Physiol. 1993;464:183&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1175380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8229798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RK, Knight KL, Draper DO, Parcell AC. Effects of warm-up before eccentric exercise on indirect markers of muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:1892&#x2013;1899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12471293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM. Influence of previous concentric exercise on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. J Sports Sci. 1997;15:477&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9386205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodenburg JB, Steenbeek D, Schiereck P, B&#xe4;r PR. Warm-up, stretching and massage diminish harmful effects of eccentric exercise. Int J Sports Med. 1994;15:414&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8002121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargeant AJ. Effect of muscle temperature on leg extension force and short-term power output in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1987;56:693&#x2013;698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3678224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shellock FG, Prentice WE. Warming-up and stretching for improved physical performance and prevention of sports-related injuries. Sports Med. 1985;2:267&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3849057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safran MR, Garrett WE, Jr, Seaber AV, Glisson RR, Ribbeck BM. The role of warmup in muscular injury prevention. Am J Sports Med. 1988;16:123&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3377095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safran MR, Seaber AV, Garrett WE., Jr Warm-up and muscle injury prevention: an update. Sports Med. 1989;8:239&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2692118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strickler T, Malone T, Garrett WE. The effects of passive warming on muscle injury. Am J Sports Med. 1990;18:141&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2343981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM. Changes in indicators of inflammation after eccentric exercise of the elbow flexors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8871903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szymanski DJ. Recommendations for the avoidance of delayed-onset muscle soreness. Strength Cond J. 2001;23:7&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isabell WK, Durrant E, Myrer W, Anderson S. The effects of ice massage, ice massage with exercise, and exercise on the prevention and treatment of delayed onset muscle soreness. J Athl Train. 1992;27:208&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yackzan L, Adams C, Francis KT. The effects of ice massage on delayed muscle soreness. Am J Sports Med. 1984;12:159&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6742292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones DJ, Quigley BM. Effect of cryotherapy on muscle soreness and strength following eccentric exercise. Int J Sports Med. 1997;18:588&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9443590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donley PB. Shortwave and microwave diathermy. In: Prentice WE, editor. Therapeutic Modalities in Sports Medicine. 2nd ed. St Louis, MO: Time Mirror/Mosby College Publishing; 1990. pp. 149&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goats GC. Microwave diathermy. Br J Sports Med. 1990;24:212&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1478902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2097017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper DO, Knight K, Fujiwara T, Castel JC. Temperature change in human muscle during and after pulsed short-wave diathermy. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1999;29:13&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10100117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowdon BJ, Moore RJ. Determinants and nature of intramuscular temperature changes during cold therapy. Am J Phys Med. 1975;54:223&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1180351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemke JE, Andersen JC, Guion KW, McMillan J, Joyner AB. Intramuscular temperature responses in the human leg to two forms of cryotherapy: ice massage and ice bag. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1998;27:301&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9549714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Newton M, Sacco P. Delayed-onset muscle soreness does not reflect the magnitude of eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2002;12:337&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergh U, Ekblom B. Influence of muscle temperature on maximal muscle strength and power output in human skeletal muscles. Acta Physiol Scand. 1979;107:33&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">525366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie B, Thomas CK, Rice CL, Howarth JV, Woods JJ. Muscle temperature, contractile speed, and motoneuron firing rates during human voluntary contractions. J Appl Physiol. 1992;73:2457&#x2013;2461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1490958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies CTM, Young K. Effect of temperature on the contractile properties and muscle power of triceps surae in humans. J Appl Physiol. 1983;55:191&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6885568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meigal AY, Lupandin YV, H&#xe4;nninen O. Influence of cold and hot conditions on postactivation in human skeletal muscles. Pflugers Arch. 1996;432:121&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8662276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranatunga KW, Sharpe B, Turnbull B. Contractions of a human skeletal muscle at different temperatures. J Physiol. 1987;390:383&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1192187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3443940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myrer JW, Draper DO, Durrant E. Contrast therapy and intramuscular temperature in the human leg. J Athl Train. 1994;29:318&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyton AC. Textbook of Medical Physiology. 8th ed. Philadelphia, PA: WB Saunders Co; 1991. pp. 797&#x2013;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth VJ, Van Lunen BL, Mistry D, Saliba E, McCue FC. Temperature changes in deep muscles of humans during upper and lower extremity exercise. J Athl Train. 1998;33:211&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1320425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuitunen S, Avela J, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Nicol C, Komi PV. Acute and prolonged reduction in joint stiffness in humans after exhausting stretch-shortening cycle exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88:107&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan TJ, Best TM, Seaber AV, Garrett WE., Jr Thermal effects on skeletal muscle tensile behavior. Am J Sports Med. 1993;21:517&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8368411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross KM, Worrell TW. Effects of a static stretching program on the incidence of lower extremity musculotendinous strains. J Athl Train. 1999;34:11&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1322867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>