<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20034396</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5918</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Dynamic medicine : DM</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dyn Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of age on skeletal muscle and the phosphocreatine energy system: can creatine supplementation help older adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1476-5918-8-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Creatine supplementation has been found to significantly increase muscle strength and hypertrophy in young adults (&lt;/= 35 yr) particularly when consumed in conjunction with a resistance training regime. Literature examining the efficacy of creatine supplementation in older adults (55-82 yr) suggests creatine to promote muscle strength and hypertrophy to a greater extent than resistance training alone. The following is a review of literature reporting on the effects of creatine supplementation on intramuscular high energy phosphates, skeletal muscle morphology and quality of life in older adults. Results suggest creatine supplementation to be a safe, inexpensive and effective nutritional intervention, particularly when consumed in conjunction with a resistance training regime, for slowing the rate of muscle wasting that is associated with aging. Physicians should strongly consider advising older adults to supplement with creatine and to begin a resistance training regime in an effort to enhance skeletal muscle strength and hypertrophy, resulting in enhanced quality of life.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dalbo</LastName><ForeName>Vincent J</ForeName><Initials>VJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Biochemistry and Molecular Physiology Laboratory, Department of Health &amp; Exercise Science, University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK, USA. vinnyjames@ou.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lockwood</LastName><ForeName>Chris M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tucker</LastName><ForeName>Patrick S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreider</LastName><ForeName>Richard B</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerksick</LastName><ForeName>Chad M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Dyn Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101152197</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1476-5918</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20034396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2807421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-5918-8-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1476-5918-8-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Giresi PG, Stevenson EJ, Theilhaber J, Koncarevic A, Parkington J, Fielding RA, Kandarian SC. Identification of a molecular signature of sarcopenia. Physiol Genomics. 2005;21:253&#x2013;263. doi: 10.1152/physiolgenomics.00249.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiolgenomics.00249.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15687482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Shepard DS, Katzmarzyk PT, Roubenoff R. The healthcare costs of sarcopenia in the United States. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004;52:80&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2004.52014.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2004.52014.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borst SE. Interventions for sarcopenia and muscle weakness in older people. Age Ageing. 2004;33:548&#x2013;555. doi: 10.1093/ageing/afh201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afh201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel HK. Sarcopenia and aging. Nutr Rev. 2003;61:157&#x2013;167. doi: 10.1301/nr.2003.may.157-167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1301/nr.2003.may.157-167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12822704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calof OM, Singh AB, Lee ML, Kenny AM, Urban RJ, Tenover JL, Bhasin S. Adverse events associated with testosterone replacement in middle-aged and older men: a meta-analysis of randomized, placebo-controlled trials. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2005;60:1451&#x2013;1457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Hannibal NS, Nindl BC, Gentile CL, Hamed J, Vukovich MD. Comparison of creatine ingestion and resistance training on energy expenditure and limb blood flow. Metabolism. 2001;50:1429&#x2013;1434. doi: 10.1053/meta.2001.28159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2001.28159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipila I, Rapola J, Simell O, Vannas A. Supplementary creatine as a treatment for gyrate atrophy of the choroid and retina. N Engl J Med. 1981;304:867&#x2013;870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7207523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becque MD, Lochmann JD, Melrose DR. Effects of oral creatine supplementation on muscular strength and body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:654&#x2013;658. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200003000-00016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200003000-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Snell PG, Rodriguez R, Almada AL, Mitchell TL. The effect of creatine monohydrate ingestion on anaerobic power indices, muscular strength and body composition. Acta Physiol Scand. 1995;153:207&#x2013;209. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1995.tb09854.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1995.tb09854.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7778463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly V, Jenkins D. Effect of oral creatine supplmentation on near-maximal strength and repeated sets of high-intensity bench press exercise. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 1998;12:109&#x2013;115. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(1998)012&lt;0109:EOOCSO&gt;2.3.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(1998)012&lt;0109:EOOCSO&gt;2.3.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan D, Berg K, Latin R, Wagner J, Reimers K. Effects of varying dosages of oral creatine relative to fat free body mass on strength and body composition. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 1998;12:104&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(1998)012&lt;0104:EOVDOO&gt;2.3.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(1998)012&lt;0104:EOVDOO&gt;2.3.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson D, Hamby D, Russel W, Harris T. Long-term effects of creatine monohydrate on strength and power. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 1999;13:187&#x2013;192. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(1999)013&lt;0187:LTEOCM&gt;2.0.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(1999)013&lt;0187:LTEOCM&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters B, Lantz C, Mayhew J. Effect of oral creatine monohydrate and creatine phosphate supplementation on maximal strength indices, body composition, and blood pressure. The Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 1999;13:3&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(1999)013&lt;0003:EOOCMA&gt;2.0.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(1999)013&lt;0003:EOOCMA&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Goris M, Van Hecke P, Van Leemputte M, Vangerven L, Hespel P. Long-term creatine intake is beneficial to muscle performance during resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:2055&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1674&#x2013;1681. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200105001-00170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200105001-00170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Wehnert ML, Clarkson PM. Effects of 30 days of creatine ingestion in older men. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1999;80:139&#x2013;144. doi: 10.1007/s004210050570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10408325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotshalk LA, Kraemer WJ, Mendonca MA, Vingren JL, Kenny AM, Spiering BA, Hatfield DL, Fragala MS, Volek JS. Creatine supplementation improves muscular performance in older women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102:223&#x2013;231. doi: 10.1007/s00421-007-0580-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0580-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17943308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM, Price TB, Miles MP. Differential response of muscle phosphocreatine to creatine supplementation in young and old subjects. Acta Physiol Scand. 2002;174:57&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-201x.2002.00924.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-201x.2002.00924.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11851597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Chad KE, Chrusch MJ, Davison KS, Burke DG. Effect of ceasing creatine supplementation while maintaining resistance training in older men. J Aging Phys Act. 2004;12:219&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15263100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eijnde BO, Van Leemputte M, Goris M, Labarque V, Taes Y, Verbessem P, Vanhees L, Ramaekers M, Eynde B Vanden, Van Schuylenbergh R. Effects of creatine supplementation and exercise training on fitness in men 55-75 yr old. J Appl Physiol. 2003;95:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM. Acute creatine supplementation in older men. Int J Sports Med. 2000;21:71&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1055/s-2000-8859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2000-8859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotshalk LA, Volek JS, Staron RS, Denegar CR, Hagerman FC, Kraemer WJ. Creatine supplementation improves muscular performance in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:537&#x2013;543. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200203000-00023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200203000-00023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermon S, Venembre P, Sachet C, Valour S, Dolisi C. Effects of creatine monohydrate ingestion in sedentary and weight-trained older adults. Acta Physiol Scand. 1998;164:147&#x2013;155. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-201X.1998.00427.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-201X.1998.00427.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9805101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrusch MJ, Chilibeck PD, Chad KE, Davison KS, Burke DG. Creatine supplementation combined with resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:2111&#x2013;2117. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200105001-00090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200105001-00090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brose A, Parise G, Tarnopolsky MA. Creatine supplementation enhances isometric strength and body composition improvements following strength exercise training in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2003;58:11&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12560406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiroth JB, Bermon S, Andrei S, Dalloz E, Hebuterne X, Dolisi C. Effects of oral creatine supplementation on maximal pedalling performance in older adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;84:533&#x2013;539. doi: 10.1007/s004210000370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210000370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11482548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura K, Ashida H, Ishikawa T, Fujii M. Human major psoas muscle and sacrospinalis muscle in relation to age: a study by computed tomography. J Gerontol. 1983;38:678&#x2013;681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6630901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Henriksson-Larsen K, Winblad B, Sjostrom M. Distribution of different fiber types in human skeletal muscles: effects of aging studied in whole muscle cross sections. Muscle Nerve. 1983;6:588&#x2013;595. doi: 10.1002/mus.880060809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.880060809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6646161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyle UG, Genton L, Hans D, Karsegard L, Slosman DO, Pichard C. Age-related differences in fat-free mass, skeletal muscle, body cell mass and fat mass between 18 and 94 years. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2001;55:663&#x2013;672. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1601198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11477465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller P, Bergstrom J, Furst P, Hellstrom K. Effect of aging on energy-rich phosphagens in human skeletal muscles. Clin Sci (Lond) 1980;58:553&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7428286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller P, Brandt R. The effect of physical training in elderly subjects with special reference to energy-rich phosphagens and myoglobin in leg skeletal muscle. Clin Physiol. 1982;2:307&#x2013;314. doi: 10.1111/j.1475-097X.1982.tb00035.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-097X.1982.tb00035.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6751657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien C, Sanchez J. Phosphagens and glycogen content in skeletal muscle after treadmill training in young and old rats. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1984;52:291&#x2013;295. doi: 10.1007/BF01015212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01015212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6539680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coggan AR, Spina RJ, Rogers MA, King DS, Brown M, Nemeth PM, Holloszy JO. Histochemical and enzymatic characteristics of skeletal muscle in master athletes. J Appl Physiol. 1990;68:1896&#x2013;1901. doi: 10.1063/1.346579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.346579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2361892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berneis K, Ninnis R, Haussinger D, Keller U. Effects of hyper- and hypoosmolality on whole body protein and glucose kinetics in humans. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E188&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hespel P, Op't Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, Urso B, Greenhaff PL, Labarque V, Dymarkowski S, Van Hecke P, Richter EA. Oral creatine supplementation facilitates the rehabilitation of disuse atrophy and alters the expression of muscle myogenic factors in humans. J Physiol. 2001;536:625&#x2013;633. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0625c.xd</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingwall JS. Creatine and the control of muscle-specific protein synthesis in cardiac and skeletal muscle. Circ Res. 1976;38:I115&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1269086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young RB, Denome RM. Effect of creatine on contents of myosin heavy chain and myosin-heavy-chain mRNA in steady-state chicken muscle-cell cultures. Biochem J. 1984;218:871&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1153417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6721838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dangott B, Schultz E, Mozdziak PE. Dietary creatine monohydrate supplementation increases satellite cell mitotic activity during compensatory hypertrophy. Int J Sports Med. 2000;21:13&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1055/s-2000-8848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2000-8848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagaard P, Kadi F, Tufekovic G, Verney J, Olesen JL, Suetta C, Kjaer M. Creatine supplementation augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol. 2006;573:525&#x2013;534. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2006.107359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2006.107359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey A, Constantin-Teodosiu D, Howell S, Hultman E, Greenhaff PL. Creatine ingestion favorably affects performance and muscle metabolism during maximal exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1996;271:E31&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8760078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Volek JS. Effects of creatine supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and weightlifting performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:822&#x2013;831. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(2003)017&lt;0822:EOCSAR&gt;2.0.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(2003)017&lt;0822:EOCSAR&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Barton ML Jr, Cyr-Campbell D, Davey SL, Beard JL, Parise G, Evans WJ. Effects of an omnivorous diet compared with a lactoovovegetarian diet on resistance-training-induced changes in body composition and skeletal muscle in older men. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;70:1032&#x2013;1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10584048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Lond) 1992;83:367&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsom PD, Soderlund K, Sjodin B, Ekblom B. Skeletal muscle metabolism during short duration high-intensity exercise: influence of creatine supplementation. Acta Physiol Scand. 1995;154:303&#x2013;310. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1995.tb09914.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1995.tb09914.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7572228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, Staron RS, Putukian M, Gomez AL, Pearson DR, Fink WJ, Kraemer WJ. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:1147&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA. Potential benefits of creatine monohydrate supplementation in the elderly. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2000;3:497&#x2013;502. doi: 10.1097/00075197-200011000-00013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00075197-200011000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11085837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg AM, Nilsson E, Werneman J, Bergstrom J, Hultman E. Muscle composition in relation to age and sex. Clin Sci (Lond) 1991;81:249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1716189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SA, Montain SJ, Matott RP, Zientara GP, Jolesz FA, Fielding RA. Creatine supplementation and age influence muscle metabolism during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85:1349&#x2013;1356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9760327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke DG, Chilibeck PD, Parise G, Candow DG, Mahoney D, Tarnopolsky M. Effect of creatine and weight training on muscle creatine and performance in vegetarians. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:1946&#x2013;1955. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000093614.17517.79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000093614.17517.79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14600563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shomrat A, Weinstein Y, Katz A. Effect of creatine feeding on maximal exercise performance in vegetarians. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2000;82:321&#x2013;325. doi: 10.1007/s004210000222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210000222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derave W, Eijnde BO, Ramaekers M, Hespel P. No effects of lifelong creatine supplementation on sarcopenia in senescence-accelerated mice (SAMP8) Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;289:E272&#x2013;277. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00039.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00039.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15727953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender A, Beckers J, Schneider I, Holter SM, Haack T, Ruthsatz T, Vogt-Weisenhorn DM, Becker L, Genius J, Rujescu D. Creatine improves health and survival of mice. Neurobiol Aging. 2008;29:1404&#x2013;1411. doi: 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2007.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2007.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17416441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangarajan A, Weinberg RA. Opinion: Comparative biology of mouse versus human cells: modelling human cancer in mice. Nat Rev Cancer. 2003;3:952&#x2013;959. doi: 10.1038/nrc1235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrc1235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14737125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobi JM, Rice CL, Curtin SV, Marsh GD. Neuromuscular properties and fatigue in older men following acute creatine supplementation. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;84:321&#x2013;328. doi: 10.1007/s004210000373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210000373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11374116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout J, Graves S, Cramer J, Goldstein E, Costa P, Smith A, Walter A. Effects of creatine supplementation on the onset of neuromuscular fatigue threshold and muscle strength in elderly men and women (64 - 86 years) Journal of Nutrition, Health &amp; Aging. 2007;11:459&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17985060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Little JP, Chilibeck PD, Abeysekara S, Zello GA, Kazachkov M, Cornish SM, Yu PH. Low-Dose Creatine Combined with Protein during Resistance Training in Older Men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(9):1645&#x2013;1652. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318176b310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318176b310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18685526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Bodin K, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on skeletal muscle phosphocreatine resynthesis. Am J Physiol. 1994;266:E725&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8203511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syrotuik DG, Bell GJ. Acute creatine monohydrate supplementation: a descriptive physiological profile of responders vs. nonresponders. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:610&#x2013;617. doi: 10.1519/12392.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/12392.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Armstrong RB, Saubert CWt, Piehl K, Saltin B. Enzyme activity and fiber composition in skeletal muscle of untrained and trained men. J Appl Physiol. 1972;33:312&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4403464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson L, Karlsson J. Isometric and dynamic endurance as a function of age and skeletal muscle characteristics. Acta Physiol Scand. 1978;104:129&#x2013;136. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1978.tb06259.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1978.tb06259.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">152565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Downham D. What is the effect of ageing on type 2 muscle fibres? J Neurol Sci. 1992;107:250&#x2013;251. doi: 10.1016/0022-510X(92)90297-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-510X(92)90297-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1564525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Taylor CC, Sjostrom M. What is the cause of the ageing atrophy? Total number, size and proportion of different fiber types studied in whole vastus lateralis muscle from 15- to 83-year-old men. J Neurol Sci. 1988;84:275&#x2013;294. doi: 10.1016/0022-510X(88)90132-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-510X(88)90132-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3379447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan PL, Boyd SG, Dohm GL. Differential effect of maturation on insulin- vs. contraction-stimulated glucose transport in Zucker rats. Am J Physiol. 1995;268:E1154&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7611391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku CP, Passow H. Creatine and creatinine transport in old and young human red blood cells. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1980;600:212&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1016/0005-2736(80)90426-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0005-2736(80)90426-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7397170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Hultman E, Nordesjo LO. Glycogen, glycolytic intermediates and high-energy phosphates determined in biopsy samples of musculus quadriceps femoris of man at rest. Methods and variance of values. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1974;33:109&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4852173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green AL, Hultman E, Macdonald IA, Sewell DA, Greenhaff PL. Carbohydrate ingestion augments skeletal muscle creatine accumulation during creatine supplementation in humans. Am J Physiol. 1996;271:E821&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8944667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Loon LJ, Oosterlaar AM, Hartgens F, Hesselink MK, Snow RJ, Wagenmakers AJ. Effects of creatine loading and prolonged creatine supplementation on body composition, fuel selection, sprint and endurance performance in humans. Clin Sci (Lond) 2003;104:153&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1042/CS20020159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/CS20020159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12546637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sewell DA, Robinson TM, Greenhaff PL. Creatine supplementation does not affect human skeletal muscle glycogen content in the absence of prior exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104:508&#x2013;512. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00787.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00787.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>