<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27239423</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2190-5991</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cachexia, sarcopenia and muscle</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of creatine supplementation in combination with resistance training on lean mass in the elderly.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>413</StartPage><EndPage>421</EndPage><MedlinePgn>413-21</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcsm.12094</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Human ageing is a process characterized by loss of muscle mass, strength, and bone mass. We aimed to examine the efficacy of low-dose creatine supplementation associated with resistance training on lean mass, strength, and bone mass in the elderly.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a 12-week, parallel-group, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. The individuals were randomly allocated into one of the following groups: placebo plus resistance training (PL&#x2009;+&#x2009;RT) and creatine supplementation plus resistance training (CR&#x2009;+&#x2009;RT) . The participants were assessed at baseline and after 12&#x2009;weeks. The primary outcomes were lean mass and strength, assessed by dual energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) and ten-repetition maximal tests (10&#x2009;RM), respectively. Secondary outcomes included the lumbar spine, right and left femoral neck, both femur and whole body bone mineral density (BMD), and whole body bone mineral content (BMC), assessed by DXA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The CR&#x2009;+&#x2009;RT group had superior gains in lean mass when compared with the PL&#x2009;+&#x2009;RT group (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02). Changes in the 10&#x2009;RM tests in bench press and leg press exercises, body composition, BMD, and BMC of all assessed sites did not significantly differ between the groups (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Twelve weeks of low-dose creatine supplementation associated with resistance training resulted in increases in lean mass in the elderly.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Camila Lemos</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Research in Clinical Nutrition and Sports (Labince) Faculty of Nutrition Federal University of Goi&#xe1;s St 227, block 68, Setor Leste Universit&#xe1;rio Goi&#xe2;nia Goi&#xe1;s 74.605-080 Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Botelho</LastName><ForeName>Patr&#xed;cia Borges</ForeName><Initials>PB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Research in Clinical Nutrition and Sports (Labince) Faculty of Nutrition Federal University of Goi&#xe1;s St 227, block 68, Setor Leste Universit&#xe1;rio Goi&#xe2;nia Goi&#xe1;s 74.605-080 Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carneiro</LastName><ForeName>Juliana Alves</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education Federal University of Goi&#xe1;s Esperan&#xe7;a Avenue, Campus Samambaia Goi&#xe2;nia Goi&#xe1;s 74.690-900 Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mota</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Felipe</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Research in Clinical Nutrition and Sports (Labince) Faculty of Nutrition Federal University of Goi&#xe1;s St 227, block 68, Setor Leste Universit&#xe1;rio Goi&#xe2;nia Goi&#xe1;s 74.605-080 Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101552883</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2190-5991</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ageing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Creatine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27239423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4864174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JCSM12094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Global health and ageing. National Institute on Aging (NIA), National Institutes of Health (NIH), 2011. 32 p. Available from: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Washington.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Brazilian Geography and Statistics Institute Web site [Internet]
. Brazilian Geography and Statistics Institute, 2013.  [cited 2014 Sep 9]. Available from: http://www.ibge.gov.br/home/estatistica/populacao/projecao_da_populacao/2013/default.shtm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo AP, Bertolini SMMG, Junior JM. Morphophysiologial alterations resulted from the process of musculoskeletal system aging and its consequences for the human body. Perspectivas: biol&#xf3;gicas e sa&#xfa;de 2014;4:22&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Cruz&#x2010;Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, Boirie Y, Cederholm T, Landi F, <i>et al</i>
Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: report of the european working group on sarcopenia in older people. Age Ageing
2010;39:412&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss M, Kaddurah&#x2010;Daouk R. Creatine and creatinine metabolism. Physiol Rev 2000;80:1107&#x2013;1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10893433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Artioli GG, Poortmans JR, Lancha Junior AH. Exploring the therapeutic role of creatine supplementation. Amino Acids 2010;38:31&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19253023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Lieberman HR, Walsh TM, Zuber SM, Harhart JM, Matthews TC. Creatine supplementation does not improve cognitive function in young adults. Physiol Behav 2008;95:130&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18579168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Roschel H, Lancha&#x2010;Jr AH, Brightbill CE, Rawson ES. In sickness and in health: the widespread application of creatine supplementation. Amino Acids 2012;43:519&#x2013;529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Sale DG, Webber CE. Exercise and bone mineral density. Sports Med 1995;19:103&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7747001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Wehnert ML, Clarkson PM. Effects of 30&#x2009;days of creatine ingestion in older men. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 1999;80:139&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10408325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM. Acute creatine supplementation in older men. Int J Sports Med 2000;21:71&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotshalk LA, Volek JS, Staron RS, Denegar CR, Hagerman FC, Kraemer WJ. Creatine supplementation improves muscular performance in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2002;34:537&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Stout JR, Sue Graves B, Cramer JT, Goldstein ER, Costa PB, Smith AE, <i>et al</i>
Effects of creatine supplementation on the onset of neuromuscular fatigue threshold and muscle strength in elderly men and women (64&#x2013;86&#x2009;years). J Nutr Health Aging
2007;11:459&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17985060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gotshalk LA, Kraemer WJ, Mendonca MA, Vingren JL, Kenny AM, Spiering BA, <i>et al</i>
Creatine supplementation improves muscular performance in older women. Eur J Appl Physiol
2008;102:223&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17943308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Forbes SC. Creatine supplementation and aging musculoskeletal health. Endocrine 2014;45:354&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24190049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devries MC, Phillips SM. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in older adults&#x2010;a meta&#x2010;analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2014;46:1194&#x2013;1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24576864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri A, Scaglioni G, Pousson M, Capodaglio P, Van Hoecke J, Narici MV. Strength and power changes of the human plantar flexors and knee extensors in response to resistance training in old age. Acta Physiol Scand 2003;177:69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12492780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, McCarthy JP, Bamman MM. Effects of resistance training on older adults. Sports Med 2004;34:329&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD. Potential of creatine supplementation for improving aging bone health. J Nutr Health Aging 2010;14:149&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20126964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiVasta AD, Gordon CM. Exercise and bone: where do we stand? Metabolism 2013;62:1714&#x2013;1717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24140089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, S&#xf6;derlund K, Timmons JA, Cederblad G, Greenhaff PL. Muscle creatine loading in men. J Appl Physiol 1996;81:232&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8828669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green AL, Hultman E, Macdonald IA, Sewell DA, Greenhaff PL. Carbohydrate ingestion augments skeletal muscle creatine accumulation during creatine supplementation in humans. Am J Physiol 1996;271:E821&#x2013;E826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8944667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green AL, Simpson EJ, Littlewood JJ, Macdonald IA, Greenhaff PL. Carbohydrate ingestion augments creatine retention during creatine feeding in humans. Acta Physiol Scand 1996;158:195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8899067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Ciccone V. The effects of pre versus post workout supplementation of creatine monohydrate on body composition and strength. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2013;10:36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23919405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Deschenes M. General principles of exercise prescription In Pescatello LS, Arena R, Riebe D, Thompson PD, eds. ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Baltimore: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2014. p162&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galante AP. Development and validation of a computerized method for assessment of dietary intake, filled by adults using the Web [dissertation]. S&#xe3;o Paulo (SP): University of S&#xe3;o Paulo; 2007. p 1&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Gillis N, Van Leemputte M, Van Hecke P, Vanstapel F, Hespel P. Caffeine counteracts the ergogenic action of muscle creatine loading. J Appl Physiol 1996;80:452&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8929583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti PT, Geraldes AA, Bottaro MF, Lima MV, Albuquerque RB, Fleck SJ. Effects of different resistance training frequencies on the muscle strength and functional performance of active women older than 60&#x2009;years. J Strength Cond Res 2013;27:2225&#x2013;2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23168371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Miguel FM, Grings LA, Pereira GB, Leite RD, Vieira A, Sousa NMF, <i>et al</i>
Different cardiovascular responses to a resistance training session in hypertensive women receiving propanolol compared with normotensive controls. Sci World J
2012; doi: 10.1100/2012/913271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1100/2012/913271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3354718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22645465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman TG, Roche AF, Martorell R. Anthropometric standardization reference manual. Human Kinetics: Champaign (IL); 1988. p177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Baumgartner RN, Koehler KM, Gallagher D, Romero L, Heymsfield SB, Ross RR, <i>et al</i>
Epidemiology of sarcopenia among the elderly in New Mexico. Am J Epidemiol
1998;147:755&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9554417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Lauretani F, Russo CR, Bandinelli S, Bartali B, Cavazzini C, Di Iorio A, <i>et al</i>
Age&#x2010;associated changes in skeletal muscles and their effect on mobility: an operational diagnosis of sarcopenia. J Appl Physiol
2003;95:1851&#x2013;1860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14555665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Guralnik JM, Simonsick EM, Ferrucci L, Glynn RJ, Berkman LF, Blazer DG, <i>et al</i>
A short physical performance battery assessing lower extremity function: association with self&#x2010;reported disability and prediction of mortality and nursing home admission. J Gerontol
1994;49:M85&#x2013;M94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8126356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willett WC, Howe GR, Kushi LH. Adjustment for total energy intake in epidemiologic studies. Am J Clin Nutr 1997;654 Suppl: 1220S&#x2013;1228S discussion 1229S&#x2013;1231S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9094926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrusch MJ, Chilibeck PD, Chad KE, Davison KS, Burke DG. Creatine supplementation combined with resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2001;33:2111&#x2013;2117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Goodpaster BH, Park SW, Harris TB, Kritchevsky SB, Nevitt M, Schwartz AV, <i>et al</i>
The loss of skeletal muscle strength, mass, and quality in older adults: the health, aging and body composition study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci
2006;61:1059&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17077199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Cawthon PM, Fox KM, Gandra SR, Delmonico MJ, Chiou CF, Anthony MS, <i>et al</i>
Do muscle mass, muscle density, strength, and physical function similarly influence risk of hospitalization in older adults?
J Am Geriatr Soc
2009;57:1411&#x2013;1419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3269169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19682143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Delmonico MJ, Harris TB, Visser M, Park SW, Conroy MB, Velasquez&#x2010;Mieyer P, <i>et al</i>
Longitudinal study of muscle strength, quality, and adipose tissue infiltration. Am J Clin Nutr
2009;90:1579&#x2013;1585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermon S, Venembre P, Sachet C, Valour S, Dolisi C. Effects of creatine monohydrate ingestion in sedentary and weight&#x2010;trained older adults. Acta Physiol Scand 1998;164:147&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9805101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Eijnde B, Van Leemputte M, Goris M, <i>et al</i>
Effects of creatine supplementation and exercise training on fitness in men 55&#x2013;75&#x2009;yr old. J Appl Physiol1985 2003;95:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter JM, Bemben DA, Knehans AW, Bemben MG, Witten MS. Does nutritional supplementation influence adaptability of muscle to resistance training in men aged 48 to 72&#x2009;years. J Geriatr Phys Ther 2005;28:40&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16236227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Landeryou T, Kaviani M, Paus&#x2010;Jenssen L. Effects of creatine and resistance training on bone health in postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2015;47:1587&#x2013;1595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Venezia AC. Use of creatine in the elderly and evidence for effects on cognitive function in young and old. Amino Acids 2011;40:1349&#x2013;1362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21394604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, S&#xf6;derlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Colch) 1992;83:367&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM, Price TB, Miles MP. Differential response of muscle phosphocreatine to creatine supplementation in young and old subjects. Acta Physiol Scand 2002;174:57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11851597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson TM, Sewell DA, Hultman E, Greenhaff PL. Role of submaximal exercise in promoting creatine and glycogen accumulation in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol 1999;87:598&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10444618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>