<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25435783</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1303-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sports science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Heavy resistance training and peri-exercise ingestion of a multi-ingredient ergogenic nutritional supplement in males: effects on body composition, muscle performance and markers of muscle protein synthesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>894</StartPage><EndPage>903</EndPage><MedlinePgn>894-903</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>This study determined the effects of heavy resistance training and peri-exercise ergogenic multi-ingredient nutritional supplement ingestion on blood and skeletal markers of muscle protein synthesis (MPS), body composition, and muscle performance. Twenty-four college-age males were randomly assigned to either a multi-ingredient SizeOn Maximum Performance (SIZE) or protein/carbohydrate/creatine (PCC) comparator supplement group in a double-blind fashion. Body composition and muscle performance were assessed, and venous blood samples and muscle biopsies were obtained before and after 6 weeks of resistance training and supplementation. Data were analyzed by 2-way ANOVA (p &#x2264; 0.05). Total body mass, body water, and fat mass were not differentially affected (p &gt; 0.05). However, fat-free mass was significantly increased in both groups in response to resistance training (p = 0.037). Lower-body muscle strength (p = 0.029) and endurance (p = 0.027) were significantly increased with resistance training, but not supplementation (p &gt; 0.05). Serum insulin, IGF-1, GH, and cortisol were not differentially affected (p &gt; 0.05). Muscle creatine content was significantly increased in both groups from supplementation (p = 0.044). Total muscle protein (p = 0.038), MHC 1 (p = 0.041), MHC 2A, (p = 0.029), total IRS- (p = 0.041), and total Akt (p = 0.011) were increased from resistance training, but not supplementation. In response to heavy resistance training when compared to PCC, the peri-exercise ingestion of SIZE did not preferentially improve body composition, muscle performance, and markers indicative of MPS. Key pointsIn response to 42 days of heavy resistance training and either SizeOn Maximum Performance or protein/carbohydrate/creatine supplementation, similar increases in muscle mass and strength in both groups occurred; however, the increases were not different between supplement groups.The supplementation of SizeOn Maximum Performance had no preferential effect on augmenting serum insulin, IGF-1, and GH, or in decreasing cortisol.While resistance training was effective in increasing total creatine content in skeletal muscle, myofibrillar protein, and the content of total IRS-1 and Akt, it was not preferentially due to SizeOn Maximum Performance supplementation.At the daily dose of 50 g, SizeOn Maximum Performance supplementation for 42 days combined with resistance training does not increases muscle mass and strength due to its ability to elevate serum hormones and growth factors or in its ability to augment skeletal muscle signaling pathway markers indicative of muscle protein synthesis when compared to an equivalent daily dose of protein/carbohydrate/creatine.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spillane</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance, and Recreation, Baylor University , Waco, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwarz</LastName><ForeName>Neil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance, and Recreation, Baylor University , Waco, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willoughby</LastName><ForeName>Darryn S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance, and Recreation, Baylor University , Waco, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1303-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Whey protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amino acids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbohydrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">creatine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">men</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25435783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8;rsheim E., Tipton K., Wolf S., Wolfe R. (2002) Essential amino acids and muscle protein recovery from resistance exercise. American Journal of Physiology Endocrinology and Metabolism 283, E648-E657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12217881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford M. (1976) A rapid and sensitive method for the quantification of microgram quantities of protein using the principle of protein dye binding. Analytical Biochemistry 72, 248-254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">942051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen L., Phillips S. (2011) Skeletal muscle protein metabolism in the elderly: Interventions to counteract the &#x2018;anabolic resistance&#x2018; of ageing. Nutrition and Metabolism (London) 8, 68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3201893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21975196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow D., Burke N., Smith-Palmer T., Burke D. (2006). Effect of whey and soy protein supplementation combined with resistance training in young adults. International Journal of Sport Nutrition and Exercise Metabolism 16, 233-244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16948480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke M., La Bounty P., Buford T., Shelmadine B., Redd L., Hudson G., Willoughby D. (2011) Ingestion of 10 grams of whey protein prior to a single bout of resistance exercise does not augment Akt/mTOR pathway signaling compared to carbohydrate. Journal of the International Society of Sport Nutrition 8, 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3231804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22068021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer H., Blanco C., Sattler F., Schroeder E., Wiswell R. (2006) Satellite cell numbers in young and older men 24 hours after eccentric exercise. Muscle and Nerve 33, 242-253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16315322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn-Lewis C., Kraemer W., Kupchak B., Kelly N., Creighton B., Luk H., Ballard K., Comstock B., Szivak T., Hooper D., Denegar C., Volek J. (2011) A multi-nutrient supplement reduced markers of inflammation and improved physical performance in active individuals of middle to older age: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Nutrition Journal 10, 90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3180350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21899733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenech M., Ferguson L. (2001) Vitamins/minerals and genomic stability in humans. Mutation Research 475, 1-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11295148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira M., Li R., Cooke M., Kreider R., Willoughby D. (2014) Peri-exercise co-ingestion of branched-chain amino acids and carbohydrate in men does not preferentially augment resistance exercise-induced increase in PI3K/Akt-mTOR pathway markers indicative of muscle protein synthesis. Nutrition Research 34, 191-198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24655485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fumarola C., La Monica S., Guidotti G. (2005) Amino acid signaling through the mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway: Role of glutamine and of cell shrinkage. Journal of Cell Physiology 204, 155-165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15605414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway S., Talanian J., Shoveller A., Heigenhauser G., Spriet L. (2008) Seven days of oral taurine supplementation does not increase muscle taurine content or alter substrate metabolism during prolonged exercise in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology 105, 643-651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18583380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynn E., Fry C., Timmerman K., Drummond M., Volpi E., Rasmussen B. (2013) Addition of carbohydrate or alanine to an essential amino acid mixture does not enhance human skeletal muscle protein anabolism. Journal of Nutrition 143, 307-314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3713020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23343676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman C., Horvath D., Stathis C., Mori T., Croft K., Murphy R., Hayes A. (2009) Taurine supplementation increases skeletal muscle force production and protects muscle function during and after high-frequency in vitro stimulation. Journal of Applied Physiology 107, 144-154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2711783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19423840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris R., Hultman E., Nordesj&#xf6; L. (1974) Glycogen, glycolytic intermediates and high energy phosphates determined in biopsy samples of musculus femoris of man at rest: Methods and variance values. Scandinavian Journal of Clinical Laboratory Investigation 33, 109-120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4852173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jentjens R., Jeukendrup A. (2003) Determinants of post-exercise glycogen synthesis during short-term recovery. Sports Medicine 33, 117-144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Beelen M., Stellingwerff T., Pennings B., Saris W., Kles A., Kuipers H., Van Loon L. (2007) Coingestion of carbohydrate with protein does not further augment postexercise muscle protein synthesis. American Journal of Physiology Endocrinology and Metabolism 293, E833-842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lina B., Jonker D., Kozianowski G. (2002) Isomaltulose (Palatinose): a review of biological and toxicological studies. Food and Chemical Toxicology 40, 1375-1381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12387299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman T. (1986) Applicability of body composition techniques and constants for children and youths. Exercise and Sports Science Reviews 14, 325-357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3525188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manninen A. (2009) Protein hydrolysates in sports nutrition. Nutrition and Metabolism (London) 28 (6), 38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2761917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19785737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2018;Connor K., Stip E., Pelissier M., Aardema F., Guay S., Gaudette G., Van Haaster I., Robillard S., Grenier S., Careau Y., Doucet P., Leblanc V. (2007) Treating delusional disorder: a comparison of cognitive-behavioral therapy and attention placebo control. Can Journal of Psychiatry 52, 182-190</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17479527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D., Sheffield-Moore M., Katsanos C., Zhang X., Wolfe R. (2006) Differential stimulation of muscle protein synthesis in elderly humans following isocaloric ingestion of amino acids or whey protein. Experimental Gerontology 41, 215-229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16310330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pari L., Satheesh M. (2006) Effect of pterostilbene on hepatic key enzymes of glucose metabolism in streptozotocin- and nicotinamide-induced diabetic rats. Life Science 79, 641-645</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16616938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson E., Volek J. (2003) Effects of creatine supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and weightlifting performance. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 17, 822-831</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts C., Barnard R., Sindhu R., Jurczak M., Ehdaie A., Vaziri N. (2005) A high-fat, refined-carbohydrate diet induces endothelial dysfunction and oxidant/antioxidant imbalance and depresses NOS protein expression. Journal of Applied Physiology 98, 203-210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15333612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakkas G., Schambelan M., Mulligan K. (2009) Can the use of creatine supplementation attenuate muscle loss in cachexia and wasting? Current Opinions in Clinical Nutrition and Metabolic Care 12, 623-625</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2905310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19741514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz S., Hofheins J., Lemieux R. (2010) Nine weeks of supplementation with a multi-nutrient product augments gains in lean mass, strength, and muscular performance in resistance trained men. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition 7, 40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3016253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21162744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selsby J., DiSilvestro R., Devor S. (2004) Mg2+-creatine chelate and a low-dose creatine supplementation regimen improve exercise performance. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 18, 311-315</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelmadine B., Buford T., Hudson G., Redd L., Cooke M., Leutholtz B., Willoughby D. (2009) Effects of 28 days of NO-Shotgun supplementation on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of satellite cell activation, and clinical safety markers in males. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition 6, 16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sola-Penna M., Meyer-Fernandes J. (1998) Stabilization against thermal inactivation promoted by sugars on enzyme structure and function: why is trehalose more effective than other sugars? Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics 360, 10-14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9826423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M., Schoch R., Cooke M., Harvey T., Greenwood M., Kreider R., Willoughby D. (2009) The effects of creatine ethyl ester supplementation combined with heavy resistance training on body composition, muscle performance, and serum and muscle creatine levels. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition 6, 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2649889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M., Willoughby D. (2012) The effects of eight weeks of heavy resistance training and branched-chain amino acid supplementation on muscle performance and body composition. Nutrition and Health 21, 263-273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24620007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staples A., Burn N., West D., Currie K., Atherton P., Moore D., Rennie M., Maddonald M., Baker S., Phillips S. (2011). Carbohydrate does not augment exedrcise-induced protein accretion versus protein alone. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 43, 1154-1161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J., Manolakos J., Kujbida G., Lysecki P., Moore D., Phillips S. (2007) Minimal whey protein with carbohydrate stimualtes muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise in trained young men. Applied Physiology Nutrition and Metabolism 107, 987-992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18059587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D., Stout J., Wilborn C. (2007). Effects of heavy resistance training and timed ingestion of a protein and amino acid supplementation on muscle strength and mass and muscle anabolism. Amino Acids 32, 467-478</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16988909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>