<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="review-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Cureus</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2757</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">cureus</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Cureus</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2168-8184</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Cureus Inc.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12674588</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12674588.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12674588</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12674588</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41346907</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7759/cureus.96017</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Sports Medicine</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Pharmacology</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Nutrition</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The Effect of Oral Pure Branched-Chain Amino Acid Supplementation on Exercise Performance and Body Composition: A Systematic Review</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Muacevic</surname><given-names initials="A">Alexander</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Adler</surname><given-names initials="JR">John R</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Julea</surname><given-names initials="M">Maxim</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-1" ref-type="aff">1</xref><xref rid="aff-2" ref-type="aff">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Saleh</surname><given-names initials="SN">Sohag N</given-names></name><xref rid="aff-1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff-1">
<label>1</label>
Pharmacology, Imperial College London, London, GBR </aff><aff id="aff-2">
<label>2</label>
Critical Care Medicine, Doncaster and Bassetlaw Teaching Hospitals, Doncaster, GBR </aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1">
Maxim Julea <email>maxim.julea1@nhs.net</email>
</corresp></author-notes><pub-date date-type="pub" publication-format="electronic"><day>3</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date date-type="collection" publication-format="electronic"><month>11</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>17</volume><issue>11</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">499895</issue-id><elocation-id>e96017</elocation-id><history><date date-type="accepted"><day>3</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>03</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>04</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-12-05 09:25:13.193"><day>05</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright © 2025, Julea et al.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Julea et al.</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License CC-BY 4.0., which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000096017.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://cureus.com/articles/429019-the-effect-of-oral-pure-branched-chain-amino-acid-supplementation-on-exercise-performance-and-body-composition-a-systematic-review">This article is available from https://cureus.com/articles/429019-the-effect-of-oral-pure-branched-chain-amino-acid-supplementation-on-exercise-performance-and-body-composition-a-systematic-review</self-uri><abstract><p>Branched-chain amino acids (BCAAs) are an increasingly popular sports supplement used by athletes as they are advertised to increase endurance, muscle recovery, lean muscle mass, and decrease muscle soreness and fatigue. However, the mechanisms behind BCAAs are not well-established, and previous studies have had mostly equivocal results; thus, the possible performance-enhancing effect of BCAAs is controversial. The aim of this systematic review was to evaluate the current literature on the effect of pure BCAA supplementation on exercise performance and body composition. Randomized controlled trials with healthy participants &gt;18 years old were included. The intervention was pure combined BCAA supplements, and the comparator was a matched control. Studies with outcomes related to exercise performance and/or body composition were eligible. PubMed, Ovid Medline, Scopus, Web of Science, and Google Scholar were searched until 15/08/2025. We assessed selection, attrition, performance, detection, attrition, reporting and other biases from low to high risk based on the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews. Twenty-two studies were included with 511 participants in total. Eleven studies had trained athletes, whereas 11 articles had untrained participants. Daily doses ranged from 1.5g to 82g. The age varied from 18 to 71.7 years, whereas the study length varied from one day to six months. One study found significant differences in body composition after BCAA supplementation. There were 13 studies with significant findings for various exercise performance outcomes such as endurance, strength, muscle recovery, speed, and fitness. The results moderately support BCAA reducing muscle soreness; however, there is inconsistent evidence to support BCAAs having an ergogenic effect on strength and endurance. Due to unclear/high risk of bias in several studies, no meta-analysis was performed. In conclusion, BCAA supplementation may reduce muscle soreness post-exercise, but evidence for improvements in strength, endurance, and body composition remains inconsistent. However, future studies should consider improving certain limitations such as implementing incremental doses, strict diets, and enrolling more participants with diverse backgrounds.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="author"><kwd>body composition</kwd><kwd>branched-chain amino acid</kwd><kwd>exercise</kwd><kwd>nutrition</kwd><kwd>performance</kwd><kwd>supplements</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro"><title>Introduction and background</title><p>Prevalence of branched-chain amino acid (BCAA) supplements</p><p>Sports supplements are increasing in popularity as more people take them to improve performance [<xref rid="REF1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. One of these supplements is BCAAs, which are advertised as ergogenic aids that increase endurance, muscle recovery, and decrease muscle soreness and fatigue [<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. Moreover, supplement companies claim that BCAAs enhance body composition by increasing/preserving lean muscle mass [<xref rid="REF2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. In a 2017 national survey of about 23028 US college athletes, 13.2% reported taking amino acid supplements for sports performance [<xref rid="REF3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. In 2022, the global BCAA market was valued at approximately USD 1.45 billion and is projected to reach USD 2.6 billion by 2032 [<xref rid="REF4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. Despite the advertising claims, previous studies have shown inconsistent effects of BCAAs on performance and body composition [<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>-<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>].</p><p>BCAA physiology</p><p>BCAAs (leucine, isoleucine, and valine) are part of the essential amino acid (EAA) category, which cannot be synthesized by the human body and hence, need to be sourced from the diet [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. BCAAs are abundant in skeletal muscle as they are the main component of the structural proteins in muscles and play various nutritional and functional roles [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. BCAAs can be used as an energy substrate during exercise [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], function as a signaling factor during protein synthesis [<xref rid="REF10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>,<xref rid="REF12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>], inhibit protein catabolism via the ubiquitin-proteosome pathway [<xref rid="REF13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>], stimulate myotube proliferation [<xref rid="REF12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>] and decrease inflammatory cytokine release and oxidative stress [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,<xref rid="REF14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>] (see Figure <xref rid="FIG1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> for summary). However, there is limited research on some of the effects of BCAAs, such as decreasing fatigue [<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>] or the physiology of reducing muscle soreness [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>].</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><title>Mind map of the main hypothesized physiological effects of BCAAs.</title><p>Created by the author</p><p>BCAA: Branched-chain amino acid</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000096017-i01.jpg"/></fig><p>Exercise-induced muscle damage</p><p>It is well established that eccentric exercise causes muscle damage and pain [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Exercise-induced muscle damage (EIMD) is believed to occur due to degradation of myofibrillar proteins (proteolysis) [<xref rid="REF17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. Furthermore, proteolysis leads to increased myofiber proteins (e.g. creatine kinase and myoglobin) in the blood [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. EIMD symptoms include increased muscle soreness, pain and reduced range of motion and muscle function [<xref rid="REF19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. These symptoms reduce performance and recovery, which may prevent repeated exercise sessions which are needed for adaptations to exercise, such as enhanced exercise tolerance or muscle hypertrophy [<xref rid="REF18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. Seeking a solution for EIMD, adequate nutrition was shown to limit muscle protein breakdown [<xref rid="REF20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Consequently, nutritional interventions such as protein and amino acid supplements have been studied to improve performance by reducing the deleterious effects of exercise [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,<xref rid="REF22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>].</p><p>Muscle soreness</p><p>BCAAs may increase the rate of recovery after exercise by activating the mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1) and the nuclear factor kappa B (NFkB) signaling pathways in muscle cells [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>], lymphocytes [<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>], and macrophages [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>,<xref rid="REF23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]. Consequently, by increasing recovery, BCAAs are hypothesized to reduce the symptoms of delayed-onset muscle soreness (DOMS) that occur after exercise. Moreover, activation of certain neurotrophin pathways (Nerve Growth Factor- NGF and cyclooxygenase enzyme- COX-2) contributes to the development of DOMS [<xref rid="REF24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="REF25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. As BCAAs have been shown to prevent the upregulation of neurotrophin pathways, this is another way BCAAs are believed to aid muscle recovery [<xref rid="REF9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>].</p><p>Muscle synthesis</p><p>Muscle tissues are composed of two protein types, i.e. actin and myosin [<xref rid="REF26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Actin and myosin consist of leucine, isoleucine, and valine [<xref rid="REF26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. Consequently, replenishing BCAAs increases the raw materials available for muscle synthesis. It has been shown that BCAA-enriched supplements (such as whey protein or essential amino acids), given post-exercise, augment muscle synthesis and aid recovery [<xref rid="REF27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,<xref rid="REF28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. BCAA supplements, in tandem with exercise, were shown to help muscle synthesis by stimulating mTOR and p70-S6 kinase, both of which are key regulators in cell growth, transcription, and protein synthesis [<xref rid="REF29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>].</p><p>Energy substrate</p><p>BCAAs are primarily oxidized in skeletal muscle and can contribute as an energy substrate during exercise [<xref rid="REF30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. Isoleucine and valine may increase oxaloacetate levels which may increase free fatty acid oxidation, especially in a glycogen-depleted state [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. Consequently, BCAAs may increase endurance by providing extra energy in glycogen-depleted states e.g. during fasting or prolonged exercise [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>].</p><p>Fatigue</p><p>BCAAs are also hypothesized to decrease fatigue by improving fatigue substances levels in the blood. Previous studies found that fatigue can have peripheral or central causes [<xref rid="REF32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. BCAAs may help reduce peripheral fatigue substances such as lactate and ammonia or central fatigue substances like serotonin (5-HT) [<xref rid="REF33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>]. Brain 5-HT increases during exercise; thus, it is believed to be a cause of central fatigue [<xref rid="REF33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="REF34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Free tryptophan increases uptake of serotonin in the brain [<xref rid="REF34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. As BCAAs compete for the same carrier as tryptophan, increased blood levels of tryptophan are believed to decrease serotonin uptake in the brain and hence reduce central fatigue [<xref rid="REF33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="REF34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Consequently, by reducing fatigue, athletes may be able to perform exercise for longer bouts.</p><p>Body composition</p><p>The mechanism behind how BCAAs may enhance body composition is not clear; however, it is believed to be a mixture of BCAAs stimulating muscle protein synthesis [<xref rid="REF35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>], preventing muscle catabolism [<xref rid="REF36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>], and promoting fat oxidation [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] as an alternative energy substrate. Consequently, these three processes combined are thought to aid athletes increase or preserve lean muscle mass.</p><p>Formulations of BCAAs</p><p>The effects of BCAAs have been studied in different formulations; however, in this paper, we investigated the combined formulation which is their most common mode of administration [<xref rid="REF37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]. Leucine monotherapy has been studied, and findings indicate that leucine alone can stimulate an anabolic effect [<xref rid="REF38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>], whereas there is no evidence for such an effect for isoleucine or valine [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Thus, it may be expected that leucine alone would be more effective than the combined form of all BCAAs. However, supplementation with leucine alone has its limitations. Firstly, leucine administered alone would limit the extent of muscle protein synthesis due to the lack of availability of other essential amino acids [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. Secondly, leucine administration stimulates the oxidation of all other amino acids; thus, it may lead to depletion of isoleucine and valine. Consequently, it is believed that co-administration of leucine with isoleucine and valine is the most effective formulation [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. On the other side, it has been proposed that the combined form of BCAAs, although preferred, could limit leucine effects due to competition between amino acids for transport into muscle fibres [<xref rid="REF37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]. Moreover, supplements with BCAA alone may not be as effective at controlling muscle protein turnover compared to supplements with more essential amino acids [<xref rid="REF8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,<xref rid="REF37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>].</p><p>Some independent studies have studied oral BCAA supplementation in humans and found BCAAs to stimulate muscle protein synthesis, reduce muscle protein breakdown, EIMD and fatigue with doses ranging from 77mg/kg to 3g/kg [<xref rid="REF37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]. The most used BCAA ratio is 2:1:1 leucine, isoleucine, and valine, respectively, as BCAA supplementation is safest if in proportions close to mammal body protein [<xref rid="REF30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>].</p><p>Aims and hypotheses</p><p>Supplements with BCAAs commonly contain other ingredients such as caffeine, creatine, carbohydrates, or vitamins [<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="REF15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="REF39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>]. Some of these ingredients are proven ergogenic aids [<xref rid="REF40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,<xref rid="REF41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. Thus they may have acted as confounders in previous studies investigating the effect of BCAAs on exercise performance. In addition, some of the effects in humans that are advertised by producers are hypothesized from cellular and animal models [<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Also, previous studies done with humans have mostly equivocal findings [<xref rid="REF5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>-<xref rid="REF7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. Thus, the aim of this systematic review was to investigate the effects of pure combined BCAA supplementation on exercise performance and body composition by synthesizing and updating the current randomized controlled trial evidence. Both acute and chronic supplementation protocols were considered, and the review evaluates outcomes across multiple performance domains, including endurance, strength, and muscle recovery.</p><p>Based on the previous literature, our null hypothesis was that BCAA supplementation would have no effect on performance or body composition. Contrastingly, our alternative hypothesis was that BCAA supplementation would increase exercise performance and fat-free muscle mass.</p></sec><sec sec-type="review"><title>Review</title><p>Methods</p><p>This systematic review followed the guidelines of the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) [<xref rid="REF42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>].</p><p>Literature Search</p><p>A search for articles investigating the effect of BCAA supplementation on exercise performance and body composition was performed using the following international databases: PubMed, Ovid Medline, Scopus, and Web of Science. Google Scholar was used as a supplementary search engine. The search was carried out for all time until 15/08/2025. The search was limited to studies in English and Portuguese as these were the languages accessible to the reviewer and included all studies identified as relevant during preliminary screening. The single study published in Portuguese was translated into English using Google Translate and manually checked for accuracy and terminology consistency by the primary reviewer. Furthermore, the following search strategy was used ("branched-chain amino acid*" OR "bcaa") AND ("exercise" OR "exercise tolerance" OR "sport*" OR "endurance" OR "resistance" OR "train*" OR "athlet*" OR "stamina" OR "performance" or "fatigue" or "fitness" or "muscle damage" or "muscle soreness"). Google Scholar was searched using a refined version of the same core search strategy, and the first 210 records were screened, consistent with prior systematic review practice recognizing the limited relevance of later-ranked results. The detailed search strategies for all databases are provided in the Appendices (see Table <xref rid="TAB4" ref-type="table">4</xref>).</p><p>Inclusion and Exclusion Criteria</p><p>The studies were selected based on Population, Intervention, Comparator, Outcomes and Study design (PICOS system). To observe the physiological effect of BCAAs, the population was composed of healthy individuals &gt;18 years old without chronic diseases. A minimum of five participants per study arm was required. This threshold was selected to ensure adequate data for between-group comparison and to exclude very small case-series and aligns with current concerns regarding underpowered trials in sports and exercise science [<xref rid="REF43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>,<xref rid="REF44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. Moreover, the intervention was defined as a combined BCAA supplement (only leucine, isoleucine, and valine). In addition, studies had to include at least one group with a pure BCAA to observe isolated effects; thus, any studies with extra ingredients were excluded. The comparator was a matched control. The outcomes included were any measure of exercise performance and body composition. The study design was restricted to randomized controlled trials. Furthermore, any dissertations, theses, partially published articles, or articles with only abstracts were excluded.</p><p>Data Collection and Analysis</p><p>All records identified through database searches were imported into Covidence (Veritas Health Innovation, Melbourne, Australia) for screening. Duplicates were removed automatically within the platform and verified manually to ensure accuracy. Titles and abstracts were then screened to remove irrelevant studies, reviews, animal experiments, and non-randomized designs. Full texts of potentially eligible articles were retrieved and assessed against predefined inclusion and exclusion criteria. Any studies not meeting these criteria were excluded, and reasons for exclusion were documented (see Figure <xref rid="FIG2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG2" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><title>PRISMA flowchart indicating the distinct levels of screening, reasons for excluding articles and numbers of included/excluded articles at each stage</title><p>PRISMA: Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000096017-i02.jpg"/></fig><p>Risk of Bias</p><p>Studies were assessed in RevMan 5 for selection bias, performance bias, detection bias, attrition bias, reporting bias and other biases (e.g. sponsors, uncontrolled variables) based on the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews [<xref rid="REF43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>]. Studies were classified as unclear risk (if there was insufficient information to quantify risk), high risk (factors that could strongly influence objectivity of findings) or low risk (all reasonable information and controlled variables are clearly presented and accounted for). The Cochrane Handbook [<xref rid="REF43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>] suggests that meta-analyses should not be performed when there is risk of bias in all/some studies; thus, as all RCTs included had instances of unclear/high risk, we chose not to perform a meta-analysis to avoid misleading results.</p><p>Results</p><p>Studies</p><p>After the initial database search, 1973 articles were identified. Following removal of duplicates, 976 articles were screened by title and abstract. Of these, 909 articles were excluded as irrelevant, reviews, animal studies, or non-randomized trials; 67 full text articles were then assessed for eligibility, of which 45 were excluded for not meeting the inclusion criteria (e.g. mixed supplements, wrong population, or non-English/Portuguese text). Consequently, 22 studies met all inclusion criteria and were included in the final analysis (Figure <xref rid="FIG2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>). The search covered all years up to 15 August 2025, and the publication years of included articles ranged from 2004 to 2025. Study durations varied from one day to six months. Of the 22 included studies, 21 were published in English and one in Portuguese.</p><p>Participants</p><p>The included studies were randomized controlled trials. A total of 511 people participated in these studies. The number of participants varied from 5 to 100 with a sample mean of 23.2 +/-19.2 participants. The ages varied from 18 to 71.7 years. Eighteen studies were done only on men, one was done only on women, and three included both women and men. Eleven studies included untrained participants (sedentary or healthy/active), whereas 11 included trained participants (athletes or “resistance-trained”) (see Table <xref rid="TAB1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Randomized controlled trials included (n=22) with details of study design, age and numbers of participants, exercise protocol, diet, investigated outcomes and study length</title><p>RCT: randomized controlled trial; CK: creatine kinase; LDH: lactate dehydrogenase; PMS: perceived muscle soreness; RM: maximum repetitions; MVC: maximal voluntary contraction; HR: heart rate; RPE: rating of perceived exertion; 1RM: maximum weight displaced for one repetition; CRP: C-reactive protein; CMJ: countermovement jump</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Author and Year</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Type of Study and Sample Size</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">  Age Range</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gender</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Type of Exercise</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Investigated Outcomes</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Length and Follow-Up</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aminiaghdam (2012) [<xref rid="REF45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind RCT with soccer players (n=30)    </td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.2±0.7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CK, LDH, PMS</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Nine days</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Areces (2014) [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind, RCT with experienced runners (n=46)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">41.4±7.4</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male &amp; Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise (running)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vertical jump, handgrip, lower limb strength and power, running speed, PMS, urine myoglobin, urine pH, urine protein</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Seven days</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Asjodi (2018) [<xref rid="REF47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">RCT with untrained participants (n=50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">22.2±2.3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CK, LDH, RM, PMS</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">72h</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bagheri (2021) [<xref rid="REF48" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind, RCT with postmenopausal women (n=30)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">56±3.7</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Female</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Body composition, strength, myokines and IGF-1</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Eight weeks</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dorrell (2016) [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Single-blind, counterbalanced RCT with resistance-trained participants (n=5)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.8±0.8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mixture of Plyometric, Aerobic and resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Countermovement (CMJ) and squat jump (SJ), peak (PP) and mean (MP) power, Medicine Ball Throw distance, PMS</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">One day</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fouré (2016) [<xref rid="REF50" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind, RCT with young healthy participants (n=26)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">22.5±1.6</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Neuromuscular stimulation</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CK, phosphocreatine (PCr), inorganic phosphate (Pi), MVC, power, PMS, alanine, citrulline, tyrosine, phenylalanine, glycine, histidine, leucine, isoleucine, valine</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Eleven days</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gee (2016) [<xref rid="REF51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Single-blind counterbalanced RCT with resistance-trained participants (n=11)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.7±5.9</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PMS, countermovement jump, seated shot-put throw</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">One day</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Greer (2011) [<xref rid="REF52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind, cross-over RCT with sedentary participants (n=9)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21.6±3.2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise (Cycling)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Total distance performed, perceived exertion, respiratory exchange ratio</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">One day, with eight weeks between supplementation protocols</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gualano (2011) [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind cross-over RCT with healthy participants (n=7)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24±2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise(running)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Time to exhaustion, respiratory exchange ratio (RER), plasma glucose, free fatty acids (FFA), blood ketones and lactate</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Three days</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Howatson (2012) [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind RCT with rugby and football competitors (n=12)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">23±2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Plyometric exercise (drop jumps)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CK, PMS, MVC, vertical jump and thigh and calf circumference.  </td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Twelve days</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Luan (2025) [<xref rid="REF54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind RCT with young healthy active college students (n=11)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">21±1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise (cycling)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Logged dietary intake- same plan was replicated for all trials</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fat/CHO oxidation, cycling efficiency, fatigue (VAS), RPE, HR, insulin, blood ammonia, time to exhaustion</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Three days</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Manaf (2021) [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind counterbalanced crossover RCT with recreationally active participants (n=18)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.7±4.8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise (cycling)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Controlled dietary intake- same plan was replicated for all trials</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rating of perceived exertion, power, cadence, HR, MVC, muscle voluntary activation level and electrically evoked torque using single and doublet stimulations</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">One day</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Martín-Martínez (2020) [<xref rid="REF56" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind RCT with professional volleyball players (n=12)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">24.6±3.8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Plyometric exercise (vertical jumps)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Countermovement vertical jump</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Seven days</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Meng (2025) [<xref rid="REF57" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind crossover RCT with untrained males (n=24)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">23.1±2.2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training and plyometric exercise (vertical jumps)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet (logged calories and protein for 3 days before trial)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">VAS (soreness), CMJ, IL-6, CRP, CK, blood lactate (30 min, 24h, 48h post)</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">One day (doses 1x Pre &amp; 1x Post) with seven-day washout and crossover</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mor (2022) [<xref rid="REF58" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Single-blind RCT with football players (n=24)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.5±2.3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Running anaerobic speed test, ball speed measurement, blood lactate, HR, power</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Seven days</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Muscella (2024) [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind RCT with resistance-trained candidates (n=100)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">35.9±10.0</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male &amp; Female (50/50)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet-logged food intake</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Body composition (lean/fat/muscle), 1RM (squat, bench, deadlift), DOMS (VAS), fatigue (ROF scale)</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Six months</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Robbins (2025) [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pilot double-blind RCT with older adults (n=20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.5±1.2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male and female (63% F/37%M)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Supervised aerobic + resistance training, 3x/week</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Diet monitored and adjusted based on Healthy Eating index</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Handgrip strength, chair stands, gait speed, VO2 max, 400m walk; CES-D, FAS, ISI, VAS (QoL, fatigue, pain)</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Eight weeks</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Shenoy (2017) [<xref rid="REF61" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Stratified double-blind RCT with road cyclists (n=20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20±1.2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Plyometric exercise (drop jumps)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CK, High sensitivity C- reactive protein (hs-crp), and myeloperoxidase (MPO), isometric knee muscle strength, PMS, aerobic capacity (VO2max), HR</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">28 days</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Smith (2018) [<xref rid="REF62" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind RCT with resistance-trained participants (n=13)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">23±3.8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintain usual diet</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cortisol, glucose, insulin, resistance exercise performance</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Seven days with blood tests 60 min after exercise</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> </td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Uchida (2008) [<xref rid="REF63" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind, cross-over RCT with healthy participants from the Brazilian Army (n=17)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">22±2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise (running)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Controlled diet with 16%  protein</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lactate, ammonia, total distance performed, perceived exertion, time to exhaustion</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">One day, with seven days between supplementation protocols</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">VanDusseldorp (2018) [<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>]        </td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind, RCT with active resistance trained participants (n=20)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">22.3±1.5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Resistance training</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Controlled diet with protein 1.2 g/kg body weight</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">CK, vertical jump, MVC, jump squat peak power, PMS</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">Eight days</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Watson (2004) [<xref rid="REF65" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Double-blind RCT with recreationally active males (n=8)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">28.5±8.2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Male</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aerobic exercise (cycling in warm environment i.e. 30°C &amp; 38% humidity</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Standardized diet and activity for 48h pre-test</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Time to exhaustion, HR, rectal/skin temp, RPE, thermal comfort, blood glucose &amp; lactate, expired air parameters</td><td colspan="2" rowspan="1">One day testing (one week washout and crossover)</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Type of Exercise</p><p>Types of exercise included resistance exercise (seven studies) and aerobic exercise (eight studies), plyometric exercise (three studies), mixture/multiple (three studies) and neuromuscular stimulation (one study) (see Table <xref rid="TAB1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><p>Supplementation</p><p>The BCAA doses included either fixed doses or individual doses (calculated per body mass) (Table <xref rid="TAB2" ref-type="table">2</xref>). Overall, the daily dose varied from 1.5 to 82g. The control was either a carbohydrate or an artificial sweetener. Length and time of administration varied from a single dose to multiple doses per day for up to six months. All included trials administered pure BCAA supplements without additional amino acids, carbohydrates, or other ergogenic additives.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><title>Supplementation protocol of included randomized controlled trials (n=22)</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">  Author/Year</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Composition Leu/Iso/Val</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">  Total Daily Amount (g)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Individual Dose (mg/kg of Body Weight)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Supplementation Length</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">  Matched Control</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Supplementation Details</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Aminiaghdam (2012) [<xref rid="REF45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">~15.1g base o r ~44.8g or ~81.9g on exercise days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">68 mg/kg +200mg/kg or 450 mg/kg 30 min before or after exercise</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dextrin</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3X/day with extra 200 mg/kg or 450 mg/kg before and after exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Areces (2014) [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dextrose: Cellulose</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Once daily</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Asjodi (2018) [<xref rid="REF47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">~1.5g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 mg/kg</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maltodextrin(30mg/kg)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split 30 min before and immediately after exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bagheri (2021) [<xref rid="REF48" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3X/week for 8 weeks</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Guar gum</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split 30 min before and immediately after exercise</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dorrell (2016) [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">12g or 36g (daily)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Artificial sweetener</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6g or 18 g 20 min before and after exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Fouré (2016) [<xref rid="REF50" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">~7g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">100mg/kg</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cellulose</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 doses on Day 1, then 1 dose/day for Days 2-5</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gee (2016) [<xref rid="REF51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Artificial sweetener</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split before and after exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Greer (2011) [<xref rid="REF52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">48.6g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Artificial sweetener</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split before and after exercise</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gualano (2011) [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">300mg/kg/day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maltodextrin</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1X/ day before exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Howatson (2012) [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">12 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Artificial sweetener</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split 10g with an additional 20g before and after exercise</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Luan (2024) [<xref rid="REF54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.2 g/kg body weight/each time</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 days(pre-ex) + 1 dose on exercise day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Isocaloric starch</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day for three days and then once in the morning of exercise day</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Manaf (2021) [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">9.4g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.084 mg/kg before + 0.056 mg/kg*h during exercise</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Non-caloric cordial</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Martín-Martínez (2020) [<xref rid="REF56" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">--</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 days during a week</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Watermelon flavored drink</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7g/ day Monday, Wednesday, and Friday</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Meng (2025) [<xref rid="REF57" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">40mg/kg</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day (2 doses)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maltodextrin</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1X Supplement 30 min pre- exercise 1x supplement immediately post-exercise 7-day washout then crossover</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mor (2022) [<xref rid="REF58" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bran</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split 30 min before and 1h after exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Muscella (2024) [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7-10g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 mg/kg body weight</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 months</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Undefined placebo</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Daily – on exercise days, immediately after exercise, non -exercise to consume in morning, supplement contained lecithin</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Robbins (2025) [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 mg/kg/day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 weeks</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maltodextrin</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Acute intervention- one dose pre-ex on first day- then measured; long-term intervention- eight weeks daily supplementation followed by re-measurement</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Shenoy (2017) [<xref rid="REF61" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">20g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">28 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Artificial sweetener</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split 10g</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Smith (2018) [<xref rid="REF62" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.5g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Artificially flavored water</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Six doses split before warm-up, after warm-up and after exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Uchida (2008) [<xref rid="REF63" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4:3:3</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">77mg/kg</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maltodextrin</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split 45 min before and 20 min before</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">VanDusseldorp (2018) [<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3:1:2</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">220mg/kg/day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 days</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maltodextrin</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2X/ day split one in the morning and one in the evening</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Watson (2004) [<xref rid="REF65" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>]</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2:1:1</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">12g base+ 5.4-18g</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">-</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 day</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sugar-free fruit drink</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">12g during 2h before exercise then varying increments during exercise (until failure). Increments based on exercise length. Seven-day washout, then crossover</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Risk of Bias</p><p>Fifteen studies were classified as unclear bias risk due to giving insufficient information on randomization (Figure <xref rid="FIG3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). Sixteen studies did not offer information on allocation concealment. One study was single-blinded (labelled “high risk” as only participants were blinded), and two studies offered limited information on their double-blinded protocol (labelled “unclear risk”). Two did not blind their outcome assessors (high risk), whereas four other studies had unclear risk for detection bias due to insufficient information. One study omitted certain data (high risk of attrition bias), whereas one study gave no participant numbers or information on excluded data (unclear risk). A preliminary study protocol was not available for 15 studies; thus, they were classified as unclear risk of reporting bias. Two studies were labelled as high risk of other bias due to being funded by the supplement producer or failure to control protein intake.</p><fig position="anchor" fig-type="figure" id="FIG3" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><title>Multiple panels indicating our risk of bias assessment for the included studies (n=22) based on the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Green indicates low risk of bias, yellow indicates unclear risk, and red indicates high risk. Panel A shows an overall percentage of risk of bias per bias type. Panel B presents assessment of risk of bias for individual studies. Low risk was the most common level.</title></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="cureus-0017-00000096017-i03.jpg"/></fig><p>Main Findings</p><p>There was substantial heterogeneity amongst the studies regarding the parameters used to measure body composition, and performance (see Table <xref rid="TAB3" ref-type="table">3</xref>). The most common formulation of BCAAs was 2:1:1.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="TAB3" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><title>Summary of significant effects of different doses of BCAAs on body composition and exercise performance</title><p>* sign marks studies with statistically significant results between BCAA and placebo groups (p&lt;0.05)</p><p>BCAA: Branched-chain amino acid</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td colspan="3" rowspan="1">    Outcome</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of Studies with Significant Studies</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">    Main Findings</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" rowspan="5">                    Body Composition</td><td rowspan="5" colspan="1">  1/5 (20%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Areces et al. [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>] (n=46): (5g BCAA) body mass was reduced in both groups with no significant difference (BCAA: -3.0 ± 1.1 and PLAC: - 2.5 ± 1.1 %, P = 0.13)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bagheri et al. [<xref rid="REF48" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>] (n=30): (9g BCAA) body mass, body mass index (BMI), and muscle mass significantly increased in both groups. Body fat percentage significantly decreased in both groups (PLA: -2.7%; BCAA: -3.1%, p&lt;0.05). No significant difference between groups.</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Muscella et al. [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>] (n=100)*: 7-10g. BCAA significantly increased muscle mass and fat-free mass in both sexes after six months</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Robbins et al. [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>] (n=20): BMI and body weight were not significantly different from placebo after eight weeks of 5g BCAA supplementation</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>] (n=12): (20 g BCAA) no significant difference in the calf or thigh circumference between the BCAA and placebo</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="29" colspan="1">  Exercise Performance</td><td rowspan="10" colspan="1">Endurance</td><td rowspan="5" colspan="1">Perceived exertion</td><td rowspan="5" colspan="1"> 5/9 (55.5%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Greer et al. [<xref rid="REF52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>] (n=9)*: 48.6g/day BCAA group had significantly lower rates of perceived exertion at 75(-11%), and 90 minutes (-16%) after cycling than the placebo trial (p&lt;0.05).</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Luan et al. [<xref rid="REF54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>](n=11)*: 0.2g/kg bodyweight BCAA significantly reduced perceived exertion with lower VAS values in the BCAA cohort</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>](n=18)*:  approx. 9.4g BCAA/day significantly reduced perceived exertion levels (-3.5%,) in the BCAA group compared to the placebo group, after a cycling time trial</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Muscella et al. [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>](n=100)*: 7-10g BCAA significantly reduced fatigue after exercise (women experienced greater reduction in fatigue)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Robbins et al. [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>](n=20)*: 5g BCAA significantly decreased fatigue score (measured with VAS) after 8 weeks of BCAA supplementation</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">Maximum repetitions</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">2/3 (66%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Asjodi et al. [<xref rid="REF47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>] (n=50)*: Approx. 1.5 g BCAA significantly increased maximum repetitions at 72h post-exercise than any other group</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Robbins et al. [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>](n=20)*: 5g BCAA significantly increased number of chair stand repetitions after eight weeks of BCAA supplementation</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Time to exhaustion</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">¼ (25%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gualano et al. [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>](n=7)*: 300mg/kg BCAA supplementation promoted a greater time to exhaustion (+17.2%) when compared to placebo.</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cycled distance</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">0/1 (0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Greer et al. [<xref rid="REF52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>] (n=9): No significant difference between BCAA and placebo (BCAA: 4.4 ± 0.5km vs PLAC: 3.9 ±0.4 km, p&gt;0.05)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cycling efficiency</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">1/1 (100%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Luan et al. [<xref rid="REF54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>] (n=11)*: 0.2g/kg bodyweight BCAA significantly increased cycling efficiency in BCAA cohort (measured blood respiratory gases)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="10" colspan="1">Strength</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">Contraction force and torque</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1"> 2/7 (29%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>] (n=12)*: 20g BCAA led to a significantly lower decrement in force and greater recovery of force, compared to placebo. 24h after exercise, the peak decrement in force from pre-exercise maximal voluntary contraction was -18% in the BCAA vs -27% in the placebo(p=0.01). (Compared to pre-exercise force)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vandusseldorp et al. [<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>] (n=20)*: Force output(N/m) was significantly reduced after resistance training at all post-exercise time points (0-72h) for placebo, whereas for the BCAA group, the force output was only significantly decreased 0-4hr, becoming non-significant at 24h and onwards.</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="5" colspan="1">  Power</td><td rowspan="5" colspan="1"> 5/8 (57%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dorrell et al. [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>] (n=5)*: Mean power and peak power decreased in both groups after resistance training; however, BCAA supplementation with 6g or 18g decreased the peak power decrement significantly compared to placebo (BCAA 6g: 1107 ± 27 W vs. BCAA 18g: 1133 ± 46 W vs. PLAC: 1044 ± 69 W respectively, p&lt;0.05)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] (n=18)*: 9.4g BCAA supplementation yielded significantly higher mean power output (+4.6%) after cycling, compared to placebo (BCAA: 130.2 W± 4.5; PLAC: 124.5 ± 4.5, p&lt;0.001)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mor et al. [<xref rid="REF58" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>] (n=24)*:  5g BCAA significantly increased average power after aerobic exercise whereas in the placebo group, power decreased non-significantly. (Average power in BCAA group was 6.5% higher than PLAC group)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Muscella et al. [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>] (n=100)*: 7-10g BCAA significantly increased 1-repetition max power (men experienced greater increase in 1-RM)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Robbins et al. [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>] (n=20)*: 5g BCAA significantly increased handgrip strength (kg)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">Vertical Jump performance</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1"> 2/6 (33%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dorrell et al. [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>] (n=5)*: Countermovement jumps, and squat jump distances were reduced after resistance training in all groups; however, BCAA supplementation significantly decreased the performance decrement. Moreover, the decrement in performance was significantly lower with 18g compared to 6g BCAA. CMJ (BCAA 6g:57.7 ± 8.0 cm vs. BCAA 18g: 59.1 ± 7.9 cm vs. CON: 56.6 ± 7.9 cm respectively) and SJ (BCAA 6g: 52.8 ± 9.9 cm vs. BCAA 18g: 54.0 ± 9.9 cm vs. CON: 51.7 ± 10.7 cm respectively)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gee et al. [<xref rid="REF51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>] (n=11)*:  20 g BCAA significantly decreased the jump height decrement (BCAA: 52.8± 5.9 cm; PLAC: 50.6± 7.3 cm, p=0.031)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Medicine Ball throw distance</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> ½ (50%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gee et al. [<xref rid="REF51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>] (n=11)*: The distance the ball was thrown decreased after resistance training in all groups. 20g BCAA supplementation significantly decreased the decrements in distance thrown compared to placebo (4.37± 0.61 m vs 4.22 ± 0.64 m, p=0.044).</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="3" colspan="1">Measures of speed</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1">Time to completion</td><td rowspan="2" colspan="1"> 2/2 (100%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] (n=18)*: The group supplemented with 9.4g BCAA took significantly less time (-6.7%) to complete a running time trial compared to placebo.</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Robbins et al. [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>] (n=20)*: 5g BCAA significantly decreased time to complete 400m walk</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Running pace</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> 0/1 (0%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Areces et al. [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>] (n=46): No significant difference between groups (3.3 ± 0.4 vs. 3.3 ± 0.5 m s<sup>-1</sup>, respectively, 0.98)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="5" colspan="1">Muscle recovery</td><td rowspan="5" colspan="1">Perceived muscle soreness</td><td rowspan="5" colspan="1"> 5/11 (45%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dorrell et al. [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>] (n=5)*: 6g and 18g BCAA significantly reduced muscle soreness (-9% and 18%, respectively) compared to placebo. Significant difference between 6g and 18g (p=0.025)</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>] (n=12)*: 20g BCAA significantly reduced muscle soreness 24h and 48h after plyometric exercise, compared to placebo (at 24h: -33%, at 48h: -23%)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Meng et al. [<xref rid="REF57" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>](n=24)*: 40mg/kg BCAA significantly reduced DOMS after exercise at 24h and 48h post-exercise</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Muscella et al. [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>](n=100)*: 7-10g BCAA significantly reduced DOMS after exercise (women experienced greater reduction in DOMS)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Vandusseldorp et al. [<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>] (n=20)*: approx. 19g BCAA led to significantly lower levels of muscle soreness 48h (-35%) and 72h (-64%) after resistance training, compared to placebo(maltodextrin).</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Measures of  fitness</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Heart rate</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"> 1/4 (25%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] (n=18)*: Average HR found to be significantly elevated (+1.5%) in the BCAA supplemented group, compared to placebo</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Body Composition</p><p>Five studies [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>,<xref rid="REF48" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>,<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>,<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>,<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>] investigated the effect of BCAA supplementation on body composition by measuring body mass, BMI, fat-free mass, muscle mass or limb circumference. Only one study had statistically significant results. Muscella et al. [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>] found that 100mg/kg bodyweight BCAA supplementation significantly increased muscle mass (BCAA: 2.2±1.3 kg, PLA: -0.6±2.3 kg, p&lt;0.001), and fat-free body mass (BCAA: 1.1±1.2 kg, PLA: -0.5±2.3 kg, p&lt;0.001).</p><p>Performance</p><p>Parameters that could be broadly categorized as ‘endurance’ included perceived exertion, maximum repetitions, time to exhaustion, cycling distance, and cycling efficiency. Seven out of 10 studies found that BCAA usage significantly improved endurance measures. For example, Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] found a significant reduction in the perceived exertion after a cycling trial (BCAA: 13.6±0.4 points, PLA: 14.1±0.4 points, p&lt;0.05), whilst Gualano et al. [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] showed that BCAA supplementation significantly increased the time to exhaustion.</p><p>Parameters that measured strength included contraction force &amp; torque, power, vertical jump performance, and medicine ball throw distance. Only eight of the 16 studies showed significant improvements in measures of strength. These include the study by Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>], which found a significantly reduced decrement in contraction force after plyometric exercise (BCAA: -18% PLAC: -27%, p=0.01), and that by Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>], which showed a significantly increased power output during cycling (BCAA: 130.2 W± 4.5; PLAC: 124.5 ± 4.5, p&lt;0.001).</p><p>Measures of speed included time to completion, and running pace. Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] found a significant improvement in the time to completion (BCAA: 66 min, PLAC:71 min, p=0.04). Robbins et al. [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>] found significantly reduced time to walk 400 m with BCAA supplementation (BCAA: -14%; PLAC: +13%, p&lt;0.001). Areces et al. [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>] did not find a significant improvement in running pace.</p><p>Certain studies also looked at the impact of BCAAs on recovery, measured by investigating perceived muscle soreness. Five out of 11 studies found a significant reduction in muscle soreness between the BCAA group and the placebo group.</p><p>Finally, heart rate was used as a measure of fitness in four studies, with Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] finding a significant increase in heart rate compared to placebo (BCAA: 151.2±3 BPM, PLA: 148.9±3 BPM, p ≤ 0.001).</p><p>Discussion</p><p>This systematic review aimed to assess the effect of BCAA supplementation on body composition, and exercise performance. We found limited evidence of a significant BCAA effect on body composition i.e. one study out of five. For performance, we found some studies with significant results with BCAA supplementation (13/22 studies); however, they were inconsistent. Overall, our findings in this review support the hypothesis that BCAA supplementation has an ergogenic effect on recovery outcomes (with moderate certainty evidence). However, there is inconsistent and context-dependent evidence to support the hypothesis that BCAAs have an ergogenic effect on body composition, strength, and endurance performance.</p><p>Body Composition</p><p>We hypothesized that BCAA supplementation would increase lean muscle mass; however, our findings mostly do not support this hypothesis. The mechanism behind the possible effect of BCAA on body composition is not clear, but BCAAs are thought to increase lean muscle mass by stimulating muscle protein synthesis [<xref rid="REF35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>], inhibiting muscle catabolism [<xref rid="REF36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>], and stimulating lipid oxidation [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. Consequently, as free fatty acid oxidation is increased, especially in glycogen-deprived states or fasted states, lean muscle mass is spared, leading to a net increase in lean muscle mass.</p><p>Muscella et al. found that 100mg/kg significantly increased muscle mass and fat-free mass after six months of supplementation [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]. The significant results could be due to having a longer supplementation period, and a larger sample size (n=100) compared to other studies with non-significant results [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>,<xref rid="REF48" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>,<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>,<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>]. Men had a more pronounced increase in muscle mass gained, whereas women had a more pronounced increase in fat-free mass. The more pronounced difference in males could be due to higher baseline muscle mass, and testosterone levels, which increase the anabolic effect of BCAA. Women show a lower impact from BCAA supplementation on muscle mass, most likely due to hormonal differences and lower baseline muscle mass. This indicates there are sex-specific responses to BCAA supplementation. They suggest that women benefit more from fat oxidation properties and nutrient timing (before and after exercise) of BCAA supplementation, leading to increased lean mass, and aiding weight maintenance rather than weight loss. However, the strength of their conclusions is reduced by the modest sample size (despite being the largest in this review), incomplete lifestyle control, and limited follow-up.</p><p>Areces et al. found a decrease in body mass for both groups with no significant difference [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>]. The decrease could be attributed to water loss due to the short follow-up period. Hence, the results may have been more accurate if the follow-up period had been longer. Furthermore, Bagheri et al. found an increase in muscle mass and a decrease in fat with no difference between groups [<xref rid="REF48" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>]. Similarly, Howatson et al. found no difference in limb circumference after BCAA supplementation [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]. Our findings agree with previous literature. Spillane et al. failed to find an ergogenic effect of eight-week BCAA supplementation (9g/day) on muscle mass after resistance exercise [<xref rid="REF35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. Similarly, Antonio et al. found 18g of EAA (including 9g of BCAA) to have no significant effect on body composition after six weeks of resistance training [<xref rid="REF66" ref-type="bibr">66</xref>]. However, these studies [<xref rid="REF35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,<xref rid="REF66" ref-type="bibr">66</xref>] were not randomized controlled trials. Hence, selection bias may have confounded the results, which is why they were not included in this review.</p><p>Contrastingly, there are certain studies that disagree with our findings. Dudgeon et al. found BCAA supplementation (26g/day) to preserve lean muscle mass in a 12-week trial carried out with young men on a calorie-restricted “cut” diet [<xref rid="REF36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]. The favorable BCAA effect could be attributed to a longer duration of supplementation and/or a higher dose of BCAAs. Hence, this could indicate that larger BCAA doses may be needed to reach a certain threshold where BCAAs would have a significant effect. However, Dudgeon et al. [<xref rid="REF36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>] used a supplement that contained other ingredients such as L-Citrulline, which was shown by Hwang et al. [<xref rid="REF67" ref-type="bibr">67</xref>] to increase lean mass; hence, it was not included in our review. Moreover, the lack of change in lean muscle mass raises the question about whether the effect can truly be attributed to the BCAA supplement or just poor adherence to the diet.</p><p>Moreover, Ikeda et al. investigated the effect of 3.4g BCAA on postmenopausal women, combined with rehabilitative exercise after total hip arthroplasty, and found that the participants had increased upper limb muscle mass [<xref rid="REF68" ref-type="bibr">68</xref>]. However, the positive effect could be due to age, sex or untrained people having a greater potential for muscle increase [<xref rid="REF69" ref-type="bibr">69</xref>]. The study by Ikeda et al. was not included as it did not have solely healthy participants [<xref rid="REF68" ref-type="bibr">68</xref>]. However their significant findings indicate that further research into the effects of BCAAs in post-surgical recovery patients is warranted.</p><p>Given the current literature, the evidence for BCAAs improving lean muscle mass is equivocal, especially compared to more complete protein supplements such as whey protein which have been proven to enhance muscle protein synthesis even in calorie-restricted diets [<xref rid="REF70" ref-type="bibr">70</xref>]. There appear to be some significant results with longer term supplementation in resistance-trained people with sex-specific differences.</p><p>Exercise Performance</p><p>Thirteen studies had significant findings for exercise performance outcomes. Some findings support the hypothesis that BCAAs have an ergogenic effect on exercise performance, such as increasing endurance, strength, muscle recovery, and speed. However, despite showing positive findings, the mechanism of action is not well established, which contributes to the controversy between studies with significant and non-significant findings.</p><p>Endurance</p><p>Seven studies found a significant BCAA effect on endurance; however, the evidence is low, and likely context-dependent (environment, glycogen status, exercise modality). Several mechanisms are proposed for how BCAAs may increase endurance. When performing long-term exercise, glycogen stores are depleted, and transamination enzymes in muscles increase their activity to use BCAAs for energy [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,<xref rid="REF71" ref-type="bibr">71</xref>]. Consequently, it is thought, with BCAA supplementation, there is a higher availability of BCAAs to be used as an energy resource in glycogen-deprived states.</p><p>Another theory is based on the effect BCAAs may have on lipid oxidation. Gualano et al. [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] stipulate that the tricarboxylic acid cycle is regulated by the condensation of sufficient amounts of oxaloacetate, and citrate. As glycogen concentrations cannot support the oxaloacetate demands during severe fasting or exhaustive exercise, free fatty acid oxidation is limited by the availability of carbohydrates. Hence, they hypothesized that an increased BCAA availability would lead to increased lipid oxidation which could increase performance. Supporting their hypothesis, Gualano et al. [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] found a significantly reduced respiratory exchange ratio (RER), and better performance in the BCAA group which conveyed increased lipid oxidation. They also suggest the decreased RER indicates a glycogen-sparring effect of BCAA supplementation which could further improve endurance by increasing energy substrate availability [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. Gualano et al. [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] also suggest that exercise capacity may be improved by BCAA supplementation by reducing the fatiguing effects of hypoglycemia. They found BCAAs to prevent exercise-induced hypoglycemia, especially in glycogen-deprived individuals.</p><p>Moreover, endurance may be enhanced by BCAAs decreasing central fatigue. Exercise is associated with increased serotonin in the brain, and elevated central fatigue [<xref rid="REF33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>,<xref rid="REF34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Previous literature indicates that the concentration of serotonin is proportional to the rate of tryptophan passing through the blood-brain barrier, and BCAAs compete for the same carrier protein that tryptophan uses to reach the blood-brain barrier [<xref rid="REF72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>,<xref rid="REF73" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>]. Consequently, an increased plasma level of BCAA may decrease the amount of tryptophan passing the blood-brain barrier, and, thus, serotonin production [<xref rid="REF72" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>,<xref rid="REF73" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>]. However, there have been discrepancies between studies investigating the effect of BCAAs on central fatigue. Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] suggest that the discrepancy exists due to inter-individual differences such as different rates in TRP transport or sensitivity to serotoninergic activity.</p><p>Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] found perceived exertion to be significantly reduced in the BCAA group. They hypothesize that BCAAs may decrease mental fatigue or alter perceived effort without affecting neuromuscular factors associated with fatigue development. They claim the BCAA effect may be clearer in participants with lower training levels, thus suggesting that the possible ergogenic effects of BCAA may be limited to this group of athletes [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>].</p><p>Greer et al. [<xref rid="REF52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>] suggest that the mechanisms underlying the central fatigue hypothesis take one hour to manifest as they found a significantly lower perceived exertion rate for the BCAA group, 75 and 90 minutes after commencing exercise. This is further supported by Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>], who indicate that BCAA supplementation has shown more favorable effects in “slower” marathon runners, possibly due to longer exercise periods.</p><p>Luan et al. have found supplementation with 0.2g/kg bodyweight BCAA to reduce perceived exertion [<xref rid="REF54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>]. One mechanism they propose is that BCAAs prevent blood ammonia levels from increasing. Hence, as ammonia causes central fatigue when crossing the blood-brain barrier, BCAAs would alleviate central fatigue. However, the lack of muscle biopsies and short-term nature of their study limit the generalizability of their results.</p><p>Muscella et al. found that 100mg/kg BCAA (7-10g for their participants) significantly reduced fatigue levels post-exercise, the effect being more prominent in women [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]. They suggest that women have an enhanced effect, possibly due to hormonal influences on amino acid metabolism, by experiencing increased protein oxidation during the luteal phase of the menstrual cycle and estrogen affecting how BCAAs are utilized during exercise to decrease perceived exertion.</p><p>Robbins et al. also found that 5g BCAA reduced perceived exertion in older adults [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>]. Like other studies [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>,<xref rid="REF65" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>], they suggest that BCAA reduce fatigue levels through the central serotonin synthesis pathway but also by modulating the kynurenine pathway and reducing neurotoxic metabolites associated with fatigue. However, their results are limited by participant sex imbalances and the absence of biomarker assessment.</p><p>Both Areces et al. [<xref rid="REF46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>] and Uchida et al. [<xref rid="REF63" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>] found no significant difference in endurance between BCAAs and placebo. The non-significant effect may be attributed to the lower BCAA doses used (Areces et al.: 5g and Uchida et al: approx. 5.34g) compared to studies with significant effects, which used higher doses (e.g. Manaf et al: 9.4g and Greer et al.: 48.6g). However, this should be considered with caution as Asjodi et al. [<xref rid="REF47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>] found significantly increased endurance with lower BCAA doses (approx. 1.5g), yet their participants were untrained which may have amplified the effect. Consequently, future studies should be carried out with higher doses of BCAAs to investigate the dose-response of BCAAs on endurance.</p><p>BCAAs are not the sole supplement that are advertised as performance-enhancing; Creatine is another popular pre-workout ergogenic aid used by athletes for various performance gains such as enhanced power, strength, endurance, and muscle recovery [<xref rid="REF74" ref-type="bibr">74</xref>]. Creatine was studied extensively, and it was found that it works by increasing available ATP in muscles [<xref rid="REF74" ref-type="bibr">74</xref>]. Even though there is limited comparative analysis between BCAAs and creatine, the evidence supporting creatine’s ergogenic effects is less equivocal and more consistent than that for BCAAs [<xref rid="REF74" ref-type="bibr">74</xref>]. Mor et al. found both BCAA and creatine to improve anaerobic capacity and endurance [<xref rid="REF58" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>]. However, despite creatine’s proven ergogenic effects, current literature suggests that the efficacy of creatine supplementation is more limited for endurance sports [<xref rid="REF74" ref-type="bibr">74</xref>]. Wax et al. found that the ergogenic potential of creatine is diminished as exercise duration increases [<xref rid="REF74" ref-type="bibr">74</xref>]. Hence, BCAA supplementation may have more pronounced effects during prolonged physical activity, for example, based on Greer et al. [<xref rid="REF52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>] trial, longer than one hour. This indicates that further research should be carried out to study BCAA and creatine supplementation in parallel and possibly, even combined, to assess their effects on endurance.</p><p>Strength</p><p>Eight studies found significant results for strength outcomes, however with low to moderate evidence that BCAAs improve strength recovery with little support for acute strength enhancement. The mechanism for how BCAA supplementation may increase strength is not well understood. It is believed to be a combination of BCAAs stimulating myofibrillar protein synthesis via mTORC1 and p706S kinase [<xref rid="REF29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>] and inhibiting muscle catabolism [<xref rid="REF36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>], thus accelerating recovery. Consequently, with a more rapid recovery, performance may be regained more quickly, which may allow faster strength development.</p><p>Muscella et al. reported that daily BCAA supplementation (7-10 g) over six months significantly improved one-repetition maximum power, with a more pronounced effect observed in male participants [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]. Despite having lower doses than other studies, their significant results could be attributed to having the longest trial period in this review i.e. six months. The difference between sexes could be attributed to menstrual cycle-related hormonal differences, as women experience higher protein catabolism during the luteal phase. This means protein requirements for women fluctuate with the menstrual cycle, which may affect strength gains if protein intake is not adjusted when the requirement increases. However, their conclusions are limited to the 20 to 48-year age group.</p><p>Robbins et al. found that 5g BCAAs significantly increased handgrip strength in older participants (60-80 years) [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>]. The lower BCAA dose and shorter period of supplementation may have a significant effect (compared to studies with non-significant findings and higher doses) due to the participants being untrained which has been found to be associated with a greater BCAA effect. However, their conclusions are limited by the sample size, type of exercise and age group.</p><p>Dorrell et al. found that both 12g and 36g alleviate the decrement in muscle performance after resistance training, in a dose-dependent manner [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]. Their results were similar to those of Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>] which were more prominent. However, the difference in results could be attributed to different factors. Dorrell et al. [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>] employed a resistance training design that would emulate real-life exercise, whereas Howatson et al. used a high-intensity resistance training program to maximize muscle damage markers [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]. As da Luz et al. [<xref rid="REF75" ref-type="bibr">75</xref>] have shown that perceivable effects of prophylactic supplementation, such as BCAAs, are more evident under conditions of greater muscle damage, a more prominent effect was expected in the study by Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]. Moreover, the more evident effect could be attributed to a higher total dose of BCAAs employed in Howatson et al.(260g) compared to that of Dorrell et al. (12g or 36g). The lower BCAA dose could also explain why Foure et al. [<xref rid="REF50" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>] did not find a significant difference in strength outcomes. Greer et al. suggest that future studies should also measure blood BCAA levels to find the exact plasma levels at which effects are significant [<xref rid="REF52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>].</p><p>Like Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>] and Dorrell et al. [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>], Vandusseldorp et al. [<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>] also found BCAA supplementation (approx.19g) to significantly reduce the decrement in muscle strength after exercise. However, it could be argued that their maximal voluntary isometric contraction regimen is not representative of all types of athletic performance movements, and their results may be limited to isometric contractions. Hence, future research should consider exploring the effects of BCAAs on different types of performance movements.</p><p>Moreover, like in other similar studies [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>,<xref rid="REF63" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>], Vandusseldorp et al. [<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>] did not control the participants’ diet completely; hence, the true effect may be confounded by variations in protein intake between participants. Moreover, even though Vandusseldorp et al. controlled the protein intake (1.2g/kg BW/day) and applied an amount lower than the recommended value for resistance training males [<xref rid="REF76" ref-type="bibr">76</xref>], it could be argued that the dietary protein may have been enough to produce favorable performance outcomes, hence BCAAs may have had a negligible effect.</p><p>Another reason why there are inconsistencies in findings could be the level of training the participants possess. Cadore et al. suggest that untrained individuals have a greater anabolic response than well-trained participants [<xref rid="REF77" ref-type="bibr">77</xref>], which may indicate that the effects of BCAA supplementation may be less evident in well-trained subjects.</p><p>Caffeine is another common ingredient in pre-workout supplements that is advertised and proven to increase performance [<xref rid="REF41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. The mechanisms behind caffeine’s ergogenic effects are still to be elucidated but it is believed to be a combination of recruiting more motor units and reducing fatigue via adenosine inhibition [<xref rid="REF78" ref-type="bibr">78</xref>]. Like creatine, the evidence for caffeine’s ergogenic effects is stronger than that for BCAAs [<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="REF41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. However, future research should consider a comparative analysis to assess their effects in parallel. Furthermore, one limitation of caffeine is habituation, as its ergogenic aid has been indicated to decrease with long-term use [<xref rid="REF41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. Consequently, BCAAs should also be assessed for long-term habituation. </p><p>Although BCAAs show some effect in stimulating muscle synthesis, current literature indicates that more complete proteins, including all EAA, offer a higher/maximal muscle protein synthesis response [<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Marcon et al. argue that athletes who perform regular exercise and have specific protein requirements can achieve the same dietary needs with a balanced diet [<xref rid="REF6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Future studies could compare the effect of BCAAs and that of more complete protein supplements in the context of different exercise modalities.</p><p>Speed and Fitness</p><p>Manaf et al. [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>] and Robbins et al. [<xref rid="REF60" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>] had significant findings for speed and fitness. They found a significantly lower completion time for the BCAA group which could be attributed to lower RPE and increased power. Moreover, Manaf et al. found a significantly higher heart rate for the BCAA group which could show that the BCAA group exercised at a harder intensity compared to the control group, possibly due to lower perceived exertion [<xref rid="REF55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>]. However, this is unlike previous studies which found no difference [<xref rid="REF65" ref-type="bibr">65</xref>] or lower HR [<xref rid="REF79" ref-type="bibr">79</xref>]. Thus, future research should be performed to assess the effect on HR.</p><p>Muscle Recovery</p><p>Five studies found significantly lower muscle soreness with BCAA supplementation after exercise [<xref rid="REF49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>,<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>,<xref rid="REF57" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>,<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>,<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>]. However, four have not enforced a strict diet that was 100% monitored, hence variability in protein intake or calories may have confounded the results. These studies have found that BCAA supplementation significantly reduced muscle soreness 24 to 96 hours post-exercise and not immediately after. The level of evidence is moderate, showing more consistent findings, particularly after eccentric/resistance exercise.</p><p>The mechanism for aiding muscle recovery may be related to reducing factors that contribute to peripheral fatigue. Vandusseldorp et al. suggest that the increased muscle recovery may be related to BCAA degradation producing glutamine [<xref rid="REF64" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>]. Research indicates that intense exercise causes increased inflammation. The increased inflammatory response was discovered to increase the sensitivity of muscle nociceptors which is correlated with the elevated feeling of soreness [<xref rid="REF80" ref-type="bibr">80</xref>]. After consumption, some BCAAs may be transaminated to produce glutamate, later converted into glutamine [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Glutamine can be taken up by immune cells as a substrate to decrease the inflammatory response [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Nicastro et al. suggest that BCAA supplementation decreases muscle inflammation by increasing the bioavailability of amino acids, especially glutamine, for immune cells [<xref rid="REF11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. However, this theory should be tested by further studies. Furthermore, BCAAs are be hypothesized to be involved in muscle sarcolemma membrane preservation/repair, yet more research is needed.</p><p>Both Gee et al. [<xref rid="REF51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>] and Shenoy et al. [<xref rid="REF61" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>] supplemented participants with 20g BCAAs yet failed to find a significant difference in muscle soreness. However, the soreness scores were lower in the BCAA group. As both studies used trained participants, the results did not reach significance, possibly because the BCAA effect is limited in more trained individuals.</p><p>Another factor that may impact the BCAA effect is muscle mass. Shimomura et al. gave 5g BCAA to both women and men and found a significant ergogenic effect on muscle soreness, observing a greater effect in women than men [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. They explain that women had a lower muscle mass and thus possibly needed less BCAA to produce a significant effect [<xref rid="REF21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. However, this study should be considered with caution as they employed a crossover design, which is limited by the repeated bout effect. Muscella et al. suggest that men may exhibit a more pronounced reduction in muscle damage markers, lactate, and ammonia (which are associated with fatigue and muscle soreness) due to higher muscle mass and more efficient BCAA absorption compared to women [<xref rid="REF59" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>].</p><p>Timing may also be a key factor in BCAA effect on muscle soreness. Howatson et al. [<xref rid="REF53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>] claim that early feeding may increase BCAA efficacy because BCAA blood levels peak 30 minutes after ingestion. Contrastingly, Ra et al. argue that pre-workout supplementation is more efficient as it may limit muscle catabolism during exercise [<xref rid="REF16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. Consequently, future studies should investigate different timings.</p><p>Future Study Improvements</p><p>The inconsistency in findings in the current literature can be due to different study design limitations. Many studies utilize BCAA supplements that include other proven ergogenic supplements such as caffeine or carbohydrates that confound the results; hence, future research should aim for standardised pure BCAA formulations. Moreover, the accuracy may be enhanced if less subjective measures of muscle soreness or exertion are used. Also, in the future, aiming for multicenter RCTs, increasing the sample sizes and using more participants of different ages, sex (especially more women), and ethnicities would further improve the study design. Moreover, training outcomes should be monitored for longer periods. Incremental doses combined with blood BCAA levels may more accurately indicate the threshold for BCAA ergogenic aid. Furthermore, increased exercise length may indicate the true effect on central fatigue. Moreover, future studies should employ strict diets and minimize the repeated-bout effect by separating exercise periods appropriately. The impact of different timings, lengths, and participant training levels should also be investigated. Furthermore, more studies should specifically investigate the effect of BCAA supplementation during different stages of the menstrual cycles. Closely monitoring hormones, blood markers of metabolism and muscle damage may also allow better objective correlation with BCAA doses.</p><p>Limitations of Our Review</p><p>Our review may be limited by the exclusion/inclusion criteria employed, and screening method, as these may have influenced the studies included (publication bias) and conclusions drawn. This could be improved by using several reviewers to establish criteria, independently screen the articles, and cross-reference all data in the end. The reach could also be increased by adding studies in more languages. Moreover, due to the high heterogeneity between studies, we could not objectively assess our hypothesis and significance of our findings through statistical tests; thus, our study is limited by a Type 2 error. This could be improved by increasing the number of studies with similar outcomes. One other limitation is including industry funded research which may sway the results, hence in the future these could be excluded. Although only studies using pure BCAA formulations were included, one study [<xref rid="REF31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] did not specify the precise composition or ratio, limiting interpretability. Future research should ensure transparent reporting of BCAA composition and ratios to allow better comparison between trials and improve reproducibility.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>Conclusions</title><p>In this review of 22 RCTs, we show that, according to current literature, there is consistent evidence to moderately support the hypothesis that pure BCAA supplementation decreases muscle soreness and improves recovery following eccentric or resistance exercise. Until more robust evidence emerges, BCAA supplementation should be considered primarily for recovery rather than performance enhancement. We suggest further research into the mechanisms behind BCAAs while using more participants with diverse backgrounds, employing incremental doses, and a strict diet.</p></sec></body><back><ack><p>The author would like to acknowledge that this review was initiated while studying as a medical student at Imperial College London and completed while working at Doncaster and Bassetlaw Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust. The author also wishes to thank Dr. Sohag Saleh for supervision and valuable feedback during the preparation of this manuscript.</p></ack><fn-group content-type="conflict"><title>Disclosures</title><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Conflicts of interest:</bold> In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following:</p><p><bold>Payment/services info:</bold> All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Financial relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work.</p><p><bold>Other relationships:</bold> All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</p></fn></fn-group><fn-group content-type="other"><title>Author Contributions</title><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Concept and design:</bold>  Maxim Julea, Sohag N. Saleh</p><p><bold>Acquisition, analysis, or interpretation of data:</bold>  Maxim Julea</p><p><bold>Drafting of the manuscript:</bold>  Maxim Julea, Sohag N. Saleh</p><p><bold>Critical review of the manuscript for important intellectual content:</bold>  Maxim Julea, Sohag N. Saleh</p><p><bold>Supervision:</bold>  Sohag N. Saleh</p></fn></fn-group><app-group><app><title>Appendices</title><table-wrap position="anchor" id="TAB4" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><title>Complete search strategies for all databases and search engines (search date: August 15, 2025)</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Database/ Search Engine</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Tailored Search Terms</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Filters Applied</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Date Searched</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">PubMed</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">(("branched-chain amino acid*"[Title/Abstract] OR bcaa[Title/Abstract]) AND (exercise[Title/Abstract] OR "exercise tolerance"[Title/Abstract] OR sport*[Title/Abstract] OR endurance[Title/Abstract] OR resistance[Title/Abstract] OR train*[Title/Abstract] OR athlet*[Title/Abstract] OR stamina[Title/Abstract] OR performance[Title/Abstract] OR fatigue[Title/Abstract] OR fitness[Title/Abstract] OR "muscle damage"[Title/Abstract] OR "muscle soreness"[Title/Abstract])) AND (randomized controlled trial[pt] OR randomized[Title/Abstract] OR randomised[Title/Abstract])</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">English, Portuguese, Human, Adult (≥18 years)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">15/08/2025</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ovid Medline</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">((branched-chain amino acid* or bcaa) and (exercise or "exercise tolerance" or sport* or endurance or resistance or train* or athlet* or stamina or performance or fatigue or fitness or "muscle damage" or "muscle soreness")).ti,ab. and (random*.ti,ab. or randomized controlled trial.pt.)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">English, Portuguese, Human, Adult (≥18 years)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">15/08/2025</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Scopus</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">TITLE-ABS-KEY ( ( "branched-chain amino acid*" OR bcaa ) AND ( exercise OR "exercise tolerance" OR sport* OR endurance OR resistance OR train* OR athlet* OR stamina OR performance OR fatigue OR fitness OR "muscle damage" OR "muscle soreness" ) ) AND TITLE-ABS-KEY ( random* )</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">English, Portuguese, Human, Adult (≥18 years)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">15/08/2025</td></tr><tr style="background-color:#ccc"><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Web of Science</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">TS=(("branched-chain amino acid*" OR bcaa) AND (exercise OR "exercise tolerance" OR sport* OR endurance OR resistance OR train* OR athlet* OR stamina OR performance OR fatigue OR fitness OR "muscle damage" OR "muscle soreness")) AND TS=(random*)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">English, Portuguese, Human, Adult (≥18 years)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">15/08/2025</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Google Scholar</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">("branched-chain amino acid*" OR bcaa) AND ("exercise performance" OR "exercise tolerance" OR "muscle damage" OR "muscle soreness" OR endurance OR fatigue OR strength) AND ("randomized controlled trial" OR rct OR "randomised controlled trial") AND ("healthy adults" OR "young adults" OR "recreationally active")</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">English, Portuguese; first 210 results screened manually</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">15/08/2025</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></app></app-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="REF1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Prevalence, knowledge and attitudes towards using sports supplements among young athletes</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jovanov</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Đorđić</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Obradović</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Barak</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pezo</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Marić</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sakač</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>27</fpage><volume>16</volume><year>2019</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31272457</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12970-019-0294-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6611041</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>BCAA benefits: a review of branched-chain amino acids</article-title><date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
<month>5</month>
<year>2022</year>
</date-in-citation><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Petre A: BCAA</surname><given-names>Benefits</given-names></name>
</person-group><year>2021</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/bcaa">https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/bcaa</uri></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>NCAA national study on substance use habits of college student-athletes</article-title><date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
<month>5</month>
<year>2022</year>
</date-in-citation><year>2018</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://ncaaorg.s3.amazonaws.com/research/substance/2018RES_SubstanceUseFinalReport.pdf.">https://ncaaorg.s3.amazonaws.com/research/substance/2018RES_SubstanceUseFinalReport.pdf.</uri></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Global Market Insights. Branched-Chain Amino Acids (BCAAs) Market Size - By Type (L-Leucine, L-Isoleucine, and L-Valine), Application (Sports Nutrition, Food and Beverage, Animal Feed, Pharmaceuticals, Cosmetics and Personal Care), Form &amp; Global Forecast, 2023-2032</article-title><date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
<month>11</month>
<year>2025</year>
</date-in-citation><fpage>2022</fpage><lpage>2028</lpage><volume>36</volume><year>2023</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.gminsights.com/industry-analysis/branched-chain-amino-acids-market">https://www.gminsights.com/industry-analysis/branched-chain-amino-acids-market</uri></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>Dietary supplements for exercise and athletic performance</article-title><date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
<month>5</month>
<year>2022</year>
</date-in-citation><year>2021</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://ods.od.nih.gov/factsheets/ExerciseAndAthleticPerformance-HealthProfessional/.">https://ods.od.nih.gov/factsheets/ExerciseAndAthleticPerformance-HealthProfessional/.</uri></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The effect of branched-chain amino acids supplementation in physical exercise: a systematic review of human randomized controlled trials</article-title><source>Sci Sports</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Marcon</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zanella</surname><given-names>PB</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>393</fpage><lpage>404</lpage><volume>37</volume><year>2022</year></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The effect of branched-chain amino acid on muscle damage markers and performance following strenuous exercise: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Appl Physiol Nutr Metab</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Doma</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Boullosa</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Connor</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>1303</fpage><lpage>1313</lpage><volume>46</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34612716</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1139/apnm-2021-0110</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acids and muscle protein synthesis in humans: myth or reality?</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wolfe</surname><given-names>RR</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>30</fpage><volume>14</volume><year>2017</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28852372</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12970-017-0184-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5568273</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The use of BCAA to decrease delayed-onset muscle soreness after a single bout of exercise: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Amino Acids</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Weber</surname><given-names>MG</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dias</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>de Angelis</surname><given-names>TR</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>1663</fpage><lpage>1678</lpage><volume>53</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34669012</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00726-021-03089-2</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Regulation of skeletal muscle function by amino acids</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kamei</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hatazawa</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Uchitomi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yoshimura</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
</person-group><volume>12</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu12010261</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7019684</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31963899</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF11"><label>11</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Does branched-chain amino acids supplementation modulate skeletal muscle remodeling through inflammation modulation? Possible mechanisms of action</article-title><source>J Nutr Metab</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nicastro</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>da Luz</surname><given-names>CR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chaves</surname><given-names>DF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bechara</surname><given-names>LR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Voltarelli</surname><given-names>VA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rogero</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lancha AH</surname><given-names>Jr</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>136937</fpage><volume>2012</volume><year>2012</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22536489</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1155/2012/136937</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3321450</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF12"><label>12</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of branched-chain amino acid ratio on the proliferation, differentiation, and expression levels of key regulators involved in protein metabolism of myocytes</article-title><source>Nutrition</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Duan</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>8</fpage><lpage>16</lpage><volume>36</volume><year>2017</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28336113</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.nut.2016.10.016</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF13"><label>13</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acids administration suppresses endurance exercise-related activation of ubiquitin proteasome signaling in trained human skeletal muscle</article-title><source>J Physiol Sci</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lysenko</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Vepkhvadze</surname><given-names>TF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lednev</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Vinogradova</surname><given-names>OL</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Popov</surname><given-names>DV</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>43</fpage><lpage>53</lpage><volume>68</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27913948</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s12576-016-0506-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10717082</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF14"><label>14</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Amino acid supplementation and impact on immune function in the context of exercise</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cruzat</surname><given-names>VF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krause</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Newsholme</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>61</fpage><volume>11</volume><year>2014</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25530736</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12970-014-0061-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4272512</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF15"><label>15</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of a commercially available branched-chain amino acid-alanine-carbohydrate-based sports supplement on perceived exertion and performance in high intensity endurance cycling tests</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gervasi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sisti</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Amatori</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>6</fpage><volume>17</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31959202</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12970-020-0337-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6971972</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF16"><label>16</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of BCAA supplement timing on exercise-induced muscle soreness and damage: a pilot placebo-controlled double-blind study</article-title><source>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ra</surname><given-names>SG</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Miyazaki</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kojima</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>1582</fpage><lpage>1591</lpage><volume>58</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28944645</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.23736/S0022-4707.17.07638-1</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF17"><label>17</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Insights into the molecular etiology of exercise-induced inflammation: opportunities for optimizing performance</article-title><source>J Inflamm Res</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fatouros</surname><given-names>IG</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jamurtas</surname><given-names>AZ</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>175</fpage><lpage>186</lpage><volume>9</volume><year>2016</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27799809</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/JIR.S114635</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5085309</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF18"><label>18</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acid ingestion can ameliorate soreness from eccentric exercise</article-title><source>Med Sci Sports Exerc</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jackman</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Witard</surname><given-names>OC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jeukendrup</surname><given-names>AE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tipton</surname><given-names>KD</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>962</fpage><lpage>970</lpage><volume>42</volume><year>2010</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19997002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181c1b798</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF19"><label>19</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Nutritional and supplementation strategies to prevent and attenuate exercise-induced muscle damage: a brief review</article-title><source>Sports Med Open</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Harty</surname><given-names>PS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cottet</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Malloy</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kerksick</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>1</fpage><volume>5</volume><year>2019</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30617517</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s40798-018-0176-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6323061</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF20"><label>20</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Nutritional support for exercise-induced injuries</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tipton</surname><given-names>KD</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>104</lpage><volume>45 Suppl 1</volume><year>2015</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-015-0398-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4672013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26553492</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF21"><label>21</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Nutraceutical effects of branched-chain amino acids on skeletal muscle</article-title><source>J Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shimomura</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bajotto</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>529</fpage><lpage>532</lpage><volume>136</volume><year>2006</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/jn/136.2.529S</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16424141</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF22"><label>22</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of protein supplements on muscle damage, soreness and recovery of muscle function and physical performance: a systematic review</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pasiakos</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lieberman</surname><given-names>HR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>McLellan</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>655</fpage><lpage>670</lpage><volume>44</volume><year>2014</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24435468</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-013-0137-7</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF23"><label>23</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Slc3a2 mediates branched-chain amino-acid-dependent maintenance of regulatory T cells</article-title><source>Cell Rep</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ikeda</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kinoshita</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kayama</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>1824</fpage><lpage>1838</lpage><volume>21</volume><year>2017</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29141216</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.celrep.2017.10.082</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF24"><label>24</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Acute and chronic administration of the branched-chain amino acids decreases nerve growth factor in rat hippocampus</article-title><source>Mol Neurobiol</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Scaini</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mello-Santos</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Furlanetto</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>581</fpage><lpage>589</lpage><volume>48</volume><year>2013</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23559405</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s12035-013-8447-1</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF25"><label>25</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Anti-inflammatory and anti-genotoxic activity of branched chain amino acids (BCAA) in lipopolysaccharide (LPS) stimulated RAW 264.7 macrophages</article-title><source>Food Sci Biotechnol</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>1371</fpage><lpage>1377</lpage><volume>26</volume><year>2017</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30263672</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s10068-017-0165-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6049802</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF26"><label>26</label><element-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>A review of the importance of amino acids in sports performance</article-title><date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
<month>5</month>
<year>2022</year>
</date-in-citation><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zaman</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
</person-group><year>2016</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://aminomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Aminomics-and-Sports-Performance.pdf">https://aminomics.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Aminomics-and-Sports-Performance.pdf</uri></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF27"><label>27</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Leucine-enriched essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion following resistance exercise enhances mTOR signaling and protein synthesis in human muscle</article-title><source>Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dreyer</surname><given-names>HC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Drummond</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pennings</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>400</lpage><volume>294</volume><year>2008</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/ajpendo.00582.2007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2706121</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18056791</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF28"><label>28</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men</article-title><source>J Appl Physiol (1985)</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Moore</surname><given-names>DR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kujbida</surname><given-names>GW</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tarnopolsky</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>987</fpage><lpage>992</lpage><volume>107</volume><year>2009</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19589961</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF29"><label>29</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acids activate key enzymes in protein synthesis after physical exercise</article-title><source>J Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Blomstrand</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Eliasson</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Karlsson</surname><given-names>HK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Köhnke</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>269</fpage><lpage>273</lpage><volume>136</volume><year>2006</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/jn/136.1.269S</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16365096</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF30"><label>30</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Exercise promotes BCAA catabolism: effects of BCAA supplementation on skeletal muscle during exercise</article-title><source>J Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shimomura</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Murakami</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nakai</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nagasaki</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>1583</fpage><lpage>1587</lpage><volume>134</volume><year>2004</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/jn/134.6.1583S</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15173434</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF31"><label>31</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acids supplementation enhances exercise capacity and lipid oxidation during endurance exercise after muscle glycogen depletion</article-title><source>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gualano</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bozza</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Campos PL</surname><given-names>de</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>82</fpage><lpage>88</lpage><volume>51</volume><year>2011</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/49813873_Branched_chain_amino_acids_supplementation_enhance_exercise_capacity_and_lipid_oxidation_during_endurance_exercise_after_muscle_glycogen_depletion">https://www.researchgate.net/publication/49813873_Branched_chain_amino_acids_supplementation_enhance_exercise_capacity_and_lipid_oxidation_during_endurance_exercise_after_muscle_glycogen_depletion</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21297567</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF32"><label>32</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A role for branched-chain amino acids in reducing central fatigue</article-title><source>J Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Blomstrand</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>544</fpage><lpage>547</lpage><volume>136</volume><year>2006</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/jn/136.2.544S</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16424144</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF33"><label>33</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of BCAA intake during endurance exercises on fatigue substances, muscle damage substances, and energy metabolism substances</article-title><source>J Exerc Nutrition Biochem</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>DH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>WS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>HY</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>169</fpage><lpage>180</lpage><volume>17</volume><year>2013</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5717/jenb.2013.17.4.169</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4241904</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25566428</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF34"><label>34</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Carbohydrates, branched-chain amino acids, and endurance: the central fatigue hypothesis</article-title><source>Int J Sport Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>38</lpage><volume>5 Suppl</volume><year>1995</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/ijsn.5.s1.s29</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7550256</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF35"><label>35</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The effects of 8 weeks of heavy resistance training and branched-chain amino acid supplementation on body composition and muscle performance</article-title><source>Nutr Health</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Spillane</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Emerson</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Willoughby</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>263</fpage><lpage>273</lpage><volume>21</volume><year>2012</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24620007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/0260106013510999</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF36"><label>36</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>In a single-blind, matched group design: branched-chain amino acid supplementation and resistance training maintains lean body mass during a caloric restricted diet</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dudgeon</surname><given-names>WD</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kelley</surname><given-names>EP</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Scheett</surname><given-names>TP</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>1</fpage><volume>13</volume><year>2016</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26733764</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12970-015-0112-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4700774</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF37"><label>37</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Ergogenic effect of BCAAs and L-alanine supplementation: proof-of-concept study in a murine model of physiological exercise</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mantuano</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bianchini</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cappellari</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><volume>12</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu12082295</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7468919</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32751732</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF38"><label>38</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of leucine and its metabolite β-hydroxy-β-methylbutyrate on human skeletal muscle protein metabolism</article-title><source>J Physiol</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wilkinson</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hossain</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hill</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>2911</fpage><lpage>2923</lpage><volume>591</volume><year>2013</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23551944</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1113/jphysiol.2013.253203</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3690694</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF39"><label>39</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The effect of beta-alanine versus alkaline agent supplementation combined with branched-chain amino acids and creatine malate in highly-trained sprinters and endurance athletes: a randomized double-blind crossover study</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Durkalec-Michalski</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kusy</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ciekot-Sołtysiak</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zieliński</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><volume>11</volume><year>2019</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu11091961</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6769605</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31438535</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF40"><label>40</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Creatine supplementation with specific view to exercise/sports performance: an update</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cooper</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Naclerio</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Allgrove</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jimenez</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>33</fpage><volume>9</volume><year>2012</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22817979</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/1550-2783-9-33</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3407788</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF41"><label>41</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Wake up and smell the coffee: caffeine supplementation and exercise performance-an umbrella review of 21 published meta-analyses</article-title><source>Br J Sports Med</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Grgic</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Grgic</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pickering</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Schoenfeld</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bishop</surname><given-names>DJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pedisic</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>681</fpage><lpage>688</lpage><volume>54</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30926628</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bjsports-2018-100278</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF42"><label>42</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews</article-title><source>BMJ</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Page</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>McKenzie</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bossuyt</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>0</fpage><volume>372</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s13643-021-01626-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8008539</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33781348</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF43"><label>43</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><article-title>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions</article-title><source>Cochrane</source><publisher-name>Cochrane</publisher-name><year>2024</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.cochrane.org/authors/handbooks-and-manuals/handbook">https://www.cochrane.org/authors/handbooks-and-manuals/handbook</uri></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF44"><label>44</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Replication concerns in sports and exercise science: a narrative review of selected methodological issues in the field</article-title><source>R Soc Open Sci</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mesquida</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Murphy</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lakens</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Warne</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>220946</fpage><volume>9</volume><year>2022</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36533197</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1098/rsos.220946</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9748505</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF45"><label>45</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The effects of BCAA supplementation on muscle damage following a lower-body resistance exercise bout in soccer players</article-title><source>Football Sci</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Amini-Aghdam</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Baturak</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Panahi</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hatami</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>62</fpage><lpage>69</lpage><volume>9</volume><year>2012</year></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF46"><label>46</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A 7-day oral supplementation with branched-chain amino acids was ineffective to prevent muscle damage during a marathon</article-title><source>Amino Acids</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Areces</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Salinero</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Abian-Vicen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>1169</fpage><lpage>1176</lpage><volume>46</volume><year>2014</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24477835</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00726-014-1677-3</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF47"><label>47</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Impacts of combined or single supplementation of branched-chain amino acids on delayed onset muscle soreness and muscle damage following resistance exercise</article-title><source>Progress Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Asjodi</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Khotbesara</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gargari</surname><given-names>BP</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Izadi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>263</fpage><lpage>272</lpage><volume>20</volume><year>2018</year></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF48"><label>48</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of branched-chain amino acid supplementation and resistance training in postmenopausal women</article-title><source>Exp Gerontol</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bagheri</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Forbes</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Candow</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>111185</fpage><volume>144</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33279662</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.exger.2020.111185</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF49"><label>49</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The acute effects different quantities of branched-chain amino acids have on recovery of muscle function</article-title><source>Sports Nutr Ther</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dorrell</surname><given-names>HF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gee</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>115</fpage><volume>1</volume><year>2016</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.omicsonline.org/peer-reviewed/abstract-page.php?url=the-acute-effects-different-quantities-of-branchedchain-amino-acidsrnhave-on-recovery-of-muscle-function-84390">https://www.omicsonline.org/peer-reviewed/abstract-page.php?url=the-acute-effects-different-quantities-of-branchedchain-amino-acidsrnhave-on-recovery-of-muscle-function-84390</uri></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF50"><label>50</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of branched-chain amino acids supplementation on both plasma amino acids concentration and muscle energetics changes resulting from muscle damage: a randomized placebo controlled trial</article-title><source>Clin Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fouré</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nosaka</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gastaldi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>83</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><volume>35</volume><year>2016</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25886707</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.clnu.2015.03.014</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF51"><label>51</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acid supplementation attenuates a decrease in power-producing ability following acute strength training</article-title><source>J Sports Med Phys Fitness</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gee</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Deniel</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
</person-group><volume>56</volume><year>2016</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/293634836_Branched-chain_amino_acid_supplementation_attenuates_a_decrease_in_power-producing_ability_following_acute_strength_training">https://www.researchgate.net/publication/293634836_Branched-chain_amino_acid_supplementation_attenuates_a_decrease_in_power-producing_ability_following_acute_strength_training</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26853239</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF52"><label>52</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acid supplementation lowers perceived exertion but does not affect performance in untrained males</article-title><source>J Strength Cond Res</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Greer</surname><given-names>BK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>White</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Arguello</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Haymes</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>539</fpage><lpage>544</lpage><volume>25</volume><year>2011</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20386134</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181bf443a</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF53"><label>53</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Exercise-induced muscle damage is reduced in resistance-trained males by branched chain amino acids: a randomized, double-blind, placebo controlled study</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Howatson</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hoad</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Goodall</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tallent</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bell</surname><given-names>PG</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>French</surname><given-names>DN</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>20</fpage><volume>9</volume><year>2012</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22569039</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/1550-2783-9-20</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3395580</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF54"><label>54</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acid supplementation enhances substrate metabolism, exercise efficiency and reduces post-exercise fatigue in active young males</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Luan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>1290</fpage><volume>17</volume><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40219047</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu17071290</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11990590</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF55"><label>55</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acid supplementation improves cycling performance in untrained cyclists</article-title><source>J Sci Med Sport</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Manaf</surname><given-names>FA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Peiffer</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Maker</surname><given-names>GL</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fairchild</surname><given-names>TJ</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>412</fpage><lpage>417</lpage><volume>24</volume><year>2021</year><uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2020.10.014">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2020.10.014</uri><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33162329</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jsams.2020.10.014</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF56"><label>56</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Short-term branched-chain amino acid supplementation does not enhance vertical jump in professional volleyball players. A double-blind, controlled, randomized study</article-title><source>Nutr Hosp</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Martín-Martínez</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Calleja Gonzalez</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Adsuar Sala</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gómez-Pomares</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Carlos-Vivas</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pérez-Gómez</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>1007</fpage><lpage>1011</lpage><volume>37</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32960643</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.20960/nh.03032</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF57"><label>57</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of timing of branched-chain amino acid supplementation on muscle recovery after resistance training in healthy males</article-title><source>Am J Mens Health</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Meng</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
</person-group><volume>19</volume><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/15579883251332731</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12033860</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40231445</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF58"><label>58</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The effects of BCAA and creatine supplementation on anaerobic capacity and ball kicking speed in male football players</article-title><source>J Men's Health</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mor</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Acar</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yılmaz</surname><given-names>AK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Arslanoglu</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>5</fpage><volume>21</volume><year>2025</year></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF59"><label>59</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Sex-based effects of branched-chain amino acids on strength training performance and body composition</article-title><source>Sports (Basel)</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Muscella</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Felline</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Marsigliante</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>275</fpage><volume>12</volume><year>2024</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39453241</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/sports12100275</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11510782</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF60"><label>60</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acids combined with exercise improves physical function and quality of life in older adults: results from a pilot randomized controlled trial</article-title><source>Dietetics (Basel)</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Robbins</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>O'Connor</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cortes</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Serra</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name>
</person-group><volume>4</volume><year>2025</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/dietetics4030032</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12377484</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40860958</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF61"><label>61</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of chronic supplementation of branched chain amino acids on exercise-induced muscle damage in trained athletes</article-title><source>J Sports Sci</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shenoy</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dhawan</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sandhu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><volume>5</volume><year>2017</year></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF62"><label>62</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of carbohydrate and branched-chain amino acid beverage ingestion during acute upper body resistance exercise on performance and postexercise hormone response</article-title><source>Appl Physiol Nutr Metab</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>JW</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krings</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shepherd</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Waldman</surname><given-names>HS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Basham</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>McAllister</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>504</fpage><lpage>509</lpage><volume>43</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29244956</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1139/apnm-2017-0563</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF63"><label>63</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acids ingestion does not affect endurance performance (Article in Portuguese)</article-title><source>Rev Bras Med Esporte</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Uchida</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bacurau</surname><given-names>AVN</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Aoki</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bacurau</surname><given-names>RF</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>42</fpage><lpage>45</lpage><volume>14</volume><year>2008</year></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF64"><label>64</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of branched-chain amino acid supplementation on recovery following acute eccentric exercise</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>VanDusseldorp</surname><given-names>TA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Escobar</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Johnson</surname><given-names>KE</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><volume>10</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu10101389</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6212987</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30275356</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF65"><label>65</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>The effect of acute branched-chain amino acid supplementation on prolonged exercise capacity in a warm environment</article-title><source>Eur J Appl Physiol</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Watson</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shirreffs</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Maughan</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>306</fpage><lpage>314</lpage><volume>93</volume><year>2004</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15349784</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00421-004-1206-2</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF66"><label>66</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of exercise training and amino-acid supplementation on body composition and physical performance in untrained women</article-title><source>Nutrition</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Antonio</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sanders</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ehler</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Uelmen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Raether</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stout</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>1043</fpage><lpage>1046</lpage><volume>16</volume><year>2000</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11118822</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/s0899-9007(00)00434-2</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF67"><label>67</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Eight weeks of resistance training in conjunction with glutathione and L-Citrulline supplementation increases lean mass and has no adverse effects on blood clinical safety markers in resistance-trained males</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Morales Marroquín</surname><given-names>FE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gann</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>30</fpage><volume>15</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29945625</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12970-018-0235-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6020314</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF68"><label>68</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effect of exercise therapy combined with branched-chain amino acid supplementation on muscle strength in elderly women after total hip arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial</article-title><source>Asia Pac J Clin Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ikeda</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Matsunaga</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kanbara</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>720</fpage><lpage>726</lpage><volume>28</volume><year>2019</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31826368</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.6133/apjcn.201912_28(4).0007</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF69"><label>69</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults</article-title><source>Br J Sports Med</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Morton</surname><given-names>RW</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Murphy</surname><given-names>KT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>McKellar</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>376</fpage><lpage>384</lpage><volume>52</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28698222</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097608</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5867436</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF70"><label>70</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Protein recommendations for weight loss in elite athletes: a focus on body composition and performance</article-title><source>Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hector</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>170</fpage><lpage>177</lpage><volume>28</volume><year>2018</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29182451</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0273</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF71"><label>71</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Exercise-induced activation of the branched-chain 2-oxo acid dehydrogenase in human muscle</article-title><source>Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wagenmakers</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brookes</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Coakley</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Reilly</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names>RH</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>159</fpage><lpage>167</lpage><volume>59</volume><year>1989</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2583157</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/BF02386181</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF72"><label>72</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Branched-chain amino acids and central fatigue</article-title><source>J Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Newsholme</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Blomstrand</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>274</fpage><lpage>276</lpage><volume>136</volume><year>2006</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1093/jn/136.1.274S</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16365097</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF73"><label>73</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Effects of oral branched-chain amino acids (BCAAs) intake on muscular and central fatigue during an incremental exercise</article-title><source>J Hum Kinet</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>AbuMoh'd</surname><given-names>MF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Matalqah</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Al-Abdulla</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>69</fpage><lpage>78</lpage><volume>72</volume><year>2020</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32269649</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2478/hukin-2019-0099</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7126259</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF74"><label>74</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Creatine for exercise and sports performance, with recovery considerations for healthy populations</article-title><source>Nutrients</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wax</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kerksick</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jagim</surname><given-names>AR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mayo</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lyons</surname><given-names>BC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kreider</surname><given-names>RB</given-names></name>
</person-group><volume>13</volume><year>2021</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/nu13061915</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8228369</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34199588</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF75"><label>75</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Potential therapeutic effects of branched-chain amino acids supplementation on resistance exercise-based muscle damage in humans</article-title><source>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>da Luz</surname><given-names>CR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nicastro</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zanchi</surname><given-names>NE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chaves</surname><given-names>DF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lancha AH</surname><given-names>Jr</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>23</fpage><volume>8</volume><year>2011</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22168756</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/1550-2783-8-23</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3261811</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF76"><label>76</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Dietary protein for athletes: from requirements to optimum adaptation</article-title><source>J Sports Sci</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Phillips</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Van Loon</surname><given-names>LJ</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>0</fpage><lpage>38</lpage><volume>29 Suppl 1</volume><year>2011</year><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/02640414.2011.619204</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22150425</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF77"><label>77</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Hormonal responses to resistance exercise in long-term trained and untrained middle-aged men</article-title><source>J Strength Cond Res</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cadore</surname><given-names>EL</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lhullier</surname><given-names>FL</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brentano</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group><fpage>1617</fpage><lpage>1624</lpage><volume>22</volume><year>2008</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18714223</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31817bd45d</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF78"><label>78</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Caffeine and anaerobic performance: ergogenic value and mechanisms of action</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Green</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>813</fpage><lpage>832</lpage><volume>39</volume><year>2009</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19757860</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2165/11317770-000000000-00000</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF79"><label>79</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Repeated sprint ability is not enhanced by caffeine, arginine, and branched-chain amino acids in moderately trained soccer players</article-title><source>J Exerc Rehabil</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ermolao</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zanotto</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Carraro</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fornasier</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zaccaria</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Neunhaeuserer</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bergamin</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>55</fpage><lpage>61</lpage><volume>13</volume><year>2017</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28349034</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.12965/jer.1732722.361</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5332000</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="REF80"><label>80</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><article-title>Muscle soreness and delayed-onset muscle soreness</article-title><source>Clin Sports Med</source><person-group>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lewis</surname><given-names>PB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ruby</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bush-Joseph</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name>
</person-group><fpage>255</fpage><lpage>262</lpage><volume>31</volume><year>2012</year><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22341015</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.csm.2011.09.009</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>