<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33306588</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does the Muscle Action Duration Induce Different Regional Muscle Hypertrophy in Matched Resistance Training Protocols?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2371</StartPage><EndPage>2380</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2371-2380</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003883</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diniz, RCR, Tourino, FD, Lacerda, LT, Martins-Costa, HC, Lanza, MB, Lima, FV, and Chagas, MH. Does the muscle action duration induce different regional muscle hypertrophy in matched resistance training protocols? J Strength Cond Res 36(9): 2371-2380, 2022-The manipulation of the muscle action duration (MAD) can influence the instantaneous torque along the range of motion, which can lead to adaptations of regional muscle hypertrophy. The aim of this study was to compare the effects of matched resistance training (RT) on the knee extension machine with different MAD in the cross-sectional area (CSA) responses within the quadriceps femoris (QF) and its muscles. Forty-four subjects were allocated into a control and 3 experimental groups. For a period of 10 weeks, subjects in the experimental groups performed the training protocols that were different only by the MAD: group 5c1e (5s concentric action [CON] and 1s eccentric action [ECC]; group 3c3e (3s CON and 3s ECC) and group 1c5e (1s CON and 5s ECC). Magnetic resonance imaging was performed (before and after the intervention) to determine the relative change (%) in CSA of the QF muscles along proximal (30%), middle (50%), and distal regions (70% distal of the femur). The change in CSA of the rectus femoris at the middle region are greater in 5c1e (6.8 &#xb1; 6.5%) and 1c5e (7.4 &#xb1; 6.0%) groups than 3c3e (3.4 &#xb1; 6.6%) and control groups (0.2 &#xb1; 1.8%). In addition, vastus lateralis at the distal region (5c1e = 15.9 &#xb1; 11.8%; 1c5e = 14.4 &#xb1; 10.0%) presenting greater increases in change of CSA than the others vastus only 5c1e (vastus lateralis [VI] = 5.0 &#xb1; 4.7%; vastus medialis [VM] = 4.2 &#xb1; 3.2%) and 1c5e groups (VI = 4.7 &#xb1; 3.6%; VM = 3.4 &#xb1; 3.1%). In conclusion, this study showed that matched RT protocols with different MAD resulted in different region-specific muscle hypertrophic across the individual muscles of QF.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diniz</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo C R</ForeName><Initials>RCR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tourino</LastName><ForeName>Frank Douglas</ForeName><Initials>FD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lacerda</LastName><ForeName>Lucas T</ForeName><Initials>LT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education of Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State University of Minas Gerais, Divin&#xf3;polis, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports, Technological Education Federal Center of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martins-Costa</LastName><ForeName>Hugo C</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education of Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lanza</LastName><ForeName>Marcel Bahia</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation, School of Medicine, University of Maryland, Baltimore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lima</LastName><ForeName>Fernando Vitor</ForeName><Initials>FV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chagas</LastName><ForeName>Mauro Heleno</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007717" MajorTopicYN="N">Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019415" MajorTopicYN="N">Torque</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202209000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kumagai K, Brechue WF. Fascicle length of leg muscles is greater in sprinters than distance runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 1125&#x2013;1129, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alegre LM, Ferri-Morales A, Rodriguez-Casares R, Aguado X. Effects of isometric training on the knee extensor moment&#x2013;angle relationship and vastus lateralis muscle architecture. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 2437&#x2013;2446, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J. Nonuniform response of skeletal muscle to heavy resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 14: 102&#x2013;113, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnouin Y, Butler-Browne G, Voit T, et al. Manual segmentation of individual muscles of the quadriceps femoris using MRI: A reappraisal. J Magn Reson Imaging 40: 239&#x2013;247, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW. The importance of a priori sample size estimation in strength and conditioning research. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2323&#x2013;2337, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley JR, Amonette WE, De Witt JK, Hagan RD. Effects of different lifting cadences on ground reaction forces during the squat exercise. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1414&#x2013;1420, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomquist K, Langberg H, Karlsen S, et al. Effect of range of motion in heavy load squatting on muscle and tendon adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2133&#x2013;2142, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coburn JW, Housh DJ, Housh TJ, et al. Effects of leucine and whey protein supplementation during eight weeks of unilateral resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 20: 284&#x2013;291, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dancey CP, Reidy J. Analysis of differences between three or more conditions. In: Statistics Without Maths for Psychology (5th ed.). Dancey CP and Reidy J, eds. Harlow, United Kingdom: Pearson Education Limited, 2011. pp. 297&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Ruiter CJ, de Boer MD, Spanjaard M, de Haan A. Knee angle-dependent oxygen consumption during isometric contractions of the knee extensors determined with near-infrared spectroscopy. J Appl Physiol 99: 579&#x2013;586, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diniz RCR, Martins-Costa HC, Machado SC, et al. Repetition duration influences ratings of perceived exertion. Percept Mot Skills 118: 261&#x2013;273, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Newton RU, Cormie P, Blazevich AJ. Inhomogeneous quadriceps femoris hypertrophy in response to strength and power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 2389&#x2013;2397, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Stucchi DT, Demartini JK, Roti MW. Regional surface electromyography of the vastus lateralis during strength and power exercises. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1585&#x2013;1591, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inferior muscularity of the rectus femoris to vasti in varsity oarsmen. Int J Sports Med 35: 293&#x2013;297, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2691&#x2013;2703, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med 48: 499&#x2013;505, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland J, Morris B. Variable-cam resistance training machines: Do they match the angle&#x2014;Torque relationship in humans? J Sports Sci 26: 163&#x2013;169, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training. Sports Med 37: 145&#x2013;168, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3085&#x2013;3092, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz CO, Morris PE, Richler JJ. Effect size estimates: Current use, calculations, and interpretation. J Exp Psychol Gen 141: 2&#x2013;18, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, et al. Selective muscle hypertrophy, changes in EMG and force, and serum hormones during strength training in older women. J Appl Physiol 91: 569&#x2013;580, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm L, Reitelseder S, Pedersen TG, et al. Changes in muscle size and MHC composition in response to resistance exercise with heavy and light loading intensity. J Appl Physiol 105: 1454&#x2013;1461, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hug F, Marqueste T, Le Fur Y, et al. Selective training-induced thigh muscles hypertrophy in professional road cyclists. Eur J Appl Physiol 97: 591&#x2013;597, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanehisa H, Funato K, Kuno S, Fukunaga T, Katsuta S. Growth trend of the quadriceps femoris muscle in junior Olympic weight lifters: An 18-month follow-up survey. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 238&#x2013;242, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooistra RD, de Ruiter CJ, de Haan A. Muscle activation and blood flow do not explain the muscle length-dependent variation in quadriceps isometric endurance. J Appl Physiol 98: 810&#x2013;816, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumagai K, Abe T, Brechue WF, et al. Sprint performance is related to muscle fascicle length in male 100-m sprinters. J Appl Physiol 88: 811&#x2013;816, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerda LT, Costa CG, Lima FV, et al. Longer concentric action increases muscle activation and neuromuscular fatigue responses in protocols equalized by repetition duration. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1629&#x2013;1639, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerda LT, Martins-Costa HC, Diniz RCR, et al. Variations in repetition duration and repetition numbers influence muscular activation and blood lactate response in protocols equalized by time under tension. J Strength Cond Res 30: 251&#x2013;258, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Scala Teixeira CV, Motoyama Y, de Azevedo PHSM, Evangelista AL, Steele J, Bocalini DS. Effect of resistance training set volume on upper body muscle hypertrophy: Are more sets really better than less? Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 38: 727&#x2013;732, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon GE, Morse CI, Burden A, Winwood K, Onamb&#xe9;l&#xe9; GL. Impact of range of motion during ecologically valid resistance training protocols on muscle size, subcutaneous fat, and strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 245&#x2013;255, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnyk JA, Rogers MA, Hurley BF. Effects of strength training and detraining on regional muscle in young and older men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol 105: 929&#x2013;938, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto N, Wakahara T, Ema R, Kawakami Y. Non-uniform muscle oxygenation despite uniform neuromuscular activity within the vastus lateralis during fatiguing heavy resistance exercise. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 33: 463&#x2013;469, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Hoppeler H, Kayser B, et al. Human quadriceps cross-sectional area, torque and neural activation during 6 months strength training. Acta Physiol Scand 157: 175&#x2013;186, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noorkoiv M, Nosaka K, Blazevich AJ. Neuromuscular adaptations associated with knee joint angle-specific force change. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 1525&#x2013;1537, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen LA, Nicoll JX, Fry AC. The skeletal muscle fiber: A mechanically sensitive cell. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 333&#x2013;349, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson JA, Donohoe A, Groeller H. Effect of concentric and eccentric velocity during heavy-load non-ballistic elbow flexion resistance exercise. J Sci Med Sport 17: 306&#x2013;311, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott AJ, Knott M. A cluster analysis method for grouping means in the analysis of variance. Biometrics 30: 507&#x2013;512, 1974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedliak M, Finni T, Cheng S, Lind M, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Effect of time-of-day-specific strength training on muscular hypertrophy in men. J Strength Cond Res 23: 2451&#x2013;2457, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, de Boer M, Narici MV. Early skeletal muscle hypertrophy and architectural changes in response to high-intensity resistance training. J Appl Physiol 102: 368&#x2013;373, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanimoto M, Ishii N. Effects of low-intensity resistance exercise with slow movement and tonic force generation on muscular function in young men. J Appl Physiol 100: 1150&#x2013;1157, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol 126: 30&#x2013;43, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Ema R, Miyamoto N, Kawakami Y. Inter- and intramuscular differences in training-induced hypertrophy of the quadriceps femoris: Association with muscle activation during the first training session. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 37: 405&#x2013;412, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawkami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 2158&#x2013;2165, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Sugisaki N, et al. Association between regional differences in muscle activation in one session of resistance exercise and in muscle hypertrophy after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1569&#x2013;1576, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med 37: 225&#x2013;264, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>