<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23015982</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Periodization: current review and suggested implementation for athletic rehabilitation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>509</StartPage><EndPage>518</EndPage><MedlinePgn>509-18</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Clinicians are constantly faced with the challenge of designing training programs for injured and noninjured athletes that maximize healing and optimize performance. Periodization is a concept of systematic progression-that is, resistance training programs that follow predictable patterns of change in training variables. The strength training literature is abundant with studies comparing periodization schemes on uninjured, trained, and untrained athletes. The rehabilitation literature, however, is scarce with information about how to optimally design resistance training programs based on periodization principles for injured athletes. The purpose of this review is to discuss relevant training variables and methods of periodization, as well as periodization program outcomes. A secondary purpose is to provide an anecdotal framework regarding implementation of periodization principles into rehabilitation programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="EVIDENCE ACQUISITION" NlmCategory="METHODS">A Medline search from 1979 to 2009 was implemented with the keywords periodization, strength training, rehabilitation, endurance, power, hypertrophy, and resistance training with the Boolean term AND in all possible combinations in the English language. Each author also undertook independent hand searching of article references used in this review.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Based on the studies researched, periodized strength training regimens demonstrate improved outcomes as compared to nonperiodized programs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Despite the evidence in the strength training literature supporting periodization programs, there is a considerable lack of data in the rehabilitation literature about program design and successful implementation of periodization into rehabilitation programs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorenz</LastName><ForeName>Daniel S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Providence Medical Center, Kansas City, Kansas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reiman</LastName><ForeName>Michael P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker</LastName><ForeName>John C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">linear periodization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nonlinear periodization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">periodization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">undulating periodization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3438871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738110375910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_1941738110375910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alfredson H, Pietila T, Jonsson P, Lorenzton R. Heavy-load eccentric calf muscle training for the treatment of chronic Achilles tendinosis. Am J Sports Med. 1998;26:360-366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9617396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allerheiligen WB. Speed development and plyometric training. In: Baechle TR, ed. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1994:314-344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine Position stand: progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:364-380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson T, Kearney JT. Effects of three resistance training programs on muscular strength and absolute and relative endurance. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1982;53:1-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7079558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atha J. Strengthening muscle. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1981;9:1-73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6749520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagenhammer S, Hansson EE. Repeated sets or single sets of resistance training: a systematic review. Adv Physiother. 2007;9:154-160</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. A series of studies on the training of high-intensity muscle power and rugby league football player. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15:198-209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11710405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Wilson G, Carolyn R. Periodization: the effect on strength of manipulating volume and intensity. J Strength Cond Res. 1994;8:235-242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger RA. Effect of varied weight training programs on strength. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1962;33:168-181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beynnon BD, Uh BS, Johnson RJ, et al. Rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective, randomized, double-blind comparison of programs administered over two different time intervals. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33:347-359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15716250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bompa TO. Theory and Methodology of Training: The Key to Athletic Performance. Dubuque, IA: Kendall/Hunt; 1994</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borst SE, Dehoyos DV, Garzarella L, et al. Effects of resistance training on insulin-like growth factor-1 and IGF binding proteins. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:648-653</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11283443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford TW, Rossi SJ, Smith DB, Warren AJ. A comparison of periodization models during nine weeks with equated volume and intensity for strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:1245-1250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88:50-60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capen EK. Study of four programs of heavy resistance exercises for development of muscular strength. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1956;27:132-142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu DA. Jumping Into Plyometrics. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark MA. Integrated Training for the New Millennium. Thousand Oaks, CA: National Academy of Sports Medicine; 2001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke DH. Adaptations in strength and muscular endurance resulting from exercise. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1973;1:73-102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4806385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman AE. Nautilus vs universal gym strength training in adult males. Am Correct Ther J. 1977;31:103-107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">899994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordova ML, Ingersoll CD, Kovaleski JE, Knight KL. A comparison of isokinetic and isotonic predictions of a functional task. J Athl Train. 1995;30:319-322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1318001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLorme TL. Restoration of muscle power by heavy resistance exercise. J Bone Joint Surg. 1945;27:645-667</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudley GA, Djamil R. Incompatibility of endurance- and strength-training modes of exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1985;59:1446-1451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4066574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigenbaum MS, Pollock ML. Prescription of resistance training for health and disease. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:38-45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9927008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fish DE, Krabak BJ, Johnson-Greene D, DeLateur BJ. Optimal resistance training: comparison of DeLorme with Oxford techniques. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;82:903-909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14627926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer WJ. Designing Resistance Training Programs. 3rd ed. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ. Periodized strength training: a critical review. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13:82-89</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Schutt RC. Types of strength training. Clin Sports Med. 1985;4:159-167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber JP, Marcus RL, Dibble LE, et al. Effects of early progressive eccentric exercise on muscle structure after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2007;89:559-570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17332105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant JA, Mohtadi NG, Maitland ME, et al. Comparison of home versus physical therapy-supervised rehabilitation programs after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized clinical trial. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33:1288-1296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, Komi PV. Changes in isometric force-and relaxation-time, electromyographic and muscle fibre characteristics of human skeletal muscle during strength training and detraining. Acta Physiol Scand. 1985;125:573-585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4091001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harman E. The biomechanics of resistance exercise. In: Baechle TR, ed. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1994:65-92</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Klatt M, et al. Comparison between different off-season resistance training programs in Division III American college football players. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23;11-19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holten Institute.  [Accessed March 26, 2009].   http://www.holteninstitute.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson BH. A comparison of two progressive weight training techniques on knee extensor strength. J Athl Train. 1986;21:315-319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell R, Asmundson G. A comparison of two forms of periodized exercise rehabilitation programs in the management of chronic nonspecific low-back pain. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:513-523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19209082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler WK, Lauber D, Engelke K, Weineck J. Effects of single- vs multiple-set resistance training on maximum strength and body composition in trained postmenopausal women. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:689-694</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight KL. Quadriceps strengthening with the DAPRE technique: case studies with neurological implications. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1985;17:646-650</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4079735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuttgen HG, Kraemer WJ. Terminology and measurement in exercise performance. J Appl Sport Sci Res. 1987;1:1-10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ. A series of studies-the physiological basis for strength training in American football: fact over philosophy. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11:131-142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ. Involvement of eccentric muscle action may optimize adaptations to resistance training. Sport Sci Exchange. 1992;4(41):230-238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ. Optimizing Strength Training: Designing Non-linear Periodization Workouts. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Hakkinen K, Triplett-Mcbride NT, et al. Physiological changes with periodized resistance training in women tennis players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:157-168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12544650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Newton RU. Training for muscular power. Phys Med Rehabil Clin North Am. 2000;11:341-368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10810765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:697-688</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess N, Fry AC, et al. Influence of resistance training volume and periodization on physiological and performance adaptations in college women tennis players. Am J Sports Med. 2000;28:626-633</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11032216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JB, Stone MH, O&#x2019;Bryant HS, et al. Effects of single vs multiple sets of weight training: impact of volume, intensity, and variation. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11:143-147</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kravitz L, Akalan C, Nowicki K, Kinzey SJ. Prediction of 1 repetition maximum in high-school power lifters. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:167-172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langberg H, Ellingsgaard H, Madsen T, et al. Eccentric rehabilitation exercise increases peritendinous type I collagen synthesis in humans with Achilles tendinosis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2007;17:61-66</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16787448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matveyev L. Fundamentals of Sports Training. Moscow: Progress; 1981</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew JL, Gross PM. Body composition changes in young women with high resistance training. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1974;45:433-440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4531658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCardle WD, Katch FI, Katch VI. Exercise Physiology: Energy, Nutrition, and Human Performance. 4th ed. Baltimore, MD: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 1996</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh MJN, Davies CTM. Adaptive responses of mammalian skeletal muscle to exercise with high loads. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1984;52:139-155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6370691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kraemer WJ. Developing explosive muscular power: implications for a mixed methods training strategy. J Strength Cond. 1994;16:20-31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kraemer WJ, Hakkinen K. Effects of ballistic training on preseason preparation of elite volleyball players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:323-330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10063823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohberg L, Lorentzon R, Alfredson H. Eccentric training in patients with chronic Achilles tendinosis: normalized tendon structure and decreased thickness at follow-up. Br J Sports Med. 2004;38:8-11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14751936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski KJ, Wilson GJ, Weatherby R, Murphy PW, Lyttle AD. The effect of weight training volume on hormonal output and muscular size and function. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11:148-154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson D, Faigenbaum A, Conley M, Kraemer WJ. The National Strength and Conditioning Association&#x2019;s basic guidelines for the resistance training of athletes. Strength Cond J. 2000;22:14-27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Maximizing strength development in athletes: a meta-analysis to determine the dose-response relationship. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:377-382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poliquin C. Five steps to increasing the effectiveness of your strength training program. NSCA J. 1988;10:34-39</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, De Lima C, Frollini AB, et al. Comparison of linear and reverse linear periodization effects on maximal strength and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:266-274</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radcliffe JC, Farentinos RC. High Powered Plyometrics. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, et al. ACSM position stand: progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687-708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds JM, Gordon TJ, Robergs RA. Prediction of one repetition maximum strength from multiple repetition maximum testing and anthropometry. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:584-592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alderman BL. A meta-analysis of periodized versus nonperiodized strength and power training programs. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2004;75:413-423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15673040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Ball SD, Burkett LN. Three sets of weight training superior to 1 set with equal intensity for eliciting strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16:525-529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Burkett LN, Ball SD. A meta-analysis to determine the dose response for strength development. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:456-464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Ball SD, Phillips WT, Burkett LN. A comparison of linear and daily undulating periodized programs with equated volume and intensity for strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16:250-255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11991778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Phillips WT, Burkett LN, et al. A comparison of linear and daily undulating programs with equated volume and intensity for local muscular endurance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:82-87</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanborn K, Boros R, Hruby J, et al. Short-term performance effects of weight training with multiple sets not to failure vs a single set to failure in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14:328-331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiotz MK, Potteiger JA, Huntsinger PG, Denmark DC. The short-term effects of periodized and constant-intensity training on body composition, strength, and performance. J Strength Cond Res. 1998;12:173-178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlumberger A, Stec J, Schmidtbleicher D. Single- vs multiple-set strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15:284-289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11710652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selye H. Stress Without Distress. New York, NY: JB Lippincott; 1974</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalabi A, Kristoffersen-Wilberg M, Svensson L, Aspelin P, Movin T. Eccentric training of the gastrocnemius-soleus complex in chronic Achilles tendinopathy results in decreased tendon volume and intratendinous signal as evaluated by magnetic resonance imaging. Am J Sports Med. 2004;32:1286-1296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15262655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siff MC, Verkoshansky YV. Supertraining. 4th ed. Denver, CO: Supertraining International; 1999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starkey DB, Pollock ML, Ishida Y, et al. Effect of resistance training volume on strength and muscle thickness. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:1311-1320</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8897390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Johnson RL, Carter DR. A short term comparison of two different methods of resistance training on leg strength and power. J Athl Train. 1979;14:158-161</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, O&#x2019;Bryant HS. Weight Training: A Scientific Approach. Minneapolis, MN: Burgess; 1987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone WJ, Coulter SP. Strength/endurance effects from three resistance training protocols with women. J Strength Cond Res. 1994;8:231-234</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stowers T, McMillian J, Scala D, et al. The short-term effects of three different strength-power training methods. NSCA J. 1983;5:24-27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thein BL. Endurance impairment. In: Hall CM, Thein BL, eds. Therapeutic Exercise: Moving Toward Function, Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 1999:87-111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran QT, Docherty D, Behm D. The effects of varying time under tension and volume load on acute neuromuscular responses. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;98:402-410</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16969639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wathen D. NSCA position stand: plyometric exercise. NSCA J. 1993;15(3):16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wawryzniak JR, Tracy JE, Catizone PV, Storrow RR. Effect of closed chain exercises on quadriceps femoris peak torque and functional performance. J Athl Train. 1996;31:335-340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1318918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss LW, Coney HD, Clark FC. Differential functional adaptations to short-term low-, moderate and high-repetition weight training. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13:236-241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS. The effects of mesocycle-length weight training programs involving periodization and partially equated volumes on upper and lower body strength. J Strength Cond Res. 1993;7:2-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Murphy AJ, Walshe AD. Performance benefits from weight and plyometric training: effects of initial strength levels. Coach Sport Sci J. 1997;2:3-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Newton RU, Murphy AJ, et al. The optimal training load for the development of dynamic athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1993;25(11):1279-1286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8289617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witvrouw E, Danneels L, Van Tiggelen D, et al. Open versus closed kinetic chain exercises in patellofemoral pain: a five year prospective randomized study. Am J Sports Med. 2004;32:1122-1130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15262632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong Y, Chan S, Tang K, Ng G. Two modes of weight training programs and patellar stabilization. J Athl Train. 2009;44:264-271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2681218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yack HJ, Collins CE, Whieldon TJ. Comparison of closed and open kinetic chain exercise in the anterior cruciate ligament-deficient knee. Am J Sports Med. 1993;21:49-53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8267687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaryski C, Smith DJ. Training principles and issues for ultra-endurance athletes. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2005;4:165-170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15907270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>