<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32224716</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ischemic Preconditioning Improves Resistance Training Session Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2993</StartPage><EndPage>2998</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2993-2998</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003532</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>da Silva Novaes, J, da Silva Telles, LG, Monteiro, ER, da Silva Araujo, G, Vingren, JL, Silva Panza, P, Reis, VM, Laterza, MC, and Vianna, JM. Ischemic preconditioning improves resistance training session performance. J Strength Cond Res 35(11): 2993-2998, 2021-The aim of this study was to investigate the acute effect of ischemic preconditioning (IPC) in a resistance exercise (RE) training session on the number of repetitions performed, total volume, and rating of perceived exertion in recreationally trained and normotensive men. Sixteen recreationally trained and normotensive men completed 3 RE sessions in a counterbalanced and randomized order: (a) IPC protocol using 220 mm Hg followed by RE (IPC), (b) IPC cuff control protocol with 20 mm Hg followed by RE (CUFF), and (c) no IPC (control) followed by RE (CON). RE was performed with 3 sets of each exercise (bench press, leg press, lateral pulldown, hack machine squat, shoulder press, and Smith back squat) until concentric muscular failure, at 80% of one repetition maximum, with 90 seconds of rest between sets and 2 minutes of rest between exercises. Ischemic preconditioning and CUFF consisted of 4 cycles of 5 minutes of occlusion/low pressure alternating with 5 minutes of no occlusion (0 mm Hg) using a pneumatic tourniquet applied around the subaxillary region of the upper arm. For each condition, the number of repetitions completed, total volume of work performed, and rating of perceived exertion were determined. No significant difference was found for rating of perceived exertion between any experimental protocol. Ischemic preconditioning significantly (p &lt; 0.05) increased the number of repetitions across exercises. Consequently, total volume performed (sum of total number of repetitions x load for each exercise) was significantly higher in IPC (46,170 kg) compared with CON (34,069 kg) and CUFF (36,590 kg) across all exercises. This work may have important implications for athletic populations because it demonstrates increase in muscle performance outcomes during a single RE session. Therefore, performing IPC before RE could be an important exercise prescription recommendation to increase maximum repetition performance and total volume of work performed and thus potentially increase desired training adaptations (i.e., strength and hypertrophy).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva Novaes</LastName><ForeName>Jefferson</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Juiz de Fora, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva Telles</LastName><ForeName>Luiz Guilherme</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>S&#xe1; University Station Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monteiro</LastName><ForeName>Est&#xea;v&#xe3;o Rios</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Augusto Motta University, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva Araujo</LastName><ForeName>Gleisson</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center of Barra Mansa, Barra Mansa, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vingren</LastName><ForeName>Jakob L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotion, and Recreation, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva Panza</LastName><ForeName>Patr&#xed;cia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Juiz de Fora, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reis</LastName><ForeName>Victor Machado</ForeName><Initials>VM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center in Sports Sciences, Health Sciences and Human Development, Vila Real, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laterza</LastName><ForeName>Mateus Camaroti</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Juiz de Fora, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vianna</LastName><ForeName>Jeferson Macedo</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education and Sports, Federal University of Juiz de Fora, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019194" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ischemic Preconditioning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="N">Rest</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32224716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202111000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Addison PD, Neligan PC, Asharafpour H, et al. Noninvasive remote ischemic preconditioning for global protection of skeletal muscle against infarction. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 285: 1435&#x2013;1443, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Proctor LT, Sebranek JJ, Pegelow DF, Dempsey JA. Opioid-mediated muscle afferents inhibit central motor drive and limit peripheral muscle fatigue development in humans. J Physiol 587: 271&#x2013;283, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Blain GM, Proctor LT, et al. Implications of group III and IV muscle afferents for highintensity endurance exercise performance in humans. J Physiol 589: 5299&#x2013;5309, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreas M, Schmid AI, Keilani M, et al. Effect of ischemic preconditioning in skeletal muscle measured by functional magnetic resonance imaging and spectroscopy: A randomized crossover trial. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson 13: 32, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker JS, McCormick MC, Robergs RA. Interaction among skeletal muscle metabolic energy systems during intense exercise. J Nutr Metab 2010: 905612, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa TC, Machado AC, Braz ID, et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning delays fatigue development during handgrip exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports 25: 356&#x2013;364, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW. The importance of a priori sample size estimation in strength and conditioning research. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2323&#x2013;2337, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito PJ, Alvarez-Sa&#xc2;nchez M, D&#xf5;&#xc2;az V, et al. Cardiovascular fitness and energy expenditure response during a combined aerobic and circuit weight training protocol. PLoS One 11: e0164349, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Barroso R. Ischemic preconditioning improves strength endurance performance. J Strength Cond Res 33: 3332&#x2013;3337, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleland SM, Murias JM, Kowalchuk JM, Paterson DH. Effects of prior heavy-intensity exercise on oxygen uptake and muscle deoxygenation kinetics of a subsequent heavy-intensity cycling and knee-extension exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 37: 138&#x2013;148, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisafulli A, Tangianu F, Tocco F, et al. Ischemic preconditioning of the muscle improves maximal exercise performance but not maximal oxygen uptake in humans. J Appl Physiol (1985) 111: 530&#x2013;536, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz RS, de Aguiar RA, Turnes T, Pereira KL, Caputo F. Effects of ischemic preconditioning on maximal constant-load cycling performance. J Appl Physiol 119: 961&#x2013;967, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dragasis S, Bassiakou E, Iacovidou N, et al. The role of opioid receptor agonists in ischemic preconditioning. Eur J Pharmacol 720: 401&#x2013;408, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1339, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incognito AV, Burr JF, Millar PJ. The effects of ischemic preconditioning on human exercise performance. Sports Med 46: 531&#x2013;544, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jean-St-Michel E, Manlhiot C, Li J, et al. Remote preconditioning improves maximal performance in highly trained athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1280&#x2013;1286, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura M, Ueda K, Goto C, et al. Repetition of ischemic preconditioning augments endothelium-dependent vasodilation in humans: Role of endothelium-derived nitric oxide and endothelial progenitor cells. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 27: 1403&#x2013;1410, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson CS, Downey JM. Preconditioning: State of the art myocardial protection. Cardiovasc Res 27: 542&#x2013;550, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XD, Cheng YT, Yang YJ, et al. PKA-mediated eNOS phosphorylation in the protection of ischemic preconditioning against no-reflow. Microvasc Res 84: 44&#x2013;54, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libonati JR, Cox M, Incanno N, et al. Brief periods of occlusion and reperfusion increase skeletal muscle force output in humans. Cardiologia 43: 1355&#x2013;1360, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Da Mota GR, Pelegrini V, Appell Coriolano HJ. Are the beneficial effects of ischemic preconditioning on performance partly a placebo effect? Int J Sports Med 36: 822&#x2013;825, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Willardson JM, Marocolo IC, et al. Ischemic preconditioning and placebo intervention improves resistance exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1462&#x2013;1469, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Marocolo IC, Da Mota GR, et al. Beneficial effects of ischemic preconditioning in resistance exercise fade over time. Int J Sports Med 37: 819&#x2013;824, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murry CE, Jennings RB, Reimer KA. Preconditioning with ischemia: A delay of lethal cell injury in ischemic myocardium. Circulation 74: 112&#x2013;436, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paix&#xe3;o RC, Da Mota GR, Marocolo M. Acute effect of ischemic preconditioning is detrimental to anaerobic performance in cyclists. Int J Sports Med 35: 912&#x2013;915, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang CY, Yang RZ, Zhong A, et al. Acute ischaemic preconditioning protects against skeletal muscle infarction in the pig. Cardiovasc Res 29: 782&#x2013;788, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis-Desch&#xea;nes P, Joanisse DR, Billaut F. Ischemic preconditioning increases muscle perfusion, oxygen uptake, and force in strength-trained athletes. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 41: 938&#x2013;944, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis-Desch&#xea;nes P, Joanisse DR, Billaut F. Sex-Specific impact of ischemic preconditioning on tissue oxygenation and maximal concentric force. Front Physiol 7: 674, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, BA Alvar, TK Evetovich, et al. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand: Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exer 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis VM, Garrido ND, Vianna J, et al. Energy cost of intensities. PLoS One 12: e0181311, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res 18: 918&#x2013;920, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson RJ, Goss FL, Rutkowski J, et al. Concurrent validation of the OMNI perceived exertion scale for resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 333&#x2013;341, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador AF, De Aguiar RA, Lisboa FD, et al. Ischemic preconditioning and exercise performance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 4: 14, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Farinatti PdeT, Polito MD, Maior AS, Fleck SJ. Influence of exercise order on the number of repetitions performed and perceived exertion during resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 19: 152&#x2013;156, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott CB, Croteau A, Ravlo T. Energy expenditure before, during, and after the bench press. J Strength Cond Res 23: 611&#x2013;618, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott CB, Leighton BH, Ahearn KJ, McManus JJ. Aerobic, anaerobic and excess postexercise oxygen consumption energy expenditure of muscular endurance and strength: 1-set of bench press to muscular fatigue. J Strength Cond Res 25: 903&#x2013;908, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka D, Suga T, Tanaka T, et al. Ischemic preconditioning enhances muscle endurance during sustained isometric exercise. Int J Sports Med 37: 614&#x2013;618, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vianna JM, Lima JP, Saavedra FJ, Reis VM. Aerobic and anaerobic energy during resistance exercise at 80% 1RM. J Hum Kinet 29A: 69&#x2013;74, 2011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>