<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39074191</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Microvascular Reactivity Is Greater Following Blood Flow Restriction Resistance Exercise Compared with Traditional Resistance Exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e553</StartPage><EndPage>e562</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e553-e562</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004873</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Perlet, MR, Hosick, PA, Licameli, N, and Matthews, EL. Microvascular reactivity is greater following blood flow restriction resistance exercise compared with traditional resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res 38(10): e553-e562, 2024-Chronic blood flow restriction (BFR) resistance exercise can improve muscular strength, hypertrophy, and microvasculature function, but the acute microvascular effects are unknown. We aimed to test the effects of acute BFR resistance exercise on postexercise microvascular reactivity in an exercising muscle and nonexercising muscle compared with traditional resistance exercise (TRE). Twenty-five adults (men = 14, women = 11, age: 22 &#xb1; 3 years, body mass: 71.69 &#xb1; 14.49 kg, height: 170 &#xb1; 10 cm) completed barbell back squat 1-repetition maximum (1RM) testing followed by 2 randomized and counterbalanced resistance exercise visits separated by &#x2265;48 hours. The 2 visits involved either BFR (4 sets of 30-15-15-15 repetitions at 30% 1RM, with 60-second rest intervals) or TRE (4 sets of 10 repetitions at 70% 1RM, 60-second rest intervals). During each exercise visit, a pre- and postbarbell back squat vascular occlusion test was performed using near-infrared spectroscopy to measure skeletal muscle oxygen (SmO 2 ) in the vastus lateralis (VL) and flexor carpi radialis (FCR). Two-way repeated-measures ANOVA found an interaction effect ( p = 0.020) for SmO 2 reactivity in the VL. Post hoc analysis found greater reactive hyperemia postexercise in the VL for the BFR condition ( p &lt; 0.001) but not the TRE condition ( p &#x2265; 0.05). There were no time, condition, or interaction effects (all p &gt; 0.05) for the same analysis in the FCR. This analysis suggests that BFR, but not TRE, lead to acutely improved microvasculature function. Moreover, it suggests that the effects of BFR resistance exercise are local to the exercised or occluded limb and not systemic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perlet</LastName><ForeName>Michael R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Physical Education, Montclair State University, Montclair, New Jersey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosick</LastName><ForeName>Peter A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Physical Education, Montclair State University, Montclair, New Jersey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Licameli</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength Together, Inc., Nutley, New Jersey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matthews</LastName><ForeName>Evan L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5499-2429</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Physical Education, Montclair State University, Montclair, New Jersey; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008833" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microcirculation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019265" MajorTopicYN="N">Spectroscopy, Near-Infrared</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055806" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microvessels</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Flow Restriction Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39074191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202410000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barstow TJ. Understanding near infrared spectroscopy and its application to skeletal muscle research. J Appl Physiol (1985) 126: 1360&#x2013;1376, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezemer R, Lima A, Myers D, et al. Assessment of tissue oxygen saturation during a vascular occlusion test using near-infrared spectroscopy: The role of probe spacing and measurement site studied in healthy volunteers. Crit Care 13: 244, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biazon TM, Ugrinowitsch C, Soligon SD, et al. The association between muscle deoxygenation and muscle hypertrophy to blood flow restricted training performed at high and low loads. Front Physiol 10: 446, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Jerger S, Lauber B, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction and high-load resistance training induce comparable changes in patellar tendon properties. Med Sci Sports Exerc 54: 582&#x2013;589, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Liu K, Joneschild E, et al. Role of nitric oxide in vasodilation in upstream muscle during intermittent pneumatic compression. J Appl Physiol 92: 559&#x2013;566, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citherlet T, Raberin A, Manferdelli G, Mota GR, Millet GP. Age and sex differences in microvascular responses during reactive hyperaemia. Exp Physiol 109: 804&#x2013;811, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coccarelli A, Nelson MD. Modeling reactive hyperemia to better understand and assess microvascular function: A review of techniques. Ann Biomed Eng 51: 479&#x2013;492, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delsys. Technical Note 101: EMG Sensor Placement. Boston, MA: Delsys, https://delsys.com/downloads/TECHNICALNOTE/101-emg-sensor-placement.pdf (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dipla K, Triantafyllou A, Koletsos N, et al. Impaired muscle oxygenation and elevated exercise blood pressure in hypertensive patients: Links with vascular stiffness. Hypertension 70: 444&#x2013;451, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson RA, Hunt JEA, Lewis MP, et al. The acute angiogenic signalling response to low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 397&#x2013;406, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas EDS, Galletti BRA, Koziol KJ, et al. The acute physiological responses to traditional vs. practical blood flow restriction resistance exercise in untrained men and women. Front Physiol 11: 577224, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas EDS, Miller RM, Heishman AD, et al. Acute physiological responses to resistance exercise with continuous versus intermittent blood flow restriction: A randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol 11: 132, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol 103: 903&#x2013;910, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gundermann DM, Fry CS, Dickinson JM, et al. Reactive hyperemia is not responsible for stimulating muscle protein synthesis following blood flow restriction exercise. J Appl Physiol 112: 1520&#x2013;1528, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan KS, Fahs CA, Iwamoto GA, et al. Resistance exercise training reduces central blood pressure and improves microvascular function in African American and White Men. Atherosclerosis 207: 220&#x2013;226, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hladky SB, Rink TJ. Osmotic behaviour of human red blood cells: An interpretation in terms of negative intracellular fluid pressure. J Physiol 274: 437&#x2013;446, 1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi M, Okita K. Microvascular responses during reactive hyperemia assessed by near-infrared spectroscopy and arterial stiffness in young, middle-aged, and older women. Microvasc Res 129: 103972, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt JEA, Galea D, Tufft G, Bunce D, Ferguson RA. Time course of regional vascular adaptations to low load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol 115: 403&#x2013;411, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannetta D, Inglis EC, Soares RN, et al. Reliability of microvascular responsiveness measures derived from near-infrared spectroscopy across a variety of ischemic periods in young and older individuals. Microvasc Res 122: 117&#x2013;124, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones H, Hopkins N, Bailey TG, et al. Seven-day remote ischemic preconditioning improves local and systemic endothelial function and microcirculation in healthy humans. Am J Hypertens 27: 918&#x2013;925, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller JL, Kennedy KG. Men exhibit faster skeletal muscle tissue desaturation than women before and after a fatiguing handgrip. Eur J Appl Physiol 121: 3473&#x2013;3483, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller JL, Traylor MK, Gray SM, Hill EC, Weir JP. Sex differences in NIRS-derived values of reactive hyperemia persist after experimentally controlling for the ischemic vasodilatory stimulus. J Appl Physiol 135: 3&#x2013;14, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer R, Lorenzen J, Kabbani M, et al. Acute effects of remote ischemic preconditioning on cutaneous microcirculation - a controlled prospective cohort study. BMC Surg 11: 32, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino G, et al. Effects of exercise intensity and occlusion pressure after 12 weeks of resistance training with blood-flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 2471&#x2013;2480, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz DS, Bailey L, Wilk KE, et al. Blood flow restriction training. J Athl Train 56: 937&#x2013;944, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maga M, Sch&#xf6;nborn M, Wachsmann-Maga A, et al. Stimulation of the vascular endothelium and angiogenesis by blood-flow-restricted exercise. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19: 15859, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancini D, Bollinger L, Li H, et al. Validation of near-infrared spectroscopy in humans. J Appl Physiol 77: 2740&#x2013;2747, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews EL, Guers JJ, Hosick PA. Young healthy adults with a family history of hypertension have increased microvascular reactivity but decreased macrovascular function. Microcirculation 28: e12676, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Dickinson A, Pattany PM, Fleck SJ. Muscle fiber hypertrophy, hyperplasia, and capillary density in college men after resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 81: 2004&#x2013;2012, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLay KM, Nederveen JP, Pogliaghi S, Paterson DH, Murias JM. Repeatability of vascular responsiveness measures derived from near-infrared spectroscopy. Physiol Rep 4: 1&#x2013;8, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus CJ, Collison J, Cooper CE. Performance comparison of the MOXY and PortaMon near-infrared spectroscopy muscle oximeters at rest and during exercise. J Biomed Opt 23: 1&#x2013;14, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messere A, Roatta S. Influence of cutaneous and muscular circulation on spatially resolved versus standard Beer-Lambert near-infrared spectroscopy. Physiol Rep 1: e00179, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanas S, Gerovasili V, Dimopoulos S, et al. Inotropic agents improve the peripheral microcirculation of patients with end-stage chronic heart failure. J Card Fail 14: 400&#x2013;406, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Strength and Conditioning Association. Exercise Technique Manual for Resistance Training (Part 2). (4th ed.). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2022. p. 46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuna N, Pedro R, Leucht A, de Paula Ramos S, Nakamura F. Cardiac autonomic recovery after a single session of resistance exercise with and without vascular occlusion. J Strength Cond Res 28: 1143&#x2013;1150, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormsbee MJ, Dong Choi M, Medlin JK, et al. Regulation of fat metabolism during resistance exercise in sedentary lean and obese men. J Appl Physiol 106: 1529&#x2013;1537, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Ferguson RA. Increase in calf post-occlusive blood flow and strength following short-term resistance exercise training with blood flow restriction in young women. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 1025&#x2013;1033, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise position stand: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol 10: 533, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrey S, Quaresima V, Ferrari M. Muscle oximetry in sports science: An updated systematic review. Sports Med 48: 597&#x2013;616, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope ZK, Willardson JM, Schoenfeld BJ. Exercise and blood flow restriction. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2914&#x2013;2926, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rytter N, Carter H, Piil P, et al. Ischemic preconditioning improves microvascular endothelial function in remote vasculature by enhanced prostacyclin production. J Am Heart Assoc 9: e016017, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarelius I, Pohl U. Control of muscle blood flow during exercise: Local factors and integrative mechanisms. Acta Physiol 199: 349&#x2013;365, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz R. System and Methods for Measuring Oxygenation. Hutchinson, MN: United States Patent, https://patents.google.com/patent/US8941830B2/en (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med 43: 179&#x2013;194, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Triplett NT: Program design for resistance training. In: Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning (4th ed.). Haff G and Triplett NT, eds. Champaign, IL, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf8;berg KA, Fr&#xf8;sig C, Kj&#xf8;bsted R, et al. Exercise increases human skeletal muscle insulin sensitivity via coordinated increases in microvascular perfusion and molecular signaling. Diabetes 66: 1501&#x2013;1510, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares RN, de Oliveira GV, Alvares TS, Murias JM. The effects of the analysis strategy on the correlation between the NIRS reperfusion measures and the FMD response. Microvasc Res 127: 103922, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, et al. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol 88: 61&#x2013;65, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, et al. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol 88: 2097&#x2013;3106, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanimoto M, Madarame H, Ishii N. Muscle oxygenation and plasma growth hormone concentration during and after resistance exercise: Comparison between &#x201c;KAATSU&#x201d; and other types of regimen J STAGE 1: 51&#x2013;56, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Jacquesa SL, Zhengb L. MCML-Monte Carlo modeling of light transport in multi-layered tissues. Comput Methods Programs Biomed 47: 131&#x2013;146, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaheer F, Roy SH, De Luca CJ. Preferred sensor sites for surface EMG signal decomposition. Physiol Meas 33: 195&#x2013;206, 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>