<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37535335</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Free-Weight and Machine-Based Training Are Equally Effective on Strength and Hypertrophy: Challenging a Traditional Myth.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2316</StartPage><EndPage>2327</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2316-2327</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003271</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">This study aimed to compare the effects of free-weight and machine-based resistance training on strength, hypertrophy, and joint discomfort.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Thirty-eight resistance-trained men participated in an 8-wk resistance program allocated into free-weight ( n = 19) or machine-based ( n = 19) groups. Training variables were identical for both modalities, so they only differed in the use of barbells or machines to execute the full squat, bench press, prone bench pull, and shoulder press exercises. The velocity-based method was implemented to accurately adjust the intensity throughout the program. Strength changes were evaluated using eight velocity-monitored loading tests (four exercises &#xd7; two modalities) and included the relative one-repetition maximum (1RM Rel ), as well as the mean propulsive velocity against low (MPV Low ) and high (MPV High ) loads. Ultrasound-derived cross-sectional area of quadriceps (proximal and distal regions), pectoralis major, and rectus abdominis was measured to examine hypertrophy. Complementarily, Western Ontario and McMaster Universities and Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder and Hand questionnaires were administrated to assess changes in lower- and upper-limb joint discomfort. Outcomes were compared using ANCOVA and percentage of change (&#x2206;) statistics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Each group significantly ( P &lt; 0.001) increased 1RM Rel , MPV Low , and MPV High for both modalities tested, but especially in the one they trained. When considering together the eight exercises tested, strength changes for both modalities were similar (&#x2206; differences &#x2264;1.8%, P &#x2265; 0.216). Likewise, the cross-sectional area of all the muscles evaluated was significantly increased by both modalities, with no significant differences between them (&#x2206; difference &#x2264;2.0%, P &#x2265; 0.208). No between-group differences ( P &#x2265; 0.144) were found for changes in stiffness, pain, and functional disability levels, which were reduced by both modalities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Free-weight and machine-based modalities are similarly effective to promote strength and hypertrophy without increasing joint discomfort.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance and Sports Science Laboratory, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Murcia, Murcia, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez-Cava</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buend&#xed;a-Romero</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;ngel</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franco-L&#xf3;pez</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pallar&#xe9;s</LastName><ForeName>Jes&#xfa;s G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011187" MajorTopicYN="N">Posture</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37535335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202312000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bloomquist K, Langberg H, Karlsen S, Madsgaard S, Boesen M, Raastad T. Effect of range of motion in heavy load squatting on muscle and tendon adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2013;113(8):2133&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann H, Wirth K, Klusemann M, Dalic J, Matuschek C, Schmidtbleicher D. Influence of squatting depth on jumping performance. J Strength Cond Res . 2012;26(12):3243&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Zajac A, Tufano JJ. The influence of movement tempo during resistance training on muscular strength and hypertrophy responses: a review. Sports Med . 2021;51(8):1629&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schick EE, Coburn JW, Brown LE, et al. A comparison of muscle activation between a Smith machine and free weight bench press. J Strength Cond Res . 2010;24(3):779&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaw ST, Friday JJ. A comparison of muscle activity between a free weight and machine bench press. J Strength Cond Res . 1994;8(4):259&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DR, Lambert MI, Hunter AM. Trunk muscle activation in the back and hack squat at the same relative loads. J Strength Cond Res . 2019;33(Suppl 1):S60&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuilliam SJ, Clark DR, Erskine RM, Brownlee TE. Free-weight resistance training in youth athletes: a narrative review. Sports Med . 2020;50(9):1567&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Collins D, Plisk S, Haff G, Stone ME. Training principles: evaluation of modes and methods of resistance training. Strength Cond J . 2000;22(3):65&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwanbeck SR, Cornish SM, Barss T, Chilibeck PD. Effects of training with free weights versus machines on muscle mass, strength, free testosterone, and free cortisol levels. J Strength Cond Res . 2020;34(7):1851&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Schoenfeld BJ, Ocetnik S, et al. Strength, body composition, and functional outcomes in the squat versus leg press exercises. J Sports Med Phys Fitness . 2018;58(3):263&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidel KA, Novak ZJ, Dankel SJ. Machines and free weight exercises: a systematic review and meta-analysis comparing changes in muscle size, strength, and power. J Sports Med Phys Fitness . 2022;62(8):1061&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Keiner M, Hartmann H, Sander A, Mickel C. Effect of 8 weeks of free-weight and machine-based strength training on strength and power performance. J Hum Kinet . 2016;53:201&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Hartmann H, Sander A, Mickel C, Szilvas E, Keiner M. The impact of back squat and leg-press exercises on maximal strength and speed-strength parameters. J Strength Cond Res . 2016;30(5):1205&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustsson J, Esko A, Thome&#xe9; R, Svantesson U. Weight training of the thigh muscles using closed vs. open kinetic chain exercises: a comparison of performance enhancement. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther . 1998;27(1):3&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz NA, Harper SP, Waldhelm A, McKinley-Barnard SK, Holden SL, Kovaleski JE. A comparison of machine versus free-weight squats for the enhancement of lower-body power, speed, and change-of-direction ability during an initial training phase of recreationally-active women. Sports (Basel) . 2019;7(10):215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Olsen A, Behm DG, Bardstu HB, Andersen V. The short- and long-term effects of resistance training with different stability requirements. PLoS One . 2019;14(4):e0214302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacchio A, Don R, Ranavolo A, et al. Effects of 8-week strength training with two models of chest press machines on muscular activity pattern and strength. J Electromyogr Kinesiol . 2008;18(4):618&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Andersen V, van den Tillaar R, et al. The effects of ten weeks resistance training on sticking region in chest-press exercises. PLoS One . 2020;15(7):e0235555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew JL, Smith AE, Arabas JL, Roberts BS. Upper-body strength gains from different modes of resistance training in women who are underweight and women who are obese. J Strength Cond Res . 2010;24(10):2779&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG. Roundtable discussion: machines versus free weights. Strength Cond J . 2000;22(6):18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Longo S, Mallinson J, et al. Muscle thickness correlates to muscle cross-sectional area in the assessment of strength training-induced hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2018;28(3):846&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Newton RU, Cormie P, Blazevich AJ. Inhomogeneous quadriceps femoris hypertrophy in response to strength and power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2015;47(11):2389&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Castilla AP, Ramos AG, Van Hooren B, McGuigan MR, Helms ER. The acute and chronic effects of implementing velocity loss thresholds during resistance training: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and critical evaluation of the literature. Sports Med . 2023;53(1):177&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(6):1206&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Buend&#xed;a-Romero &#xc1;, Pallar&#xe9;s JG, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A. Velocity-based method in free-weight and machine-based training modalities: the degree of freedom matters. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(9):e500&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2017;27(7):724&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos WDND, Vieira CA, Bottaro M, et al. Resistance training performed to failure or not to failure results in similar total volume, but with different fatigue and discomfort levels. J Strength Cond Res . 2021;35(5):1372&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alc&#xe1;zar J, S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as J, et al. Velocity loss as a critical variable determining the adaptations to strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2020;52(8):1752&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, Torres-Torrelo J, Mora-Custodio R, Marques MC, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effort index as a novel variable for monitoring the level of effort during resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res . 2018;32(8):2139&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Conesa-Ros E, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Level of effort: a reliable and practical alternative to the velocity-based approach for monitoring resistance training. J Strength Cond Res . 2022;36(11):2992&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DT, Erdman KA, Burke LM. American College of Sports Medicine joint position statement. Nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2016;48(3):543&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, P&#xe9;rez CE, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Importance of the propulsive phase in strength assessment. Int J Sports Med . 2010;31(2):123&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. The 2-point method: a quick, accurate, and repeatable approach to estimate ultrasound-derived quadriceps femoris cross-sectional area. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2022;17(10):1480&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Pectoralis cross-sectional area can be accurately measured using panoramic ultrasound: a validity and repeatability study. Ultrasound Med Biol . 2022;48(3):460&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka NI, Ogawa M, Yoshiko A, Akima H. Validity of extended-field-of-view ultrasound imaging to evaluate quantity and quality of trunk skeletal muscles. Ultrasound Med Biol . 2021;47(3):376&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Morrison M, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Johnston R, James L, Cole MH. The validity and reliability of commercially available resistance training monitoring devices: a systematic review. Sports Med . 2021;51(3):443&#x2013;502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escobar A, Quintana JM, Bilbao A, Azk&#xe1;rate J, G&#xfc;enaga JI. Validation of the Spanish version of the WOMAC questionnaire for patients with hip or knee osteoarthritis. Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Osteoarthritis Index. Clin Rheumatol . 2002;21(6):466&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herv&#xe1;s MT, Navarro Collado MJ, Peir&#xf3; S, Rodrigo P&#xe9;rez JL, L&#xf3;pez Mat&#xe9;u P, Mart&#xed;nez Tello I. Spanish version of the DASH questionnaire. Cross-cultural adaptation, reliability, validity and responsiveness. Med Clin (Barc) . 2006;127(12):441&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV. Distribution theory for Glass&#x2019;s estimator of effect size and related estimators. J Educ Stat . 1981;6(2):107&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Nevill AM. Statistical methods for assessing measurement error (reliability) in variables relevant to sports medicine. Sports Med . 1998;26(4):217&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Longing for a longitudinal proxy: acutely measured surface EMG amplitude is not a validated predictor of muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med . 2022;52(2):193&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Massey GJ, Folland JP. The human muscle size and strength relationship: effects of architecture, muscle force, and measurement location. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(10):2140&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Roberts MD. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol . 2019;10:247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga EM, Pareja-Blanco F. Maximal intended velocity training induces greater gains in bench press performance than deliberately slower half-velocity training. Eur J Sport Sci . 2014;14(8):772&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga EM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on neuromuscular performance. Int J Sports Med . 2014;35(11):916&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: the most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med . 2018;48(3):499&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>