<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">18831752</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Milk: the new sports drink? A Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-5-15</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There has been growing interest in the potential use of bovine milk as an exercise beverage, especially during recovery from resistance training and endurance sports. Based on the limited research, milk appears to be an effective post-resistance exercise beverage that results in favourable acute alterations in protein metabolism. Milk consumption acutely increases muscle protein synthesis, leading to an improved net muscle protein balance. Furthermore, when post-exercise milk consumption is combined with resistance training (12 weeks minimum), greater increases in muscle hypertrophy and lean mass have been observed. Although research with milk is limited, there is some evidence to suggest that milk may be an effective post-exercise beverage for endurance activities. Low-fat milk has been shown to be as effective, if not more effective, than commercially available sports drinks as a rehydration beverage. Milk represents a more nutrient dense beverage choice for individuals who partake in strength and endurance activities, compared to traditional sports drinks. Bovine low-fat fluid milk is a safe and effective post exercise beverage for most individuals, except for those who are lactose intolerant. Further research is warranted to better delineate the possible applications and efficacy of bovine milk in the field of sports nutrition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Brian D</ForeName><Initials>BD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Muscle Metabolism and Biophysics, Faculty of Applied Health Sciences, Brock University, St. Catharines, Ontario, Canada. Brian.Roy@brocku.ca</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2008</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2008</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18831752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2569005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-5-15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-5-15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haug A, Hostmark AT, Harstad OM. Bovine milk in human nutrition &#x2013; a review. Lipids Health Dis. 2007;6:25. doi: 10.1186/1476-511X-6-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-511X-6-25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2039733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17894873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bos C, Metges CC, Gaudichon C, Petzke KJ, Pueyo ME, Morens C, Everwand J, Benamouzig R, Tome D. Postprandial kinetics of dietary amino acids are the main determinant of their metabolism after soy or milk protein ingestion in humans. J Nutr. 2003;133:1308&#x2013;1315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12730415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Duncan ND, Volek JS. Resistance training and elite athletes: adaptations and program considerations. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1998;28:110&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9699161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1997;273:E99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Phillips SM, Doyle DJ, Wolfe RR. Postexercise net protein synthesis in human muscle from orally administered amino acids. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E628&#x2013;E634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Elliott TA, Cree MG, Wolf SE, Sanford AP, Wolfe RR. Ingestion of casein and whey proteins result in muscle anabolism after resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:2073&#x2013;2081. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000147582.99810.C5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000147582.99810.C5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15570142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsheim E, Cree MG, Tipton KD, Elliott TA, Aarsland A, Wolfe RR. Effect of carbohydrate intake on net muscle protein synthesis during recovery from resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2004;96:674&#x2013;678. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00333.2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00333.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14594866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy BD, Tarnopolsky MA, MacDougall JD, Fowles J, Yarasheski KE. Effect of glucose supplement timing on protein metabolism after resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1997;82:1882&#x2013;1888. doi: 10.1063/1.365993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.365993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9173954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy BD, Fowles J, Hill R, Tarnopolsky MA. Macronutrient intake and whole body protein metabolism following resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1412&#x2013;1418. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200008000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200008000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10949007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen BB, Tipton KD, Miller SL, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. An oral essential amino acid-carbohydrate supplement enhances muscle protein anabolism after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:386&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10658002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Rasmussen BB, Miller SL, Wolf SE, Owens-Stovall SK, Petrini BE, Wolfe RR. Timing of amino acid-carbohydrate ingestion alters anabolic response of muscle to resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2001;281:E197&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11440894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliot TA, Cree MG, Sanford AP, Wolfe RR, Tipton KD. Milk ingestion stimulates net muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:667&#x2013;674. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Macdonald MJ, Macdonald JR, Armstrong D, Phillips SM. Consumption of fluid skim milk promotes greater muscle protein accretion after resistance exercise than does consumption of an isonitrogenous and isoenergetic soy-protein beverage. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;85:1031&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17413102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin JW, Goldman LP, Puglisi MJ, Nickols-Richardson SM, Earthman CP, Gwazdauskas FC. Effect of post-exercise supplement consumption on adaptations to resistance training. J Am Coll Nutr. 2004;23:322&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15310736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman JW, Tang JE, Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Lawrence RL, Fullerton AV, Phillips SM. Consumption of fat-free fluid milk after resistance exercise promotes greater lean mass accretion than does consumption of soy or carbohydrate in young, novice, male weightlifters. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;86:373&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemel MB. Role of calcium and dairy products in energy partitioning and weight management. Am J Clin Nutr. 2004;79:907S&#x2013;912S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15113738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SL, Maresh CM, Armstrong LE, Ebbeling CB, Lennon S, Rodriguez NR. Metabolic response to provision of mixed protein-carbohydrate supplementation during endurance exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2002;12:384&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12500983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SL, Gaine PC, Maresh CM, Armstrong LE, Ebbeling CB, Lamont LS, Rodriguez NR. The effects of nutritional supplementation throughout an endurance run on leucine kinetics during recovery. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17:456&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18046055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JK, Maughan RJ, Shirreffs SM, Watson P. Effects of milk ingestion on prolonged exercise capacity in young, healthy men. Nutrition. 2008;24:340&#x2013;347. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2008.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2008.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18328410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh PR, Moran TH. Calories and gastric emptying: a regulatory capacity with implications for feeding. Am J Physiol. 1979;236:R254&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">109014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karp JR, Johnston JD, Tecklenburg S, Mickleborough TD, Fly AD, Stager JM. Chocolate milk as a post-exercise recovery aid. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2006;16:78&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16676705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirreffs SM, Watson P, Maughan RJ. Milk as an effective post-exercise rehydration drink. Br J Nutr. 2007;98:173&#x2013;180. doi: 10.1017/S0007114507695543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114507695543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17459189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Leiper JB, Vist GE. Gastric emptying and fluid availability after ingestion of glucose and soy protein hydrolysate solutions in man. Exp Physiol. 2004;89:101&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1113/expphysiol.2003.002655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2003.002655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15109215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>