<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34054079</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2152-0895</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2022 Jul-Sep 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of geriatric physical therapy (2001)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Geriatr Phys Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Photobiomodulation/Laser Therapy Combined With Resistance Training on Quadriceps Hypertrophy and Strength, and Postural Balance in Older Women: A Randomized, Triple-Blinded, Placebo-Controlled Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>125</StartPage><EndPage>133</EndPage><MedlinePgn>125-133</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000313</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">Physical and therapeutic strategies to maintain and rehabilitate skeletal muscle mass, strength, and postural balance are clinically relevant to improve the health, well-being, and quality of life of older adults. The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of photobiomodulation (PBM)/laser therapy combined with a resistance training (RT) program on quadriceps hypertrophy and strength, and postural balance in older women.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In a randomized, triple-blinded, placebo-controlled design, twenty-two older women (age 66.6 &#xb1; 5.2 years) were engaged in a supervised 10-wk RT program (2 times per week) involving unilateral leg extension exercise, in which each leg of the same participant was randomly assigned to receive active (&#x3bb; = 808 nm, optical output = 100 mW, total energy = 42 J) or placebo laser PBM immediately before the RT sessions. Maximal dynamic strength by unilateral knee extension 1-repetition maximum (1RM), muscle hypertrophy by vastus lateralis muscle thickness, and postural balance by one-legged stance test on a force platform were assessed before and after the training program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Significance statistical analysis revealed a similar improvement (time P = .003) from pre- to posttraining for muscle hypertrophy and strength, and postural balance between active and placebo laser conditions. However, clinical interpretation for muscle hypertrophy showed a moderate effect (effect size [ES] = 0.58) for the active laser and a small effect (ES = 0.38) for the placebo laser. Clinical difference was not noticed between conditions for other analyzed variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">These findings indicate that RT alone can be clinically important for counteracting the deleterious effects of aging on muscle size, strength, and balance, and that applying laser PBM therapy before the RT sessions may further improve gains in muscle hypertrophy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 APTA Geriatrics, An Academy of the American Physical Therapy Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigues</LastName><ForeName>Claudiane Pedro</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacinto</LastName><ForeName>Jeferson Lucas</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roveratti</LastName><ForeName>Mirela Casonato</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merlo</LastName><ForeName>Jeanne Karlette</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soares-Caldeira</LastName><ForeName>L&#xfa;cio Fl&#xe1;vio</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Junior</LastName><ForeName>Eros de Oliveira</ForeName><Initials>EO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguiar</LastName><ForeName>Andreo Fernando</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Research in Health Sciences, Northern University of Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Geriatr Phys Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101142169</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1539-8412</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053685" MajorTopicYN="Y">Laser Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007834" MajorTopicYN="N">Lasers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D028022" MajorTopicYN="Y">Low-Level Light Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34054079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00139143-202207000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li R, Xia J, Zhang XI, et al. Associations of muscle mass and strength with all-cause mortality among US older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(3):458&#x2013;467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metter EJ, Talbot LA, Schrager M, Conwit R. Skeletal muscle strength as a predictor of all-cause mortality in healthy men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57(10):B359&#x2013;B365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Hai S, Liu Y, Liu Y, Dong B. Skeletal muscle mass as a mortality predictor among nonagenarians and centenarians: a prospective cohort study. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):2420. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-38893-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JC, Harhay MO, Harhay MN. Sarcopenia and mortality among a population-based sample of community-dwelling older adults. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2016;7(3):290&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunout D, de la Maza MP, Barrera G, Leiva L, Hirsch S. Association between sarcopenia and mortality in healthy older people. Australas J Ageing. 2011;30(2):89&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung SSY, Reijnierse EM, Pham VK, et al. Sarcopenia and its association with falls and fractures in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2019;10(3):485&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadelha AB, Neri SGR, Oliveira RJ, et al. Severity of sarcopenia is associated with postural balance and risk of falls in community-dwelling older women. Exp Aging Res. 2018;44(3):258&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu IC, Lin CC, Hsiung CA, et al. Epidemiology of sarcopenia among community-dwelling older adults in Taiwan: a pooled analysis for a broader adoption of sarcopenia assessments. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2014;14(suppl 1):52&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Zhang W, Wang C, Tao W, Dou Q, Yang Y. Sarcopenia as a predictor of hospitalization among older people: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2018;18(1):188. doi:10.1186/s12877-018-0878-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2019&#x2013;2052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucci HT, Figueiredo DS, de Paula Carvalho R, et al. Quadriceps femoris performance after resistance training with and without photobiomodulation in elderly women: a randomized clinical trial. Lasers Med Sci. 2019;34(8):1583&#x2013;1594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamblin MR. Mechanisms and applications of the anti-inflammatory effects of photobiomodulation. AIMS Biophys. 2017;4(3):337&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraresi C, Huang YY, Hamblin MR. Photobiomodulation in human muscle tissue: an advantage in sports performance? J Biophotonics. 2016;9(11/12):1273&#x2013;1299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toma RL, Tucci HT, Antunes HK, et al. Effect of 808 nm low-level laser therapy in exercise-induced skeletal muscle fatigue in elderly women. Lasers Med Sci. 2013;28(5):1375&#x2013;1382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toma RL, Oliveira MX, Renno ACM, Laakso EL. Photobiomodulation (PBM) therapy at 904 nm mitigates effects of exercise-induced skeletal muscle fatigue in young women. Lasers Med Sci. 2018;33(6):1197&#x2013;1205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassao PG, Toma RL, Antunes HK, Tucci HT, Renno AC. Effects of photobiomodulation on the fatigue level in elderly women: an isokinetic dynamometry evaluation. Lasers Med Sci. 2016;31(2):275&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal Junior EC, Lopes-Martins RA, Frigo L, et al. Effects of low-level laser therapy (LLLT) in the development of exercise-induced skeletal muscle fatigue and changes in biochemical markers related to postexercise recovery. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2010;40(8):524&#x2013;532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraresi C, Hamblin MR, Parizotto NA. Low-level laser (light) therapy (LLLT) on muscle tissue: performance, fatigue and repair benefited by the power of light. Photonics Lasers Med. 2012;1(4):267&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Almeida P, Lopes-Martins RA, De Marchi T, et al. Red (660 nm) and infrared (830 nm) low-level laser therapy in skeletal muscle fatigue in humans: what is better? Lasers Med Sci. 2012;27(2):453&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanin AA, Verhagen E, Barboza SD, Costa LOP, Leal-Junior ECP. Photobiomodulation therapy for the improvement of muscular performance and reduction of muscular fatigue associated with exercise in healthy people: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lasers Med Sci. 2018;33(1):181&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal-Junior EC, Vanin AA, Miranda EF, de Carvalho Pde T, Dal Corso S, Bjordal JM. Effect of phototherapy (low-level laser therapy and light-emitting diode therapy) on exercise performance and markers of exercise recovery: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Lasers Med Sci. 2015;30(2):925&#x2013;939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toma RL, Vassao PG, Assis L, Antunes HK, Renno AC. Low level laser therapy associated with a strength training program on muscle performance in elderly women: a randomized double blind control study. Lasers Med Sci. 2016;31(6):1219&#x2013;1229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vass&#xe3;o PGTRL, Antunes HKM, Renno ACM Photobiomodulation and physical exercise on strength, balance and functionality of elderly women. Fisioter Mov. 2018;31:e003109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritsch CG, Dornelles MP, Teodoro JL, et al. Effects of photobiomodulation therapy associated with resistance training in elderly men: a randomized double-blinded placebo-controlled trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(1):279&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Martel GF, Ivey FM, et al. Skeletal muscle satellite cell characteristics in young and older men and women after heavy resistance strength training. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2001;56(6):B240&#x2013;B247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson GC, Dhatariya K, Ford GC, et al. Higher muscle protein synthesis in women than men across the lifespan, and failure of androgen administration to amend age-related decrements. FASEB J. 2009;23(2):631&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero D, Madsen K, Meinild-Lundby AK, Edin F, Lundby C. Sexual dimorphism of substrate utilization: differences in skeletal muscle mitochondrial volume density and function. Exp Physiol. 2018;103(6):851&#x2013;859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinale DA, Larsen FJ, Schiffer TA, et al. Superior intrinsic mitochondrial respiration in women than in men. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1133. doi:10.3389/fphys.2018.01133</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pua YH, Ong PH, Clark RA, Matcher DB, Lim EC. Falls efficacy, postural balance, and risk for falls in older adults with falls-related emergency department visits: prospective cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2017;17(1):291. doi:10.1186/s12877-017-0682-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtig-Wennlof A, Hagstromer M, Olsson LA. The International Physical Activity Questionnaire modified for the elderly: aspects of validity and feasibility. Public Health Nutr. 2010;13(11):1847&#x2013;1854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal Junior EC, Lopes-Martins RA, Vanin AA, et al. Effect of 830 nm low-level laser therapy in exercise-induced skeletal muscle fatigue in humans. Lasers Med Sci. 2009;24(3):425&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips WT, Batterham AM, Valenzuela JE, Burkett LN. Reliability of maximal strength testing in older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;85(2):329&#x2013;334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman A, Freeman P, Steel S, Shennan A. Validation of the Omron MX3 Plus oscillometric blood pressure monitoring device according to the European Society of Hypertension international protocol. Blood Press Monit. 2005;10(3):165&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering TG, Hall JE, Appel LJ, et al. Recommendations for blood pressure measurement in humans and experimental animals: part 1: blood pressure measurement in humans: a statement for professionals from the Subcommittee of Professional and Public Education of the American Heart Association Council on High Blood Pressure Research. Hypertension. 2005;45(1):142&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Januario RS, Junior RP, et al. Long-term creatine supplementation improves muscular performance during resistance training in older women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(4):987&#x2013;996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho M, Gentil P, Raiol R, Del Vecchio FB, Ramirez-Campillo R, Coswig VS. High 1RM tests reproducibility and validity are not dependent on training experience, muscle group tested or strength level in older women. Sports (Basel). 2018;6(4):171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijholt W, Scafoglieri A, Jager-Wittenaar H, Hobbelen JSM, van der Schans CP. The reliability and validity of ultrasound to quantify muscles in older adults: a systematic review. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2017;8(5):702&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj IS, Bird SR, Shield AJ. Reliability of ultrasonographic measurement of the architecture of the vastus lateralis and gastrocnemius medialis muscles in older adults. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2012;32(1):65&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikezoe T, Asakawa Y, Tsutou A. The relationship between quadriceps strength and balance to fall of elderly admitted to a nursing home. J Phys Ther Sci. 2003;15(2):75&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes MM, Reis JG, Carvalho RL, Tanaka EH, Hyppolito MA, Abreu DC. Analysis of postural control and muscular performance in young and elderly women in different age groups. Braz J Phys Ther. 2015;19(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott D, Stuart AL, Kay D, Ebeling PR, Nicholson G, Sanders KM. Investigating the predictive ability of gait speed and quadriceps strength for incident falls in community-dwelling older women at high risk of fracture. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2014;58(3):308&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadiahangar A, Javadian Y, Babaei M, Heidari B, Hosseini S, Aminzadeh M. The role of quadriceps muscle strength in the development of falls in the elderly people, a cross-sectional study. Chiropr Man Therap. 2018;26:31. doi:10.1186/s12998-018-0195-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang DJ, Park SK, Uhm YH, Park SH, Chun DW, Kim JH. The correlation between muscle activity of the quadriceps and balance and gait in stroke patients. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28(8):2289&#x2013;2292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Cuthill IC. Effect size, confidence interval and statistical significance: a practical guide for biologists. Biol Rev Camb Philos Soc. 2007;82(4):591&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page P. Beyond statistical significance: clinical interpretation of rehabilitation research literature. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2014;9(5):726&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batterham AM, Hopkins WG. Making meaningful inferences about magnitudes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2006;1(1):50&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson M. Distinguishing between statistical significance and practical/clinical meaningfulness using statistical inference. Sports Med. 2014;44(3):295&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemieux J, Beaton DE, Hogg-Johnson S, Bordeleau LJ, Goodwin PJ. Three methods for minimally important difference: no relationship was found with the net proportion of patients improving. J Clin Epidemiol. 2007;60(5):448&#x2013;455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112(1):155&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraresi C, de Brito Oliveira T, de Oliveira Zafalon L, et al. Effects of low level laser therapy (808 nm) on physical strength training in humans. Lasers Med Sci. 2011;26(3):349&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni BM, Rodrigues R, Freire BB, Franke Rde A, Geremia JM, Vaz MA. Effect of low-level laser therapy on muscle adaptation to knee extensor eccentric training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(3):639&#x2013;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GI, Reeds DN, Hall AM, Chambers KT, Finck BN, Mittendorfer B. Sexually dimorphic effect of aging on skeletal muscle protein synthesis. Biol Sex Differ. 2012;3(1):11. doi:10.1186/2042-6410-3-11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Freitas LF, Hamblin MR. Proposed mechanisms of photobiomodulation or low-level light therapy. IEEE J Sel Top Quantum Electron. 2016;22(3):7000417. doi:10.1109/JSTQE.2016.2561201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefer G, Partridge TA, Heslop L, Gross JG, Oron U, Halevy O. Low-energy laser irradiation promotes the survival and cell cycle entry of skeletal muscle satellite cells. J Cell Sci. 2002;115(pt 7):1461&#x2013;1469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakano J, Kataoka H, Sakamoto J, Origuchi T, Okita M, Yoshimura T. Low-level laser irradiation promotes the recovery of atrophied gastrocnemius skeletal muscle in rats. Exp Physiol. 2009;94(9):1005&#x2013;1015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansai JH, Aurichio TR, Goncalves R, Rebelatto JR. Effects of two physical exercise protocols on physical performance related to falls in the oldest old: a randomized controlled trial. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2016;16(4):492&#x2013;499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Mangine GT, Fragala MS, et al. Resistance training improves single leg stance performance in older adults. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2014;26(1):89&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa HB, Ferraresi JR, Prata MG, Scheicher ME. Postural balance and functional independence of elderly people according to gender and age: cross-sectional study. Sao Paulo Med J. 2017;135(3):260&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>