<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40289456</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Mar-Apr</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High-Load Strength Training Reduces Injury Incidence and Injury Burden and Improves Physical Fitness in Young Highly Trained Soccer Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>269</StartPage><EndPage>278</EndPage><MedlinePgn>269-278</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19417381251333417</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19417381251333417</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">There is little available information on the reduction of injury incidence and injury burden after strength training programs. This study aimed to analyze the effects of a 12-week high-load strength training program on injury incidence, injury burden, and fitness in young, highly trained, soccer players.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">It was hypothesized that well-targeted high-load training focused on the gluteal and hamstring musculature could aid in injury prevention and increase physical fitness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A randomized controlled trial design was applied, which followed the CONSORT Statement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level 2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty players were assigned randomly to the experimental group (EG, n = 10 players), who performed a high-load strength training program, or to the control group (CG, n = 10 players), who performed only their usual soccer training. Injury incidence (injuries per 1000 hours exposure) and injury burden (days of absence per 1000 hours exposure) were recorded during the intervention, as well as the physical fitness attributes before and after the training program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A significant (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05) lower injury incidence was observed in the EG (CG, 11.34 vs EG, 1.31 injuries per 1000 hours of exposure) and a significant (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001) lower injury burden in the EG (CG, 304.66 versus EG, 19.72 days of absence per 1000 h of exposure). The analysis of covariance model revealed significant between-group differences favoring the EG, showing significantly greater improvements in jumping, change of direction ability, sprinting, and imbalance strength tests (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001; effect size, 3.02 to -7.23).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrated the beneficial effects of a 12-week high-load strength training program on injury incidence, injury burden and physical fitness, in highly trained soccer players.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study provides positive information for implementing this type of strength training in the daily training sessions of young soccer players for both performance enhancement and injury prevention.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dur&#xe1;n-Custodio</LastName><ForeName>Roberto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education and Sport, University of the Basque Country (UPV/EHU), Vitoria-Gasteiz, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yanci</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Society, Sports and Physical Exercise Research Group (GIKAFIT), Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Education and Sport, University of the Basque Country (UPV/EHU), Vitoria-Gasteiz, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez</LastName><ForeName>Javier</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Grupo de Investigaci&#xf3;n en deporte y educaci&#xf3;n f&#xed;sica para el desarrollo personal y social (GIDEPSO), Department of Specific Didactics, Faculty of Education Sciences and Psychology, University of C&#xf3;rdoba, C&#xf3;rdoba, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beato</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Allied Health Sciences, University of Suffolk, Ipswich, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4159-6475</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Valoraci&#xf3;n del Rendimiento Deportivo, Actividad F&#xed;sica y Salud, y Lesiones Deportivas (REDAFLED) Research Group, Faculty of Education, University of Valladolid, Soria, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012916" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soccer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">football</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injury severity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no potential conflicts of interest in the development and publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40289456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12037537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381251333417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aguilera-Castells J, Busc&#xe0; B, Morales J, Solana-Tramunt M, et al. Muscle activity of Bulgarian squat. Effects of additional vibration, suspension and unstable surface. PLoS One. 2019;14(8):e0221710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6709890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31449568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen V, Fimland M, Cumming K, Vraalsen &#xd8;, Saeterbakken A. Explosive resistance training using elastic bands in young female team handball players. Sports Med Int Open. 2018;2(6):E171-E178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6280676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30539135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahr R, Clarsen B, Ekstrand J. Why we should focus on the burden of injuries and illnesses, not just their incidence. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(16):1018-1021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29021247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldjian A, Mohrenberger H, Ciladi M. Estudio epidemiol&#xf3;gico de lesiones en un equipo profesional de f&#xfa;tbol en Argentina. Arg J Resp Phys. 2022;4(3):23-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barjaste A, Mirzaei B. The periodization of resistance training in soccer players: changes in maximal strength, lower extremity power, body composition and muscle volume. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2018;58(9):1218-1225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28229570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M. Recommendations for the design of randomized controlled trials in strength and conditioning. Common design and data interpretation. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:981836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9493045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Maroto-Izquierdo S, Turner A, Bishop C. Implementing strength training strategies for injury prevention in soccer: scientific rationale and methodological recommendations. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16(3):456-461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33503589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103(5):1565-1575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17717119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Gill ND, Bronks R, Newton RU. Training-specific muscle architecture adaptation after 5-wk training in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(12):2013-2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14652496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Sharp NCC. Understanding muscle architectural adaptation: macro- and micro-level research. Cells Tissues Organs. 2005;181(1):1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16439814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Luhtanen P, Komi PV. A simple method for measurement of mechanical power in jumping. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1983;50(2):273-282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6681758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgeois F, McGuigan M, Gill N, Gamble P. Physical characteristics and performance in change of direction tasks: a brief review and training considerations. J Aust Strength Cond. 2017;25(5):104-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brughelli M, Cronin J, Levin G, Chaouachi A. Understanding change of direction ability in sport: a review of resistance training studies. Sports Med. 2008;38(12):1045-1063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo D, Lago-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Dom&#xed;nguez-D&#xed;ez M. Relationships between players&#x2019; physical performance and small-sided game external responses in a youth soccer training context. Sustainability. 2020;12(11):4482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates: Hillsdale, NJ; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Hoyo M, Gonzalo-Skok O, Sa&#xf1;udo B, et al. Comparative effects of in-season full-back squat, resisted sprint training, and plyometric training on explosive performance in U-19 elite soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(2):368-377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26813630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado J, Drinkwater EJ, Banyard HG, Haff GG, Nosaka K. Comparison between back squat, Romanian deadlift, and barbell hip thrust for leg and hip muscle activities during hip extension. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(10):2595-2601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31356511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dur&#xe1;n-Custodio R, Castillo D, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Yanci J. Is a maximal strength-training program effective on physical fitness, injury incidence, and injury burden in semi-professional soccer players? A randomized controlled trial. Healthcare (Basel). 2023;11(24):3195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10742471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38132085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J, H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M. Injury incidence and injury patterns in professional football: the UEFA injury study. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45(7):553-558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19553225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emamvirdi M, Letafatkar A, Khaleghi Tazji M. The effect of valgus control instruction exercises on pain, strength, and functionality in active females with patellofemoral pain syndrome. Sports Health. 2019;11(3):223-237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franettovich S, Bonacci J, Mendis MD, Christie C, Rotstein A, Hides JA. Gluteus medius activation during running is a risk factor for season hamstring injuries in elite footballers. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(2):159-163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27526636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ, Domrow N. Relationships between training load, injury, and fitness in sub-elite collision sport athletes. J Sports Sci. 2007;25(13):1507-1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17852696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Montesinos JL, D&#xed;az N, Garc&#xed;a L, Mora J, Castro J, Silva M. Jumping ability and elasticity index in primary education. Rev Int Med Cienc Act F&#xed;s Deporte. 2007;7(28):359-373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths B, Grant J, Langdown L, Gentil P, Fisher J, Steele J. The effect of in-season traditional and explosive resistance training programs on strength, jump height, and speed in recreational soccer players. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2019;90(1):95-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30707090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M, Ekstrand J. Injury incidence and distribution in elite football&#x2014;a prospective study of the Danish and the Swedish top divisions. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2005;15(1):21-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15679568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M, Magnusson H, Kristenson K, Bengtsson H, Ekstrand J. Injuries affect team performance negatively in professional football: an 11-year follow-up of the UEFA Champions League injury study. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(12):738-742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23645832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heick JD, Talkington M, Jain T. Electromyographic analysis of gluteal recruitment: an exploration of activation during jumping tasks. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15(6):1019-1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, McCall A, Meyer T, van Smeden M. Measures of (injury and illness) occurrence: a primer on epidemiological concepts and terminology for authors. Sci Med Footb. 2022;6(2):137-140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35378046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Rampinini E, Maffiuletti N, Marcora SM. A vertical jump force test for assessing bilateral strength asymmetry in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(11):2044-2050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17986914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf6;nhagen S, Ackermann P, Saartok T. Forward lunge: a training study of eccentric exercises of the lower limbs. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(3):972-978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19387378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkwood BR. and SJA. Essential Medical Statistics. 2nd ed. Oxford: Blackwell Science; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Gall F, Carling C, Williams M, Reilly T. (2010). Anthropometric and fitness characteristics of international, professional and amateur male graduate soccer players from an elite youth academy. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(1):90-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18835220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Valenciano A, Ruiz-P&#xe9;rez I, Garcia-G&#xf3;mez A. Epidemiology of injuries in professional football: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(12):711-718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9929604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31171515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell R, Siegler JC, Knox M, Brennan S, Marshall PW. Acute neuromuscular and performance responses to Nordic hamstring exercises completed before or after football training. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(24):2286-2294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig O, Kelm J. Groin pain and muscular imbalance of quadriceps and hamstrings in an elite Soccer Player - a case study. Sportverletz Sportschaden. 2016;30(3):163-167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27490356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcote-Peque&#xf1;o R, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Cuadrado-Pe&#xf1;afiel V, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, G&#xf3;mez M&#xc1;, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P. Association between the force-velocity profile and performance variables obtained in jumping and sprinting in elite female soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(2):209-215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30040003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PWM, Lovell R, Knox MF, Brennan SL, Siegler JC. Hamstring fatigue and muscle activation changes during six sets of Nordic hamstring exercise in amateur soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(11):3124-3133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25886019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascarin NC, de Lira CA, Vancini RL, da Silva AC, Andrade MS. The effects of preventive rubber band training on shoulder joint imbalance and throwing performance in handball players: a randomized and prospective study. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2017;21(4):1017-1023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29037617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiguchia J, Edouard P, Samozino P, et al. Field monitoring of sprinting power-force-velocity profile before, during and after hamstring injury: two case reports. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(6):535-541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26648237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor B, Simmons J, O&#x2019;Shea P. Weight Training Today. St. Paul, MN: West Publishing, 1989:201-204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen AL, Wong del P, Dellal A, Paul DJ, Orhant E, Collie S. Effect of an injury prevention program on muscle injuries in elite professional soccer. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(12):3275-3285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23524368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owoeye OB, Aiyegbusi AI, Fapojuwo OA, Badru OA, Babalola AR. Injuries in male and female semi-professional football (soccer) players in Nigeria: prospective study of a National Tournament. BMC Res Notes. 2017;10(1):133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5361784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28327163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ, McMahon J. Lower limb mechanical properties: determining factors and implications for performance. Sports Med. 2012;42(11):929-940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23009192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;ailillo L, Esp&#xed;ldora F, Jannas-Vela S, Mujika I, Zbinden-Foncea H. Muscle strength and speed performance in youth soccer players. J Hum Kinet. 2016;50(1):203-210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5260655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28149358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotkin D, Coleman M, Van Every D, et al. Progressive overload without progressing load? The effects of load or repetition progression on muscular adaptations. PeerJ. 2022;10:e14142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9528903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36199287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. Strength training for injury prevention in Soccer: a systematic review. J Physical Educ Sports. 2017;49:23-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Torres Martin L, Beato M, Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez A, Sanchez-Sanchez J. The effects of training based on Nordic hamstring and sprint exercises on measures of physical fitness and hamstring injury prevention in U19 male soccer players. Res Sports Med. 2023;31(5):588-603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34841995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Franco N, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Monta&#xf1;o-Munuera JA. Validity and reliability of a low-cost digital dynamometer for measuring isometric strength of lower limb. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(22):2179-2184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez J, Torres Mart&#xed;n L, Ramirez-Campillo R, Castillo D, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. The effects of jump training on measures of physical performance, lower extremities injury incidence and burden in highly trained male soccer players. Res Sports Med. 2022;32(1):107-121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35616245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D. Open access correspondence BioMed central CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMC Med. 2010;8:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2860339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20334633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semmler JG. Motor unit synchronization and neuromuscular performance. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2002;30(1):8-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11800501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard J, Young W. Agility literature review: classifications, training and testing. J Sports Sci. 2006;24(9):919-932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16882626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvers-Granelli HJ, Bizzini M, Arundale A, Mandelbaum BR, Snyder-Mackler L. Does the FIFA 11+ injury prevention program reduce the incidence of ACL injury in male soccer players? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2017;475(10):2447-2455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28389864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer M, Pyne D, Santisteban J, Mujika I. Fitness determinants of repeated-sprint ability in highly trained youth football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2011;6(4):497-508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21937759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Filopoulos D, Nguyen V, et al. Sprinting, strength, and architectural adaptations following hamstring training in Australian footballers. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31(6):1276-1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33617061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trecroci A, Duca M, Formenti D, Alberti G, Marcello Iaia F, Longo S. Short-term compound training on physical performance in young soccer players. Sports. 2020;8(8):108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32751640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, Trezise J, Haff GG, Newton RU, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Blazevich AJ. Increased fascicle length but not patellar tendon stiffness after accentuated eccentric-load strength training in already-trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120(11):2371-2382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7560914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young WB, James R, Montgomery I. Is muscle power related to running speed with changes of direction? J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2002;42(3):282-288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12094116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>