<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29875682</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2018</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Anabolic Heterogeneity Following Resistance Training: A Role for Circadian Rhythm?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>569</StartPage><MedlinePgn>569</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">569</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2018.00569</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It is now well established that resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis and promotes gains in muscle mass and strength. However, considerable variability exists following standardized resistance training programs in the magnitude of muscle cross-sectional area and strength responses from one individual to another. Several studies have recently posited that alterations in satellite cell population, myogenic gene expression and microRNAs may contribute to individual variability in anabolic adaptation. One emerging factor that may also explain the variability in responses to resistance exercise is circadian rhythms and underlying molecular clock signals. The molecular clock is found in most cells within the body, including skeletal muscle, and principally functions to optimize the timing of specific cellular events around a 24 h cycle. Accumulating evidence investigating the skeletal muscle molecular clock indicates that exercise-induced contraction and its timing may regulate gene expression and protein synthesis responses which, over time, can influence and modulate key physiological responses such as muscle hypertrophy and increased strength. Therefore, the circadian clock may play a key role in the heterogeneous anabolic responses with resistance exercise. The central aim of this Hypothesis and Theory is to discuss and propose the potential interplay between the circadian molecular clock and established molecular mechanisms mediating muscle anabolic responses with resistance training. This article begins with a current review of the mechanisms associated with the heterogeneity in muscle anabolism with resistance training before introducing the molecular pathways regulating circadian function in skeletal muscle. Recent work showing members of the core molecular clock system can regulate myogenic and translational signaling pathways is also discussed, forming the basis for a possible role of the circadian clock in the variable anabolic responses with resistance exercise.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Camera</LastName><ForeName>Donny M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Nutrition Research Program, Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise adaptation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular clock</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle growth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">responder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29875682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.00569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abraham U., Granada A. E., Westermark P. O., Heine M., Kramer A., Herzel H. (2010). Coupling governs entrainment range of circadian clocks. Mol. Syst. Biol. 6:438. 10.1038/msb.2010.92</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/msb.2010.92</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3010105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21119632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen J. P., Pakarinen A., Alen M., Kraemer W. J., H&#xe4;kkinen K. (2003). Muscle hypertrophy, hormonal adaptations and strength development during strength training in strength-trained and untrained men. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 89, 555&#x2013;563. 10.1007/s00421-003-0833-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-003-0833-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akashi M., Tsuchiya Y., Yoshino T., Nishida E. (2002). Control of intracellular dynamics of mammalian period proteins by casein kinase I epsilon (CKIepsilon) and CKIdelta in cultured cells. Mol. Cell. Biol. 22, 1693&#x2013;1703. 10.1128/MCB.22.6.1693-1703.2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/MCB.22.6.1693-1703.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC135601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11865049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews J. L., Zhang X., McCarthy J. J., McDearmon E. L., Hornberger T. A., Russell B., et al. (2010). CLOCK and BMAL1 regulate MyoD and are necessary for maintenance of skeletal muscle phenotype and function. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 107, 19090&#x2013;19095. 10.1073/pnas.1014523107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1014523107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2973897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auclair D., Garrel D. R., Chaouki Zerouala A., Ferland L. H. (1997). Activation of the ubiquitin pathway in rat skeletal muscle by catabolic doses of glucocorticoids. Am. J. Phys. 272(3 Pt 1), C1007&#x2013;C1016. 10.1152/ajpcell.1997.272.3.C1007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1997.272.3.C1007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9124503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman M. M., Petrella J. K., Kim J. S., Mayhew D. L., Cross J. M. (2007). Cluster analysis tests the importance of myogenic gene expression during myofiber hypertrophy in humans. J. Appl. Physiol. 102, 2232&#x2013;2239. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00024.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00024.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17395765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman M. M., Roberts B. M., Adams G. R. (2017). Molecular regulation of exercise-induced muscle fiber hypertrophy. Cold Spring Harb. Perspect. Med. a029751. 10.1101/cshperspect.a029751. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a029751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barger L. K., Wright K. P., Jr., Hughes R. J., Czeisler C. A. (2004). Daily exercise facilitates phase delays of circadian melatonin rhythm in very dim light. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 286, R1077&#x2013;R1084. 10.1152/ajpregu.00397.2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00397.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15031136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass J., Takahashi J. S. (2010). Circadian integration of metabolism and energetics. Science 330, 1349&#x2013;1354. 10.1126/science.1195027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1195027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3756146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21127246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito M., Valverde A. M., Lorenzo M. (1996). IGF-I: a mitogen also involved in differentiation processes in mammalian cells. Int. J. Biochem. Cell Biol. 28, 499&#x2013;510. 10.1016/1357-2725(95)00168-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/1357-2725(95)00168-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8697095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird S. P., Tarpenning K. M. (2004). Influence of circadian time structure on acute hormonal responses to a single bout of heavy-resistance exercise in weight-trained men. Chronobiol. Int. 21, 131&#x2013;146. 10.1081/CBI-120027987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1081/CBI-120027987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15129828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine S. C., Stitt T. N., Gonzalez M., Kline W. O., Stover G. L., Bauerlein R., et al. (2001). Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy <i>in vivo</i>. Nat. Cell Biol.
3, 1014&#x2013;1019. 10.1038/ncb1101-1014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncb1101-1014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth F. W., Laye M. J. (2010). The future: genes, physical activity and health. Acta Physiol. 199, 549&#x2013;556. 10.1111/j.1748-1716.2010.02117.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.2010.02117.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20345416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C., An P., Rice T., Skinner J. S., Wilmore J. H., Gagnon J., et al. (1999). Familial aggregation of VO(2max) response to exercise training: results from the HERITAGE Family Study. J. Appl. Physiol. 87, 1003&#x2013;1008. 10.1152/jappl.1999.87.3.1003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1999.87.3.1003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10484570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C., Sarzynski M. A., Rice T. K., Kraus W. E., Church T. S., Sung Y. J., et al. (2011). Genomic predictors of the maximal O(2) uptake response to standardized exercise training programs. J. Appl. Physiol. 110, 1160&#x2013;1170. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00973.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00973.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3098655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21183627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozek K., Rel&#xf3;gio A., Kielbasa S. M., Heine M., Dame C., Kramer A., et al. (2009). Regulation of clock-controlled genes in mammals. PLoS ONE 4:e4882. 10.1371/journal.pone.0004882</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0004882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19287494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray M. S., Ratcliffe W. F., Grenett M. H., Brewer R. A., Gamble K. L., Young M. E. (2013). Quantitative analysis of light-phase restricted feeding reveals metabolic dyssynchrony in mice. Int. J. Obes. 37, 843&#x2013;852. 10.1038/ijo.2012.137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2012.137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3505273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22907695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown S. A., Zumbrunn G., Fleury-Olela F., Preitner N., Schibler U. (2002). Rhythms of mammalian body temperature can sustain peripheral circadian clocks. Curr. Biol. 12, 1574&#x2013;1583. 10.1016/S0960-9822(02)01145-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0960-9822(02)01145-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunger M. K., Wilsbacher L. D., Moran S. M., Clendenin C., Radcliffe L. A., Hogenesch J. B., et al. (2000). Mop3 is an essential component of the master circadian pacemaker in mammals. Cell 103, 1009&#x2013;1017. 10.1016/S0092-8674(00)00205-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0092-8674(00)00205-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11163178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burley S. D., Whittingham-Dowd J., Allen J., Grosset J. F., Onambele-Pearson G. L. (2016). The differential hormonal milieu of morning versus evening may have an impact on muscle hypertrophic potential. PLoS ONE 11:e0161500. 10.1371/journal.pone.0161500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0161500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5008805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27583459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busino L., Bassermann F., Maiolica A., Lee C., Nolan P. M., Godinho S. I., et al. (2007). SCFFbxl3 controls the oscillation of the circadian clock by directing the degradation of cryptochrome proteins. Science 316, 900&#x2013;904. 10.1126/science.1141194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1141194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17463251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buxton O. M., Lee C. W., L'Hermite-Baleriaux M., Turek F. W., Van Cauter E. (2003). Exercise elicits phase shifts and acute alterations of melatonin that vary with circadian phase. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 284, R714&#x2013;R724. 10.1152/ajpregu.00355.2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00355.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12571075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera D. M., Burniston J. G., Pogson M. A., Smiles W. J., Hawley J. A. (2017). Dynamic proteome profiling of individual proteins in human skeletal muscle after a high-fat diet and resistance exercise. FASEB J. 31, 5478&#x2013;5494. 10.1096/fj.201700531R</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.201700531R</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28855275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera D. M., Edge J., Short M. J., Hawley J. A., Coffey V. G. (2010). Early time course of Akt phosphorylation after endurance and resistance exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 42, 1843&#x2013;1852. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181d964e4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181d964e4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera D. M., Smiles W. J., Hawley J. A. (2016). Exercise-induced skeletal muscle signaling pathways and human athletic performance. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 98, 131&#x2013;143. 10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2016.02.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2016.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26876650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera D. M., West D. W., Burd N. A., Phillips S. M., Garnham A. P., Hawley J. A., et al. (2012). Low muscle glycogen concentration does not suppress the anabolic response to resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 113, 206&#x2013;214. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00395.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00395.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22628371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee S., Ma K. (2016). Circadian clock regulation of skeletal muscle growth and repair. F1000Res 5:1549. 10.12688/f1000research.9076.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.9076.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4965692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27540471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee S., Nam D., Guo B., Kim J. M., Winnier G. E., Lee J., et al. (2013). Brain and muscle Arnt-like 1 is a key regulator of myogenesis. J. Cell Sci. 126(Pt 10), 2213&#x2013;2224. 10.1242/jcs.120519</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jcs.120519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3672937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23525013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H., Souissi N. (2012). The effect of training at a specific time of day: a review. J. Strength Cond. Res. 26, 1984&#x2013;2005. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825770a7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825770a7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22531613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne T. A., Tieland M., Verdijk L. B., Leenders M., Dirks M. L., de Groot L. C., et al. (2015). There are no nonresponders to resistance-type exercise training in older men and women. J. Am. Med. Dir. Assoc. 16, 400&#x2013;411. 10.1016/j.jamda.2015.01.071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2015.01.071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25717010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemmons D. R. (2009). Role of IGF-I in skeletal muscle mass maintenance. Trends Endocrinol. Metab. 20, 349&#x2013;356. 10.1016/j.tem.2009.04.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2009.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19729319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey V. G., Zhong Z., Shield A., Canny B. J., Chibalin A. V., Zierath J. R., et al. (2006). Early signaling responses to divergent exercise stimuli in skeletal muscle from well-trained humans. FASEB J. 20, 190&#x2013;192. 10.1096/fj.05-4809fje</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.05-4809fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16267123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damiola F., Le Minh N., Preitner N., Kornmann B., Fleury-Olela F., Schibler U. (2000). Restricted feeding uncouples circadian oscillators in peripheral tissues from the central pacemaker in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Genes Dev. 14, 2950&#x2013;2961. 10.1101/gad.183500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gad.183500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC317100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11114885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattilo M., Antunes H. K., Medeiros A., M&#xf4;nico Neto M., Souza H. S., Tufik S., et al. (2011). Sleep and muscle recovery: endocrinological and molecular basis for a new and promising hypothesis. Med. Hypotheses 77, 220&#x2013;222. 10.1016/j.mehy.2011.04.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2011.04.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21550729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidsen P. K., Gallagher I. J., Hartman J. W., Tarnopolsky M. A., Dela F., Helge J. W., et al. (2011). High responders to resistance exercise training demonstrate differential regulation of skeletal muscle microRNA expression. J. Appl. Physiol. 110, 309&#x2013;317. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00901.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00901.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21030674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer H. C., Fujita S., Cadenas J. G., Chinkes D. L., Volpi E., Rasmussen B. B. (2006). Resistance exercise increases AMPK activity and reduces 4E-BP1 phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle. J. Physiol. 576(Pt 2), 613&#x2013;624. 10.1113/jphysiol.2006.113175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2006.113175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1890364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyar K. A., Ciciliot S., Tagliazucchi G. M., Pallafacchina G., Tothova J., Argentini C., et al. (2015). The calcineurin-NFAT pathway controls activity-dependent circadian gene expression in slow skeletal muscle. Mol. Metab. 4, 823&#x2013;833. 10.1016/j.molmet.2015.09.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmet.2015.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4632177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26629406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyar K. A., Ciciliot S., Wright L. E., Bienso R. S., Tagliazucchi G. M., Patel V. R., et al. (2014). Muscle insulin sensitivity and glucose metabolism are controlled by the intrinsic muscle clock. Mol. Metab. 3, 29&#x2013;41. 10.1016/j.molmet.2013.10.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmet.2013.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3929910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24567902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eide E. J., Woolf M. F., Kang H., Woolf P., Hurst W., Camacho F., et al. (2005). Control of mammalian circadian rhythm by CKIepsilon-regulated proteasome-mediated PER2 degradation. Mol. Cell. Biol. 25, 2795&#x2013;2807. 10.1128/MCB.25.7.2795-2807.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/MCB.25.7.2795-2807.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1061645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15767683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facer-Childs E., Brandstaetter R. (2015). The impact of circadian phenotype and time since awakening on diurnal performance in athletes. Curr. Biol. 25, 518&#x2013;522. 10.1016/j.cub.2014.12.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cub.2014.12.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25639241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feillet C. A., Albrecht U., Challet E. (2006). &#x201c;Feeding time&#x201d; for the brain: a matter of clocks. J. Physiol. Paris 100, 252&#x2013;260. 10.1016/j.jphysparis.2007.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphysparis.2007.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17629684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gekakis N., Staknis D., Nguyen H. B., Davis F. C., Wilsbacher L. D., King D. P., et al. (1998). Role of the CLOCK protein in the mammalian circadian mechanism. Science 280, 1564&#x2013;1569. 10.1126/science.280.5369.1564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.280.5369.1564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9616112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golombek D. A., Rosenstein R. E. (2010). Physiology of circadian entrainment. Physiol. Rev. 90, 1063&#x2013;1102. 10.1152/physrev.00009.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00009.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harfmann B. D., Schroder E. A., Esser K. A. (2015). Circadian rhythms, the molecular clock, and skeletal muscle. J. Biol. Rhythms 30, 84&#x2013;94. 10.1177/0748730414561638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0748730414561638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25512305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman J. W., Tang J. E., Wilkinson S. B., Tarnopolsky M. A., Lawrence R. L., Fullerton A. V., et al. (2007). Consumption of fat-free fluid milk after resistance exercise promotes greater lean mass accretion than does consumption of soy or carbohydrate in young, novice, male weightlifters. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 86, 373&#x2013;381. 10.1093/ajcn/86.2.373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/86.2.373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley J. A., Hargreaves M., Joyner M. J., Zierath J. R. (2014). Integrative biology of exercise. Cell 159, 738&#x2013;749. 10.1016/j.cell.2014.10.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2014.10.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25417152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes L. D., Bickerstaff G. F., Baker J. S. (2010). Interactions of cortisol, testosterone, and resistance training: influence of circadian rhythms. Chronobiol. Int. 27, 675&#x2013;705. 10.3109/07420521003778773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/07420521003778773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20560706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L., Hannon G. J. (2004). MicroRNAs: small RNAs with a big role in gene regulation. Nat. Rev. Genet. 5, 522&#x2013;531. 10.1038/nrg1379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrg1379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15211354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodge B. A., Wen Y., Riley L. A., Zhang X., England J. H., Harfmann B. D., et al. (2015). The endogenous molecular clock orchestrates the temporal separation of substrate metabolism in skeletal muscle. Skelet. Muscle 5:17. 10.1186/s13395-015-0039-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13395-015-0039-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4440511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26000164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogenesch J. B., Gu Y. Z., Jain S., Bradfield C. A. (1998). The basic-helix-loop-helix-PAS orphan MOP3 forms transcriptionally active complexes with circadian and hypoxia factors. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 95, 5474&#x2013;5479. 10.1073/pnas.95.10.5474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.95.10.5474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC20401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9576906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal M. J., Gordish-Dressman H., Thompson P. D., Price T. B., Hoffman E. P., Angelopoulos T. J., et al. (2005). Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 37, 964&#x2013;972. 10.1249/01.mss.0000170469.90461.5f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000170469.90461.5f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idda M. L., Bertolucci C., Vallone D., Gothilf Y., S&#xe1;nchez-V&#xe1;zquez F. J., Foulkes N. S. (2012). Circadian clocks: lessons from fish. Prog. Brain Res. 199, 41&#x2013;57. 10.1016/B978-0-444-59427-3.00003-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-444-59427-3.00003-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22877658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman R. W., Kandarian S. C. (2004). The molecular basis of skeletal muscle atrophy. Am. J. Physiol,. Cell Physiol. 287, C834&#x2013;C843. 10.1152/ajpcell.00579.2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00579.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15355854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefta M., Wolff G., Esser K. A. (2011). Circadian rhythms, the molecular clock, and skeletal muscle. Curr. Top. Dev. Biol. 96, 231&#x2013;271. 10.1016/B978-0-12-385940-2.00009-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-385940-2.00009-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4545213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipton J. O., Yuan E. D., Boyle L. M., Ebrahimi-Fakhari D., Kwiatkowski E., Nathan A., et al. (2015). The circadian protein BMAL1 regulates translation in response to S6K1-mediated phosphorylation. Cell 161, 1138&#x2013;1151. 10.1016/j.cell.2015.04.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2015.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4447213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25981667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lortie G., Simoneau J. A., Hamel P., Boulay M. R., Landry F., Bouchard C. (1984). Responses of maximal aerobic power and capacity to aerobic training. Int. J. Sports Med. 5, 232&#x2013;236. 10.1055/s-2008-1025911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1025911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6500788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loudon A. S. (2012). Circadian biology: a 2.5 billion year old clock. Curr. Biol. 22, R570&#x2013;R571. 10.1016/j.cub.2012.06.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cub.2012.06.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22835791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew D. L., Hornberger T. A., Lincoln H. C., Bamman M. M. (2011). Eukaryotic initiation factor 2B epsilon induces cap-dependent translation and skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J. Physiol. 589(Pt 12), 3023&#x2013;3037. 10.1113/jphysiol.2010.202432</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2010.202432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3139084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21486778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy J. J., Andrews J. L., McDearmon E. L., Campbell K. S., Barber B. K., Miller B. H., et al. (2007). Identification of the circadian transcriptome in adult mouse skeletal muscle. Physiol. Genomics 31, 86&#x2013;95. 10.1152/physiolgenomics.00066.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiolgenomics.00066.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6080860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17550994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B. H., McDearmon E. L., Panda S., Hayes K. R., Zhang J., Andrews J. L., et al. (2007). Circadian and CLOCK-controlled regulation of the mouse transcriptome and cell proliferation. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 104, 3342&#x2013;3347. 10.1073/pnas.0611724104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0611724104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1802006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17360649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell C. J., Churchward-Venne T. A., Bellamy L., Parise G., Baker S. K., Phillips S. M. (2013). Muscular and systemic correlates of resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. PLoS ONE 8:e78636. 10.1371/journal.pone.0078636</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0078636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3793973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24130904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell C. J., Churchward-Venne T. A., West D. W., Burd N. A., Breen L., Baker S. K., et al. (2012). Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J. Appl. Physiol. 113, 71&#x2013;77. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki T., Hashimoto S., Masubuchi S., Honma S., Honma K. I. (2001). Phase-advance shifts of human circadian pacemaker are accelerated by daytime physical exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 281, R197&#x2013;R205. 10.1152/ajpregu.2001.281.1.R197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.2001.281.1.R197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11404294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero D., Lundby C. (2017). Refuting the myth of non-response to exercise training: &#x2018;non-responders&#x2019; do respond to higher dose of training. J. Physiol. 595, 3377&#x2013;3387. 10.1113/JP273480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP273480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5451738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28133739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy B. A., Wagner A. L., McGlynn O. F., Kharazyan F., Browne J. A., Elliott J. A. (2014). Exercise influences circadian gene expression in equine skeletal muscle. Vet. J. 201, 39&#x2013;45. 10.1016/j.tvjl.2014.03.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tvjl.2014.03.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24888677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R., Akimoto T., Umeno T., Sawada S., Hamaoka T., Fujita S. (2016). MicroRNA expression profiling in skeletal muscle reveals different regulatory patterns in high and low responders to resistance training. Physiol. Genomics 48, 320&#x2013;324. 10.1152/physiolgenomics.00124.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiolgenomics.00124.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26850043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen B. K., Febbraio M. A. (2012). Muscles, exercise and obesity: skeletal muscle as a secretory organ. Nat. Rev. Endocrinol. 8, 457&#x2013;465. 10.1038/nrendo.2012.49</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrendo.2012.49</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22473333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peek C. B., Affinati A. H., Ramsey K. M., Kuo H. Y., Yu W., Sena L. A., et al. (2013). Circadian clock NAD+ cycle drives mitochondrial oxidative metabolism in mice. Science 342:1243417. 10.1126/science.1243417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1243417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24051248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrin L., Loizides-Mangold U., Skarupelova S., Pulimeno P., Chanon S., Robert M., et al. (2015). Human skeletal myotubes display a cell-autonomous circadian clock implicated in basal myokine secretion. Mol. Metab. 4, 834&#x2013;845. 10.1016/j.molmet.2015.07.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmet.2015.07.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4632112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26629407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson M. D., Rhea M. R., Sen A., Gordon P. M. (2010). Resistance exercise for muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Ageing Res. Rev. 9, 226&#x2013;237. 10.1016/j.arr.2010.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2010.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2892859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20385254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella J. K., Kim J. S., Mayhew D. L., Cross J. M., Bamman M. M. (2008). Potent myofiber hypertrophy during resistance training in humans is associated with satellite cell-mediated myonuclear addition: a cluster analysis. J. Appl. Physiol. 104, 1736&#x2013;1742. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01215.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01215.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips B. E., Williams J. P., Gustafsson T., Bouchard C., Rankinen T., Knudsen S., et al. (2013). Molecular networks of human muscle adaptation to exercise and age. PLoS Genet. 9:e1003389. 10.1371/annotation/0dd3671e-1460-48fa-9d6a-2865dce78c07</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/annotation/0dd3671e-1460-48fa-9d6a-2865dce78c07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23555298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Hartman J. W., Wilkinson S. B. (2005). Dietary protein to support anabolism with resistance exercise in young men. J. Am. Coll. Nutr. 24, 134S&#x2013;139S. 10.1080/07315724.2005.10719454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.2005.10719454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15798080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preitner N., Damiola F., Lopez-Molina L., Zakany J., Duboule D., Albrecht U., et al. (2002). The orphan nuclear receptor REV-ERBalpha controls circadian transcription within the positive limb of the mammalian circadian oscillator. Cell 110, 251&#x2013;260. 10.1016/S0092-8674(02)00825-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0092-8674(02)00825-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12150932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi L., Boateng S. Y. (2006). The circadian protein Clock localizes to the sarcomeric Z-disk and is a sensor of myofilament cross-bridge activity in cardiac myocytes. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 351, 1054&#x2013;1059. 10.1016/j.bbrc.2006.10.168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2006.10.168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17097616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen B. B., Phillips S. M. (2003). Contractile and nutritional regulation of human muscle growth. Exerc. Sport Sci. Rev. 31, 127&#x2013;131. 10.1097/00003677-200307000-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003677-200307000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raue U., Trappe T. A., Estrem S. T., Qian H. R., Helvering L. M., Smith R. C., et al. (2012). Transcriptome signature of resistance exercise adaptations: mixed muscle and fiber type specific profiles in young and old adults. J. Appl. Physiol. 112, 1625&#x2013;1636. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00435.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00435.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3365403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22302958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeds P. J., Palmer R. M., Hay S. M., McMillan D. N. (1986). Protein synthesis in skeletal muscle measured at different times during a 24 hour period. Biosci. Rep. 6, 209&#x2013;213. 10.1007/BF01115008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01115008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3719085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea M. R., Alvar B. A., Burkett L. N., Ball S. D. (2003). A meta-analysis to determine the dose response for strength development. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 35, 456&#x2013;464. 10.1249/01.MSS.0000053727.63505.D4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000053727.63505.D4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roenneberg T., Daan S., Merrow M. (2003). The art of entrainment. J. Biol. Rhythms 18, 183&#x2013;194. 10.1177/0748730403018003001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0748730403018003001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12828276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahar S., Zocchi L., Kinoshita C., Borrelli E., Sassone-Corsi P. (2010). Regulation of BMAL1 protein stability and circadian function by GSK3&#x3b2;-mediated phosphorylation. PLoS ONE 5:e8561. 10.1371/journal.pone.0008561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0008561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2797305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20049328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanada K., Okano T., Fukada Y. (2002). Mitogen-activated protein kinase phosphorylates and negatively regulates basic helix-loop-helix-PAS transcription factor BMAL1. J. Biol. Chem. 277, 267&#x2013;271. 10.1074/jbc.M107850200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M107850200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11687575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzynski M. A., Ghosh S., Bouchard C. (2017). Genomic and transcriptomic predictors of response levels to endurance exercise training. J. Physiol. 595, 2931&#x2013;2939. 10.1113/JP272559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP272559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27234805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato T. K., Panda S., Miraglia L. J., Reyes T. M., Rudic R. D., McNamara P., et al. (2004). A functional genomics strategy reveals Rora as a component of the mammalian circadian clock. Neuron 43, 527&#x2013;537. 10.1016/j.neuron.2004.07.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2004.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15312651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroder E. A., Esser K. A. (2013). Circadian rhythms, skeletal muscle molecular clocks, and exercise. Exerc. Sport Sci. Rev. 41, 224&#x2013;229. 10.1097/JES.0b013e3182a58a70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JES.0b013e3182a58a70</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3866019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroder E. A., Harfmann B. D., Zhang X., Srikuea R., England J. H., Hodge B. A., et al. (2015). Intrinsic muscle clock is necessary for musculoskeletal health. J. Physiol. 593, 5387&#x2013;5404. 10.1113/JP271436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP271436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4704520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26486627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedliak M., Finni T., Cheng S., Kraemer W. J., Hakkinen K. (2007). Effect of time-of-day-specific strength training on serum hormone concentrations and isometric strength in men. Chronobiol. Int. 24, 1159&#x2013;1177. 10.1080/07420520701800686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07420520701800686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18075805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedliak M., Finni T., Cheng S., Lind M., Hakkinen K. (2009). Effect of time-of-day-specific strength training on muscular hypertrophy in men. J. Strength Cond. Res. 23, 2451&#x2013;2457. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181bb7388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181bb7388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedliak M., Zeman M., Buzg&#xf3; G., Cvecka J., Hamar D., Laczo E., et al. (2017). Morphological, molecular and hormonal adaptations to early morning versus afternoon resistance training. Chronobiol. Int. 35, 450&#x2013;464. 10.1080/07420528.2017.1411360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07420528.2017.1411360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29283292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazian D., Roux P. P., Mieulet V., Cohen M. S., Raught B., Taunton J., et al. (2006). The mTOR/PI3K and MAPK pathways converge on eIF4B to control its phosphorylation and activity. EMBO J. 25, 2781&#x2013;2791. 10.1038/sj.emboj.7601166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.emboj.7601166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1500846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16763566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shavlakadze T., Anwari T., Soffe Z., Cozens G., Mark P. J., Gondro C., et al. (2013). Impact of fasting on the rhythmic expression of myogenic and metabolic factors in skeletal muscle of adult mice. Am. J. Physiol. Cell Physiol. 305, C26&#x2013;C35. 10.1152/ajpcell.00027.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00027.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23596176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirogane T., Jin J., Ang X. L., Harper J. W. (2005). SCFbeta-TRCP controls clock-dependent transcription via casein kinase 1-dependent degradation of the mammalian period-1 (Per1) protein. J. Biol. Chem. 280, 26863&#x2013;26872. 10.1074/jbc.M502862200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M502862200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15917222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T., Nederveen J. P., McKay B. R., Joanisse S., Verdijk L. B., van Loon L. J., et al. (2015). Satellite cells in human skeletal muscle plasticity. Front. Physiol. 6:283. 10.3389/fphys.2015.00283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2015.00283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4617172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26557092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi N., Gauthier A., Sesbo&#xfc;&#xe9; B., Larue J., Davenne D. (2002). Effects of regular training at the same time of day on diurnal fluctuations in muscular performance. J. Sports Sci. 20, 929&#x2013;937. 10.1080/026404102320761813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404102320761813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12430993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stec M. J., Kelly N. A., Many G. M., Windham S. T., Tuggle S. C., Bamman M. M. (2016). Ribosome biogenesis may augment resistance training-induced myofiber hypertrophy and is required for myotube growth <i>in vitro</i>. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab.
310, E652&#x2013;E61. 10.1152/ajpendo.00486.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00486.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4835943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26860985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahara Y., Shibata S. (2013). Chronobiology and nutrition. Neuroscience 253:78&#x2013;88. 10.1016/j.neuroscience.2013.08.049</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2013.08.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24007937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G., Georgiadis G., Stratakos G., Vogiatzis I., Kavouras S., Manta P., et al. (2008). Resistance exercise-induced increase in muscle mass correlates with p70S6 kinase phosphorylation in human subjects. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 102, 145&#x2013;152. 10.1007/s00421-007-0564-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0564-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17874120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thalacker-Mercer A., Stec M., Cui X., Cross J., Windham S., Bamman M. (2013). Cluster analysis reveals differential transcript profiles associated with resistance training-induced human skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Physiol. Genomics 45, 499&#x2013;507. 10.1152/physiolgenomics.00167.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiolgenomics.00167.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3680779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23632419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmons J. A., Knudsen S., Rankinen T., Koch L. G., Sarzynski M., Jensen T., et al. (2010). Using molecular classification to predict gains in maximal aerobic capacity following endurance exercise training in humans. J. Appl. Physiol. 108, 1487&#x2013;1496. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01295.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01295.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20133430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Moorsel D., Hansen J., Havekes B., Scheer F. A., J&#xf6;rgensen J. A., Hoeks J., et al. (2016). Demonstration of a day-night rhythm in human skeletal muscle oxidative capacity. Mol. Metab. 5, 635&#x2013;645. 10.1016/j.molmet.2016.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmet.2016.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5021670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27656401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Reeth O., Sturis J., Byrne M. M., Blackman J. D., L'Hermite-Baleriaux M., Leproult R., et al. (1994). Nocturnal exercise phase delays circadian rhythms of melatonin and thyrotropin secretion in normal men. Am. J. Physiol. 266(6 Pt 1), E964&#x2013;E974. 10.1152/ajpendo.1994.266.6.E964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1994.266.6.E964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8023928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Proud C. G. (2006). The mTOR pathway in the control of protein synthesis. Physiology 21, 362&#x2013;369. 10.1152/physiol.00024.2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiol.00024.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16990457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng Q. P., Kozlowski M., Belham C., Zhang A., Comb M. J., Avruch J. (1998). Regulation of the p70 S6 kinase by phosphorylation <i>in vivo</i>. Analysis using site-specific anti-phosphopeptide antibodies. J. Biol. Chem.
273, 16621&#x2013;16629. 10.1074/jbc.273.26.16621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.273.26.16621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9632736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West D. W., Burd N. A., Tang J. E., Moore D. R., Staples A. W., Holwerda A. M., et al. (2010). Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J. Appl. Physiol. 108, 60&#x2013;67. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01147.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01147.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West D. W., Kujbida G. W., Moore D. R., Atherton P., Burd N. A., Padzik J. P., et al. (2009). Resistance exercise-induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J. Physiol. 587(Pt 21), 5239&#x2013;5247. 10.1113/jphysiol.2009.177220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2009.177220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19736298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldt E., Sebti Y., Solt L. A., Duhem C., Lancel S., Eeckhoute J., et al. (2013). Rev-erb-alpha modulates skeletal muscle oxidative capacity by regulating mitochondrial biogenesis and autophagy. Nat. Med. 19, 1039&#x2013;1046. 10.1038/nm.3213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.3213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23852339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff G., Esser K. A. (2012). Scheduled exercise phase shifts the circadian clock in skeletal muscle. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 44, 1663&#x2013;1670. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318255cf4c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318255cf4c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3414645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22460470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N., MacArthur D. G., Gulbin J. P., Hahn A. G., Beggs A. H., Easteal S., et al. (2003). ACTN3 genotype is associated with human elite athletic performance. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 73, 627&#x2013;631. 10.1086/377590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/377590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1180686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12879365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L., Joshi S., Wu N., Tong X., Lazar M. A. (2010). E3 ligases Arf-bp1 and Pam mediate lithium-stimulated degradation of the circadian heme receptor Rev-erb alpha. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 107, 11614&#x2013;11619. 10.1073/pnas.1000438107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1000438107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20534529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambon A. C., McDearmon E. L., Salomonis N., Vranizan K. M., Johansen K. L., Adey D., et al. (2003). Time- and exercise-dependent gene regulation in human skeletal muscle. Genome Biol. 4:R61. 10.1186/gb-2003-4-10-r61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/gb-2003-4-10-r61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC328450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14519196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Lahens N. F., Ballance H. I., Hughes M. E., Hogenesch J. B. (2014). A circadian gene expression atlas in mammals: implications for biology and medicine. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 111, 16219&#x2013;16224. 10.1073/pnas.1408886111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1408886111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25349387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Fang B., Emmett M. J., Damle M., Sun Z., Feng D., et al. (2015). GENE REGULATION. Discrete functions of nuclear receptor Rev-erbalpha couple metabolism to the clock. Science 348, 1488&#x2013;1492. 10.1126/science.aab3021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aab3021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4613749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26044300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>