<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38934511</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute and Chronic Changes in Muscle Androgen Receptor Markers Are Not Associated with Muscle Hypertrophy in Women and Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2146</StartPage><EndPage>2155</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2146-2155</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003509</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Androgen receptor (AR) expression and signaling have been regarded as a mechanism for regulating muscle hypertrophy. However, little is known about the associations between acute and chronic changes in skeletal muscle total AR, cytoplasmic AR (cAR), nuclear AR (nAR), and AR DNA-binding (AR-DNA) induced by resistance training (RT) and hypertrophy outcomes in women and men. This study aimed to investigate the acute and chronic effects of RT on skeletal muscle total AR, cAR, and nAR contents and AR-DNA in women and men. In addition, we investigated whether these acute and chronic changes in these markers were associated with muscle hypertrophy in both sexes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nineteen women and 19 men underwent 10 wk of RT. Muscle biopsies were performed at baseline, 24 h after the first RT session, and 96 h after the last session. AR, cAR, and nAR were analyzed using Western blotting, and AR-DNA using an ELISA-oligonucleotide assay. Fiber cross-sectional area (fCSA) was analyzed through immunohistochemistry and muscle cross-sectional area (mCSA) by ultrasound.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At baseline, men demonstrated greater nAR than women. Baseline cAR was significantly associated with type II fCSA hypertrophy in men. Acutely, both sexes decreased AR and cAR, whereas men demonstrated greater decreases in nAR. After 10 wk of RT, AR, and nAR remained unchanged, men demonstrated greater cAR compared with women, and both sexes decreased AR-DNA activity. Acute and chronic changes in AR markers did not correlate with muscle hypertrophy (type I/II fCSA and mCSA) in women or men.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Baseline cAR content may influence hypertrophy in men, whereas neither RT-induced acute nor chronic changes in AR, cAR, nAR, and AR-DNA are associated with muscle hypertrophy in women or men.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergamasco</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o G A</ForeName><Initials>JGA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scarpelli</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#xed;ra C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Godwin</LastName><ForeName>Joshua S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mesquita</LastName><ForeName>Paulo H C</ForeName><Initials>PHC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaves</LastName><ForeName>Talisson S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DA Silva</LastName><ForeName>Deivid G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bittencourt</LastName><ForeName>Diego</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dias</LastName><ForeName>Nathalia F</ForeName><Initials>NF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Medalha Junior</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carello Filho</LastName><ForeName>Paulo C</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Angleri</LastName><ForeName>Vitor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Luiz A R</ForeName><Initials>LAR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo (USP), S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michel</LastName><ForeName>J Max</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vechin</LastName><ForeName>Felipe C</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo (USP), S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kavazis</LastName><ForeName>Andreas N</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugrinowitsch</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011944">Receptors, Androgen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011944" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptors, Androgen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012737" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38934511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202411000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ruizeveld de Winter J, Trapman J, Vermey M, Mulder E, Zegers ND, van der Kwast T. Androgen receptor expression in human tissues: an immunohistochemical study. J Histochem Cytochem . 1991;39(7):927&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen PJ, Brinkmann AO, Boersma WJ, Van der Kwast T. Immunohistochemical detection of the androgen receptor with monoclonal antibody F39. 4 in routinely processed, paraffin-embedded human tissues after microwave pre-treatment. J Histochem Cytochem . 1994;42(8):1169&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey RA, Grossmann M. Androgen receptor structure, function and biology: from bench to bedside. Clin Biochem Rev . 2016;37(1):3&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ. Endocrine responses to resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1988;20(5 Suppl):S152&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Shipp JR, Jiang J, et al. Mechanical load increases muscle IGF-I and androgen receptor mRNA concentrations in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol . 2001;280(3):E383&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Taylor L. Effects of sequential bouts of resistance exercise on androgen receptor expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2004;36(9):1499&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, et al. Androgen receptor content following heavy resistance exercise in men. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol . 2005;93(1):35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Spiering BA, Volek JS, et al. Androgenic responses to resistance exercise: effects of feeding and l -carnitine. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2006;38(7):1288&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Ahtiainen JP, Sel&#xe4;nne H, et al. Androgen receptors and testosterone in men&#x2014;effects of protein ingestion, resistance exercise and fiber type. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol . 2008;110(1&#x2013;2):130&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering BA, Kraemer WJ, Vingren JL, et al. Elevated endogenous testosterone concentrations potentiate muscle androgen receptor responses to resistance exercise. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol . 2009;114(3&#x2013;5):195&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingren JL, Kraemer WJ, Hatfield DL, et al. Effect of resistance exercise on muscle steroid receptor protein content in strength-trained men and women. Steroids . 2009;74(13&#x2013;14):1033&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Kujbida GW, Moore DR, et al. Resistance exercise&#x2013;induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. Physiol J . 2009;587(21):5239&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Tang JE, et al. Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2010;108(1):60&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, et al. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training&#x2013;mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2016;121(1):129&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sato K, Gallaugher MP, et al. Muscle androgen receptor content but not systemic hormones is associated with resistance training&#x2013;induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy in healthy, young men. Front Physiol . 2018;9:1373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Hulmi JJ, Kraemer WJ, et al. Heavy resistance exercise training and skeletal muscle androgen receptor expression in younger and older men. Steroids . 2011;76(1&#x2013;2):183&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Bellamy L, Parise G, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Muscular and systemic correlates of resistance training&#x2013;induced muscle hypertrophy. PLoS One . 2013;8(10):e78636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley CB, Haun CT, Roberson PA, et al. Biomarkers associated with low, moderate, and high vastus lateralis muscle hypertrophy following 12 weeks of resistance training. PLoS One . 2018;13(4):e0195203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatt AA, Kamal M, Mikhail AI, et al. Nuclear-localized androgen receptor content following resistance exercise training is associated with hypertrophy in males but not females. FASEB J . 2024;38(2):e23403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, McCarthy JJ, Hornberger TA, et al. Mechanisms of mechanical overload-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: current understanding and future directions. Physiol Rev . 2023;103(4):2679&#x2013;757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RM. The steroid and thyroid hormone receptor superfamily. Science . 1988;240(4854):889&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claessens F, Verrijdt G, Schoenmakers E, et al. Selective DNA binding by the androgen receptor as a mechanism for hormone-specific gene regulation. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol . 2001;76(1&#x2013;5):23&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eder IE, Culig Z, Putz T, Nessler-Menardi C, Bartsch G, Klocker H. Molecular biology of the androgen receptor: from molecular understanding to the clinic. Eur Urol . 2001;40(3):241&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyce A, Bai Y, Nagpal S, Thompson CC. Research resource: the androgen receptor modulates expression of genes with critical roles in muscle development and function. Mol Endocrinol . 2010;24(8):1665&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Dalbo VJ, Hassell SE, Kerksick CM. The expression of androgen-regulated genes before and after a resistance exercise bout in younger and older men. J Strength Cond Res . 2009;23(4):1060&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M, Schwarz N, Willoughby DS. Upper-body resistance exercise augments vastus lateralis androgen receptor&#x2013;DNA binding and canonical Wnt/&#x3b2;-catenin signaling compared to lower-body resistance exercise in resistance-trained men without an acute increase in serum testosterone. Steroids . 2015;98:63&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardaci TD, Machek SB, Wilburn DT, Heileson JL, Willoughby DS. High-load resistance exercise augments androgen receptor&#x2013;DNA binding and Wnt/&#x3b2;-catenin signaling without increases in serum/muscle androgens or androgen receptor content. Nutrients . 2020;12(12):3829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neale S, Hocking R, Biswas M, et al. Adult testosterone and calculated free testosterone reference ranges by tandem mass spectrometry. Ann Clin Biochem . 2013;50(2):159&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Churchward-Venne TA, et al. Sex-based comparisons of myofibrillar protein synthesis after resistance exercise in the fed state. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2012;112(11):1805&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts BM, Nuckols G, Krieger JW. Sex differences in resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res . 2020;34(5):1448&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Nuckols G, Galpin A, Gallagher I, Hamilton DL, Fyfe J. Biological sex differences in absolute and relative changes in muscle size following resistance training in healthy adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. SportRxiv . 2024:SRXIV.400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves TS, Scarpelli MC, Bergamasco JGA, et al. Effects of resistance training overload progression protocols on strength and muscle mass. Int J Sports Med . 2024;45(7):504&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli MC, Bergamasco JGA, Godwin JS, et al. Resistance training&#x2013;induced changes in muscle proteolysis and extracellular matrix remodeling biomarkers in the untrained and trained states. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2024;124(9):2763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey AL, Kjaer M, Charifi N, et al. Assessment of satellite cell number and activity status in human skeletal muscle biopsies. Muscle Nerve . 2009;40(3):455&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Y, Murach KA, Vechetti IJ Jr., et al. MyoVision: software for automated high-content analysis of skeletal muscle immunohistochemistry. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2018;124(1):40&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges L, Olkin I. Estimation of a single effect size: parametric and nonparametric methods. In: Statistical Methods for Meta-Analysis . New York (NY): Academic Press; 1985. pp. 76&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Cuthill IC. Effect size, confidence interval and statistical significance: a practical guide for biologists. Biol Rev . 2007;82(4):591&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JD. Straightforward Statistics for the Behavioral Sciences . Pacific Grove (CA): Thompson Brooks/Cole Publishing Co; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southren AL, Gordon GG, Tochimoto S. Further study of factors affecting the metabolic clearance rate of testosterone in man. J Clin Endocrinol Metab . 1968;28(8):1105&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handelsman DJ, Hirschberg AL, Bermon S. Circulating testosterone as the hormonal basis of sex differences in athletic performance. Endocr Rev . 2018;39(5):803&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med . 2005;35(4):339&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA, et al. Resistance training in young men induces muscle transcriptome-wide changes associated with muscle structure and metabolism refining the response to exercise-induced stress. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2018;118(12):2607&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res . 2014;28(11):3085&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson BM, Hillebrandt HL, Sculley DV, Barba-Moreno L, Janse de Jonge XAK. The acute effect of the menstrual cycle and oral contraceptive cycle on measures of body composition. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2021;121(11):3051&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekenros L, Papoutsi Z, Frid&#xe9;n C, Dahlman Wright K, Lind&#xe9;n Hirschberg A. Expression of sex steroid hormone receptors in human skeletal muscle during the menstrual cycle. Acta Physiol (Oxf) . 2017;219(2):486&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>