<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33521042</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>LAT1 Protein Content Increases Following 12 Weeks of Resistance Exercise Training in Human Skeletal Muscle.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>628405</StartPage><MedlinePgn>628405</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">628405</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2020.628405</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Introduction:</b> Amino acid transporters are essential for cellular amino acid transport and promoting protein synthesis. While previous literature has demonstrated the association of amino acid transporters and protein synthesis following acute resistance exercise and amino acid supplementation, the chronic effect of resistance exercise and supplementation on amino acid transporters is unknown. The purpose herein was to determine if amino acid transporters and amino acid metabolic enzymes were related to skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise training with different nutritional supplementation strategies. <b>Methods:</b> 43 college-aged males were separated into a maltodextrin placebo (PLA, <i>n</i> = 12), leucine (LEU, <i>n</i> = 14), or whey protein concentrate (WPC, <i>n</i> = 17) group and underwent 12 weeks of total-body resistance exercise training. Each group's supplement was standardized for total energy and fat, and LEU and WPC supplements were standardized for total leucine (6 g/d). Skeletal muscle biopsies were obtained prior to training and ~72 h following each subject's last training session. <b>Results:</b> All groups increased type I and II fiber cross-sectional area (fCSA) following training (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.050). LAT1 protein increased following training (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001) and increased more in PLA than LEU and WPC (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.050). BCKDH&#x3b1; protein increased and ATF4 protein decreased following training (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.001). Immunohistochemistry indicated total LAT1/fiber, but not membrane LAT1/fiber, increased with training (<i>p</i> = 0.003). Utilizing all groups, the change in ATF4 protein, but no other marker, trended to correlate with the change in fCSA (<i>r</i> = 0.314; <i>p</i> = 0.055); however, when regression analysis was used to delineate groups, the change in ATF4 protein best predicted the change in fCSA only in LEU (<i>r</i> <sup>2</sup> = 0.322; <i>p</i> = 0.043). In C2C12 myoblasts, LAT1 protein overexpression caused a paradoxical decrease in protein synthesis levels (<i>p</i> = 0.002) and decrease in BCKDH&#x3b1; protein (<i>p</i> = 0.001). <b>Conclusions:</b> Amino acid transporters and metabolic enzymes are affected by resistance exercise training, but do not appear to dictate muscle fiber hypertrophy. In fact, overexpression of LAT1 <i>in vitro</i> decreased protein synthesis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Roberson, Mobley, Romero, Haun, Osburn, Mumford, Vann, Greer, Ferrando and Roberts.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberson</LastName><ForeName>Paul A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mobley</LastName><ForeName>C Brooks</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, College of Medicine, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Romero</LastName><ForeName>Matthew A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haun</LastName><ForeName>Cody T</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osburn</LastName><ForeName>Shelby C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mumford</LastName><ForeName>Petey W</ForeName><Initials>PW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vann</LastName><ForeName>Christopher G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greer</LastName><ForeName>Rory A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrando</LastName><ForeName>Arny A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatrics, Donald W. Reynolds Institute on Aging, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences, Little Rock, AK, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, AL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>F32 DK126312</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ATF4</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BCKDH</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amino acid metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein supplementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein synthesis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding for participant compensation and reagents were provided by monetary donations to MDR through Hilmar Ingredients (Hilmar, CA, USA), Bionutritional Research Group (Irvine, CA, USA), and Lockwood, LLC (Belton, TX, USA). Funding for the data procured in the current manuscript as well as article publishing charges were provided by a discretionary laboratory fund of MDR. Dr. Christopher Lockwood (Lockwood, LLC) was involved in the study design for the parent paper of this current manuscript (39). However, he had no involvement in the collection, analysis, interpretation of data, the writing of this current article or the decision to submit it for publication. The results of this study are presented clearly, honestly, and without fabrication, falsification, or inappropriate data manipulation. The laboratory of MDR performs contracted research for nutritional supplement companies. Moreover, MDR has served as a paid consultant with various nutritional supplement companies. However, MDR has not served as a consultant for Hilmar Ingredients, Bionutritional Research Group, or Lockwood, LLC. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7840583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2020.628405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC. Disuse-induced muscle wasting. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. (2013) 45:2200&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.biocel.2013.06.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocel.2013.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3856924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberson PA, Shimkus KL, Welles JE, Xu D, Whitsell AL, Kimball EM, et al. A time course for markers of protein synthesis and degradation with hindlimb unloading and the accompanying anabolic resistance to refeeding. J Appl Physiol. (2020) 129:36&#x2013;46. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00155.2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00155.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7469230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32407240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberson PA, Romero MA, Mumford PW, Osburn SC, Haun CT, Vann CG, et al. Protein supplementation throughout 10 weeks of progressive run training is not beneficial for time trial improvement. Front Nutr. (2018) 5:97. 10.3389/fnut.2018.00097</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2018.00097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6230989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30456213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vann CG, Osburn SC, Mumford PW, Roberson PA, Fox CD, Sexton CL, et al. Skeletal muscle protein composition adaptations to 10 weeks of high-load resistance training in previously-trained males. Front Physiol. (2020) 11:259. 10.3389/fphys.2020.00259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Van Loon LJ. Dietary protein for athletes: from requirements to optimum adaptation. J Sports Sci. (2011) 29(Suppl. 1):S29&#x2013;38. 10.1080/02640414.2011.619204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2011.619204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22150425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato H, Suzuki K, Bannai M, Moore DR. Protein requirements are elevated in endurance athletes after exercise as determined by the indicator amino acid oxidation method. PLoS ONE. (2016) 11:e0157406. 10.1371/journal.pone.0157406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0157406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4913918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, Mckellar SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Henselmans M, Helms E, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med. (2018) 52:376&#x2013;84. 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097608</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpi E, Kobayashi H, Sheffield-Moore M, Mittendorfer B, Wolfe RR. Essential amino acids are primarily responsible for the amino acid stimulation of muscle protein anabolism in healthy elderly adults. Am J Clin Nutr. (2003) 78:250&#x2013;8. 10.1093/ajcn/78.2.250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/78.2.250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12885705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Wagenmakers AJ, Manders RJ, Zorenc AH, Senden JM, Gorselink M, et al. Combined ingestion of protein and free leucine with carbohydrate increases postexercise muscle protein synthesis <i>in vivo</i> in male subjects. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2005) 288:E645&#x2013;53. 10.1152/ajpendo.00413.2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00413.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15562251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Verdijk L, Manders RJ, Gijsen AP, Gorselink M, Pijpers E, et al. Co-ingestion of protein and leucine stimulates muscle protein synthesis rates to the same extent in young and elderly lean men. Am J Clin Nutr. (2006) 84:623&#x2013;32. 10.1093/ajcn/84.3.623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/84.3.623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton LE, Wilson GJ, Layman DK, Moulton CJ, Garlick PJ. Leucine content of dietary proteins is a determinant of postprandial skeletal muscle protein synthesis in adult rats. Nutr Metab. (2012) 9:67. 10.1186/1743-7075-9-67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-9-67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3488566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton PJ, Smith K, Etheridge T, Rankin D, Rennie MJ. Distinct anabolic signalling responses to amino acids in C2C12 skeletal muscle cells. Amino Acids. (2010) 38:1533&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00726-009-0377-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-009-0377-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19882215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Hossain T, Hill DS, Phillips BE, Crossland H, Williams J, et al. Effects of leucine and its metabolite &#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate on human skeletal muscle protein metabolism. J Physiol. (2013) 591:2911&#x2013;23. 10.1113/jphysiol.2013.253203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2013.253203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23551944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu D, Shimkus KL, Lacko HA, Kutzler L, Jefferson LS, Kimball SR. Evidence for a role for sestrin1 in mediating leucine-induced activation of mTORC1 in skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2019) 316:E817&#x2013;28. 10.1152/ajpendo.00522.2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00522.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6580170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30835510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;gmundsd&#xf3;ttir MH, Heublein S, Kazi S, Reynolds B, Visvalingam SM, Shaw MK, et al. Proton-assisted amino acid transporter PAT1 complexes with Rag GTPases and activates TORC1 on late endosomal and lysosomal membranes. PLoS ONE. (2012) 7:e36616. 10.1371/journal.pone.0036616</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0036616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3344915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22574197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmberg SE, Adams CM. Insulin signaling and the general amino acid control response. Two distinct pathways to amino acid synthesis and uptake. J Biol Chem. (2008) 283:19229&#x2013;34. 10.1074/jbc.M801331200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M801331200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18480057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilberg MS, Shan J, Su N. ATF4-dependent transcription mediates signaling of amino acid limitation. Trends Endocrinol Metab. (2009) 20:436&#x2013;43. 10.1016/j.tem.2009.05.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2009.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3587693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19800252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Glynn EL, Fry CS, Timmerman KL, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. An increase in essential amino acid availability upregulates amino acid transporter expression in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2010) 298:E1011&#x2013;18. 10.1152/ajpendo.00690.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00690.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20304764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Fry CS, Glynn EL, Timmerman KL, Dickinson JM, Walker DK, et al. Skeletal muscle amino acid transporter expression is increased in young and older adults following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. (2011) 111:135&#x2013;42. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01408.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01408.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Dickinson JM, Fry CS, Walker DK, Gundermann DM, Reidy PT, et al. Bed rest impairs skeletal muscle amino acid transporter expression, mTORC1 signaling, and protein synthesis in response to essential amino acids in older adults. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2012) 302:E1113&#x2013;22. 10.1152/ajpendo.00603.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00603.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3361979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22338078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reidy PT, Walker DK, Dickinson JM, Gundermann DM, Drummond MJ, Timmerman KL, et al. Soy-dairy protein blend and whey protein ingestion after resistance exercise increases amino acid transport and transporter expression in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. (2014) 116:1353&#x2013;64. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01093.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01093.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4044402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24699854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert SM, Monteys AM, Fox DK, Bongers KS, Shields BE, Malmberg SE, et al. The transcription factor ATF4 promotes skeletal myofiber atrophy during fasting. Mol Endocrinol. (2010) 24:790&#x2013;9. 10.1210/me.2009-0345</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/me.2009-0345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2852358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20197309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert SM, Dyle MC, Bullard SA, Dierdorff JM, Murry DJ, Fox DK, et al. Identification and small molecule inhibition of an activating transcription factor 4 (ATF4)-dependent pathway to age-related skeletal muscle weakness and atrophy. J Biol Chem. (2015) 290:25497&#x2013;511. 10.1074/jbc.M115.681445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M115.681445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4646196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T, Ebert SM, Adams CM, Rasmussen BB. Amino acid sensing in skeletal muscle. Trends Endocrinol Metab. (2016) 27:796&#x2013;806. 10.1016/j.tem.2016.06.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2016.06.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5075248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27444066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimomura Y, Obayashi M, Murakami T, Harris RA. Regulation of branched-chain amino acid catabolism: nutritional and hormonal regulation of activity and expression of the branched-chain alpha-keto acid dehydrogenase kinase. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. (2001) 4:419&#x2013;23. 10.1097/00075197-200109000-00013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00075197-200109000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11568504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii H, Shimomura Y, Murakami T, Nakai N, Sato T, Suzuki M, et al. Branched-chain alpha-keto acid dehydrogenase kinase content in rat skeletal muscle is decreased by endurance training. Biochem Mol Biol Int. (1998) 44:1211&#x2013;6. 10.1080/15216549800202302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15216549800202302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9623776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howarth KR, Burgomaster KA, Phillips SM, Gibala MJ. Exercise training increases branched-chain oxoacid dehydrogenase kinase content in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. (2007) 293:R1335&#x2013;41. 10.1152/ajpregu.00115.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00115.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17581840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mckenzie S, Phillips SM, Carter SL, Lowther S, Gibala MJ, Tarnopolsky MA. Endurance exercise training attenuates leucine oxidation and BCOAD activation during exercise in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2000) 278:E580&#x2013;7. 10.1152/ajpendo.2000.278.4.E580</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.2000.278.4.E580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimomura Y, Murakami T, Nakai N, Nagasaki M, Harris RA. Exercise promotes BCAA catabolism: effects of BCAA supplementation on skeletal muscle during exercise. J Nutr. (2004) 134:1583S&#x2212;7S. 10.1093/jn/134.6.1583S</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/134.6.1583S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Maggi SP, Williams BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Increased rates of muscle protein turnover and amino acid transport after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. (1995) 268:E514&#x2013;20. 10.1152/ajpendo.1995.268.3.E514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1995.268.3.E514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trappe S, Williamson D, Godard M, Porter D, Rowden G, Costill D. Effect of resistance training on single muscle fiber contractile function in older men. J Appl Physiol. (2000) 89:143&#x2013;52. 10.1152/jappl.2000.89.1.143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.89.1.143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10904046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Ivey FM, Martel GF, Lemmer JT, Hurlbut DE, Siegel EL, et al. Muscle size responses to strength training in young and older men and women. J Am Geriatr Soc. (2001) 49:1428&#x2013;33. 10.1046/j.1532-5415.2001.4911233.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1532-5415.2001.4911233.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11890579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trappe S, Godard M, Gallagher P, Carroll C, Rowden G, Porter D. Resistance training improves single muscle fiber contractile function in older women. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. (2001) 281:C398&#x2013;406. 10.1152/ajpcell.2001.281.2.C398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.2001.281.2.C398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11443039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol. (2006) 101:531&#x2013;44. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Drummond MJ, Pennings B, Fujita S, Glynn EL, Chinkes DL, et al. Leucine-enriched essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion following resistance exercise enhances mTOR signaling and protein synthesis in human muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2008) 294:E392&#x2013;400. 10.1152/ajpendo.00582.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00582.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2706121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18056791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Tang JE, Burd NA, Rerecich T, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Differential stimulation of myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic protein synthesis with protein ingestion at rest and after resistance exercise. J Physiol. (2009) 587:897&#x2013;904. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.164087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.164087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2669978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberson PA, Haun CT, Mobley CB, Romero MA, Mumford PW, Martin JS, et al. Skeletal muscle amino acid transporter and BCAT2 expression prior to and following interval running or resistance exercise in mode-specific trained males. Amino Acids. (2018) 50:961&#x2013;5. 10.1007/s00726-018-2570-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-018-2570-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29725856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickinson JM, Gundermann DM, Walker DK, Reidy PT, Borack MS, Drummond MJ, et al. Leucine-enriched amino acid ingestion after resistance exercise prolongs myofibrillar protein synthesis and amino acid transporter expression in older men. J Nutr. (2014) 144:1694&#x2013;702. 10.3945/jn.114.198671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.114.198671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4195415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25332468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley CB, Haun CT, Roberson PA, Mumford PW, Romero MA, Kephart WC, et al. Effects of whey, soy or leucine supplementation with 12 weeks of resistance training on strength, body composition, and skeletal muscle and adipose tissue histological attributes in college-aged males. Nutrients. (2017) 9:972. 10.3390/nu9090972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9090972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28869573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero MA, Mobley CB, Mumford PW, Roberson PA, Haun CT, Kephart WC, et al. Acute and chronic resistance training downregulates select LINE-1 retrotransposon activity markers in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. (2018) 314:C379&#x2013;88. 10.1152/ajpcell.00192.2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00192.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberson PA, Romero MA, Osburn SC, Mumford PW, Vann CG, Fox CD, et al. Skeletal muscle LINE-1 ORF1 mRNA is higher in older humans but decreases with endurance exercise and is negatively associated with higher physical activity. J Appl Physiol. (2019) 127:895&#x2013;904. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00352.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00352.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31369326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Mobley CB, Vann CG, Haun CT, Schoenfeld BJ, Young KC, et al. Synergist ablation-induced hypertrophy occurs more rapidly in the plantaris than soleus muscle in rats due to different molecular mechanisms. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. (2019) 318:R360&#x2013;8. 10.1152/ajpregu.00304.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00304.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31850817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodson N, Brown T, Joanisse S, Aguirre N, West DWD, Moore DR, et al. Characterisation of L-type amino acid transporter 1 (LAT1) expression in human skeletal muscle by immunofluorescent microscopy. Nutrients. (2017) 10:23. 10.3390/nu10010023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10010023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29278358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter AE, Jones TR, Lamprecht MR, Clarke C, Kang IH, Friman O, et al. CellProfiler: image analysis software for identifying and quantifying cell phenotypes. Genome Biol. (2006) 7:R100. 10.1186/gb-2006-7-10-r100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/gb-2006-7-10-r100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1794559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17076895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokes T, Hector AJ, Morton RW, Mcglory C, Phillips SM. Recent perspectives regarding the role of dietary protein for the promotion of muscle hypertrophy with resistance exercise training. Nutrients. (2018) 10:180. 10.3390/nu10020180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10020180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5852756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29414855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanagida O, Kanai Y, Chairoungdua A, Kim DK, Segawa H, Nii T, et al. Human L-type amino acid transporter 1 (LAT1): characterization of function and expression in tumor cell lines. Biochim Biophys Acta. (2001) 1514:291&#x2013;302. 10.1016/S0005-2736(01)00384-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0005-2736(01)00384-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11557028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CH, Park KJ, Park JR, Kanai Y, Endou H, Park JC, et al. The RNA interference of amino acid transporter LAT1 inhibits the growth of KB human oral cancer cells. Anticancer Res. (2006) 26:2943&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16886618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milkereit R, Persaud A, Vanoaica L, Guetg A, Verrey F, Rotin D. LAPTM4b recruits the LAT1-4F2hc Leu transporter to lysosomes and promotes mTORC1 activation. Nat Commun. (2015) 6:7250. 10.1038/ncomms8250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms8250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25998567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyde R, Hajduch E, Powell DJ, Taylor PM, Hundal HS. Ceramide down-regulates system A amino acid transport and protein synthesis in rat skeletal muscle cells. FASEB J. (2005) 19:461&#x2013;3. 10.1096/fj.04-2284fje</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.04-2284fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15611152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She P, Zhou Y, Zhang Z, Griffin K, Gowda K, Lynch CJ. Disruption of BCAA metabolism in mice impairs exercise metabolism and endurance. J Appl Physiol. (2010) 108:941&#x2013;9. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01248.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01248.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2853195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20133434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch CJ, Kimball SR, Xu Y, Salzberg AC, Kawasawa YI. Global deletion of BCATm increases expression of skeletal muscle genes associated with protein turnover. Physiol Genomics. (2015) 47:569&#x2013;80. 10.1152/physiolgenomics.00055.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiolgenomics.00055.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4629004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26351290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley CB, Mumford PW, Mccarthy JJ, Miller ME, Young KC, Martin JS, et al. Whey protein-derived exosomes increase protein synthesis and hypertrophy in C2C12 myotubes. J Dairy Sci. (2017) 100:48&#x2013;64. 10.3168/jds.2016-11341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2016-11341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28341051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobukuni Y, Mitsubuchi H, Akaboshi I, Indo Y, Endo F, Yoshioka A, et al. Maple syrup urine disease. Complete defect of the E1 beta subunit of the branched chain alpha-ketoacid dehydrogenase complex due to a deletion of an 11-bp repeat sequence which encodes a mitochondrial targeting leader peptide in a family with the disease. J Clin Invest. (1991) 87:1862&#x2013;6. 10.1172/JCI115209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI115209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC295312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2022752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnet DS, O'leary MN, Gutierrez MA, Nguyen SM, Mateen S, Hsu Y, et al. Metformin inhibits branched chain amino acid (BCAA) derived ketoacidosis and promotes metabolic homeostasis in MSUD. Sci Rep. (2016) 6:28775 10.1038/srep28775</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep28775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27373929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao D, Villet O, Zhang Z, Choi SW, Yan J, Ritterhoff J, et al. Glucose promotes cell growth by suppressing branched-chain amino acid degradation. Nat Commun. (2018) 9:2935. 10.1038/s41467-018-05362-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-05362-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6062555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30050148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scalise M, Galluccio M, Console L, Pochini L, Indiveri C. The human SLC7A5 (LAT1): the intriguing histidine/large neutral amino acid transporter and its relevance to human health. Front Chem. (2018) 6:243. 10.3389/fchem.2018.00243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchem.2018.00243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29988369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>