<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39590559</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Stair-Climbing Versus Machine-Based Resistance Exercise to Improve Muscle Power Among Older Adults: A Noninferiority Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e496</StartPage><EndPage>e505</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e496-e505</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005005</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Van Roie, E, van Uffelen, J, and Delecluse, C. Stair-climbing versus machine-based resistance exercise to improve muscle power among older adults: a non-inferiority trial. J Strength Cond Res 39(3): e496-e505, 2025-Machine-based resistance training (RT) can reduce the age-related loss in muscle power ( Pmax ). However, weight-bearing exercises have greater potential for implementation. This study investigated whether stair-climbing exercise (STAIR) was non-inferior to improve Pmax compared with machine-based RT among older adults. Functional capacity tests were secondary outcomes. Older adults (30&#x2642; and 16&#x2640;; 70.9 &#xb1; 4.3 years) were randomly assigned to RT or STAIR ( n = 23 per group). Supervised laboratory-based training sessions were performed 2 times per week for 12 weeks. In week 1-4, exercises were performed at controlled speed (hypertrophy-oriented; 4 &#xd7; 12-15 repetitions; 55% of 1 repetition maximum (1RM) in RT; step-up exercise with height of 30-40 cm in STAIR), in week 5-12 as fast as possible (power-oriented, 4 &#xd7; 12 repetitions; 40% of 1RM for RT and 4 &#xd7; 2 flights of 6 steps for STAIR). Leg-extensor Pmax and functional capacity were measured pre-intervention and post-intervention, and Pmax also after 4 weeks of training. Gains in Pmax were not statistically different in RT (19.5 &#xb1; 12.2%) and STAIR (13.7 &#xb1; 16.5%) ( d = 0.39, pint = 0.086), whereas non-inferiority analyses were inconclusive (between-group difference in gains: 5.8% (95% CI -3.1 to 14.6); non-inferiority limit 3.9%). STAIR increased more in stair ascent performance ( d = 0.45-0.61, pint &lt; 0.05) than RT. STAIR and RT improved similarly on 10-m fast walk, 5-repetition sit-to-stand, and countermovement jump ( pint &gt; 0.05). To conclude, STAIR and RT both induced significant changes in Pmax and functional capacity in older adults. STAIR was beneficial over RT for gains in stair-climbing performance. Future research should investigate the effects of STAIR in a home-based unsupervised setting.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Roie</LastName><ForeName>Evelien</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4547-589</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement Sciences, Physical Activity, KU Leuven, Sports and Health Research Group, Leuven, Belgium ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Hasselt, Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, REVAL-Rehabilitation Research Center, Diepenbeek, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Uffelen</LastName><ForeName>Jannique</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement Sciences, Physical Activity, KU Leuven, Sports and Health Research Group, Leuven, Belgium ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delecluse</LastName><ForeName>Christophe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement Sciences, Physical Activity, KU Leuven, Sports and Health Research Group, Leuven, Belgium ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05263115</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>12Z5720N</GrantID><Agency>Research Foundation Flanders</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000073843">Equivalence Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="N">instrumentation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072799" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stair Climbing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39590559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202503000-00026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alcazar J, Rodriguez-Lopez C, Ara I, et al. The force-velocity relationship in older people: Reliability and validity of a systematic procedure. Int J Sports Med 38: 1097&#x2013;1104, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcazar J, Rodriguez-Lopez C, Delecluse C, Thomis M, Van Roie E. Ten-year longitudinal changes in muscle power, force, and velocity in young, middle-aged, and older adults. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 14: 1019&#x2013;1032, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggen RJ, Van Roie E, van Dieen JH, Verschueren SM, Delecluse C. Weight bearing exercise can elicit similar peak muscle activation as medium-high intensity resistance exercise in elderly women. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 531&#x2013;541, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggen RJ, Van Roie E, Verschueren SM, et al. Bench stepping with incremental heights improves muscle volume, strength and functional performance in older women. Exp Gerontol 120: 6&#x2013;14, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker MK, Atlantis E, Fiatarone Singh MA. Multi-modal exercise programs for older adults. Age Ageing 36: 375&#x2013;381, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balachandran AT, Gandia K, Jacobs KA, et al. Power training using pneumatic machines vs. plate-loaded machines to improve muscle power in older adults. Exp Gerontol 98: 134&#x2013;142, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balachandran AT, Steele J, Angielczyk D, et al. Comparison of power training vs traditional strength training on physical function in older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open 5: e2211623, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandeira-Guimar&#xe3;es M, Blanco-Rambo E, Vieira AF, et al. Chronic effects of different intensities of power training on neuromuscular parameters in older people: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med Open 9: 9 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bean J, Herman S, Kiely DK, et al. Weighted stair climbing in mobility-limited older people: A pilot study. J Am Geriatr Soc 50: 663&#x2013;670, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich A. Are training velocity and movement pattern important determinants of muscular rate of force development enhancement? Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 3689&#x2013;3691, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Casas-Herrero A, Zambom-Ferraresi F, et al. Multicomponent exercises including muscle power training enhance muscle mass, power output, and functional outcomes in institutionalized frail nonagenarians. Age (Dordr) 36: 773&#x2013;785, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J A power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa CS, LaRoche DP, Cadore EL, et al. 3 different types of strength training in older women. Int J Sports Med 33: 962&#x2013;969, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vos NJ, Singh NA, Ross DA, et al. Optimal load for increasing muscle power during explosive resistance training in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 60: 638&#x2013;647, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donath L, Faude O, Roth R, Zahner L. Effects of stair-climbing on balance, gait, strength, resting heart rate, and submaximal endurance in healthy seniors. Scand J Med Sci Sports 24: e93-e101, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: Position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2019&#x2013;2052, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Ramirez-V&#xe9;lez R, S&#xe1;ez de Asteasu ML, et al. Safety and effectiveness of long-term exercise interventions in older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Med 50: 1095&#x2013;1106, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamel KA, Cavanagh PR. Stair performance in people aged 75 and older. J Am Geriatr Soc 52: 563&#x2013;567, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Mizelle C, Beam S, DeVita P. Old adults perform activities of daily living near their maximal capabilities. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 58: M453&#x2013;M460, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Merchant RA, Morley JE, et al. International exercise recommendations in older adults (ICFSR): Expert consensus guidelines. J Nutr Health Aging 25: 824&#x2013;853, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SJ, Ahn CH. The effects of home-based stair and normal walking exercises on lower extremity functional ability, fall risk factors, and cardiovascular health risk factors in middle-aged older women. J Exerc Rehabil 15: 584&#x2013;591, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennis E, Verschueren SM, Bogaerts A, et al. Effects of fitness and vibration training on muscle quality: A 1-year postintervention follow-up in older men. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 94: 910&#x2013;918, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MK, Kim CY, Baek CY, et al. The effects of various stair-climbing exercises on functional mobility and trunk muscle activation in community-dwelling older adults: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Med (Baltimore) 103: e38446, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk B, French C, Gebauer M, et al. Diagnostic power of relative sit-to-stand muscle power, grip strength, and gait speed for identifying a history of recurrent falls and fractures in older adults. Eur Geriatr Med 14: 421&#x2013;428, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirn DR, Reid KF, Hau C, Phillips EM, Fielding RA. What is a clinically meaningful improvement in leg-extensor power for mobility-limited older adults? J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 71: 632&#x2013;636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Losa-Reyna J, Alcazar J, Carnicero J, et al. Impact of relative muscle power on hospitalization and all-cause mortality in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 77: 781&#x2013;789, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mair JL, De Vito G, Boreham CA. Low volume, home-based weighted step exercise training can improve lower limb muscle power and functional ability in community-dwelling older women. J Clin Med 8: 41, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meulemans L, Van Roie E, Seghers J, Delecluse D. Older adults&#x2019; lower-limb muscle power production throughout a full flight of stairs: Reliability and comparison between different stair models. PLoS One 19: e0296074, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer P, Kayser B, Mach F. Stair use for cardiovascular disease prevention. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil 16: S17&#x2013;S18, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagan JI, Bradshaw BA, Bejte B, et al. Task-specific resistance training adaptations in older adults: Comparing traditional and functional exercise interventions. Front Aging 5: 1335534, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, Cornejo-Daza PJ, et al. Effects of velocity loss in the bench press exercise on strength gains, neuromuscular adaptations, and muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports 30: 2154&#x2013;2166, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Loturco I. Velocity-based training for monitoring training load and assessing training effects. In: Resistance Training Methods: From Theory to Practice. Mu&#xf1;oz-L&#xf3;pez A, Taiar R, Sa&#xf1;udo B, eds. Champaign, IL: Springer International Publishing, 2022. pp. 153&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poff&#xe9; C, Koppo K, Jaspers A, et al. Recreational football training increases leg-extensor velocity production in 55- to 70-year old adults: a randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci Med 22: 345&#x2013;57, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Trajano GS, Freitas SR, et al. Power training prescription in older individuals: Is it safe and effective to promote neuromuscular functional improvements? Sports Med 53: 569&#x2013;576, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Castillo A, de la Fuente CI, et al. High-speed resistance training is more effective than low-speed resistance training to increase functional capacity and muscle performance in older women. Exp Gerontol 58: 51&#x2013;57, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Fielding RA. Skeletal muscle power: A critical determinant of physical functioning in older adults. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 40: 4&#x2013;12, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Lopez C, Alcazar J, Losa-Reyna J, et al. Acute physiological response to light- and heavy-load power-oriented exercise in older adults. Int J Sports Med 42: 1287&#x2013;1296, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Lopez C, Alcazar J, Sanchez-Martin C, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations after 12 weeks of light- vs. heavy-load power-oriented resistance training in older adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports 32: 324&#x2013;337, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Rosell D, Yanez-Garcia JM, Sanchez-Medina L, Mora-Custodio R, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Relationship between velocity loss and repetitions in reserve in the bench press and back squat exercises. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2537&#x2013;2547, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Gibson K. High-speed power training in older adults: A shift of the external resistance at which peak power is produced. J Strength Cond Res 28: 616&#x2013;621, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schott N, Johnen B, Holfelder B. Effects of free weights and machine training on muscular strength in high-functioning older adults. Exp Gerontol 122: 15&#x2013;24, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steves CJ, Mehta MM, Jackson SH, Spector TD. Kicking back cognitive ageing: Leg power predicts cognitive ageing after ten years in older female twins. Gerontol 62: 138&#x2013;149, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taaffe DR, Duret C, Wheeler S, Marcus R. Once-weekly resistance exercise improves muscle strength and neuromuscular performance in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc 47: 1208&#x2013;1214, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiedemann AC, Sherrington C, Lord SR. Physical and psychological factors associated with stair negotiation performance in older people. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 62: 1259&#x2013;1265, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Bautmans I, Coudyzer W, Boen F, Delecluse C. Low- and high-resistance exercise: Long-term adherence and motivation among older adults. Gerontol 61: 551&#x2013;560, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Delecluse C, Coudyzer W, Boonen S, Bautmans I. Strength training at high versus low external resistance in older adults: Effects on muscle volume, muscle strength, and force-velocity characteristics. Exp Gerontol 48: 1351&#x2013;1361, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Van Driessche S, Huijben B, et al. A body-fixed-sensor-based analysis of stair ascent and sit-to-stand to detect age-related differences in leg-extensor power. PLoS One 14: e0210653, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Walker S, Van Driessche S, et al. An age-adapted plyometric exercise program improves dynamic strength, jump performance and functional capacity in older men either similarly or more than traditional resistance training. PLoS One 15: e0237921, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verghese J, Wang C, Xue X, Holtzer R. Self-reported difficulty in climbing up or down stairs in nondisabled elderly. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 89: 100&#x2013;104, 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>