<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29339993</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>60</Volume><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional and Muscle-Size Effects of Flywheel Resistance Training with Eccentric-Overload in Professional Handball Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>133</StartPage><EndPage>143</EndPage><MedlinePgn>133-143</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/hukin-2017-0096</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of the study was to analyse the effects of 6 week (15 sessions) flywheel resistance training with eccentric-overload (FRTEO) on different functional and anatomical variables in professional handball players. Twenty-nine athletes were recruited and randomly divided into two groups. The experimental group (EXP, n = 15) carried out 15 sessions of FRTEO in the leg-press exercise, with 4 sets of 7 repetitions at a maximum-concentric effort. The control group (CON, n = 14) performed the same number of training sessions including 4 sets of 7 maximum repetitions (7RM) using a weight-stack leg-press machine. The results which were measured included maximal dynamic strength (1RM), muscle power at different submaximal loads (PO), vertical jump height (CMJ and SJ), 20 m sprint time (20 m), T-test time (T-test), and Vastus-Lateralis muscle (VL) thickness. The results of the EXP group showed a substantially better improvement (p &lt; 0.05-0.001) in PO, CMJ, 20 m, T-test and VL, compared to the CON group. Moreover, athletes from the EXP group showed significant improvements concerning all the variables measured: 1RM (ES = 0.72), PO (ES = 0.42 - 0.83), CMJ (ES = 0.61), SJ (ES = 0.54), 20 m (ES = 1.45), T-test (ES = 1.44), and VL (ES = 0.63 - 1.64). Since handball requires repeated short, explosive effort such as accelerations and decelerations during sprints with changes of direction, these results suggest that FRTEO affects functional and anatomical changes in a way which improves performance in well-trained professional handball players.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maroto-Izquierdo</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedicine (IBIOMED), University of Le&#xf3;n, Le&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, European University Miguel de Cervantes, Valladolid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Paz</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedicine (IBIOMED), University of Le&#xf3;n, Le&#xf3;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iso-inertial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport performance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29339993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5765793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hukin-2017-0096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2017-0096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alegre LM, Aguado X, Rojas-Martin D, Martin-Garcia M, Ara I, Csapo R.. Load-controlled moderate and high-intensity resistance training programs provoke similar strength gains in young women. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51(1):92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24828840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alegre LM, Ferri-Morales A, Rodriguez-Casares R, Aguado X.. Effects of isometric training on the knee extensor moment-angle relationship and vastus lateralis muscle architecture. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(11):2437&#x2013;2446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25099962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkner B, Tesch PA.. Efficacy of a gravity-independent resistance exercise device as a countermeasure to muscle atrophy during 29-day bed rest. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;181:345&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15196095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkner BA, Berg HE, Kozlovskaya I, Sayenko D, Tesch P.. Effects of strength training, using a gravity-independent exercise system, performed during 110 days of simulated space station confinement. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;90:44&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askling C, Karlsson J, Thorstensson A.. Hamstring injury occurrence in elite soccer players after preseason strength training with eccentric overload. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2003;13(4):244&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12859607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg HE, Tesch A.. A gravity-independent ergometer to be used for resistance training in space. Aviat Space Environ Med. 1994;65(8):752&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7980338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzenczek-Owczarzak W, Naczk M, Arlet J, Forjasz J, Jedrzejczak T, Adach Z.. Estimation of the efficacy of inertial training in older women. J Aging Phys Act. 2013;21(4):433&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23238048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso JF, Hernandez DA, Porter A, Schweikert T, Saito K, Cho M, De Garmo N, Nelson NM.. Integrated electromyography and performance outcomes to inertial resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(1):151&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16503675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd. Hillsdale, NJ: L.: Erlbaum Associates; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, de la Torre A, Pradas F, Sanudo B, Carrasco L, Mateo-Cortes J, Dominguez-Cobo S, Fernandes O, Gonzalo-Skok O.. Effects of eccentric overload bout on change of direction and performance in soccer players. Int J Sports Med. 2014;36(4):308&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25525954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, Pozzo M, Sanudo B, Carrasco L, Gonzalo-Skok O, Dominguez-Cobo S, Moran-Camacho E.. Effects of a 10-week in-season eccentric-overload training program on muscle-injury prevention and performance in junior elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015a;10(1):46&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, Sanudo B, Carrasco L, Dominguez-Cobo S, Mateo-Cortes J, Cadenas-Sanchez MM, Nimphius S.. Effects of traditional versus horizontal inertial flywheel power training on common sport-related tasks. J Hum Kinet. 2015b;47:155&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26557200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, Sanudo B, Carrasco L, Mateo-Cortes J, Dominguez-Cobo S, Fernandes O, Del Ojo JJ, Gonzalo-Skok O.. Effects of 10-week eccentric overload training on kinetic parameters during change of direction in football players. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(14):1380&#x2013;1387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26963941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudley GA, Tesch PA, Miller BJ, Buchanan P.. Importance of eccentric actions in performance adaptations to resistance training. Aviat Space Environ Med. 1991;62(6):543&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1859341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Lundberg TR, Alvarez-Alvarez L, de Paz JA.. Muscle damage responses and adaptations to eccentric-overload resistance exercise in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014a;114(5):1075&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24519446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Nissemark C, Aslund B, Tesch PA, Sojka P.. Chronic stroke patients show early and robust improvements in muscle and functional performance in response to eccentric-overload flywheel resistance training: a pilot study. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2014b;11:150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4236468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25359231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedmann-Bette B, Bauer T, Kinscherf R, Vorwald S, Klute K, Bischoff D, Muller H, Weber MA, Metz J, Kauczor HU, Bartsch P, Billeter R.. Effects of strength training with eccentric overload on muscle adaptation in male athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108(4):821&#x2013;836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19937450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hather BM, Tesch PA, Buchanan P, Dudley GA.. Influence of eccentric actions on skeletal muscle adaptations to resistance training. Acta Physiol Scand. 1991;143(2):177&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1835816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J.. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, DeVita P, LaStayo P.. Neuromuscular and balance responses to flywheel inertial versus weight training in older persons. J Biomech. 2009;42(7):956&#x2013;author reply 957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19285673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Devita P, Money J, Barrier J.. Effects of standard and eccentric overload strength training in young women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(7):1206&#x2013;1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally KM, Robertson RJ.. Construct validity of the OMNI resistance exercise scale. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(2):252&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massuca LM, Fragoso I, Teles J.. Attributes of top elite team-handball players. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(1):178&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23591948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naczk M, Brzenczek-Owczarzak W, Arlet J, Naczk A, Adach Z.. Training effectiveness of the inertial training and measurement system. J Hum Kinet. 2014;44:19&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4327370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naczk M, Naczk A, Brzenczek-Owczarzak W, Arlet J, Adach Z.. Impact of inertial training on strength and power performance in young active men. J Strength Cond Res. 2013 [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27457914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naczk M, Naczk A, Brzenczek-Owczarzak W, Arlet J, Adach Z.. Efficacy of inertial training in elbow joint muscles: influence of different movement velocities. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2016;56(3):223&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25766053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L, Fluckey JD, Pozzo M, Tesch PA.. Resistance training using eccentric overload induces early adaptations in skeletal muscle size. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102(3):271&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17926060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L, Pozzo M, Tesch PA.. Flywheel resistance training calls for greater eccentric muscle activation than weight training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(5):997&#x2013;1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20676897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauole K, Madole K, Garhammer J, Lacourse M, Rozenek R.. Reliability and Validity of the T-Test as a Measure of Agility, Leg Power, and Leg Speed in College-Aged Men and Women. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14(4):443&#x2013;450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Gomez J, Calbet JA.. Training methods to improve vertical jump performance. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2013;53(4):339&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23828282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittweger J, Felsenberg D, Maganaris C, Ferretti JL.. Vertical jump performance after 90 days bed rest with and without flywheel resistive exercise, including a 180 days follow-up. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100(4):427&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17406887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Rodriguez D, Gual G, Tesch PA.. Efficacy of an inertial resistance training paradigm in the treatment of patellar tendinopathy in athletes: a case-series study. Phys Ther Sport. 2011;12(1):43&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21256449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, de Boer M, Narici MV.. Early skeletal muscle hypertrophy and architectural changes in response to high-intensity resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2007;102(1):368&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17053104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Ekberg A, Lindquist DM, Trieschmann JT.. Muscle hypertrophy following 5-week resistance training using a non-gravity-dependent exercise system. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;180:89&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14706117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Ekberg A, Lindquist DM, Trieschmann JT.. Muscle hypertrophy following 5-week resistance training using a non-gravity-dependent exercise system. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;180(1):89&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14706117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tous-Fajardo J, Gonzalo-Skok O, Arjol-Serrano JL, Tesch P.. Enhancing Change-of-Direction Speed in Soccer Players by Functional Inertial Eccentric Overload and Vibration Training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(1):66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25942419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trappe S, Trappe T, Gallagher P, Harber M, Alkner B, Tesch P.. Human single muscle fibre function with 84 day bed-rest and resistance exercise. J Physiol. 2004;557(Pt 2):501&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1665105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>