<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31895290</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle Failure Promotes Greater Muscle Hypertrophy in Low-Load but Not in High-Load Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>346</StartPage><EndPage>351</EndPage><MedlinePgn>346-351</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003454</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lasevicius, T, Schoenfeld, BJ, Silva-Batista, C, Barros, TdS, Aihara, AY, Brendon, H, Longo, AR, Tricoli, V, Peres, BdA, and Teixeira, EL. Muscle failure promotes greater muscle hypertrophy in low-load but not in high-load resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 36(2): 346-351, 2022-The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of an 8-week resistance training program at low and high loads performed with and without achieving muscle failure on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Twenty-five untrained men participated in the 8-week study. Each lower limb was allocated to 1 of 4 unilateral knee extension protocols: repetitions to failure with low load (LL-RF; &#x223c;34.4 repetitions); repetitions to failure with high load (HL-RF; &#x223c;12.4 repetitions); repetitions not to failure with low load (LL-RNF; &#x223c;19.6 repetitions); and repetitions not to failure with high load (HL-RNF; &#x223c;6.7 repetitions). All conditions performed 3 sets with total training volume equated between conditions. The HL-RF and HL-RNF protocols used a load corresponding to 80% 1 repetition maximum (RM), while LL-RF and LL-RNF trained at 30% 1RM. Muscle strength (1RM) and quadriceps cross-sectional area (CSA) were assessed before and after intervention. Results showed that 1RM changes were significantly higher for HL-RF (33.8%, effect size [ES]: 1.24) and HL-RNF (33.4%, ES: 1.25) in the post-test when compared with the LL-RF and LL-RNF protocols (17.7%, ES: 0.82 and 15.8%, ES: 0.89, respectively). Quadriceps CSA increased significantly for HL-RF (8.1%, ES: 0.57), HL-RNF (7.7%, ES: 0.60), and LL-RF (7.8%, ES: 0.45), whereas no significant changes were observed in the LL-RNF (2.8%, ES: 0.15). We conclude that when training with low loads, training with a high level of effort seems to have greater importance than total training volume in the accretion of muscle mass, whereas for high load training, muscle failure does not promote any additional benefits. Consistent with previous research, muscle strength gains are superior when using heavier loads.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lasevicius</LastName><ForeName>Thiago</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva-Batista</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Arts, Sciences and Humanities, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barros</LastName><ForeName>Talita de Souza</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aihara</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9; Yui</ForeName><Initials>AY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>America`s Diagnostics S/A, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brendon</LastName><ForeName>Helderson</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longo</LastName><ForeName>Ariel Roberth</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tricoli</LastName><ForeName>Valmor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peres</LastName><ForeName>Bergson de Almeida</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Emerson Luiz</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202202000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Administration of the Borg Scales. In: Borg's Perceived Exertion and Pain Scales. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 1998. pp. 44&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. ASEP procedures recommendation I: Accurate assessment of muscular strength and power. J Exerc Physiol Online 4: 1&#x2013;21, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol 588: 3119&#x2013;3130, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Staples AW, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS One 5: e12033, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Some issues in power analysis. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 531&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of training leading to repetition failure on muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 487&#x2013;502, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, Lindsell RP, et al. Training leading to repetition failure enhances bench press strength gains in elite junior athletes. J Strength Cond Res 19: 382&#x2013;388, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2691&#x2013;2703, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, De Paoli F, Bjerg K, et al. Blood flow restricted and traditional resistance training performed to fatigue produce equal muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports 25: 754&#x2013;763, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink J, Kikuchi N, Yoshida S, Terada K, Nakazato K. Impact of high versus low fixed loads and non-linear training loads on muscle hypertrophy, strength and force development. Springerplus 5: 698, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Irish C, Roberts J, Tarr J, Jones DA. Fatigue is not a necessary stimulus for strength gains during resistance training. Br J Sports Med 36: 370&#x2013;373, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC. The role of resistance exercise intensity on muscle fibre adaptations. Sports Med 34: 663&#x2013;679, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 955&#x2013;963, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayatpour N, Falla D. Non-uniform muscle adaptations to eccentric exercise and the implications for training and sport. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 22: 329&#x2013;333, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Gonzalez-Izal M, Navarro-Amezqueta I, et al. Effects of strength training on muscle fatigue mapping from surface EMG and blood metabolites. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 303&#x2013;311, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins ND, Housh TJ, Buckner SL, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations after 2 and 4 weeks of 80% versus 30% 1 repetition maximum resistance training to failure. J Strength Cond Res 30: 2174&#x2013;2185, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W, Adams K, Cafarelli E, et al. American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 34: 364&#x2013;380, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 772&#x2013;780, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnamo V, Pakarinen A, Komi PV, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute hormonal responses to submaximal and maximal heavy resistance and explosive exercises in men and women. J Strength Cond Res 19: 566, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Neya M, Ochi E, et al. Cross-transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc 40: 258, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martorelli S, Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, et al. Strength training with repetitions to failure does not provide additional strength and muscle hypertrophy gains in young women. Eur J Transl Myol 27: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol 113: 71&#x2013;77, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods 11: 364&#x2013;386, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, et al. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol 121: 129&#x2013;138, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs. volitional interruption at high-and low-intensities on muscle mass and strength. J Strength Cond Res 32: 162&#x2013;169, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Low-load bench press training to fatigue results in muscle hypertrophy similar to high-load bench press training. Int J Clin Med 4: 114, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2585&#x2013;2601, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Nygaard H, Raastad T. Physiological elevation of endogenous hormones results in superior strength training adaptation. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 2249&#x2013;2259, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney KJ, Herbert RD, Balnave RJ. Fatigue contributes to the strength training stimulus. Med Sci Sports Exerc 26: 1160&#x2013;1164, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to strength training. In: 2nd, ed. Strength and Power in Sports. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley-Blackwell, 2008. pp. 281&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson JA, Groeller H. Is repetition failure critical for the development of muscle hypertrophy and strength? Scand J Med Sci Sports 26: 375&#x2013;383, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low-vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2954&#x2013;2963, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Andersen CH, et al. Muscle activation strategies during strength training with heavy loading vs. repetitions to failure. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1897&#x2013;1903, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Wright JE, Vogel JA, et al. The influence of muscle metabolic characteristics on physical performance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 54: 237&#x2013;243, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Bautmans I, Coudyzer W, Boen F, Delecluse C. Low-and high-resistance exercise: Long-term adherence and motivation among older adults. Gerontology 61: 551&#x2013;560, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Ema R, Miyamoto N, Kawakami Y. Inter- and intramuscular differences in training-induced hypertrophy of the quadriceps femoris: Association with muscle activation during the first training session. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 37: 405&#x2013;412, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker KS, Kambadur R, Sharma M, Smith HK. Resistance training alters plasma myostatin but not IGF-1 in healthy men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 787&#x2013;793, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM. The application of training to failure in periodized multiple-set resistance exercise programs. J Strength Cond Res 21: 628, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>