<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40166787</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Blood Flow Restriction Training on the Upper Extremities: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e79876</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e79876</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e79876</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.79876</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>High-intensity training leads to muscle growth in the upper extremities but at the expense of a greater risk of damaging joints, ligaments, or tendons due to this region being more prone to injury. In contrast, low-intensity resistance training implements a low load with high repetition, which is safer but yields less muscle hypertrophy and greater time consumption. Blood flow restriction&#xa0;(BFR) training&#xa0;potentially provides a solution as it achieves the muscle growth and strengthening of high-intensity resistance training while safely performing low-intensity resistance training. This technique reduces venous return and arterial blood flow to the targeted limb, creating a physiological environment to induce muscle hypertrophy, increase strength, and prolong endurance while minimizing tissue stress. This study will analyze literature within the past 10 years on the usage of BFR training in the upper extremities. An extensive search on PubMed was performed using the term "blood flow restriction training upper extremity," which resulted in 98 articles that were narrowed down to 17 based on clinical trials and relevance to upper extremities. Results from this study demonstrate that BFR training enhances muscle hypertrophy and strength in the upper extremity muscles, including the biceps brachii and triceps brachii at low loads. Additionally, BFR training has been shown to promote adaptations in non-occluded muscles proximal and contralateral to the cuff location. Clinical applications include postoperative recovery, rehabilitation of rotator cuff injuries, and treatment of tendinopathies. BFR training offers an effective alternative to high-load resistance training for the upper extremities with promising applications in rehabilitation and injury prevention. Future research is necessary to address long-term effects, optimize protocols, and diversify its applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Sinnott et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinnott</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Florida International University, Herbert Wertheim College of Medicine, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Nova Southeastern University, Davie, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vanguri</LastName><ForeName>Pradeep</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Human Performance, Nova Southeastern University, Fort Lauderdale, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elbow injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shoulder injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper extremities</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40166787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11956748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.79876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Upper extremity injuries in crossfit athletes&#x2014;a review of the current literature. Nicolay RW, Moore LK, DeSena TD, Dines JS. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2022;15:402&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9463423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35867271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natural history of degenerative rotator cuff tears. Codding JL, Keener JD. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2018;11:77&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5825342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29411321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hughes L, Paton B, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1003&#x2013;1011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28259850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction training: implementation into clinical practice. Vanwye WR, Weatherholt AM, Mikesky AE. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10:649&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5609669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28966705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Re-tear rates following rotator cuff repair surgery. Routledge JC, Saber AY, Pennington N, Gupta N. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9981227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36874651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Pearson SJ, Hussain SR. Sports Med. 2015;45:187&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:61&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Differential training benefits and motor unit remodeling in wrist force precision tasks following high and low load blood flow restriction exercises under volume-matched conditions. Lin YT, Wong CM, Chen YC, Chen Y, Hwang IS. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2024;21:123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11264616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39030574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction training in patients with rotator cuff tendinopathy: a randomized, assessor-blinded, controlled trial. Kara D, Ozcakar L, Demirci S, Huri G, Duzgun I. Clin J Sport Med. 2024;34:10&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37706671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction: the metabolite/volume threshold theory. Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Wilson JM, Bemben MG. Med Hypotheses. 2011;77:748&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21840132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lower extremity blood flow restriction training in athletes significantly improves strength-related outcomes in 58% of studies compared to non-blood flow restriction control. Tollefson LV, Schoenecker J, Solie B, Monson J, LaPrade CM, Mullin EP, LaPrade RF. Arthroscopy. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39672247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction combined with resistance training on muscle strength and thickness improvement in young adults: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression. Ma F, He J, Wang Y. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1379605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11345148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39189029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upper-extremity blood flow restriction: the proximal, distal, and contralateral effects-a randomized controlled trial. Bowman EN, Elshaar R, Milligan H, et al. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2020;29:1267&#x2013;1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32423577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unilateral bicep curl hemodynamics: low-pressure continuous vs high-pressure intermittent blood flow restriction. Brandner CR, Kidgell DJ, Warmington SA. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25:770&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25055880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction training for the shoulder: a case for proximal benefit. Lambert B, Hedt C, Daum J, Taft C, Chaliki K, Epner E, McCulloch P. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49:2716&#x2013;2728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccentric, but not concentric blood flow restriction resistance training increases muscle strength in the untrained limb. Hill EC. Phys Ther Sport. 2020;43:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32035361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction attenuates eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage without perceptual and cardiovascular overload. Curty VM, Melo AB, Caldas LC, et al. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2018;38:468&#x2013;476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28444936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of cuff width on muscle adaptations after blood flow restriction training. Laurentino GC, Loenneke JP, Teixeira EL, Nakajima E, Iared W, Tricoli V. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:920&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26656773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross-transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Madarame H, Neya M, Ochi E, Nakazato K, Sato Y, Ishii N. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adaptations in maximal motor unit discharge rate to strength training in young and older adults. Patten C, Kamen G, Rowland DM. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:542&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11268027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross education of muscular strength during unilateral resistance training and detraining. Shima N, Ishida K, Katayama K, Morotome Y, Sato Y, Miyamura M. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;86:287&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11990741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterns of responses and time-course of changes in muscle size and strength during low-load blood flow restriction resistance training in women. Hill EC, Housh TJ, Keller JL, et al. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:1473&#x2013;1485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33638690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optimal blood flow restriction occlusion pressure for shoulder muscle recruitment with upper extremity exercise . Roehl T, Lambert BS, Ankersen J, Hernandez K, McCulloch PC, Hedt C. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51:1859&#x2013;1871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37092707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low-intensity climbing with blood flow restriction over 5 weeks increases grip and elbow flexor endurance in advanced climbers: a randomized controlled trial. Held S, Rappelt L, Rein R, Wiedenmann T, Donath L. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23:2031&#x2013;2037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37167343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotator cuff training with upper extremity blood flow restriction produces favorable adaptations in division IA collegiate pitchers: a randomized trial. Lambert BS, Hedt C, Ankersen JP, et al. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2023;32:0&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36933646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use and safety of KAATSU training: results of a national survey. Nakajima T, Kurano M, Iida H, et al. Int J KAATSU Training Res. 2006;2:5&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overall safety and risks associated with blood flow restriction therapy: a literature review. Anderson KD, Rask DM, Bates TJ, Nuelle JA. Mil Med. 2022;187:1059&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35284924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Application and side effects of blood flow restriction technique: a cross-sectional questionnaire survey of professionals. de Queiros VS, Dantas M, Neto GR, et al. Medicine (Baltimore) 2021;100:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8104249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33950976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The safety of blood flow restriction training as a therapeutic intervention for patients with musculoskeletal disorders: a systematic review. Minniti MC, Statkevich AP, Kelly RL, Rigsby VP, Exline MM, Rhon DI, Clewley D. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:1773&#x2013;1785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31710505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood flow restriction training and the exercise pressor reflex: a call for concern. Spranger MD, Krishnan AC, Levy PD, O'Leary DS, Smith SA. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2015;309:0&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26342064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical safety of blood flow-restricted training? A comprehensive review of altered muscle metaboreflex in cardiovascular disease during ischemic exercise. Cristina-Oliveira M, Meireles K, Spranger MD, O'Leary DS, Roschel H, Pe&#xe7;anha T. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2020;318:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31702969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A useful blood flow restriction training risk stratification for exercise and rehabilitation. Nascimento DD, Rolnick N, Neto IV, Severin R, Beal FL. Front Physiol. 2022;13:808622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8963452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>