<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37994729</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Conserved and species-specific transcriptional responses to daily programmed resistance exercise in rat and mouse.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e23299</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e23299</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202301611R</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mice are often used in gain or loss of function studies to understand how genes regulate metabolism and adaptation to exercise in skeletal muscle. Once-daily resistance training with electrical nerve stimulation produces hypertrophy of the dorsiflexors in rat, but not in mouse. Using implantable pulse generators, we assessed the acute transcriptional response (1-h post-exercise) after 2, 10, and 20&#x2009;days of training in free-living mice and rats using identical nerve stimulation paradigms. RNA sequencing revealed strong concordance in the timecourse of many transcriptional responses in the tibialis anterior muscles of both species including responses related to "stress responses/immediate-early genes, and "collagen homeostasis," "ribosomal subunits," "autophagy," and "focal adhesion." However, pathways associated with energy metabolism including "carbon metabolism," "oxidative phosphorylation," "mitochondrial translation," "propanoate metabolism," and "valine, leucine, and isoleucine degradation" were oppositely regulated between species. These pathways were suppressed in the rat but upregulated in the mouse. Our transcriptional analysis suggests that although many pathways associated with growth show remarkable similarities between species, the absence of an actual growth response in the mouse may be because the mouse prioritizes energy metabolism, specifically the replenishment of fuel stores and intermediate metabolites.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. The FASEB Journal published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viggars</LastName><ForeName>Mark R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0722-7051</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport &amp; Exercise Science, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Aging, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Myology Institute, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sutherland</LastName><ForeName>Hazel</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5570-1379</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport &amp; Exercise Science, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardozo</LastName><ForeName>Christopher P</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4013-2537</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spinal Cord Damage Research Center, James J. Peters VA Medical Center, Bronx, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine, Mount Sinai, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jarvis</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8982-6279</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport &amp; Exercise Science, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>SC190031</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Department of Defense (DOD)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>I50RX002020</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs (VA)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014176" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Biosynthesis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle atrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcription</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37994729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202301611R</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Gale CR, Martyn CN, Cooper C, Sayer AA. Grip strength, body composition, and mortality. Int J Epidemiol. 2007;36(1):228-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Kupelian V, Visser M, et&#xa0;al. Strength, but not muscle mass, is associated with mortality in the health, aging and body composition study cohort. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61(1):72-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcos DM, Robichaud JA, David FJ, et&#xa0;al. A two-year randomized controlled trial of progressive resistance exercise for Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2013;28(9):1230-1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashida R, Kawaguchi T, Bekki M, et&#xa0;al. Aerobic vs. resistance exercise in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review. J Hepatol. 2017;66(1):142-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcleod JC, Stokes T, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise training as a primary countermeasure to age-related chronic disease. Front Physiol. 2019;10:645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braith RW, Stewart KJ. Resistance exercise training: its role in the prevention of cardiovascular disease. Circulation. 2006;113(22):2642-2650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC, Stitt TN, Gonzalez M, et&#xa0;al. Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy in&#xa0;vivo. Nat Cell Biol. 2001;3(11):1014-1019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass DJ. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy and atrophy signaling pathways. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2005;37(10):1974-1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Fujita S, Hornberger TA, et&#xa0;al. The role of mTOR signalling in the regulation of skeletal muscle mass in a rodent model of resistance exercise. Sci Rep. 2016;6(1):31142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Arihara Y, Takegaki J, Nakazato K, Ishii N. Relationship between exercise volume and muscle protein synthesis in a rat model of resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2017;123(4):710-716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinert ND, Potts GK, Wilson GM, et&#xa0;al. Mapping of the contraction-induced phosphoproteome identifies TRIM28 as a significant regulator of skeletal muscle size and function. Cell Rep. 2021;34(9):108796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GR, Zhao B, Lindholm ME, et&#xa0;al. Multiomic identification of key transcriptional regulatory programs during endurance exercise training. bioRxiv 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JJ, Srikuea R, Kirby TJ, Peterson CA, Esser KA. Inducible Cre transgenic mouse strain for skeletal muscle-specific gene targeting. Skelet Muscle. 2012;2:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach KA, McCarthy JJ, Peterson CA, Dungan CM. Making mice mighty: recent advances in translational models of load-induced muscle hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol. 2020;129(3):516-521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar K, Esser K. Phosphorylation of p70(S6k) correlates with increased skeletal muscle mass following resistance exercise. Am J Physiol. 1999;276(1):C120-C127. doi:10.1152/ajpcell.1999.276.1.C120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader GA, Esser KA. Intracellular signaling specificity in skeletal muscle in response to different modes of exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2001;90(5):1936-1942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viggars MR, Sutherland H, Lanm&#xfc;ller H, Schmoll M, Bijak M, Jarvis JC. Adaptation of the transcriptional response to resistance exercise over 4&#x2009;weeks of daily training. FASEB J. 2022;37(1):e22686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmoll M, Unger E, Sutherland H, et&#xa0;al. SpillOver stimulation: a novel hypertrophy model using co-contraction of the plantar-flexors to load the tibial anterior muscle in rats. PloS One. 2018;13(11):e0207886. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0207886</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viggars MR, Wen Y, Peterson CA, Jarvis JC. Automated cross-sectional analysis of trained, severely atrophied and recovering rat skeletal muscles using MyoVision 2.0. J Appl Physiol. 2022;132:593-610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Mangum JE, Gao S, et&#xa0;al. Eccentric contraction-induced myofiber growth in tumor-bearing mice. J Appl Physiol. 2016;120(1):29-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Gao S, Puppa MJ, Kostek MC, Wilson LB, Carson JA. High-frequency stimulation on skeletal muscle maintenance in female cachectic mice. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(9):1828-1837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotri-Koffi A, Pauly M, Lemari&#xe9; E, et&#xa0;al. Chronic neuromuscular electrical stimulation improves muscle mass and insulin sensitivity in a mouse model. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):7252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You J-S, McNally RM, Jacobs BL, et&#xa0;al. The role of raptor in the mechanical load-induced regulation of mTOR signaling, protein synthesis, and skeletal muscle hypertrophy. FASEB J. 2019;33(3):4021-4034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potts GK, McNally RM, Blanco R, et&#xa0;al. A map of the phosphoproteomic alterations that occur after a bout of maximal-intensity contractions. J Physiol. 2017;595(15):5209-5226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viggars MR, Owens DJ, Stewart C, Coirault C, Mackey AL, Jarvis JC. PCM1 labeling reveals myonuclear and nuclear dynamics in skeletal muscle across species. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2023;324(1):C85-C97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owens DJ, Mess&#xe9;ant J, Moog S, et&#xa0;al. Lamin-related congenital muscular dystrophy alters mechanical signaling and skeletal muscle growth. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(1):306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes DC, Turner DC, Baehr LM, et&#xa0;al. Knockdown of the E3 ubiquitin ligase UBR5 and its role in skeletal muscle anabolism. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2021;320(1):C45-C56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobin A, Davis CA, Schlesinger F, et&#xa0;al. STAR: ultrafast universal RNA-seq aligner. Bioinformatics. 2013;29(1):15-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jong TV, Chen H, Brashear WA, et&#xa0;al. mRatBN7. 2: familiar and unfamiliar features of a new rat genome reference assembly. Physiol Genomics. 2022;54(7):251-260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howe K, Dwinell M, Shimoyama M, et&#xa0;al. The genome sequence of the Norway rat, Rattus norvegicus Berkenhout 1769. Wellcome Open Res. 2021;6(118):118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Love MI, Huber W, Anders S. Moderated estimation of fold change and dispersion for RNA-seq data with DESeq2. Genome Biol. 2014;15(12):550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis G, Sherman BT, Hosack DA, et&#xa0;al. DAVID: database for annotation, visualization, and integrated discovery. Genome Biol. 2003;4(9):P3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AM, Steen CB, Liu CL, et&#xa0;al. Determining cell type abundance and expression from bulk tissues with digital cytometry. Nat Biotechnol. 2019;37(7):773-782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach KA, Liu Z, Jude B, et&#xa0;al. Multi-transcriptome analysis following an acute skeletal muscle growth stimulus yields tools for discerning global and MYC regulatory networks. J Biol Chem. 2022;298(11):102515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashida Y, Himori K, Tatebayashi D, Yamada R, Ogasawara R, Yamada T. Effects of contraction mode and stimulation frequency on electrical stimulation-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol. 2018;124(2):341-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaillou T. Ribosome specialization and its potential role in the control of protein translation and skeletal muscle size. J Appl Physiol. 2019;127:599-607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaillou T, Zhang X, McCarthy JJ. Expression of muscle-specific ribosomal protein L3-like impairs myotube growth. J Cell Physiol. 2016;231(9):1894-1902. doi:10.1002/jcp.25294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shavlakadze T, Xiong K, Mishra S, et&#xa0;al. Age-related gene expression signatures from limb skeletal muscles and the diaphragm in mice and rats reveal common and species-specific changes. Skel Muscle. 2023;13(1):11. doi:10.1186/s13395-023-00321-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher AG, Seaborne RA, Hughes TM, et&#xa0;al. Transcriptomic and epigenetic regulation of disuse atrophy and the return to activity in skeletal muscle. FASEB J. 2017;31(12):5268-5282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murton A, Constantin D, Greenhaff P. The involvement of the ubiquitin proteasome system in human skeletal muscle remodelling and atrophy. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2008;1782(12):730-743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC, Baehr LM. Skeletal muscle atrophy and the E3 ubiquitin ligases MuRF1 and MAFbx/atrogin-1. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2014;307(6):E469-E484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You J-S, Anderson GB, Dooley MS, Hornberger TA. The role of mTOR signaling in the regulation of protein synthesis and muscle mass during immobilization in mice. Dis Model Mech. 2015;8(9):1059-1069. doi:10.1242/dmm.019414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai S, Sitzmann JM, Dastidar SG, et&#xa0;al. Muscle-specific 4E-BP1 signaling activation improves metabolic parameters during aging and obesity. J Clin Invest. 2015;125(8):2952-2964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Mobley CB, Vann CG, et&#xa0;al. Synergist ablation-induced hypertrophy occurs more rapidly in the plantaris than soleus muscle in rats due to different molecular mechanisms. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2020;318(2):R360-R368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoneau J-A, Pette D. Species-specific effects of chronic nerve stimulation upon tibialis anterior muscle in mouse, rat, Guinea pig, and rabbit. Pflugers Arch. 1988;412:86-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furrer R, Heim B, Schmid S, et&#xa0;al. Molecular control of endurance training adaptation in mouse skeletal muscle. bioRxiv 2023. doi:10.1101/2023.02.18.529055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbom JM, Ydfors M, Lovric A, Perry CG, Rundqvist H, Rullman E. A HIF-1 signature dominates the attenuation in the human skeletal muscle transcriptional response to high-intensity interval training. J Appl Physiol. 2022;132(6):1448-1459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry CG, Lally J, Holloway GP, Heigenhauser GJ, Bonen A, Spriet LL. Repeated transient mRNA bursts precede increases in transcriptional and mitochondrial proteins during training in human skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2010;588(23):4795-4810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jandova T, Narici MV, Steffl M, et&#xa0;al. Muscle hypertrophy and architectural changes in response to eight-week neuromuscular electrical stimulation training in healthy older people. Life. 2020;10(9):184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barberi L, Scicchitano BM, Musaro A. Molecular and cellular mechanisms of muscle aging and sarcopenia and effects of electrical stimulation in seniors. Eur J Transl Myol. 2015;25(4):231-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern H, Hofer C, Loefler S, et&#xa0;al. Atrophy, ultra-structural disorders, severe atrophy and degeneration of denervated human muscle in SCI and Aging. Implications for their recovery by Functional Electrical Stimulation, updated 2017. Neurol Res. 2017;39(7):660-666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group MS, Amar D, Gay NR, et&#xa0;al. Temporal dynamics of the multi-omic response to endurance exercise training across tissues. BioRxiv 2022. doi:10.1101/2022.09.21.508770</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>