<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">26689694</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1945-5763</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Season>Fall</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Topics in spinal cord injury rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuromuscular Electrical Stimulation-Induced Resistance Training After SCI: A Review of the Dudley Protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>294</StartPage><EndPage>302</EndPage><MedlinePgn>294-302</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1310/sci2104-294</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES), often referred to as functional electrical stimulation (FES), has been used to activate paralyzed skeletal muscle in people with spinal cord injury (SCI). The goal of NMES has been to reverse some of the dramatic losses in skeletal muscle mass, to stimulate functional improvements in people with incomplete paralysis, and to produce some of the health benefits associated with exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this brief review is to describe a quantifiable resistance training form of NMES developed by Gary A. Dudley.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">People with motor complete SCI were first tested to confirm that an NMES-induced muscle contraction of the quadriceps muscle could be achieved. The contraction stimulus consisted of biphasic pulses at 35 Hz performed with increasing current up to what was needed to produce full knee extension. Four sets of 10 knee extensions were elicited, if possible. Training occurred biweekly for 3 to 6 months, with ankle weights being increased up to an added weight of 9.1 kg if the 40 repetitions could be performed successfully for 2 sessions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Many participants have performed this protocol without adverse events, and all participants showed progression in the number of repetitions and/or the amount of weight lifted. Large increases in muscle mass occur, averaging 30% to 40%. Additional physiological adaptations to stimulated muscle have also been reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results demonstrate that the affected skeletal muscle after SCI responds robustly to progressive resistance training many years after injury. Future work with NMES should determine whether gains in lean mass translate to improved health, function, and quality of life.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bickel</LastName><ForeName>C Scott</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Physical Therapy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UAB Center for Exercise Medicine, University of Alabama at Birmingham.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yarar-Fisher</LastName><ForeName>Ceren</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Sciences.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UAB Center for Exercise Medicine, University of Alabama at Birmingham.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahoney</LastName><ForeName>Edward T</ForeName><Initials>ET</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCully</LastName><ForeName>Kevin K</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD039676</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01HD039676</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9515174</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1082-0744</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004558" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electric Stimulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004599" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electric Stimulation Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013119" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal cord injury</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4750814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1310/sci2104-294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, He X. A meta-analysis of the motion function through the therapy of spinal cord injury with intravenous transplantation of bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells in rats. PloS One. 2014;9(4):e93487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3972121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24690752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angeli CA, Edgerton VR, Gerasimenko YP, Harkema SJ. Altering spinal cord excitability enables voluntary movements after chronic complete paralysis in humans. Brain. 2014;137(pt 5):1394&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3999714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24713270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruciger O, Tegenthoff M, Schwenkreis P, Schildhauer TA, Aach M. Locomotion training using voluntary driven exoskeleton (HAL) in acute incomplete SCI. Neurology. 2014;83(5):474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25074892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro MJ, Apple DF, Jr, Hillegass EA, Dudley GA. Influence of complete spinal cord injury on skeletal muscle cross-sectional area within the first 6 months of injury. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1999;80(4):373&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10483809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spungen AM, Adkins RH, Stewart CA, et al. Factors influencing body composition in persons with spinal cord injury: A cross-sectional study. J Appl Physiol. 2003;95(6):2398&#x2013;2407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12909613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cragg JJ, Noonan VK, Noreau L, Borisoff JF, Kramer JK. Neuropathic pain, depression, and cardiovascular disease: A national multicenter study. Neuroepidemiology. 2015;44(3):130&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25896718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gater DR., Jr Obesity after spinal cord injury. Phys Med Rehabil Clinics N Am. 2007;18(2):333&#x2013;351, vii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17543776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby G, Broberg C, Krotkiewska I, Krotkiewski M. Muscle fiber composition in patients with traumatic cord lesion. Scand J Rehabil Med. 1976;8(1):37&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">132700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stilwill EW, Sahgal V. Histochemical and morphologic changes in skeletal muscle following cervical cord injury: A study of upper and lower motor neuron lesions. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1977;58(5):201&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">66912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scelsi R, Marchetti C, Poggi P, Lotta S, Lommi G. Muscle fiber type morphology and distribution in paraplegic patients with traumatic cord lesion. Histochemical and ultrastructural aspects of rectus femoris muscle. Acta Neuropathol (Berl). 1982;57(4):243&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7136501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnham R, Martin T, Stein R, Bell G, MacLean I, Steadward R. Skeletal muscle fibre type transformation following spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 1997;35(2):86&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9044514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro MJ, Apple DF, Jr., Staron RS, Campos GE, Dudley GA. Influence of complete spinal cord injury on skeletal muscle within 6 mo of injury. J Appl Physiol. 1999;86(1):350&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9887150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel CS, Slade JM, Dudley GA. Long-term spinal cord injury increases susceptibility to isometric contraction-induced muscle injury. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;91(2&#x2013;3):308&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14586584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Jeon J, Weiss C, Bell G, Burnham R. Histochemical changes in muscle of individuals with spinal cord injury following functional electrical stimulated exercise training. Spinal Cord. 1999;37(4):264&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10338346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr T, Andersen JL, Biering-Sorensen F, et al. Longterm adaptation to electrically induced cycle training in severe spinal cord injured individuals. Spinal Cord. 1997;35(1):1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9025213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochester L, Chandler CS, Johnson MA, Sutton RA, Miller S. Influence of electrical stimulation of the tibialis anterior muscle in paraplegic subjects. 1. Contractile properties. Paraplegia. 1995;33(8):437&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7478737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frotzler A, Coupaud S, Perret C, et al. High-volume FES-cycling partially reverses bone loss in people with chronic spinal cord injury. Bone. 2008;43(1):169&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18440891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudley GA, Castro MJ, Rogers S, Apple DF., Jr A simple means of increasing muscle size after spinal cord injury: A pilot study. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1999;80(4):394&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10483812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney ET, Bickel CS, Elder C, et al. Changes in skeletal muscle size and glucose tolerance with electrically stimulated resistance training in subjects with chronic spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2005;86(7):1502&#x2013;1504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16003691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan TE, Brizendine JT, Backus D, McCully KK. Electrically induced resistance training in individuals with motor complete spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;94(11):2166&#x2013;2173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23816921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgey AS, Mather KJ, Cupp HR, Gater DR. Effects of resistance training on adiposity and metabolism after spinal cord injury. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(1):165&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21659900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruther CL, Golden CL, Harris RT, Dudley GA. Hypertrophy, resistance training, and the nature of skeletal muscle activation. J Strength Cond Res. 1995;9(3):155&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson SW, Dudley GA. Dietary creatine supplementation and muscular adaptation to resistive overload. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(8): 1304&#x2013;1310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11474331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Dickinson A, Pattany PM, Fleck SJ. Muscle fiber hypertrophy, hyperplasia, and capillary density in college men after resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81(5):2004&#x2013;2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8941522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgey AS, Shepherd C. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy and decreased intramuscular fat after unilateral resistance training in spinal cord injury: Case report. J Spinal Cord Med. 2010;33(1):90&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2853337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloan KE, Bremner LA, Byrne J, Day RE, Scull ER. Musculoskeletal effects of an electrical stimulation induced cycling programme in the spinal injured. Paraplegia. 1994;32(6):407&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8090549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hather BM, Tesch PA, Buchanan P, Dudley GA. Influence of eccentric actions on skeletal muscle adaptations to resistance training. Acta Physiol Scand. 1991;143(2):177&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1835816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatier MJ, Stoner L, Mahoney ET, et al. Electrically stimulated resistance training in SCI individuals increases muscle fatigue resistance but not femoral artery size or blood flow. Spinal Cord. 2006;44(4):227&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16158074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney E, Puetz TW, Dudley GA, McCully KK. Low-frequency fatigue in individuals with spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med. 2007;30(5):458&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2141726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18092561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoner L, Sabatier MJ, Mahoney ET, Dudley GA, McCully KK. Electrical stimulation-evoked resistance exercise therapy improves arterial health after chronic spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2007;45(1):49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16718276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginis KA, Hicks AL, Latimer AE, et al. The development of evidence-informed physical activity guidelines for adults with spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2011;49(11):1088&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modlesky CM, Slade JM, Bickel CS, Meyer RA, Dudley GA. Deteriorated geometric structure and strength of the midfemur in men with complete spinal cord injury. Bone. 2005;36(2):331&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15780960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modlesky CM, Majumdar S, Narasimhan A, Dudley GA. Trabecular bone microarchitecture is deteriorated in men with spinal cord injury. J Bone Miner Res. 2004;19(1):48&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14753736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade JM, Bickel CS, Modlesky CM, Majumdar S, Dudley GA. Trabecular bone is more deteriorated in spinal cord injured versus estrogenfree postmenopausal women. Osteoporos Int. 2005;16(3):263&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15338112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields RK, Dudley-Javoroski S. Musculoskeletal plasticity after acute spinal cord injury: Effects of long-term neuromuscular electrical stimulation training. J Neurophysiol. 2006;95(4):2380&#x2013;2390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3298883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16407424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>