<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41474371</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance training load does not determine resistance training-induced hypertrophy across upper and lower limbs in healthy young males.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP289684</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Resistance exercise training (RET) leads to marked interindividual heterogeneity in the hypertrophic response. Whether such heterogeneity is due to endogenous (i.e. inherent biological factors) or exogenous variables (i.e. external load) has not been firmly established. Twenty healthy young male participants completed thrice-weekly resistance exercise sessions for 10&#xa0;weeks. Each participant had their legs and arms randomly assigned to perform unilateral bicep curls or knee extensions with either a higher (heavier) load (HL: 8-12 repetitions; &#x223c;70%-80% of one-repetition maximum (1RM)) or, in the contralateral limb, lower load (LL: 20-25 repetitions at &#x223c;30%-40% 1RM) for three sets to volitional fatigue during each session. Fat- and bone-free mass (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry), muscle size (ultrasonography and muscle biopsies) and strength were measured pretraining and at 10&#xa0;weeks. Skeletal muscle biopsies were obtained from the vastus lateralis, and we used ingested deuterated water to assess myofibrillar protein synthesis (MyoPS) at weeks 1 and 10 during training. Despite considerable interindividual variability in hypertrophic responses, we observed that muscle hypertrophy following RET was relatively well conserved within versus between subjects and was unaffected by load. Rates of MyoPS in weeks 1 and 10 of training were increased relative to rest (Week 1: &#x394;0.27&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.11, P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001; Week 10: &#x394;0.10&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.14%/d, P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.009); however, MyoPS was attenuated in week 10 versus week 1 (&#x394;0.16&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.18%/d, P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). MyoPS rates were less heterogenous within versus between individuals. Variation in RET-induced muscle hypertrophy occurred independent of external load and was relatively well conserved (i.e., retention of the hypertrophic response) across different anatomical limbs within an individual. KEY POINTS: Considerable interindividual variability exists in resistance exercise training (RET)-induced muscle hypertrophy. However we observed that RET-induced muscle hypertrophy is relatively conserved within an individual (i.e. between the upper- and lower body) and is independent of external load when RET is performed to volitional fatigue. Changes in myofibrillar protein synthesis (MyoPS) rates are comparable with both higher and lower loads but are blunted following a period of RET despite progressive overload. There is negligible shared variance between RET-induced increases in muscle size and strength. Additionally, there are limited relationships between measures used to assess RET-induced muscle hypertrophy. We conclude that when effort is matched (i.e. working to volitional muscular fatigue), RET-induced hypertrophy is mediated to a far greater degree by inherent endogenous biological factors, which account for a large proportion of the heterogeneity between individuals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). The Journal of Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lees</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mcleod</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Health Studies, Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morton</LastName><ForeName>Robert W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Currier</LastName><ForeName>Brad S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fliss</LastName><ForeName>Matthew D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McKellar</LastName><ForeName>Sean R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sidhu</LastName><ForeName>Rajbir S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stansfield</LastName><ForeName>Ben N</ForeName><Initials>BN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Webb</LastName><ForeName>Erin K</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGlory</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Health Studies, Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burniston</LastName><ForeName>Jatin G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Stuart M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1956-4098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RGPIN-2020-06346</GrantID><Agency>Canadian Government | Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CRC-2021-00495</GrantID><Agency>Canada Research Chairs (Chaires de recherche du Canada)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein metabolism</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41474371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP289684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen, J. P., Walker, S., Peltonen, H., Holviala, J., Sillanpaa, E., Karavirta, L., Sallinen, J., Mikkola, J., Valkeinen, H., Mero, A., Hulmi, J. J., &amp; Hakkinen, K. (2016). Heterogeneity in resistance training&#x2010;induced muscle strength and mass responses in men and women of different ages. Age (Dordr), 38(1), 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri, V., Damas, F., Phillips, S. M., Selistre&#x2010;de&#x2010;Araujo, H. S., Cornachione, A. S., Stotzer, U. S., Santanielo, N., Soligon, S. D., Costa, L. A. R., Lixandrao, M. E., Conceicao, M. S., Vechin, F. C., Ugrinowitsch, C., &amp; Libardi, C. A. (2022). Resistance training variable manipulations are less relevant than intrinsic biology in affecting muscle fiber hypertrophy. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 32(5), 821&#x2013;832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook, M. S., Wilkinson, D. J., Mitchell, W. K., Lund, J. N., Szewczyk, N. J., Greenhaff, P. L., Smith, K., &amp; Atherton, P. J. (2015). Skeletal muscle hypertrophy adaptations predominate in the early stages of resistance exercise training, matching deuterium oxide&#x2010;derived measures of muscle protein synthesis and mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 signaling. Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology Journal, 29(11), 4485&#x2013;4496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho, L., Junior, R. M., Barreira, J., Schoenfeld, B. J., Orazem, J., &amp; Barroso, R. (2022). Muscle hypertrophy and strength gains after resistance training with different volume&#x2010;matched loads: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism = Physiologie Appliquee, Nutrition et Metabolisme, 47(4), 357&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charbonneau, D. E., Hanson, E. D., Ludlow, A. T., Delmonico, M. J., Hurley, B. F., &amp; Roth, S. M. (2008). ACE genotype and the muscle hypertrophic and strength responses to strength training. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 40(4), 677&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholewa, J., Rossi, F. E., MacDonald, C., Hewins, A., Gallo, S., Micenski, A., Norton, L., &amp; Campbell, B. I. (2018). The effects of moderate&#x2010; versus high&#x2010;load training on body composition, muscle growth, and performance in college aged females. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 32(6), 1511&#x2013;1524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward&#x2010;Venne, T. A., Tieland, M., Verdijk, L. B., Leenders, M., Dirks, M. L., de Groot, L. C., &amp; van Loon, L. J. (2015). There are no nonresponders to resistance&#x2010;type exercise training in older men and women. Journal of the American Medical Directors Association, 16(5), 400&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counts, B. R., Buckner, S. L., Dankel, S. J., Jessee, M. B., Mattocks, K. T., Mouser, J. G., Laurentino, G. C., &amp; Loenneke, J. P. (2016). The acute and chronic effects of &#x201c;NO LOAD&#x201d; resistance training. Physiology &amp; Behavior, 164(Pt A), 345&#x2013;352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha, P. M., Nunes, J. P., Tomeleri, C. M., Nascimento, M. A., Schoenfeld, B. J., Antunes, M., Gobbo, L. A., Teixeira, D., &amp; Cyrino, E. S. (2020). Resistance training performed with single and multiple sets induces similar improvements in muscular strength, muscle mass, muscle quality, and IGF&#x2010;1 in older women: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 34(4), 1008&#x2013;1016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currier, B. S., McLeod, J. C., Banfield, L., Beyene, J., Welton, N. J., D'Souza, A. C., Keogh, J. A. J., Lin, L., Coletta, G., Yang, A., Colenso&#x2010;Semple, L., Lau, K. J., Verboom, A., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2023). Resistance training prescription for muscle strength and hypertrophy in healthy adults: A systematic review and bayesian network meta&#x2010;analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 57(18), 1211&#x2013;1220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas, F., Angleri, V., Phillips, S. M., Witard, O. C., Ugrinowitsch, C., Santanielo, N., Soligon, S. D., Costa, L. A. R., Lixandr&#xe3;o, M. E., Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o, M. S., &amp; Libardi, C. A. (2019). Myofibrillar protein synthesis and muscle hypertrophy individualized responses to systematically changing resistance training variables in trained young men. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 127(3), 806&#x2013;815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas, F., Phillips, S. M., Libardi, C. A., Vechin, F. C., Lixandr&#xe3;o, M. E., Jannig, P. R., Costa, L. A., Bacurau, A. V., Snijders, T., Parise, G., Tricoli, V., Roschel, H., &amp; Ugrinowitsch, C. (2016). Resistance training&#x2010;induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. The Journal of Physiology, 594(18), 5209&#x2013;5222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidsen, P. K., Gallagher, I. J., Hartman, J. W., Tarnopolsky, M. A., Dela, F., Helge, J. W., Timmons, J. A., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2011). High responders to resistance exercise training demonstrate differential regulation of skeletal muscle microRNA expression. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 110(2), 309&#x2013;317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dufner, D. A., Bederman, I. R., Brunengraber, D. Z., Rachdaoui, N., Ismail&#x2010;Beigi, F., Siegfried, B. A., Kimball, S. R., &amp; Previs, S. F. (2005). Using 2H2O to study the influence of feeding on protein synthesis: Effect of isotope equilibration in vivo vs. in cell culture. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Endocrinology and Metabolism, 288(6), E1277&#x2013;E1283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine, R. M., Fletcher, G., &amp; Folland, J. P. (2014). The contribution of muscle hypertrophy to strength changes following resistance training. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 114(6), 1239&#x2013;1249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine, R. M., Williams, A. G., Jones, D. A., Stewart, C. E., &amp; Degens, H. (2014). The individual and combined influence of ACE and ACTN3 genotypes on muscle phenotypes before and after strength training. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 24(4), 642&#x2013;648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher, J. P., &amp; Steele, J. (2017). Heavier and lighter load resistance training to momentary failure produce similar increases in strength with differing degrees of discomfort. Muscle &amp; Nerve, 56(4), 797&#x2013;803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun, C. T., Vann, C. G., Roberts, B. M., Vigotsky, A. D., Schoenfeld, B. J., &amp; Roberts, M. D. (2019). A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Size matters but so does the measurement. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holwerda, A. M., Paulussen, K. J. M., Overkamp, M., Smeets, J. S. J., Gijsen, A. P., Goessens, J. P. B., Verdijk, L. B., &amp; van Loon, L. J. C. (2018). Daily resistance&#x2010;type exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis in vivo in young men. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 124(1), 66&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal, M. J., Gordish&#x2010;Dressman, H., Thompson, P. D., Price, T. B., Hoffman, E. P., Angelopoulos, T. J., Gordon, P. M., Moyna, N. M., Pescatello, L. S., Visich, P. S., Zoeller, R. F., Seip, R. L., &amp; Clarkson, P. M. (2005). Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 37(6), 964&#x2013;972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakubowski, J. S., Wong, E. P. T., Nunes, E. A., Noguchi, K. S., Vandeweerd, J. K., Murphy, K. T., Morton, R. W., McGlory, C., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2019). Equivalent hypertrophy and strength gains in beta&#x2010;hydroxy&#x2010;beta&#x2010;methylbutyrate&#x2010; or leucine&#x2010;supplemented men. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 51(1), 65&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee, M. B., Buckner, S. L., Mouser, J. G., Mattocks, K. T., Dankel, S. J., Abe, T., Bell, Z. W., Bentley, J. P., &amp; Loenneke, J. P. (2018). Muscle adaptations to high&#x2010;load training and very low&#x2010;load training with and without blood flow restriction. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 1448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse, S., Lim, C., McKendry, J., McLeod, J. C., Stokes, T., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2020). Recent advances in understanding resistance exercise training&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy in humans. F1000Research, 9, 141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgenson, K. W., Hibbert, J. E., Sayed, R. K. A., Lange, A. N., Godwin, J. S., Mesquita, P. H. C., Ruple, B. A., McIntosh, M. C., Kavazis, A. N., Roberts, M. D., &amp; Hornberger, T. A. (2024). A novel imaging method (FIM&#x2010;ID) reveals that myofibrillogenesis plays a major role in the mechanically induced growth of skeletal muscle. eLife, 12, RP92674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, P. L., Staron, R. S., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2005). Fasted&#x2010;state skeletal muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise is altered with training. The Journal of Physiology, 568(1), 283&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavin, K. M., Bell, M. B., McAdam, J. S., Peck, B. D., Walton, R. G., Windham, S. T., Tuggle, S. C., Long, D. E., Kern, P. A., Peterson, C. A., &amp; Bamman, M. M. (2021). Muscle transcriptional networks linked to resistance exercise training hypertrophic response heterogeneity. Physiological Genomics, 53(5), 206&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, C., Nunes, E. A., Currier, B. S., McLeod, J. C., Thomas, A. C. Q., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2022). An evidence&#x2010;based narrative review of mechanisms of resistance exercise&#x2010;induced human skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 54(9), 1546&#x2013;1559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao, M. E., Ugrinowitsch, C., Bottaro, M., Chacon&#x2010;Mikahil, M. P., Cavaglieri, C. R., Min, L. L., de Souza, E. O., Laurentino, G. C., &amp; Libardi, C. A. (2014). Vastus lateralis muscle cross&#x2010;sectional area ultrasonography validity for image fitting in humans. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 28(11), 3293&#x2013;3297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke, J. P., Buckner, S. L., Dankel, S. J., &amp; Abe, T. (2019). Exercise&#x2010;induced changes in muscle size do not contribute to exercise&#x2010;induced changes in muscle strength. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 49(7), 987&#x2013;991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, D. E., Peck, B. D., Lavin, K. M., Dungan, C. M., Kosmac, K., Tuggle, S. C., Bamman, M. M., Kern, P. A., &amp; Peterson, C. A. (2022). Skeletal muscle properties show collagen organization and immune cell content are associated with resistance exercise response heterogeneity in older persons. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 132(6), 1432&#x2013;1447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez, P., Radaelli, R., Taaffe, D. R., Newton, R. U., Galvao, D. A., Trajano, G. S., Teodoro, J. L., Kraemer, W. J., Hakkinen, K., &amp; Pinto, R. S. (2021). Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: Systematic review and network meta&#x2010;analysis. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 53(6), 1206&#x2013;1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald, A. J., Small, A. C., Greig, C. A., Husi, H., Ross, J. A., Stephens, N. A., Fearon, K. C., &amp; Preston, T. (2013). A novel oral tracer procedure for measurement of habitual myofibrillar protein synthesis. Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry, 27(15), 1769&#x2013;1777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis, M. J., McGlory, C., Gibala, M. J., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2017). Investigating human skeletal muscle physiology with unilateral exercise models: When one limb is more powerful than two. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism = Physiologie Appliquee, Nutrition et Metabolisme, 42(6), 563&#x2013;570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca, A., Dragone, D., Dvir, Z., &amp; Deriu, F. (2017). Cross&#x2010;education of muscular strength following unilateral resistance training: A meta&#x2010;analysis. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 117(11), 2335&#x2013;2354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manca, A., Hortobagyi, T., Carroll, T. J., Enoka, R. M., Farthing, J. P., Gandevia, S. C., Kidgell, D. J., Taylor, J. L., &amp; Deriu, F. (2021). Contralateral effects of unilateral strength and skill training: Modified delphi consensus to establish key aspects of cross&#x2010;education. Sports Medicine (Auckland, N.Z.), 51(1), 11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattioni Maturana, F., Soares, R. N., Murias, J. M., Schellhorn, P., Erz, G., Burgstahler, C., Widmann, M., Munz, B., Thiel, A., &amp; Nie&#xdf;, A. M. (2021). Responders and non&#x2010;responders to aerobic exercise training: Beyond the evaluation of V&#x2d9;O2max. Physiological Reports, 9(16), e14951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks, K. T., Buckner, S. L., Jessee, M. B., Dankel, S. J., Mouser, J. G., &amp; Loenneke, J. P. (2017). Practicing the test produces strength equivalent to higher volume training. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 49(9), 1945&#x2013;1954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory, C., von Allmen, M. T., Stokes, T., Morton, R. W., Hector, A. J., Lago, B. A., Raphenya, A. R., Smith, B. K., McArthur, A. G., Steinberg, G. R., Baker, S. K., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2018). Failed recovery of glycemic control and myofibrillar protein synthesis with 2 wk of physical inactivity in overweight, prediabetic older adults. Journals of Gerontology. Series A, Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences, 73(8), 1070&#x2013;1077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKendry, J., Lowisz, C. V., Nanthakumar, A., MacDonald, M., Lim, C., Currier, B. S., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2024). The effects of whey, pea, and collagen protein supplementation beyond the recommended dietary allowance on integrated myofibrillar protein synthetic rates in older males: A randomized controlled trial. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 120(1), 34&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcleod, J. C., Currier, B. S., Lowisz, C. V., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2024). The influence of resistance exercise training prescription variables on skeletal muscle mass, strength, and physical function in healthy adults: An umbrella review. Journal of Sport and Health Science, 13(1), 47&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton, R. W., Colenso&#x2010;Semple, L., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2019). Training for strength and hypertrophy: An evidence&#x2010;based approach. Current Opinion in Physiology, 10, 90&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton, R. W., Murphy, K. T., McKellar, S. R., Schoenfeld, B. J., Henselmans, M., Helms, E., Aragon, A. A., Devries, M. C., Banfield, L., Krieger, J. W., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2018). A systematic review, meta&#x2010;analysis and meta&#x2010;regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training&#x2010;induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 52(6), 376&#x2013;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton, R. W., Oikawa, S. Y., Wavell, C. G., Mazara, N., McGlory, C., Quadrilatero, J., Baechler, B. L., Baker, S. K., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2016). Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training&#x2010;mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance&#x2010;trained young men. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 121(1), 129&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton, R. W., Sato, K., Gallaugher, M. P. B., Oikawa, S. Y., McNicholas, P. D., Fujita, S., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2018). Muscle androgen receptor content but not systemic hormones is associated with resistance training&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy in healthy, young men. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 1373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli, A., Gentil, P., Moro, T., Marcolin, G., &amp; Bianco, A. (2017). Resistance training with single vs. multi&#x2010;joint exercises at equal total load volume: Effects on body composition, cardiorespiratory fitness, and muscle strength. Frontiers in Physiology, 8, 1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella, J. K., Kim, J. S., Mayhew, D. L., Cross, J. M., &amp; Bamman, M. M. (2008). Potent myofiber hypertrophy during resistance training in humans is associated with satellite cell&#x2010;mediated myonuclear addition: A cluster analysis. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 104(6), 1736&#x2013;1742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips, S. M., Parise, G., Roy, B. D., Tipton, K. D., Wolfe, R. R., &amp; Tamopolsky, M. A. (2002). Resistance&#x2010;training&#x2010;induced adaptations in skeletal muscle protein turnover in the fed state. Canadian Journal of Physiology and Pharmacology, 80(11), 1045&#x2013;1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, M. D., Haun, C. T., Mobley, C. B., Mumford, P. W., Romero, M. A., Roberson, P. A., Vann, C. G., &amp; McCarthy, J. J. (2018). Physiological differences between low versus high skeletal muscle hypertrophic responders to resistance exercise training: Current perspectives and future research directions. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, M. D., McCarthy, J. J., Hornberger, T. A., Phillips, S. M., Mackey, A. L., Nader, G. A., Boppart, M. D., Kavazis, A. N., Reidy, P. T., Ogasawara, R., Libardi, C. A., Ugrinowitsch, C., Booth, F. W., &amp; Esser, K. A. (2023). Mechanisms of mechanical overload&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Current understanding and future directions. Physiological Reviews, 103(4), 2679&#x2013;2757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, M. D., Romero, M. A., Mobley, C. B., Mumford, P. W., Roberson, P. A., Haun, C. T., Vann, C. G., Osburn, S. C., Holmes, H. H., Greer, R. A., Lockwood, C. M., Parry, H. A., &amp; Kavazis, A. N. (2018). Skeletal muscle mitochondrial volume and myozenin&#x2010;1 protein differences exist between high versus low anabolic responders to resistance training. PeerJ, 6, e5338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross, R., Goodpaster, B. H., Koch, L. G., Sarzynski, M. A., Kohrt, W. M., Johannsen, N. M., Skinner, J. S., Castro, A., Irving, B. A., Noland, R. C., Sparks, L. M., Spielmann, G., Day, A. G., Pitsch, W., Hopkins, W. G., &amp; Bouchard, C. (2019). Precision exercise medicine: Understanding exercise response variability. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 53(18), 1141&#x2013;1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruple, B. A., Mesquita, P. H. C., Godwin, J. S., Sexton, C. L., Osburn, S. C., McIntosh, M. C., Kavazis, A. N., Libardi, C. A., Young, K. C., &amp; Roberts, M. D. (2022). Changes in vastus lateralis fibre cross&#x2010;sectional area, pennation angle and fascicle length do not predict changes in muscle cross&#x2010;sectional area. Experimental Physiology, 107(11), 1216&#x2013;1224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruple, B. A., Smith, M. A., Osburn, S. C., Sexton, C. L., Godwin, J. S., Edison, J. L., Poole, C. N., Stock, M. S., Fruge, A. D., Young, K. C., &amp; Roberts, M. D. (2022). Comparisons between skeletal muscle imaging techniques and histology in tracking midthigh hypertrophic adaptations following 10 wk of resistance training. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 133(2), 416&#x2013;425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld, B. J., Grgic, J., &amp; Krieger, J. (2019). How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. Journal of Sports Sciences, 37(11), 1286&#x2013;1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld, B. J., Grgic, J., Ogborn, D., &amp; Krieger, J. W. (2017). Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low&#x2010; vs. high&#x2010;load resistance training: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 31(12), 3508&#x2013;3523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soendenbroe, C., Karlsen, A., Svensson, R. B., Kjaer, M., Andersen, J. L., &amp; Mackey, A. L. (2024). Marked irregular myofiber shape is a hallmark of human skeletal muscle ageing and is reversed by heavy resistance training. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 15(1), 306&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stec, M. J., Thalacker&#x2010;Mercer, A., Mayhew, D. L., Kelly, N. A., Tuggle, S. C., Merritt, E. K., Brown, C. J., Windham, S. T., Dell'Italia, L. J., Bickel, C. S., Roberts, B. M., Vaughn, K. M., Isakova&#x2010;Donahue, I., Many, G. M., &amp; Bamman, M. M. (2017). Randomized, four&#x2010;arm, dose&#x2010;response clinical trial to optimize resistance exercise training for older adults with age&#x2010;related muscle atrophy. Experimental Gerontology, 99, 98&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokes, T., Timmons, J. A., Crossland, H., Tripp, T. R., Murphy, K., McGlory, C., Mitchell, C. J., Oikawa, S. Y., Morton, R. W., Phillips, B. E., Baker, S. K., Atherton, P. J., Wahlestedt, C., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2020). Molecular transducers of human skeletal muscle remodeling under different loading states. Cell Reports, 32(5), 107980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokes, T., Tripp, T. R., Murphy, K., Morton, R. W., Oikawa, S. Y., Lam Choi, H., McGrath, J., McGlory, C., MacDonald, M. J., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2021). Methodological considerations for and validation of the ultrasonographic determination of human skeletal muscle hypertrophy and atrophy. Physiological Reports, 9(1), e14683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vossel, K., Hardeel, J., Van de Casteele, F., Van der Stede, T., Weyns, A., Boone, J., Blemker, S. S., Lievens, E., &amp; Derave, W. (2023). Can muscle typology explain the inter&#x2010;individual variability in resistance training adaptations? The Journal of Physiology, 601(12), 2307&#x2013;2327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson, D. J., Franchi, M. V., Brook, M. S., Narici, M. V., Williams, J. P., Mitchell, W. K., Szewczyk, N. J., Greenhaff, P. L., Atherton, P. J., &amp; Smith, K. (2014). A validation of the application of D(2)O stable isotope tracer techniques for monitoring day&#x2010;to&#x2010;day changes in muscle protein subfraction synthesis in humans. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Endocrinology and Metabolism, 306(5), E571&#x2013;E579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson, S. B., Tarnopolsky, M. A., Grant, E. J., Correia, C. E., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2006). Hypertrophy with unilateral resistance exercise occurs without increases in endogenous anabolic hormone concentration. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 98(6), 546&#x2013;555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, W. G., Thomas, A. C. Q., Wilson, G. M., McGlory, C., Hibbert, J. E., Flynn, C. G., Sayed, R. K. A., Paez, H. G., Meinhold, M., Jorgenson, K. W., You, J. S., Steinert, N. D., Lin, K. H., MacInnis, M. J., Coon, J. J., Phillips, S. M., &amp; Hornberger, T. A. (2025). Identification of a resistance&#x2010;exercise&#x2010;specific signalling pathway that drives skeletal muscle growth. Nature Metabolism, 7(7), 1404&#x2013;1423.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>