<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30662699</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does the addition of single joint exercises to a resistance training program improve changes in performance and anthropometric measures in untrained men?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7827</StartPage><MedlinePgn>7827</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7827</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2018.7827</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The present study compared changes in muscle performance and anthropometric measures in young men performing resistance training (RT) programs composed of only multi joint (MJ) exercises, or with the addition of single joint (SJ) exercises (MJ+SJ). Twenty untrained men were randomized to MJ or MJ+SJ groups for 8 weeks. Both groups performed the same MJ exercises. The difference was that the MJ+SJ group added SJ exercises for upper and lower limbs. Participants were tested for 10 repetitions maximum (10RM), flexed arm circumference, and biceps and triceps skinfolds. Both groups significantly increased 10RM load for the bench press (MJ 38.5%, MJ+SJ 40.1%), elbow extension (MJ 28.7%, MJ+SJ 31.9%), pull down (MJ 34.0% MJ+SJ 38.5%), elbow flexion (MJ 38.2%, MJ+SJ 45.3%), leg press (MJ 40.8%, MJ+SJ 46.8%) and knee extension (MJ 26.9%, MJ+SJ 32.9%), with no significant difference between them. The decreases in biceps (MJ -3.6%, MJ+SJ -3.9%) and triceps (MJ -3.4%, MJ+SJ -3.3%) skinfolds were significant for both groups, with no difference between them. However, the flexed arm circumference increased significantly more for MJ+SJ (5.2%), than for MJ (4.0%). The use of SJ exercises as a complement to a RT program containing MJ exercises brings no additional benefit to untrained men in terms of muscle performance and skinfold reduction, though it promoted higher increases in arm circumference.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbalho</LastName><ForeName>Matheus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Ci&#xea;ncias Biol&#xf3;gicas e da Sa&#xfa;de. Universidade da Amaz&#xf4;nia, Bel&#xe9;m, Par&#xe1;, Brasil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculdade de Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica e Dan&#xe7;a, Universidade Federal de Goi&#xe1;s, Goi&#xe2;nia, Brasil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coswig</LastName><ForeName>Victor Silveira</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculdade de Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica. Universidade Federal do Par&#xe1;, Castanhal, Par&#xe1;, Brasil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raiol</LastName><ForeName>Rodolfo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Ci&#xea;ncias Biol&#xf3;gicas e da Sa&#xfa;de. Centro Universit&#xe1;rio do Estado do Par&#xe1;, Bel&#xe9;m, Par&#xe1;, Brasil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steele</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health, Exercise and Sport Science, Southampton Solent University, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ukactive Research Institute, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fisher</LastName><ForeName>James P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health, Exercise and Sport Science, Southampton Solent University, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paoli</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bianco</LastName><ForeName>Antonino</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise Sciences Research Unit, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gentil</LastName><ForeName>Paulo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculdade de Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica e Dan&#xe7;a, Universidade Federal de Goi&#xe1;s, Goi&#xe2;nia, Brasil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise selection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isolation exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training volume</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest The authors declare no conflicts of interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30662699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6317138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2018.7827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM. Progression Models in Resistance Training for Healthy Adults. Med Sci Sport Exerc 2009;3:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez-Pavon D, Lavie CJ. High-intensity intermittent training versus moderate-intensity intermittent training: Is it a matter of intensity or intermittent efforts? Br J Sports Med 2017;51:1319&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28137785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A. Resistance training: the multifaceted side of exercise. AJP Endocrinol Metab 2012;302:E387&#x2013;E387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22275762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fisher J, Steele J. A Review of the Acute Effects and Long-Term Adaptations of Single- and Multi-Joint Exercises during Resistance Training [Internet]. Sport Med 2017;47:843-55. doi:10.1007/s40279-016-0627-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27677913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha J&#xfa;nior V de A, Gentil P, Oliveira E, Do Carmo J. Comparison among the EMG activity of the pectoralis major, anterior deltoidis and triceps brachii during the bench press and peck deck exercises. Rev Bras Med Esporte 2007;13:43&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza D, Santos J, de Jesus D, Gentil P. Biochemical Profile and Body Composition Alteration of Amateur Bodybuilders during the Pre-Contest Period. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 2018;3:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Barbosa de Lira CA, Paoli A, et al. Nutrition, pharmacological and training strategies adopted by six bodybuilders: case report and critical review. Eur J Transl Myol 2017;27:51&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5391526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28458804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 2013;27:1609&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22990567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana R, Gentil P, Brasileiro E, et al. High Resistance Training Volume and Low Caloric and Protein Intake Are Associated with Detrimental Alterations in Body Composition of an Amateur Bodybuilder Using Anabolic Steroids: A Case Report. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 2017;2:37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Soares S, Bottaro M. Single vs. Multi-Joint Resistance Exercises: Effects on Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy. Asian J Sport Med 2015;6:e24057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4592763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26446291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Gentil P, Moro T, et al. Resistance training with single vs. multi-joint exercises at equal total load volume: Effects on body composition, cardiorespiratory fitness, and muscle strength. Front Physiol 2017;8:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5744434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29312007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Rodrigo S, Soares S, et al. Effects of adding single-joint exercises to a multi-joit exercise resistance-training program on strength and hypertrophy in untrained subjects. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 2013;344:341&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23537028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Franca HS, Branco PA, Guedes Junior DP, et al. The effects of adding single-joint exercises to a multi-joint exercise resistance training program on upper body muscle strength and size in trained men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 2015;40:822&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26244600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-L&#xf3;pez M, Gallegos AG, Extremera AB. Perceived barriers by university students in the practice of physical activities. J Sport Sci Med 2010;9:374&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimm SYS, Glynn NW, Mcmahon RP, et al. Self-perceived barriers to activity participation among sedentary adolescent girls. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2006;38:534&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16540842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho M, Gentil P, Raiol R, et al. Influence of Adding Single-Joint Exercise to a Multijoint Resistance Training Program in Untrained Young Women. 2018;(May):1 [ePub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29781936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Sugisaki N, et al. Association between regional differences in muscle activation in one session of resistance exercise and in muscle hypertrophy after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 2012;112:1569&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21858666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawakami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy: Its relation to muscle activation in training session. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2013;45:2158&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23657165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Bottaro M. Effects of Training Attendance on Muscle Strength of Young Men after 11 Weeks of Resistance Training [Internet]. Asian J Sport Med 2013;4:101-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Determining Strength: A Case for Multiple Methods of Measurement. Sport Med 2017;47:193&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. High- and Low-Load Resistance Training: Interpretation and Practical Application of Current Research Findings. Sport Med 2017;47:393&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27480764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Bottaro M. Influence of supervision ratio on muscle adaptations to resistance training in nontrained subjects. J Strength Cond Res 2010;24:639&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, Giessing J, Gentil P. Clarity in reporting terminology and definitions of set endpoints in resistance training [Internet]. Muscle and Nerve 2017; doi:10.1002/mus.25557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28044366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Del Vecchio FB, Paoli A, et al. Isokinetic Dynamometry and 1RM Tests Produce Conflicting Results for Assessing Alterations in Muscle Strength. J Hum Kinet 2017;56(1):19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5384049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, et al. Muscle hypertrophy, hormonal adaptations and strength development during strength training in strength-trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 2003;89:555&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, et al. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci 2012;4:217&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3831787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24265879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akima H, Foley JM, Prior BM, et al. Vastus lateralis fatigue alters recruitment of musculus quadriceps femoris in humans. J Appl Physiol 2002;92:679&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11796681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arruda A, Souza D, Steele J, et al. Reliability of meta-analyses to evaluate resistance training programmes. J Sports Sci 2017;35:1982&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27809704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 2017;35:1073&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira DV, Gentil P, Soares SRS, Bottaro M. Recovery of pectoralis major and triceps brachii after bench press exercise. Muscle and Nerve 2017;56:963&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28029681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argus CK, Gill N, Keogh J, et al. Effects of a short-term pre-season training programme on the body composition and anaerobic performance of professional rugby union players. J Sports Sci 2010;(June 2015):37&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cureton KJ, Collins MA, Hill DW, McElhannon FM. Muscle hypertrophy in men and women. Med Sci Sports Exer. 1988;20:338&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3173042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka T, Farley RS, Caputo JL. Occlusion training increases muscular strength in division IA football players. J Strength Cond Res 2012;26:2523&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22105051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MJ, Gibson NV, Sorbie GG, et al. Activation of the Gluteus Maximus During Performance of the Back Squat, Split Squat, and Barbell Hip Thrust and the Relationship With Maximal Sprinting. J Strength Cond Res 2018;(May):1 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni BM, Geremia JM, Rodrigues R, et al. Muscle architecture adaptations to knee extensor eccentric training: Rectus femoris vs. Vastus lateralis. Muscle Nerve. 2013;48:498&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23852989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, de Paoli F, Bjerg K, Riis S, Ringgard S, Vissing K. Blood flow restricted and traditional resistance training performed to fatigue produce equal muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sport 2015;25:754&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25603897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med 1979;58:115&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">453338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, Boer M De, Narici MV, et al. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med 2007;35:572&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>