<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38090747</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Moderators of Resistance Training Effects in Healthy Young Women: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>804</StartPage><EndPage>814</EndPage><MedlinePgn>804-814</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004666</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Molinari, T, Radaelli, R, Rech, A, Brusco, CM, Markarian, AM, and Lopez, P. Moderators of resistance training effects in healthy young women: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 38(4): 804-814, 2024-To systematically review and analyze the effects of resistance-based exercise programs and potential moderators of change in body fat percentage, whole-body fat and lean mass, muscle hypertrophy, muscle strength, and muscle power/rapid force in healthy young women (between 18 and 35 years). A systematic search was undertaken in 7 databases from inception to May 2022. Eligible randomized controlled trials examined the effects of resistance-based exercise programs on outcomes of interest in healthy young women. Meta-analysis was undertaken with a 3-level mixed-effects model. Associations between standardized mean difference (SMD) and potential moderators (number of sessions, weekly volume, and intensity) were tested by meta-regression models. Statistical significance was set at an &#x3b1; level of 0.05, whereas an &#x3b1; level of 0.05-0.10 was also considered for potential moderators of resistance training effects. Forty articles ( n = 1,312) were included. Resistance-based exercise programs resulted in a significant improvement of 0.4 SMD (95% confidence intervals [95% CI]: 0.2 to 0.5, p &lt; 0.001) in lean mass/muscle hypertrophy and 1.2 SMD (95% CI: 0.9 to 1.5, p &lt; 0.001) in muscle strength. A higher number of sessions was associated with changes in lean mass/muscle hypertrophy ( &#x3b2; = 0.01 &#xb1; 0.00, p = 0.009), whereas a higher weekly volume approached statistical significance to moderate changes in muscle strength ( &#x3b2; = 0.01 &#xb1; 0.01, p = 0.053). Body fat percentage (-0.4 SMD, 95% CI: -0.6 to -0.1, p = 0.006) and muscle power/rapid force (0.6 SMD, 95% CI: 0.2 to 1.1, p = 0.011) were significantly improved. In conclusion, a higher resistance training volume was associated with greater improvements in lean mass/muscle hypertrophy, muscle strength, and body fat percentage, whereas muscle power/rapid force improvements were observed irrespective of prescription characteristics. These findings may help in designing resistance training programs for muscle hypertrophy, strength and power, and body fat percentage in healthy women.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molinari</LastName><ForeName>Talita</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise Neuromechanics Group, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande, Rio Grande, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Radaelli</LastName><ForeName>R&#xe9;gis</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Egas Moniz Center for Interdisciplinary Research (CiiEM), Egas Moniz School of Health &amp; Science, Caparica, Almada, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rech</LastName><ForeName>Anderson</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Universidade de Caxias do Sul, Caxias do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group on Exercise for Clinical Populations (GPCLIN), Universidade de Caxias do Sul, Caxias do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brusco</LastName><ForeName>Clarissa M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Markarian</LastName><ForeName>Anna Maria</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopez</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3897-667</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Group on Exercise for Clinical Populations (GPCLIN), Universidade de Caxias do Sul, Caxias do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pleural Medicine Unit, Institute for Respiratory Health, Perth, Australia; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, Faculty of Health &amp; Medical Sciences, University of Western Australia, Perth, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38090747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202404000-00023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Fukunaga T. Sex differences in whole body skeletal muscle mass measured by magnetic resonance imaging and its distribution in young Japanese adults. Br J Sports Med 37: 436&#x2013;440, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Salek L, Nikfal E, et al. Comparable endocrine and neuromuscular adaptations to variable vs. constant gravity-dependent resistance training among young women. J Transl Med 18: 239, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, B&#xfc;ttner F, Andrade R, et al. Implementing the 27 PRISMA 2020 statement items for systematic reviews in the sport and exercise medicine, musculoskeletal rehabilitation and sports science fields: The PERSiST (implementing Prisma in exercise, rehabilitation, Sport medicine and SporTs science) guidance. Br J Sports Med 56: 175&#x2013;195, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell GJ, Syrotuik D, Martin TP, Burnham R, Quinney HA. Effect of concurrent strength and endurance training on skeletal muscle properties and hormone concentrations in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol 81: 418&#x2013;427, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Wilson CJ, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias JA. Effects of resistance training movement pattern and velocity on isometric muscular rate of force development: A systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. Sports Med 50: 943&#x2013;963, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botton CE, Radaelli R, Wilhelm EN, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations to unilateral vs. bilateral strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1924&#x2013;1932, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RD, Harrison JM. The effects of a strength training program on the strength and self-concept of two female age groups. Res Q Exerc Sport 57: 315&#x2013;320, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell AR, Vigotsky AD, Tenan MS, et al. Moving sport and exercise science forward: A call for the adoption of more transparent research practices. Sports Med 50: 449&#x2013;459, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesar Mde C, Borin JP, Gonelli PR, et al. The effect of local muscle endurance training on cardiorespiratory capacity in young women. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1637&#x2013;1643, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung MW-L. Modeling dependent effect sizes with three-level meta-analyses: A structural equation modeling approach. Psychol Methods 19: 211, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis. Curr Dir Psychol Sci 1: 98&#x2013;101, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Garcia-Masso X, Pellicer M, et al. A comparison of elastic tubing and isotonic resistance exercises. Int J Sports Med 31: 810&#x2013;817, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colenso-Semple LM, D'Souza AC, Elliott-Sale KJ, Phillips SM. Current evidence shows no influence of women's menstrual cycle phase on acute strength performance or adaptations to resistance exercise training. Front Sports Act Living 5: 1054542, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Beato M, Bertinato L, et al. Including the eccentric phase in resistance training to counteract the effects of detraining in women: A randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 36: 3023&#x2013;3031, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Adaptations in athletic performance after ballistic power versus strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 1582&#x2013;1598, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello JT, Bieuzen F, Bleakley CM. Where are all the female participants in Sports and Exercise Medicine research? Eur J Sport Sci 14: 847&#x2013;851, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lima C, Boullosa DA, Frollini AB, et al. Linear and daily undulating resistance training periodizations have differential beneficial effects in young sedentary women. Int J Sports Med 33: 723&#x2013;727, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delecluse C, Roelants M, Verschueren S. Strength increase after whole-body vibration compared with resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 1033&#x2013;1041, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diniz RCR, Tourino FD, Lacerda LT, et al. Resistance training intervention performed with different muscle action durations influences the maximal dynamic strength without promoting joint-angle specific strength gains. J Sports Sci 39: 2386&#x2013;2392, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drevon D, Fursa SR, Malcolm AL. Intercoder reliability and validity of WebPlotDigitizer in extracting graphed data. Behav Modif 41: 323&#x2013;339, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutra MT, Alex S, Mota MR, et al. Effect of strength training combined with antioxidant supplementation on muscular performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 43: 775&#x2013;781, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focht BC. Perceived exertion and training load during self-selected and imposed-intensity resistance exercise in untrained women. J Strength Cond Res 21: 183&#x2013;187, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco CMC, Carneiro M, Alves LTH, et al. Lower-Load is more effective than higher-load resistance training in increasing muscle mass in young women. J Strength Cond Res 33: S152&#x2013;S158, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furlan AD, Pennick V, Bombardier C, van Tulder M. 2009 updated method guidelines for systematic reviews in the Cochrane Back Review Group. Spine 34: 1929&#x2013;1941, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guadalupe-Grau A, Perez-Gomez J, Olmedillas H, et al. Strength training combined with plyometric jumps in adults: Sex differences in fat-bone axis adaptations. J Appl Physiol 106: 1100&#x2013;1111, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstrom AD, Marshall PW, Halaki M, Hackett DA. The effect of resistance training in women on dynamic strength and muscular hypertrophy: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med 50: 1075&#x2013;1093, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K. Neuromuscular fatigue in males and females during strenuous heavy resistance loading. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol 34: 205&#x2013;214, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handelsman DJ. Sex differences in athletic performance emerge coinciding with the onset of male puberty. Clin Endocrinol 87: 68&#x2013;72, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handelsman DJ, Hirschberg AL, Bermon S. Circulating testosterone as the hormonal basis of sex differences in athletic performance. Endocr Rev 39: 803&#x2013;829, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, et al. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol 10: 247, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrickson NR, Sharp MA, Alemany JA, et al. Combined resistance and endurance training improves physical capacity and performance on tactical occupational tasks. Eur J Appl Physiol 109: 1197&#x2013;1208, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Special topics in statistics. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0: 482&#x2013;488, 2011. Available at: www.cochrane-handbook.org ; Accessed October, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Byrne NM, Sirikul B, et al. Resistance training conserves fat-free mass and resting energy expenditure following weight loss. Obesity 16: 1045&#x2013;1051, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK. Sex differences in fatigability of dynamic contractions. Exp Physiol 101: 250&#x2013;255, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins NDM, Rogers EM, Banks NF, Muddle TWD, Colquhoun RJ. Increases in motor unit action potential amplitudes are related to muscle hypertrophy following eight weeks of high-intensity exercise training in females. Eur J Sport Sci 21: 1403&#x2013;1413, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong J, Choi DH, Song Y, Shin CS. Muscle strength training alters muscle activation of the lower extremity during side-step cutting in females. J Mot Behav 52: 703&#x2013;712, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E, Dear A, Ferguson SL, Seo D, Bemben MG. Effects of 4 weeks of traditional resistance training vs. superslow strength training on early phase adaptations in strength, flexibility, and aerobic capacity in college-aged women. J Strength Cond Res 25: 3006&#x2013;3013, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocao&#x11f;lu Y, Erkmen N. The effect of elastic resistance band training on postural control and body composition in sedentary women. Spor Bilimleri Ara&#x15f;t&#x131;rmalar&#x131; Dergisi 6: 233&#x2013;245, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Keuning M, Ratamess NA, et al. Resistance training combined with bench-step aerobics enhances women's health profile. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 259&#x2013;269, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Nindl BC, Ratamess NA, et al. Changes in muscle hypertrophy in women with periodized resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 697&#x2013;708, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess N, Fry AC, et al. Influence of resistance training volume and periodization on physiological and performance adaptations in collegiate women tennis players. Am J Sports Med 28: 626&#x2013;633, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeMura LM, von Duvillard SP, Andreacci J, et al. Lipid and lipoprotein profiles, cardiovascular fitness, body composition, and diet during and after resistance, aerobic and combination training in young women. Eur J Appl Physiol 82: 451&#x2013;458, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang MT, Quezada L, Lau WJ, Sokmen B, Spalding TW. Effect of short-term upper-body resistance training on muscular strength, bone metabolic markers, and BMD in premenopausal women. Open Access J Sports Med 3: 201&#x2013;208, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate healthcare interventions: Explanation and elaboration. BMJ 339: b2700, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, et al. Moderators of resistance training effects in overweight and obese adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 54: 1804&#x2013;1816, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: Systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 53: 1206&#x2013;1216, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Resistance training effectiveness on body composition and body weight outcomes in individuals with overweight and obesity across the lifespan: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev 23: e13428, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luder G, Aeberli D, Mebes CM, et al. Effect of resistance training on muscle properties and function in women with generalized joint hypermobility: A single-blind pragmatic randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 13: 10, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx JO, Ratamess NA, Nindl BC, et al. Low-volume circuit versus high-volume periodized resistance training in women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 635&#x2013;643, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride JM, Triplett-McBride T, Davie A, Newton RU. The effect of heavy- vs. light-load jump squats on the development of strength, power, and speed. J Strength Cond Res 16: 75&#x2013;82, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghadam AN, Mohammadi R, Arab AM, Kazamnajad A. The effect of shoulder core exercises on isometric torque of glenohumeral joint movements in healthy young females. J Res Med Sci 16: 1555&#x2013;1563, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghadasi M, Siavashpour S. The effect of 12 weeks of resistance training on hormones of bone formation in young sedentary women. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 25&#x2013;32, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Custodio R, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Pareja-Blanco F, Ya&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effect of low- vs. Moderate-load squat training on strength, jump and sprint performance in physically active women. Int J Sports Med 37: 476&#x2013;482, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosti MP, Carlsen T, Aas E, et al. Maximal strength training improves bone mineral density and neuromuscular performance in young adult women. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2935&#x2013;2945, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AG, Chambers RS, McGown CM, Penrose KW. Proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation versus weight training for enhancement of muscular strength and athletic performance. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 7: 250&#x2013;253, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Deaner RO. Men and women differ in their interest and willingness to participate in exercise and sports science research. Scand J Med Sci Sports 33: 1850&#x2013;1865, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. Mapping of reporting guidance for systematic reviews and meta-analyses generated a comprehensive item bank for future reporting guidelines. J Clin Epidemiol 118: 60&#x2013;68, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandit A, Tran TB, Letton M, et al. Data informing governing body resistance-training guidelines exhibit sex bias: An audit-based review. Sports Med 53: 1681&#x2013;1691, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters JL, Sutton AJ, Jones DR, Abrams KR, Rushton L. Contour-enhanced meta-analysis funnel plots help distinguish publication bias from other causes of asymmetry. J Clin Epidemiol 61: 991&#x2013;996, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poehlman ET, Dvorak RV, DeNino WF, Brochu M, Ades PA. Effects of resistance training and endurance training on insulin sensitivity in nonobese, young women: A controlled randomized trial. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 85: 2463&#x2013;2468, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakaran B, Dowling EA, Branch JD, Swain DP, Leutholtz BC. Effect of 14 weeks of resistance training on lipid profile and body fat percentage in premenopausal women. Br J Sports Med 33: 190&#x2013;195, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pustejovsky JE, Tipton E. Small-sample methods for cluster-robust variance estimation and hypothesis testing in fixed effects models. J Bus Econ Stat 36: 672&#x2013;683, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rana SR, Chleboun GS, Gilders RM, et al. Comparison of early phase adaptations for traditional strength and endurance, and low velocity resistance training programs in college-aged women. J Strength Cond Res 22: 119&#x2013;127, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Faigenbaum AD, Hoffman JR, Kang J. Self-selected resistance training intensity in healthy women: The influence of a personal trainer. J Strength Cond Res 22: 103&#x2013;111, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Hamilton DL, Paval DR, et al. Influence of resistance training load on measures of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and improvements in maximal strength and neuromuscular task performance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 39: 1723&#x2013;1745, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos E, Rhea MR, Sim&#xe3;o R, et al. Influence of moderately intense strength training on flexibility in sedentary young women. J Strength Cond Res 24: 3144&#x2013;3149, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlumberger A, Stec J, Schmidtbleicher D. Single- vs. multiple-set strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res 15: 284&#x2013;289, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senefeld J, Yoon T, Bement MH, Hunter SK. Fatigue and recovery from dynamic contractions in men and women differ for arm and leg muscles. Muscle Nerve 48: 436&#x2013;439, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Lemos A, Salles B, et al. The influence of strength, flexibility, and simultaneous training on flexibility and strength gains. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1333&#x2013;1338, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 366: l4898, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stien N, Pedersen H, Ravn&#xf8;y AH, Andersen V, Saeterbakken AH. Training specificity performing single-joint vs. multi-joint resistance exercises among physically active females: A randomized controlled trial. PLoS One 15: e0233540, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock MS, Olinghouse KD, Drusch AS, et al. Evidence of muscular adaptations within four weeks of barbell training in women. Hum Mov Sci 45: 7&#x2013;22, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung E, Han A, Hinrichs T, et al. Effects of follicular versus luteal phase-based strength training in young women. Springerplus 3: 668, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temesi J, Arnal PJ, Rupp T, et al. Are females more resistant to extreme neuromuscular fatigue? Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 1372&#x2013;1382, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Softw 36: 1&#x2013;48, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpe SL, Walberg-Rankin J, Rodman KW, Sebolt DR. The effect of endurance running on training adaptations in women participating in a weight lifting program. J Strength Cond Res 7: 101&#x2013;107, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wawrzyniak JR, Tracy JE, Catizone PV, Storrow RR. Effect of closed chain exercise on quadriceps femoris peak torque and functional performance. J Athl Train 31: 335&#x2013;340, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss LW, Clark FC, Howard DG. Effects of heavy-resistance triceps surae muscle training on strength and muscularity of men and women. Phys Ther 68: 208&#x2013;213, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wewege MA, Desai I, Honey C, et al. The effect of resistance training in healthy adults on body fat percentage, fat mass and visceral fat: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 52: 287&#x2013;300, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikstr&#xf6;m-Fris&#xe9;n L, Boraxbekk CJ, Henriksson-Lars&#xe9;n K. Effects on power, strength and lean body mass of menstrual/oral contraceptive cycle based resistance training. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 57: 43&#x2013;52, 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>