<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25414750</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of 16 weeks of resistance training on fatigue resistance in men and women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>165</StartPage><EndPage>174</EndPage><MedlinePgn>165-74</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2014-0071</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of hypertrophy-type resistance training (RT) on upper limb fatigue resistance in young adult men and women. Fifty-eight men (22.7&#xb1;3.7 years, 70.6&#xb1;9.3 kg, and 176.8&#xb1;6.4 cm) and 65 women (21.6&#xb1;3.7 years, 58.8&#xb1;11.9 kg, and 162.6&#xb1;6.2 cm) underwent RT for 16 weeks. Training consisted of 10-12 whole body exercises with 3 sets of 8-12 repetitions maximum performed 3 times per week. Before and after the RT intervention participants were submitted to 1RM testing, as well as a fatigue protocol consisting of 4 sets at 80% 1RM on bench press (BP) and arm curl (AC). The sum of the number of repetitions accomplished in the 4 sets in each exercise was used to indicate fatigue resistance. There was a significant (p&lt;0.05) time-by-group interaction in 1RM BP (men=+16%, women=+26%), however in 1RM AC no significant time-by-group interaction was observed (men=+14%, women=+23%). For the total number of repetitions, men and women showed a significant increase in BP (men=+16.3%, women=+10.5%) with no time-by-group interaction. The results suggest that the adaptation in maximal strength is influenced by sex in BP. On the other hand, for fatigue resistance, the individual's sex does not seem to influence outcomes either in BP or AC.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avelar</LastName><ForeName>Ademar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Maring&#xe1; State University, Maring&#xe1;, PR Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science Department, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, New York, EUA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trindade</LastName><ForeName>Michele C C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ing&#xe1; - Uning&#xe1; College, Maring&#xe1;, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ritti-Dias</LastName><ForeName>Raphael M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Pernambuco University, Recife, PE, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altimari</LastName><ForeName>Leandro R</ForeName><Initials>LR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Londrina State University, Londrina, PR, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscular endurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">one-repetition maximum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sex</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25414750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jhk-42-165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2000;81:174&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10638374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avin KG, Naughton MR, Ford BW, Moore HE, Monitto-Webber MN, Stark AM, Gentile AJ, Law LA. Sex differences in fatigue resistance are muscle group dependent. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1943&#x2013;1950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2917609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautmans I, Njemini R, Predom H, Lemper JC, Mets T. Muscle endurance in elderly nursing home residents is related to fatigue perception, mobility, and circulating tumor necrosis factor-alpha, interleukin-6, and heat shock protein 70. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2008;56:389&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18179479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentes CM, Sim&#xe3;o R, Bunker T, Rhea MR, Miranda H, Gomes TM, Novaes JS. Acute effects of dropsets among different resistance training methods in upper body performance. J Hum Kinet. 2012;34:105&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3590834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billaut F, Bishop D. Muscle fatigue in males and females during multiple-sprint exercise. Sports Med. 2009;39:257&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19317516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes MR, Kraemer WJ. Performance and physiologic adaptations to resistance training. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;81:3&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12409807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eches EHP, Ribeiro AS, Nascimento MA, Cyrino ES. Motor performance in sustained multiple weight exercises to concentric failure. Motriz. 2013;19:S43&#x2013;S48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel DA, Kamen G, Frost G. Neural adaptations to resistive exercise: mechanisms and recommendations for training practices. Sports Med. 2006;36:133&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16464122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatzikotoulas K, Siatras T, Spyropoulou E, Paraschos I, Patikas D. Muscle fatigue and electromyographic changes are not different in women and men matched for strength. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92:298&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15083371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks AL, Kent-Braun J, Ditor DS. Sex differences in human skeltal muscle fadigue. Exerc Sports Sci Rev. 2001;29:109&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11474957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, Price TB, Hoffman EP, Angelopoulos TJ, Gordon PM, Moyna NM, Pescatello LS, Visich PS, Zoeller RF, Seip RL, Clarkson PM. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK. Sex differences and mechanisms of task-specific muscle fadigue. Exerc Sports Sci Rev. 2009;37:113&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2909485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19550202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivey FM, Roth SM, Ferrell RE, Tracy BL, Lemmer JT, Hurlbut DE, Martel GF, Siegel EL, Fozard JL, Jeffrey Metter E, Fleg JL, Hurley BF. Effects of age, gender, and myostatin genotype on the hypertrophic response to heavy resistance strength training. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2000;55:M641&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11078093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell RT. The influence of periodized resistance training on strength changes in men and women. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:735&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20613654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemmer JT, Hurlbut DE, Martel GF, Tracy BL, Ivey FM, Metter EJ, Fozard JL, Fleg JL, Hurley BF. Age and gender responses to strength training and detraining. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1505&#x2013;1512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10949019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemmer JT, Ivey FM, Ryan AS, Martel GF, Hurlbut DE, Metter JE, Fozard JL, Fleg JL, Hurley BF. Effect of strength training on resting metabolic rate and physical activity: age and gender comparisons. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:532&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11283427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemmer JT, Martel GF, Hurlbut DE, Hurley BF. Age and sex differentially affect regional changes in one repetition maximum strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:731&#x2013;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17685712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Ward GR, Sale DG, Sutton JR. Biochemical adaptation of human skeletal muscle to heavy resistance training and immobilization. J Appl Physiol. 1977;43:700&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">908686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martel GF, Roth SM, Ivey FM, Lemmer JT, Tracy BL, Hurlbut DE, Metter EJ, Hurley BF, Rogers MA. Age and sex affect human muscle fibre adaptations to heavy-resistance strength training. Exp Physiol. 2006;91:457&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16407471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Hagan FT, Sale DG, MacDougall JD, Garner SH. Response to resistance training in young women and men. Int J Sports Med. 1995;16:314&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7558529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Pistilli E, Haff GG, Hoffman EP, Gordon PM. Progression of volume load and muscular adaptation during resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:1063&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4215195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21113614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritti-Dias RM, Cyrino ES, Salvador EP, Nakamura FY, Pina FLC, Oliveira AR. Impact of an eight-week training program on the muscular strength of men and women. Braz J Sports Med. 2005;11:224&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritti-Dias RM, Avelar A, Salvador EP, Cyrino ES. Influence of previous experience on resistance training on reliability of one-repetition maximum test. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:1418&#x2013;1422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues CEC, Rocha PECP. Resistance training: theory and practice. Rio de Janeiro: Sprint; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Ivey FM, Martel GF, Lemmer JT, Hurlbut DE, Siegel EL, Metter EJ, Fleg JL, Fozard JL, Kostek MC, Wernick DM, Hurley BF. Muscle size responses to strength training in young and older men and women. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2001;49:1428&#x2013;1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11890579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador EP, Ritti-Dias RM, Gurj&#xe3;o ALD, Avelar A, Pinto LG, Cyrino ES. Effect of eight weeks of strength training on fatigue resistance in men and women. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2009;17:101&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 2013;43:179&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23338987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sforzo GA, Touey PR. Manipulating exercise order affects muscular performance during a resistance exercise training session. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10:20&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares-Caldeira LF, Ritti-Dias RM, Okuno NM, Cyrino ES, Gurjao AL, Ploutz-Snyder LL. Familiarization indexes in sessions of 1-RM tests in adult women. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:2039&#x2013;2045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willems MET, Sallis CW, Haskell JA. Effects of multi-ingredient supplementation on resistance training in young males. J Hum Kinet. 2012;33:91&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23487491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>