<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32735428</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Different Foot Positioning During Calf Training to Induce Portion-Specific Gastrocnemius Muscle Hypertrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2347</StartPage><EndPage>2351</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2347-2351</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003674</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nunes, JP, Costa, BDV, Kassiano, W, Kunevaliki, G, Castro-e-Souza, P, Rodacki, ALF, Fortes, LS, and Cyrino, ES. Different foot positioning during calf training to induce portion-specific gastrocnemius muscle hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 34(8): 2347-2351, 2020-The aim of this study was to compare the changes in gastrocnemius muscle thickness (MT) between conditions such as which foot was pointed outward (FPO), foot was pointed inward (FPI), or foot was pointed forward (FPF). Twenty-two young men (23 &#xb1; 4 years) were selected and performed a whole-body resistance training program 3 times per week for 9 weeks, with differences in the exercise specific for calves. The calf-raise exercise was performed unilaterally, in a pin-loaded seated horizontal leg-press machine, in 3 sets of 20-25 repetitions for training weeks 1-3 and 4 sets for weeks 4-9. Each subject's leg was randomly assigned for 1 of the 3 groups according to the foot position: FPO, FPI, and FPF. Measurements with a B-mode ultrasound were performed to assess changes in MT of medial and lateral gastrocnemius heads. After the training period, there were observed increases in MT of both medial (FPO = 8.4%, FPI = 3.8%, and FPF = 5.8%) and lateral (FPO = 5.5%, FPI = 9.1%, and FPF = 6.4%) gastrocnemius heads, and significant differences for magnitude of the gains were observed between FPO and FPI conditions (p &lt; 0.05). Positioning FPO potentiated the increases in MT of the medial gastrocnemius head, whereas FPI provided greater gains for the lateral gastrocnemius head. Our results suggest that head-specific muscle hypertrophy may be obtained selectively for gastrocnemius after 9 weeks of calf training in young male adults.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Bruna D V</ForeName><Initials>BDV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassiano</LastName><ForeName>Witalo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunevaliki</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castro-E-Souza</LastName><ForeName>P&#xe2;mela</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodacki</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9; L F</ForeName><Initials>ALF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Paran&#xe1;, Curitiba, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fortes</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo S</ForeName><Initials>LS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Para&#xed;ba, Jo&#xe3;o Pessoa, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005528" MajorTopicYN="N">Foot</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007866" MajorTopicYN="N">Leg</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202008000-00030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Antonio J. Nonuniform response of skeletal muscle to heavy resistance training: Can bodybuilders induce regional muscle hypertrophy? J Strength Cond Res 14: 102&#x2013;113, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cibulka M, Wenthe A, Boyle Z, et al. Variation in medial and lateral gastrocnemius muscle activity with foot position. Int J Sports Phys Ther 12: 233&#x2013;241, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras B, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Beardsley C, Cronin J. A comparison of gluteus maximus, biceps femoris, and vastus lateralis electromyography amplitude for the barbell, band, and american hip thrust variations. J Appl Biomech 32: 254&#x2013;260, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Training to fatigue: The answer for standardization when assessing muscle hypertrophy? Sport Med 47: 1021&#x2013;1027, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Akagi R, Wakahara T, Kawakami Y. Training-induced changes in architecture of human skeletal muscles: Current evidence and unresolved issues. J Phys Fit Sport Med 5: 37&#x2013;46, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Kawakami Y. Quantitative profiles of the quadriceps femoris in sport athletes. In: Sports Performance. Kanosue K, Nagami T, Tshuchiya J, eds. Tokyo, Japan: Springer Japan, 2015. pp. 175&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3085&#x2013;3092, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Spreadsheets for analysis of validity and reliability. Sportscience 19: 36&#x2013;42, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami Y, Ichinose Y, Fukunaga T. Architectural and functional features of human triceps surae muscles during contraction. J Appl Physiol 85: 398&#x2013;404, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of squat training with different depths on lower limb muscle volumes. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 1933&#x2013;1942, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SSM, Piazza SJ. Inversion-eversion moment arms of gastrocnemius and tibialis anterior measured in vivo. J Biomech 41: 3366&#x2013;3370, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maganaris CN. Force-length characteristics of the in vivo human gastrocnemius muscle. Clin Anat 16: 215&#x2013;223, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcori AJ, Moura TBMA, Okazaki VH. A Gastrocnemius muscle activation during plantar flexion with different feet positioning in physically active young men. Isokinet Exerc Sci 25: 121&#x2013;125, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Zuniga AF, et al. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. J Physiol 597: 4601&#x2013;4613, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Nakamura M, et al. Does stretch training induce muscle hypertrophy in humans? A review of the literature. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 40: 148&#x2013;156, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Loftin M, Abe T. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci 4: 217&#x2013;220, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira RS, Azevedo JB, Politti F, et al. Does feet position alter triceps surae EMG record during heel-raise exercises in leg press machine? Man Ther Posturol Rehabil J 15: 529, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemann BL, Limbaugh GK, Eitner JD, LeFavi RG. Medial and lateral gastrocnemius activation differences during heelraise exercise with three different foot positions. J Strength Cond Res 25: 634&#x2013;639, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Accentuating muscular development through active insufficiency and passive tension. Strength Cond J 24: 20&#x2013;22, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B. Attentional focus for maximizing muscle development: The mind-muscle connection. Strength Cond J 38: 27&#x2013;29, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Vigotsky AD, et al. Upper body muscle activation during low-versus high-load resistance exercise in the bench press. Isokinet Exerc Sci 24: 217&#x2013;224, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger JW. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci 37: 1286&#x2013;1295, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- versus high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Vigotsky A, Contreras B, et al. Differential effects of attentional focus strategies during long-term resistance training. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 705&#x2013;712, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder BJ, Fry WR. Effect of verbal instruction on muscle activity during the bench press exercise. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2394&#x2013;2400, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trappe TA, Raue U, Tesch PA. Human soleus muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise. Acta Physiol Scand 182: 189&#x2013;196, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Beardsley C, Contreras B, et al. Greater electromyographic responses do not imply greater motor unit recruitment and &#x201c;hypertrophic potential&#x201d; cannot be inferred. J Strength Cond Res 31: e1&#x2013;e4, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Lehman GJ, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Interpreting signal amplitudes in surface electromyography studies in sport and rehabilitation sciences. Front Physiol 8: 985, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawakami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy: Its relation to muscle activation in training session. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 2158&#x2013;2165, 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>