<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35916746</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Set-Structure on Upper-Body Muscular Hypertrophy and Performance in Recreationally-Trained Male and Female.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2176</StartPage><EndPage>2185</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2176-2185</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003971</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Davies, TB, Halaki, M, Orr, R, Mitchell, L, Helms, ER, Clarke, J, and Hackett, DA. Effect of set structure on upper-body muscular hypertrophy and performance in recreationally trained men and women. J Strength Cond Res 36(8): 2176-2185, 2022-This study explored the effect of volume-equated traditional-set and cluster-set structures on muscular hypertrophy and performance after high-load resistance training manipulating the bench press exercise. Twenty-one recreationally trained subjects (12 men and 9 women) performed a 3-week familiarization phase and were then randomized into one of two 8-week upper-body and lower-body split programs occurring over 3 and then progressing to 4 sessions per week. Subjects performed 4 sets of 5 repetitions at 85% one repetition maximum (1RM) using a traditional-set structure (TRAD, n = 10), which involved 5 minutes of interset rest only, or a cluster-set structure, which included 30-second inter-repetition rest and 3 minutes of interset rest (CLUS, n = 11). A 1RM bench press, repetitions to failure at 70% 1RM, regional muscle thickness, and dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry were used to estimate changes in muscular strength, local muscular endurance, regional muscular hypertrophy, and body composition, respectively. Velocity loss was assessed using a linear position transducer at the intervention midpoint. TRAD demonstrated a significantly greater velocity loss magnitude (g = 1.50) and muscle thickness of the proximal pectoralis major (g = -0.34) compared with CLUS. There were no significant differences between groups for the remaining outcomes, although a small effect size favoring TRAD was observed for the middle region of the pectoralis major (g = -0.25). It seems that the greater velocity losses during sets observed in traditional-set compared with cluster-set structures may promote superior muscular hypertrophy within specific regions of the pectoralis major in recreationally trained subjects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davies</LastName><ForeName>Timothy B</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sports Science, Sydney School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halaki</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sports Science, Sydney School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orr</LastName><ForeName>Rhonda</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sports Science, Sydney School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitchell</LastName><ForeName>Lachlan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sports Science, Sydney School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helms</LastName><ForeName>Eric R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clarke</LastName><ForeName>Jillian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Medical Imaging Science, Sydney School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hackett</LastName><ForeName>Daniel A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sports Science, Sydney School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Health, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35916746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202208000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol 81: 174&#x2013;180, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Hoffren M, Hulmi JJ, et al. Panoramic ultrasonography is a valid method to measure changes in skeletal muscle cross-sectional area. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 273&#x2013;279, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson T, Kearney JT. Effects of three resistance training programs on muscular strength and absolute and relative endurance. Res Q Exerc Sport 53: 1&#x2013;7, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson G, Nevill AM. Statistical methods for assessing measurement error (reliability) in variables relevant to sports medicine. Sports Med 26: 217&#x2013;238, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of training leading to repetition failure on muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 487&#x2013;502, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Halaki M, Orr R, Helms ER, Hackett DA. Changes in bench press velocity and power after 8 weeks of high-load cluster- or traditional-set structures. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2734&#x2013;2742, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on dynamic muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 1603&#x2013;1617, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, Lindsell RP, et al. Training leading to repetition failure enhances bench press strength gains in elite junior athletes. J Strength Cond Res 19: 382&#x2013;388, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffey MJ, Challis JH. Fatigue effects on bar kinematics during the bench press. J Strength Cond Res 21: 556&#x2013;560, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Irish CS, Roberts JC, Tarr JE, Jones DA. Fatigue is not a necessary stimulus for strength gains during resistance training. Br J Sports Med 36: 370&#x2013;373, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: Morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med 37: 145&#x2013;168, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Steele J, Pereira MC, et al. Comparison of upper body strength gains between men and women after 10 weeks of resistance training. PeerJ 4: e1627, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Sanchez-Medina L. Movement velocity as a measure of loading intensity in resistance training. Int J Sports Med 31: 347&#x2013;352, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Casta&#xf1;o-Zambudio A, et al. Mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual acute responses to different set configurations in full squat. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1581&#x2013;1590, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Am&#xe9;zqueta I, Calbet JA, et al. Energy metabolism during repeated sets of leg press exercise leading to failure or not. PLoS One 7: e40621, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 955&#x2013;963, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: A systematic review. Sports Med 48: 137&#x2013;151, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett D, Roberts-Clarke D, Jain N, et al. Body composition and its association with physical performance, quality of life, and clinical indictors in charcot-marie-tooth disease: A pilot study. Disabil Rehabil 41: 405&#x2013;412, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Davies TB, Orr R, Kuang K, Halaki M. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on muscle-specific hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 473&#x2013;482, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Lawrence MM, Zwetsloot KA, et al. Effect of cluster set configurations on power clean technique. J Sports Sci 31: 488&#x2013;496, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W. Available at: http://www.sportsci.org/resource/stats/relycalc.html . Accessed March 26, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Spreadsheets for analysis of validity and reliability. Sportscience 19: 36&#x2013;42, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Mayo X, Rio-Rodriguez D, et al. Inter-repetition rest training and traditional set configuration produce similar strength gains without cortical adaptations. J Sports Sci 34: 1473&#x2013;1484, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Ibanez J, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, et al. Differential effects of strength training leading to failure versus not to failure on hormonal responses, strength, and muscle power gains. J Appl Physiol 100: 1647&#x2013;1656, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins ND, Miller JM, Buckner SL, et al. Test-retest reliability of single transverse versus panoramic ultrasound imaging for muscle size and echo intensity of the biceps brachii. Ultrasound Med Biol 41: 1584&#x2013;1591, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten B, Fu YL, Larumbe-Zabala E, Seijo M, Naclerio F. Impact of two high-volume set configuration workouts on resistance training outcomes in recreationally trained men. J Strength Cond Res 35(Suppl 1): S136&#x2013;143, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Wang Z, Heymsfield SB, Baumgartner RN, Gallagher D. Total-body skeletal muscle mass: Estimation by a new dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry method. Am J Clin Nutr 76: 378&#x2013;383, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo TK, Li MY. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability esearch. J Chiropr Med 15: 155&#x2013;163, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 772&#x2013;780, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew JL, Ball TE, Arnold MD, Bowen JC. Relative muscular endurance performance as a predictor of bench press strength in college men and women. J Strength Cond Res 6: 200&#x2013;206, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Custodio R, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, et al. Effect of different inter-repetition rest intervals across four load intensities on velocity loss and blood lactate concentration during full squat exercise. J Sports Sci 36: 2856&#x2013;2864, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Artacho AJ, Padial P, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Feriche B. Influence of a cluster set configuration on the adaptations to short-term power training. J Strength Cond Res 32: 930&#x2013;937, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med 58: 115&#x2013;130, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Farias Zuniga A, et al. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. J Physiol 597: 4601&#x2013;4613, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson G, Ispoglou T, Bissas A. The impact of repetition mechanics on the adaptations resulting from strength-, hypertrophy- and cluster-type resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1875&#x2013;1888, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Loftin M, Abe T. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci 4: 217&#x2013;220, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Jagim AR, Sanchez AC, et al. Greater gains in strength and power with intraset rest intervals in hypertrophic training. J Strength Cond Res 27: 3116&#x2013;3131, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Kreutzer A, Jenke S, et al. Acute response to cluster sets in trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 2383&#x2013;2393, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Sanchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 724&#x2013;735, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Villalba-Fernandez A, Cornejo-Daza PJ, Sanchez-Valdepenas J, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Time course of recovery following resistance exercise with different loading magnitudes and velocity loss in the set. Sports (Basel) 7: 59, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetovich TK, et al. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richens B, Cleather DJ. The relationship between the number of repetitions performed at given intensities is different in endurance and strength trained athletes. Biol Sport 31: 157&#x2013;161, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney KJ, Herbert RD, Balnave RJ. Fatigue contributes to the strength training stimulus. Med Sci Sports Exerc 26: 1160&#x2013;1164, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Influence of exercise and training on motor unit activation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 15: 95&#x2013;151, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1725&#x2013;1734, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Evidence-based guidelines for resistance training volume to maximize muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J 41: 108&#x2013;113, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Does training to failure maximize muscle hypertrophy? Strength Cond J 41: 108&#x2013;113, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott JM, Martin DS, Ploutz-Snyder R, et al. Panoramic ultrasound: A novel and valid tool for monitoring change in muscle mass. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 8: 475&#x2013;481, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Triplett NT. Program design for resistance training. In: Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Haff GG, Triplett NT., eds. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2016. p. 465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering BA, Kraemer WJ, Anderson JM, et al. Resistance exercise biology: Manipulation of resistance exercise programme variables determines the responses of cellular and molecular signalling pathways. Sports Med 38: 527&#x2013;540, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, McGuff D, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. Resistance training to momentary muscular failure improves cardiovascular fitness in humans: A review of acute physiological responses and chronic physiological adaptations. J Exerc Physiol Online 15: 53&#x2013;80, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Brown LE, Haff GG. Theoretical and practical aspects of different cluster set structures: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 31: 848&#x2013;867, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, et al. Maintenance of velocity and power with cluster sets during high-volume back squats. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 885&#x2013;892, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol 126: 30&#x2013;43, 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>