<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33555822</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Resistance Training Performed to Failure or Not to Failure on Muscle Strength, Hypertrophy, and Power Output: A Systematic Review With Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1165</StartPage><EndPage>1175</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1165-1175</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003936</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vieira, AF, Umpierre, D, Teodoro, JL, Lisboa, SC, Baroni, BM, Izquierdo, M, and Cadore, EL. Effects of resistance training performed to failure or not to failure on muscle strength, hypertrophy, and power output: A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 35(4): 1165-1175, 2021-The aim of this review was to summarize the evidence from longitudinal studies assessing the effects induced by resistance training (RT) performed to failure (RTF) vs. not to failure (RTNF) on muscle strength, hypertrophy, and power output in adults. Three electronic databases were searched using terms related to RTF and RTNF. Studies were eligible if they met the following criteria: randomized and nonrandomized studies comparing the effects of RTF vs. RTNF on muscle hypertrophy, maximal strength, and muscle power in adults, and RT intervention &#x2265;6 weeks. Results were presented as standardized mean differences (SMDs) between treatments with 95% confidence intervals, and calculations were performed using random effects models. Significance was accepted when p &lt; 0.05. Thirteen studies were included in this review. No difference was found between RTF and RTNF on maximal strength in overall analysis (SMD: -0.08; p = 0.642), but greater strength increase was observed in RTNF considering nonequalized volumes (SMD: -0.34; p = 0.048). Resistance training performed to failure showed a greater increase in muscle hypertrophy than RTNF (SMD: 0.75; p = 0.005), whereas no difference was observed considering equalized RT volumes. No difference was found between RTF and RTNF on muscle power considering overall analysis (SMD: -0.20; p = 0.239), whereas greater improvement was observed in RTNF considering nonequalized RT volumes (SMD: -0.61; p = 0.025). Resistance training not to failure may induce comparable or even greater improvements in maximal dynamic strength and power output, whereas no difference between RTF vs. RTNF is observed on muscle hypertrophy, considering equalized RT volumes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vieira</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Research Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Dance, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Umpierre</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Science and Technology for Health Technology Assessment (IATS/HCPA), Clinical Research Center, Clinicas Hospital of Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Pathophysiology Laboratory, Graduate Program in Cardiology and Cardiovascular Sciences, University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teodoro</LastName><ForeName>Juliana L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Research Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Dance, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lisboa</LastName><ForeName>Salime C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Research Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Dance, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baroni</LastName><ForeName>Bruno M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Rehabilitation Sciences, Federal University of Health Sciences of Porto Alegre, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Izquierdo</LastName><ForeName>Mikel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Navarrabiomed, Hospital Complex of Navarra (CHN)-Public University of Navarra (UPNA), IdiSNA, Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cadore</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Research Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Dance, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202104000-00039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, Alberton CL, et al. Strength prior to endurance intra-session exercise sequence optimizes neuromuscular and cardiovascular gains in elderly men. Exp Gerontol 47: 164&#x2013;169, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Menger E, Teodoro JL, et al. Functional and physiological adaptations following concurrent training using sets with and without concentric failure in elderly men: A randomized clinical trial. Exp Gerontol 110: 182&#x2013;190, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Pinto RS, Lhullier FLR, et al. Physiological effects of concurrent training in elderly men. Int J Sports Med 31: 689&#x2013;697, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Pinto RS, Reischak-Oliveira &#xc1;, Izquierdo M. Explosive type of contractions should not be avoided during resistance training in elderly. Exp Gerontol 102: 81&#x2013;83, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casas-Herrero A, Cadore EL, Zambom-Ferraresi F, et al. Functional capacity, muscle fat infiltration, power output, and cognitive impairment in institutionalized frail oldest old. Rejuvenation Res 16: 396&#x2013;403, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of training leading to repetition failure on muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 487&#x2013;502, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Erratum to: Effect of training leading to repetition failure on muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 605&#x2013;610, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, Lindsell RP, et al. Training leading to repetition failure enhances bench press strength gains in elite junior athletes. J Strength Cond Res 19: 382&#x2013;388, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, McKenna MJ, et al. Increased number of forced repetitions does not enhance strength development with resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 21: 841&#x2013;847, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finn HT, Brennan SL, Gonano BM, et al. Muscle activation does not increase after a fatigue plateau is reached during 8 sets of resistance exercise in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 28: 1226&#x2013;1234, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Smith D. Attempting to better define &#x201c;intensity&#x201d; for muscular performance: Is it all wasted effort? Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 4183&#x2013;4185, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Blossom D, Steele J. A comparison of volume-equated knee extensions to failure, or not to failure, upon rating of perceived exertion and strength adaptations. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 41: 168&#x2013;174, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Irish C, Roberts J, et al. Fatigue is not a necessary stimulus for strength gains during resistance training. Br J Sports Med 36: 370&#x2013;373, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: Position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2019&#x2013;2052, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giessing J, Fisher J, Steele J, et al. The effects of low volume resistance training with and without advanced techniques in trained participants. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 56: 249&#x2013;258, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gj&#xf8;vaag TF, Mirtaheri P, Simon K, et al. Hemodynamic responses to resistance exercise in patients with coronary artery disease. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 581&#x2013;588, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Am&#xe9;zqueta I, Calbet JAL, et al. Energy metabolism during repeated sets of leg press exercise leading to failure or not. PLoS One 7: e40621, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Am&#xe9;zqueta I, Calbet JAL, et al. Blood ammonia and lactate as markers of muscle metabolites during leg press exercise. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2775&#x2013;2785, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Eldridge S, Li T. Chapter 23: Including variants on randomized trials. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.0.Cochrane. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley Online Library, 2019. pp. 2311&#x2013;2316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Green S. Chapter 8: Assessment of risk of bias in included studies. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley-Blackwell: Cochrane Book Series: Cochrane Collaboration, 2008. pp. 187&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ 327: 557&#x2013;560, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff J, Helgerud J. Endurance and strength training for soccer players. Sports Med 34: 165&#x2013;180, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Gonzalez-Badillo J, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Gorostiaga E. Effects of long-term training specificity on maximal strength and power of the upper and lower extremities in athletes from different sports. Eur J Appl Physiol 87: 264&#x2013;271, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Kraemer WJ, Larrion JL, Gorostiaga EM. Once weekly combined resistance and cardiovascular training in healthy older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 435&#x2013;443, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Iba&#xf1;ez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, et al. Differential effects of strength training leading to failure versus not to failure on hormonal responses, strength, and muscle power gains. J Appl Physiol 100: 1647&#x2013;1656, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Gabarren M, Gonz&#xe1;lez de Txabarri Exp&#xf3;sito R, Garc&#xed;a-Pallar&#xe9;s J, et al. Concurrent endurance and strength training not to failure optimizes performance gains. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 1191&#x2013;1199, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keitaro K, Toshihiro I, Hideaki Y. Effects of 4, 8, and 12 repetition maximum resistance training protocols on muscle volume and strength. J Strength Cond Res 1, 2020. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003575</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Newton RU, et al. Effects of heavy-resistance training on hormonal response patterns in younger vs. older men. J Appl Physiol 87: 982&#x2013;992, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Patton JF, Gordon SE, et al. Compatibility of high-intensity strength and endurance training on hormonal and skeletal muscle adaptations. J Appl Physiol 78: 976&#x2013;989, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JB, Stone MH, O'Bryant HS, et al. Effects of single vs. multiple sets of weight training: Impact of volume, intensity, and variation. J Strength Cond Res: 143&#x2013;147, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise: A meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1890&#x2013;1901, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: Explanation and elaboration. PLoS Med 6: e1000100, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Ugrinowitsch C, Tricoli V, Pivetti B, Roschel H. Different loading schemes in power training during the preseason promote similar performance improvements in Brazilian elite soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1791&#x2013;1797, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell DI, Cuneo R, Gass GC. The blood pressure response of older men to maximum and sub-maximum strength testing. J Sci Med Sport 14: 254&#x2013;258, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martorelli S, Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, et al. Strength training with repetitions to failure does not provide additional strength and muscle hypertrophy gains in young women. Eur J Transl Myol 27: 6339, 2017. Available at: http://www.pagepressjournals.org/index.php/bam/article/view/6339 . Accessed June 27, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, P&#xe9;rez CE, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R, et al. Time course of recovery following resistance training leading or not to failure. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 2387&#x2013;2399, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin J-B, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Brughelli M, Samozino P. When jump height is not a good indicator of lower limb maximal power output: Theoretical demonstration, experimental evidence and practical solutions. Sports Med 49: 999&#x2013;1006, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio F, Faigenbaum AD, Larumbe-Zabala E, et al. Effects of different resistance training volumes on strength and power in team sport athletes. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1832&#x2013;1840, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nery SdS, Gomides RS, Silva GVd, et al. Intra-arterial blood pressure response in hypertensive subjects during low- and high-intensity resistance exercise. Clinics (Sao Paulo) 65: 271&#x2013;277, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs. Volitional interruption at high- and low-intensities on muscle mass and strength. J Strength Cond Res 32: 162&#x2013;169, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter KB, Haff GG, Ramsey MW, et al. Strength gains: Block versus daily undulating periodization weight training among track and field athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 7: 161&#x2013;169, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga E, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo J. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on neuromuscular performance. Int J Sports Med 35: 916&#x2013;924, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 724&#x2013;735, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto S, Cadore E, Alberton C, et al. Effects of intra-session exercise sequence during water-based concurrent training. Int J Sports Med 35: 41&#x2013;48, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Botton CE, Wilhelm EN, et al. Time course of low- and high-volume strength training on neuromuscular adaptations and muscle quality in older women. Age (Dordr) 36: 881&#x2013;892, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Fielding RA. Skeletal muscle power: A critical determinant of physical functioning in older adults. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 40: 4&#x2013;12, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney KJ, Herbert RD, Balnave RJ. Fatigue contributes to the strength training stimulus. Med Sci Sports Exerc 26: 1160&#x2013;1164, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson JA, Groeller H. Is repetition failure critical for the development of muscle hypertrophy and strength?: Failure is not necessary for strength gain. Scand J Med Sci Sports 26: 375&#x2013;383, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanborn K, Boros R, Hruby J, et al. Short-term performance effects of weight training with multiple sets not to failure vs. a single set to failure in women. J Strength Cond Res 14: 328&#x2013;331, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1725&#x2013;1734, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. High-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2954&#x2013;2963, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamseer L, Moher D, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: Elaboration and explanation. BMJ 349: g7647, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva LXN, Teodoro JL, Menger E, et al. Repetitions to failure versus not to failure during concurrent training in healthy elderly men: A randomized clinical trial. Exp Gerontol 108: 18&#x2013;27, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J. Intensity; in-ten-si-ty; noun. 1. Often used ambiguously within resistance training. 2. Is it time to drop the term altogether? Br J Sports Med 48: 1586&#x2013;1588, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Andersen CH, et al. Muscle activation strategies during strength training with heavy loading vs. Repetitions to failure. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1897&#x2013;1903, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tajra V, Vieira DCL, Tibana RA, et al. Different acute cardiovascular stress in response to resistance exercise leading to failure versus not to failure in elderly women with and without hypertension&#x2014;A pilot study. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 127&#x2013;133, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teodoro JL, da Silva LXN, Fritsch CG, et al. Concurrent training performed with and without repetitions to failure in older men: A randomized clinical trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports 29: 1141&#x2013;1152, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W, Cheung MWL. Outlier and influence diagnostics for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods 1: 112&#x2013;125, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM. The application of training to failure in periodized multiple-set resistance exercise programs. J Strength Cond Res 21: 628&#x2013;631, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Norton L, Wilson G. Training to failure and beyond in mainstream resistance exercise programs. Strength Cond J 32: 21&#x2013;29, 2010.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>