<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41343037</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Resistance Training Dose Response: Meta-Regressions Exploring the Effects of Weekly Volume and Frequency on Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength Gains.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>481</StartPage><EndPage>505</EndPage><MedlinePgn>481-505</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02344-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Weekly set volume and frequency are used to manipulate resistance training dosage. Previous research has identified higher weekly set volume as enhancing muscle hypertrophy and strength gains, but the nature of the dose-response relationship still needs to be investigated. Mixed evidence exists regarding the effects of higher weekly frequency.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We aimed to explore the dose-response relationships between key resistance training dosage variables (weekly set volume and frequency) and strength and hypertrophy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Before meta-analyzing the volume and frequency research, all contributing resistance training sets were classified as direct or indirect, depending on their specificity to the hypertrophy/strength measurement. Then, weekly set volume/frequency for indirect sets was quantified as 1 for 'total,' 0.5 for 'fractional,' and 0 for 'direct.' A series of multi-level meta-regressions were performed for muscle hypertrophy and strength, utilizing 67 total studies of 2058 participants (79.1% male, 20.9% female; average age 25.16&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.22&#xa0;years). All models were adjusted for the duration of the intervention and training status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The relative evidence for the 'fractional' quantification method was strongest; therefore, this quantification method was used for the primary meta-regression models. The posterior probability of the marginal slope exceeding zero for the effect of volume on both hypertrophy and strength was 100%, indicating that gains in muscle size and strength increase as volume increases. However, both best-fit models suggest diminishing returns, with the diminishing returns for strength being considerably more pronounced. The posterior probability of the marginal slope exceeding zero for frequency's effect on hypertrophy was less than 100%, indicating compatibility with negligible effects. In contrast, the posterior probability for strength was 100%, suggesting strength gains increase with increasing frequency, albeit with diminishing returns.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Distinguishing between direct and indirect sets appears essential for predicting adaptations to a given resistance training protocol, such as using the 'fractional' quantification method. This method's dose-response models revealed that volume and frequency have unique dose-response relationships with each hypertrophy and strength gains. The dose-response relationship between volume and hypertrophy appears to differ from that with strength, with the latter exhibiting more pronounced diminishing returns. The dose-response relationship between frequency and hypertrophy appears to differ from that with strength, as only the latter exhibits consistently identifiable effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pelland</LastName><ForeName>Joshua C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-5962-9603</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle Physiology Laboratory, Department of Exercise Science and Health Promotion, Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Rd., Boca Raton, FL, 33431, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Remmert</LastName><ForeName>Jacob F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5227-6541</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle Physiology Laboratory, Department of Exercise Science and Health Promotion, Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Rd., Boca Raton, FL, 33431, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robinson</LastName><ForeName>Zac P</ForeName><Initials>ZP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-1672-2903</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle Physiology Laboratory, Department of Exercise Science and Health Promotion, Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Rd., Boca Raton, FL, 33431, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hinson</LastName><ForeName>Seth R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle Physiology Laboratory, Department of Exercise Science and Health Promotion, Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Rd., Boca Raton, FL, 33431, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zourdos</LastName><ForeName>Michael C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3265-7683</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle Physiology Laboratory, Department of Exercise Science and Health Promotion, Florida Atlantic University, 777 Glades Rd., Boca Raton, FL, 33431, USA. mzourdos@fau.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012044" MajorTopicYN="N">Regression Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflicts of Interest/Competing Interests: The authors have no conflicts of interest specifically pertaining to this article. However, the authors have written about fitness and resistance training content previously; therefore, we wish to note that Joshua Pelland, Jacob Remmert, Zac Robinson, Seth Hinson, and Michael Zourdos are coaches and writers in the fitness industry. Ethics Approval: Not applicable. Consent to Participate: Not applicable. Consent for Publication: Not applicable. Availability of Data and Material: All data and supplementary materials are available on the Open Science Framework project page ( https://osf.io/6z3xu ). Code Availability: The code is available on the Open Science Framework project page ( https://osf.io/6z3xu ). Authors&#x2019; Contributions: All authors contributed to the concept of the manuscript. JCP and JFR performed the systematic search. JCP, JFR, and SRH extracted data. ZPR performed the statistical analysis, with assistance from JCP. JCP wrote the initial manuscript. All authors revised the manuscript and approved the final version.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41343037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02344-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02344-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2016.1210197 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1210197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner S, Moreno E, Baxter HT. The dose-response relationship between resistance training volume and muscle hypertrophy: there are still doubts. J Trainology. 2023;12(2):29&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.17338/trainology.12.2_29 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17338/trainology.12.2_29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Fontes-Villalba M, Santos-Concejero J. Total number of sets as a training volume quantification method for muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(3):870&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002776 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Fisher J, Grgic J, Haun C, Helms E, Phillips S, et al. Resistance training recommendations to maximize muscle hypertrophy in an athletic population: position stand of the IUSCA. Int J Strength Cond. 2021. https://doi.org/10.47206/ijsc.v1i1.81 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47206/ijsc.v1i1.81</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Alix-Fages C, Santos-Concejero J. A systematic review of the effects of different resistance training volumes on muscle hypertrophy. J Hum Kinet. 2022;81:199&#x2013;210. https://doi.org/10.2478/hukin-2022-0017 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2022-0017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35291645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8884877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(4):1150&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d4d436 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d4d436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(12):2585&#x2013;601. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-017-0762-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0762-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28755103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5684266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royston P, Altman DG, Sauerbrei W. Dichotomizing continuous predictors in multiple regression: a bad idea. Stat Med. 2006;25(1):127&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1002/sim.2331 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.2331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16217841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naggara O, Raymond J, Guilbert F, Roy D, Weill A, Altman DG. Analysis by categorizing or dichotomizing continuous variables is inadvisable: an example from the natural history of unruptured aneurysms. Am J Neuroradiol. 2011;32(3):437&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.3174/ajnr.A2425 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3174/ajnr.A2425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21330400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8013096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannarino P, Matta T, Lima J, Sim&#xe3;o R, Freitas de Salles B. Single-joint exercise results in higher hypertrophy of elbow flexors than multijoint exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(10):2677&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003234 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31268995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand&#xe3;o L, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, Silva-Batista C, Brendon H, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Varying the order of combinations of single- and multi-joint exercises differentially affects resistance training adaptations. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(5):1254&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003550 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J, Haun C, Itagaki T, Helms E. Calculating set-volume for the limb muscles with the performance of multi-joint exercises: implications for resistance training prescription. Sports. 2019;7(7):177. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports7070177 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7070177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31336594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6681288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Soares S, Bottaro M. Single vs. multi-joint resistance exercises: effects on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Asian J Sports Med. 2015;6(2):e24057. https://doi.org/10.5812/asjsm.24057 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/asjsm.24057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26446291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4592763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger J. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(11):1286&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2018.1555906 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2018.1555906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effects of resistance training frequency on measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(11):1689&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-016-0543-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0543-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27102172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Buchan D, Baker JS. Weekly training frequency effects on strength gain: a meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2018;4(1):36. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40798-018-0149-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-018-0149-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6081873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, Lazinica B, Krieger JW, Pedisic Z. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(5):1207&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbert M, Haff GG, Arent SM, Ripley N, McMahon JJ, Evans M, et al. Effects of variations in resistance training frequency on strength development in well-trained populations and implications for in-season athlete training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51(9):1967&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-021-01460-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01460-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8363540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currier BS, Mcleod JC, Banfield L, Beyene J, Welton NJ, D&#x2019;Souza AC, et al. Resistance training prescription for muscle strength and hypertrophy in healthy adults: a systematic review and Bayesian network meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(18):1211&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2023-106807 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37414459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10579494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Ioannidis JPA, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: explanation and elaboration. PLoS Med. 2009;21:e1000100. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1000100 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1000100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Nuckols GL, Fisher J, Heathers J, Krieger J, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Improbable data patterns in the work of Barbalho et al. 2020. Available from: https://osf.io/sg3wm . Accessed 30 Jul 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Waldron M, Ismail H, Giallauria F, Vigorito C, Cornelissen V, et al. Validation of a new tool for the assessment of study quality and reporting in exercise training studies: TESTEX. Int J Evid Based Healthc. 2015;13(1):9&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1097/XEB.0000000000000020 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/XEB.0000000000000020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L. Graphical augmentations to sample-size-based funnel plot in meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2019;10(3):376&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrsm.1340 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30664834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6642847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Lagisz M, Jennions MD, Koricheva J, Noble DWA, Parker TH, et al. Methods for testing publication bias in ecological and evolutionary meta-analyses. Methods Ecol Evol. 2022;13(1):4&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1111/2041-210X.13724 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.13724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starkey DB, Pollock ML, Ishida Y, Welsch MA, Brechue WF, Graves JE, et al. Effect of resistance training volume on strength and muscle thickness. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28(10):1311&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-199610000-00016 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199610000-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8897390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcelos LC, Nunes PRP, de Souza LRMF, de Oliveira AA, Furlanetto R, Marocolo M, et al. Low-load resistance training promotes muscular adaptation regardless of vascular occlusion, load, or volume. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(7):1559&#x2013;68. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-015-3141-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3141-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25731927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly SB, Brown LE, Coburn JW, Zinder SM, Gardner LM, Nguyen D. The effect of single versus multiple sets on strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(4):1003&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1519/R-22356.1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-22356.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shigaki L, Ara&#xfa;jo CGA, Calderon MG, Costa TKC, Aguiar AF, Costa LOP, et al. Effects of volume training on strength and endurance of back muscles: a randomized controlled trial. J Sport Rehabil. 2018;27(4):340&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1123/jsr.2016-0253 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2016-0253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28513268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Abernethy PJ, Logan PA, Barber M, McEniery MT. Resistance training frequency: strength and myosin heavy chain responses to two and three bouts per week. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1998;78(3):270&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004210050419 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio F, Faigenbaum AD, Larumbe-Zabala E, Perez-Bibao T, Kang J, Ratamess NA, et al. Effects of different resistance training volumes on strength and power in team sport athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(7):1832&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182736d10 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182736d10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23044934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride JM, Blaak JB, Triplett-McBride T. Effect of resistance exercise volume and complexity on EMG, strength, and regional body composition. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;90(5&#x2013;6):626&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-003-0930-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-003-0930-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12923645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra R, Saavedra F, Jotta B, Novaes J, Cardozo D, Alves H, et al. The influence weekly resistance training frequency on strength and body composition. Int J Sports Sci. 2018;8(1):19&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.5923/j.sports.20180801.04 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5923/j.sports.20180801.04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Asadi A. Effects of 8 weeks equal-volume resistance training with different workout frequency on maximal strength, endurance and body composition. Int J Sports Sci Eng. 2011;05(02):112&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humburg H, Baars H, Schr&#xf6;der J, Reer R, Braumann KM. 1-set vs. 3-set resistance training: a crossover study. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):578&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1519/R-21596.1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-21596.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Hern&#xe1;ndez J, Mar&#xed;n PJ, Men&#xe9;ndez H, Ferrero C, Loenneke JP, Herrero AJ. Muscular adaptations after two different volumes of blood flow-restricted training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23(2):e114&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.12036 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braith RW, Graves JE, Pollock ML, Leggett SL, Carpenter DM, Colvin AB. Comparison of 2 vs 3 days/week of variable resistance training during 10- and 18-week programs. Int J Sports Med. 1989;10(6):450&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-2007-1024942 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1024942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2628366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMichele PL, Pollock ML, Graves JE, Foster DN, Carpenter D, Garzarella L, et al. Isometric torso rotation strength: effect of training frequency on its development. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1997;78(1):64&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0003-9993(97)90012-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0003-9993(97)90012-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9014960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher JP, Smith D, Schoenfeld BJ, Yang Y, Nakagawa S. Meta-analysis of variation in sport and exercise science: examples of application within resistance training research. J Sports Sci. 2023;41(17):1617&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1080/02640414.2023.2286748 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2023.2286748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38037792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amrhein V, Greenland S, McShane B. Scientists rise up against statistical significance. Nature. 2019;567(7748):305&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-019-00857-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/d41586-019-00857-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner MJ, Altman DG. Confidence intervals rather than P values: estimation rather than hypothesis testing. Br Med J Clin Res Ed. 1986;292(6522):746&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.292.6522.746 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.292.6522.746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3082422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1339793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White IR, Turner RM, Karahalios A, Salanti G. A comparison of arm-based and contrast-based models for network meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2019;38(27):5197&#x2013;213. https://doi.org/10.1002/sim.8360 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.8360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31583750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6899819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crippa A, Discacciati A, Bottai M, Spiegelman D, Orsini N. One-stage dose&#x2013;response meta-analysis for aggregated data. Stat Methods Med Res. 2019;28(5):1579&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1177/0962280218773122 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0962280218773122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29742975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods. 2008;11(2):364&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1177/1094428106291059 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1094428106291059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lajeunesse MJ. On the meta-analysis of response ratios for studies with correlated and multi-group designs. Ecology. 2011;92(11):2049&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1890/11-0423.1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/11-0423.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Williams C, Senior AM, Morrison K, Ricolfi L, Pan J, et al. Bivariate multilevel meta-analysis of log response ratio and standardized mean difference for robust and reproducible environmental and biological sciences. 2024. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.13.594019 . Accessed 1 Aug 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al., editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. 1st ed. Wiley; 2019. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119536604 . Accessed 1 Aug 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Noble DWA, Lagisz M, Spake R, Viechtbauer W, Senior AM. A robust and readily implementable method for the meta-analysis of response ratios with and without missing standard deviations. Ecol Lett. 2023;26(2):232&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1111/ele.14144 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ele.14144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36573275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Schielzeth H. A general and simple method for obtaining R <sup>2</sup> from generalized linear mixed-effects models. Methods Ecol Evol. 2013;4(2):133&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2041-210x.2012.00261.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2041-210x.2012.00261.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;decke D, Ben-Shachar M, Patil I, Waggoner P, Makowski D. Performance: an R package for assessment, comparison and testing of statistical models. J Open Source Softw. 2021;6(60):3139. https://doi.org/10.21105/joss.03139 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21105/joss.03139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenth RV. emmeans: estimated marginal means, aka least-squares means. 2017: p. 1.10.3. Available from: https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=emmeans . cited 2024 Aug 1].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedder H, Dias S, Bennetts M, Boucher M, Welton NJ. Joining the dots: linking disconnected networks of eeidence using dose-response model-based network meta-analysis. Med Decis Making. 2021;41(2):194&#x2013;208. https://doi.org/10.1177/0272989X20983315 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X20983315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7879230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kass RE, Raftery AE. Bayes factors. J Am Stat Assoc. 1995;90(430):773&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1080/01621459.1995.10476572 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01621459.1995.10476572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddaway NR, Page MJ, Pritchard CC, McGuinness LA. PRISMA2020&#x202f;: an R package and Shiny app for producing PRISMA 2020-compliant flow diagrams, with interactivity for optimised digital transparency and open synthesis. Campbell Syst Rev. 2022;18(2):e1230. https://doi.org/10.1002/cl2.1230 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cl2.1230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36911350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8958186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirthalingam T, Mavros Y, Wilson GC, Clarke JL, Mitchell L, Hackett DA. Effects of a modified German volume training program on muscular hypertrophy and strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(11):3109&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000001747 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27941492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo AR, Silva-Batista C, Pedroso K, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Volume load rather than resting interval influences muscle hypertrophy during high-intensity resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(6):1554&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003668 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares LD, de Souza EO, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino GC, Roschel H, Aihara AY, et al. Effects of different strength training frequencies during reduced training period on strength and muscle cross-sectional area. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(6):665&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2017.1298673 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1298673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28316261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fitzpatrick A, Bruce-Low S, Fisher J. The effects of set volume during isolated lumbar extension resistance training in recreationally trained males. PeerJ. 2015;3:e878. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.878 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4389271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Egeland W, Kvamme NH, Refsnes PE, Kadi F, Raastad T. Dissimilar effects of one- and three-set strength training on strength and muscle mass gains in upper and lower body in untrained subjects. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(1):157&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1519/00124278-200702000-00028 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200702000-00028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PWM, McEwen M, Robbins DW. Strength and neuromuscular adaptation following one, four, and eight sets of high intensity resistance exercise in trained males. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(12):3007&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-011-1944-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1944-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21451937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evangelista AL, Braz TV, La Scala Teixeira CV, Rica RL, Alonso AC, Barbosa WA, et al. Split or full-body workout routine: which is best to increase muscle strength and hypertrophy? Einstein (S&#xe3;o Paulo). 2021;19:eAO5781. https://doi.org/10.31744/einstein_journal/2021AO5781 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31744/einstein_journal/2021AO5781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34468591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8372753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves RP, Vechin FC, Teixeira EL, da Silva DD, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, et al. Effect of different training frequencies on maximal strength performance and muscle hypertrophy in trained individuals-a within-subject design. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(10):e0276154. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0276154 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0276154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36228016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9560172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corr&#xea;a DA, Brigatto FA, Braz TV, DE Carmargo JB, Aoki MS, Marchetti PH, et al. Twice-daily sessions result in a greater muscle strength and a similar muscle hypertrophy compared to once-daily session in resistance-trained men. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2022;62(3):324&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.23736/S0022-4707.21.12118-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.21.12118-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33634677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaroni RS, Brigatto FA, Schoenfeld BJ, Braz TV, Benvenutti JC, Germano MD, et al. High resistance-training frequency enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(Suppl. 1):S140&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002643 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31260419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Burke DG. Effect of short-term equal-volume resistance training with different workout frequency on muscle mass and strength in untrained men and women. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(1):204&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1519/00124278-200702000-00037 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200702000-00037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun RJ, Gai CM, Aguilar D, Bove D, Dolan J, Vargas A, et al. Training volume, not frequency, indicative of maximal strength adaptations to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(5):1207&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002414 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29324578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fisher J, Steele J, Campos MH, Silva MH, Paoli A, et al. Effects of equal-volume resistance training with different training frequencies in muscle size and strength in trained men. PeerJ. 2018;6:e5020. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.5020 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.5020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29942690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6016534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, Grgic J, Delcastillo K, Belliard R, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(1):94&#x2013;103. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000001764 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6303131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes GK, Franco CM, Nunes PRP, Orsatti FL. High-frequency resistance training is not more effective than low-frequency resistance training in increasing muscle mass and strength in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(Suppl. 1):S130&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002559 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco CMC, Carneiro MAS, de Sousa JFR, Gomes GK, Orsatti FL. Influence of high- and low-frequency resistance training on lean body mass and muscle strength gains in untrained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(8):2089&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003145 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar G, Pandey V, Thapa RK, Weldon A, Granacher U, Ramirez-Campillo R. Effects of exercise frequency with complex contrast training on measures of physical fitness in active adult males. Sports. 2023;11(1):11. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports11010011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports11010011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36668715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9862768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Asadi A, Gentil P, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R, Jahangiri P, Ghorbani A, et al. Effects of different resistance training frequencies on body composition and muscular performance adaptations in men. PeerJ. 2021;9:e10537. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.10537 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.10537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33976952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8067909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, de Lima LEM, Germano MD, Aoki MS, Braz TV, Lopes CR. High resistance-training volume enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(1):22&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003413 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31868813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Nymark BS, Raastad T. Effects of in-season strength maintenance training frequency in professional soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(10):2653&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e31822dcd96 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31822dcd96</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21873897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamarsland H, Moen H, Skaar OJ, Jorang PW, R&#xf8;dahl HS, R&#xf8;nnestad BR. Equal-volume strength training with different training frequencies induces similar muscle hypertrophy and strength improvement in trained participants. Front Physiol. 2021;12:789403. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2021.789403 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.789403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Fleck SJ, Leite T, Leite RD, Pinto RS, Fernandes L, et al. Dose-response of 1, 3, and 5 sets of resistance exercise on strength, local muscular endurance, and hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(5):1349&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000000758 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25546444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Myklestad D, Raastad T. The influence of volume of exercise on early adaptations to strength training. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(1):115&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1519/1533-4287(2003)017%3c0115:tiovoe%3e2.0.co;2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(2003)017&lt;0115:tiovoe&gt;2.0.co;2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Amirthalingam T, Mitchell L, Mavros Y, Wilson GC, Halaki M. Effects of a 12-week modified German volume training program on muscle strength and hypertrophy: a pilot study. Sports. 2018;6(1):7. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports6010007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports6010007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5969184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Laurentino G, Tavares LD, Tricoli V. Similar muscular adaptations in resistance training performed two versus three days per week. J Hum Kinet. 2019;68:135&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.2478/hukin-2019-0062 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2019-0062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31531139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6724585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Braz TV, da Zanini TCC, Germano MD, Aoki MS, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effect of resistance training frequency on neuromuscular performance and muscle morphology after 8 weeks in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2104&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002563 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29528962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen E, van den Tillaar R. Effects of training frequency on muscular strength for trained men under volume matched conditions. PeerJ. 2021;9:e10781. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.10781 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.10781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7897409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Tiryaki-Sonmez G. Influence of resistance training frequency on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(7):1821&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000000970 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25932981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortes LS, Costa MC, Ferreira MEC, Nascimento-J&#xfa;nior JRA, Fiorese L, Lima-J&#xfa;nior DRAA, et al. Frequency of resistance training does not affect inhibitory control or improve strength in well-trained young adults. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(11):e0206784. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0206784 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0206784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30388181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6214533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fischer B, Martorelli AS, Lima RM, Bottaro M. Effects of equal-volume resistance training performed one or two times a week in upper body muscle size and strength of untrained young men. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2015;55(3):144&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24732784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaselgrave SR, Blacker J, Smeuninx B, McKendry J, Breen L. Dose-response relationship of weekly resistance-training volume and frequency on muscular adaptations in trained men. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(3):360&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2018-0427 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30160627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas MH, Burns SP. Increasing lean mass and strength: a comparison of high frequency strength training to lower frequency strength training. Int J Exerc Sci. 2016;9(2):159&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/HDLQ5133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27182422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4836564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcelos C, Damas F, N&#xf3;brega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Marcelino Eder Dos Santos L, et al. High-frequency resistance training does not promote greater muscular adaptations compared to low frequencies in young untrained men. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(8):1077&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2018.1476590 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1476590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29852092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saric J, Lisica D, Orlic I, Grgic J, Krieger JW, Vuk S, et al. Resistance training frequencies of 3 and 6 times per week produce similar muscular adaptations in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(Suppl. 1):S122&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002909 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Garzarella L, de Hoyos D, Pollock ML. Single versus multiple sets in long-term recreational weightlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(1):235&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-200001000-00035 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200001000-00035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aube D, Wadhi T, Rauch J, Anand A, Barakat C, Pearson J, et al. Progressive resistance training volume: effects on muscle thickness, mass, and strength adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(3):600&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Ball SD, Burkett LN. Three sets of weight training superior to 1 set with equal intensity for eliciting strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16(4):525&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue FL, Karsten B, Larumbe-Zabala E, Seijo M, Naclerio F. Comparison of 2 weekly-equalized volume resistance-training routines using different frequencies on body composition and performance in trained males. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(5):475&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1139/apnm-2017-0575 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2017-0575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29216446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sooneste H, Tanimoto M, Kakigi R, Saga N, Katamoto S. Effects of training volume on strength and hypertrophy in young men. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(1):8&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182679215 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182679215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23249767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker JS, Davies B, Cooper SM, Wong DP, Buchan DS, Kilgore L. Strength and body composition changes in recreationally strength-trained individuals: comparison of one versus three sets resistance-training programmes. BioMed Res Int. 2013;2013:615901. https://doi.org/10.1155/2013/615901 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/615901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24083231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3780552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottaro M, Veloso J, Wagner D, Gentil P. Resistance training for strength and muscle thickness: effect of number of sets and muscle group trained. Sci Sports. 2011;26(5):259&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scispo.2010.09.009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2010.09.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLester JRJR, Bishop E, Guilliams ME. Comparison of 1 day and 3 days per week of equal-volume resistance training in experienced subjects. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14(3):273&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DWD, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113(1):71&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3404827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski KJ, Wilson GJ, Weatherby R, Murphy PW, Lyttle AD. The effect of weight training volume on hormonal output and muscular size and function. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(3):148&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlumberger A, Stec J, Schmidtbleicher D. Single- vs. multiple-set strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15(3):284&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11710652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochi E, Maruo M, Tsuchiya Y, Ishii N, Miura K, Sasaki K. Higher training frequency is important for gaining muscular strength under volume-matched training. Front Physiol. 2018;9:744. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2018.00744 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.00744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30013480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6036131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth C, Schwiete C, Happ K, Rettenmaier L, Schoenfeld BJ, Behringer M. Resistance training volume does not influence lean mass preservation during energy restriction in trained males. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2023;33(1):20&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.14237 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36114738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reba&#xef; H, Chtourou H, Zarrouk N, Harzallah A, Kanoun I, Dogui M, et al. Reducing resistance training volume during Ramadan improves muscle strength and power in football players. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(5):432&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0033-1353216 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0033-1353216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24048913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammarstr&#xf6;m D, &#xd8;fsteng S, Koll L, Hanestadhaugen M, Hollan I, Apr&#xf3; W, et al. Benefits of higher resistance-training volume are related to ribosome biogenesis. J Physiol. 2020;598(3):543&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP278455 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP278455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31813190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enes A, DE Souza EO, Souza-Junior TP. Effects of different weekly set progressions on muscular adaptations in trained males: is there a dose-response effect? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2024;56(3):553&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000003317 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37796222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Vossel K, Hardeel J, Van de Casteele F, Van der Stede T, Weyns A, Boone J, et al. Can muscle typology explain the inter-individual variability in resistance training adaptations? J Physiol. 2023;601(12):2307&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP284442 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP284442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37038845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy KG, Schwarz NA, Mota JA, Colquhoun RJ. No differences in strength improvements following low- or high-volume resistance training. In: International Journal of Exercise Science: Conference Proceedings 2023. Available from: https://digitalcommons.wku.edu/ijesab/vol2/iss15/41 . Accessed 5 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen H, Iversen VM, Vereide PF, Stien N, Saeterbakken AH, Fimland MS, et al. High-frequency resistance training improves maximal lower-limb strength more than low frequency. Eur J Sport Sci. 2024;24(5):557&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsc.12055 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejsc.12055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11235667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel CS, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Exercise dosing to retain resistance training adaptations in young and older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1177&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e318207c15d .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318207c15d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molinari T, Radaelli R, Rech A, Brusco CM, Markarian AM, Lopez P. Moderators of resistance training effects in healthy young women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(4):804&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000004666 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38090747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson ZP, Pelland JC, Remmert JF, Refalo MC, Jukic I, Steele J, et al. Exploring the dose-response relationship between estimated resistance training proximity to failure, strength gain, and muscle hypertrophy: a series of meta-regressions. Sports Med. 2024;54(9):2209&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-024-02069-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02069-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38970765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitz RW, Kataoka R, Dankel SJ, Bell ZW, Song JS, Wong V, et al. Quantifying the generality of strength adaptation: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(3):637&#x2013;48. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-022-01790-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01790-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36396899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstrom AD, Marshall PW, Halaki M, Hackett DA. The effect of resistance training in women on dynamic strength and muscular hypertrophy: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(6):1075&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01247-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01247-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31820374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1997;273(1 Pt 1):E99-107. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E99 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E99</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Perco JG, Moore DR, Wilkinson SB, Phillips SM. Resistance training alters the response of fed state mixed muscle protein synthesis in young men. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2008;294(1):R172&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpregu.00636.2007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00636.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Gibala MJ, Tarnopolsky MA, MacDonald JR, Interisano SA, Yarasheski KE. The time course for elevated muscle protein synthesis following heavy resistance exercise. Can J Appl Physiol. 1995;20(4):480&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1139/h95-038 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h95-038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8563679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Libardi CA, Vechin FC, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Jannig PR, et al. Resistance training-induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. J Physiol. 2016;594(18):5209&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP272472 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP272472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27219125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5023708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Counts BR, et al. Frequency: the overlooked resistance training variable for inducing muscle hypertrophy? Sports Med. 2017;47(5):799&#x2013;805. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-016-0640-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0640-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remmert J, Pelland J, Robinson Z, Hinson S, Zourdos M. Is there too much of a good thing?: meta-regressions of the effect of per-session volume on hypertrophy and strength. 2025. Available from: https://sportrxiv.org/index.php/server/preprint/view/537/version/689 . Accessed 26 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mouser JG, Loenneke JP. Practicing the test produces strength equivalent to higher volume training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(9):1945&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000001300 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Trajano GS, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(6):1206&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000002585 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8126497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito PJ, Cupeiro R, Ramos-Campo DJ, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias J&#xc1;. A systematic review with meta-analysis of the effect of resistance training on whole-body muscle growth in healthy adult males. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(4):1285. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17041285 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17041285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32079265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7068252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Atherton PJ, Selby A, Rankin D, Williams J, Smith K, et al. Muscle protein synthetic responses to exercise: effects of age, volume, and intensity. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2012;67(11):1170&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1093/gerona/gls141 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/gls141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22859389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, West DWD, Staples AW, Cain NE, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men: Resistance exercise volume and myofibrillar protein synthesis. J Physiol. 2010;588(16):3119&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2010.192856 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2010.192856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2956949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G, Spengos K, Mascher H, Georgiadis G, Manta P, Blomstrand E. The degree of p70S6k and S6 phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle in response to resistance exercise depends on the training volume. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(4):835&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-010-1527-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1527-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20617335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Angleri V, Phillips SM, Witard OC, Ugrinowitsch C, Santanielo N, et al. Myofibrillar protein synthesis and muscle hypertrophy individualized responses to systematically changing resistance training variables in trained young men. J Appl Physiol. 2019;127(3):806&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00350.2019 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00350.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31268828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Walker S, Silvennoinen M, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Nindl BC, H&#xe4;kkinen K, et al. Exercise type and volume alter signaling pathways regulating skeletal muscle glucose uptake and protein synthesis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(9):1835&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-015-3155-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3155-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Arihara Y, Takegaki J, Nakazato K, Ishii N. Relationship between exercise volume and muscle protein synthesis in a rat model of resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2017;123(4):710&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.01009.2016 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01009.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28729395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe BL, Lemura LM, Cole PJ. Quantitative analysis of single- vs multiple-set programs in resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(1):35-47. https://doi.org/10.1519/1533-4287(2004)018&lt;0035:qaosvm&gt;2.0.co;2 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise: a meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(6):1890&#x2013;901. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b370be .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b370be</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Buckner SL, Dankel SJ, Abe T. Exercise-induced changes in nuscle size do not contribute to exercise-induced changes in muscle strength. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):987&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01106-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01106-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber CB, Vigotsky A, Nuckols G, Haun CT. Exercise-induced myofibrillar hypertrophy is a contributory cause of gains in muscle strength. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):993&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01107-8 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01107-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31016546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Meur Y, Hausswirth C, Mujika I. Tapering for competition: a review. Sci Sports. 2012;27(2):77&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scispo.2011.06.013 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2011.06.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Androulakis-Korakakis P, Michalopoulos N, Fisher JP, Keogh J, Loenneke JP, Helms E, et al. The minimum effective training dose required for 1RM strength in powerlifters. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3:713655. https://doi.org/10.3389/fspor.2021.713655 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.713655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34527944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8435792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelland JC, Robinson ZP, Remmert JF, Cerminaro RM, Benitez B, John TA, et al. Methods for controlling and reporting resistance training proximity to failure: current issues and future directions. Sports Med. 2022;52(7):1461&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-022-01667-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01667-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35247203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson ZP, Helms ER, Trexler ET, Steele J, Hall ME, Huang CJ, et al. N of 1: optimizing nethodology for the detection of individual response variation in resistance training. Sports Med. 2024;54(8):1979&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-024-02050-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02050-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38878117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine JA, Abboud L, Barry M, Reed JE, Sheedy PF, Jensen MD. Measuring leg muscle and fat mass in humans: comparison of CT and dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(2):452&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.2000.88.2.452 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.2.452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10658010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Roberts MD. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol. 2019;10:247. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.00247 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6423469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Nosaka K, Libardi CA, Chen TC, Ugrinowitsch C. Susceptibility to exercise-induced muscle damage: a cluster analysis with a large sample. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37(8):633&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0042-100281 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0042-100281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27116346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Sakamoto K. Effect of elbow joint angle on the magnitude of muscle damage to the elbow flexors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(1):22&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-200101000-00005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200101000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11194107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka K, Clarkson PM. Changes in indicators of inflammation after eccentric exercise of the elbow flexors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28(8):953&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-199608000-00003 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199608000-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8871903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon JA, Hoffman JR, Arroyo E, Varanoske AN, Coker NA, Gepner Y, et al. Comparisons in the recovery response from resistance exercise between young and middle-aged men. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3454&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000002219 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28859014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira DV, Ferreira-J&#xfa;nior JB, Soares SRS, Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, Brown LE, et al. Chest press exercises with different stability requirements result in similar muscle damage recovery in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(1):71&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000001453 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27100318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Roschel H, et al. Early resistance training-induced increases in muscle cross-sectional area are concomitant with edema-induced muscle swelling. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(1):49&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-015-3243-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3243-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26280652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>