<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34580749</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2149-9322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Turkish journal of obstetrics and gynecology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Turk J Obstet Gynecol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Are women with polycystic ovary syndrome more vulnerable to COVID-19 infection?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>221</StartPage><EndPage>223</EndPage><MedlinePgn>221-223</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4274/tjod.galenos.2021.05014</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe acute respiratory syndrome-coronavirus-2, the causative virus of Coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19), penetrates into the hosts' tissues via binding of its spike protein to the angiotensin converting enzyme-2 (ACE-2) receptors after activation of the hosts' protease enzymes. The most prominent effect is observed when the virus binds to the ACE-2 receptors of the alveolar epithelium and endothelium. Testosterone exhibits an immunosuppressive effect, and androgens play a modulatory role on protease enzymes. It is known that various comorbidities, including obesity; pregnancy; diabetes mellitus (type 1 or type 2); hypertension; cancer; chronic kidney, liver, and lung diseases; cerebrovascular disease; heart conditions; human immunodeficiency virus infection; immunologic disease; and immune suppression; affect the severity of COVID-19 infection. Polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) affects 5-10% of reproductive aged-women. Hirsutism is observed in 70-80% of the patients, while increased testosterone levels are detected in more than 50% of the women with PCOS. This syndrome is also associated with hyperandrogenism, insulin resistance, increased renin-angiotensin system activity, diabetes, and metabolic syndrome in a remarkable number of cases. PCOS also manifests a chronic pro-inflammatory state. Hyperandrogenism through hyperinsulinemia causes adipocyte hypertrophy and dysfunction that result in increased secretion of pro-inflammatory adipokine, which culminates in the creation of a chronic inflammatory state. In light of the metabolic and hormonal changes observed in women with PCOS, which make them more susceptible to severe COVID-19 infection, health care givers should provide special care and detailed counseling services.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dilbaz</LastName><ForeName>Berna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1137-8650</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Health Sciences Turkey, Etlik Z&#xfc;beyde Han&#x131;m Women's Health Training and Research Hospital, Clinic of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Ankara, Turkey</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>Turk J Obstet Gynecol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101656661</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2149-9330</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperandrogenism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polycystic ovary syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8480216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4274/tjod.galenos.2021.05014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Price LC, Mac Cabe C, Garfield B, Wort SJ. Thrombosis and COVID-19 pneumonia: the clot thickens! Eur Respir J. 2020;56:2001608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan Y, Shang J, Graham R, Baric RS, Li F. Receptor recognition by the novel coronavirus from Wuhan: an analysis based on decade-long structural studies of SARS coronavirus. J Virol. 2020;94:e00127&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7081895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31996437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalidhindi RSR, Borkar NA, Ambhore NS, Pabelick CM, Prakash YS, Sathish V. Sex steroids skew ACE2 expression in human airway: a contributing factor to sex differences in COVID-19? Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2020;319:L843&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32996784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanff TC, Harhay MO, Brown TS, Cohen JB, Mohareb AM. Is there an association between cov&#x131;d-19 mortality and the renin-angiotensin system? A call for epidemiologic &#x131;nvestigations. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;28;71:870&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scully EP, Haverfield J, Ursin RL, Tannenbaum C, Klein SL. Considering how biological sex impacts immune responses and COVID-19 outcomes. Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20:442&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32528136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kragholm K, Andersen MP, Gerds TA, Butt JH, &#xd8;stergaard L, Polcwiartek C, et al. Association between male sex and outcomes of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19)-a Danish Nationwide, register-based study. Clin Infect Dis. 2020..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32634827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudley JP, Lee NT. Disparities in age-specific morbidity and mortality from SARS-CoV-2 in China and the Republic of Korea. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;15:863&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32232322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerson-Gil A, Palaiodimos L, Assa A, Karamanis D, Kokkinidis D, Chamorro-Pareja N, et al. Sex-specific impact of severe obesity in the outcomes of hospitalized patients with COVID-19: a large retrospective study from the Bronx, New York. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2021;40:1963&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8101338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33956286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasselli G, Greco M, Zanella A, Albano G, Antonelli M, Bellani G, et al. Risk factors associated with mortality among patients with COVID-19 in intensive care units in Lombardy, Italy. JAMA Intern Med. 2020;180:1345&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7364371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrilli CM, Jones SA, Yang J, Rajagopalan H, O&#x2019;Donnell L, Chernyak Y, et al. Factors associated with hospital admission and critical illness among 5279 people with coronavirus disease 2019 in New York City: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2020;369:m1966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi MC, Tieri P, Ortona E, Ruggieri A. ACE2 expression and sex disparity in COVID-19. Cell Death Discov. 2020;6:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32499922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein SL, Flanagan KL. Sex differences in immune responses. Nat Rev Immunol. 2016;16:626&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27546235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouman A, Heineman MJ, Faas MM. Sex hormones and the immune response in humans. Hum Reprod Update. 2005;11:411&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wambier CG, Goren A. Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection is likely to be androgen mediated. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;83:308&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Channappanavar R, Fehr AR, Vijay R, Mack M, Zhao J, Meyerholz DK, et al. Dysregulated type I interferon and inflammatory monocyte-macrophage responses cause lethal pneumonia in SARS-CoV infected mice. Cell Host Microbe. 2016;19:181&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4752723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26867177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spritzer PM, Barone CR, Oliveira FB. Hirsutism in polycystic ovary syndrome: pathophysiology and management. Curr Pharm Des. 2016;22:5603&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27510481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasquali R, Zanotti L, Fanelli F, Mezzullo M, Fazzini A, Labate AMM, et al. Defining hyperandrogenism in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a challenging perspective. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2016;101:2013&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26964728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huffman AM, Rezq S, Basnet J, Yanes Cardozo LL, Romero DG. SARS-CoV-2 viral entry proteins in hyperandrogenemic female mice: &#x131;mplications for women with PCOS and COVID-19. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:4472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33922918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitriadis GK, Kyrou I, Randeva HS. Polycystic ovary syndrome as a proinflammatory state: the role of adipokines. Curr Pharm Des. 2016;22:5535&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27464726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird ST, Hartzema AG, Brophy JM, Etminan M, Delaney JA. Risk of venous thromboembolism in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a population-based matched cohort analysis. CMAJ. 2013;185:E115&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3563911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23209115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Y, Wang XM, Mannan R, Pitchiaya S, Zhang Y, Wotring JW, et al. Targeting transcriptional regulation of SARS-CoV-2 entry factors ACE2 and TMPRSS2. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;118:e2021450118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7817128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33310900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian A, Anand A, Adderley NJ, Okoth K, Toulis KA, Gokhale K, et al. Increased COVID-19 infections in women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a population-based study. Eur J Endocrinol. 2021;184:637&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8052516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33635829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgante G, Tro&#xec;a L, De Leo V. Coronavirus disease 2019 (SARS-CoV-2) and polycystic ovarian disease: Is there a higher risk for these women? J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2021;205:105770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7550902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33065278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao CY, Fang XJ, Chen Y, Zhang Q. Effect of vitamin D supplementation on polycystic ovary syndrome: A meta-analysis. Exp Ther Med. 2020;19:2641&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32256745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant WB, Lahore H, McDonnell SL, Baggerly CA, French CB, Aliano JL, et al. Evidence that vitamin D supplementation could reduce risk of influenza and COVID-19 infections and deaths. Nutrients. 2020;12:988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32252338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>