<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32304514</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of 4, 8, and 12 Repetition Maximum Resistance Training Protocols on Muscle Volume and Strength.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>879</StartPage><EndPage>885</EndPage><MedlinePgn>879-885</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003575</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kubo, K, Ikebukuro, T, and Yata, H. Effects of 4, 8, and 12 repetition maximum resistance training protocols on muscle volume and strength. J Strength Cond Res 35(4): 879-885, 2021-The purpose of this study was to determine skeletal muscle adaptations (strength and hypertrophy) in response to volume-equated resistance training with divergent repetition strategies. Forty-two men were randomly assigned to 4 groups: higher load-lower repetition group performing 4 repetition maximum (RM) for 7 sets (4RM, n = 10), intermediate load-intermediate repetition group performing 8RM for 4 sets (8RM, n = 12), lower load-higher repetition group performing 12RM for 3 sets (12RM, n = 10), and nonexercising control group (CON, n = 10). The volume of the pectoralis major muscle (by magnetic resonance imaging) and 1RM of the bench press were measured before and after 10 weeks of training (2 times per week). No significant difference was observed in the relative increase in the muscle volume among the 4RM, 8RM, and 12RM groups. The relative increase in 1RM was significantly lower in the 12RM group than in the 4RM group (p = 0.029) and the 8RM group (p = 0.021). The relative increase in 1RM was significantly correlated with that in the muscle volume in the 12RM group (r = 0.684, p = 0.042), but not in the 4RM (r = -0.265, p = 0.777) or 8RM (r = -0.045, p = 0.889) groups. These results suggest that the increase in muscle size is similar among the 3 training protocols when the training volume was equated, whereas the increase in muscle strength is lower with the 12RM protocol than the other protocols.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kubo</LastName><ForeName>Keitaro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Science (Sports Sciences), the University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikebukuro</LastName><ForeName>Toshihiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Science (Sports Sciences), the University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yata</LastName><ForeName>Hideaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human and Environmental Well-being, Wako University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202104000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol 81: 174&#x2013;180, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg HE, Tedner B, Tesch PA. Changes in lower limb muscle cross-sectional area and tissue fluid volume after transition from standing to supine. Acta Physiol Scand 148: 379&#x2013;385, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomquist K, Langberg H, Karlsen S, et al. Effect of range of motion in heavy load squatting on muscle and tendon adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2133&#x2013;2142, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GER, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 50&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chestnut JL, Docherty D. The effects of 4 and 10 repetition maximum weight-training protocols on neuromuscular adaptations in untrained men. J Strength Cond Res 13: 353&#x2013;359, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J, Takahashi H, Itai Y. The difference between effects of &#x201c;power-up&#x201d; and &#x201c;bulk-up&#x201d; strength training exercises: With special reference to muscle cross-sectional area. Jpn J Phys Fitness Sports Med 47: 119&#x2013;129, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun RJ, Gai CM, Aguilar D, et al. Training volume, not frequency, indicative of maximal strength adaptations to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1207&#x2013;1213, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hisaeda H, Miyagawa K, Kuno S, Fukunaga T, Muraoka I. Influence of two different modes of resistance training in female subjects. Ergonomics 39: 842&#x2013;852, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanehisa H, Nagareda H, Kawakami Y, et al. Effects of equivolume isometric training programs comprising medium or high resistance on muscle size and strength. Eur J Appl Physiol 87: 112&#x2013;119, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami Y, Abe T, Kuno S, Fukunaga T. Training-induced changes in muscle architecture and specific tension. Eur J Appl Physiol 72: 37&#x2013;43, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exer 36: 674&#x2013;688, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of squat training with different depths on lower limb muscle volumes. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 1933&#x2013;1942, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yaeshima K, et al. Effects of static and dynamic training on the stiffness and blood volume of tendon in vivo. J Appl Physiol 106: 412&#x2013;417, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Morimoto M, Komuro T, et al. Effects of plyometric and weight training on muscle-tendon complex and jump performance. Med Sci Sports Exer 39: 1801&#x2013;1810, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Gonzalez AM, et al. The effect of training volume and intensity on improvements in muscular strength and size in resistance-trained men. Physiol Rep 3: e12472, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew JL, Johnson BD, LaMonte MJ, Lauber D, Kemmler W. Accuracy of prediction equations for determining one repetition maximum bench press in women before and after resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1570&#x2013;1577, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries H. Potential for gross muscle hypertrophy in older men. J Gerontol 35: 672&#x2013;682, 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Hoppeler H, Kayser B, et al. Human quadriceps cross-sectional area, torque and neural activation during 6 months strength training. Acta Physiol Scand 157: 175&#x2013;186, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Yasuda T, Sakamaki M, Ozaki H, Abe T. Effects of periodic and continued resistance training on muscle CSA and strength in previously untrained men. Clin Physiol Func Imaging 31: 399&#x2013;404, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Applications of the dose-response for muscular strength development: A review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J Strength Cond Res 19: 950&#x2013;958, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Maximizing strength development in athletes: A meta-analysis to determine the dose-response relationship. J Strength Cond Res 18: 377&#x2013;382, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG, Martin JE, Moroz DE. Hypertrophy without increased isometric strength after weight training. Eur J Appl Physiol 64: 51&#x2013;55, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exer 51: 94&#x2013;103, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Vigotsky AD, Peterson M. Differential effects of heavy versus moderate loads on measures of strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Sports Sci Med 15: 715&#x2013;722, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, et al. Longer interset rest periods enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1805&#x2013;1812, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, et al. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2909&#x2013;2918, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson SR, Rozenek R, Garhammer J, Lacourse M, Storer T. Comparison of one repetition maximums between free weight and universal machine exercises. J Strength Cond Res 11: 103&#x2013;106, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, O'Bryant H, Garhammer J. A hypothetical model for strength training. J Sports Med 21: 342&#x2013;351, 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawakami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy: Its relation to muscle activation in training session. Med Sci Sports Exer 45: 2158&#x2013;2165, 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>