<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38085619</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Patellar Tendon Adaptations to Downhill Running Training and Their Relationships With Changes in Mechanical Stress and Loading History.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>21</StartPage><EndPage>29</EndPage><MedlinePgn>21-29</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004617</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bontemps, B, Gruet, M, Louis, J, Owens, DJ, Mir&#xed;c, S, Vercruyssen, F, and Erskine, RM. Patellar tendon adaptations to downhill running training and their relationships with changes in mechanical stress and loading history. J Strength Cond Res 38(1): 21-29, 2024-It is unclear whether human tendon adapts to moderate-intensity, high-volume long-term eccentric exercise, e.g., downhill running (DR) training. This study aimed to investigate the time course of patellar tendon (PT) adaptation to short-term DR training and to determine whether changes in PT properties were related to changes in mechanical stress or loading history. Twelve untrained, young, healthy adults (5 women and 7 men) took part in 4 weeks' DR training, comprising 10 sessions. Running speed was equivalent to 60-65% V&#x307;O2max, and session duration increased gradually (15-30 minutes) throughout training. Isometric knee extensor maximal voluntary torque (MVT), vastus lateralis (VL) muscle physiological cross-sectional area (PCSA) and volume, and PT CSA, stiffness, and Young's modulus were assessed at weeks 0, 2, and 4 using ultrasound and isokinetic dynamometry. Patellar tendon stiffness (+6.4 &#xb1; 7.4%), Young's modulus (+6.9 &#xb1; 8.8%), isometric MVT (+7.5 &#xb1; 12.3%), VL volume (+6.6 &#xb1; 3.2%), and PCSA (+3.8 &#xb1; 3.3%) increased after 4 weeks' DR (p &lt; 0.05), with no change in PT CSA. Changes in VL PCSA correlated with changes in PT stiffness (r = 0.70; p = 0.02) and Young's modulus (r = 0.63; p = 0.04) from 0 to 4 weeks, whereas changes in MVT did not correlate with changes in PT stiffness and Young's modulus at any time point (p &gt; 0.05). To conclude, 4 weeks' DR training promoted substantial changes in PT stiffness and Young's modulus that are typically observed after high-intensity, low-volume resistance training. These tendon adaptations seemed to be driven primarily by loading history (represented by VL muscle hypertrophy), whereas increased mechanical stress throughout the training period did not seem to contribute to changes in PT stiffness or Young's modulus.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bontemps</LastName><ForeName>Bastien</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4323-7804</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Toulon, Laboratoire IAPS (n&#xb0;201723207F), Toulon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; C&#xf4;te d'Azur, LAMHESS, Nice, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gruet</LastName><ForeName>Mathieu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Toulon, Laboratoire IAPS (n&#xb0;201723207F), Toulon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Louis</LastName><ForeName>Julien</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9109-0958</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owens</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1908-8677</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mir&#xed;c</LastName><ForeName>Stella</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vercruyssen</LastName><ForeName>Fabrice</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Toulon, Laboratoire IAPS (n&#xb0;201723207F), Toulon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erskine</LastName><ForeName>Robert M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5705-0207</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport, Exercise and Health, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017847" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patellar Ligament</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013314" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Mechanical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055119" MajorTopicYN="N">Elastic Modulus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38085619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202401000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arampatzis A, De Monte G, Karamanidis K, Morey-Klapsing G, Stafilidis S, Br&#xfc;ggemann GP. Influence of the muscle-tendon unit's mechanical and morphological properties on running economy. J Exp Biol 209: 3345&#x2013;3357, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arampatzis A, Karamanidis K, Albracht K. Adaptational responses of the human Achilles tendon by modulation of the applied cyclic strain magnitude. J Exp Biol 210: 2743&#x2013;2753, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arampatzis A, Karamanidis K, Mademli L, Albracht K. Plasticity of the human tendon to short- and long-term mechanical loading. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 37: 66&#x2013;72, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arampatzis A, Karamanidis K, Morey-Klapsing G, De Monte G, Stafilidis S. Mechanical properties of the triceps surae tendon and aponeurosis in relation to intensity of sport activity. J Biomech 40: 1946&#x2013;1952, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm S, Mersmann F, Tettke M, Kraft M, Arampatzis A. Human Achilles tendon plasticity in response to cyclic strain: Effect of rate and duration. J Exp Biol 217: 4010&#x2013;4017, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bontemps B, Gruet M, Louis J, et al. The time course of different neuromuscular adaptations to short-term downhill running training and their specific relationships with strength gains. Eur J Appl Physiol 122: 1071&#x2013;1084, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bontemps B, Vercruyssen F, Gruet M, Louis J. Downhill running: What are the effects and how can we adapt? A narrative review. Sports Med 50: 2083&#x2013;2110, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buczek FL, Cavanagh PR. Stance phase knee and ankle kinematics and kinetics during level and downhill running. Med Sci Sports Exerc 22: 669&#x2013;677, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess KE, Pearson SJ, Onambele GL. Patellar tendon properties with fluctuating menstrual cycle hormones. J Strength Condit Res 24: 2088&#x2013;2095, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couppe C, Kongsgaard M, Aagaard P, et al. Habitual loading results in tendon hypertrophy and increased stiffness of the human patellar tendon. J Appl Physiol 105: 805&#x2013;810, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dideriksen K, Sindby AK, Krogsgaard M, Schjerling P, Holm L, Langberg H. Effect of acute exercise on patella tendon protein synthesis and gene expression. SpringerPlus 2: 109, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorn TW, Schache AG, Pandy MG. Muscular strategy shift in human running: Dependence of running speed on hip and ankle muscle performance. J Exp Biol 215: 1944&#x2013;1956, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekizos A, Papatzika F, Charcharis G, Bohm S, Mersmann F, Arampatzis A. Ultrasound does not provide reliable results for the measurement of the patellar tendon cross sectional area. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 23: 1278&#x2013;1282, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Jones DA, Maganaris CN, Degens H. In vivo specific tension of the human quadriceps femoris muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol 106: 827&#x2013;838, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, Rahbek SK, Vendelbo MH, et al. Whey protein hydrolysate augments tendon and muscle hypertrophy independent of resistance exercise contraction mode. Scand J Med Sci Sports 24: 788&#x2013;798, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett WE Jr. Muscle strain injuries. Am J Sports Med 24: S2&#x2013;S8, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geremia JM, Baroni BM, Bobbert MF, Bini RR, Lanferdini FJ, Vaz MA. Effects of high loading by eccentric triceps surae training on Achilles tendon properties in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 1725&#x2013;1736, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giandolini M, Vernillo G, Samozino P, et al. Fatigue associated with prolonged graded running. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1859&#x2013;1873, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottschall JS, Kram R. Ground reaction forces during downhill and uphill running. J Biomech 38: 445&#x2013;452, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen P, Aagaard P, Kjaer M, Larsson B, Magnusson SP. Effect of habitual running on human Achilles tendon load-deformation properties and cross-sectional area. J Appl Physiol 95: 2375&#x2013;2380, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeier KM, Olesen JL, Haddad F, et al. Expression of collagen and related growth factors in rat tendon and skeletal muscle in response to specific contraction types. J Physiol 582: 1303&#x2013;1316, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeier KM, Olesen JL, Schjerling P, et al. Short-term strength training and the expression of myostatin and IGF-I isoforms in rat muscle and tendon: Differential effects of specific contraction types. J Appl Physiol 102: 573&#x2013;581, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz B. The relation between force and speed in muscular contraction. J Physiol 96: 45&#x2013;64, 1939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaux J-F, Drion P, Libertiaux V, et al. Eccentric training improves tendon biomechanical properties: A rat model. J Orthop Res 31: 119&#x2013;124, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E, Baltzopoulos V. The effects of antagonist moment on the resultant knee joint moment during isokinetic testing of the knee extensors. Eur J Appl Physiol 76: 253&#x2013;259, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaer M. Role of extracellular matrix in adaptation of tendon and skeletal muscle to mechanical loading. Physiol Rev 84: 649&#x2013;698, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongsgaard M, Reitelseder S, Pedersen TG, et al. Region specific patellar tendon hypertrophy in humans following resistance training. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 191: 111&#x2013;121, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krevolin JL, Pandy MG, Pearce JC. Moment arm of the patellar tendon in the human knee. J Biomech 37: 785&#x2013;788, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ishigaki T, Ikebukuro T. Effects of plyometric and isometric training on muscle and tendon stiffness in vivo. Physiol Rep 5: e13374, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. Elastic properties of muscle-tendon complex in long-distance runners. Eur J Appl Physiol 81: 181&#x2013;187, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langberg H, Skovgaard D, Petersen LJ, Bulow J, Kjaer M. Type I collagen synthesis and degradation in peritendinous tissue after exercise determined by microdialysis in humans. J Physiol 521: 299&#x2013;306, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeda E, Shelton JC, Bader DL, Lee DA. Differential regulation of gene expression in isolated tendon fascicles exposed to cyclic tensile strain in vitro. J Appl Physiol 106: 506&#x2013;512, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson SP, Kjaer M. Region-specific differences in Achilles tendon cross-sectional area in runners and non-runners. Eur J Appl Physiol 90: 549&#x2013;553, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson SP, Narici MV, Maganaris CN, Kjaer M. Human tendon behaviour and adaptation, in vivo. J Physiol 586: 71&#x2013;81, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malliaras P, Kamal B, Nowell A, et al. Patellar tendon adaptation in relation to load-intensity and contraction type. J Biomech 46: 1893&#x2013;1899, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massey GJ, Balshaw TG, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Folland JP. Tendinous tissue properties after short- and long-term functional overload: Differences between controls, 12 weeks and 4 years of resistance training. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 222: e13019, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntosh JE, Matthews CD, Crocker JM, Broom TJ, Cox LW. Predicting me luteinizing hormone surge: Relationship between me duration of me follicular and luteal phases and the length of the human menstrual cycle. Fertil Steril 34: 125&#x2013;130, 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller BF, Olesen JL, Hansen M, et al. Coordinated collagen and muscle protein synthesis in human patella tendon and quadriceps muscle after exercise. J Physiol 567: 1021&#x2013;1033, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monte A, Baltzopoulos V, Maganaris CN, Zamparo P. Gastrocnemius medialis and vastus lateralis in vivo muscle&#x2010;tendon behavior during running at increasing speeds. Scand J Med Sci Sports 30: 1163&#x2013;1176, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olesen JL, Heinemeier KM, Gemmer C, Kjaer M, Flyvbjerg A, Langberg H. Exercise-dependent IGF-I, IGFBPs, and type I collagen changes in human peritendinous connective tissue determined by microdialysis. J Appl Physiol 102: 214&#x2013;220, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Jeon HM, Lam WK, Stefanyshyn D, Ryu J. The effects of downhill slope on kinematics and kinetics of the lower extremity joints during running. Gait Posture 68: 181&#x2013;186, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan JI, Franchi MV, Gharahdaghi N, et al. Muscle and tendon adaptations to moderate load eccentric vs. concentric resistance exercise in young and older males. Geroscience 43: 1567&#x2013;1584, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roig M, O'Brien K, Kirk G, et al. The effects of eccentric versus concentric resistance training on muscle strength and mass in healthy adults: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med 43: 556&#x2013;568, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, Erskine RM, Maganaris CN, et al. Training-induced changes in structural and mechanical properties of the patellar tendon are related to muscle hypertrophy but not to strength gains. J Appl Physiol 107: 523&#x2013;530, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonsen EB, Klitgaard H, Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller F. The influence of strength training, swim training and ageing on the Achilles tendon and m. soleus of the rat. J Sports Sci 13: 291&#x2013;295, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyomura J, Mori H, Tayashiki K, Yamamoto M, Kanehisa H, Maeo S. Efficacy of downhill running training for improving muscular and aerobic performances. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 43: 403&#x2013;410, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JH. Mechanobiology of tendon. J Biomech 39: 1563&#x2013;1582, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westh E, Kongsgaard M, Bojsen-Moller J, et al. Effect of habitual exercise on the structural and mechanical properties of human tendon, in vivo, in men and women. Scand J Med Sci Sports 18: 23&#x2013;30, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger HP, Kosters A, Muller E, Seynnes OR. Effects of increased loading on in vivo tendon properties: A systematic review. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 1885&#x2013;1895, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger HP, Rieder F, Kosters A, Muller E, Seynnes OR. Are sport-specific profiles of tendon stiffness and cross-sectional area determined by structural or functional integrity? PLoS One 11: e0158441, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger HP, Rieder F, Kosters A, Muller E, Seynnes OR. Sport-specific capacity to use elastic energy in the patellar and Achilles tendons of elite athletes. Front Physiol 8: 132, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wren TA, Lindsey DP, Beaupr&#xe9; GS, Carter DR. Effects of creep and cyclic loading on the mechanical properties and failure of human Achilles tendons. Ann Biomed Eng 31: 710&#x2013;717, 2003.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>