<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33826122</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Equating Resistance-Training Volume Between Programs Focused on Muscle Hypertrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1171</StartPage><EndPage>1178</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1171-1178</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-021-01449-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Calculating resistance-training volume in programs focused on muscle hypertrophy is an attempt to quantify the external workload carried out, then to estimate the dose of stimulus imposed on targeted muscles. The volume is usually expressed in some variables that directly affected the total training work, such as the number of sets, repetitions, and volume-load. These variables are used to try to quantify the training work easily, for the subsequent organization and prescription of training programs. One of the main uses of measures of volume quantification is seen in studies in which the purpose is to compare the effects of different training protocols on muscle growth in a volume-equated format. However, it seems that not all measures of volume are always appropriate for equating training protocols. In the current paper, it is discussed what training volume is and the potentials and shortcomings of each one of the most common ways to equate it between groups depending on the independent variable to be compared (e.g., weekly frequency, intensity of load, and advanced techniques).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8144-5906</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil. joaonunes.jpn@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassiano</LastName><ForeName>Witalo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Bruna D V</ForeName><Initials>BDV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayhew</LastName><ForeName>Jerry L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science Program, Truman State University, Kirksville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, University of Northern Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory. Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33826122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01449-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-021-01449-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: the most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med. 2018;48(3):499&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29022275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Colenso-Semple L, Phillips SM. Training for strength and hypertrophy: an evidence-based approach. Curr Opin Physiol. 2019;10:90&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger JW. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(11):1286&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer WJ. Designing resistance training programs. 4th ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost DM, Cronin J, Newton RU. A biomechanical evaluation of resistance: fundamental concepts for training and sports performance. Sports Med. 2010;40(4):303&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20364875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG. Quantifying workloads in resistance training: a brief review. UK Strength Cond J. 2010;19:31&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J. Evidence-based guidelines for resistance training volume to maximize muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J. 2018;40(4):107&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Duthie GM, Thornton HR, Dascombe BJ. Training monitoring for resistance exercise: theory and applications. Sports Med. 2016;46(5):687&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marston KJ, Peiffer JJ, Newton MJ, Scott BR. A comparison of traditional and novel metrics to quantify resistance training. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):5606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28717150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5514046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride JM, McCaulley GO, Cormie P, Nuzzo JL, Cavill MJ, Triplett NT. Comparison of methods to quantify volume during resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(1):106&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, Mouser JG, Counts BR, Buckner SL, et al. Training to fatigue: the answer for standardization when assessing muscle hypertrophy? Sports Med. 2017;47(6):1021&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27677915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu LZF. Biomechanical methods to quantify muscle effort during resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(2):502&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29120981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de S&#xe1; EC, Medeiros AR, Ferreira AS, Ramos AG, Janicijevic D, Boullosa D. Validity of the iLOAD&#xae; app for resistance training monitoring. PeerJ. 2019;7:e7372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31410306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6689219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castilla AP, Boullosa DA, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A. Reliability and validity of the iLOAD&#xae; application for monitoring the mean set velocity during the back squat and bench press exercises performed against different loads. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(Suppl 1):S57&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Geiser G, Krzykowski J, Kipp K. Validity and reliability of a computer-vision-based smartphone app for measuring barbell trajectory during the snatch. J Sports Sci. 2020;38(6):710&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32079484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polito MD. Improving muscular strength and hypertrophy: are we following the right scientific way? J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2019;59(2):342&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29619802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Costa BDV, Nunes JP, Aguiar A., de Salles BF, Ribeiro AS. Are we exploring the potential role of specialized training techniques in muscle hypertrophy? Int J Sports Med. 2021 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Fontes-Villalba M, Santos-Concejero J. Total number of sets as a training volume quantification method for muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(3):870&#x2013;878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaroni RS, Brigatto FA, Schoenfeld BJ, Braz TV, Benvenutti JC, Germano MD, et al. High resistance-training frequency enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(Suppl 1):140&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes GK, Franco CM, Nunes PRP, Orsatti FL. High-frequency resistance training is not more effective than low-frequency resistance training in increasing muscle mass and strength in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(Suppl 1):130&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saric J, Lisica D, Orlic I, Grgic J, Krieger JW, Vuk S, et al. Resistance training frequencies of 3 and 6 times per week produce similar muscular adaptations in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(Suppl 1):122&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina FLC, Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Nascimento MA, Gerage AM, Janu&#xe1;rio RSB, et al. Effects of different weekly sets-equated resistance training frequencies on muscular strength, muscle mass, and body fat in older women. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(10):2990&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30908365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson J, Wadhi T, Barakat C, Aube D, Schoenfeld BJ, Andersen JC, et al. Does varying repetition tempo in a single-joint lower body exercise augment muscle size and strength in resistance-trained men? J Strength Cond Res. 2021 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo AR, Silva-Batista C, Pedroso K, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Volume load rather than resting interval influences muscle hypertrophy during high-intensity resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Tufano JJ, Zajac A. The influence of movement tempo on acute neuromuscular, hormonal, and mechanical responses to resistance exercise&#x2014;a mini review. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(8):2369&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Krieger JW, Schoenfeld BJ. The effects of short versus long inter-set rest intervals in resistance training on measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(8):983&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28641044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tot&#xf3; ECC, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o M, Vieira A, Pareja-Blanco F, Bottaro M, Boullosa D. Are cluster sets an effective method to induce muscular hypertrophy in response to resistance training? Braz J Sport Med. 2020;42:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Wilk M, Wojda&#x142;a G, Go&#x142;as A. Maximizing muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review of advanced resistance training techniques and methods. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(24):E4897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Grgic J, Cunha PM, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, de Salles BF, et al. What influence does resistance exercise order have on muscular strength gains and muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effect of repetition duration during resistance training on muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(4):577&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Nunes JP, Cunha PM, Aguiar AF, Schoenfeld BJ. The potential role of pre-exhaustion training in maximizing muscle hypertrophy: a review of the literature. Strength Cond J. 2019;41(1):75&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Ugrinowitsch C, Augusto C. Crescent pyramid and drop-set systems do not promote greater strength gains, muscle hypertrophy, and changes on muscle architecture compared with traditional resistance training in well- trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(2):359&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Reeves ND, Narici MV. Skeletal muscle remodeling in response to eccentric vs. concentric loading: morphological, molecular, and metabolic adaptations. Front Physiol. 2017;8:447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28725197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5495834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Vigotsky AD, Franchi MV, Krieger JW. Hypertrophic effects of concentric vs. eccentric muscle actions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(9):2599&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28486337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Amirthalingam T. A brief review of forced repetitions for the promotion of muscular hypertrophy. Strength Cond J. 2015;37(5):14&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Looze MP, Toussaint HM, Commissaris DACM, Jans MP, Sargeant AJ. Relationships between energy expenditure and positive and negative mechanical work in repetitive lifting and lowering. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77(1):420&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7961264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott BC, Bigland B, Ritchie JM. The physiological cost of negative work. J Physiol. 1952;117(3):380&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14946742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1392548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(6):1609&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22990567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Sonmez GT, Alvar BA. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(10):2909&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24714538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- versus high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, Roschel H, Tavares LD, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(6):772&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29564973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GER, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(1&#x2013;2):50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeger WWK, Hopkins DR, Barrete SL, Hale DF. Relationship between repetitions and selected percentages of one repetition maximum: a comparison between untrained and trained males and females. J Strength Cond Res. 1990;4(2):47&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimano T, Kraemer WJ, Spiering BA, Volek JS, Hatfield DL, Silvestre R, et al. Relationship between the number of repetitions and selected percentages of one repetition maximum in free weight exercises in trained and untrained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(4):819&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Endres A, Fisher J, Gentil P, Giessing J. Ability to predict repetitions to momentary failure is not perfectly accurate, though improves with resistance training experience. PeerJ. 2017;5:e4105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29204323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5712461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emanuel A, Smukas IIR, Halperin I. An analysis of the perceived causes leading to task-failure in resistance-exercises. PeerJ. 2020;8:e9611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33194334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7391967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansfield S, Peiffer J, Hughes L, Scott B. Estimating repetitions in reserve for resistance exercise: an analysis of factors which impact on prediction accuracy. J Strength Cond Res. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Sabol F. Effects of resistance training performed to repetition failure or non-failure on muscular strength and hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2021 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Cronin J, Storey A, Zourdos MC. Application of the repetitions in reserve-based rating of perceived exertion scale for resistance training. Strength Cond J. 2016;38(4):42&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27531969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4961270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martorelli S, Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, Celes R, Martorelli A, Cleto VA, et al. Strength training with repetitions to failure does not provide additional strength and muscle hypertrophy gains in young women. Eur J Transl Myol. 2017;27(2):113&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva-Batista C, Barros T de S, Aihara AY, Brendon H, et al. Muscle failure promotes greater muscle hypertrophy in low-load but not in high-load resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2019 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Nakamura M, Ribeiro AS, Cunha PM, Cyrino ES. Does stretch training induce muscle hypertrophy in humans? A review of the literature. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2020;40(3):148&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31984621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Mattocks KT, Dankel SJ, Abe T, et al. Muscle adaptations to high-load training and very low-load training with and without blood flow restriction. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30386254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6198179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martorelli AS, de Lima FD, Vieira A, Tufano JJ, Ernesto C, Boullosa D, et al. The interplay between internal and external load parameters during different strength training sessions in resistance-trained men. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;21(1):16&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Pina FLC, Ribeiro AS, Cunha PM, Kassiano W, Costa BDV, et al. Responsiveness to muscle mass gain following 12 and 24 weeks of resistance training in older women. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aube D, Wadhi T, Rauch J, Anand A, Barakat C, Pearson J, et al. Progressive resistance training volume: effects on muscle thickness, mass, and strength adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli MC, N&#xf3;brega SR, Santanielo N, Alvarez IF, Otoboni GB, Ugrinowitsch C, et al. Muscle hypertrophy response is affected by previous resistance training volume in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2857&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgenson KW, Phillips SM, Hornberger TA. Identifying the structural adaptations that drive the mechanical load-induced growth of skeletal muscle: a scoping review. Cells. 2020;9(7):1658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7408414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Teo WP, Spathis J, van den Hoek D. Long-term strength adaptation: a 15-year analysis of powerlifting athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(9):2412&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32865942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7448836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelico D. A comparison of open and closed chain knee extension exercises on patterns of quadriceps hypertrophy [Internet]. 2020. https://digitalcommons.uri.edu/theses/1845 . Accessed 19 Jan 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Gentil P, Moro T, Marcolin G, Bianco A. Resistance training with single vs. multi-joint exercises at equal total load volume: effects on body composition, cardiorespiratory fitness, and muscle strength. Front Physiol. 2017;8:1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29312007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5744434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newmire DE, Willoughby DS. Partial compared with full range of motion resistance training for muscle hypertrophy: a brief review and an identification of potential mechanisms. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(9):2652&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of squat training with different depths on lower limb muscle volumes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(9):1933&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31230110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomquist K, Langberg H, Karlsen S, Madsgaard S, Boesen M, Raastad T. Effect of range of motion in heavy load squatting on muscle and tendon adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(8):2133&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23604798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, de Souza EO, Wilson JM, Laurentino GC, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(11):3085&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand&#xe3;o L, de Salles PV, Lasevicius T, Silva-Batista C, Brendon H, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Varying the order of combinations of single- and multi-joint exercises differentially affects resistance training adaptations. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(5):1254&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto RS, Gomes N, Radaelli R, Botton CE, Brown LE, Bottaro M. Effect of range of motion on muscle strength and thickness. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(8):2140&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22027847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Soares S, Bottaro M. Single vs multi-joint resistance exercises: effects on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Asian J Sports Med. 2015;6(2):e24057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26446291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4592763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Meng H, Yuhang W, Sakurai H, Kusagawa Y, Sugiyama T, et al. Greater hamstrings muscle hypertrophy but similar damage protection after training at long versus short muscle lengths. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(4):825&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves SFN, Rocha-J&#xfa;nior VA, Encarna&#xe7;&#xe3;o IGA, Martins-Costa HC, Freitas EDS, Coelho DB, et al. Effects of horizontal and incline bench press on neuromuscular adaptations in untrained young men. Int J Exerc Sci. 2020;13(6):859&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7449336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Costa BDV, Kassiano W, Kunevaliki G, Castro-e-Souza P, Rodacki ALF, et al. Different foot positioning during calf training to induce portion-specific gastrocnemius muscle hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(8):2347&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Jacinto JL, Ribeiro AS, Mayhew JL, Nakamura M, Capel DMG, et al. Placing greater torque at shorter or longer muscle lengths? Effects of cable vs. barbell preacher curl training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in young adults. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(16):5859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa BD V, Kassiano W, Nunes JP, Kunevaliki G, Castro-e-Souza P, Rodacki ALF, et al. Does performing different resistance exercises induce non-homogeneous hypertrophy? Int J Sports Med. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauch JT, Ugrinowitsch C, Barakat CI, Alvarez MR, Brummert DL, Aube DW, et al. Auto-regulated exercise selection training regimen produces small increases in lean body mass and maximal strength adaptations in highly trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(4):1133&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Schoenfeld BJ, Torres-Unda J, Santos-Concejero J, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C. The effects of exercise variation in muscle thickness, maximal strength and motivation in resistance trained men. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(12):e0226989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31881066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6934277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannarino P, Matta T, Lima J, Sim&#xe3;o R, de Salles BF. Single-joint exercise results in higher hypertrophy of elbow flexors than multijoint exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2019 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Sen A, Gordon PM. Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(2):249&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2995836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(4):1150&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borde R, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U. Dose-response relationships of resistance training in healthy old adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(12):1693&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4656698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(12):2585&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28755103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5684266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Haun C, Itagaki T, Helms ER. Calculating set-volume for the limb muscles with the performance of multi-joint exercises: implications for resistance training prescription. Sport. 2019;7:177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise: a meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(6):1890&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arruda A, Souza D, Steele J, Fisher J, Giessing J, Gentil P. Reliability of meta-analyses to evaluate resistance training programmes. J Sports Sci. 2016;35(20):1982&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27809704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. The dose&#x2013;response relationship between resistance training volume and muscle hypertrophy: are there really still any doubts? J Sports Sci. 2017;35(20):1985&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27805470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Loftin M, Abe T. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci. 2012;4(4):217&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24265879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3831787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawakami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy: its relation to muscle activation in training session. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(11):2158&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23657165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(11):2691&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23949789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Sugisaki N, Murata K, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y, et al. Association between regional differences in muscle activation in one session of resistance exercise and in muscle hypertrophy after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(4):1569&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21858666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Ema R, Miyamoto N, Kawakami Y. Inter- and intramuscular differences in training-induced hypertrophy of the quadriceps femoris: association with muscle activation during the first training session. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2017;37(4):405&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26576937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ. Selection of resistance exercises for older individuals: the forgotten variable. Sports Med. 2020;50(6):1051&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32008175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy along the length induced by resistance training. In: Kanosue K, Nagami T, Tshuchiya J, editors. Sports performance. Tokyo: Springer Japan; 2015. p. 157&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stronska K, Golas A, Wilk M, Zajac A, Maszczyk A, Stastny P. The effect of targeted resistance training on bench press performance and the alternation of prime mover muscle activation patterns. Sport Biomech. 2020 (ahead of print).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>