<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38900180</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Aerobic Training With Blood Flow Restriction on Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength: Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1341</StartPage><EndPage>1349</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1341-1349</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004800</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>de Lemos Muller, CH, Farinha, JB, Leal-Menezes, R, and Ramis, TR. Aerobic training with blood flow restriction on muscle hypertrophy and strength: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 38(7): 1341-1349, 2024-Integrating strength and endurance training in a single exercise session, even on separate days, can be physically demanding and time-consuming. Therefore, there is a growing interest in identifying efficient training methods that can concurrently enhance cardiovascular and neuromuscular performance through a singular training modality. This study conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis to explore the effects of aerobic training with blood flow restriction (AT + BFR) on muscle hypertrophy and strength gains in healthy individuals. Our study was registered at PROSPERO and used multiple databases (PubMed, Embase, Scopus, and Web of Science), seeking clinical trials that examined AT + BFR influence on muscle hypertrophy and strength gains in individuals aged 18-60 years and comparing with aerobic training without BFR. The risk of bias and method quality were assessed using the ROB2.0 tool and PEDro scale, respectively, and the quality of evidence was evaluated with the GRADE method. A random-effects model was used for meta-analysis, and standardized mean difference (SMD) was calculated for each outcome. Of 4,462 records, 29 full texts were assessed for eligibility, with 7 articles meeting the inclusion criteria. The results indicated that AT + BFR was more beneficial for inducing muscle hypertrophy than aerobic training without BFR (SMD [95% CI] = 0.86 [0.37-1.35]; I2 = 42%). Furthermore, AT + BFR was associated with greater improvements in muscle strength (SMD [95% CI] = 0.41 [0.10-0.72]; I2 = 0%). Despite the generally high risk of bias for both outcomes, these encouraging findings underscore the clinical significance of AT + BFR as a compelling tool for enhancing neuromuscular parameters.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Lemos Muller</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Henrique</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Inflammation, Metabolism and Exercise Research (LAPIMEX) and Laboratory of Cellular Physiology, Department of Physiology, Institute of Basic Health Sciences, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto-Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farinha</LastName><ForeName>Juliano B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Teaching School of the Federal University of Pelotas, Pelotas, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leal-Menezes</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Dance, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto-Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramis</LastName><ForeName>Thiago R</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5252-1209</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center in Natural and Exact Sciences, Graduate Program in Biological Sciences: Toxicological Biochemistry, Federal University of Santa Maria, Santa Maria, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Methods and Techniques, Exercise Biochemistry Laboratory (BIOEX), Federal University of Santa Maria, Santa Maria, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090003" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Flow Restriction Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000084062" MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal Muscle Enlargement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38900180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202407000-00021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Fujita S, Nakajima T, et al. Effects of low-intensity cycle training with restricted leg blood flow on thigh muscle volume and VO 2 max in young men. J Sports Sci Med 9: 452&#x2013;458, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Sato Y. Muscle size and strength are increased following walk training with restricted venous blood flow from the leg muscle, Kaatsu-walk training. J Appl Physiol 100: 1460&#x2013;1466, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artero EG, Lee DC, Lavie CJ, et al. Effects of muscular strength on cardiovascular risk factors and prognosis. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev 32: 351&#x2013;358, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behringer M, Behlau D, Montag JCK, McCourt ML, Mester J. Low-intensity sprint training with blood flow restriction improves 100-m dash. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2462&#x2013;2472, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cawthon PM, Fox KM, Gandra SR, et al. Health, Aging and Body Composition Study. Do muscle mass, muscle density, strength, and physical function similarly influence risk of hospitalization in older adults? J Am Geriatr Soc 57: 1411&#x2013;1419, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Wiegel P, Gollhofer A, Konig D. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 49: 95&#x2013;108, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiansen D, Eibye K, Hostrup M, Bangsbo J. The effect of blood-flow-restricted interval training on lactate and H(+) dynamics during dynamic exercise in man. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 231: e13580, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiansen D, Murphy RM, Bangsbo J, Stathis CG, Bishop DJ. Increased FXYD1 and PGC-1&#x3b1; mRNA after blood flow-restricted running is related to fibre type-specific AMPK signalling and oxidative stress in human muscle. Acta Physiol 223: e13045, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson MJ, Conway L, Warmington SA. Blood flow restriction walking and physical function in older adults: A randomized control trial. J Sci Med Sport 20: 1041&#x2013;1046, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, Junior EMM, Telles GD, et al. Augmented anabolic responses after 8-wk cycling with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 84&#x2013;93, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Landi F, Schneider SM, et al. Prevalence of and interventions for sarcopenia in ageing adults: A systematic review. Report of the international sarcopenia initiative (EWGSOP and IWGS). Age Ageing 43: 748&#x2013;759, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira MF, Caputo F, Corvino RB, Denadai BS. Short-term low-intensity blood flow restricted interval training improves both aerobic fitness and muscle strength. Scand J Med Sci Sports 26: 1017&#x2013;1025, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JP, Altman DG, Group CSM. Chapter 10: Analysing Data and Undertaking Meta&#x2010;Analyses. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. 2019, pp. 241&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira Jr A, de Araujo AC, Chimin P, Okuno NM. Effect of walk training with blood flow restriction on oxygen uptake kinetics, maximum oxygen uptake and muscle strength in middle-aged adults. Med dello Sport 72: 616&#x2013;627, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Cavero-Redondo I, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, et al. Muscular strength as a predictor of all-cause mortality in an apparently healthy population: A systematic review and meta-analysis of data from approximately 2 million men and women. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 99: 2100&#x2013;2113.e5, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, et al. GRADE Working Group. GRADE: An emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ 336: 924&#x2013;926, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, Deeks JJ. Chapter 6: Choosing Effect Measures and Computing Estimates of Effect. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. 2019, pp.143&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Singh H, Loenneke JP, et al. Comparative effects of vigorous-intensity and low-intensity blood flow restricted cycle training and detraining on muscle mass, strength, and aerobic capacity. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1453&#x2013;1461, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 361&#x2013;378, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Abe T, Bemben MG. The anabolic benefits of venous blood flow restriction training may be induced by muscle cell swelling. Med Hypotheses 78: 151&#x2013;154, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Thrower AD, Balapur A, Barnes JT, Pujol TJ. Blood flow-restricted walking does not result in an accumulation of metabolites. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 32: 80&#x2013;82, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson GJ, Wilson JM. A mechanistic approach to blood flow occlusion. Int J Sports Med 31: 1&#x2013;4, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez JA, Page MJ, Lipsey MW, Higgins JPT. Dealing with effect size multiplicity in systematic reviews and meta-analyses. Res Synth Methods 9: 336&#x2013;351, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Kakigi R, Kobayashi H, et al. Effects of walking combined with restricted leg blood flow on mTOR and MAPK signalling in young men. Acta Physiol Oxf Engl 211: 97&#x2013;106, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Sakamaki M, Yasuda T, et al. Increases in thigh muscle volume and strength by walk training with leg blood flow reduction in older participants. J Gerontol Ser A Biol Sci Med Sci 66: 257&#x2013;263, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 372: n71, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, Sterne J. Chapter 13: Assessing Risk of Bias due to Missing Results in a Synthesis. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6. Cochrane, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce JR, Clark BC, Ploutz-Snyder LL, Kanaley JA. Growth hormone and muscle function responses to skeletal muscle ischemia. J Appl Physiol 101: 1588&#x2013;1595, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramis TR, Muller CHD, Boeno FP, et al. Effects of traditional and vascular restricted strength training program with equalized volume on isometric and dynamic strength, muscle thickness, electromyographic activity, and endothelial function adaptations in young adults. J Strength Cond Res 34: 689&#x2013;698, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Mujika I. Optimizing strength training for running and cycling endurance performance: A review. Scand J Med Sci Sports 24: 603&#x2013;612, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shavlakadze T, Grounds M. Of bears, frogs, meat, mice and men: Complexity of factors affecting skeletal muscle mass and fat. Bioessays 28: 994&#x2013;1009, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiwa SR, Costa LOP, Moser ADdL, Aguiar IdC, Oliveira LVFd. PEDro: The physiotherapy evidence database [PEDro: a base de dados de evid&#xea;ncias em fisioterapia]. Fisioterapia Em Movimento 24: 523&#x2013;533, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz J, Stultz J, Burr JF. The efficacy of blood flow restricted exercise: A systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 19: 669&#x2013;675, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: A tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ 355: i4919, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 366: l4898, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, et al. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol (1985) 88: 61&#x2013;65, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zampieri S, Pietrangelo L, Loefler S, et al. Lifelong physical exercise delays age-associated skeletal muscle decline. J Gerontol Ser A Biol Sci Med Sci 70: 163&#x2013;173, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>