<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31281989</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differential muscle hypertrophy and edema responses between high-load and low-load exercise with blood flow restriction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1713</StartPage><EndPage>1726</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1713-1726</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.13516</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We sought to determine whether early increases in cross-sectional area (CSA) of different muscles composing the quadriceps with low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction (LL-BFR) were mainly driven by muscle hypertrophy or by edema-induced swelling. We also compared these changes to those promoted by high-load resistance training (HL-RT). In a randomized within-subject design, fifteen healthy, untrained men were submitted to magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) for CSA and edema-induced muscle swelling assessment (fast spin echo inversion recovery, FSE-STIR). MRI was performed in LL-BFR and HL-RT at baseline (W0) and after 3&#xa0;weeks (W3), with a further measure after 6&#xa0;weeks (W6) for HL-RT. Participants were also assessed at these time points for indirect muscle damage markers (range of motion, ROM; muscle soreness, SOR). CSA significantly increased for all the quadriceps muscles, for both LL-BFR and HL-RT at W3 (all P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.05) compared to W0. However, FSE-STIR was elevated at W3 for all the quadriceps muscles only for HL-RT (all P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.0001), not LL-BFR (all P&#xa0;&gt;&#xa0;.05). Significant increases and decreases were shown in SOR and ROM, respectively, for HL-RT in W3 compared to W0 (both P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.05), while these changes were mitigated at W6 compared to W0 (both P&#xa0;&gt;&#xa0;.05). No significant changes in SOR or ROM were demonstrated for LL-BFR across the study. Early increases in CSA with LL-BFR seem to occur without the presence of muscle edema, whereas initial gains obtained by HL-RT were influenced by muscle edema, in addition to muscle hypertrophy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiromaru</LastName><ForeName>Fabiano Freitas</ForeName><Initials>FF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Salles Painelli</LastName><ForeName>Vitor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5828-9669</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva-Batista</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Arts, Sciences and Humanities, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longo</LastName><ForeName>Ariel Roberth</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lasevicius</LastName><ForeName>Thiago</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4979-5783</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Cuny Lehman College, Bronx, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aihara</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9; Yui</ForeName><Initials>AY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>America's Diagnostics S/A, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tricoli</LastName><ForeName>Valmor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Almeida Peres</LastName><ForeName>Bergson</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Emerson Luiz</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003250" MajorTopicYN="N">Constriction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004487" MajorTopicYN="Y">Edema</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063806" MajorTopicYN="N">Myalgia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood supply</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle swelling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31281989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Deschenes MR, Kraemer WJ. Performance and physiologic adaptations to resistance training. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;81:3-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37:145-168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2009;41:687-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 1988;20:135-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>May DA, Disler DG, Jones EA, Balkissoon AA, Manaster BJ. Abnormal signal intensity in skeletal muscle at MR imaging: patterns, pearls, and pitfalls. Radiographics. 2000;20:295-315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, DeVries HA. Neural factors vs hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med. 1979;58:115-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock MS, Mota JA, DeFranco RN, et al. The time course of short-term hypertrophy in the absence of eccentric muscle damage. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:989-1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krentz JR, Farthing JP. Neural and morphological changes in response to 20-day intense eccentric training protocol. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110:333-340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, de Boer M, Narici MV. Early skeletal muscle hypertrophy and architectural changes in response to high-intensity resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2007;102:368-373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFreitas JM, Beck TW, Stock MS, Dillon MA, Kasishke PR 2nd. An examination of the time course of training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:2785-2790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, et al. Early resistance training-induced increases in muscle cross-sectional area are concomitant with edema-induced muscle swelling. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:49-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Libardi CA, et al. Resistance training-induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. J Physiol. 2016;594:5209-5222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C. The development of skeletal muscle hypertrophy through resistance training: the role of muscle damage and muscle protein synthesis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118:485-500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Abe T, Spitz RW, et al. Impact of acute fluid retention on ultrasound echo intensity. J Clin Densitom. 2019. pii: S1094-6950(19)30045-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocd.2019.02.008 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. Does exercise-induced muscle damage play a role in skeletal muscle hypertrophy? J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:1441-1453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Nosaka K. Responses of elbow flexors to two strenuous eccentric exercise bouts separated by three days. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:108-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HL, Nosaka K, Pearce AJ, Chen TC. Two maximal isometric contractions attenuate the magnitude of eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2012;37:680-689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training vs low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:361-378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Yasuda T, Midorikawa T, et al. Skeletal muscle size and circulating IGF-1 are increased after two weeks of twice daily &#x201c;KAATSU&#x201d; resistance training. Int J Kaatsu Training Res. 2005;1:6-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita T, Brechue WF, Kurita K, Sato Y, Abe T. Increased muscle volume and strength following six days of low-intensity resistance training with restricted muscle blood flow. Int J Kaatsu Training Res. 2008;4:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, et al. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Physiol. 2012;590:4351-4361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Abe T, Sato Y, et al. Muscle fiber cross-sectional area is increased after two weeks of twice daily KAATSU-resistance training. Int J Kaatsu Training Res. 2005;1:65-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umbel JD, Hoffman RL, Dearth DJ, Chleboun GS, Manini TM, Clark BC. Delayed-onset muscle soreness induced by low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:687-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Hisdal J, Raastad T. Contractile function and sarcolemmal permeability after acute low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;112:2051-2063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiebaud RS, Yasuda T, Loenneke J, Abe T. Effects of low-intensity concentric and eccentric exercise combined with blood flow restriction on indices of exercise-induced muscle damage. Interv Med Appl Sci. 2013;5:53-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumming KT, Paulsen G, Wernbom M, Ugelstad I, Raastad T. Acute response and subcellular movement of HSP27, &#x3b1;B-crystallin and HSP70 in human skeletal muscle after blood-flow-restricted low-load resistance exercise. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2014;211:634-646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiebaud RS, Loenneke J, Fahs CA, et al. Muscle damage after low-intensity eccentric contractions with blood flow restriction. Acta Physiol Hung. 2014;101:150-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Lida H, Nakajima T. Effect of low-load resistance exercise with and without blood flow restriction to volitional fatigue on muscle swelling. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115:919-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, de Paoli F, Bjerg K, Riis S, Ringgard S, Vissing K. Blood flow restricted and traditional resistance training performed to fatigue produce equal muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25:754-763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieljacks P, Matzon A, Wernbom M, Ringgard S, Vissing K, Overgaard K. Muscle damage and repeated bout effect following blood flow restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:513-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biazon T, Ugrinowitsch C, Soligon SD, et al. The Association between muscle deoxygenation and muscle hypertrophy to blood flow restricted training performed at high and low loads. Front Physiol. 2019;10:446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:61-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Abe T, Bemben MG. Blood flow restriction does not result in prolonged decrements in torque. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:923-931.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Prokhorova TA, et al. Blood flow restricted training leads to myocellular macrophage infiltration and upregulation of heat shock proteins, but no apparent muscle damage. J Physiol. 2017;595:4857-4873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greco A, McNamara MT, Escher RM, Trifilio G, Parienti J. Spin-echo and STIR MR imaging of sports-related muscle injuries at 1.5 T. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 1991;15:994-999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RC, Constable RT, Reinhold C, McCauley T, Lange RC, McCarthy S. Fast spin echo STIR imaging. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 1994;18:209-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieljacks P, Knudsen L, Wernbom M, Vissing K. Body position influences arterial occlusion pressure: implications for the standardization of pressure during blood flow restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(2):303-312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:406-412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Loenneke JP, Teixeira EL, Nakajima E, Iared W, Tricoli V. The effect of cuff width on muscle adaptations after blood flow restriction training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:920-925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. Accurate assessment of muscular strength and power, ASEP procedures recommendation. JEPonline. 2001;4:1-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerniglia LM, Delmonico MJ, Lindle R, Hurley BF, Rogers MA. Effects of acute supine rest on mid-thigh cross-sectional area as measured by computed tomography. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2007;27:249-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Time course of recovery from resistance exercise before and after a training program. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2019. https://doi.org/10.23736/S0022-4707.19.09334-4 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Chen HL, Lin MJ, Chen CH, Pearce AJ, Nosaka K. Effect of two maximal isometric contractions on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage of the elbow flexors. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:1545-1554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP. Recent advances in the understanding of the repeated bout effect: the protective effect against muscle damage from a single bout of eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2003;13:88-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi H, Kuno S, Miyamoto T, et al. Changes in magnetic resonance images in human skeletal muscle after eccentric exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69:408-413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf8;gaard G, Adams RP, Saltin B. Water and ion shifts in skeletal muscle of humans with intense dynamic knee extension. Am J Physiol. 1985;248:R190-R196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu JG, Liu JX, Carlsson L, Thornell LE, Stal PS. Re-evaluation of sarcolemma injury and muscle swelling in human skeletal muscles after eccentric exercise. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e62056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A, Strazar K. Frequent low-load ischemic resistance exercise to failure enhances muscle oxygen delivery and endurance capacity. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:e231-e241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieljacks P, Degn R, Hollaender K, Wernbom M, Vissing K. Non-failure blood flow restricted exercise induces similar muscle adaptations and less discomfort than failure protocols. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29:336-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Hoppeler H, Kayser B, et al. Human quadriceps cross-sectional area, torque and neural activation during 6&#xa0;months strength training. Acta Physiol Scand. 1996;157:175-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:2691-2703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matta TT, Nascimento FX, Trajano GS, Sim&#xe3;o R, Willardson JM, Oliveira LF. Selective hypertrophy of the quadriceps musculature after 14&#xa0;weeks of isokinetic and conventional resistance training. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2017;37:137-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Ema R, Miyamoto N, Kawakami Y. Inter- and intramuscular differences in training-induced hypertrophy of the quadriceps femoris: association with muscle activation during the first training session. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2017;37:405-412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MA, Polgar J, Weightman D, Appleton D. Data on the distribution of fibre types in thirty-six human muscles. An autopsy study. J Neurol Sci. 1973;18:111-129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Kim D, Fahs CA, et al. The effects of resistance exercise with and without different degrees of blood-flow restriction on perceptual responses. J Sports Sci. 2015;33:1472-1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Murphy BG, Labarbera KE. Neuromuscular function after a bout of low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:67-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Komuro T, Ishiguro N, et al. Effects of low-load resistance training with vascular occlusion on the mechanical properties of muscle and tendon. J Appl Biomech. 2006;22:112-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Determining strength: a case for multiple methods of measurement. Sports Med. 2017;47:193-195.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>