<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34324735</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Higher strength gain after hypoxic vs normoxic resistance training despite no changes in muscle thickness and fractional protein synthetic rate.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e21773</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e21773</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202100654RR</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Acute hypoxia has previously been suggested to potentiate resistance training-induced hypertrophy by activating satellite cell-dependent myogenesis rather than an improvement in protein balance in human. Here, we tested this hypothesis after a 4-week hypoxic vs normoxic resistance training protocol. For that purpose, 19 physically active male subjects were recruited to perform 6 sets of 10 repetitions of a one-leg knee extension exercise at 80% 1-RM 3 times/week for 4&#xa0;weeks in normoxia (FiO<sub>2</sub> : 0.21; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;9) or in hypoxia (FiO<sub>2</sub> : 0.135, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;10). Blood and skeletal muscle samples were taken before and after the training period. Muscle fractional protein synthetic rate was measured over the whole period by deuterium incorporation into the protein pool and muscle thickness by ultrasound. At the end of the training protocol, the strength gain was higher in the hypoxic vs the normoxic group despite no changes in muscle thickness and in the fractional protein synthetic rate. Only early myogenesis, as assessed by higher MyoD and Myf5 mRNA levels, appeared to be enhanced by hypoxia compared to normoxia. No effects were found on myosin heavy chain expression, markers of oxidative metabolism and lactate transport in the skeletal muscle. Though the present study failed to unravel clearly the mechanisms by which hypoxic resistance training is particularly potent to increase muscle strength, it is important message to keep in mind that this training strategy could be effective for all athletes looking at developing and optimizing their maximal muscle strength.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Doorslaer de Ten Ryen</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warnier</LastName><ForeName>Geoffrey</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gnimassou</LastName><ForeName>Olouyomi</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belhaj</LastName><ForeName>Mehdi R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benoit</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naslain</LastName><ForeName>Damien</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brook</LastName><ForeName>Matthew S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC/ARUK Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research and National Institute for Health Research (NIHR), Nottingham Biomedical Research Centre (BRC), School of Medicine, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC/ARUK Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research and National Institute for Health Research (NIHR), Nottingham Biomedical Research Centre (BRC), School of Medicine, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilkinson</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC/ARUK Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research and National Institute for Health Research (NIHR), Nottingham Biomedical Research Centre (BRC), School of Medicine, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nielens</LastName><ForeName>Henri</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cliniques Universitaires Saint-Luc, UCLouvain, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atherton</LastName><ForeName>Philip J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC/ARUK Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research and National Institute for Health Research (NIHR), Nottingham Biomedical Research Centre (BRC), School of Medicine, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Francaux</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8182-1588</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deldicque</LastName><ForeName>Louise</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3393-5278</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, UCLouvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/P021220/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009124">Muscle Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S88TT14065</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010100">Oxygen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005786" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009124" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="Y">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010100" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032496" MajorTopicYN="N">Satellite Cells, Skeletal Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deuterium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein synthesis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34324735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202100654RR</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>D'Hulst G, Jamart C, Van Thienen R, Hespel P, Francaux M, Deldicque L. Effect of acute environmental hypoxia on protein metabolism in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol. 2013;208(3):251-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Francaux M. Acute vs. chronic hypoxia: what are the consequences for skeletal muscle mass? Cell Mol Exerc Physiol. 2013;2(1):e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura A, Sugita M, Kato K, Fukuda A, Sudo A, Uchida A. Hypoxia increases muscle hypertrophy induced by resistance training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(4):497-508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inness MW, Billaut F, Walker EJ, Petersen AC, Sweeting AJ, Aughey RJ. Heavy resistance training in hypoxia enhances 1RM squat performance. Front Physiol. 2016;7:502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feriche B, Garcia-Ramos A, Morales-Artacho AJ, Padial P. Resistance training using different hypoxic training strategies: a basis for hypertrophy and muscle power development. Sports Med Open. 2017;3(1):12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo DJ, Scott BR, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias JA. The efficacy of resistance training in hypoxia to enhance strength and muscle growth: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(1):92-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Dyar KA, Ciciliot S, Blaauw B, Sandri M. Mechanisms regulating skeletal muscle growth and atrophy. FEBS J. 2013;280(17):4294-4314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gnimassou O, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Verdejo R, Brook M, et al. Environmental hypoxia favors myoblast differentiation and fast phenotype but blunts activation of protein synthesis after resistance exercise in human skeletal muscle. FASEB J. 2018;32(10):5272-5284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etheridge T, Atherton PJ, Wilkinson D, et al. Effects of hypoxia on muscle protein synthesis and anabolic signaling at rest and in response to acute resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;301(4):E697-E702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Cameron-Smith D, Phillips SM. What is the relationship between the acute muscle protein synthesis response and changes in muscle mass? J Appl Physiol. 2015;118(4):495-497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ohiwa N, Honda A, et al. Effects of systemic hypoxia on human muscular adaptations to resistance exercise training. Physiol Rep. 2014;2(6).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedmann B, Kinscherf R, Borisch S, Richter G, Bartsch P, Billeter R. Effects of low-resistance/high-repetition strength training in hypoxia on muscle structure and gene expression. Pflugers Arch. 2003;446(6):742-751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britto FA, Gnimassou O, De Groote E, et al. Acute environmental hypoxia potentiates satellite cell-dependent myogenesis in response to resistance exercise through the inflammation pathway in human. FASEB J. 2020;34(1):1885-1900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancinelli R, Pietrangelo T, La Rovere R, et al. Cellular and molecular responses of human skeletal muscle exposed to hypoxic environment. J Biol Regul Homeost Agents. 2011;25(4):635-645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Doorslaer de ten Ryen S, Francaux M, Deldicque L. Regulation of satellite cells by exercise in hypoxic conditions: a narrative review. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:1531-1542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazgir B, Fathi R, Rezazadeh Valojerdi M, Mozdziak P, Asgari A. Satellite cells contribution to exercise mediated muscle hypertrophy and repair. Cell J. 2017;18(4):473-484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang NC, Rudnicki MA. Satellite cells: the architects of skeletal muscle. Curr Top Dev Biol. 2014;107:161-181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller W, Lohman TG, Stewart AD, et al. Subcutaneous fat patterning in athletes: selection of appropriate sites and standardisation of a novel ultrasound measurement technique: ad hoc working group on body composition, health and performance, under the auspices of the IOC Medical Commission. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(1):45-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Tomaru T, Nakajima T. Thigh muscle size and vascular function after blood flow-restricted elastic band training in older women. Oncotarget. 2016;7(23):33595-33607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie F, Millet GP, Girard O. Neuro-mechanical and metabolic adjustments to the repeated anaerobic sprint test in professional football players. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(5):891-903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Pearce E, Smith K, Lach B. Suction-modified Bergstrom muscle biopsy technique: experience with 13,500 procedures. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43(5):717-725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Cegielski J, Phillips BE, et al. Internal comparison between deuterium oxide (D2O) and L-[ring-13C6] phenylalanine for acute measurement of muscle protein synthesis in humans. Physiol Rep. 2015;3(7).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandesompele J, De Preter K, Pattyn F, et al. Accurate normalization of real-time quantitative RT-PCR data by geometric averaging of multiple internal control genes. Genome Biol. 2002;3(7):RESEARCH0034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawilowsky SS. New effect size rules of thumb. J Mod Appl Stat Methods. 2009;8(2):597-599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, McKay BR, Nederveen JP, et al. Satellite cell activity, without expansion, after nonhypertrophic stimuli. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2015;309(9):R1101-R1111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook MS, Wilkinson DJ, Mitchell WK, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy adaptations predominate in the early stages of resistance exercise training, matching deuterium oxide-derived measures of muscle protein synthesis and mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 signaling. FASEB J. 2015;29(11):4485-4496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppo K, Bouckaert J, Jones AM. Oxygen uptake kinetics during high-intensity arm and leg exercise. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2002;133(3):241-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepstone TN, Tang JE, Dallaire S, Schuenke MD, Staron RS, Phillips SM. Short-term high- vs. low-velocity isokinetic lengthening training results in greater hypertrophy of the elbow flexors in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98(5):1768-1776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D, Leveritt M, Lonergan A, Abernethy P. Adaptation to chronic eccentric exercise in humans: the influence of contraction velocity. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;85(5):466-471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Manimmanakorn N, Taylor R, et al. Effects of resistance training combined with vascular occlusion or hypoxia on neuromuscular function in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(7):1767-1774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Simao R, Miranda F, Novaes Jda S, Lemos A, Willardson JM. Rest interval between sets in strength training. Sports Med. 2009;39(9):765-777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurobe K, Huang Z, Nishiwaki M, Yamamoto M, Kanehisa H, Ogita F. Effects of resistance training under hypoxic conditions on muscle hypertrophy and strength. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2015;35(3):197-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho JY, Kuo TY, Liu KL, Dong XY, Tung K. Combining normobaric hypoxia with short-term resistance training has no additive beneficial effect on muscular performance and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(4):935-941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson RS, Newcomer SC, Noyszewski EA. Skeletal muscle intracellular PO(2) assessed by myoglobin desaturation: response to graded exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91(6):2679-2685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen DD, Kim G, Pae EK. Modulation of muscle fiber compositions in response to hypoxia via pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase-1. Front Physiol. 2016;7:604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Loenneke JP, Jo E, Wilson GJ, Zourdos MC, Kim JS. The effects of endurance, strength, and power training on muscle fiber type shifting. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(6):1724-1729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puype J, Van Proeyen K, Raymackers JM, Deldicque L, Hespel P. Sprint interval training in hypoxia stimulates glycolytic enzyme activity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(11):2166-2174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamim B, Hawley JA, Camera DM. Protein availability and satellite cell dynamics in skeletal muscle. Sports Med. 2018;48(6):1329-1343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majmundar AJ, Lee DS, Skuli N, et al. HIF modulation of Wnt signaling regulates skeletal myogenesis in vivo. Development. 2015;142(14):2405-2412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masschelein E, Van Thienen R, D'Hulst G, Hespel P, Thomis M, Deldicque L. Acute environmental hypoxia induces LC3 lipidation in a genotype-dependent manner. FASEB J. 2014;28(2):1022-1034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaillou T, Lanner JT. Regulation of myogenesis and skeletal muscle regeneration: effects of oxygen levels on satellite cell activity. FASEB J. 2016;30(12):3929-3941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagaard P, Kadi F, et al. Creatine supplementation augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J Physiol. 2006;573(Pt 2):525-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, Gillen JB, Bellamy LM, et al. Evidence for the contribution of muscle stem cells to nonhypertrophic skeletal muscle remodeling in humans. FASEB J. 2013;27(11):4596-4605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T. Neuromuscular adaptations during the acquisition of muscle strength, power and motor tasks. J Biomech. 1993;26:95-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Loenneke JP, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Exercise with blood flow restriction: an updated evidence-based approach for enhanced muscular development. Sports Med. 2015;45(3):313-325.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>