<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32049887</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Velocity Loss as a Critical Variable Determining the Adaptations to Strength Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1752</StartPage><EndPage>1762</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1752-1762</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002295</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">This study aimed to compare the effects of four resistance training (RT) programs with different velocity loss (VL) thresholds: 0% (VL0), 10% (VL10), 20% (VL20), and 40% (VL40) on sprint and jump performance, muscle strength, neuromuscular, muscle hypertrophy, and architectural adaptations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Sixty-four young resistance-trained men were randomly assigned into four groups (VL0, VL10, VL20, and VL40) that differed in the VL allowed in each set. Subjects followed an RT program for 8 wk (two sessions per week) using the full-squat (SQ) exercise, with similar relative intensity (70%-85% 1-repetition maximum), number of sets (3), and interset recovery period (4 min). Before and after the RT program, the following tests were performed: 1) muscle hypertrophy and architecture of the vastus lateralis (VLA), 2) tensiomyography, 3) 20-m running sprint, 4) vertical jump, 5) maximal voluntary isometric contraction in SQ, 6) progressive loading test in SQ, and 7) fatigue test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">No between-group differences existed for RT-induced gains in sprint, jump, and strength performance despite the differences in the total volume performed by each group. VL20 and VL40 showed significant increases (P &lt; 0.001) in muscle hypertrophy (group-time interaction, P = 0.06). However, only VL40 exhibited a significant slowing (P &lt; 0.001) of the delay time in the VLA muscle (group-time interaction, P = 0.05). Moreover, VL40 showed a significant decrease in the early rate of force development (P = 0.04).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Higher VL thresholds (i.e., VL20 and VL40) maximized hypertrophic adaptations, although an excessive VL during the set (i.e., VL40) may also induce negative neuromuscular adaptations. Therefore, moderate VL thresholds should be chosen to maximize strength adaptations and to prevent negative neuromuscular adaptations.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pareja-Blanco</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alcazar</LastName><ForeName>Julian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Performance &amp; Sports Research Center, Sports and Computers Sciences, Universidad Pablo de Olavide, Seville, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cornejo-Daza</LastName><ForeName>Pedro J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Performance &amp; Sports Research Center, Sports and Computers Sciences, Universidad Pablo de Olavide, Seville, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piqueras-Sanchiz</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Performance &amp; Sports Research Center, Sports and Computers Sciences, Universidad Pablo de Olavide, Seville, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mora-Vela</LastName><ForeName>Ra&#xfa;l</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Performance &amp; Sports Research Center, Sports and Computers Sciences, Universidad Pablo de Olavide, Seville, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;nchez-Moreno</LastName><ForeName>Miguel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports, University of Seville, Seville, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bachero-Mena</LastName><ForeName>Beatriz</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sports, University of Seville, Seville, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortega-Becerra</LastName><ForeName>Manuel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alegre</LastName><ForeName>Luis M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32049887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202008000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: training considerations. Sports Med. 2018;48(4):765&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose&#x2013;response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(4):674&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Gorostiaga EM, Arellano R, Izquierdo M. Moderate resistance training volume produces more favorable strength gains than high or low volumes during a short-term training cycle. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(3):689&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Izquierdo M, Gorostiaga EM. Moderate volume of high relative training intensity produces greater strength gains compared with low and high volumes in competitive weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(1):73&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busso T. Variable dose&#x2013;response relationship between exercise training and performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(7):1188&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho M, Coswig VS, Steele J, Fisher JP, Paoli A, Gentil P. Evidence for an upper threshold for resistance training volume in trained women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(3):515&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski KJ, Wilson GJ, Weatherby R, Murphy PW, Lyttle AD. The effect of weight training volume on hormonal output and muscular size and function. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(3):148&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(12):2585&#x2013;601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(9):1725&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Aagaard P, et al. Time course of recovery from resistance exercise with different set configurations [published online ahead of print July 20, 2018]. J Strength Cond Res. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran-Navarro R, Perez CE, Mora-Rodriguez R, et al. Time course of recovery following resistance training leading or not to failure. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(12):2387&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richens B, Cleather DJ. The relationship between the number of repetitions performed at given intensities is different in endurance and strength trained athletes. Biol Sport. 2014;31(2):157&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Rosell D, Yanez-Garcia JM, Sanchez-Medina L, Mora-Custodio R, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Relationship between velocity loss and repetitions in reserve in the bench press and back squat exercises [published online ahead of print April 25, 2019]. J Strength Cond Res. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Sanchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(7):724&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Sanchez-Medina L, Suarez-Arrones L, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on performance in professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(4):512&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csapo R, Alegre LM, Baron R. Time kinetics of acute changes in muscle architecture in response to resistance exercise. J Sci Med Sport. 2011;14(3):270&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alegre LM, Ferri-Morales A, Rodriguez-Casares R, Aguado X. Effects of isometric training on the knee extensor moment-angle relationship and vastus lateralis muscle architecture. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(11):2437&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10(5):361&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizaj D, Simunic B, Zagar T. Short-term repeatability of parameters extracted from radial displacement of muscle belly. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2008;18(4):645&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macgregor LJ, Hunter AM, Orizio C, Fairweather MM, Ditroilo M. Assessment of skeletal muscle contractile properties by radial displacement: the case for tensiomyography. Sports Med. 2018;48(7):1607&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Perez CE, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Importance of the propulsive phase in strength assessment. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31(2):123&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Androulakis-Korakakis P, Fisher JP, Steele J. The minimum effective training dose required to increase 1RM strength in resistance-trained men: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(4):751&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness: a review of the acute programme variables. Sports Med. 2005;35(10):841&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Ibanez J, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, et al. Differential effects of strength training leading to failure versus not to failure on hormonal responses, strength, and muscle power gains. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100(5):1647&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2857&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Newton RU, Cormie P, Blazevich AJ. Inhomogeneous quadriceps femoris hypertrophy in response to strength and power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(11):2389&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Redd MJ, Gonzalez AM, et al. Resistance training does not induce uniform adaptations to quadriceps. PLoS One. 2018;13(8):e0198304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2012;113(1):71&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(1):94&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagar T, Krizaj D. Validation of an accelerometer for determination of muscle belly radial displacement. Med Biol Eng Comput. 2005;43(1):78&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubac D, Simunic B. Skeletal muscle contraction time and tone decrease after 8 weeks of plyometric training. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(6):1610&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubac D, Paravlic A, Koren K, Felicita U, Simunic B. Plyometric exercise improves jumping performance and skeletal muscle contractile properties in seniors. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2019;19(1):38&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisot R, Narici MV, Simunic B, et al. Whole muscle contractile parameters and thickness loss during 35-day bed rest. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(2):409&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Gil S, Laurino CF, et al. Differences in muscle mechanical properties between elite power and endurance athletes: a comparative study. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(6):1723&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simunic B, Degens H, Rittweger J, Narici M, Mekjavic IB, Pisot R. Noninvasive estimation of myosin heavy chain composition in human skeletal muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(9):1619&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LL, Andersen JL, Zebis MK, Aagaard P. Early and late rate of force development: differential adaptive responses to resistance training? Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(1):e162&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>