<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33343066</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs non-failure on strength, hypertrophy and muscle architecture in trained individuals.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>333</StartPage><EndPage>341</EndPage><MedlinePgn>333-341</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2020.96317</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this study was to compare the effects of resistance training to muscle failure (RT-F) and non-failure (RT-NF) on muscle mass, strength and activation of trained individuals. We also compared the effects of these protocols on muscle architecture parameters. A within-subjects design was used in which 14 participants had one leg randomly assigned to RT-F and the other to RT-NF. Each leg was trained 2 days per week for 10 weeks. Vastus lateralis (VL) muscle cross-sectional area (CSA), pennation angle (PA), fascicle length (FL) and 1-repetition maximum (1-RM) were assessed at baseline (Pre) and after 20 sessions (Post). The electromyographic signal (EMG) was assessed after the training period. RT-F and RT-NF protocols showed significant and similar increases in CSA (RT-F: 13.5% and RT-NF: 18.1%; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001), PA (RT-F: 13.7% and RT-NF: 14.4%; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001) and FL (RT-F: 11.8% and RT-NF: 8.6%; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001). All protocols showed significant and similar increases in leg press (RT-F: 22.3% and RT-NF: 26.7%; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001) and leg extension (RT-F: 33.3%, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001 and RT-NF: 33.7%; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001) 1-RM loads. No significant differences in EMG amplitude were detected between protocols (<i>P</i> &gt; 0.05). In conclusion, RT-F and RT-NF are similarly effective in promoting increases in muscle mass, PA, FL, strength and activation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2020.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santanielo</LastName><ForeName>Natalia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB - Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>N&#xf3;brega</LastName><ForeName>Sanmy R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB - Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scarpelli</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#xed;ra C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB - Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alvarez</LastName><ForeName>Ieda F</ForeName><Initials>IF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB - Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otoboni</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele B</ForeName><Initials>GB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB - Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pintanel</LastName><ForeName>Lucas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB - Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB - Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fascicle length</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pennation angle</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.96317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">96317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Medicine and science in sports and exercise. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA. Crescent pyramid and drop-set systems do not promote greater strength gains, muscle hypertrophy, and changes on muscle architecture compared with traditional resistance training in well-trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(2):359&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voet NB, van der Kooi EL, Riphagen II, Lindeman E, van Engelen BG, Geurts AC. Strength training and aerobic exercise training for muscle disease. The Cochrane database of systematic reviews. 2013;(7):CD003907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23835682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect Of Resistance Training To Muscle Failure Versus Volitional Interruption At High- And Low-Intensities On Muscle Mass And Strength. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research. 2018;32(1):162&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of Low- vs. High-Load Resistance Training on Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy in Well-Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins ND, Housh TJ, Bergstrom HC, Cochrane KC, Hill EC, Smith CM, Johnson GO, Schmidt RJ, Cramer JT. Muscle activation during three sets to failure at 80 vs. 30% 1RM resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(11):2335&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26159316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM. The application of training to failure in periodized multiple-set resistance exercise programs. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):628&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky VM, Kraemer WJ. Science and Practice of Strength Training. 2nd ed. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cressey EM, West CA, Tiberio DP, Kraemer WJ, Maresh CM. The effects of ten weeks of lower-body unstable surface training on markers of athletic performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):561&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky V. Science and practice of strength training. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 1995. p. 242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Does Training to Failure Maximize Muscle Hypertrophy? Strength and conditioning journal. 2019;41(5):108&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Beardsley C, Contreras B, Steele J, Ogborn D, Phillips SM. Greater electromyographic responses do not imply greater motor unit recruitment and &#x2018;hypertrophic potential&#x2019; cannot be inferred. J Strength Cond Res. 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26670996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Farias Zuniga A, Mohammad IYZ, Jones A, McGlory C, Keir PJ, Potvin JR, Phillips SM. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. The Journal of physiology. 2019;597(17):4601&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, West DWD, Staples AW, Cain NE, Cashaback JGA, Potvin JR, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol. 2010;588(Pt 16):3119&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM. American College of Sports Medicine position stand Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Andersen CH, Zebis MK, Mortensen OS, Andersen LL. Muscle activation strategies during strength training with heavy loading vs. repetitions to failure. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(7):1897&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21986694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, Mouser JG, Counts BR, Dankel SJ, Loenneke JP. Determining Strength: A Case for Multiple Methods of Measurement. Sports Med. 2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of Training Leading to Repetition Failure on Muscular Strength: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(4):487&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26666744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association WM World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: Ethical Principles for Medical Research Involving Human Subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levinger I, Goodman C, Hare DL, Jerums G, Toia D, Selig S. The reliability of the 1RM strength test for untrained middle-aged individuals. J Sci Med Sport. 2009;12(2):310&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18078784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Bottaro M, Chacon-Mikahil MP, Cavaglieri CR, Min LL, Oliveira de Souza E, Laurentino GC, Libardi CA. Vastus lateralis muscle cross sectional area ultrasonography validity for image-fitting in humans. Journal of strength and conditioning research. 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Lixandrao ME, Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Roschel H, Tricoli V, Ugrinowitsch C. Early resistance training-induced increases in muscle cross-sectional area are concomitant with edema-induced muscle swelling. European journal of applied physiology. 2016;116(1):49&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26280652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton MJ, Morgan GT, Sacco P, Chapman DW, Nosaka K. Comparison of responses to strenuous eccentric exercise of the elbow flexors between resistance-trained and untrained men. Journal of strength and conditioning research. 2008;22(2):597&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlon TC, Fragala MS, Stout JR, Emerson NS, Beyer KS, Oliveira LP, Hoffman JR. Muscle architecture and strength: adaptations to short-term resistance training in older adults. Muscle Nerve. 2013;49(4):584&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23893353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2007;103(5):1565&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17717119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. ASEP procedures recommendation I: accurate assessment of muscular strength and power. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2001;4(3):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli MC, N&#xf3;brega SR, Santanielo N, Alvarez IF, Otoboni GB, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA. Muscle Hypertrophy Response Is Affected by Previous Resistance Training Volume in Trained Individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;(27)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32108724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitcher JB, Miles TS. Influence of muscle blood flow on fatigue during intermittent human hand-grip exercise and recovery. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 1997;24(7):471&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9248662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SENIAM P. Recommendations for sensor locations on individual muscles 2005.  [cited 2016 12 Jan]. Available from:  http://seniam.org/sensor_location.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges L, Olkin I. Statistical Methods for Meta-Analysis. New York, NY: Academic Press; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten B, Fu YL, Larumbe-Zabala E, Seijo M, Naclerio F. Impact of Two High-Volume Set Configuration Workouts on Resistance Training Outcomes in Recreationally Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31365457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Sanchis-Moysi J, Dorado C, Mora-Custodio R, Y&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, Morales-Alamo D, P&#xe9;rez-Su&#xe1;rez I, Calbet JAL, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(7):724&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27038416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam A, De Luca CJ. Recruitment order of motor units in human vastus lateralis muscle is maintained during fatiguing contractions. J Neurophysiol. 2003;90(5):2919&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14615422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, McGlory C, Gibala MJ, Phillips SM. Investigating human skeletal muscle physiology with unilateral exercise models: when one limb is more powerful than two. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42(6):563&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28177712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C, An P, Rice T, Skinner JS, Wilmore JH, Gagnon J, P&#xe9;russe L, Leon AS, Rao DC. Familial aggregation of VO(2max) response to exercise training: results from the HERITAGE Family Study. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1999;87(3):1003&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10484570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA, Burke LM, Phillips SM, Spriet LL. Nutritional modulation of training-induced skeletal muscle adaptations. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2011;110(3):834&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21030665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson SL. Sleep in elite athletes and nutritional interventions to enhance sleep. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):S13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Andersen JL, Dyhre-Poulsen P, Leffers AM, Wagner A, Magnusson SP, Halkjaer-Kristensen J, Simonsen EB. A mechanism for increased contractile strength of human pennate muscle in response to strength training: changes in muscle architecture. J Physiol. 2001;534(Pt. 2):613&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11454977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva-Batista C, Barros TS, Aihara AY, Brendon H, Longo AR, Tricoli V, Peres BA, Teixeira EL. Muscle Failure Promotes Greater Muscle Hypertrophy in Low-Load but Not in High-Load Resistance Training. J Strength Cond Res. 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, de Souza EO, Wilson JM, Laurentino GC, Aihara AY, de Souza Le&#xe3;o AR, Ugrinowitsch C. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(11):3085&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, Lindsell RP, Pyne DB, Hunt PH, McKenna MJ. Training leading to repetition failure enhances bench press strength gains in elite junior athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(2):382&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Grant EJ, Correia CE, Phillips SM. Hypertrophy with unilateral resistance exercise occurs without increases in endogenous anabolic hormone concentration. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;98(6):546&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16972050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>