<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31294822</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>597</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4601</StartPage><EndPage>4613</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4601-4613</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP278056</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS">Performing resistance exercise with heavier loads is often proposed to be necessary for the recruitment of larger motor units and activation of type II muscle fibres, leading to type II fibre hypertrophy. Indirect measures [surface electromyography (EMG)] have been used to support this thesis, although we propose that lighter loads lifted to task failure (i.e. volitional fatigue) result in the similar activation of type II fibres. In the present study, participants performed resistance exercise to task failure with heavier and lighter loads with both a normal and longer repetition duration (i.e. time under tension). Type I and type II muscle fibre glycogen depletion was determined by neither load, nor repetition duration during resistance exercise performed to task failure. Surface EMG amplitude was not related to muscle fibre glycogen depletion or anabolic signalling; however, muscle fibre glycogen depletion and anabolic signalling were related. Performing resistance exercise to task failure, regardless of load lifted or repetition duration, necessitates the activation of type II muscle fibres.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT">Heavier loads (&gt;60% of maximal strength) are considered to be necessary during resistance exercise (RE) to activate and stimulate hypertrophy of type II fibres. Support for this proposition comes from observation of higher surface electromyography (EMG) amplitudes during RE when lifting heavier vs. lighter loads. We aimed to determine the effect of RE, to task failure, with heavier vs. lighter loads and shorter or longer repetition durations on: EMG-derived variables, muscle fibre activation, and anabolic signalling. Ten recreationally-trained young men performed four unilateral RE conditions randomly on two occasions (two conditions, one per leg per visit). Muscle biopsies were taken from the vastus lateralis before and one hour after RE. Broadly, total time under load, number of repetitions, exercise volume, EMG amplitude (at the beginning and end of each set) and total EMG activity were significantly different between conditions (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05); however, neither glycogen depletion (in both type I and type II fibres), nor phosphorylation of relevant signalling proteins showed any difference between conditions. We conclude that muscle fibre activation and subsequent anabolic signalling are independent of load, repetition duration and surface EMG amplitude when RE is performed to task failure. The results of the present study provide evidence indicating that type I and type II fibres are activated when heavier and lighter loads are lifted to task failure. We propose that our results explain why RE training with higher or lower loads, when loads are lifted to task failure, leads to equivalent muscle hypertrophy and occurs in both type I and type II fibres.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology &#xa9; 2019 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morton</LastName><ForeName>Robert W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0099-4167</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sonne</LastName><ForeName>Michael W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8627-1295</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farias Zuniga</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammad</LastName><ForeName>Ibrahim Y Z</ForeName><Initials>IYZ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9783-4225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGlory</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4853-4960</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keir</LastName><ForeName>Peter J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9811-1547</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Potvin</LastName><ForeName>Jim R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Stuart M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1956-4098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Physiol. 2019 Sep;597(18):4691-4692. doi: 10.1113/JP278627.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">31389011</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018656" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fibers, Fast-Twitch</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018657" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fibers, Slow-Twitch</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">load</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein signalling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface EMG</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP278056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Bell DG &amp; Jacobs I (1989). Muscle fiber-specific glycogen utilization in strength-trained males and females. Med Sci Sports Exerc 21, 649-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloemberg D &amp; Quadrilatero J (2012). Rapid determination of myosin heavy chain expression in rat, mouse, and human skeletal muscle using multicolor immunofluorescence analysis. PLoS ONE 7, e35273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, West DW, Staples AW, Cain NE, Cashaback JG, Potvin JR, Baker SK &amp; Phillips SM (2010). Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol 588, 3119-3130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE &amp; Tsairis P (1974). Trophic functions of the neuron. II. Denervation and regulation of muscle. The correlation of physiological properties with histochemical characteristics in single muscle units. Ann NY Acad Sci 228, 145-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera DM, West DW, Burd NA, Phillips SM, Garnham AP, Hawley JA &amp; Coffey VG (2012). Low muscle glycogen concentration does not suppress the anabolic response to resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 113, 206-214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Herbert RD, Munn J, Lee M &amp; Gandevia SC (2006). Contralateral effects of unilateral strength training: evidence and possible mechanisms. J Appl Physiol (1985) 101, 1514-1522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumming KT, Paulsen G, Wernbom M, Ugelstad I &amp; Raastad T (2014). Acute response and subcellular movement of HSP27, alphaB-crystallin and HSP70 in human skeletal muscle after blood-flow-restricted low-load resistance exercise. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 211, 634-646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dideriksen JL, Enoka RM &amp; Farina D (2011). Neuromuscular adjustments that constrain submaximal EMG amplitude at task failure of sustained isometric contractions. J Appl Physiol (1985) 111, 485-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dideriksen JL, Farina D &amp; Enoka RM (2010). Influence of fatigue on the simulated relation between the amplitude of the surface electromyogram and muscle force. Philos Trans A Math Phys Eng Sci 368, 2765-2781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM &amp; Duchateau J (2015). Inappropriate interpretation of surface EMG signals and muscle fiber characteristics impedes understanding of the control of neuromuscular function. J Appl Physiol (1985) 119, 1516-1518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairchild TJ &amp; Fournier PA (2004). Glycogen determination using periodic acid-Schiff: artifact of muscle preparation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36, 2053-2058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R &amp; Enoka RM (2004). The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG. J Appl Physiol (1985) 96, 1486-1495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Armstrong RB, Sembrowich WL, Shepherd RE &amp; Saltin B (1973). Glycogen depletion pattern in human skeletal muscle fibers after heavy exercise. J Appl Physiol 34, 615-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Karlsson J, Piehl K &amp; Saltin B (1974a). Selective glycogen depletion in skeletal muscle fibres of man following sustained contractions. J Physiol 241, 59-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Piehl K &amp; Saltin B (1974b). Selective glycogen depletion pattern in human muscle fibres after exercise of varying intensity and at varying pedalling rates. J Physiol 241, 45-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J &amp; Schoenfeld BJ (2018). Are the hypertrophic adaptations to high and low-load resistance training muscle fiber type specific? Front Physiol 9, 402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Mumford PW, Roberson PA, Romero MA, Mobley CB, Kephart WC, Anderson RG, Colquhoun RJ, Muddle TWD, Luera MJ, Mackey CS, Pascoe DD, Young KC, Martin JS, DeFreitas JM, Jenkins NDM &amp; Roberts MD (2017). Molecular, neuromuscular, and recovery responses to light versus heavy resistance exercise in young men. Physiol Rep 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holwerda AM, Paulussen KJM, Overkamp M, Smeets JSJ, Gijsen AP, Goessens JPB, Verdijk LB &amp; van Loon LJC (2018). Daily resistance-type exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis in vivo in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 124, 66-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakubowski JS, Wong EPT, Nunes EA, Noguchi KS, Vandeweerd JK, Murphy KT, Morton RW, McGlory C &amp; Phillips SM (2019). Equivalent hypertrophy and strength gains in beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate- or leucine-supplemented men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51, 65-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins ND, Housh TJ, Bergstrom HC, Cochrane KC, Hill EC, Smith CM, Johnson GO, Schmidt RJ &amp; Cramer JT (2015). Muscle activation during three sets to failure at 80&#xa0;vs. 30% 1RM resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 115, 2335-2347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight CA &amp; Kamen G (2005). Superficial motor units are larger than deeper motor units in human vastus lateralis muscle. Muscle Nerve 31, 475-480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Manders RJ, Jonkers RA, Hul GB, Kuipers H &amp; van Loon LJ (2006). Intramyocellular lipid and glycogen content are reduced following resistance exercise in untrained healthy males. Eur J Appl Physiol 96, 525-534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen DE, Albers PH, Prats C, Baba O, Birk JB &amp; Wojtaszewski JF (2015). Human muscle fibre type-specific regulation of AMPK and downstream targets by exercise. J Physiol 593, 2053-2069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Looney DP, Kraemer WJ, Joseph MF, Cornstock BA, Denegar CR, Flanagan SD, Newton RU, Szivak TK, DuPont WH, Hooper DR, Hakkinen K &amp; Maresh CM (2016). Electromyographical and perceptual responses to different resistance intensities in a squat protocol: does performing sets to failure with light loads produce the same activity? J Strength Cond Res 30, 792-799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, Zacharewicz E, Martin BJ, Haikalis ME, Skelly LE, Tarnopolsky MA, Murphy RM &amp; Gibala MJ (2017). Superior mitochondrial adaptations in human skeletal muscle after interval compared to continuous single-leg cycling matched for total work. J Physiol 595, 2955-2968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathiassen SE, Winkel J &amp; Hagg GM (1995). Normalization of surface EMG amplitude from the upper trapezius muscle in ergonomic studies&#xa0;-&#xa0;a review. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 5, 197-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeod JC, Stokes T &amp; Phillips SM (2019). Resistance exercise training as a primary countermeasure to age-related chronic disease. Front Physiol 10, 645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus JF (1948). Histological and histochemical uses of periodic acid. Stain Technol 23, 99-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendell LM (2005). The size principle: a rule describing the recruitment of motoneurons. J Neurophysiol 93, 3024-3026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Bellamy L, Parise G, Baker SK &amp; Phillips SM (2013). Muscular and systemic correlates of resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. PLoS ONE 8, e78636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK &amp; Phillips SM (2012). Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 113, 71-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, McGlory C &amp; Phillips SM (2015). Nutritional interventions to augment resistance training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Front Physiol 6, 245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, Mazara N, McGlory C, Quadrilatero J, Baechler BL, Baker SK &amp; Phillips SM (2016). Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 121, 129-138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muceli S, Poppendieck W, Negro F, Yoshida K, Hoffmann KP, Butler JE, Gandevia SC &amp; Farina D (2015). Accurate and representative decoding of the neural drive to muscles in humans with multi-channel intramuscular thin-film electrodes. J Physiol 593, 3789-3804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muddle TWD, Colquhoun RJ, Magrini MA, Luera MJ, DeFreitas JM &amp; Jenkins NDM (2018). Effects of fatiguing, submaximal high- versus low-torque isometric exercise on motor unit recruitment and firing behavior. Physiol Rep 6, e13675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn J, Herbert RD &amp; Gandevia SC (2004). Contralateral effects of unilateral resistance training: a meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol (1985) 96, 1861-1866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy RM &amp; Lamb GD (2013). Important considerations for protein analyses using antibody based techniques: down-sizing Western blotting up-sizes outcomes. J Physiol 591, 5823-5831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potvin JR &amp; Fuglevand AJ (2017). A motor unit-based model of muscle fatigue. PLoS Comput Biol 13, e1005581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prats C, Gomez-Cabello A, Nordby P, Andersen JL, Helge JW, Dela F, Baba O &amp; Ploug T (2013). An optimized histochemical method to assess skeletal muscle glycogen and lipid stores reveals two metabolically distinct populations of type I muscle fibers. PLoS ONE 8, e77774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ &amp; Triplett NT (2009). American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41, 687-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robergs RA, Pearson DR, Costill DL, Fink WJ, Pascoe DD, Benedict MA, Lambert CP &amp; Zachweija JJ (1991). Muscle glycogenolysis during differing intensities of weight-resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 70, 1700-1706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaart G, Hesselink RP, Keizer HA, van Kranenburg G, Drost MR &amp; Hesselink MK (2004). A modified PAS stain combined with immunofluorescence for quantitative analyses of glycogen in muscle sections. Histochem Cell Biol 122, 161-169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D &amp; Krieger JW (2017). Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31, 3508-3523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Beardsley C, Contreras B, Steele J, Ogborn D &amp; Phillips SM (2017). Greater electromyographic responses do not imply greater motor unit recruitment and &#x2018;hypertrophic potential&#x2019; cannot be inferred. J Strength Cond Res 31, e1-e4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Ogborn D &amp; Phillips SM (2016). Motor unit recruitment cannot be inferred from surface EMG amplitude and basic reporting standards must be adhered to. Eur J Appl Physiol 116, 657-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollestad NK &amp; Blom PC (1985). Effect of varying exercise intensity on glycogen depletion in human muscle fibres. Acta Physiol Scand 125, 395-405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollestad NK, Blom PC &amp; Gronnerod O (1989). Resynthesis of glycogen in different muscle fibre types after prolonged exhaustive exercise in man. Acta Physiol Scand 137, 15-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollestad NK, Vaage O &amp; Hermansen L (1984). Muscle glycogen depletion patterns in type I and subgroups of type II fibres during prolonged severe exercise in man. Acta Physiol Scand 122, 433-441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Franchi MV, Brook MS, Narici MV, Williams JP, Mitchell WK, Szewczyk NJ, Greenhaff PL, Atherton PJ &amp; Smith K (2014). A validation of the application of D(2)O stable isotope tracer techniques for monitoring day-to-day changes in muscle protein subfraction synthesis in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 306, E571-E579.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>