<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31803531</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2159-2896</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of sports physical therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Sports Phys Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>FLYWHEEL TRAINING IN MUSCULOSKELETAL REHABILITATION: A CLINICAL COMMENTARY.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>994</StartPage><EndPage>1000</EndPage><MedlinePgn>994-1000</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Flywheel training is a relatively new method used to train the human body with continuous resistance and eccentric overload. The performed exercises result in improvements of strength and power, hypertrophy, muscle activation, muscle length, and tendon stiffness. Other positive effects of flywheel training are athletically relevant improvements in things such as speed, jump height and change of direction. The positive results can be explained by the eccentric and power characteristics of the training, making flywheel training ideal for use in musculoskeletal rehabilitation. Flywheel training can be used for injury prevention, training after a period of unloading, tendon and muscle rehabilitation, as part of post-operative rehabilitation, during late stage sport specific rehabilitation as well as for fall prevention and treatment of sarcopenia among elderly. The purpose of this commentary is to inform physical therapists about the use of flywheel training in musculoskeletal rehabilitation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">5.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 by the Sports Physical Therapy Section.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wonders</LastName><ForeName>Jaap</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SMC Rijnland Fysiotherapeuten, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Sports Phys Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101553140</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2159-2896</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eccentric overload</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flywheel training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">movement system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tendinosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: The author reports no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31803531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Krog August A. Bicycle ergometer and respiration apparatus for the experimental study of muscular work. Acta Physiologica. 1913;30(3):375-394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen TE Lindhard J. On the maximum work of human muscles especially the flexors of the elbow. J Physiol. 1923;57(5):287&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1405436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16993572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg HE Tesch A. A gravity-independent ergometer to be used for resistance training in space. Aviat Space Environ Med. 1994;65(8):752-756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7980338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch Per A Fernandez-Gonzalo R Lundberg TR. Clinical Applications of Iso-Inertial, Eccentric-Overload (YoYoTM) Resistance Exercise. Front in Physiol. 2017;8:241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5406462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L Pozzo M Tesch PA. Flywheel resistance training calls for greater eccentric muscle activation than weight training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(5):997-1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20676897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roig M O&#x2019;Brien K Kirk G, et al. The effects of eccentric versus concentric resistance training on muscle strength and mass in healthy adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(8):556-568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18981046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez D Fernandez-Gonzalo R, et al. Skeletal muscle functional and structural adaptations after eccentric overload flywheel resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20(10):943-951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28385560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gual G Fort-Vanmeerhaeghe A Romero-Rodr&#xed;guez D. Effects of In-Season Inertial Resistance Training With Eccentric Overload in a Sports Population at Risk for Patellar Tendinopathy. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(7):1834-1842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26670989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J Pearson S Ross A. Chronic Adaptations to Eccentric Training: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2017;47(5):917-941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27647157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hessel AL Lindstedt SL Nishikawa KC. Physiological Mechanisms of Eccentric Contraction and Its Applications: A Role for the Giant Titin Protein. Front in Physiol. 2017;8(70): 1-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5299520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28232805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahonony DJ Safdar A Parise G, et al. Gene expression profiling in human skeletal muscle during recovery from eccentric exercise. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2008;294(6):1901-1910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18321953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyo de M Pozzo M Sa&#xf1;udo B, et al. Effects of a 10-week in-season eccentric-overload training program on muscle-injury prevention and performance in junior elite soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(1):46-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askling C Karlsson J Thorstensson A. Hamstring injury occurrence in elite soccer players after preseason strength training with eccentric overload. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2003;13(4):244-250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12859607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monjati A Larumbe E Goss-Sampson M, et al. Injury prevention programs based on flywheel vs. body weight resistance in recreational athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;00(00):1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neil S Watson PJ Barry S. Why are eccentric exercises effective for achilles tendinopathy? Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2015;10(4):552-562</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4527202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26347394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaconas EJ Kolber MJ Hanney WJ, et al. Shoulder external rotator eccentric training versus general shoulder exercise for subacromial pain syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2017;12(7):1121-1133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29234564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler TF Nicholas SJ Schmitt BM. Clinical outcomes of the addition of eccentrics for rehabilitation of previously failed treatments of golfers elbow. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2014;9(3):365-370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4060314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24944855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer R Kongsgaard M Hougs Kj&#xe6;r B, et al. Heavy Slow Resistance Versus Eccentric Training as Treatment for Achilles Tendinopathy: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(7):1704-1711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26018970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malliaras P Barton CJ Reeves ND, et al. Achilles and patellar tendinopathy loading programmes: a systematic review comparing clinical outcomes and identifying potential mechanisms for effectiveness. Sports Med. 2013;43(4):267-286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23494258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanz-L&#xf3;pez F Berzosa C Hita-Contreras F, et al. Effects of eccentric overload training on patellar tendon and vastus lateralis in three days of consecutive running. Knee. 2017;24(3):570-579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanz-L&#xf3;pez F Berzosa S&#xe1;nchez C Hita-Contreras F. Ultrasound Changes in Achilles Tendon and Gastrocnemius Medialis Muscle on Squat Eccentric Overload and Running Performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(7):2010-2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26677829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayer ML Magnusson SP Kj&#xe6;r M. Early versus Delayed Rehabilitation after Acute Muscle Injury. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;377(13):1300-1301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28953439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoegberget-Kalisz M Jensen MH, et al. Role of tissue perfusion, muscle strength recovery and pain in rehabilitation after acute muscle strain injury: A randomized controlled trial comparing early and delayed rehabilitation. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018; Published Online First.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A Bisschop M Benjaminse A, et al. Quadriceps function following ACL reconstruction and rehabilitation: implications for optimisation of current practices. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;(22)5:1163-1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23812438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz D Reiman M. The role and implementation of eccentric training in athletic rehabilitation: tendinopathy, hamstring strains and acl reconstruction. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2011;6(1):27-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3105370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21655455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz D Morrison S. Current concepts in periodization of strength and conditioning for the sports physical therapist. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2015;10(6):734-747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4637911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26618056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>