<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38197297</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nuclear-localized androgen receptor content following resistance exercise training is associated with hypertrophy in males but not females.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e23403</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e23403</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202301291RR</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Androgen receptor (AR) content has been implicated in the differential response between high and low responders following resistance exercise training (RET). However, the influence of AR expression on acute skeletal muscle damage and whether it may influence the adaptive response to RET in females is poorly understood. Thus, the purpose of this exploratory examination was to 1) investigate changes in AR content during skeletal muscle repair and 2) characterize AR-mediated sex-based differences following RET. A skeletal muscle biopsy from the vastus lateralis was obtained from 26 healthy young men (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;13) and women (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;13) at baseline and following 300 eccentric kicks. Subsequently, participants performed 10&#x2009;weeks of full-body RET and a final muscle biopsy was collected. In the untrained state, AR mRNA expression was associated with paired box protein-7 (PAX7) mRNA in males. For the first time in human skeletal muscle, we quantified AR content in the myofiber and localized to the nucleus where AR has been shown to trigger cellular outcomes related to growth. Upon eccentric damage, nuclear-associated AR (nAR) content increased (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05) in males and not females. Males with the greatest increase in cross-sectional area (CSA) post-RET had more (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05) nAR content than females with the greatest gain CSA. Collectively, skeletal muscle damage and RET increased AR protein, and both gene and hypertrophy measures revealed sex differences in relation to AR. These findings suggest that AR content but more importantly, nuclear localization, is a factor that differentiates RET-induced hypertrophy between males and females.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hatt</LastName><ForeName>Aidan A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Faculty of Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamal</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3055-6793</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Faculty of Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mikhail</LastName><ForeName>Andrew I</ForeName><Initials>AI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8977-2055</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Faculty of Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fortino</LastName><ForeName>Stephen A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Faculty of Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wageh</LastName><ForeName>Mai</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9619-2454</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Faculty of Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumbhare</LastName><ForeName>Dinesh</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3889-7557</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Toronto Rehabilitation Institute, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parise</LastName><ForeName>Gianni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0272-1528</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Faculty of Science, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011944">Receptors, Androgen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000728">Androgens</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011944" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptors, Androgen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000728" MajorTopicYN="N">Androgens</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">androgen receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eccentric damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">responder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">satellite cell</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sex-based differences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle hypertrophy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38197297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202301291RR</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Ochala J. Skeletal muscle: a brief review of structure and function. Behav Genet. 2015;45(2):183-195. doi:10.1007/s00223-014-9915-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3&#x2009;days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101(2):531-544. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilwik R, Snijders T, Leenders M, et&#xa0;al. The decline in skeletal muscle mass with aging is mainly attributed to a reduction in type II muscle fiber size. Exp Gerontol. 2013;48(5):492-498. doi:10.1016/j.exger.2013.02.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello LS, Kostek MA, Gordish-Dressman H, et&#xa0;al. ACE ID genotype and the muscle strength and size response to unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(6):1074-1081. doi:10.1249/01.mss.0000222835.28273.80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Devaney JM, Gordish-Dressman H, et&#xa0;al. ACTN3 genotype is associated with increases in muscle strength in response to resistance training in women. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99(1):154-163. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.01139.2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. A brief review of critical processes in exercise-induced muscular hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2014;44:71-77. doi:10.1007/s40279-014-0152-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Brattain MG. The maximal size of protein to diffuse through the nuclear pore is larger than 60 kDa. FEBS Lett. 2007;581(17):3164-3170. doi:10.1016/j.febslet.2007.05.082</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saporita AJ, Zhang Q, Navai N, et&#xa0;al. Identification and characterization of a ligand-regulated nuclear export signal in androgen receptor. J Biol Chem. 2003;278(43):41998-42005. doi:10.1074/jbc.M302460200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyagi RK, Lavrovsky Y, Ahn SC, Song CS, Chatterjee B, Roy AK. Dynamics of intracellular movement and nucleocytoplasmic recycling of the ligand-activated androgen receptor in living cells. Mol Endocrinol. 2000;14(8):1162-1174. doi:10.1210/mend.14.8.0497</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, Nindl BC. Recovery responses of testosterone, growth hormone, and IGF-1 after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2017;122(3):549-558. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00599.2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine H, Jay R, Gonzalez AM, Townsend JR, et&#xa0;al. Exercise-induced hormone elevations are related to muscle growth. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(1):45-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DWD, Phillips SM. Associations of exercise-induced hormone profiles and gains in strength and hypertrophy in a large cohort after weight training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(7):2693-2702. doi:10.1007/s00421-011-2246-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sato K, Gallaugher MPB, et&#xa0;al. Muscle androgen receptor content but not systemic hormones is associated with resistance training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy in healthy, young men. Front Physiol. 2018;9(October):1-11. doi:10.3389/fphys.2018.01373</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakakibara I, Yanagihara Y, Himori K, et&#xa0;al. Myofiber androgen receptor increases muscle strength mediated by a skeletal muscle splicing variant of Mylk4. iScience. 2021;24(4):102303. doi:10.1016/j.isci.2021.102303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L, Lu L, Lin X, Wang X. Crucial role of androgen receptor in resistance and endurance trainings-induced muscle hypertrophy through IGF-1/IGF-1R-PI3K/Akt-mTOR pathway. Nutr Metab. 2020;17(1):1-10. doi:10.1186/s12986-020-00446-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nederveen JP, Joanisse S, Snijders T, Thomas ACQ, Kumbhare D, Parise G. The influence of capillarization on satellite cell pool expansion and activation following exercise-induced muscle damage in healthy young men. J Physiol. 2018;596(6):1063-1078. doi:10.1113/JP275155</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Nederveen JP, Mckay BR, et&#xa0;al. Satellite cells in human skeletal muscle plasticity. Front Physiol. 2015;6(October):1-21. doi:10.3389/fphys.2015.00283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C, et&#xa0;al. Early- and later-phases satellite cell responses and myonuclear content with resistance training in young men. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(1):1-12. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0191039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Shipp JR, Jiang J, et&#xa0;al. Mechanical load increases muscle IGF-I and androgen receptor mRNA concentrations in humans. Am J Physiol - Endocrinol Metab. 2001;280(3):E383-E390. doi:10.1152/ajpendo.2001.280.3.e383</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Han GC, Seo JY, et&#xa0;al. Sex hormones establish a reserve pool of adult muscle stem cells. Nat Cell Biol. 2016;18(9):930-940. doi:10.1038/ncb3401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackrell JG, Yaden BC, Bullock H, et&#xa0;al. Molecular targets of androgen signaling that characterize skeletal muscle recovery and regeneration. Nucl Receptor Signal. 2015;13:1-19. doi:10.1621/nrs.13005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney DJ, Safdar A, Parise G, et&#xa0;al. Gene expression profiling in human skeletal muscle during recovery from eccentric exercise. Am J Physiol - Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2008;294(6):R1901-R1910. doi:10.1152/ajpregu.00847.2007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortino SA, Wageh M, Pontello R, et&#xa0;al. Sex-based differences in the myogenic response and inflammatory gene expression following eccentric contractions in humans. Front Physiol. 2022;13(April):1-10. doi:10.3389/fphys.2022.880625</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Bellamy L, Parise G, Baker SK. Muscular and systemic correlates of resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(10):78636. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0078636</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Hulmi JJ, Kraemer WJ, et&#xa0;al. Heavy resistance exercise training and skeletal muscle androgen receptor expression in younger and older men. Steroids. 2011;76:183-192. doi:10.1016/j.steroids.2010.10.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLean HE, Chiu WSM, Notini AJ, et&#xa0;al. Impaired skeletal muscle development and function in male, but not female, genomic androgen receptor knockout mice. FASEB J. 2008;22(8):2676-2689. doi:10.1096/fj.08-105726</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DWD, Burd NA, Tang JE, et&#xa0;al. Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:60-67. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.01147.2009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englund DA, Peck BD, Murach KA, et&#xa0;al. Resident muscle stem cells are not required for testosterone-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Am J Physiol - Cell Physiol. 2019;317(4):C719-C724. doi:10.1152/ajpcell.00260.2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha-Hikim I, Roth SM, Lee MI, Bhasin S. Testosterone-induced muscle hypertrophy is associated with an increase in satellite cell number in healthy, young men. Am J Physiol - Endocrinol Metab. 2003;285(1):E197-E205. doi:10.1152/ajpendo.00370.2002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wageh M, Fortino SA, McGlory C, Kumbhare D, Phillips SM, Parise G. The effect of a multi-ingredient supplement on resistance training-induced adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(8):1699-1707. doi:10.1249/mss.0000000000002641</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaton LJ, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Variability in estimating eccentric contraction-induced muscle damage and inflammation in humans. Rapid Commun. 2002;27(5):516-526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proske U, Morgan DL. Muscle damage from eccentric exercise: mechanism, mechanical signs, adaptation and clinical applications. J Physiol. 2001;537(2):333-345. doi:10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00333.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lisio M, Farup J, Sukiennik RA, et&#xa0;al. The acute response of pericytes to muscle-damaging eccentric contraction and protein supplementation in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2015;119(8):900-907. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.01112.2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, O'Reilly CE, Phillips SM, Tarnopolsky MA, Parise G. Co-expression of IGF-1 family members with myogenic regulatory factors following acute damaging muscle-lengthening contractions in humans. J Physiol. 2008;586(22):5549-5560. doi:10.1113/jphysiol.2008.160176</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarnopolsky MA, Pearce E, Smith K, Lach B. Suction-modified Bergstr&#xf6;m muscle biopsy technique: experience with 13,500 procedures. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43(5):716-725. doi:10.1002/mus.21945</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livak KJ, Schmittgen TD. Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2-&#x394;&#x394;CT method. Methods. 2001;25(4):402-408. doi:10.1006/meth.2001.1262</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nederveen JP, Joanisse S, Thomas ACQ, et&#xa0;al. Age-related changes to the satellite cell niche are associated with reduced activation following exercise. FASEB J. 2020;34(7):8975-8989. doi:10.1096/fj.201900787R</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering BA, Kraemer WJ, Vingren JL, et&#xa0;al. Elevated endogenous testosterone concentrations potentiate muscle androgen receptor responses to resistance exercise. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2009;114(3-5):195-199. doi:10.1016/j.jsbmb.2009.02.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Taylor L. Effects of sequential bouts of resistance exercise on androgen receptor expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(9):1499-1506. doi:10.1249/01.MSS.0000139795.83030.D1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davey RA, Grossmann M. Androgen receptor structure, function and biology: from bench to bedside. Clin Biochem Rev. 2016;37(1):3-15. pmid: 27057074; PMCID: PMC4810760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altuwaijri S, Lee DK, Chuang K, et&#xa0;al. Androgen receptor regulates expression of skeletal muscle-specific proteins and muscle cell types. Endocrine. 2004;25(1):27-32. 10.1385/ENDO:25:1:27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Ahtiainen JP, Sel&#xe4;nne H, et&#xa0;al. Androgen receptors and testosterone in men-effects of protein ingestion, resistance exercise and fiber type. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2008;110(1-2):130-137. doi:10.1016/j.jsbmb.2008.03.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentzinger CF, Wang YX, Rudnicki MA. Building muscle: molecular regulation of myogenesis. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2012;4(2):1-16. doi:10.1101/cshperspect.a008342</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha-Hikim I, Cornford M, Gaytan H, Lee ML, Bhasin S. Effects of testosterone supplementation on skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy and satellite cells in community-dwelling older men. J Clini Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91(8):3024-3033. doi:10.1210/jc.2006-0357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha-hikim I, Taylor WE, Gonzalez-cadavid NF, Zheng WEI, Bhasin S. Androgen receptor in human skeletal muscle and cultured muscle satellite cells: up-regulation by androgen treatment. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89(10):5245-5255. doi:10.1210/jc.2004-0084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joubert Y, Tobin C. Testosterone treatment results in quiescent satellite cells being activated and recruited into cell cycle in rat levator ani muscle. Dev Biol. 1995;169(1):286-294. doi:10.1006/dbio.1995.1144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikezoe T, Yang Y, Saito T, Koeffler HP, Taguchi H. Proteasome inhibitor PS-341 down-regulates prostate-specific antigen (PSA) and induces growth arrest and apoptosis of androgen-dependent human prostate cancer LNCaP cells. Cancer Sci. 2004;95(3):271-275. doi:10.1111/j.1349-7006.2004.tb02215.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DK, Chang C. Endocrine mechanisms of disease: expression and degradation of androgen receptor: mechanism and clinical implication. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003;88(9):4043-4054. doi:10.1210/jc.2003-030261</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, et&#xa0;al. Androgen receptor content following heavy resistance exercise in men. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2005;93:35-42. doi:10.1016/j.jsbmb.2004.10.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DWD, Burd NA, Churchward-Venne TA, et&#xa0;al. Sex-based comparisons of myofibrillar protein synthesis after resistance exercise in the fed state. J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(11):1805-1813. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00170.2012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingren JL, Kraemer WJ, Hatfield DL, et&#xa0;al. Effect of resistance exercise on muscle steroid receptor protein content in strength-trained men and women. Steroids. 2009;74(13-14):1033-1039. doi:10.1016/j.steroids.2009.08.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto-Mikami E, Tsuji K, Horii N, et&#xa0;al. Gene expression profile of muscle adaptation to high-intensity intermittent exercise training in young men. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):1-14. doi:10.1038/s41598-018-35115-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumasian RA, Harish A, Kundu G, et&#xa0;al. Skeletal muscle transcriptome in healthy aging. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):2014. doi:10.1038/s41467-021-22168-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicoll JX, Fry AC, Mosier EM, Olsen LA, Sontag SA. MAPK, androgen, and glucocorticoid receptor phosphorylation following high-frequency resistance exercise non-functional overreaching. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(10):2237-2253. doi:10.1007/s00421-019-04200-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velders M, Schleipen B, Fritzemeier KH, Zierau O, Diel P. Selective estrogen receptor-&#x3b2; activation stimulates skeletal muscle growth and regeneration. FASEB J. 2012;26(5):1909-1920. doi:10.1096/fj.11-194779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltais ML, Desroches J, Dionne IJ. Changes in muscle mass and strength after menopause. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2009;9(4):186-197. https://www.ismni.org/jmni/pdf/38/02MALTAIS.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diel P, Baadners D, Schl&#xfc; K, Velders M, Schwarz JP. C2C12 myoblastoma cell differentiation and proliferation is stimulated by androgens and associated with a modulation of myostatin and Pax7 expression. J Mol Endocrinol. 2008;40:231-241. doi:10.1677/JME-07-0175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doumitt ME, Cook DR, Merkel RA. Testosterone up-regulates androgen receptors and decreases differentiation of porcine myogenic satellite cells in&#xa0;vitro. Endocrinology. 1996;137(4):1385-1394. doi:10.1210/en.137.4.1385</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>