<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35561231</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>107</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of obesity and acute resistance exercise on skeletal muscle angiogenic communication pathways.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>906</StartPage><EndPage>918</EndPage><MedlinePgn>906-918</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP090152</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="NEW FINDINGS">What is the central question of this study? Do obesity and acute resistance exercise alter the regulation of muscle intercellular communication pathways consistent with inadequate compensatory angiogenesis in response to muscle loading present in individuals with obesity? What is the main finding and its importance? Obesity is associated with differences in both pro- and anti-angiogenic signalling consistent with lower muscle capillarization. Acute resistance exercise increases the release of skeletal muscle small extracellular vesicles independent of body mass. These results identify new cellular factors associated with impaired angiogenesis in obesity and the positive effects of acute resistance exercise in lean and obese skeletal muscle.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT">Obesity (OB) impairs cell-to-cell communication signalling. Small extracellular vesicles (EVs), which include exosomes, are released by skeletal muscle and participate in cell-to-cell communication, including the regulation of angiogenesis. Resistance exercise (REx) increases muscle fibre size and capillarization. Although obesity increases muscle fibre size, there is an inadequate increase in capillarization such that capillary density is reduced. It was hypothesized that REx-induced angiogenic signalling and EV biogenesis would be lower with obesity. Sedentary lean (LN) and OB subjects (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;8 per group) performed three sets of single-leg knee-extension REx at 80% of maximum. Muscle biopsies were obtained at rest, 15&#xa0;min and 3&#xa0;h postexercise and analysed for angiogenic and EV biogenesis mRNA and protein. In OB subjects, muscle fibre size was &#x223c;20% greater and capillary density with type&#xa0;II fibres &#x223c;25% lower compared with LN subjects (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.001). In response to REx, the increase in VEGF mRNA (pro-angiogenic) was similar (3-fold) between groups, while thrombospondin-1 (TSP-1) mRNA (anti-angiogenic) increased &#x223c;2.5-fold in OB subjects only (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.010). miR-130a (pro-angiogenic) was &#x223c;1.4-fold (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.011) and miR-503 (anti-angiogenic) &#x223c;1.8-fold (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.017) greater in OB compared with LN subjects at all time points. In both groups, acute REx decreased the EV surface protein Alix by &#x223c;50%, consistent with the release of exosomes (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.016). Acute REx appears to induce the release of skeletal muscle small EVs independent of body mass. However, with obesity there is predominantly impaired angiogenic signalling, consistent with inadequate angiogenesis in response to basal muscle hypertrophy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Experimental Physiology &#xa9; 2022 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garner</LastName><ForeName>Ron T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3035-6326</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Science and Humanities, Husson University, Bangor, Maine, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiss</LastName><ForeName>Jessica A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Kinesiology and Max E. Wastl Human Performance Laboratory, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Yaohui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Kinesiology and Max E. Wastl Human Performance Laboratory, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Sciences, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sullivan</LastName><ForeName>Brian P</ForeName><Initials>BP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Kinesiology and Max E. Wastl Human Performance Laboratory, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kargl</LastName><ForeName>Christopher K</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Kinesiology and Max E. Wastl Human Performance Laboratory, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drohan</LastName><ForeName>Cathal J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Performance, Dublin City University, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuang</LastName><ForeName>Shihuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Sciences, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stout</LastName><ForeName>Julianne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9992-1333</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Indiana University School of Medicine West Lafayette, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gavin</LastName><ForeName>Timothy P</ForeName><Initials>TP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0679-7076</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Kinesiology and Max E. Wastl Human Performance Laboratory, Purdue University, West Lafayette, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D035683">MicroRNAs</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D042461">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035683" MajorTopicYN="N">MicroRNAs</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018919" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neovascularization, Physiologic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042461" MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angiogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exosomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multivesicular bodies</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35561231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP090152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ascaso, J. F., Pardo, S., Real, J. T., Lorente, R. I., Priego, A., &amp; Carmena, R. (2003). Diagnosing insulin resistance by simple quantitative methods in subjects with normal glucose metabolism. Diabetes Care, 26(12), 3320-3325. https://doi.org/10.2337/diacare.26.12.3320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aswad, H., Forterre, A., Wiklander, O. P. B., Vial, G., Danty-Berger, E., Jalabert, A., Lamazi&#xe8;re, A., Meugnier, E., Pesenti, S., Ott, C., Chikh, K., El-Andaloussi, S., Vidal, H., Lefai, E., Rieusset, J., &amp; Rome, S. (2014). Exosomes participate in the alteration of muscle homeostasis during lipid-induced insulin resistance in mice. Diabetologia, 57(10), 2155-2164. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-014-3337-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azmi, A. S., Bao, B., &amp; Sarkar, F. H. (2013). Exosomes in cancer development, metastasis, and drug resistance: A comprehensive review. Cancer and Metastasis Reviews, 32(3-4), 623-642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babst, M. (1997). Endosomal transport function in yeast requires a novel AAA-type ATPase, Vps4p. The EMBO Journal, 16(8), 1820-1831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos, G., Luecke, T., Wendeln, H., Toma, K., Hagerman, F., Murray, T., Ragg, K., Ratamess, N., Kraemer, W., &amp; Staron, R. (2002). Muscular adpatations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 88, 50-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caporali, A., Meloni, M., V&#xf6;llenkle, C., Bonci, D., Sala-Newby, G. B., Addis, R., Spinetti, G., Losa, S., Masson, R., Baker, A. H., Agami, R., Le Sage, C., Condorelli, G., Madeddu, P., Martelli, F., &amp; Emanueli, C. (2011). Deregulation of microRNA-503 contributes to diabetes mellitus-induced impairment of endothelial function and reparative angiogenesis after limb ischemia. Circulation, 123(3), 282-291. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.110.952325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., &amp; Gorski, D. H. (2008). Regulation of angiogenesis through a microRNA (miR-130a) that down-regulates antiangiogenic homeobox genes GAX and HOXA5. Blood, 111(3), 1217-1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo, M., Moita, C., Van Niel, G., Kowal, J., Vigneron, J., Benaroch, P., Manel, N., Moita, L. F., Th&#xe9;ry, C., &amp; Raposo, G. (2013). Analysis of ESCRT functions in exosome biogenesis, composition and secretion highlights the heterogeneity of extracellular vesicles. Journal of Cell Science, 126(Pt 24), 5553-5565. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.128868</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckel, R. H., Grundy, S. M., &amp; Zimmet, P. Z. (2005). The metabolic syndrome. The Lancet, 365(9468), 1415-1428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esquela-Kerscher, A., &amp; Slack, F. J. (2006). Oncomirs-microRNAs with a role in cancer. Nature Reviews Cancer, 6(4), 259-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada, A. L., Valenti, Z. J., Hehn, G., Amorese, A. J., Williams, N. S., Balestrieri, N. P., Deighan, C., Allen, C. P., Spangenburg, E. E., Kruh-Garcia, N. A., &amp; Lark, D. S. (2022). Extracellular vesicle secretion is tissue-dependent ex vivo and skeletal muscle myofiber extracellular vesicles reach the circulation in vivo. American Journal of Physiology. Cell Physiology, 322(2), C246-C259. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpcell.00580.2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrante, S. C., Nadler, E. P., Pillai, D. K., Hubal, M. J., Wang, Z., Wang, J. M., Gordish-Dressman, H., Koeck, E., Sevilla, S., Wiles, A. A., &amp; Freishtat, R. J. (2015). Adipocyte-derived exosomal miRNAs: A novel mechanism for obesity-related disease. Pediatric Research, 77(3), 447-454. https://doi.org/10.1038/pr.2014.202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara, N. (2001). Role of vascular endothelial growth factor in regulation of physiological angiogenesis. American Journal of Physiology-Cell Physiology, 280(6), C1358-C1366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, L., Wang, H. -. J., Tian, C., &amp; Zucker, I. H. (2021). Skeletal muscle Nrf2 contributes to exercise-evoked systemic antioxidant defense via extracellular vesicular communication. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 49(3), 213-222. https://doi.org/10.1249/JES.0000000000000257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner, R. T., Solfest, J. S., Nie, Y., Kuang, S., Stout, J., &amp; Gavin, T. P. (2020). Multivesicular body and exosome pathway responses to acute exercise. Experimental Physiology, 105(3), 511-521. https://doi.org/10.1113/EP088017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin, T. P., Drew, J. L., Kubik, C. J., Pofahl, W. E., &amp; Hickner, R. C. (2007). Acute resistance exercise increases skeletal muscle angiogenic growth factor expression. Acta Physiologica, 191, 139-146. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;dopt=Citation&amp;list_uids=17565567</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin, T. P., Robinson, C. B., Yeager, R. C., England, J. A., Nifong, L. W., &amp; Hickner, R. C. (2004). Angiogenic growth factor response to acute systemic exercise in human skeletal muscle. Journal of Applied Physiology, 96(1), 19-24. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;dopt=Citation&amp;list_uids=12949011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin, T. P., Stallings, H. W., Zwetsloot, K. A., Westerkamp, L. M., Ryan, N. A., Moore, R. A., Pofahl, W. E., &amp; Hickner, R. C. (2005). Lower capillary density but no difference in VEGF expression in obese vs. lean young skeletal muscle in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 98(1), 315-321. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00353.2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham, T., &amp; Kahn, B. (2007). Tissue-specific alterations of glucose transport and molecular mechanisms of intertissue communication in obesity and type 2 diabetes. Hormone and Metabolic Research, 39(10), 717-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, H., Goreham, C., Ouyang, J., Ball-Burnett, M., &amp; Ranney, D. (1999). Regulation of fiber size, oxidative potential, and capillarization in human muscle by resistance exercise. American Journal of Physiology, 276(2), R591-R596. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpregu.1999.276.2.R591</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hales, C. M., Carroll, M. D., Fryar, C. D., &amp; Ogden, C. L. (2020). Prevalence of obesity and severe obesity among adults: United States, 2017-2018. NCHS Data Brief, &#xa0;(360), 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden, M. R., Patel, K., Habibi, J., Gupta, D., Tekwani, S. S., Whaley-Connell, A., &amp; Sowers, J. R. (2008). Attenuation of endocrine-exocrine pancreatic communication in type 2 diabetes: Pancreatic extracellular matrix ultrastructural abnormalities. Journal of the Cardiometabolic Syndrome, 3(4), 234-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henne, W. M., Buchkovich, N. J., &amp; Emr, S. D. (2011). The ESCRT pathway. Developmental Cell, 21(1), 77-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hepple, R. T., Mackinnon, S. L. M., Goodman, J. M., Thomas, S. G., &amp; Plyley, M. J. (1997). Resistance and aerobic training in older men: Effects on VO2peak and the capillary supply to skeletal muscle. Journal of Applied Physiology, 82, 1305-1310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoier, B., Olsen, K., Hanskov, D. J., Jorgensen, M., Norup, L. R., &amp; Hellsten, Y. (2020). Early time course of change in angiogenic proteins in human skeletal muscle and vascular cells with endurance training. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 30(7), 1117-1131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoier, B., Prats, C., Qvortrup, K., Pilegaard, H., Bangsbo, J., &amp; Hellsten, Y. (2013). Subcellular localization and mechanism of secretion of vascular endothelial growth factor in human skeletal muscle. Faseb Journal, 27(9), 3496-3504. https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.12-224618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howley, E. T., Bassett, D. R., &amp; Welch, H. G. (1995). Criteria for maximal oxygen uptake: Review and commentary. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 27(9), 1292-1301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenberg, J., Wink, D., &amp; Roberts, D. (2006). Thrombospondin-1 antagonizes nitric oxide-stimulated vascular smooth muscle cell responses. Cardiovascular Research, 71(4), 785-793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivy, J. L. (1997). Role of exercise training in the prevention and treatment of insulin resistance and non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. Sports Medicine, 24(5), 321-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, K., Ma, R., Cai, W., Huang, W., Paul, C., Liang, J., Wang, Y., Zhao, T., Kim, H. W., Xu, M., Millard, R. W., Wen, Z., &amp; Wang, Y. (2015). Exosomes secreted from CXCR4 overexpressing mesenchymal stem cells promote cardioprotection via Akt signaling pathway following myocardial infarction. Stem Cells International, 2015, 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller, S., Sanderson, M. P., Stoeck, A., &amp; Altevogt, P. (2006). Exosomes: From biogenesis and secretion to biological function. Immunology Letters, 107(2), 102-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowal, J., Arras, G., Colombo, M., Jouve, M., Morath, J. P., Primdal-Bengtson, B., Dingli, F., Loew, D., Tkach, M., &amp; Th&#xe9;ry, C. (2016). Proteomic comparison defines novel markers to characterize heterogeneous populations of extracellular vesicle subtypes. PNAS, 113(8), E968-977. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1521230113</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus, R. M., Stallings, H. W., Yeager, R. C., &amp; Gavin, T. P. (2004). Circulating plasma VEGF response to exercise in sedentary and endurance-trained men. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md. : 1985), 96(4), 1445-1450. https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.01031.2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillioja, S., Young, A. A., Culter, C. L., Ivy, J. L., Abbott, W. G., Zawadzki, J. K., Yki-J&#xe4;rvinen, H., Christin, L., Secomb, T. W., &amp; Bogardus, C. (1987). Skeletal muscle capillary density and fiber type are possible determinants of in vivo insulin resistance in man. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 80(2), 415-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livak, K. J., &amp; Schmittgen, T. D. (2001). Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2&#x2212; &#x394;&#x394;CT method. Methods (San Diego, Calif.), 25(4), 402-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek, M. H., &amp; Olfert, I. M. (2009). Global deletion of thrombospondin-1 increases cardiac and skeletal muscle capillarity and exercise capacity in mice. Experimental Physiology, 94(6), 749-760. https://doi.org/10.1113/expphysiol.2008.045989</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccall, G. E., Byrnes, W. C., Dickinson, A., Pattany, P. M., &amp; Fleck, S. J. (1996). Muscle fiber hypertrophy, hyperplasia, and capillary density in college men after resistance training. Journal of Applied Physiology, 81(5), 2004-2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcdonald, B., &amp; Martin-Serrano, J. (2008). Regulation of Tsg101 expression by the steadiness box: A role of Tsg101-associated ligase. Molecular Biology of the Cell, 19(2), 754-763. https://doi.org/10.1091/mbc.e07-09-0957</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura, K., Jinnin, M., Harada, M., Kudo, H., Nakayama, W., Inoue, K., Ogata, A., Kajihara, I., Fukushima, S., &amp; Ihn, H. (2016). Altered expression of CD63 and exosomes in scleroderma dermal fibroblasts. Journal of Dermatological Science, 84(1), 30-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie, Y., Sato, Y., Garner, R. T., Kargl, C., Wang, C., Kuang, S., Gilpin, C. J., &amp; Gavin, T. P. (2019). Skeletal muscle derived exosomes regulate endothelial cell functions via reactive oxygen species activated NF-kappaB signaling. Experimental Physiology, 104, 1262-1273. https://doi.org/10.1113/EP087396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olfert, I. M., Baum, O., Hellsten, Y., &amp; Egginton, S. (2016). Advances and challenges in skeletal muscle angiogenesis. American Journal of Physiology. Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 310(3), H326-H336. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00635.2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olfert, I. M., Breen, E. C., Gavin, T. P., &amp; Wagner, P. D. (2006). Temporal thrombospondin-1 mRNA response in skeletal muscle exposed to acute and chronic exercise. Growth Factors, 24(4), 253-259. https://doi.org/10.1080/08977190601000111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski, M., Carmo, N. B., Krumeich, S., Fanget, I., Raposo, G., Savina, A., Moita, C. F., Schauer, K., Hume, A. N., Freitas, R. P., Goud, B., Benaroch, P., Hacohen, N., Fukuda, M., Desnos, C., Seabra, M. C., Darchen, F., Amigorena, S., Moita, L. F., &amp; Thery, C. (2010). Rab27a and Rab27b control different steps of the exosome secretion pathway. Nature Cell Biology, 12(1), 19-30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen, B. K., &amp; Febbraio, M. A. (2012). Muscles, exercise and obesity: Skeletal muscle as a secretory organ. Nature Reviews Endocrinology, 8, 457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safdar, A., Saleem, A., &amp; Tarnopolsky, M. A. (2016). The potential of endurance exercise-derived exosomes to treat metabolic diseases. Nature reviews Endocrinology, 12(9), 504-517. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrendo.2016.76</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada, S., Kon, M., Wada, S., Ushida, T., Suzuki, K., &amp; Akimoto, T. (2013). Profiling of circulating microRNAs after a bout of acute resistance exercise in humans. Plos One, 8(7), e70823. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0070823</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, H., Liu, T., Fu, L., Zhao, S., Fan, B., Cao, J., &amp; Li, X. (2013). Identification of microRNAs involved in dexamethasone-induced muscle atrophy. Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry, 381(1-2), 105-113. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11010-013-1692-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoneau, J. -. A., Colberg, S. R., Thaete, F. L., &amp; Kelley, D. E. (1995). Skeletal muscle glycolytic and oxidative enzyme capacities are determinants of insulin sensitivity and muscle composition in obese women. The FASEB Journal, 9(2), 273-278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan, B. P., Weiss, J. A., Nie, Y., Garner, R. T., Drohan, C. J., Kuang, S., Stout, J., &amp; Gavin, T. P. (2020). Skeletal muscle IGF-1 is lower at rest and after resistance exercise in humans with obesity. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 2835-2846. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-020-04509-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, K., Breen, E. C., Gerber, H. -. P., Ferrara, N. M. A., &amp; Wagner, P. D. (2004). Capillary regression in vascular endothelial growth factor-deficient skeletal muscle. Physiological Genomics, 18(1), 63-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch, P. A., &amp; Karlsson, J. (1985). Muscle fiber types and size in trained and untrained muscles of elite athletes. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md. : 1985), 59(6), 1716-1720. https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.1985.59.6.1716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varma, V., Yao-Borengasser, A., Bodles, A. M., Rasouli, N., Phanavanh, B., Nolen, G. T., Kern, E. M., Nagarajan, R., Spencer, H. J., Lee, M.-J., Fried, S. K., Mcgehee, R. E., Peterson, C. A., &amp; Kern, P. A. (2008). Thrombospondin-1 is an adipokine associated with obesity, adipose inflammation, and insulin resistance. Diabetes, 57(2), 432-439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitham, M., Parker, B. L., Friedrichsen, M., Hingst, J. R., Hjorth, M., Hughes, W. E., Egan, C. L., Cron, L., Watt, K. I., Kuchel, R. P., Jayasooriah, N., Estevez, E., Petzold, T., Suter, C. M., Gregorevic, P., Kiens, B., Richter, E. A., James, D. E., Wojtaszewski, J. F. P., &amp; Febbraio, M. A. (2018). Extracellular vesicles provide a means for tissue crosstalk during exercise. Cell Metabolism, 27(1), 237-251.e4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2017.12.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, B., Shi, X., Zhang, H., Pan, L., Ma, Z., Liu, S., Liu, Y., Li, X., Yang, S., &amp; Li, Z. (2014). Association of serum irisin with metabolic syndrome in obese Chinese adults. Plos One, 9(4), e94235. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0094235</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>