<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26957922</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1303-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sports science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Daily Overfeeding from Protein and/or Carbohydrate Supplementation for Eight Weeks in Conjunction with Resistance Training Does not Improve Body Composition and Muscle Strength or Increase Markers Indicative of Muscle Protein Synthesis and Myogenesis in Resistance-Trained Males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17</StartPage><EndPage>25</EndPage><MedlinePgn>17-25</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>This study determined the effects of heavy resistance training and daily overfeeding with carbohydrate and/or protein on blood and skeletal muscle markers of protein synthesis (MPS), myogenesis, body composition, and muscle performance. Twenty one resistance-trained males were randomly assigned to either a protein + carbohydrate [HPC (n = 11)] or a carbohydrate [HC (n = 10)] supplement group in a double-blind fashion. Body composition and muscle performance were assessed, and venous blood samples and muscle biopsies were obtained before and after eight weeks of resistance training and supplementation. Data were analyzed by two-way ANOVA (p &#x2264; 0.05). Total body mass, body water, and fat mass were significantly increased in both groups in response to resistance training, but not supplementation (p &lt; 0.05); however, lean mass was not significantly increased in either group (p = 0.068). Upper- (p = 0.024) and lower-body (p = 0.001) muscle strength and myosin heavy chain (MHC) 1 (p = 0.039) and MHC 2A (p = 0.027) were also significantly increased with resistance training. Serum IGF-1, GH, and HGF were not significantly affected (p &gt; 0.05). Muscle total DNA, total protein, and c-Met were not significantly affected (p &gt; 0.05). In conjunction with resistance training, the peri-exercise and daily overfeeding of protein and/or carbohydrate did not preferentially improve body composition, muscle performance, and markers indicative of MPS and myogenic activation. Key pointsIn response to 56 days of heavy resistance training and HC or HPC supplementation, similar increases in muscle mass and strength in both groups occurred; however, the increases were not different between supplement groups.The supplementation of HPC had no preferential effect on augmenting serum IGF-1 GH, or HGF.The supplementation of HPC had no preferential effect on augmenting increases in total muscle protein content or the myogenic markers, total DNA and muscle cMet content.In response to 56 days of a daily supplemental dose of 94 g of protein and 196 g of carbohydrate, the HPC group was no more effective than 312 g of carbohydrate in the HC group in increasing muscle strength and mass due to its ability to elevate serum anabolic hormones and growth factors and markers of myogenic activation of satellite cells.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spillane</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Physical Education, and Leisure Studies, University of South Alabama , Mobile, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willoughby</LastName><ForeName>Darryn S</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Performance, and Recreation, Exercise and Biochemical, Nutrition Laboratory, Baylor University , Waco, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1303-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbohydrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle protein synthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myogenesis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26957922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4763837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akiyama T., Tachibana I., Shirohara H., Watanabe N., Otsuki M. (1996) High-fat hypercaloric diet induces obesity, glucose intolerance and hyperlipidemia in normal adult male Wistar rat. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice 31(1-3), 27-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8792099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J., Peacock C.A., Ellerbroek A., Fromhoff B., Silver T. (2014) The effects of consuming a high protein diet (4.4 g/kg/d) on body composition in resistance-trained individuals. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition 11, 19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4022420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24834017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta J.L., Burke L.M., Ross M.L., Camera D.M., West D.W., Broad E.M., Jeacocke N.A., Moore D.R., Stellingwerff T., Phillips S.M., Hawley J.A., Coffey V.G. (2013) Timing and distribution of protein ingestion during prolonged recovery from resistance exercise alters myofibrillar protein synthesis. Journal of Physiology 591(Pt 9), 2319-2331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton P.J., Etheridge T., Watt P.W., Wilkinson D., Selby A., Rankin D., Smith K., Rennie M.J. (2010) Muscle full effect after oral protein: time-dependent concordance and discordance between human muscle protein synthesis and mTORC1 signaling. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 92(5), 1080-1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20844073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausubel F.M. (1998) Current Protocols in Molecular Biology: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijland S., Mancini S.J., Salt I.P. (2013) Role of AMP-activated protein kinase in adipose tissue metabolism and inflammation. Clinical Science 124(8), 491-507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23298225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird S.P., Tarpenning K.M., Marino F.E. (2006) Liquid carbohydrate/essential amino acid ingestion during a short-term bout of resistance exercise suppresses myofibrillar protein degradation. Metabolism 55(5), 570-577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16631431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G., Maggi S.P., Williams B.D., Tipton K.D., Wolfe R.R. (1995) Increased rates of muscle protein turnover and amino acid transport after resistance exercise in humans. American Journal of Physiology 268(3 Pt 1), E514-520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohe J., Low J.F.A, Wolfe R.R., Rennie M.J. (2003) Human muscle protein synthesis is modulated by extracellular, not intramuscular amino acid availability: a dose-response study. Journal of Physiology 552(1), 315-324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12909668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohe J., Low J.F.A, Wolfe R.R., Rennie M.J. (2001) Latency and duration of stimulation of human muscle protein synthesis during continuous infusion of amino acids. Journal of Physiology 532(2), 575-579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11306673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford M.M. (1976) A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principle of protein-dye binding. Analytical Biochemistry 72(1), 248-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">942051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan K.A., Balon T.W., Valentine R.J., Petrocelli R., Schultz V., Brandon A., Cooney G.F., Kraegen E.W., Ruderman N.B., Saha A.K. (2015) Nutrient excess and AMPK downregulation in incubated skeletal muscle and muscle of glucose infused rats. PLOS ONE 21;10(5), e0127388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4440828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25996822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson-Stegall L., McCleave E.L., Ding Z., Doerner P.G., Wang B., Liao Y.H., Kammer L., Liu Y., Hwang J., Dessard B.M., Ivy J.L. (2011) Postexercise carbohydrate-protein supplementation improves subsequent exercise performance and intracellular signaling for protein synthesis. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 25(5), 1210-1224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier M.S., O&#x2019;Brien E. L., Bigornia S., Mott M., Caciedo J.M., Xu X.J., Gokce N., Apovian C., Ruderman N. (2011) Decreased AMP-activated protein kinase activity is associated with increased inflammation in visceral adipose tissue and with whole-body insulin resistance in morbidly obese humans. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications 404, 382-387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3061625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21130749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass C.K., Olefsky J.M. (2012) Inflammation and lipid signaling in the etiology of insulin resistance. Cell Metabolism 15(5), 635-645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4156155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22560216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haaf T.T., Weijs P.J.M. (2014) Resting energy expenditure prediction in recreational athletes of 18-35 years: confirmation of Cunningham equation and an improved weight-based alternative. PLOS ONE 9(10), 1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4183531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25275434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill J.O., Peters J.C., Reed G.W., Schlundt D.G., Sharp T., Greene H.L. (1991) Nutrient balance in humans: effects of diet composition. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 54(1), 10-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2058571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore D.R., Areta J., Coffey V.G., Stellingwerff T., Phillips S.M., Burke L.M., Cleroux M., Godin J.P., Hawley J. A. (2012) Daytime pattern of post-exercise protein intake affects whole-body protein turnover in resistance-trained males. Nutrition and Metabolism (Lond) 9 (1), 91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23067428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore D.R., Robinson M.J., Fry J.L., Tang J.E., Glover E.I., Wilkinson S.B., Prior T., Tarnopolsky M.A., Phillips S. M. (2009) Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 89(1), 161-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor K., Stip E., Pelissier M. C., Aardema F., Guay S., Gaudette G., Van Jaaster I., Robillard S., Grenier S., Careau Y, Doucet P., Leblanc V. (2007) Treating delusional disorder: a comparison of cognitive-behavioural therapy and attention placebo control. Canadian Journal of Psychiatry 52(3), 182-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17479527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Tipton K. D., Aarsland A., Wolf S. E., Wolfe R. R. (1997) Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. American Journal of Physiology 273(1 Pt 1), E99-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahbek S.K., Farup J., Moller A.B., Vendelbo M.H., Holm L., Jessen N., Vissing K. (2014) Effects of divergent resistance exercise contraction mode and dietary supplementation type on anabolic signalling, muscle protein synthesis and muscle hypertrophy. Amino Acids 46, 2377-2392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25005782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie M. J., Boh&#xe9; J., Wolfe R. R. (2002) Latency, duration and dose response relationships of amino acid effects on human muscle protein synthesis. The Journal of Nutrition 132(10), 3225S-3227S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12368422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samocha-Bonet D., Campbell L. V., Mori T. A., Croft K. D., Greenfield J. R., Turner N., Heilbronn L. K. (2012) Overfeeding reduces insulin sensitivity and increases oxidative stress, without altering markers of mitochondrial content and function in humans. PLOS ONE 7 (5), e36320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3346759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22586466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelmadine B., Cooke M., Buford T., Hudson G., Redd L., Leutholtz B., Willoughby D.S. (2009) Effects of 28 days of resistance exercise and consuming a commercially available pre-workout supplement, NO-Shotgun(R), on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of satellite cell activation, and clinical safety markers in males. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition 6, 16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M., Emerson C., Willoughby D. S. (2012) The effects of 8 weeks of heavy resistance training and branched-chain amino acid supplementation on body composition and muscle performance. Nutrition and Health 21(4), 263-273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24620007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M., Schoch R., Cooke M., Harvey T., Greenwood M., Kreider R., Willoughby D. S. (2009) The effects of creatine ethyl ester supplementation combined with heavy resistance training on body composition, muscle performance, and serum and muscle creatine levels. Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition 6, 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2649889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M., Schwarz N., Leddy S., Correa T., Minter M., Longoria V., Willoughby D.S. (2011) Effects of 28 days of resistance exercise while consuming commercially available pre- and post-workout supplements, NO-Shotgun(R) and NO-Synthesize(R) on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of protein synthesis, and clinical safety markers in males. Nutrition and Metabolism (Lond) 8, 78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3226541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22050827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane M., Schwarz N., Willoughby D.S. (2014) Heavy resistance training and peri-exercise ingestion of a multi-ingredient ergogenic nutritional supplement in males: effects on body composition, muscle performance and markers of muscle protein synthesis. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 13(4), 894-903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25435783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staples A.W., Burd N.A., West D.W., Currie K.D., Atherton P.J., Moore D.R., Rennie M.J., Macdonald M.J., Baker S.K., Phillips S. M. (2011) Carbohydrate does not augment exercise-induced protein accretion versus protein alone. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 43(7), 1154-1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyfault J.P., Carper M.J., Richmond S.R., Hulver M.W., Potteiger J.A. (2004) Effects of liquid carbohydrate ingestion on markers of anabolism following high-intensity resistance exercise. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 18(1), 174-179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vienberg S.G., Bjornholm M. (2014) Chronic glucocorticoid treatment increases de novo lipogenesis in visceral adipose tissue. Acta Physiologica (Oxford, England), 211(2), 257-259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24666590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilborn C.D., Taylor L.W., Greenwood M., Kreider R.B., Willoughby D.S. (2009) Effects of different intensities of resistance exercise on regulators of myogenesis. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 23(8), 2179-2187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19826309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby D., Stout J., Wilborn C. (2007) Effects of resistance training and protein plus amino acid supplementation on muscle anabolism, mass, and strength. Amino Acids 32(4), 467-477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16988909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard O.C., Jackman S.R., Breen L., Smith K., Selby A., Tipton K.D. (2014) Myofibrillar muscle protein synthesis rates subsequent to a meal in response to increasing doses of whey protein at rest and after resistance exercise. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 99(1), 86-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24257722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>