<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37582807</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of free-weight vs. machine-based strength training on maximal strength, hypertrophy and jump performance - a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-023-00713-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The effectiveness of strength training with free-weight vs. machine equipment is heavily debated. Thus, the purpose of this meta-analysis was to summarize the data on the effect of free-weight versus machine-based strength training on maximal strength, jump height and hypertrophy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The review was conducted in accordance with the preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses (PRISMA) guidelines, and the systematic search of literature was conducted up to January 1<sup>st</sup>, 2023. Studies that directly compared free-weight vs. machine-based strength training for a minimum of 6&#xa0;weeks in adults (18-60 yrs.) were included.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirteen studies (outcomes: maximal strength [n&#x2009;=&#x2009;12], jump performance [n&#x2009;=&#x2009;5], muscle hypertrophy [n&#x2009;=&#x2009;5]) with a total sample of 1016 participants (789 men, 219 women) were included. Strength in free-weight tests increased significantly more with free-weight training than with machines (SMD: -0.210, CI: -0.391, -0.029, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.023), while strength in machine-based tests tended to increase more with machine training than with free-weights (SMD: 0.291, CI: -0.017, 0.600, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.064). However, no differences were found between modalities in direct comparison (free-weight strength vs. machine strength) for dynamic strength (SMD: 0.084, CI: -0.106, 0.273, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.387), isometric strength (SMD: -0.079, CI: -0.432, 0.273, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.660), countermovement jump (SMD: -0.209, CI: -0.597, 0.179, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.290) and hypertrophy (SMD: -0.055, CI: -0.397, 0.287, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.751).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">No differences were detected in the direct comparison of strength, jump performance and muscle hypertrophy. Current body of evidence indicates that strength changes are specific to the training modality, and the choice between free-weights and machines are down to individual preferences and goals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haugen</LastName><ForeName>Markus E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0797-664X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Nord University, Levanger, Norway. haugen@helseogprestasjon.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>V&#xe5;rvik</LastName><ForeName>Fredrik T</ForeName><Initials>FT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science and Physical Education, Faculty of Health and Sport Sciences, University of Agder, Kristiansand, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength and Power consultant at the Norwegian Olympic and Paralympic Committee and Confederation of Sports, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norwegian Olympic and Paralympic Committee and Confederation of Sports, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Larsen</LastName><ForeName>Stian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Nord University, Levanger, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haugen</LastName><ForeName>Arvid S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia and Intensive Care, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing and Health Promotion Acute and Critical Illness, Faculty of Health Sciences, OsloMet - Oslo Metropolitan University, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Tillaar</LastName><ForeName>Roland</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences and Physical Education, Nord University, Levanger, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bj&#xf8;rnsen</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science and Physical Education, Faculty of Health and Sport Sciences, University of Agder, Kristiansand, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strength and Power consultant at the Norwegian Olympic and Paralympic Committee and Confederation of Sports, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norwegian Olympic and Paralympic Committee and Confederation of Sports, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Equipment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Force production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Modalities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle size</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest regarding the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37582807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10426227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-023-00713-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-023-00713-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luebbers PE, Fry AC. The Kansas Squat Test Modality Comparison: Free Weights vs Smith Machine. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:2186&#x2013;2193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26950349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons TS, McLester JR, Arnett SW, Thoma MJ. Specificity of training modalities on upper-body one repetition maximum performance: Free weights vs. Hammer strength equipment. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:2984&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20940634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Olsen A, Behm DG, Bardstu HB, Andersen V. The short- and long-term effects of resistance training with different stability requirements. PLoS One. 2019;14:1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6443166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30934001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidel KA, Novak ZJ, Dankel SJ. Machines and free weight exercises: a systematic review and meta-analysis comparing changes in muscle size, strength, and power. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2021. 10.23736/S0022-4707.21.12929-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34609100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Larsen S. Kinematic and EMG Comparison Between Variations of Unilateral Squats Under Different Stabilities. Sports Med Int Open. 2020;4:E59&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32685673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG. Roundtable Discussion: Machines Versus Free Weights. Strength Cond J. 2000;22:18&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr ZY, Collins CL, Dawn CR. Epidemiology of Weight Training-Related Injuries Presenting to United States Emergency Departments, 1990 to 2007. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38:765&#x2013;771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. Evidence-Based Resistance Training Recommendations. Medicina Sportiva. 2011;15:147&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Fimland MS. Muscle force output and electromyographic activity in squats with various unstable surfaces. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:130&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22450254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen VM, Norum M, Schoenfeld BJ, Fimland MS. No Time to Lift? Designing Time-Efficient Training Programs for Strength and Hypertrophy: A Narrative Review. Sports Medicine. 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8449772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34125411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langford GA, Mccurdy KW, Ernest JM, Doscher MW, Walters SD. Specificity of Machine, Barbell, and Water-Filled Log Bench Press Resistance Training on Measures of Strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lander JE, Bates BT, Sawhill JA, Hamill J. A comparison between free-weight and isokinetic bench pressing. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1985;17:344&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4021780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwanbeck S, Chilibeck PD, Binsted G. A comparison of free weight squat to Smith machine squat using electromyography. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:2588&#x2013;2591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Longing for a Longitudinal Proxy_ Acutely Measured Surface EMG Amplitude is not a Validated Predictor of Muscle Hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2022;52:193&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35006527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Lehman GJ, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Interpreting signal amplitudes in surface electromyography studies in sport and rehabilitation sciences. Front Physiol. 2018;8:JAN.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29354060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotterman ML, Darby LA, Skelly WA. Comparison of muscle force production using the Smith machine and free weights for bench press and squat exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19:169&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson K, Behm DG. Trunk muscle activity increases with unstable squat movements. Can J Appl Physiol. 2005;30:33&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm D, Colado JC. The effectiveness of resistance training using unstable surfaces and devices for rehabilitation. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2012;7:226&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22530196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:2857&#x2013;2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Van Every DW, Plotkin DL. Loading Recommendations for Muscle Strength, Hypertrophy, and Local Endurance: A Re-Examination of the Repetition Continuum. Sports. 2021;9:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7927075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33671664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. High-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerenhouts D, D&#x2019;Hondt E. Using Machines or Free Weights for Resistance Training in Novice Males? A Randomized Parallel Trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:7848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33114782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto Gonz&#xe1;lez P, Sedlacek J. Comparison of the Efficacy of Three Types of Strength Training: Body, Weight Training Machines and Free Weights. Apunts Educaci&#xf3;n F&#xed;sica y Deportes. 2021;9&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavallee ME, Balam T. An overview of strength training injuries: acute and chronic. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2010;9:307&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20827099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. The BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Andersen V, Behm DG, Krohn-Hansen EK, Smaamo M, Fimland MS. Resistance-training exercises with different stability requirements: time course of task specificity. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:2247&#x2013;2256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27671996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Andersen V, van den Tillaar R, Joly F, Stien N, Pedersen H, et al. The effects of ten weeks resistance training on sticking region in chest-press exercises. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0235555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos Junior ERT, de Salles BF, Dias I, Ribeiro AS, Sim&#xe3;o R, Willardson JM. Classification and Determination Model of Resistance Training Status. Strength Cond J. 2021;43:77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Waldron M, Ismail H, Giallauria F, Vigorito C, Cornelissen V, et al. Validation of a new tool for the assessment of study quality and reporting in exercise training studies: TESTEX. Int J Evid Based Healthc. 2015;13:9&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Grgic J, Cunha PM, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, de Salles BF, et al. What influence does resistance exercise order have on muscular strength gains and muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020;0:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustsson J, Esko A, Thome&#xe9; R, Svantesson U. Weight training of the thigh muscles using closed vs. Open kinetic chain exercises: A comparison of performance enhancement. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1998;27:3&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9440034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landis JR, Koch GG. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. Biometrics. 1977;33:159&#x2013;174. doi: 10.2307/2529310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2529310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">843571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC, Powell DR, Kraemer WJ. Validity of Isokinetic and Isometric Testing modalities for Assessing Short-term Resistance Exercise Strength Gains. J Sport Rehabil. 1992;1:275&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennon E, Mathis E, Ratermann A. Comparison of Strength Changes Following Resistance Training Using Free Weights and Machine Weights. Mo J Health, Physical Education, Recreation and Dance. 2010;20:29&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew JL, Smith AE, Arabas JL, Roberts BS. Upper-body strength gains from different modes of resistance training in women who are underweight and women who are obese. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:2779&#x2013;2784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20885198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Schoenfeld BJ, Ocetnik S, Young J, Vigotsky A, Contreras B, et al. Strength, body composition, and functional outcomes in the squat versus leg press exercises. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2018;58:263&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27735888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwanbeck S, Cornish SM, Barss T, Chilibeck PD. Effects of Training with Free Weights Versus Machines on Muscle Mass, Strength, Free Testosterone, and Free Cortisol Levels. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:1851&#x2013;1859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32358310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz N, Harper S, Waldhelm A, McKinley-Barnard S, Holden S, Kovaleski J. A Comparison of Machine versus Free-Weight Squats for the Enhancement of Lower-Body Power, Speed, and Change-of-Direction Ability during an Initial Training Phase of Recreationally Active Women. Sports. 2019;7:215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31574918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Keiner M, Hartmann H, Sander A, Mickel C. Effect of 8 weeks of free-weight and machine-based strength training on strength and power performance. J Hum Kinet. 2016;53:201&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5260589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28149424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. Introduction to meta-analysis. Chichester: Wiley; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, et al. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Wiley; 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper H, Hedges L V, Valente JC. The Handbook of research synthesis and meta-analysis. In: Sage. Second. Russel Sage Foundation; 2019. p. 1884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd Ed. Routledge; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mouser JG, Loenneke JP. Practicing the Test Produces Strength Equivalent to Higher Volume Training. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein N. The Co-ordination and regulation of movements. Oxford: Pergamong Press Ltd.; 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford OM, Jones DA. The role of learning and coordination in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1986;55:100&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Anderson KG. The role of instability with resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:716&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodworth RS, Thorndike EL. The influence of improvement in one mental function upon the efficiency of other functions. In: Psychological issues: Selected papers of Robert S. Woodworth, professor of psychology, Columbia University. New York: Columbia University Press; 2011. p. 335&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk KE, Escamilla RF, Fleisig GS, Barrentine SW, Andrews JR, Boyd ML. A comparison of tibiofemoral joint forces and electromyographic activity during open and closed kinetic chain exercises. Am J Sports Med. 1996;24:518&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8827313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lander JE, Bates BT, Sawhill JA, Hmill J. A comparison between free-weight and isokinetic bench pressing. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1985;17:344???353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4021780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, Mazara N, McGlory C, Quadrilatero J, et al. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol. 2016;121:129&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4967245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DWD, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:71&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Costa BD V, Kassiano W, Nunes JP, Kunevaliki G, Castro-E-Souza P, Rodacki A, et al. Does Performing Different Resistance Exercises for the Same Muscle Group Induce Non-Homogeneous Hypertrophy? Int J Sports Med. 2021;42:803&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33440446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of squat training with different depths on lower limb muscle volumes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119:1933&#x2013;1942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31230110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Newton RU, Cormie P, Blazevich AJ. Inhomogeneous quadriceps femoris hypertrophy in response to strength and power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47:2389&#x2013;2397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25811947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, de Souza EO, Wilson JM, Laurentino GC, et al. Changes in Exercises Are More Effective Than in Loading Schemes to Improve Muscle Strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:3085&#x2013;3092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:2691&#x2013;2703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23949789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Bryanton MA. Relative muscle contributions to net joint moments in the barbell back squat. 40th Annual Meeting of the American Society of Biomechan ics. 2016; August:7&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk DJ, Storey AG, Nelson AR, Cronin JB. Isometric training and long-term adaptations: Effects of muscle length, intensity, and intent: A systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29:484&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30580468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallar&#xe9;s JG, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Vetrovsky T, Steffl M, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J. Effects of range of motion on resistance training adaptations: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31:1866&#x2013;1881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34170576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J. Effects of range of motion on muscle development during resistance training interventions: A systematic review. SAGE Open Med. 2020;8:205031212090155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6977096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32030125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabaleta-Korta A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Pe&#xf1;a E, Torres-Unda J, Garbisu-Hualde A, Santos-Concejero J. The role of exercise selection in regional Muscle Hypertrophy: A randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2021;39:2298&#x2013;2304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34743671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of Rest Interval Duration in Resistance Training on Measures of Muscular Strength: A Systematic Review. Sports Med. 2018;48:137&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Krieger JW, Schoenfeld BJ. The effects of short versus long inter-set rest intervals in resistance training on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17:983&#x2013;993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28641044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35:1073&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Sabol F. Effects of resistance training performed to repetition failure or nonfailure on muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2022;11:202&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J. The Effects of Low-Load vs. High-Load Resistance Training on Muscle Fiber Hypertrophy: A Meta-Analysis. J Hum Kinet. 2020;74:51&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effects of Resistance Training Frequency on Measures of Muscle Hypertrophy: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46:1689&#x2013;1697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27102172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>