<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28566814</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Endocrine responses and acute mTOR pathway phosphorylation to resistance exercise with leucine and whey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>197</StartPage><EndPage>203</EndPage><MedlinePgn>197-203</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2017.65339</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Leucine ingestion reportedly activates the mTOR pathway in skeletal muscle, contributing to a hypertrophy response. The purpose of the study was to compare the post-resistance exercise effects of leucine and whey protein supplementation on endocrine responses and muscle mTOR pathway phosphorylation. On visit 1, subjects (X&#xb1;SD; n=20; age=27.8&#xb1;2.8yrs) provided baseline blood samples for analysis of cortisol, glucose and insulin; a muscle biopsy of the vastus lateralis muscle to assess mTOR signaling pathway phosphorylation; and were tested for maximum strength on the leg press and leg extension exercises. For visits 2 and 3, subjects were randomized in a double-blind crossover design to ingest either leucine and whey protein (10g+10g; supplement) or a non-caloric placebo. During these visits, 5 sets of 10 repetitions were performed on both exercises, immediately followed by ingestion of the supplement or placebo. Blood was sampled 30 min post-, and a muscle biopsy 45 min post-exercise. Western blots quantified total and phosphorylated proteins. Insulin increased (&#x3b1;&lt;.05) with supplementation with no change in glucose compared to placebo. Relative phosphorylation of AKT and rpS6 were greater with leucine and whey supplementation compared to placebo. Supplementation of leucine and whey protein immediately after heavy resistance exercise increases anabolic signaling in human skeletal muscle.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lane</LastName><ForeName>M T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eastern Kentucky University, Exercise Physiology Laboratory, 521 Lancaster Ave, Richmond, KY 40475.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herda</LastName><ForeName>T J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas, Applied Physiology Laboratory, 1301 Sunnyside Ave, Lawrence, KS 66047.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fry</LastName><ForeName>A C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas, Applied Physiology Laboratory, 1301 Sunnyside Ave, Lawrence, KS 66047.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper</LastName><ForeName>M A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas, Applied Physiology Laboratory, 1301 Sunnyside Ave, Lawrence, KS 66047.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andre</LastName><ForeName>M J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Wisconsin Lacrosse, Exercise Science, 1725 State St, La Crosse, WI 54601.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gallagher</LastName><ForeName>P M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas, Applied Physiology Laboratory, 1301 Sunnyside Ave, Lawrence, KS 66047.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AKT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leucine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mTOR</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors of this publication have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28566814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5424460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2017.65339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">65339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baar K, Esser K. Phosphorylation of p70s6k correlates with increased skeletal muscle mass following resistance exercise. Am Physiol Soc. 1999;276:120&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. The essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Human Kinetics; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Saltin B. BCAA intake affects protein metabolism in muscle after but not during exercise in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2001;281:365&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11440914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Eliasson J, Karlsson HKR, Kohnke R. Branched-chain amino acids activate key enzymes in protein synthesis after physical exercise. J Nutr. 2006;136:269&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolster DR, Kubica N, Crozier SJ, Williamson DL, Farrell PA, Kimball SR, Jefferson LS. Immediate response of mammalian target of rapamycin mTOR-mediated signaling following acute resistance exercise in rat skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2003;553:213&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Lhullier FL, Brentano MA, da Silva EM, Amrosini MB, Spinelli R, Silva RF, Kruel LF. Hormonal responses to resistance exercise in long-term trained and untrained middle-aged men. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1617&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caspary WF. Physiology and pathophysiology of intestinal absorption. Am J Clin Nutr. 1992;55:299&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1728844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Luigi L, Guidetti L, Baldari C, Romanelli F. 2003. Heredity and pituitary response to exercise-related stress in trained men. Int J Sports Med. 2003;24(8):551&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14598189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Drummond MJ, Pennings B, Fujita S, Glynn EL, Chinkes DL, Dhanani S, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Leucine enriched essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion following resistance exercise enhances mTOR signaling and protein synthesis in human muscle. Am J Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2008;294:392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2706121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18056791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Fujita S, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Resistance exercise increases leg muscle protein synthesis and mTOR signaling independent of sex. Acta Physiol. 2010;199:71&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20070283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WJ, Phinney SD, Young VR. Suction applied to a muscle biopsy maximizes sample size. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14:101&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7070249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster EB, Fisher G, Sartin JL, Elsasser TH, Wu G, Cowan W, Pascoe DD. Acute regulation of IGF-1 by alterations in post exercise macronutrients. Amino Acids. 2012;42:1405&#x2013;1416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21293890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galpin AJ, Fry AC. Experimental design II &#x2013; dependent variables, blinding, randomization, and matching. In: Armstrong L.E, Kraemer W.J, editors. ACSM&#x2019;s Research Methods. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer; 2016. pp. 143&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gran P, Cameron-Smith D. The actions of exogenous Leucine on mTOR signaling and amino acid transporters in human myotubes. BMC Physiol. 2011;11:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3141572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21702994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haegens A, Schols AM, Van Essen AL, Van Loon LJ, Langen RC. Leucine induces myofibrillar protein accretion in cultured skeletal muscle through mTOR dependent and independent control of myosin heavy chain mRNA levels. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2012;56:741&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22648621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huck S.W, Cormier W.H, Bounds W.G. Reading Statistics and Research. Harper and Row: New York; 1974. pp. 309&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson HKR, Nilsson PA, Nilsson J, Chibalin AV, Zierath JR, Blomstrand E. Branched-chain amino acids increase p70s6k phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle after resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;287:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14998784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leenders M, Verdijk LB, Hoeven LVD, Kranenburg JV, Hartgens F, Wodzig WKWH, Saris WHM, Loon LJCV. Prolonged leucine supplementation does not augment muscle mass or affect glycemic control in elderly type 2 diabetic men. J Nutr. 2011;141:1070&#x2013;1076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan JL, Stone MH, Sartin J, Keith R, Marple D, Brown C, Lewis RD. 20 hour physiological responses to a single weight training session. J Strength Cond Res. 1993;7:9&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicastro H, Da Luz CR, Chaves DFS, Bechara LRG, Voltarelli VA, Robero MM, Lancha AH. Does branched chain amino acids supplementation modulate skeletal muscle remodeling through inflammation modulation? Possible mechanisms of action. J Nutr Metabol. 2012:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3321450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22536489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton LE, Layman DK. Leucine regulates translation initiation of protein synthesis in skeletal muscle after exercise. J Nutr. 2006;136:533&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, McClung HL, McClung JP, Margolis LM, Andersen NE, Cloutier GJ, Pikosky MA, Rood JC, Fielding RA, Young AJ. Leucine-enriched essential amino acid supplementation during moderate steady state exercise enhances postexercise muscle protein synthesis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2011;94:809&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa RG, Donato JR J, Pires IS, Tirapegui J. Leucine supplementation increases serum insulin-like growth factor 1 concentration and liver protein/ RNA ratio in rats after a period of nutritional recovery. Appl Phys Nutri Metab. 2013;38:694&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23724889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennings B, Boirie Y, Senden JMG, Gijsen AP, Kuipers H, Van Loon LJC. Whey protein stimulates postprandial muscle protein accretion more effectively than do casein and casein hydrolysate in older men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2011;93:997&#x2013;1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21367943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reitelseder S, Agergaard J, Doessing S, Helmark IC, Lund P, Kristensen NB, Frystyk J, Flyvbjerg A, Schjerling P, Van Hall G, Kjaer M, Holm L. Whey and casein labeled with l-{1-13C}leucine and muscle protein synthesis: effect of resistance exercise and protein ingestion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;300:231&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21045172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rommel C, Bodine SC, Clarke BA, Rossman R, Nunez L, Stitt TN, Yancopoulos GD, Glass DJ. Mediation of IGF-1-induced skeletal myotube hypertrophy by PI(3)k/Akt.mTOR and PI(3)K/AKT/GSK3 pathways. Nature. 2001;3:1009&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron RS. Correlation between myofibrillar APTase activity and myosin heavy chain composition in single human muscle fibers. Histochemistry. 1991;96:21&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1834618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tannerstedt J, Apro W, Blomstrand E. Maximal lengthening contractions induce different signaling responses in the type I and type II fibers of human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 2009;106:1412&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19112158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G, Georgiadis G, Stratakos G, Vogiatzis I, Kavouras S, Manta P, Mascher H, Blomstrand E. Resistance exercise induced increase in muscle mass correlates with p70s6 kinase phosphorylation in human subjects. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102:145&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17874120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G, Spengos K, Mascher H, Georgiadis G, Manta P, Blomstrand E. The degree of p70s6k and s6 phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle in response to resistance exercise depends on the training volume. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110:835&#x2013;843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20617335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuma JR, Gilders R, Werdun M, Loucks AB. Circadian rhythm of cortisol confounds cortisol response to exercise: implications for future research. J Appl. Physiol. 1995;78:1657&#x2013;1664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7649899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Mei S, Wang X, Li X, Liu R, Ma Y, Hao L, Yao P, Liu L, Sun X, Gu H, Liu Z, Cao W. Leucine facilitates insulin signaling through a G alpha I protein-dependent signaling pathway in hepatocytes. J Biol Chem. 2013;288:9313&#x2013;9320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3611002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23404499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshizawa F, Mochizuki S, Sugahara K. Differential dose response of mTOR signaling to oral administration of Leucine in skeletal muscle and liver of rats. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2013;77:839&#x2013;842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23563533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshizawa K. New therapeutic strategy for amino acid medicine: notable functions of branched chain amino acids as biological regulators. J Pharmacol Sci. 2012;118:149&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22293293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeanandin G, Balage M, Schneider SM, Dupont J, Hebuterne X, Mothe-Satney I, Dardevet D. Differential effect of long-term leucine supplementation on skeletal muscle and adipose tissue in old rats: an insulin signaling pathway approach. Ageing. 2012;34:371&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3312629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21472380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>