<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33417154</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Set Structure Manipulation on Chronic Adaptations to Resistance Training: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1061</StartPage><EndPage>1086</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1061-1086</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-020-01423-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The acute effects of resistance training (RT) set structure alteration are well established; however, less is known about their effects on chronic training adaptations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this systematic review and meta-analysis was to synthesise the available evidence on the effectiveness of traditional (TS), cluster (CS) and rest redistribution (RR) set structures in promoting chronic RT adaptations, and provide an overview of the factors which might differentially influence the magnitude of specific training adaptations between set structure types.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This review was performed using the PRISMA (Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses) guidelines encompassing the literature search of five databases. Studies in English that compared muscular strength, endurance, and/or hypertrophy adaptations, as well as vertical jump performance, velocity and power at submaximal loads and shifts in the slopes of force-velocity profiles between TS and CS or RR set structures (i.e., alternative set structures) were included. Risk of bias assessment was performed using a modified Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Random-effects meta-analyses and meta-regressions were performed where possible.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">17 studies met the inclusion criteria, none had more than one risk of bias item assessed as high risk. Pooled results revealed that none of the set structures were more effective at inducing strength (standardised mean difference (SMD)&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#xa0;0.06) or hypertrophy (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#xa0;0.03). TS were more effective at improving muscular endurance compared to alternative set structures (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#xa0;0.38), whereas alternative set structures tended to be more effective for vertical jump performance gains (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.13), but this effect was not statistically significant (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.190). Greater velocity and power outputs at submaximal loads (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.18) were observed when using alternative set structures compared to TS. In addition, alternative set structures promoted greater shifts of the slope of force-velocity profiles towards more velocity dominant profiles compared to TS (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.28). Sub-group analyses controlling for each alternative set structure independently showed mixed results likely caused by the relatively small number of studies available for some outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Modifying TS to an alternative set structure (CS or RR) has a negligible impact on strength and hypertrophy. Using CS and RR can lead to greater vertical jump performance, velocity and power at submaximal loads and shifts to more velocity dominant force-velocity profiles compared to training using TS. However, TS may provide more favourable effects on muscle endurance when compared to CS and RR. These findings demonstrate that altering TS to alternative set structures may influence the magnitude of specific muscular adaptations indicating set structure manipulation is an important consideration for RT program design.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PROTOCOL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The original protocol was prospectively registered (CRD42019138954) with the PROSPERO (International Prospective Register of Systematic Reviews).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jukic</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0900-9410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand. ivan.jukic@aut.ac.nz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Hooren</LastName><ForeName>Bas</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8163-693X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Movement Sciences, NUTRIM School of Nutrition and Translational Research in Metabolism, Maastricht University Medical Centre+, Maastricht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramos</LastName><ForeName>Amador Garc&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0608-8755</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Sciences and Physical Conditioning, Faculty of Education, Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de La Sant&#xed;sima Concepci&#xf3;n, Concepci&#xf3;n, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helms</LastName><ForeName>Eric R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGuigan</LastName><ForeName>Michael R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1251-7838</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tufano</LastName><ForeName>James J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8325-0344</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Biochemistry, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, Charles University, Prague, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000064" MajorTopicYN="N">Acclimatization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="N">Rest</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01423-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-020-01423-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1419&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: training considerations. Sports Med. 2018;48(4):765&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, French DN. Resistance training for health and performance. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2002;1(3):165&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12831709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Herring MP, Caravalho A. Mental health benefits of strength training in adults. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2010;4(5):377&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigenbaum MS, Pollock ML. Prescription of resistance training for health and disease. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(1):38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9927008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CJ, Latham NK. Progressive resistance strength training for improving physical function in older adults. Cochrane Datab Syst Rev. 2009;2009:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, Izquierdo M, Kraemer WJ, Peterson MD, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the national strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N, Alvar B, Evetoch T, Housh T, Kibler W, Kraemer W. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults [ACSM position stand]. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Krieger JW, Schoenfeld BJ. The effects of short versus long inter-set rest intervals in resistance training on measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(8):983&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28641044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, Lazinica B, Krieger JW, Pedisic Z. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(5):1207&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):137&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low-vs high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on dynamic muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(8):1603&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(12):2585&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28755103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5684266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Brown LE, Haff GG. Theoretical and practical aspects of different cluster set structures: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(3):848&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga EM, Pareja-Blanco F. Maximal intended velocity training induces greater gains in bench press performance than deliberately slower half-velocity training. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(8):772&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24734902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga E, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo J. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on neuromuscular performance. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(11):916&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padulo J, Mignogna P, Mignardi S, Tonni F, Dottavio S. Effect of different pushing speeds on bench press. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33(05):376&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L. Movement velocity as a measure of loading intensity in resistance training. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31(05):347&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20180176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Ya&#xf1;ez-Garc&#xed;a JM, Mora-Custodio R, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D. Velocity loss as a variable for monitoring resistance exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2017;38(03):217&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28192832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Su&#xe1;rez-Arrones L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on performance in professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(4):512&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27618386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(9):1725&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Andrews RJ, West DW, Little JP, Cochran AJ, Hector AJ, et al. Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub-fractional synthetic responses in men. J Physiol. 2012;590(2):351&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22106173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamad NI, Cronin JB, Nosaka KK. Difference in kinematics and kinetics between high-and low-velocity resistance loading equated by volume: implications for hypertrophy training. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(1):269&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy J, Oliver J, McCleary S, Lowery R, Wilson J. Power output and electromyography activity of the back squat exercise with cluster sets. J Sports Sci. 2013;1:37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, Davis L, Avela J, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Neuromuscular fatigue during dynamic maximal strength and hypertrophic resistance loadings. J Electromyogr Kines. 2012;22(3):356&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Saeterbakken A. Effect of fatigue upon performance and electromyographic activity in 6-RM bench press. J Hum Kinet. 2014;40(1):57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4096084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute hormonal and neuromuscular responses and recovery to forced vs maximum repetitions multiple resistance exercises. Int J Sports Med. 2003;24(6):410&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12905088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, Hakkinen K. Acute hormonal responses to heavy resistance exercise in strength athletes versus nonathletes. Can J Appl Physiol. 2004;29(5):527&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15507691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaulley GO, McBride JM, Cormie P, Hudson MB, Nuzzo JL, Quindry JC, et al. Acute hormonal and neuromuscular responses to hypertrophy, strength and power type resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;105(5):695&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19066934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer W. Designing resistance training programs, 4E. Human Kinetics; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drinkwater EJ, Lawton TW, Lindsell RP, Pyne DB, Hunt PH, Mckenna MJ. Training leading to repetition failure enhances bench press strength gains in elite junior athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(2):382&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawton T, Cronin J, Drinkwater E, Lindsell R, Pyne D. The effect of continuous repetition training and intra-set rest training on bench press strength and power. J Sport Med Phys Fit. 2004;44(4):361&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(6):955&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sooneste H, Tanimoto M, Kakigi R, Saga N, Katamoto S. Effects of training volume on strength and hypertrophy in young men. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(1):8&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23249767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun RJ, Gai CM, Aguilar D, Bove D, Dolan J, Vargas A, et al. Training volume, not frequency, indicative of maximal strength adaptations to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(5):1207&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29324578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Sanchis-Moysi J, Dorado C, Mora-Custodio R, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(7):724&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27038416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as J, Cornejo-Daza PJ, Piqueras-Sanchiz F, Mora-Vela R, et al. Velocity loss as a critical variable determining the adaptations to strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000002295 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000002295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32049887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, Cornejo-Daza PJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as J, Rodriguez-Lopez C, Hidalgo-de Mora J, et al. Effects of velocity loss in the bench press exercise on strength gains, neuromuscular adaptations and muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.13775 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32949027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orange ST, Metcalfe JW, Robinson A, Applegarth MJ, Liefeith A. Effects of in-season velocity-versus percentage-based training in academy rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;15(4):554&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen KT, Cronin JB, Pickering SL, Newton MJ. Does cluster loading enhance lower body power development in preseason preparation of elite rugby union players? J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(8):2118&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Hobbs RT, Haff EE, Sands WA, Pierce KC, Stone MH. Cluster training: a novel method for introducing training program variation. Strength Cond J. 2008;30(1):67&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, Brown LE, Petkovic A, Frick J, et al. Effects of cluster sets and rest-redistribution on mechanical responses to back squats in trained men. J Hum Kinet. 2017;58(1):35&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28828076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5548153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, Brown LE, Seitz LB, Williamson BD, et al. Maintenance of velocity and power with cluster sets during high-volume back squats. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(7):885&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, Oliver JM, Kreutzer A, Haff GG. Different cluster sets result in similar metabolic, endocrine, and perceptual responses in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(2):346&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28301435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrigan JJ, Tufano JJ, Oliver JM, White JB, Fields JB, Jones MT. Reducing the loss of velocity and power in women athletes via rest redistribution. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15(2):255&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31188704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Kreutzer A, Jenke SC, Phillips MD, Mitchell JB, Jones MT. Velocity drives greater power observed during back squat using cluster sets. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(1):235&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Artacho AJ, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Padial P, Gomez AM, Peinado AM, P&#xe9;rez-C&#xf3;rdoba JL, Feriche B. Muscle activation during power-oriented resistance training: continuous vs cluster set configurations. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:95&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denton J, Cronin JB. Kinematic, kinetic, and blood lactate profiles of continuous and intraset rest loading schemes. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):528&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Carballeira E, S&#xe1;nchez-Otero T, Mayo X, Jim&#xe9;nez A, Chapman ML. Acute effects of distribution of rest between repetitions. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33(5):351&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo X, Iglesias-Soler E, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Del-Olmo M. Effects of set configuration of resistance exercise on perceived exertion. Percept Mot Skills. 2014;119(3):825&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25456248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo X, Iglesias-Soler E, Kingsley JD. Perceived exertion is affected by the submaximal set configuration used in resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(2):426&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28277430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Ramos AG, Helms ER, McGuigan MR, Tufano JJ. Acute effects of cluster and rest redistribution set structures on mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual fatigue during and after resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50(12):2209&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32901442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Jagim AR, Sanchez AC, Mardock MA, Kelly KA, Meredith HJ, et al. Greater gains in strength and power with intraset rest intervals in hypertrophic training. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(11):3116&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23736782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson G, Ispoglou T, Bissas A. The impact of repetition mechanics on the adaptations resulting from strength-, hypertrophy-and cluster-type resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(10):1875&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27473446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5020128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas-Aburto J, Jukic I, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Janicijevic D, Barboza-Gonz&#xe1;lez P, Chirosa-R&#xed;os LJ, et al. Effect of resistance-training programs differing in set configuration on maximal strength and explosive-action performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2019-1005 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-1005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32957077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi A, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R. Effects of cluster vs. traditional plyometric training sets on maximal-intensity exercise performance. Med (Kaunas, Lithuania). 2016;52(1):41&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carneiro MA, de Oliveira J&#xfa;nior GN, de Sousa JF, Santagnello SB, Souza MV, Orsatti FL. Effects of cluster training sets on muscle power and force&#x2013;velocity relationship in postmenopausal women. Sport Sci Health. 2019;2019:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Halaki M, Orr R, Helms ER, Hackett DA. Changes in bench press velocity and power after 8 weeks of high-load cluster- or traditional-set structures. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(10):2734&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Mayo X, Rio-Rodriguez D, Carballeira E, Farinas J, Fernandez-Del-Olmo M. Inter-repetition rest training and traditional set configuration produce similar strength gains without cortical adaptations. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(15):1473&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26630355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25554246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">25554246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3196245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JR, Van Hooren B, Bishop C, Buckley JD, Willy RW, Fuller JT. A systematic review and meta-analysis of crossover studies comparing physiological, perceptual and performance measures between treadmill and overground running. Sports Med. 2019;49(5):763&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30847825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins D, Best D, Briss P, Eccles M, Falck-Ytter Y, Flottorp S, et al. Grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2004;328(7454):1490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer G, Carpenter JR, R&#xfc;cker G. Meta-analysis with R. Berlin: Springer; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Softw. 2010;36(3):1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria. 2018. https://www.R-project.org/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veroniki AA, Jackson D, Viechtbauer W, Bender R, Bowden J, Knapp G, et al. Methods to estimate the between-study variance and its uncertainty in meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2016;7(1):55&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu R, Gartlehner G, Grant M, Shamliyan T, Sedrakyan A, Wilt TJ, et al. Conducting quantitative synthesis when comparing medical interventions: AHRQ and the Effective Health Care Program. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(11):1187&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21477993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Egger M, Moher D. Chapter 10: Addressing reporting biases. In: Higgins JPT, Green S, editors. Conchrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. Chichester: Wiley; 2008. p. 297&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker BJ. Synthesizing standardized mean-change measures. Brit J Math Stat Psy. 1988;41(2):257&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods. 2008;11(2):364&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Distribution of the standardized mean change effect size for meta-analysis on repeated measures. Brit J Math Stat Psy. 2000;53(1):17&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The concepts of power analysis. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Hillsdale: L. Erlbaum Associates; 1988. p. 1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB, DeShon RP. Combining effect size estimates in meta-analysis with repeated measures and independent-groups designs. Psychol methods. 2002;7(1):105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11928886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR. Introduction to meta-analysis. Amsterdan: Wiley; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias RKN, Penna EM, Noronha ASN, de Azevedo ABC, Barbalho M, Gentil PV, et al. Cluster-sets resistance training induce similar functional and strength improvements than the traditional method in postmenopausal and elderly women. Exp Gerontol. 2020;138:111011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fari&#xf1;as J, Mayo X, Giraldez-Garc&#xed;a MA, Carballeira E, Fernandez-Del-Olmo M, Rial-Vazquez J, et al. Set configuration in strength training programs modulates the cross education phenomenon. J Strength Cond Res. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000003189 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000003189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31136543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Haff GG, Padial P, Feriche B. Reliability of power and velocity variables collected during the traditional and ballistic bench press exercise. Sports Biomech. 2018;17(1):117&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28632056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Malecek J, Omcirk D, Tufano JJ. Magnitude and reliability of velocity and power variables during deadlifts performed with and without lifting straps. J Strength Cond Res. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000003608 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000003608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33298711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter EM, Abt G, Brookes FC, Challis JH, Fowler NE, Knudson DV, et al. Misuse of &#x201c;power&#x201d; and other mechanical terms in sport and exercise science research. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(1):292&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26529527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Alonso A, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Cepero M, Miras-Moreno S, Rojas FJ, P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A. Effect of augmented feedback on velocity performance during strength-oriented and power-oriented resistance training sessions. J Strength Cond Res. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000003705 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000003705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32639379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banyard HG, Nosaka K, Haff GG. Reliability and validity of the load&#x2013;velocity relationship to predict the 1RM back squat. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(7):1897&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27669192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Fernandez-del-Olmo M, Mayo X, Farinas J, Rio-Rodriguez D, Carballeira E, et al. Changes in the force-velocity mechanical profile after short resistance training programs differing in set configurations. J Appl Biomech. 2017;33(2):144&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113(1):71&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3404827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney KJ, Herbert RD, Balnave RD. Fatigue contributes to the strength training stimulus. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1994;26(9):1160&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7808251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rial-V&#xe1;zquez J, Mayo X, Tufano JJ, Fari&#xf1;as J, R&#xfa;a-Alonso M, Iglesias-Soler E. Cluster vs traditional training programmes: changes in the force&#x2013;velocity relationship. Sports Biomech. 2020;2020:1&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1080/14763141.2020.1718197 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2020.1718197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Artacho AJ, Padial P, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Feriche B. Influence of a cluster set configuration on the adaptations to short-term power training. J Strength Cond Res. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000001925 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29570595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas-Aburto J, Jukic I, Chirosa-R&#xed;os LJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez Hern&#xe1;ndez J, Janicijevic D, Barboza-Gonz&#xe1;lez P, et al. Effect of traditional, cluster, and rest redistribution set configurations on neuromuscular and perceptual responses during strength-oriented resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000003658 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000003658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32569130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, West DW, Staples AW, Cain NE, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol. 2010;588(16):3119&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2956949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J. Does training to failure maximize muscle hypertrophy? Strength Cond J. 2019;41(5):108&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Teo W-P, Drinkwater EJ, Kendall K, Haff GG. The acute neuromuscular responses to cluster set resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49(12):1861&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31506904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6851217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther B, Cronin J, Keogh J. Possible stimuli for strength and power adaptation. Sports Med. 2005;35(11):967&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16271010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Riek S, Carson RG. Neural adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 2001;31(12):829&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mouser JG, Loenneke JP. Practicing the test produces strength equivalent to higher volume training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(9):1945&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2000;81(3):174&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10638374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm D, Sale D. Velocity specificity of resistance training. Sports Med. 1993;15(6):374&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8341872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8341872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamori N, Newton RU. Velocity specificity of resistance training: actual movement velocity versus intention to move explosively. Strength Cond J. 2006;28(2):86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE. Isokinetics in human performance. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle EF, Feiring D, Rotkis T, Cote R 3rd, Roby F, Lee W, et al. Specificity of power improvements through slow and fast isokinetic training. J Appl Physiol. 1981;51(6):1437&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7319877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;mmel J, Kramer A, Giboin L-S, Gruber M. Specificity of balance training in healthy individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(9):1261&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26993132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giboin L-S, Gruber M, Kramer A. Six weeks of balance or power training induce no generalizable improvements in balance performance in healthy young adults. BMC Sports Sci Med R. 2019;11(1):31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Meur Y, Hausswirth C, Mujika I. Tapering for competition: a review. Sci Sports. 2012;27(2):77&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyne DB, Mujika I, Reilly T. Peaking for optimal performance: Research limitations and future directions. J Sports Sci. 2009;27(3):195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. Improving vertical jump performance through general, special, and specific strength training. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10:131&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT, editors. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. 4th ed. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Carballeira E, Sanchez-Otero T, Mayo X, Fernandez-Del-Olmo M. Performance of maximum number of repetitions with cluster-set configuration. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(4):637&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24154989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias E, Boullosa DA, Dopico X, Carballeira E. Analysis of factors that influence the maximum number of repetitions in two upper-body resistance exercises: curl biceps and bench press. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(6):1566&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20508460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, Brown LE, Banyard HG, Williamson BD, et al. Cluster sets: permitting greater mechanical stress without decreasing relative velocity. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(4):463&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27617387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Carballeira E, S&#xe1;nchez-Otero T, Mayo X, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Del-Olmo M. Performance of maximum number of repetitions with cluster-set configuration. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9(4):637&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24154989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Lawrence MM, Zwetsloot KA, Triplett NT, Utter AC, McBride JM. Effect of cluster set configurations on power clean technique. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(5):488&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23121475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper DR, Szivak TK, Comstock BA, Dunn-Lewis C, Apicella JM, Kelly NA, et al. Effects of fatigue from resistance training on barbell back squat biomechanics. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(4):1127&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowley JC, Gates DH. Inter-joint coordination changes during and after muscle fatigue. Hum Movement Sci. 2017;56:109&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xf4;t&#xe9; JN, Mathieu PA, Levin MF, Feldman AG. Movement reorganization to compensate for fatigue during sawing. Exp Brain Res. 2002;146(3):394&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12232697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone JD, King AC, Goto S, Mata JD, Hannon J, Garrison JC, et al. Joint-level analyses of the back squat with and without intraset rest. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(5):583&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30427251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Comfort P, Stone MH. Weightlifting pulling derivatives: Rationale for implementation and application. Sports Medicine. 2015;45(6):823&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25689955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh CE, Thomas HJ, Naylor LH, Scurrah KJ, Green DJ. Fitness and strength responses to distinct exercise modes in twins: Studies of twin responses to understand exercise as a therapy (STRUETH) study. J Physiol. 2020;598(18):3845&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32567679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Tufano JJ. Rest redistribution functions as a free and ad-hoc equivalent to commonly used velocity-based training thresholds during clean pulls at different loads. J Hum Kinet. 2019;68:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31531129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6724594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Halaj M, Kampmiller T, Novosad A, Buzgo G. Cluster sets vs traditional sets: levelling out the playing field using a power-based threshold. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(11):e0208035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30475910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6257924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamble P. Periodization of training for team sports athletes. Strength Cond J. 2006;28(5):56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Abad-Herencia JL, del Ojo-L&#xf3;pez JJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L. Effects of velocity-based resistance training on young soccer players of different ages. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(5):1329&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25486303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>