<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25713674</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>44</Volume><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Questioning the Resistance/Aerobic Training Dichotomy: A commentary on physiological adaptations determined by effort rather than exercise modality.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>137</StartPage><EndPage>142</EndPage><MedlinePgn>137-42</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2014-0119</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper discusses and challenges the current opinion that exercise adaptation is generally defined by modality; resistance exercise (RE), or aerobic exercise (AE). In presenting a strong body of recent research which demonstrably challenges these perceptions we suggest alternate hypotheses towards physiological adaptation which is hinged more upon the effort than the exercise modality. Practical implications of this interpretation of exercise adaptation might effect change in exercise adherence since existing barriers to exercise of time, costs, specialized equipment, etc. become nullified. In presenting the evidence herein we suggest that lay persons wishing to attain the health and fitness (including strength and muscle hypertrophy) benefits of exercise can choose from a wide range of potential exercise modalities so long as the effort is high. Future research should consider this hypothesis by directly comparing RE and AE for acute responses and chronic adaptations.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fisher</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health Exercise and Sport Science, Southampton Solent University, East Park Terrace, Southampton UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steele</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health Exercise and Sport Science, Southampton Solent University, East Park Terrace, Southampton UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training, exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4327364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jhk-44-137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli R. The Size Principle and a Critical Analysis of the Unsubstantiated Heavier-is-better Recommendation for Resistance Training. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2008;6:67&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daskapan A, Tuzun EH, Eker L. Perceived barriers to physical activity in university students. J Sci Med Sport. 2006;5:615&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3861763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24357957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards RHT. Biochemical bases of fatigue in exercise performance: catastrophe theory of muscle fatigue. In: Porter R, Whelan J, editors. Biochemistry of Exercise. London: Pitman Medical; 1981. pp. 1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Smith D. Attempting to better define intensity for muscular performance; is it all wasted effort? Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(12):4183&#x2013;4185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. Evidence-Based Resistance Training Recommendations. Med Sport. 2011;15:147&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. Evidence-Based Resistance Training Recommendations for Muscular Hypertrophy. Med Sport. 2013;17:217&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitts RH. Cellular Mechanisms of Muscle Fatigue. Physiol Reviews. 1994;74(1):49&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8295935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, Little JP, MacDonald MJ, Hawley JA. Physiological adaptations to low-volume, high-intensity interval training in health and disease. J Physiol. 2012;590:1077&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez-Lopez M, Gallegos AG, Extermera AB. Perceived barriers by university students in the practice of physical activities. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;9:374&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harber MP, Konopka AR, Douglass MD, Minchev K, Kaminsky LA, Trappe TA, Trappe S. Aerobic exercise training improves whole muscle and single myofiber size and function in older women. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2009;297:R1452&#x2013;R1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3774188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19692660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henritze J, Weltman A, Schurrer RL, Barlow K. Effects of training at and above the lactate threshold on the lactate threshold and maximal oxygen uptake. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1985;54:84&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4018061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jungblut S. The correct interpretation of the size principle and its practical application to resistance training. Med Sport. 2009;13:203&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimm SY, Glynn NW, McMahon RP, Voorhees CC, Striegel-Moore RH, Daniels SR. Self-perceived barriers to activity participation among sedentary adolescent girls. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2006;38:534&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16540842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konopka AR, Harber MP. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy after aerobic exercise training. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2014;42:53&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4523889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Gustafsson T, Tesch PA. Aerobic exercise does not compromise muscle hypertrophy response to short-term resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2013;114:81&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Yoshitake Y, Takai Y, Fukunaga T, Kanehisa H. Neuromuscular adaptations following 12-week maximal voluntary co-contraction training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;114:663&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24368554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormack G, Giles-Corti B, Lange A, Smith T, Martin K, Pikora TJ. An update of recent evidence of the relationship between objective and self-report measures of the physical environment and physical activity behaviours. J Sci Med Sport. 2004;7:81&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15214606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:71&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Low-load bench press training to fatigue results in muscle hypertrophy similar to high-load bench press training. Int J Clin Med. 2013;4:114&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Winett RA. Uncomplicated Resistance Training and Health-Related Outcomes: Evidence for a public health mandate. Curr Sports Med Rev. 2010;9:208&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4086449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis JF, Prochanska JJ, Taylor WC. A review of correlates of physical activity of children and adolescents. Med Sci Sports Exer. 2000;32:963&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10795788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The Mechanisms of Muscle Hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2857&#x2013;2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J. Intensity; in-ten-si-ty; noun. 1. Often used ambiguously within resistance training. 2. Is it time to drop the term altogether? Br J Sports Med. 2013;00:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23403526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J. Scientific Rigour: a Heavy or Light Load to Carry? Sports Med. 2014;44:141&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24421051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, McGuff D, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. Resistance Training to Momentary Muscular Failure Improves Cardiovascular Fitness in Humans: A Review of Acute Physiological responses and Chronic Adaptations. J Exerc Phys. 2012;15:53&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Delecluse C, Coudyzer W, Boonen S, Bautmans I. Strength training at high versus low external resistance in older adults: Effects on muscle volume, muscle strength, and force-velocity characteristics. Exp Gerontol. 2013;48(11):1351&#x2013;1361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23999311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weltman A, Seip RL, Snead D, Weltman JY, Haskvitz EM, Evans WS, Veldhuis JD, Rogol AD. Exercise Training at and above the Lactate Threshold in Previously Untrained Women. Int J Sports Med. 1992;13:257&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1601562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>