<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">21643920</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-6327</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>111</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of applied physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Appl Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neural adaptations to electrical stimulation strength training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2439</StartPage><EndPage>2449</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2439-49</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00421-011-2012-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This review provides evidence for the hypothesis that electrostimulation strength training (EST) increases the force of a maximal voluntary contraction (MVC) through neural adaptations in healthy skeletal muscle. Although electrical stimulation and voluntary effort activate muscle differently, there is substantial evidence to suggest that EST modifies the excitability of specific neural paths and such adaptations contribute to the increases in MVC force. Similar to strength training with voluntary contractions, EST increases MVC force after only a few sessions with some changes in muscle biochemistry but without overt muscle hypertrophy. There is some mixed evidence for spinal neural adaptations in the form of an increase in the amplitude of the interpolated twitch and in the amplitude of the volitional wave, with less evidence for changes in spinal excitability. Cross-sectional and exercise studies also suggest that the barrage of sensory and nociceptive inputs acts at the cortical level and can modify the motor cortical output and interhemispheric paths. The data suggest that neural adaptations mediate initial increases in MVC force after short-term EST.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hortob&#xe1;gyi</LastName><ForeName>Tibor</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Human Movement Sciences, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, The Netherlands. Hortobagyit@ecu.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maffiuletti</LastName><ForeName>Nicola A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Appl Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100954790</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1439-6319</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004558" MajorTopicYN="N">Electric Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21643920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3175340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2012-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Neural adaptation to resistance training: changes in evoked V-wave and H-reflex responses. J Appl Physiol. 2002;92:2309&#x2013;2318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12015341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya T, Bajwa S, Edgley SA. Crossed reflex actions from group II muscle afferents in the lumbar spinal cord of the anaesthetized cat. J Physiol. 1991;444:117&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1179924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1822547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin ER, Klakowicz PM, Collins DF. Wide-pulse-width, high-frequency neuromuscular stimulation: implications for functional electrical stimulation. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:228&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16627680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bax L, Staes F, Verhagen A. Does neuromuscular electrical stimulation strengthen the quadriceps femoris? A systematic review of randomised controlled trials. Sports Med. 2005;35:191&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15730336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergquist AJ, Clair JM, Lagerquist O, Mang CS, Okuma Y, Collins DF (2011) Neuromuscular electrical stimulation: implications of the electrically-evoked sensory volley. Eur J Appl Physiol (in press)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21805156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezerra P, Zhou S, Crowley Z, Brooks L, Hooper A. Effects of unilateral electromyostimulation superimposed on voluntary training on strength and cross-sectional area. Muscle Nerve. 2009;40:430&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19705423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blickenstorfer A, Kleiser R, Keller T, Keisker B, Meyer M, Riener R, Kollias S. Cortical and subcortical correlates of functional electrical stimulation of wrist extensor and flexor muscles revealed by fMRI. Hum Brain Mapp. 2009;30:963&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6870950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18344193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie F, Babault N, Cometti G, Maffiuletti N, Chatard JC. Electrostimulation training effects on the physical performance of ice hockey players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:455&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15741845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabric M, Appell HJ. Effect of electrical stimulation of high and low frequency on maximum isometric force and some morphological characteristics in men. Int J Sports Med. 1987;8:256&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3667021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabric M, Appell HJ, Resic A. Effects of electrical stimulation of different frequencies on the myonuclei and fiber size in human muscle. Int J Sports Med. 1987;8:323&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3679646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Riek S, Carson RG. Neural adaptations to resistance training: implications for movement control. Sports Med. 2001;31:829&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Riek S, Carson RG. The sites of neural adaptation induced by resistance training in humans. J Physiol. 2002;544:641&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12381833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Selvanayagam VS, Riek S, Semmler JG. Neural adaptations to strength training: moving beyond TMS and reflex studies. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2011;202(2):119&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21382178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavallari P, Fournier E, Katz R, Malmgren K, Pierrot-Deseilligny E, Shindo M. Cutaneous facilitation of transmission in Ib reflex pathways in the human upper limb. Exp Brain Res. 1985;60:197&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4043278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XY, Chen Y, Wang Y, Thompson A, Carp JS, Segal RL, Wolpaw JR (2010) Reflex conditioning: a new strategy for improving motor function after spinal cord injury. Ann NY Acad Sci 1198 Suppl 1: E12&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2925434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20590534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie A, Kamen G. Short-term training adaptations in maximal motor unit firing rates and afterhyperpolarization duration. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:651&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19941348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins DF. Central contributions to contractions evoked by tetanic neuromuscular electrical stimulation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2007;35:102&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17620928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins DF, Burke D, Gandevia SC. Sustained contractions produced by plateau-like behaviour in human motoneurones. J Physiol. 2002;538:289&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colson SS, Martin A, Van Hoecke J. Effects of electromyostimulation versus voluntary isometric training on elbow flexor muscle strength. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2009;19:311&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18621547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa A, Dalloul H, Hegyesi H, Apor P, Csende Z, Racz L, Vaczi M, Tihanyi J. Impact of repeated bouts of eccentric exercise on myogenic gene expression. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101:427&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17641910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Haan A, Gerrits KHL, de Ruiter CJ. Counterpoint: the interpolated twitch does not provide a valid measure of the voluntary activation of muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:355&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19567806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Balso C, Cafarelli E. Adaptations in the activation of human skeletal muscle induced by short-term isometric resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103:402&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17446407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dragert K, Zehr EP. Bilateral neuromuscular plasticity from unilateral training of the ankle dorsiflexors. Exp Brain Res. 2011;208:217&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21069308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Hainaut K. Training effects of sub-maximal electrostimulation in a human muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20:99&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3343922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclay J, Martin A, Robbe A, Pousson M. Spinal reflex plasticity during maximal dynamic contractions after eccentric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:722&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18317371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM. Muscle strength and its development. New perspectives. Sports Med. 1988;6:146&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3055145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation: what is activated? In: Rainoldi A, Minetto MA, Merletti R, editors. Biomedical engineering in exercise and sports. Torino: Edizioni Minerva Medica; 2006. pp. 181&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson E, Haggmark T, Kiessling KH, Karlsson J. Effect of electrical stimulation on human skeletal muscle. Int J Sports Med. 1981;2:18&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7333731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everaert DG, Thompson AK, Chong SL, Stein RB. Does functional electrical stimulation for foot drop strengthen corticospinal connections? Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2010;24:168&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19861590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Holobar A, Merletti R, Enoka RM. Decoding the neural drive to muscles from the surface electromyogram. Clin Neurophysiol. 2010;121:1616&#x2013;1623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20444646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP. Cross-education of strength depends on limb dominance: implications for theory and application. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2009;37:179&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19955867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Krentz JR, Magnus CRA, Barss TS, Lanovaz JL, Cummine J, Esopenko C, Sarty GE, Borowsky R (2011) Changes in fMRI cortical activation with cross-education to an immobilized limb. Med Sci Sports Exerc (in press)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fimland MS, Helgerud J, Solstad GM, Iversen VM, Leivseth G, Hoff J. Neural adaptations underlying cross-education after unilateral strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:723&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19756705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald GK, Delitto A. Neuromuscular electrical stimualtion for muscle strength training. In: Rainoldi A, Minetto MA, Merletti R, editors. Biomedical engineering in exercise and sports. Torino: Edizioni Minerva Medica; 2006. pp. 199&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis S, Lin X, Aboushoushah S, White TP, Phillips M, Bowtell R, Constantinescu CS. fMRI analysis of active, passive and electrically stimulated ankle dorsiflexion. Neuroimage. 2009;44:469&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18950717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel DA, Kamen G, Frost G. Neural adaptations to resistive exercise: mechanisms and recommendations for training practices. Sports Med. 2006;36:133&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16464122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glinsky J, Harvey L, van Es P, Chee S, Gandevia SC. The addition of electrical stimulation to progressive resistance training does not enhance the wrist strength of people with tetraplegia: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2009;23:696&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19470552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golaszewski SM, Bergmann J, Christova M, Nardone R, Kronbichler M, Rafolt D, Gallasch E, Staffen W, Ladurner G, Beisteiner R. Increased motor cortical excitability after whole-hand electrical stimulation: a TMS study. Clin Neurophysiol. 2010;121:248&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20036618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gondin J, Guette M, Ballay Y, Martin A. Electromyostimulation training effects on neural drive and muscle architecture. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1291&#x2013;1299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16118574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gondin J, Duclay J, Martin A. Soleus- and gastrocnemii-evoked V-wave responses increase after neuromuscular electrical stimulation training. J Neurophysiol. 2006;95:3328&#x2013;3335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16481458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gondin J, Brocca L, Bellinzona E, D&#x2019;Antona G, Maffiuletti NA, Miotti D, Pellegrino MA, Bottinelli R. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation training induces atypical adaptations of the human skeletal muscle phenotype: a functional and proteomic analysis. J Appl Physiol. 2011;110:433&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21127206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory CM, Bickel CS. Recruitment patterns in human skeletal muscle during electrical stimulation. Phys Ther. 2005;85:358&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15794706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber M, Taube W, Gollhofer A, Beck S, Amtage F, Schubert M. Training-specific adaptations of H- and stretch reflexes in human soleus muscle. J Mot Behav. 2007;39:68&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17251172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han BS, Jang SH, Chang Y, Byun WM, Lim SK, Kang DS. Functional magnetic resonance image finding of cortical activation by neuromuscular electrical stimulation on wrist extensor muscles. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;82:17&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12510180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, DeVita P. Favorable neuromuscular and cardiovascular responses to 7&#xa0;days of exercise with an eccentric overload in elderly women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2000;55:B401&#x2013;B410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10952362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Lambert J, Scott K. Incomplete muscle activation after training with electromyostimulation. Can J Appl Physiol. 1998;23:261&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9615868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Scott K, Lambert J, Hamilton G, Tracy J. Cross-education of muscle strength is greater with stimulated than voluntary contractions. Mot Control. 1999;3:205&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Devita P, Money J, Barrier J. Effects of standard and eccentric overload strength training in young women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1206&#x2013;1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Taylor JL, Russell G, Petersen N, Gandevia SC. Changes in segmental and motor cortical output with contralateral muscle contractions and altered sensory inputs in humans. J Neurophysiol. 2003;90:2451&#x2013;2459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14534271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Richardson SP, Lomarev M, Shamim E, Meunier S, Russman H, Dang N, Hallett M. Chronic low-frequency rTMS of primary motor cortex diminishes exercise training-induced gains in maximal voluntary force in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:403&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2644240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19008488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Richardson SP, Lomarev M, Shamim E, Meunier S, Russman H, Dang N, Hallett M (2011) Interhemispheric plasticity in humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc (in press)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4137570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21200340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard JD, Enoka RM. Maximum bilateral contractions are modified by neurally mediated interlimb effects. J Appl Physiol. 1991;70:306&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2010386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang LP, Zhou S, Lu Z, Tian Q, Li X, Cao LJ, Yu JH, Wang H. Bilateral effect of unilateral electroacupuncture on muscle strength. J Altern Complement Med. 2007;13:539&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17604558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvis JC, Mokrusch T, Kwende MM, Sutherland H, Salmons S. Fast-to-slow transformation in stimulated rat muscle. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19:1469&#x2013;1475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8874405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubeau M, Zory R, Gondin J, Martin A, Maffiuletti NA. Late neural adaptations to electrostimulation resistance training of the plantar flexor muscles. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;98:202&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16944193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubeau M, Gondin J, Martin A, Van Hoecke J, Maffiuletti NA. Differences in twitch potentiation between voluntary and stimulated quadriceps contractions of equal intensity. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19602194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaelin-Lang A, Luft AR, Sawaki L, Burstein AH, Sohn YH, Cohen LG. Modulation of human corticomotor excitability by somatosensory input. J Physiol. 2002;540:623&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11956348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall TL, Black CD, Elder CP, Gorgey A, Dudley GA. Determining the extent of neural activation during maximal effort. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38:1470&#x2013;1475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16888461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent-Braun JA, Le Blanc R. Quantitation of central activation failure during maximal voluntary contractions in humans. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19:861&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8965840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaslavskaia S, Sinkjaer T. Motor cortex excitability following repetitive electrical stimulation of the common peroneal nerve depends on the voluntary drive. Exp Brain Res. 2005;162:497&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15702321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CK, Takala TE, Seger J, Karpakka J. Training effects of electrically induced dynamic contractions in human quadriceps muscle. Aviat Space Environ Med. 1995;66:251&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7661836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimberley TJ, Lewis SM, Auerbach EJ, Dorsey LL, Lojovich JM, Carey JR. Electrical stimulation driving functional improvements and cortical changes in subjects with stroke. Exp Brain Res. 2004;154:450&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14618287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klakowicz PM, Baldwin ER, Collins DF. Contribution of M-waves and H-reflexes to contractions evoked by tetanic nerve stimulation in humans. J Neurophysiol. 2006;96:1293&#x2013;1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16611843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klass M, Baudry S, Duchateau J. Voluntary activation during maximal contraction with advancing age: a brief review. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100:543&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16763836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagerquist O, Zehr EP, Docherty D. Increased spinal reflex excitability is not associated with neural plasticity underlying the cross-education effect. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16357081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langzam E, Nemirovsky Y, Isakov E, Mizrahi J. Partition between volitional and induced forces in electrically augmented dynamic isometric muscle contractions. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2006;14:322&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17009492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langzam E, Nemirovsky Y, Isakov E, Mizrahi J. Muscle enhancement using closed-loop electrical stimulation: volitional versus induced torque. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2007;17:275&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16690326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Hinder MR, Gandevia SC, Carroll TJ. The ipsilateral motor cortex contributes to cross-limb transfer of performance gains after ballistic motor practice. J Physiol. 2010;588:201&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19917563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber RL, Silva PD, Daniel DM. Equal effectiveness of electrical and volitional strength training for quadriceps femoris muscles after anterior cruciate ligament surgery. J Orthop Res. 1996;14:131&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8618155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd T, De Domenico G, Strauss GR, Singer K. A review of the use of electro-motor stimulation in human muscles. Aust J Physiother. 1986;32:18&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25026318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA. Physiological and methodological considerations for the use of neuromuscular electrical stimulation. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110:223&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20473619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Pensini M, Martin A. Activation of human plantar flexor muscles increases after electromyostimulation training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;92:1383&#x2013;1392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11896001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Pensini M, Scaglioni G, Ferri A, Ballay Y, Martin A. Effect of electromyostimulation training on soleus and gastrocnemii H- and T-reflex properties. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;90:601&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12923640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin L, Cometti G, Pousson M, Morlon B. Effect of electrical stimulation training on the contractile characteristics of the triceps surae muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1993;67:457&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8299618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin L, Cometti G, Pousson M, Morlon B. The influence of electrostimulation on mechanical and morphological characteristics of the triceps surae. J Sports Sci. 1994;12:377&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7932948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMiken DF, Todd-Smith M, Thompson C. Strengthening of human quadriceps muscles by cutaneous electrical stimulation. Scand J Rehabil Med. 1983;15:25&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6828830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merton P. Voluntary strength and muscle fatigue. J Physiol. 1954;123:553&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1366225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13152698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nudo RJ, Plautz EJ, Frost SB. Role of adaptive plasticity in recovery of function after damage to motor cortex. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:1000&#x2013;1019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11439375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuhr M, Crevenna R, Gohlsch B, Bittner C, Pleiner J, Wiesinger G, Fialka-Moser V, Quittan M, Pette D. Functional and biochemical properties of chronically stimulated human skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89:202&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogino M, Shiba N, Maeda T, Iwasa K, Tagawa Y, Matsuo S, Nishimura H, Yamamoto T, Nagata K, Basford JR. MRI quantification of muscle activity after volitional exercise and neuromuscular electrical stimulation. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2002;81:446&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12023602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillard T, Noe F, Passelergue P, Dupui P. Electrical stimulation superimposed onto voluntary muscular contraction. Sports Med. 2005;35:951&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16271009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillard T, Margnes E, Maitre J, Chaubet V, Francois Y, Jully JL, Gonzalez G, Borel L. Electrical stimulation superimposed onto voluntary muscular contraction reduces deterioration of both postural control and quadriceps femoris muscle strength. Neuroscience. 2010;165:1471&#x2013;1475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19958816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez M, Lucia A, Rivero JL, Serrano AL, Calbet JA, Delgado MA, Chicharro JL. Effects of transcutaneous short-term electrical stimulation on M.vastus lateralis characteristics of healthy young men. Pflugers Arch. 2002;443:866&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11889587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perot C, Goubel F, Mora I. Quantification of T- and H-responses before and after a period of endurance training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1991;63:368&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1773814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pette D, Vrbova G. Adaptation of mammalian skeletal muscle fibers to chronic electrical stimulation. Rev Physiol Biochem Pharmacol. 1992;120:115&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1519018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichon F, Chatard JC, Martin A, Cometti G. Electrical stimulation and swimming performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27:1671&#x2013;1676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8614324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierrot-Deseilligny E, Bussel B, Sideri G, Cathala HP, Castaigne P. Effect of voluntary contraction on H reflex changes induced by cutaneous stimulation in normal man. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1973;34:185&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4119532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierrot-Deseilligny E, Bergego C, Katz R, Morin C. Cutaneous depression of Ib reflex pathways to motoneurones in man. Exp Brain Res. 1981;42:351&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7238675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popovic MR, Curt A, Keller T, Dietz V. Functional electrical stimulation for grasping and walking: indications and limitations. Spinal Cord. 2001;39:403&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11512070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridding MC, Brouwer B, Miles TS, Pitcher JB, Thompson PD. Changes in muscle responses to stimulation of the motor cortex induced by peripheral nerve stimulation in human subjects. Exp Brain Res. 2000;131:135&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10759179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridding MC, McKay DR, Thompson PD, Miles TS. Changes in corticomotor representations induced by prolonged peripheral nerve stimulation in humans. Clin Neurophysiol. 2001;112:1461&#x2013;1469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11459686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson KL, McIlwain JS, Hayes KC. Effects of H-reflex conditioning upon the contralateral alpha motoneuron pool. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1979;46:65&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">88332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruther CL, Golden CL, Harris RT, Dudley GA. Hypertrophy, resistance training, and the nature of skeletal muscle activation. J Strength Cond Res. 1995;9:155&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20:S135&#x2013;S145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3057313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaglioni G, Ferri A, Minetti AE, Martin A, Van Hoecke J, Capodaglio P, Sartorio A, Narici MV. Plantar flexor activation capacity and H reflex in older adults: adaptations to strength training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;92:2292&#x2013;2302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12015339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Gorza L, Sartore S, Saggin L, Ausoni S, Vianello M, Gundersen K, Lomo T. Three myosin heavy chain isoforms in type 2 skeletal muscle fibres. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 1989;10:197&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2547831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott OM, Vrbova G, Hyde SA, Dubowitz V. Effects of chronic low frequency electrical stimulation on normal human tibialis anterior muscle. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1985;48:774&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1028449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4031929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GV, Alon G, Roys SR, Gullapalli RP. Functional MRI determination of a dose-response relationship to lower extremity neuromuscular electrical stimulation in healthy subjects. Exp Brain Res. 2003;150:33&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12698214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Pierre D, Taylor AW, Lavoie M, Sellers W, Kots YM. Effects of 2,500&#xa0;Hz sinusoidal current on fibre area and strength of the quadriceps femoris. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 1986;26:60&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2940419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein RB, Everaert DG, Thompson AK, Chong SL, Whittaker M, Robertson J, Kuether G. Long-term therapeutic and orthotic effects of a foot drop stimulator on walking performance in progressive and nonprogressive neurological disorders. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2010;24:152&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens JE, Mizner RL, Snyder-Mackler L. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation for quadriceps muscle strengthening after bilateral total knee arthroplasty: a case series. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2004;34:21&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14964588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson SW, Dudley GA. Dietary creatine supplementation and muscular adaptation to resistive overload. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1304&#x2013;1310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11474331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki T, Uchiyama S, Uchiyama Y, Akatsuka A, Yoshimura S, Roy RR, Edgerton VR. Limited myogenic response to a single bout of weight-lifting exercise in old rats. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2000;278:C1143&#x2013;C1152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10837342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taube W, Kullmann N, Leukel C, Kurz O, Amtage F, Gollhofer A. Differential reflex adaptations following sensorimotor and strength training in young elite athletes. Int J Sports Med. 2007;28:999&#x2013;1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17497570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor J. The interpolated twitch does provide a valid measure of the voluntary activation of muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:354&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18801954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theriault R, Boulay MR, Theriault G, Simoneau JA. Electrical stimulation-induced changes in performance and fiber type proportion of human knee extensor muscles. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1996;74:311&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8911822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorstensson A, Hulten B, von Dobeln W, Karlsson J. Effect of strength training on enzyme activities and fibre characteristics in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1976;96:392&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">179278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trimble MH, Enoka RM (1991) Mechanisms underlying the training effects associated with neuromuscular electrical stimulation. Phys Ther 71:273&#x2013;280; discussion 280&#x2013;282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2008451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderthommen M, Duteil S, Wary C, Raynaud JS, Leroy-Willig A, Crielaard JM, Carlier PG. A comparison of voluntary and electrically induced contractions by interleaved 1H- and 31P-NMRS in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2003;94:1012&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12571132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt M, Chelli F, Frigo C. Changes in the excitability of soleus muscle short latency stretch reflexes during human hopping after 4&#xa0;weeks of hopping training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1998;78:522&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9840407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw JR. Spinal cord plasticity in acquisition and maintenance of motor skills. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2007;189:155&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17250566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zehr PE. Considerations for use of the Hoffmann reflex in exercise studies. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;86:455&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11944092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S. Chronic neural adaptations to unilateral exercise: mechanisms of cross education. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2000;28:177&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11064852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>