<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40336139</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association between muscle strength gains and biventricular cardiac remodeling in response to high-intensity resistance training in healthy untrained males: a longitudinal study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">116</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01165-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">High-intensity resistance training induces structural and functional adaptations in skeletal muscle, yet its impact on cardiac remodeling remains debated. This study aimed to investigate the longitudinal biventricular cardiac response to a 20-week high-intensity resistance training program in previously untrained, healthy males and examine the association between muscle strength gains and cardiac remodeling.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-seven male volunteers (aged 18-40 years) participated in a high-intensity resistance training program for 20 weeks. Assessments at baseline, 12 weeks, and 20 weeks included resting blood pressure, electrocardiogram (ECG), three-dimensional transthoracic echocardiography (3DTTE), cardiopulmonary exercise testing ([Formula: see text]O<sub>2peak</sub>), isokinetic dynamometry for muscle strength, and actimetry recordings. Time effects were analyzed using one-way repeated measures ANOVA (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-two participants completed the study. Resistance training led to significant reductions in arterial systolic and diastolic blood pressure and heart rate. After 20 weeks of training, 3DTTE showed a significant increase in left ventricular (LV) mass (120.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;15.4&#xa0;g vs. 133.7&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;16.3&#xa0;g, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), without inducing LV hypertrophy. Balanced increases were observed in LV end-diastolic volume (146.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;18.9 ml vs. 157.9&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;19.6&#xa0;ml, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and right ventricular (RV) end-diastolic volume (119&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;19.4 ml vs. 129.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;21.6&#xa0;ml, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). LV and RV systolic and diastolic function remained unchanged. There were no changes in [Formula: see text]O<sub>2peak</sub> or daily activity levels. Maximal muscle strength in the quadriceps, hamstrings, triceps, and biceps was significantly correlated with LV and RV end-diastolic volumes and LV mass (p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The resistance training program resulted in significant and rapid muscle strength gains and reduced blood pressure. Cardiac adaptations, including moderate biventricular dilatation, were observed without changes in cardiac function or [Formula: see text]O<sub>2peak</sub> and were associated with muscle strength gains. Our study highlights that intensive resistance training in novice male resistance trainers induces an adaptive cardiac response, reflecting a physiological adaptation linked to enhanced muscle performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov ID: NCT04187170.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pamart</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inter-University Laboratory of Human Movement Science (LIBM EA7424), University of Lyon, University Jean Monnet, Saint-Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drigny</LastName><ForeName>Joffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azambourg</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Remilly</LastName><ForeName>Marion</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lahjaily</LastName><ForeName>Kamal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocamora</LastName><ForeName>Am&#xe9;lia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre de Recherche Clinique (CRC), CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tournoux</LastName><ForeName>Francois</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center of the Montreal University Hospital (CRCHUM), Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saloux</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reboursi&#xe8;re</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gauthier</LastName><ForeName>Antoine</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, UFR STAPS, Caen, 14000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hodzic</LastName><ForeName>Amir</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France. hodzic-a@chu-caen.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU Caen Normandie, Caen, 14000, France. hodzic-a@chu-caen.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Physiology, Normandie Univ, UNICAEN, CHU de Caen Normandie, Inserm Comete, GIP Cyceron, Caen, 14000, France. hodzic-a@chu-caen.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Caen Normandie, avenue de la C&#xf4;te de Nacre, Caen, 14000, France. hodzic-a@chu-caen.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04187170</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Bourse Sport et Coeur</GrantID><Agency>Soci&#xe9;t&#xe9; Francaise de Cardiologie</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">3D echocardiography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athlete&#x2019;s heart</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biventricular cardiac remodeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiac hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All procedures achieved in this study were performed in accordance with the ethical standards as laid down in the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and its later amendments or comparable ethical standards. The study was approved by the French research ethics committee (EUDRACT: 2019-A01235-52). Informed consent was obtained from all participants involved in the study. All the collected data were anonymous. A compensatory allowance of &#x20ac;150 was provided for all participants, subject to their participation in the entirety of the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40336139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12057098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01165-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01165-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Paluch AE, Boyer WR, Franklin BA, Laddu D, Lobelo F, Lee DC, et al. Resistance exercise training in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: 2023 update: A scientific statement from the American heart association. Circulation. 2024;149(3):e217&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11209834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38059362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Gerche A, Wasfy MM, Brosnan MJ, Claessen G, Fatkin D, Heidbuchel H, et al. The athlete&#x2019;s Heart-Challenges and controversies: JACC focus seminar 4/4. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;80(14):1346&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2022.07.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morganroth J, Maron BJ, Henry WL, Epstein SE. Comparative left ventricular dimensions in trained athletes. Ann Intern Med. 1975;82(4):521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1119766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morganroth J, Maron BJ. The athlete&#x2019;s heart syndrome: a new perspective. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1977;301:931&#x2011;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">145202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggish AL, Wang F, Weiner RB, Elinoff JM, Tournoux F, Boland A, et al. Training-specific changes in cardiac structure and function: a prospective and longitudinal assessment of competitive athletes. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2008;104(4):1121&#x2011;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18096751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrotou S, Karatzi K, Papamichael C, Fatouros I, Mitrakou A, Zakopoulos N, et al. Effects of chronic anaerobic training on markers of sub-clinical atherosclerosis. Hellenic J Cardiol. 2013;54(3):178&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23685654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tso JV, Turner CG, Liu C, Prabakaran G, Jackson M, Galante A, et al. Longitudinal aortic root dilatation in collegiate American-Style football athletes. J Am Heart Assoc. 2023;12(12):e030314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.122.030314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10356022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37318010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haykowsky MJ, Dressendorfer R, Taylor D, Mandic S, Humen D. Resistance training and cardiac hypertrophy: unravelling the training effect. Sports Med. 2002;32(13):837&#x2011;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12392444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haykowsky M, Taylor D, Teo K, Quinney A, Humen D. Left ventricular wall stress during leg-press exercise performed with a brief Valsalva maneuver. Chest. 2001;119(1):150&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.119.1.150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11157597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandperrin A, Schuster I, Moronval P, Izem O, Rupp T, Obert P, et al. Anabolic steroids use is associated with impairments in atrial and ventricular cardiac structure and performance in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54(5):780&#x2011;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34974501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggish AL, Weiner RB, Kanayama G, Hudson JI, Lu MT, Hoffmann U, et al. Cardiovascular toxicity of illicit anabolic-androgenic steroid use. Circulation. 2017;135(21):1991&#x2011;2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5614517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28533317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berge HM, Isern CB, Berge E. Blood pressure and hypertension in athletes: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(11):716&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-093976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25631543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuki T, Maeda S, Iemitsu M, Saito Y, Tanimura Y, Ajisaka R, et al. Relationship between arterial stiffness and athletic training programs in young adult men. Am J Hypertens. 2007;20(9):967&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjhyper.2007.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17765138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pluim BM, Zwinderman AH, van der Laarse A, van der Wall EE. The athlete&#x2019;s heart. A meta-analysis of cardiac structure and function. Circulation. 2000;101(3):336&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.101.3.336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10645932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utomi V, Oxborough D, Ashley E, Lord R, Fletcher S, Stembridge M, et al. The impact of chronic endurance and resistance training upon the right ventricular phenotype in male athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(8):1673&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3147-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25779702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haykowsky MJ, Teo KK, Quinney AH, Humen DP, Taylor DA. Effects of long term resistance training on left ventricular morphology. Can J Cardiol. 2000;16(1):35&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10653931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence AL, Naylor LH, Carter HH, Buck CL, Dembo L, Murray CP, et al. A prospective randomised longitudinal MRI study of left ventricular adaptation to endurance and resistance exercise training in humans. J Physiol. 2011;589(Pt 22):5443&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2011.217125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3240883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21969450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence AL, Carter HH, Murray CP, Oxborough D, Naylor LH, George KP, et al. Magnetic resonance imaging-derived right ventricular adaptations to endurance versus resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(3):534&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3182780b0e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23073215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scharf M, Oezdemir D, Schmid A, Kemmler W, von Stengel S, May MS, et al. Myocardial adaption to HI(R)T in previously untrained men with a randomized, longitudinal cardiac MR imaging study (Physical adaptions in untrained on strength and heart trial, PUSH-trial). PLoS ONE. 2017;12(12):e0189204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0189204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5720775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29216285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports M. American college of sports medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. 2017. pp. 3508-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Van Every DW, Plotkin DL. Loading recommendations for muscle strength, hypertrophy, and local endurance: A Re-Examination of the repetition continuum. Sports (Basel). 2021;9(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7927075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33671664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pamart N, Drigny J, Azambourg H, Remilly M, Macquart M, Lefevre A, et al. Effects of a 20-Week High-Intensity strength training program on muscle strength gain and cardiac adaptation in untrained men: preliminary results of a prospective longitudinal study. JMIR Form Res. 2023;7:e47876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/47876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10630871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37874630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Drezner JA, Baggish A, Papadakis M, Wilson MG, Prutkin JM, et al. International recommendations for electrocardiographic interpretation in athletes. Eur Heart J. 2018;39(16):1466&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehw631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28329355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casale PN, Devereux RB, Alonso DR, Campo E, Kligfield P. Improved sex-specific criteria of left ventricular hypertrophy for clinical and computer interpretation of electrocardiograms: validation with autopsy findings. Circulation. 1987;75(3):565&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.75.3.565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2949887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Badano LP, Mor-Avi V, Afilalo J, Armstrong A, Ernande L, et al. Recommendations for cardiac chamber quantification by echocardiography in adults: an update from the American society of echocardiography and the European association of cardiovascular imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2015;28(1):1&#x2013;e3914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.echo.2014.10.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Test-retest reliability of the one-repetition maximum (1RM) strength assessment: a systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2020;6(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-020-00260-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binder RK, Wonisch M, Corra U, Cohen-Solal A, Vanhees L, Saner H, et al. Methodological approach to the first and second lactate threshold in incremental cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil. 2008;15(6):726&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJR.0b013e328304fed4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19050438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Thoracic S. American college of chest P. ATS/ACCP statement on cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2003;167(2):211&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.167.2.211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12524257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori G. ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription, 11th Edition. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morishita S, Tsubaki A, Takabayashi T, Fu JB. Relationship between the rating of perceived exertion scale and the load intensity of resistance training. Strength Cond J. 2018;40(2):94&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29674945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas R, Baechle RWE. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. (U.S.) NSCA. editor: Human Kinetics; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancia G, Kreutz R, Brunstrom M, Burnier M, Grassi G, Januszewicz A, et al. 2023 ESH guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension the task force for the management of arterial hypertension of the European society of hypertension: endorsed by the international society of hypertension (ISH) and the European renal association (ERA). J Hypertens. 2023;41(12):1874&#x2013;2071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37345492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonekamp NE, May AM, Halle M, Dorresteijn JAN, van der Meer MG, Ruigrok YM, et al. Physical exercise volume, type, and intensity and risk of all-cause mortality and cardiovascular events in patients with cardiovascular disease: a mediation analysis. Eur Heart J Open. 2023;3(3):oead057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ehjopen/oead057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37351547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards JJ, Deenmamode AHP, Griffiths M, Arnold O, Cooper NJ, Wiles JD, et al. Exercise training and resting blood pressure: a large-scale pairwise and network meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(20):1317&#x2011;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37491419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecchio RY, Brito LC, Pecanha T, de Moraes Forjaz CL. Potential mechanisms behind the blood Pressure-Lowering effect of dynamic resistance training. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2021;23(6):35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11906-021-01154-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34152491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Gerche A, Heidbuchel H. Can intensive exercise harm the heart? You can get too much of a good thing. Circulation. 2014;130(12):992&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.114.008141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25223770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Zhang X, Wang L, Guo Y, Xie M. Prevalence of metabolic syndrome and its components among Chinese professional athletes of strength sports with different body weight categories. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(11):e79758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0079758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3821854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24255714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanakis C, Hickson RC. Left ventricular responses to a program of lower-limb strength training. Chest. 1980;78(4):618&#x2011;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6448133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au JS, Oikawa SY, Morton RW, Phillips SM, MacDonald MJ, Stohr EJ. Unaltered left ventricular mechanics and remodelling after 12 weeks of resistance exercise training - a longitudinal study in men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2019;44(8):820&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2018-0544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30620666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccia A, Maron BJ, Spataro A, Proschan MA, Spirito P. The upper limit of physiologic cardiac hypertrophy in highly trained elite athletes. N Engl J Med. 1991;324(5):295&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199101313240504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1824720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haykowsky MJ, Quinney HA, Gillis R, Thompson CR. Left ventricular morphology in junior and master resistance trained athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(2):349&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200002000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda DPAW, Lopes HHMC, deSantana VJ, Bocchi EA, Salemi VMC. Association between right heart dimensions and muscle performance and cardiorespiratory capacity in strength and endurance athletes. Transl Sports Med. 2021;4:470&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tsm2.244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feiereisen P, Vaillant M, Eischen D, Delagardelle C. Isokinetic versus one-repetition maximum strength assessment in chronic heart failure. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(12):2156&#x2011;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20421831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloan RP, Shapiro PA, DeMeersman RE, Bagiella E, Brondolo EN, McKinley PS, et al. The effect of aerobic training and cardiac autonomic regulation in young adults. Am J Public Health. 2009;99(5):921&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2007.133165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2667843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19299682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milot E, Rehel S, Langeard A, Bigot L, Pasquier F, Matveeff L, et al. Effectiveness of multi-modal home-based videoconference interventions on sleep in older adults: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1326412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11057197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38686035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langeard A, Bigot L, Loggia G, Bherer L, Chastan N, Gauthier A. Ankle dorsiflexors and plantarflexors neuromuscular electrical stimulation training impacts gait kinematics in older adults: A pilot study. Gait Posture. 2021;84:335&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2020.12.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles OE, Drinkwater EJ, Urwin CS, Lamon S, Aisbett B. Inadequate sleep and muscle strength: implications for resistance training. J Sci Med Sport. 2018;21(9):959&#x2011;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29422383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasocka-Koriat Z, Lewicka-Potocka Z, Kaleta-Duss A, Siekierzycka A, Kalinowski L, Lewicka E, et al. Differences in cardiac adaptation to exercise in male and female athletes assessed by noninvasive techniques: a state-of-the-art review. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2024;326(5):H1065&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00756.2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11380999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38391314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>