<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">25359125</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-0827</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Calcified tissue international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Calcif Tissue Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The molecular basis for load-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>196</StartPage><EndPage>210</EndPage><MedlinePgn>196-210</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00223-014-9925-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In a mature (weight neutral) animal, an increase in muscle mass only occurs when the muscle is loaded sufficiently to cause an increase in myofibrillar protein balance. A tight relationship between muscle hypertrophy, acute increases in protein balance, and the activity of the mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1) was demonstrated 15&#xa0;years ago. Since then, our understanding of the signals that regulate load-induced hypertrophy has evolved considerably. For example, we now know that mechanical load activates mTORC1 in the same way as growth factors, by moving TSC2 (a primary inhibitor of mTORC1) away from its target (the mTORC activator) Rheb. However, the kinase that phosphorylates and moves TSC2 is different in the two processes. Similarly, we have learned that a distinct pathway exists whereby amino acids activate mTORC1 by moving it to Rheb. While mTORC1 remains at the forefront of load-induced hypertrophy, the importance of other pathways that regulate muscle mass are becoming clearer. Myostatin, is best known for its control of developmental muscle size. However, new mechanisms to explain how loading regulates this process are suggesting that it could play an important role in hypertrophic muscle growth as well. Last, new mechanisms are highlighted for how &#x3b2;2 receptor agonists could be involved in load-induced muscle growth and why these agents are being developed as non-exercise-based therapies for muscle atrophy. Overall, the results highlight how studying the mechanism of load-induced skeletal muscle mass is leading the development of pharmaceutical interventions to promote muscle growth in those unwilling or unable to perform resistance exercise.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marcotte</LastName><ForeName>George R</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, Physiology and Behavior, University of California Davis, Davis, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>West</LastName><ForeName>Daniel W D</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baar</LastName><ForeName>Keith</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG045375</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01AG045375</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Calcif Tissue Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7905481</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0171-967X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25359125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS768242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4809742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00223-014-9925-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H, Spangenburg EE, Booth FW. Control of the size of the human muscle mass. Annual review of physiology. 2004;66:799&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S, Baar K, Lewis N. Nutrition for Weight and Resistance Training. In: Lanham-New S, Stear S, Shirreffs S, Collins A, editors. Nutrition Society Textbook on Sport and Exercise Nutrition. Wiley-Blackwell; 2011. pp. 120&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Karagounis LG, Peirce N, Simpson EJ, Hazell M, Layfield R, Wackerhage H, Smith K, Atherton P, Selby A, Rennie MJ. Disassociation between the effects of amino acids and insulin on signaling, ubiquitin ligases, and protein turnover in human muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295:E595&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2536736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrando AA, Sheffield-Moore M, Wolf SE, Herndon DN, Wolfe RR. Testosterone administration in severe burns ameliorates muscle catabolism. Critical care medicine. 2001;29:1936&#x2013;1942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11588456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuvdendorj D, Chinkes DL, Zhang XJ, Suman OE, Aarsland A, Ferrando A, Kulp GA, Jeschke MG, Wolfe RR, Herndon DN. Long-term oxandrolone treatment increases muscle protein net deposition via improving amino acid utilization in pediatric patients 6 months after burn injury. Surgery. 2011;149:645&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21333314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baehr LM, Tunzi M, Bodine SC. Muscle hypertrophy is associated with increases in proteasome activity that is independent of MuRF1 and MAFbx expression. Front Physiol. 2014;5:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3930915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24600408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwee DT, Baehr LM, Philp A, Baar K, Bodine SC. Maintenance of muscle mass and load-induced growth in Muscle RING Finger 1 null mice with age. Aging Cell. 2014;13:92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23941502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg AL. Protein synthesis during work-induced growth of skeletal muscle. J Cell Biol. 1968;36:653&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2107369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5645554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman CA, Frey JW, Mabrey DM, Jacobs BL, Lincoln HC, You JS, Hornberger TA. The role of skeletal muscle mTOR in the regulation of mechanical load-induced growth. The Journal of physiology. 2011;589:5485&#x2013;5501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3240886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21946849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skerry TM. The response of bone to mechanical loading and disuse: fundamental principles and influences on osteoblast/osteocyte homeostasis. Archives of biochemistry and biophysics. 2008;473:117&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18334226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaer M, Langberg H, Heinemeier K, Bayer ML, Hansen M, Holm L, Doessing S, Kongsgaard M, Krogsgaard MR, Magnusson SP. From mechanical loading to collagen synthesis, structural changes and function in human tendon. Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports. 2009;19:500&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19706001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey AL, Brandstetter S, Schjerling P, Bojsen-Moller J, Qvortrup K, Pedersen MM, Doessing S, Kjaer M, Magnusson SP, Langberg H. Sequenced response of extracellular matrix deadhesion and fibrotic regulators after muscle damage is involved in protection against future injury in human skeletal muscle. FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology. 2011;25:1943&#x2013;1959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3101036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21368102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wycherley TP, Moran LJ, Clifton PM, Noakes M, Brinkworth GD. Effects of energy-restricted high-protein, low-fat compared with standard-protein, low-fat diets: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. The American journal of clinical nutrition. 2012;96:1281&#x2013;1298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23097268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen L, Phillips SM. Interactions between exercise and nutrition to prevent muscle waste during ageing. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;75:708&#x2013;715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3575937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22957963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer MD, Maganaris CN, Seynnes OR, Rennie MJ, Narici MV. Time course of muscular, neural and tendinous adaptations to 23 day unilateral lower-limb suspension in young men. The Journal of Physiology. 2007;583:1079&#x2013;1091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2277190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17656438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D, Sheffield-Moore M, Cree MG, Hewlings SJ, Aarsland A, Wolfe RR, Ferrando AA. Atrophy and impaired muscle protein synthesis during prolonged inactivity and stress. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91:4836&#x2013;4841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16984982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC. Disuse-induced muscle wasting. The international journal of biochemistry &amp; cell biology. 2013;45:2200&#x2013;2208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3856924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackman RW, Cornwell EW, Wu CL, Kandarian SC. Nuclear factor-kappaB signalling and transcriptional regulation in skeletal muscle atrophy. Experimental physiology. 2013;98:19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3505235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22848079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair SN. Physical inactivity: the biggest public health problem of the 21st century. British journal of sports medicine. 2009;43:1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19136507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Sui X, Lobelo F, Morrow JR, Jr, Jackson AW, Sjostrom M, Blair SN. Association between muscular strength and mortality in men: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2008;337:a439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2453303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe RR. The underappreciated role of muscle in health and disease. The American journal of clinical nutrition. 2006;84:475&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley BF, Hanson ED, Sheaff AK. Strength training as a countermeasure to aging muscle and chronic disease. Sports medicine. 2011;41:289&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21425888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villareal DT, Smith GI, Sinacore DR, Shah K, Mittendorfer B. Regular multicomponent exercise increases physical fitness and muscle protein anabolism in frail, obese, older adults. Obesity. 2011;19:312&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3069710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20489691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TS, Booth FW. Protein metabolism in rat tibialis anterior muscle after stimulated chronic eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1990;69:1718&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1703146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TS, Booth FW. Protein metabolism in rat gastrocnemius muscle after stimulated chronic concentric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1990;69:1709&#x2013;1717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1703145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TS, Booth FW. Skeletal muscle enlargement with weight-lifting exercise by rats. J Appl Physiol. 1988;65:950&#x2013;954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2459101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Staples AW, Atherton PJ, Baker JM, Moore DR, Holwerda AM, Parise G, Rennie MJ, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS ONE. 2010;5:e12033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2012;113:71&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Sato Y. Muscle size and strength are increased following walk training with restricted venous blood flow from the leg muscle, Kaatsu-walk training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2006;100:1460&#x2013;1466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, Cadenas JG, Dreyer HC, Sato Y, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2007;103:903&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papanicolaou GN, Falk EA. General Muscular Hypertrophy Induced by Androgenic Hormone. Science. 1938;87:238&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17770410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieschlag E, Nieschlag S. Testosterone deficiency: a historical perspective. Asian J Androl. 2014;16:161&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3955324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24435052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoberman JM, Yesalis CE. Scientific American. 1995. The History of Synthetic Testosterone; pp. 77&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7817189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels LT, Henschel AF, Keys A. Influence of Methyl Testosterone on Muscular Work and Creatine Metabolism in Normal Young Men. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 1942;2:649&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cureton KJ, Collins MA, Hill DW, McElhannon FM., Jr Muscle hypertrophy in men and women. Medicine and science in sports and exercise. 1988;20:338&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3173042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson ED, Sheaff AK, Sood S, Ma L, Francis JD, Goldberg AP, Hurley BF. Strength training induces muscle hypertrophy and functional gains in black prostate cancer patients despite androgen deprivation therapy. The journals of gerontology Series A, Biological sciences and medical sciences. 2013;68:490&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23089339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Tang JE, Moore DR, Staples AW, Holwerda AM, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:60&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Kujbida GW, Moore DR, Atherton P, Burd NA, Padzik JP, De Lisio M, Tang JE, Parise G, Rennie MJ, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise-induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J Physiol. 2009;587:5239&#x2013;5247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19736298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, Hakkinen K. Acute hormonal and neuromuscular responses and recovery to forced vs maximum repetitions multiple resistance exercises. Int J Sports Med. 2003;24:410&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12905088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams GR, Haddad F. The relationships among IGF-1, DNA content, and protein accumulation during skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:2509&#x2013;2516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9018499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKoy G, Ashley W, Mander J, Yang SY, Williams N, Russell B, Goldspink G. Expression of insulin growth factor-1 splice variants and structural genes in rabbit skeletal muscle induced by stretch and stimulation. J Physiol. 1999;516( Pt 2):583&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2269271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10087355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spangenburg EE, Le Roith D, Ward CW, Bodine SC. A functional insulin-like growth factor receptor is not necessary for load-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J Physiol. 2008;586:283&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17974583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuneo RC, Salomon F, Wiles CM, Hesp R, Sonksen PH. Growth hormone treatment in growth hormone-deficient adults. I. Effects on muscle mass and strength. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1991;70:688&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2022560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuneo RC, Salomon F, Wiles CM, Sonksen PH. Skeletal muscle performance in adults with growth hormone deficiency. Hormone research. 1990;33(Suppl 4):55&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2245969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornberger TA, Stuppard R, Conley KE, Fedele MJ, Fiorotto ML, Chin ER, Esser KA. Mechanical stimuli regulate rapamycin-sensitive signalling by a phosphoinositide 3-kinase-, protein kinase B- and growth factor-independent mechanism. Biochem J. 2004;380:795&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1224227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15030312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg AL. Work-induced growth of skeletal muscle in normal and hypophysectomized rats. Am J Physiol. 1967;213:1193&#x2013;1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6054866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg AL. Role of insulin in work-induced growth of skeletal muscle. Endocrinology. 1968;83:1071&#x2013;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5685568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg AL. Protein turnover in skeletal muscle. I. Protein catabolism during work-induced hypertrophy and growth induced with growth hormone. J Biol Chem. 1969;244:3217&#x2013;3222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5792657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg AL, Goodman HM. Relationship between growth hormone and muscular work in determining muscle size. J Physiol. 1969;200:655&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1350519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5765853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullough WS. The control of mitotic activity in adult mammalian tissues. Biological reviews of the Cambridge Philosophical Society. 1962;37:307&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13874622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elgjo K, Reichelt KL. Chalones: from aqueous extracts to oligopeptides. Cell Cycle. 2004;3:1208&#x2013;1211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15326370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ. Extracellular Regulation of Myostatin: A Molecular Rheostat for Muscle Mass. Immunol Endocr Metab Agents Med Chem. 2010;10:183&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21423813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherron AC, Lee SJ. Double muscling in cattle due to mutations in the myostatin gene. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1997;94:12457&#x2013;12461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC24998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9356471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosher DS, Quignon P, Bustamante CD, Sutter NB, Mellersh CS, Parker HG, Ostrander EA. A mutation in the myostatin gene increases muscle mass and enhances racing performance in heterozygote dogs. PLoS genetics. 2007;3:e79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1877876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ, McPherron AC. Regulation of myostatin activity and muscle growth. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2001;98:9306&#x2013;9311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC55416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11459935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeier KM, Olesen JL, Schjerling P, Haddad F, Langberg H, Baldwin KM, Kjaer M. Short-term strength training and the expression of myostatin and IGF-I isoforms in rat muscle and tendon: differential effects of specific contraction types. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2007;102:573&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17038487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Load-mediated downregulation of myostatin mRNA is not sufficient to promote myofiber hypertrophy in humans: a cluster analysis. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2007;103:1488&#x2013;1495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17673556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kagawa Y. Impact of Westernization on the nutrition of Japanese: changes in physique, cancer, longevity and centenarians. Prev Med. 1978;7:205&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">674107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery RD. Muscle morphology in infantile protein malnutrition. J Clin Pathol. 1962;15:511&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC480450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16810988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almurshed K, Grunewald K. The effects of dietary energy restriction on overloaded skeletal muscle in rats. The British journal of nutrition. 2000;84:697&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11177183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almurshed KS, Grunewald KK. Dietary protein does not affect overloaded skeletal muscle in rats. The Journal of nutrition. 2000;130:1743&#x2013;1748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10867045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Phillips SM, Doyle D, Jr, Wolfe RR. Postexercise net protein synthesis in human muscle from orally administered amino acids. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E628&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman JW, Tang JE, Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Lawrence RL, Fullerton AV, Phillips SM. Consumption of fat-free fluid milk after resistance exercise promotes greater lean mass accretion than does consumption of soy or carbohydrate in young, novice, male weightlifters. The American journal of clinical nutrition. 2007;86:373&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Maggi SP, Williams BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Increased rates of muscle protein turnover and amino acid transport after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1995;268:E514&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie MG, Hamilton DL, Murray JT, Taylor PM, Baar K. mVps34 is activated following high-resistance contractions. J Physiol. 2009;587:253&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2670038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19015198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Moore DR, Atherton PJ, Staples AW, Prior T, Tang JE, Rennie MJ, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Enhanced amino acid sensitivity of myofibrillar protein synthesis persists for up to 24 h after resistance exercise in young men. The Journal of nutrition. 2011;141:568&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Robinson MJ, Fry JL, Tang JE, Glover EI, Wilkinson SB, Prior T, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men. The American journal of clinical nutrition. 2009;89:161&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Moore DR, Kujbida GW, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2009;107:987&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta JL, Burke LM, Ross ML, Camera DM, West DW, Broad EM, Jeacocke NA, Moore DR, Stellingwerff T, Phillips SM, Hawley JA, Coffey VG. Timing and distribution of protein ingestion during prolonged recovery from resistance exercise alters myofibrillar protein synthesis. The Journal of Physiology. 2013;591:2319&#x2013;2331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros I, Chatzinikolaou A, Paltoglou G, Petridou A, Avloniti A, Jamurtas A, Goussetis E, Mitrakou A, Mougios V, Lazaropoulou C, Margeli A, Papassotiriou I, Mastorakos G. Acute resistance exercise results in catecholaminergic rather than hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis stimulation during exercise in young men. Stress. 2010;13:461&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20666650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Noble BJ, Clark MJ, Culver BW. Physiologic responses to heavy-resistance exercise with very short rest periods. International journal of sports medicine. 1987;8:247&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3667019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roatta S, Farina D. Sympathetic actions on the skeletal muscle. Exercise and sport sciences reviews. 2010;38:31&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20016297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryall JG, Sillence MN, Lynch GS. Systemic administration of beta2-adrenoceptor agonists, formoterol and salmeterol, elicit skeletal muscle hypertrophy in rats at micromolar doses. British journal of pharmacology. 2006;147:587&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1751341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno NE, Kelly KA, Hawkins R, Bramah-Lawani M, Amelio AL, Nwachukwu JC, Nettles KW, Conkright MD. Creb coactivators direct anabolic responses and enhance performance of skeletal muscle. The EMBO journal. 2014;33:1027&#x2013;1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4193935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24674967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg AL, Etlinger JD, Goldspink DF, Jablecki C. Mechanism of work-induced hypertrophy of skeletal muscle. Med Sci Sports. 1975;7:185&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">128681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar K, Esser K. Phosphorylation of p70(S6k) correlates with increased skeletal muscle mass following resistance exercise. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:C120&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laplante M, Sabatini DM. mTOR signaling in growth control and disease. Cell. 2012;149:274&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3331679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22500797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hara K, Maruki Y, Long X, Yoshino K, Oshiro N, Hidayat S, Tokunaga C, Avruch J, Yonezawa K. Raptor, a binding partner of target of rapamycin (TOR), mediates TOR action. Cell. 2002;110:177&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12150926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickinson JM, Fry CS, Drummond MJ, Gundermann DM, Walker DK, Glynn EL, Timmerman KL, Dhanani S, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 activation is required for the stimulation of human skeletal muscle protein synthesis by essential amino acids. The Journal of nutrition. 2011;141:856&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3077888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21430254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Fry CS, Glynn EL, Dreyer HC, Dhanani S, Timmerman KL, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Rapamycin administration in humans blocks the contraction-induced increase in skeletal muscle protein synthesis. J Physiol. 2009;587:1535&#x2013;1546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC, Stitt TN, Gonzalez M, Kline WO, Stover GL, Bauerlein R, Zlotchenko E, Scrimgeour A, Lawrence JC, Glass DJ, Yancopoulos GD. Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy in vivo. Nat Cell Biol. 2001;3:1014&#x2013;1019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman CA, Miu MH, Frey JW, Mabrey DM, Lincoln HC, Ge Y, Chen J, Hornberger TA. A phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase/protein kinase B-independent activation of mammalian target of rapamycin signaling is sufficient to induce skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Molecular biology of the cell. 2010;21:3258&#x2013;3268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20668162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G, Georgiadis G, Stratakos G, Vogiatzis I, Kavouras S, Manta P, Mascher H, Blomstrand E. Resistance exercise-induced increase in muscle mass correlates with p70S6 kinase phosphorylation in human subjects. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102:145&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17874120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoki K, Ouyang H, Zhu T, Lindvall C, Wang Y, Zhang X, Yang Q, Bennett C, Harada Y, Stankunas K, Wang CY, He X, MacDougald OA, You M, Williams BO, Guan KL. TSC2 integrates Wnt and energy signals via a coordinated phosphorylation by AMPK and GSK3 to regulate cell growth. Cell. 2006;126:955&#x2013;968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16959574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoki K, Zhu T, Guan KL. TSC2 mediates cellular energy response to control cell growth and survival. Cell. 2003;115:577&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14651849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crozier SJ, Kimball SR, Emmert SW, Anthony JC, Jefferson LS. Oral leucine administration stimulates protein synthesis in rat skeletal muscle. J Nutr. 2005;135:376&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs BL, You JS, Frey JW, Goodman CA, Gundermann DM, Hornberger TA. Eccentric contractions increase the phosphorylation of tuberous sclerosis complex-2 (TSC2) and alter the targeting of TSC2 and the mechanistic target of rapamycin to the lysosome. The Journal of Physiology. 2013;591:4611&#x2013;4620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3784202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23732640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon S, Dibble CC, Talbott G, Hoxhaj G, Valvezan AJ, Takahashi H, Cantley LC, Manning BD. Spatial control of the TSC complex integrates insulin and nutrient regulation of mTORC1 at the lysosome. Cell. 2014;156:771&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4030681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24529379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato T, Nakashima A, Guo L, Tamanoi F. Specific activation of mTORC1 by Rheb G-protein in vitro involves enhanced recruitment of its substrate protein. The Journal of biological chemistry. 2009;284:12783&#x2013;12791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2676008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19299511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibble CC, Elis W, Menon S, Qin W, Klekota J, Asara JM, Finan PM, Kwiatkowski DJ, Murphy LO, Manning BD. TBC1D7 is a third subunit of the TSC1-TSC2 complex upstream of mTORC1. Molecular cell. 2012;47:535&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3693578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22795129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee AR, Manning BD, Roux PP, Cantley LC, Blenis J. Tuberous sclerosis complex gene products, Tuberin and Hamartin, control mTOR signaling by acting as a GTPase-activating protein complex toward Rheb. Curr Biol. 2003;13:1259&#x2013;1268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12906785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoki K, Li Y, Zhu T, Wu J, Guan KL. TSC2 is phosphorylated and inhibited by Akt and suppresses mTOR signalling. Nat Cell Biol. 2002;4:648&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12172553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vander Haar E, Lee SI, Bandhakavi S, Griffin TJ, Kim DH. Insulin signalling to mTOR mediated by the Akt/PKB substrate PRAS40. Nature cell biology. 2007;9:316&#x2013;323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd PR, Withers DJ, Siddle K. Phosphoinositide 3-kinase: the key switch mechanism in insulin signalling. The Biochemical journal. 1998;333( Pt 3):471&#x2013;490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1219607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9677303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessi DR, Cohen P. Mechanism of activation and function of protein kinase B. Curr Opin Genet Dev. 1998;8:55&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9529606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessi DR, James SR, Downes CP, Holmes AB, Gaffney PR, Reese CB, Cohen P. Characterization of a 3-phosphoinositide-dependent protein kinase which phosphorylates and activates protein kinase Balpha. Curr Biol. 1997;7:261&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9094314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarbassov DD, Guertin DA, Ali SM, Sabatini DM. Phosphorylation and Regulation of Akt/PKB by the Rictor-mTOR Complex. Science. 2005;307:1098&#x2013;1101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornberger TA, Chu WK, Mak YW, Hsiung JW, Huang SA, Chien S. The role of phospholipase D and phosphatidic acid in the mechanical activation of mTOR signaling in skeletal muscle. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:4741&#x2013;4746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1450240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16537399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Atherton P, Patel R, Theisen D, Nielens H, Rennie MJ, Francaux M. Decrease in Akt/PKB signalling in human skeletal muscle by resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;104:57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18535836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You JS, Lincoln HC, Kim CR, Frey JW, Goodman CA, Zhong XP, Hornberger TA. The role of diacylglycerol kinase zeta and phosphatidic acid in the mechanical activation of mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) signaling and skeletal muscle hypertrophy. The Journal of biological chemistry. 2014;289:1551&#x2013;1563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3894336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24302719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith EM, Finn SG, Tee AR, Browne GJ, Proud CG. The tuberous sclerosis protein TSC2 is not required for the regulation of the mammalian target of rapamycin by amino acids and certain cellular stresses. The Journal of biological chemistry. 2005;280:18717&#x2013;18727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15772076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Peled L, Sabatini DM. Regulation of mTORC1 by amino acids. Trends in cell biology 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4074565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24698685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancak Y, Peterson TR, Shaul YD, Lindquist RA, Thoreen CC, Bar-Peled L, Sabatini DM. The Rag GTPases bind raptor and mediate amino acid signaling to mTORC1. Science. 2008;320:1496&#x2013;1501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2475333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18497260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long X, Ortiz-Vega S, Lin Y, Avruch J. Rheb binding to mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) is regulated by amino acid sufficiency. The Journal of biological chemistry. 2005;280:23433&#x2013;23436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15878852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancak Y, Bar-Peled L, Zoncu R, Markhard AL, Nada S, Sabatini DM. Ragulator-Rag complex targets mTORC1 to the lysosomal surface and is necessary for its activation by amino acids. Cell. 2010;141:290&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi T, Hirose E, Nakashima N, Ii M, Nishimoto T. Novel G proteins, Rag C and Rag D, interact with GTP-binding proteins, Rag A and Rag B. The Journal of biological chemistry. 2001;276:7246&#x2013;7257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E, Goraksha-Hicks P, Li L, Neufeld TP, Guan KL. Regulation of TORC1 by Rag GTPases in nutrient response. Nat Cell Biol. 2008;10:935&#x2013;945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2711503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18604198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Peled L, Chantranupong L, Cherniack AD, Chen WW, Ottina KA, Grabiner BC, Spear ED, Carter SL, Meyerson M, Sabatini DM. A Tumor suppressor complex with GAP activity for the Rag GTPases that signal amino acid sufficiency to mTORC1. Science. 2013;340:1100&#x2013;1106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3728654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23723238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Peled L, Schweitzer LD, Zoncu R, Sabatini DM. Ragulator is a GEF for the rag GTPases that signal amino acid levels to mTORC1. Cell. 2012;150:1196&#x2013;1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3517996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22980980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang CS, Jiang B, Li M, Zhu M, Peng Y, Zhang YL, Wu YQ, Li TY, Liang Y, Lu Z, Lian G, Liu Q, Guo H, Yin Z, Ye Z, Han J, Wu JW, Yin H, Lin SY, Lin SC. The Lysosomal v-ATPase-Ragulator Complex Is a Common Activator for AMPK and mTORC1, Acting as a Switch between Catabolism and Anabolism. Cell metabolism. 2014;20:526&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25002183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forgac M. Vacuolar ATPases: rotary proton pumps in physiology and pathophysiology. Nature reviews Molecular cell biology. 2007;8:917&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17912264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoncu R, Bar-Peled L, Efeyan A, Wang S, Sancak Y, Sabatini DM. mTORC1 senses lysosomal amino acids through an inside-out mechanism that requires the vacuolar H(+)-ATPase. Science. 2011;334:678&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3211112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22053050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JM, Jeong SJ, Park MC, Kim G, Kwon NH, Kim HK, Ha SH, Ryu SH, Kim S. Leucyl-tRNA synthetase is an intracellular leucine sensor for the mTORC1-signaling pathway. Cell. 2012;149:410&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22424946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsun ZY, Bar-Peled L, Chantranupong L, Zoncu R, Wang T, Kim C, Spooner E, Sabatini DM. The folliculin tumor suppressor is a GAP for the RagC/D GTPases that signal amino acid levels to mTORC1. Molecular cell. 2013;52:495&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3867817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24095279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averous J, Lambert-Langlais S, Carraro V, Gourbeyre O, Parry L, B&#x2019;Chir W, Muranishi Y, Jousse C, Bruhat A, Maurin AC, Proud CG, Fafournoux P. Requirement for lysosomal localization of mTOR for its activation differs between leucine and other amino acids. Cellular signalling. 2014;26:1918&#x2013;1927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24793303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Fry CS, Glynn EL, Timmerman KL, Dickinson JM, Walker DK, Gundermann DM, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Skeletal muscle amino acid transporter expression is increased in young and older adults following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2011;111:135&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Burd NA, Mitchell CJ, West DW, Philp A, Marcotte GR, Baker SK, Baar K, Phillips SM. Supplementation of a suboptimal protein dose with leucine or essential amino acids: effects on myofibrillar protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in men. The Journal of physiology. 2012;590:2751&#x2013;2765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3424729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22451437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ktistakis NT, Manifava M, Schoenfelder P, Rotondo S. How phosphoinositide 3-phosphate controls growth downstream of amino acids and autophagy downstream of amino acid withdrawal. Biochemical Society transactions. 2012;40:37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22260663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshiro N, Rapley J, Avruch J. Amino acids activate mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) complex 1 without changing Rag GTPase guanyl nucleotide charging. The Journal of biological chemistry. 2014;289:2658&#x2013;2674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3908400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24337580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmierer B, Hill CS. Kinetic analysis of Smad nucleocytoplasmic shuttling reveals a mechanism for transforming growth factor beta-dependent nuclear accumulation of Smads. Molecular and cellular biology. 2005;25:9845&#x2013;9858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1280270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall A, Salerno MS, Thomas M, Davies T, Berry C, Dyer K, Bracegirdle J, Watson T, Dziadek M, Kambadur R, Bower R, Sharma M. Mighty is a novel promyogenic factor in skeletal myogenesis. Exp Cell Res. 2008;314:1013&#x2013;1029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18255059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massague J, Seoane J, Wotton D. Smad transcription factors. Genes &amp; development. 2005;19:2783&#x2013;2810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16322555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaarenstroom T, Hill CS. TGF-beta signaling to chromatin: how Smads regulate transcription during self-renewal and differentiation. Seminars in cell &amp; developmental biology. 2014;32:107&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24503509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winbanks CE, Weeks KL, Thomson RE, Sepulveda PV, Beyer C, Qian H, Chen JL, Allen JM, Lancaster GI, Febbraio MA, Harrison CA, McMullen JR, Chamberlain JS, Gregorevic P. Follistatin-mediated skeletal muscle hypertrophy is regulated by Smad3 and mTOR independently of myostatin. The Journal of cell biology. 2012;197:997&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22711699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirouche A, Durieux AC, Banzet S, Koulmann N, Bonnefoy R, Mouret C, Bigard X, Peinnequin A, Freyssenet D. Down-regulation of Akt/mammalian target of rapamycin signaling pathway in response to myostatin overexpression in skeletal muscle. Endocrinology. 2009;150:286&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18801898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trendelenburg AU, Meyer A, Rohner D, Boyle J, Hatakeyama S, Glass DJ. Myostatin reduces Akt/TORC1/p70S6K signaling, inhibiting myoblast differentiation and myotube size. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2009;296:C1258&#x2013;1270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19357233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welle S, Burgess K, Mehta S. Stimulation of skeletal muscle myofibrillar protein synthesis, p70 S6 kinase phosphorylation, and ribosomal protein S6 phosphorylation by inhibition of myostatin in mature mice. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2009;296:E567&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19141683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartori R, Schirwis E, Blaauw B, Bortolanza S, Zhao J, Enzo E, Stantzou A, Mouisel E, Toniolo L, Ferry A, Stricker S, Goldberg AL, Dupont S, Piccolo S, Amthor H, Sandri M. BMP signaling controls muscle mass. Nature genetics. 2013;45:1309&#x2013;1318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24076600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winbanks CE, Chen JL, Qian H, Liu Y, Bernardo BC, Beyer C, Watt KI, Thomson RE, Connor T, Turner BJ, McMullen JR, Larsson L, McGee SL, Harrison CA, Gregorevic P. The bone morphogenetic protein axis is a positive regulator of skeletal muscle mass. The Journal of cell biology. 2013;203:345&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3812980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24145169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie MG, Hamilton DL, Pepin M, Patton A, Baar K. Inhibition of Myostatin Signaling through Notch Activation Following Acute Resistance Exercise. PLoS ONE. 2013 In Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3699505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23844238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson ME, Hsu M, Conboy IM. Imbalance between pSmad3 and Notch induces CDK inhibitors in old muscle stem cells. Nature. 2008;454:528&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7761661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18552838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu J, Jeffries S, Norton JE, Capobianco AJ, Bresnick EH. Repression of activator protein-1-mediated transcriptional activation by the Notch-1 intracellular domain. The Journal of biological chemistry. 2002;277:7587&#x2013;7597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11739397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross DA, Kadesch T. The notch intracellular domain can function as a coactivator for LEF-1. Molecular and cellular biology. 2001;21:7537&#x2013;7544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC99925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11604490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benovic JL, von Zastrow M. Editorial overview: Cell regulation: The ins and outs of G protein-coupled receptors. Current opinion in cell biology. 2014;27:v&#x2013;vi.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24529749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Bohn LM. Functional selectivity of GPCR signaling in animals. Current opinion in cell biology. 2014;27:102&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4349326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24680435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirvent P, Douillard A, Galbes O, Ramonatxo C, Py G, Candau R, Lacampagne A. Effects of chronic administration of clenbuterol on contractile properties and calcium homeostasis in rat extensor digitorum longus muscle. PLoS ONE. 2014;9:e100281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4074032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24971566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker AJ, Head SI, Wareham AC, Stephenson DG. Effect of clenbuterol on sarcoplasmic reticulum function in single skinned mammalian skeletal muscle fibers. The American journal of physiology. 1998;274:C1718&#x2013;1726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9611138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douillard A, Galbes O, Begue G, Rossano B, Levin J, Vernus B, Bonnieu A, Candau R, Py G. Calpastatin overexpression in the skeletal muscle of mice prevents clenbuterol-induced muscle hypertrophy and phenotypic shift. Clinical and experimental pharmacology &amp; physiology. 2012;39:364&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22300302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Maltzahn J, Bentzinger CF, Rudnicki MA. Wnt7a-Fzd7 signalling directly activates the Akt/mTOR anabolic growth pathway in skeletal muscle. Nature cell biology. 2012;14:186&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3271181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22179044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porporato PE, Filigheddu N, Reano S, Ferrara M, Angelino E, Gnocchi VF, Prodam F, Ronchi G, Fagoonee S, Fornaro M, Chianale F, Baldanzi G, Surico N, Sinigaglia F, Perroteau I, Smith RG, Sun Y, Geuna S, Graziani A. Acylated and unacylated ghrelin impair skeletal muscle atrophy in mice. The Journal of clinical investigation. 2013;123:611&#x2013;622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3561827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minetti GC, Feige JN, Rosenstiel A, Bombard F, Meier V, Werner A, Bassilana F, Sailer AW, Kahle P, Lambert C, Glass DJ, Fornaro M. Galphai2 signaling promotes skeletal muscle hypertrophy, myoblast differentiation, and muscle regeneration. Science signaling. 2011;4:ra80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22126963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline WO, Panaro FJ, Yang H, Bodine SC. Rapamycin inhibits the growth and muscle-sparing effects of clenbuterol. J Appl Physiol. 2007;102:740&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17068216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips BE, Williams JP, Gustafsson T, Bouchard C, Rankinen T, Knudsen S, Smith K, Timmons JA, Atherton PJ. Molecular networks of human muscle adaptation to exercise and age. PLoS genetics. 2013;9:e1003389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23555298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>