<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34372625</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2093-5978</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Endocrinology and metabolism (Seoul, Korea)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Endocrinol Metab (Seoul)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise/Resistance Training and Muscle Stem Cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>737</StartPage><EndPage>744</EndPage><MedlinePgn>737-744</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3803/EnM.2021.401</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Skeletal muscle has attracted attention as endocrine organ, because exercise-dependent cytokines called myokines/exerkines are released from skeletal muscle and are involved in systemic functions. While, local mechanical loading to skeletal muscle by exercise or resistance training alters myofiber type and size and myonuclear number. Skeletal muscle-resident stem cells, known as muscle satellite cells (MuSCs), are responsible for the increased number of myonuclei. Under steady conditions, MuSCs are maintained in a mitotically quiescent state but exit from that state and start to proliferate in response to high physical activity. Alterations in MuSC behavior occur when myofibers are damaged, but the lethal damage to myofibers does not seem to evoke mechanical loading-dependent MuSC activation and proliferation. Given that MuSCs proliferate without damage, it is unclear how the different behaviors of MuSCs are controlled by different physical activities. Recent studies demonstrated that myonuclear number reflects the size of myofibers; hence, it is crucial to know the properties of MuSCs and the mechanism of myonuclear accretion by MuSCs. In addition, the elucidation of mechanical load-dependent changes in muscle resident cells, including MuSCs, will be necessary for the discovery of new myokines/exerkines and understating skeletal muscle diseases.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukada</LastName><ForeName>So-Ichiro</ForeName><Initials>SI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Project for Muscle Stem Cell Biology, Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Osaka University, Suita, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Ayasa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Project for Muscle Stem Cell Biology, Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Osaka University, Suita, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Endocrinol Metab (Seoul)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101554139</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2093-596X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013234" MajorTopicYN="N">Stem Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, skeletal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal muscle satellite cells</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>CONFLICTS OF INTEREST</b>
. No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8419599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3803/EnM.2021.401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">EnM.2021.401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Caspersen CJ, Powell KE, Christenson GM. Physical activity, exercise, and physical fitness: definitions and distinctions for health-related research. Public Health Rep. 1985;100:126&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1424733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3920711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman JH, Smith LL, Gordon KL, Laranjeiro R, Driscoll M, Sherwood DR, et al. Swimming exercise and transient food deprivation in caenorhabditis elegans promote mitochondrial maintenance and protect against chemical-induced mitotoxicity. Sci Rep. 2018;8:8359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29844465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartee GD, Hepple RT, Bamman MM, Zierath JR. Exercise promotes healthy aging of skeletal muscle. Cell Metab. 2016;23:1034&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5045036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27304505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agudelo LZ, Femenia T, Orhan F, Porsmyr-Palmertz M, Goiny M, Martinez-Redondo V, et al. Skeletal muscle PGC-1&#x3b1;1 modulates kynurenine metabolism and mediates resilience to stress-induced depression. Cell. 2014;159:33&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25259918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen L, Idorn M, Olofsson GH, Lauenborg B, Nookaew I, Hansen RH, et al. Voluntary running suppresses tumor growth through epinephrine- and IL-6-dependent NK cell mobilization and redistribution. Cell Metab. 2016;23:554&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26895752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoi W, Naito Y, Takagi T, Tanimura Y, Takanami Y, Kawai Y, et al. A novel myokine, secreted protein acidic and rich in cysteine (SPARC), suppresses colon tumorigenesis via regular exercise. Gut. 2013;62:882&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22851666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinel C, Lukjanenko L, Batut A, Deleruyelle S, Pradere JP, Le Gonidec S, et al. The exerkine apelin reverses age-associated sarcopenia. Nat Med. 2018;24:1360&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30061698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son JS, Zhao L, Chen Y, Chen K, Chae SA, de Avila JM, et al. Maternal exercise via exerkine apelin enhances brown adipogenesis and prevents metabolic dysfunction in offspring mice. Sci Adv. 2020;6:eaaz0359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32494609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurens C, Parmar A, Murphy E, Carper D, Lair B, Maes P, et al. Growth and differentiation factor 15 is secreted by skeletal muscle during exercise and promotes lipolysis in humans. JCI Insight. 2020;5:e131870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7213799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32106110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy A, Bozi LHM, Yaghi OK, Mills EL, Xiao H, Nicholson HE, et al. pH-gated succinate secretion regulates muscle remodeling in response to exercise. Cell. 2020;183:62&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32946811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Roberts BM, Adams GR. Molecular regulation of exercise-induced muscle fiber hypertrophy. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2018;8:a029751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evano B, Tajbakhsh S. Skeletal muscle stem cells in comfort and stress. NPJ Regen Med. 2018;3:24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30588332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauro A. Satellite cell of skeletal muscle fibers. J Biophys Biochem Cytol. 1961;9:493&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2225012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13768451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepper C, Partridge TA, Fan CM. An absolute requirement for Pax7-positive satellite cells in acute injury-induced skeletal muscle regeneration. Development. 2011;138:3639&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sambasivan R, Yao R, Kissenpfennig A, Van Wittenberghe L, Paldi A, Gayraud-Morel B, et al. Pax7-expressing satellite cells are indispensable for adult skeletal muscle regeneration. Development. 2011;138:3647&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seale P, Sabourin LA, Girgis-Gabardo A, Mansouri A, Gruss P, Rudnicki MA. Pax7 is required for the specification of myogenic satellite cells. Cell. 2000;102:777&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11030621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irintchev A, Zeschnigk M, Starzinski-Powitz A, Wernig A. Expression pattern of M-cadherin in normal, denervated, and regenerating mouse muscles. Dev Dyn. 1994;199:326&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8075434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen GD, Sanes JR, LaChance R, Cunningham JM, Roman J, Dean DC. Roles for the integrin VLA-4 and its counter receptor VCAM-1 in myogenesis. Cell. 1992;69:1107&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1377605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco-Bose WE, Yao CC, Kramer RH, Blau HM. Purification of mouse primary myoblasts based on alpha 7 integrin expression. Exp Cell Res. 2001;265:212&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11302686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukada S, Ma Y, Ohtani T, Watanabe Y, Murakami S, Yamaguchi M. Isolation, characterization, and molecular regulation of muscle stem cells. Front Physiol. 2013;4:317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3824104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24273513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikemoto-Uezumi M, Uezumi A, Zhang L, Zhou H, Hashimoto N, Okamura K, et al. Reduced expression of calcitonin receptor is closely associated with age-related loss of the muscle stem cell pool. JCSM Rapid Commun. 2019;2:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukada S, Uezumi A, Ikemoto M, Masuda S, Segawa M, Tanimura N, et al. Molecular signature of quiescent satellite cells in adult skeletal muscle. Stem Cells. 2007;25:2448&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17600112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi M, Ogawa R, Watanabe Y, Uezumi A, Miyagoe-Suzuki Y, Tsujikawa K, et al. Calcitonin receptor and Odz4 are differently expressed in Pax7-positive cells during skeletal muscle regeneration. J Mol Histol. 2012;43:581&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22562803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakkalakal JV, Jones KM, Basson MA, Brack AS. The aged niche disrupts muscle stem cell quiescence. Nature. 2012;490:355&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23023126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono Y, Masuda S, Nam HS, Benezra R, Miyagoe-Suzuki Y, Takeda S. Slow-dividing satellite cells retain long-term self-renewal ability in adult muscle. J Cell Sci. 2012;125(Pt 5):1309&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22349695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Der Vartanian A, Quetin M, Michineau S, Aurade F, Hayashi S, Dubois C, et al. PAX3 confers functional heterogeneity in skeletal muscle stem cell responses to environmental stress. Cell Stem Cell. 2019;24:958&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6628901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31006622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocheteau P, Gayraud-Morel B, Siegl-Cachedenier I, Blasco MA, Tajbakhsh S. A subpopulation of adult skeletal muscle stem cells retains all template DNA strands after cell division. Cell. 2012;148:112&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22265406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang S, Kuroda K, Le Grand F, Rudnicki MA. Asymmetric self-renewal and commitment of satellite stem cells in muscle. Cell. 2007;129:999&#x2013;1010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17540178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaramozza A, Park D, Kollu S, Beerman I, Sun X, Rossi DJ, et al. Lineage tracing reveals a subset of reserve muscle stem cells capable of clonal expansion under stress. Cell Stem Cell. 2019;24:944&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6597014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31006621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Prat L, Perdiguero E, Alonso-Martin S, Dell&#x2019;Orso S, Ravichandran S, Brooks SR, et al. FoxO maintains a genuine muscle stem-cell quiescent state until geriatric age. Nat Cell Biol. 2020;22:1307&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33106654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motohashi N, Uezumi A, Asakura A, Ikemoto-Uezumi M, Mori S, Mizunoe Y, et al. Tbx1 regulates inherited metabolic and myogenic abilities of progenitor cells derived from slow- and fast-type muscle. Cell Death Differ. 2019;26:1024&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6748120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30154444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evano B, Gill D, Hernando-Herraez I, Comai G, Stubbs TM, Commere PH, et al. Transcriptome and epigenome diversity and plasticity of muscle stem cells following transplantation. PLoS Genet. 2020;16:e1009022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33125370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Akimoto T, Zhang M, Williams RS, Yan Z. Resident stem cells are not required for exercise-induced fiber-type switching and angiogenesis but are necessary for activity-dependent muscle growth. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2006;290:C1461&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16407413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masschelein E, D&#x2019;Hulst G, Zvick J, Hinte L, Soro-Arnaiz I, Gorski T, et al. Exercise promotes satellite cell contribution to myofibers in a load-dependent manner. Skelet Muscle. 2020;10:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7346400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto M, Legendre NP, Biswas AA, Lawton A, Yamamoto S, Tajbakhsh S, et al. Loss of MyoD and Myf5 in skeletal muscle stem cells results in altered myogenic programming and failed regeneration. Stem Cell Reports. 2018;10:956&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5918368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uezumi A, Fukada S, Yamamoto N, Takeda S, Tsuchida K. Mesenchymal progenitors distinct from satellite cells contribute to ectopic fat cell formation in skeletal muscle. Nat Cell Biol. 2010;12:143&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20081842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joe AW, Yi L, Natarajan A, Le Grand F, So L, Wang J, et al. Muscle injury activates resident fibro/adipogenic progenitors that facilitate myogenesis. Nat Cell Biol. 2010;12:153&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4580288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20081841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uezumi A, Ito T, Morikawa D, Shimizu N, Yoneda T, Segawa M, et al. Fibrosis and adipogenesis originate from a common mesenchymal progenitor in skeletal muscle. J Cell Sci. 2011;124(Pt 21):3654&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22045730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JJ, Mula J, Miyazaki M, Erfani R, Garrison K, Farooqui AB, et al. Effective fiber hypertrophy in satellite cell-depleted skeletal muscle. Development. 2011;138:3657&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englund DA, Murach KA, Dungan CM, Figueiredo VC, Vechetti IJ, Jr, Dupont-Versteegden EE, et al. Depletion of resident muscle stem cells negatively impacts running volume, physical function, and muscle fiber hypertrophy in response to lifelong physical activity. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2020;318:C1178&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7311742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukada SI, Akimoto T, Sotiropoulos A. Role of damage and management in muscle hypertrophy: different behaviors of muscle stem cells in regeneration and hypertrophy. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Res. 2020;1867:118742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32417255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda S, Kaneshige A, Kaji T, Noguchi YT, Takemoto Y, Zhang L, et al. Sustained expression of HeyL is critical for the proliferation of muscle stem cells in overloaded muscle. Elife. 2019;8:e48284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6768661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31545169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darr KC, Schultz E. Exercise-induced satellite cell activation in growing and mature skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1987;63:1816&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3693217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs E, Blau HM. Tissue stem cells: architects of their niches. Cell Stem Cell. 2020;27:532&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7861346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Noguchi YT, Nakayama H, Kaji T, Tsujikawa K, Ikemoto-Uezumi M, et al. The CalcR-PKA-Yap1 axis is critical for maintaining quiescence in muscle stem cells. Cell Rep. 2019;29:2154&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31747590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi M, Watanabe Y, Ohtani T, Uezumi A, Mikami N, Nakamura M, et al. Calcitonin receptor signaling inhibits muscle stem cells from escaping the quiescent state and the niche. Cell Rep. 2015;13:302&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26440893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornson CR, Cheung TH, Liu L, Tripathi PV, Steeper KM, Rando TA. Notch signaling is necessary to maintain quiescence in adult muscle stem cells. Stem Cells. 2012;30:232&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22045613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourikis P, Sambasivan R, Castel D, Rocheteau P, Bizzarro V, Tajbakhsh S. A critical requirement for notch signaling in maintenance of the quiescent skeletal muscle stem cell state. Stem Cells. 2012;30:243&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22069237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noguchi YT, Nakamura M, Hino N, Nogami J, Tsuji S, Sato T, et al. Cell-autonomous and redundant roles of Hey1 and HeyL in muscle stem cells: HeyL requires Hes1 to bind diverse DNA sites. Development. 2019;146:dev163618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahmann I, Brohl D, Zyrianova T, Isomura A, Czajkowski MT, Kapoor V, et al. Oscillations of MyoD and Hes1 proteins regulate the maintenance of activated muscle stem cells. Genes Dev. 2019;33:524&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6499323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30862660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukada S, Yamaguchi M, Kokubo H, Ogawa R, Uezumi A, Yoneda T, et al. Hesr1 and Hesr3 are essential to generate undifferentiated quiescent satellite cells and to maintain satellite cell numbers. Development. 2011;138:4609&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3265560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21989910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimaki S, Seko D, Kitajima Y, Yoshioka K, Tsuchiya Y, Masuda S, et al. Notch1 and notch2 coordinately regulate stem cell function in the quiescent and activated states of muscle satellite cells. Stem Cells. 2018;36:278&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29139178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno S, Yoda M, Shimoda M, Tohmonda T, Okada Y, Toyama Y, et al. A disintegrin and metalloprotease 10 (ADAM10) is indispensable for maintenance of the muscle satellite cell pool. J Biol Chem. 2015;290:28456&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4653702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26453297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zammit PS, Golding JP, Nagata Y, Hudon V, Partridge TA, Beauchamp JR. Muscle satellite cells adopt divergent fates: a mechanism for self-renewal? J Cell Biol. 2004;166:347&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2172269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15277541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Fry CS, Mula J, Kirby TJ, Jackson JR, Liu F, et al. Aged muscle demonstrates fiber-type adaptations in response to mechanical overload, in the absence of myofiber hypertrophy, independent of satellite cell abundance. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2016;71:461&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5175449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25878030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikemoto-Uezumi M, Uezumi A, Tsuchida K, Fukada S, Yamamoto H, Yamamoto N, et al. Pro-insulin-like growth factor-II ameliorates age-related inefficient regenerative response by orchestrating self-reinforcement mechanism of muscle regeneration. Stem Cells. 2015;33:2456&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25917344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukjanenko L, Karaz S, Stuelsatz P, Gurriaran-Rodriguez U, Michaud J, Dammone G, et al. Aging disrupts muscle stem cell function by impairing matricellular WISP1 secretion from fibro-adipogenic progenitors. Cell Stem Cell. 2019;24:433&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6408230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30686765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brett JO, Arjona M, Ikeda M, Quarta M, de Morree A, Egner IM, et al. Exercise rejuvenates quiescent skeletal muscle stem cells in old mice through restoration of cyclin D1. Nat Metab. 2020;2:307&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32601609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, Nederveen JP, Baker JM, Snijders T, Iacono C, Parise G. Exercise conditioning in old mice improves skeletal muscle regeneration. FASEB J. 2016;30:3256&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor RS, Pavlath GK. Point: counterpoint: satellite cell addition is/is not obligatory for skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2007;103:1099&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17289912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JJ, Dupont-Versteegden EE, Fry CS, Murach KA, Peterson CA. Methodological issues limit interpretation of negative effects of satellite cell depletion on adult muscle hypertrophy. Development. 2017;144:1363&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egner IM, Bruusgaard JC, Gundersen K. Satellite cell depletion prevents fiber hypertrophy in skeletal muscle. Development. 2016;143:2898&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27531949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Lee JD, Jackson JR, Kirby TJ, Stasko SA, Liu H, et al. Regulation of the muscle fiber microenvironment by activated satellite cells during hypertrophy. FASEB J. 2014;28:1654&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24376025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh Q, Millay DP. Requirement of myomaker-mediated stem cell fusion for skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Elife. 2017;6:e20007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5338923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28186492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh Q, Song T, Petrany MJ, Cramer AA, Sun C, Sadayappan S, et al. Myonuclear accretion is a determinant of exercise-induced remodeling in skeletal muscle. Elife. 2019;8:e44876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6497442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31012848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriya N, Miyazaki M. Akt1 deficiency diminishes skeletal muscle hypertrophy by reducing satellite cell proliferation. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2018;314:R741&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29443546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randrianarison-Huetz V, Papaefthymiou A, Herledan G, Noviello C, Faradova U, Collard L, et al. Srf controls satellite cell fusion through the maintenance of actin architecture. J Cell Biol. 2018;217:685&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5800804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29269426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer AAW, Prasad V, Eftestol E, Song T, Hansson KA, Dugdale HF, et al. Nuclear numbers in syncytial muscle fibers promote size but limit the development of larger myonuclear domains. Nat Commun. 2020;11:6287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33293533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson KA, Eftestol E, Bruusgaard JC, Juvkam I, Cramer AW, Malthe-Sorenssen A, et al. Myonuclear content regulates cell size with similar scaling properties in mice and humans. Nat Commun. 2020;11:6288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33293572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White RB, Bierinx AS, Gnocchi VF, Zammit PS. Dynamics of muscle fibre growth during postnatal mouse development. BMC Dev Biol. 2010;10:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2836990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20175910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>