<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38953795</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increased Neuromuscular Activity, Force Output, and Resistance Exercise Volume When Using 5-Minute Compared with 2-Minute Rest Intervals Between the Sets.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1527</StartPage><EndPage>1534</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1527-1534</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004832</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>McMahon, G, Best, N, Coulter, T, and Erskine, RM. Increased neuromuscular activation, force output and resistance exercise volume when using 5-minute compared with 2-minute rest intervals between the sets. J Strength Cond Res 38(9): 1527-1534, 2024-Longer rest intervals between resistance exercise (RE) sets may promote greater muscle hypertrophy and strength gains over time by facilitating the completion of greater training volume and intensity. However, little is known about the acute neuromuscular responses to RE sets incorporating longer vs. shorter rest intervals. Using a within-subject, crossover design, 8 healthy, young subjects completed 2 separate acute bouts of 4 sets of 8 &#xd7; 3-s maximal isometric contractions using either a 2-minute (REST-2) or 5-minute (REST-5) rest interval between sets. Peak torque (PT) and electromyography (EMG) were measured pre and 5 minutes postexercise. Peak torque and mean torque (MT), EMG, mean, and median frequencies were measured during each set, whereas blood lactate (BLa), heart rate (HR), and rating of perceived exertion (RPE) were measured following each set. Peak torque and MT were lower ( p &lt; 0.05) in sets 3 and 4, and sets 2-4 in REST-2 compared with REST-5, respectively. Electromyography and BL were lower and higher, respectively, in REST-2 vs. REST-5. There was no main effect of condition on HR or RPE. Pre-to-post exercise reductions in PT (-17 &#xb1; 9% vs. -4 &#xb1; 7%) and EMG (-29 &#xb1; 14% vs. -10 &#xb1; 7%) were greater ( p &lt; 0.001) in REST-2 vs. REST-5. Total exercise volume was less in REST-2 vs. REST-5 (9,748 &#xb1; 2296 N&#xb7;m -1 vs. 11,212 &#xb1; 2513 N&#xb7;m -1 , p &lt; 0.001). These results suggest that incorporating 5-minute between-set rest intervals into a resistance exercise session facilitates improved neuromuscular function, increased exercise volume, and less metabolic stress compared with 2-minute rest intervals. Thus, 5-minute rest intervals may be more efficacious for promoting muscle hypertrophy and strength gains in a chronic resistance training program.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McMahon</LastName><ForeName>Gerard</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise Sciences Research Institute, School of Sport, Ulster University, Belfast, Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Best</LastName><ForeName>Nathan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise Sciences Research Institute, School of Sport, Ulster University, Belfast, Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coulter</LastName><ForeName>Timothy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise Sciences Research Institute, School of Sport, Ulster University, Belfast, Northern Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erskine</LastName><ForeName>Robert M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport, Exercise and Health, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>33X04XA5AT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019344">Lactic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rest</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="Y">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019415" MajorTopicYN="Y">Torque</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019344" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lactic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38953795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202409000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Short vs. long rest period between the sets in hypertrophic resistance training: Influence on muscle strength, size, and hormonal adaptations in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 19: 572&#x2013;582, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besomi M, Hodges PW, Clancy EA, et al. Consensus for experimental design in electromyography (CEDE) project: Amplitude normalization matrix. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 53: 102438, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis GC, Nevill ME, Boobis LH, Lakomy HK, Nevill AM. Recovery of power output and muscle metabolites following 30 s of maximal sprint cycling in man. J Physiol 482: 467&#x2013;480, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol 588: 3119&#x2013;3130, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burden A. How should we normalize electromyograms obtained from healthy participants? What we have learned from over 25 years of research. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 20: 1023&#x2013;1035, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Herbert RD, Munn J, Lee M, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral strength training: Evidence and possible mechanisms. J Appl Physiol 101: 1514&#x2013;1522, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. New York: Routledge, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Sim&#xe3;o R, Miranda H, Bottaro M, Fontana F, Willardson JM. Strength increases in upper and lower body are larger with longer inter-set rest intervals in trained men. J Sci Med Sport 13: 429&#x2013;433, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Rate coding and the control of muscle force. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med 7: a029702, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG. J Appl Physiol 96: 1486&#x2013;1495, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faulkner JA, Davis CS, Mendias CL, Brooks SV. The aging of elite male athletes: Age-related changes in performance and skeletal muscle structure and function. Clin J Sport Med 18: 501&#x2013;507, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med 48: 499&#x2013;505, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Krieger JW, Schoenfeld BJ. The effects of short versus long inter-set rest intervals in resistance training on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 983&#x2013;993, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: A systematic review. Sports Med 48: 137&#x2013;151, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatanaka S, Ishii N. Effect of resistance training mainly depends on mechanical activation of fast-twitch fiber. J Phys Fitness Sports Med 11: 295&#x2013;303, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez DJ, Healy S, Giacomini ML, Kwon YS. Effect of rest interval duration on the volume completed during a high-intensity bench press exercise. J Strength Cond Res 35: 2981&#x2013;2987, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson D, Vann C, Schoenfeld BJ, Haun C. Beyond mechanical tension: A review of resistance exercise-induced lactate responses &amp; muscle hypertrophy. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 7: 81, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo AR, Silva-Batista C, Pedroso K, et al. Volume load rather than resting interval influences muscle hypertrophy during high-intensity resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1554&#x2013;1559, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntosh BR, Holash RJ, Renaud J-M. Skeletal muscle fatigue&#x2013;regulation of excitation&#x2013;contraction coupling to avoid metabolic catastrophe. J Cell Sci 125: 2105&#x2013;2114, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKendry J, P&#xe9;rez&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez A, McLeod M, et al. Short inter&#x2010;set rest blunts resistance exercise&#x2010;induced increases in myofibrillar protein synthesis and intracellular signalling in young males. Exp Physiol 101: 866&#x2013;882, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon G, Morse CI, Burden AB, Winwood K, Onambele GL. Impact of range-of-motion during ecologically valid resistance training protocols, on muscle size, subcutaneous fat and strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 245&#x2013;255, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda H, Sim&#xe3;o R, dos Santos Vig&#xe1;rio P, de Salles BF, Pacheco MTT, Willardson JM. Exercise order interacts with rest interval during upper-body resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1573&#x2013;1577, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaei B, Arazi H, Saberi Y. The effect of different rest intervals on sustainability of bench press repetitions with heavy vs light loads. Int J Fit 4: 9&#x2013;16, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Pinto MD, Nosaka K, Steele J. Maximal number of repetitions at percentages of the one repetition maximum: A meta-regression and moderator analysis of sex, age, training status, and exercise. Sports Med 54: 303&#x2013;321, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincivero DM, Lephart SM, Karunakara RG. Effects of rest interval on isokinetic strength and functional performance after short-term high intensity training. Br J Sports Med 31: 229&#x2013;234, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi R. Effect of different rest intervals on the exercise volume completed during squat bouts. J Sports Sci Med 4: 361&#x2013;366, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Falvo MJ, Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Faigenbaum AD, Kang J. The effect of rest interval length on metabolic responses to the bench press exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 100: 1&#x2013;17, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raue U, Trappe TA, Estrem ST, et al. Transcriptome signature of resistance exercise adaptations: Mixed muscle and fiber type specific profiles in young and old adults. J Appl Physiol 112: 1625&#x2013;1636, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, McCarthy JJ, Hornberger TA, et al. Mechanisms of mechanical overload-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Current understanding and future directions. Physiol Rev 103: 2679&#x2013;2757, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Reggiani C, Akimoto T, Blaauw B. Molecular mechanisms of skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J Neuromuscul Dis 8: 169&#x2013;183, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schott J, McCully K, Rutherford OM. The role of metabolites in strength training: II. Short versus long isometric contractions. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 71: 337&#x2013;341, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senna G, Willardson JM, de Salles BF, et al. The effect of rest interval length on multi and single-joint exercise performance and perceived exertion. J Strength Cond Res 25: 3157&#x2013;3162, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza-Junior TP, Willardson JM, Bloomer R, et al. Strength and hypertrophy responses to constant and decreasing rest intervals in trained men using creatine supplementation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 8: 17, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srikanthan P, Karlamangla AS. Muscle mass index as a predictor of longevity in older adults. Am J Med 127: 547&#x2013;553, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G, Spengos K, Mascher H, Georgiadis G, Manta P, Blomstrand E. The degree of p70 S6k and S6 phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle in response to resistance exercise depends on the training volume. Eur J Appl Physiol 110: 835&#x2013;843, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 126: 30&#x2013;43, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Nawaz M, DuPont C, et al. The role of action potential changes in depolarization-induced failure of excitation contraction coupling in mouse skeletal muscle. Elife 11: e71588, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. A comparison of 3 different rest intervals on the exercise volume completed during a workout. J Strength Cond Res 19: 23&#x2013;26, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. The effect of different rest intervals between sets on volume components and strength gains. J Strength Cond Res 22: 146&#x2013;152, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe RR. The underappreciated role of muscle in health and disease. Am J Clin Nutr 84: 475&#x2013;482, 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>