<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32569127</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance Training Volume Enhances Muscle Hypertrophy, but Not Strength in Postmenopausal Women: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1216</StartPage><EndPage>1221</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1216-1221</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003601</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nascimento de Oliveira J&#xfa;nior, G, de Freitas Rodrigues de Sousa, J, Augusto da Silva Carneiro, M, Martins, FM, Santagnello, SB, Campos Souza, MV, and Orsatti, FL. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy, but not strength in postmenopausal women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 36(5): 1216-1221, 2022-Among several possible resistance training (RT) variables to be manipulated, the training volume has been considered as a critical variable to maximize RT-induced hypertrophy. Many of the studies that compared one set of RT with 3 sets have failed to show a difference in muscle hypertrophy in older adults. However, it is not clear whether further increases in RT volume (i.e., 6 sets) would result in even greater RT-related hypertrophy than 3 sets in older adults. This study aimed to investigate whether higher-volume RT (HV-RT) maximizes gains in lean body mass and muscle strength (MS) when compared with lower-volume RT (LV-RT) in postmenopausal women (PW). Fifty-eight PW were randomized into 1 of the 3 groups: control group (CT, no exercise), HV-RT (6 sets per exercise), and LV-RT (3 sets per exercise). Volunteers took part in a supervised training program (leg press 45&#xb0;, leg extension, leg curl and standing calf raises) and were assessed for leg lean mass (LLM; dual X-ray absorptiometry) and lower limb MS (leg press and leg extension; 1 repetition maximum [1RM]) before and after 12 weeks of RT. Both HV-RT and LV-RT groups increased (p &lt; 0.05) LLM and MS when compared with the CT group. Higher increases in LLM gains were observed for the HV-RT group when compared with the LV-RT group (6.1 and 2.3%, p &lt; 0.001). Both HV-RT and LV-RT groups similarly increased 1RM in the leg press and leg extension. Thus, there seems to be a dose-response relationship between RT volume and muscle hypertrophy, but not for MS gains in PW.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nascimento de Oliveira-J&#xfa;nior</LastName><ForeName>Gersiel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biology Research Group (BioEx), Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Sousa</LastName><ForeName>Jairo de Freitas Rodrigues</ForeName><Initials>JFR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biology Research Group (BioEx), Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carneiro</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo Augusto da Silva</ForeName><Initials>MADS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martins</LastName><ForeName>Fernanda Maria</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biology Research Group (BioEx), Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santagnello</LastName><ForeName>Samarita Beraldo</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biology Research Group (BioEx), Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souza</LastName><ForeName>Markus Vinicius Campos</ForeName><Initials>MVC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biology Research Group (BioEx), Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Health Science Institute, Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orsatti</LastName><ForeName>F&#xe1;bio Lera</ForeName><Initials>FL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Biology Research Group (BioEx), Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Health Science Institute, Federal University of Triangulo Mineiro (UFTM), Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="N">Postmenopause</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32569127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202205000-00007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Argiles JM, Campos N, Lopez-Pedrosa JM, et al. Skeletal muscle regulates metabolism via interorgan crosstalk: Roles in health and disease. J Am Med Dir Assoc 17: 789&#x2013;796, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Massey GJ, Maden-Wilkinson TM, et al. Changes in agonist neural drive, hypertrophy and pre-training strength all contribute to the individual strength gains after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 631&#x2013;640, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckinx F, Landi F, Cesari M, et al. Pitfalls in the measurement of muscle mass: A need for a reference standard. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 9: 269&#x2013;278, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, et al. The problem of muscle hypertrophy: Revisited. Muscle Nerve 54: 1012&#x2013;1014, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Gorissen SH, van Loon LJ. Anabolic resistance of muscle protein synthesis with aging. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 41: 169&#x2013;173, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chodzko-Zajko WJ, Proctor DN, Fiatarone Singh MA, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 1510&#x2013;1530, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Breen L, Phillips SM. Alterations in human muscle protein metabolism with aging: Protein and exercise as countermeasures to offset sarcopenia. Biofactors 40: 199&#x2013;205, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins BC, Laakkonen EK, Lowe DA. Aging of the musculoskeletal system: How the loss of estrogen impacts muscle strength. Bone 123: 137&#x2013;144, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper R, Mishra G, Clennell S, et al. Menopausal status and physical performance in midlife: Findings from a British birth cohort study. Menopause 15: 1079&#x2013;1085, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa CS, Teixeira BC, Cobos RC, et al. High-volume resistance training reduces postprandial lipaemia in postmenopausal women. J Sports Sci 33: 1890&#x2013;1901, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: Revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing 48: 16&#x2013;31, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha PM, Nunes JP, Tomeleri CM, et al. Resistance training performed with single and multiple sets induces similar improvements in muscular strength, muscle mass, muscle quality, and IGF-1 in older women: A randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1008&#x2013;1016, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips S, Vechin FC, et al. A review of resistance training-induced changes in skeletal muscle protein synthesis and their contribution to hypertrophy. Sports Med 45: 801&#x2013;807, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Counts BR, Barnett BE, et al. Muscle adaptations following 21 consecutive days of strength test familiarization compared with traditional training. Muscle Nerve 56: 307&#x2013;314, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Fletcher G, Folland JP. The contribution of muscle hypertrophy to strength changes following resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 1239&#x2013;1249, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Ochala J. Skeletal muscle: A brief review of structure and function. Calcif Tissue Int 96: 183&#x2013;195, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvao DA, Taaffe DR. Resistance exercise dosage in older adults: Single- versus multiset effects on physical performance and body composition. J Am Geriatr Soc 53: 2090&#x2013;2097, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YH, Kim KI, Paik NJ, et al. Muscle strength: A better index of low physical performance than muscle mass in older adults. Geriatr Gerontol Int 16: 577&#x2013;585, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Bamman MM. Modulation of the dystrophin-associated protein complex in response to resistance training in young and older men. J Appl Physiol 104: 1476&#x2013;1484, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, et al. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol 101: 531&#x2013;544, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuh D, Bassey EJ, Butterworth S, et al. Grip strength, postural control, and functional leg power in a representative cohort of British men and women: Associations with physical activity, health status, and socioeconomic conditions. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 60: 224&#x2013;231, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Atherton PJ, Selby A, et al. Muscle protein synthetic responses to exercise: Effects of age, volume, and intensity. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 67: 1170&#x2013;1177, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Selby A, Rankin D, et al. Age-related differences in the dose-response relationship of muscle protein synthesis to resistance exercise in young and old men. J Physiol 587: 211&#x2013;217, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltais ML, Desroches J, Dionne IJ. Changes in muscle mass and strength after menopause. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 9: 186&#x2013;197, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougios V. Muscle activity. In: Exercise Biochemistry. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics Publishers, 2019. pp. 143&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahas PC, Rossato LT, Martins FM, et al. Moderate increase in protein intake promotes a small additional improvement in functional capacity, but not in muscle strength and lean mass quality, in postmenopausal women following resistance exercise: A randomized clinical trial. Nutrients 11: E1323, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes PRP, Barcelos LC, Oliveira AA, et al. Muscular strength adaptations and hormonal responses after two different multiple-set protocols of resistance training in postmenopausal women. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1276&#x2013;1285, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsatti FL, de Oliveira EP, Burini RC. Relationship between plasma hormones and anthropometric measures of muscle mass in postmenopausal women. In: Handbook of Anthropometry. New York, NY:Springer, 2012. pp. 1481&#x2013;1490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Sen A, Gordon PM. Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: A meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 249&#x2013;258, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Botton CE, Wilhelm EN, et al. Time course of low- and high-volume strength training on neuromuscular adaptations and muscle quality in older women. Age (Dordr) 36: 881&#x2013;892, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Wilhelm EN, Botton CE, et al. Effects of single vs. multiple-set short-term strength training in elderly women. Age (Dordr) 36: 9720, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Naumova EN, Carabello RJ, et al. Lower extremity muscle mass predicts functional performance in mobility-limited elders. J Nutr Health Aging 12: 493&#x2013;498, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Pina FL, et al. Resistance training in older women: Comparison of single vs. multiple sets on muscle strength and body composition. Isokinet Exerc Sci 23: 53&#x2013;60, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothney MP, Martin FP, Xia Y, et al. Precision of GE Lunar iDXA for the measurement of total and regional body composition in nonobese adults. J Clin Densitom 15: 399&#x2013;404, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos L, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. The improvement in walking speed induced by resistance training is associated with increased muscular strength but not skeletal muscle mass in older women. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 488&#x2013;494, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sc Sports Exerc 51: 94&#x2013;103, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D. CONSORT 2010 statement: Updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMJ 340: c332, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza DC, Viana RB, Coswig VS, et al. Comment on: Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med 48: 1281&#x2013;1284, 2018.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>