<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30063556</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Traditional and Vascular Restricted Strength Training Program With Equalized Volume on Isometric and Dynamic Strength, Muscle Thickness, Electromyographic Activity, and Endothelial Function Adaptations in Young Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>689</StartPage><EndPage>698</EndPage><MedlinePgn>689-698</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002717</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ramis, TR, Muller, CHdL, Boeno, FP, Teixeira, BC, Rech, A, Pompermayer, MG, Medeiros, NdS, Oliveira, &#xc1;Rd, Pinto, RS, and Ribeiro, JL. Effects of traditional and vascular restricted strength training program with equalized volume on isometric and dynamic strength, muscle thickness, electromyographic activity, and endothelial function adaptations in young adults. J Strength Cond Res 34(3): 689-698, 2020-The purpose of the study was to evaluate and compare the acute and chronic effects of partial vascular occlusion training in young, physically active adults. Neuromuscular, morphological, and endothelial function responses were compared between high-intensity resistance training (HI-RT) and low-intensity resistance training with partial vascular occlusion (LI-BFR), despite the same training volume. The 28 subjects (age, 23.96 &#xb1; 2.67 years) were randomly assigned into 2 groups: LI-BFR (n = 15) and HI-RT (n = 13). Both groups performed unilateral exercise of elbow flexion (EF) and knee extension (KE) 3 times per week for 8 weeks. This study was approved by the ethics committee. Flow-mediated dilation showed a significant difference in baseline and post-training in the LI-BFR group (4.44 &#xb1; 0.51 vs. 6.35 &#xb1; 2.08 mm, respectively). For nitrite/nitrate concentrations only, there was a significant difference when comparing pre- and post-acute exercise in both groups. The torque and rep. Sixty percent 1 repetition maximum had improvements in both groups. There were differences between groups only in isometric delta EF and isokinetic delta KE (EF 3.42 &#xb1; 5.09 and 9.61 &#xb1; 7.52 N&#xb7;m; KE 12.78 &#xb1; 25.61 and 42.69 &#xb1; 35.68 N&#xb7;m; LI-BFR and HI-RT groups, respectively). There was a significant increase of muscle thickness in both groups. An increase of both isokinetic and isometric electromyography (EMG) of biceps of the HI-RT group was observed. The same was observed for the LI-BFR group regarding isokinetic and isometric EMG of vastus lateralis. Thus, in addition to strength and hypertrophy gains, this study also shows benefits related to vascular function. For practical applications, this study demonstrates a clinical importance of LI-BFR training as an alternative methodology.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramis</LastName><ForeName>Thiago Rozales</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IPA Methodist University Center, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muller</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Henrique de Lemos</ForeName><Initials>CHL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IPA Methodist University Center, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boeno</LastName><ForeName>Francesco Pinto</ForeName><Initials>FP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IPA Methodist University Center, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Bruno Costa</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rech</LastName><ForeName>Anderson</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pompermayer</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo Gava</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Medeiros</LastName><ForeName>Niara da Silva</ForeName><Initials>NDS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IPA Methodist University Center, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>&#xc1;lvaro Reischak de</ForeName><Initials>&#xc1;R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Ronei Silveira</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Jerri Luiz</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IPA Methodist University Center, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001132" MajorTopicYN="N">Arm</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004727" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="Y">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019415" MajorTopicYN="N">Torque</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202003000-00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Yasuda T, Midorikawa T, Sato Y, Kearns CF, Inoue K, et al. Skeletal muscle size and circulating IGF-1 are increased after 2 weeks of twice daily &#x201c;KAATSU&#x201d; resistance training. Int J KAATSU Train Res 1: 6&#x2013;12, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson T, Kearney JT. Effects of three resistance training programs on muscular strength and absolute and relative endurance. Res Q Exerc Sport 53: 1&#x2013;7, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashor AW, Lara J, Siervo M, Celis-Morales C, Mathers JC. Effects of exercise modalities on arterial stiffness and wave reflection: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS One 9: e110034, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton PJ, Babraj J, Smith K, Singh J, Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H. Selective activation of AMPK-PGC-1alpha or PKB-TSC2-mTOR signaling can explain specific adaptive responses to endurance or resistance training-like electrical muscle stimulation. FASEB J 19: 786&#x2013;788, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkinson CL, Carter HH, Dawson EA, Naylor LH, Thijssen DH, Green DJ. Impact of handgrip exercise intensity on brachial artery flow-mediated dilation. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 1705&#x2013;1713, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botton CE, Radaelli R, Wilhelm EN, Rech A, Brown LE, Pinto RS. Neuromuscular adaptations to unilateral vs. bilateral strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1924&#x2013;1932, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 50&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lemos Muller CH, Ramis TR, Ribeiro JL. Comparison of the effects of resistance training with and without vascular occlusion in increases of strength and hypertrophy: A review of the literature. Sports Med J 11: 2668&#x2013;2675, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doshi SN, Naka KK, Payne N, Jones CJ, Ashton M, Lewis MJ, et al. Flow-mediated dilatation following wrist and upper arm occlusion in humans: The contribution of nitric oxide. Clin Sci 101: 629&#x2013;635, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs ME, Hackney KJ, Martin D, Caine TL, Cunningham D, O'Connor DP, et al. Acute vascular and cardiovascular responses to blood flow-restricted exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 1489&#x2013;1497, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, Cadenas JG, Dreyer HC, Sato Y, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol 103: 903&#x2013;910, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Soares SR, Pereira MC, da Cunha RR, Martorelli SS, Martorelli AS, et al. Effect of adding single-joint exercises to a multi-joint exercise resistance-training program on strength and hypertrophy in untrained subjects. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 38: 341&#x2013;344, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godawa TM, Credeur DP, Welsch MA. Influence of compressive gear on powerlifting performance: Role of blood flow restriction training. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1274&#x2013;1280, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb AH, Garten RS, Chee PD, Cho C, Reeves GV, Hollander DB, et al. Resistance exercise effects on blood glutathione status and plasma protein carbonyls: Influence of partial vascular occlusion. Eur J Appl Physiol 104: 813&#x2013;819, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzales JU, Thompson BC, Thistlethwaite JR, Scheuermann BW. Association between exercise hemodynamics and changes in local vascular function following acute exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 36: 137&#x2013;144, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi M, Okita K. Blood flow restricted exercise and vascular function. Int J Vasc Med 2012: 543218, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Bemben DA, Sherk VD, Anderson MA, Abe T, Bemben MG. Effects of high-intensity resistance training and low-intensity resistance training with vascular restriction on bone markers in older men. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 1659&#x2013;1667, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korhonen MT, Mero AA, Alen M, Sipila S, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Liikavainio T, et al. Biomechanical and skeletal muscle determinants of maximum running speed with aging. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 844&#x2013;856, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JB, Stone MH, O'Bryant HS, Conley MS, Johnson RL, Nieman DC, et al. Effects of single vs. multiple sets of weight training: Impact of volume, intensity and variation. J Strength Cond Res 11: 143&#x2013;147, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota A, Sakuraba K, Koh S, Ogura Y, Tamura Y. Blood flow restriction by low compressive force prevents disuse muscular weakness. J Sci Med Sport 14: 95&#x2013;99, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumagai K, Abe T, Brechue WF, Ryushi T, Takano S, Mizuno M. Sprint performance is related to muscle fascicle length in male 100-m sprinters. J Appl Physiol 88: 811&#x2013;816, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, Aoki MS, Soares AG, Neves M Jr, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc 44: 406&#x2013;412, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Abe T, Wilson JM, Ugrinowitsch C, Bemben MG. Blood flow restriction: how does it work? Front Physiol 3: 392, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Abe T, Bemben MG. The anabolic benefits of venous blood flow restriction training may be induced by muscle cell swelling. Med Hypotheses 78: 151&#x2013;154, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson GJ, Wilson JM. A mechanistic approach to blood flow occlusion. Int J Sports Med 31: 1&#x2013;4, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Zourdos MC, Bemben MG. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: A meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1849&#x2013;1859, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marfell-Jones TO, Stewart A, Carter L. International standards for anthropometric assessment. Glasgow, Scotland: International Society Advancement of Kinanthropometry, 2006. pp. 21&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Hernandez J, Marin PJ, Menendez H, Ferrero C, Loenneke JP, Herrero AJ. Muscular adaptations after two different volumes of blood flow-restricted training. Scand J Med Sci Sports 23: e114&#x2013;e120, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda KM, Espey MG, Wink DA. A rapid, simple spectrophotometric method for simultaneous detection of nitrate and nitrite. Nitric Oxide 5: 62&#x2013;71, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Ferguson RA. Increase in calf post-occlusive blood flow and strength following short-term resistance exercise training with blood flow restriction in young women. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 1025&#x2013;1033, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce JR, Clark BC, Ploutz-Snyder LL, Kanaley JA. Growth hormone and muscle function responses to skeletal muscle ischemia. J Appl Physiol 101: 1588&#x2013;1595, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Bottaro M, Wilhelm EN, Wagner DR, Pinto RS. Time course of strength and echo intensity recovery after resistance exercise in women. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2577&#x2013;2584, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinohara M, Kouzaki M, Yoshihisa T, Fukunaga T. Efficacy of tourniquet ischemia for strength training with low resistance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 77: 189&#x2013;191, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takano H, Morita T, Iida H, Asada K, Kato M, Uno K, et al. Hemodynamic and hormonal responses to a short-term low-intensity resistance exercise with the reduction of muscle blood flow. Eur J Appl Physiol 95: 65&#x2013;73, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol 88: 61&#x2013;65, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thijssen DH, Black MA, Pyke KE, Padilla J, Atkinson G, Harris RA, et al. Assessment of flow-mediated dilation in humans: A methodological and physiological guideline. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 300: 15, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki M, Ozaki H, Sato Y, Abe T. Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 2525&#x2013;2533, 2011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>