<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33475986</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chronic Effects of Altering Resistance Training Set Configurations Using Cluster Sets: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>707</StartPage><EndPage>736</EndPage><MedlinePgn>707-736</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-020-01408-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The acute responses to cluster set resistance training (RT) have been demonstrated. However, as compared to traditional sets, the effect of cluster sets on muscular and neuromuscular adaptations remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the effects of RT programs implementing cluster and traditional set configurations on muscular and neuromuscular adaptations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic searches of Embase, Scopus, Medline and SPORTDiscus were conducted. Inclusion criteria were: (1) randomized or non-randomized comparative studies; (2) publication in English; (3) participants of all age groups; (4) participants free of any medical condition or injury; (5) cluster set intervention; (6) comparison intervention utilizing a traditional set configuration; (7) intervention length&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;three weeks and (8) at least one measure of changes in strength/force/torque, power, velocity, hypertrophy or muscular endurance. Raw data (mean&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;SD or range) were extracted from included studies. Hedges' g effect sizes (ES)&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;standard error of the mean (SEM) and 95% confidence intervals (95% CI) were calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-nine studies were included in the meta-analysis. No differences between cluster and traditional set configurations were found for strength (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.05&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.10, 95% CI -&#x2009;0.21 to 0.11, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.56), power output (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.10, 95% CI -&#x2009;0.17 to 0.20, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.86), velocity (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.15&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.13, 95% CI -&#x2009;0.10 to 0.41, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.24), hypertrophy (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.05&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.14, 95% CI -&#x2009;0.32 to 0.23, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.73) or endurance (ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.07&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.18, 95% CI -&#x2009;0.43 to 0.29, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.70) adaptations. Moreover, no differences were observed when training volume, cluster set model, training status, body parts trained or exercise type were considered.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Collectively, both cluster and traditional set configurations demonstrate equal effectiveness to positively induce muscular and neuromuscular adaptation(s). However, cluster set configurations may achieve such adaptations with less fatigue development during RT which may be an important consideration across various exercise settings and stages of periodized RT programs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davies</LastName><ForeName>Timothy B</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3798-2445</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sport Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health, Sydney School of Health Sciences, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, 2050, Australia. timothy.davies@sydney.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Derek L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3274-363X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sport Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health, Sydney School of Health Sciences, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, 2050, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Medical School, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Royal Prince Alfred Hospital, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hogan</LastName><ForeName>Clorinda M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0293-263X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Discipline of Exercise and Sport Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health, Sydney School of Health Sciences, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, 2050, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haff</LastName><ForeName>G Gregory</ForeName><Initials>GG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0676-7750</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Directorate of Physiotherapy and Sport, University of Salford, Greater Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Latella</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5857-9671</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurophysiology Research Laboratory, School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33475986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01408-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-020-01408-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ, et al. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1419&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin J, Sleivert G. Challenges in understanding the influence of maximal power training on improving athletic performance. Sports Med. 2005;35(3):213&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15730337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Evidence-based guidelines for resistance training volume to maximize muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J. 2017;40:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granacher U, Lesinski M, B&#xfc;sch D, Muehlbauer T, Prieske O, Puta C, et al. Effects of resistance training in youth athletes on muscular fitness and athletic performance: a conceptual model for long-term athlete development. Front Physiol. 2016;7:164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27242538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4861005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Brown LE, Haff GG. Theoretical and practical aspects of different cluster set structures: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(3):848&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Burgess S, Stone M. Cluster training: theoretical and practical applications for the strength and conditioning professional. Prof Strength Cond. 2008;12:12&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2005;37:955&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawton T, Cronin J, Drinkwater E, Lindsell R, Pyne D. The effect of continuous repetition training and intra-set rest training on bench press strength and power. J Sport Med Phys Fit. 2004;44(4):361&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Loenneke JP. Do metabolites that are produced during resistance exercise enhance muscle hypertrophy? Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(11):2125&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28776271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roll F, Omer J. FOOTBALL: Tulane football winter program. Strength Cond J. 1987;9(6):34&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller C, Alderwick K. Cluster training. In: The sport of Olympic-style Weightlifting: training for the connoisseur. 1st ed. Sante Fe: Sunstone Press; 2011. p. 89&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Whitley A, McCoy LB, O&#x2019;Bryant HS, Kilgore JL, Haff EE, et al. Effects of different set configurations on barbell velocity and displacement during a clean pull. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(1):95&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Teo W-P, Drinkwater EJ, Kendall K, Haff GG. The acute neuromuscular responses to cluster set resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49(3):1861&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31506904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6851217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo X, Iglesias-Soler E, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Del-Olmo M. Effects of set configuration of resistance exercise on perceived exertion. Percept Mot Skills. 2014;119(3):825&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25456248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, Brown LE, Banyard HG, Williamson BD, et al. Cluster sets: permitting greater mechanical stress without decreasing relative velocity. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(4):463&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27617387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, Brown LE, Seitz LB, Williamson BD, et al. Maintenance of velocity and power with cluster sets during high-volume back squats. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(7):885&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Casta&#xf1;o-Zambudio A, Capelo-Ram&#xed;rez F, Marquez G, Boullosa D, et al. Mechanical, metabolic, and perceptual acute responses to different set configurations in full squat. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(6):1581&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28700515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy J, Oliver J, McCleary S, Lowery R, Wilson JR. Power output and electromyography activity of the back squat exercise with cluster sets. J Sports Sci. 2013;1:37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen KT, Cronin JB, Pickering SL, Newton MJ. Does cluster loading enhance lower body power development in preseason preparation of elite rugby union players? J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(8):2118&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney KJ, Herbert RD, Balnave RJ. Fatigue contributes to the strength training stimulus. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1994;26(9):1160&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7808251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarezadeh-Mehrizi A, Aminai M, Amiri-khorasani M. Effects of traditional and cluster resistance training on explosive power in soccer players. Iran J Health Phys Act. 2013;4(1):51&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias RKN, Penna EM, Noronha ASN, de Azevedo ABC, Barbalho M, Gentil PV, et al. Cluster-sets resistance training induce similar functional and strength improvements than the traditional method in postmenopausal and elderly women. Exp Gerontol. 2020;138:111011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Jagim AR, Sanchez AC, Mardock MA, Kelly KA, Meredith HJ, et al. Greater gains in strength and power with intraset rest intervals in hypertrophic training. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(11):3116&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23736782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samson A, Pillai PS. Effect of cluster training versus traditional training on muscular strength among recreationally active males: a comparative study. Indian J Physiother Occup Ther. 2018;12(1):122&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Halaki M, Orr R, Helms ER, Hackett DA. Changes in bench press velocity and power after 8 weeks of high-load cluster-or traditional-set structures. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(10):2734&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsten B, Fu YL, Larumbe-Zabala E, Seijo M, Naclerio F. Impact of two high-volume set configuration workouts on resistance training outcomes in recreationally trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019. (Epub ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson G, Ispoglou T, Bissas A. The impact of repetition mechanics on the adaptations resulting from strength-, hypertrophy-and cluster-type resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(10):1875&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27473446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5020128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Lawrence MM, Zwetsloot KA, Triplett NT, Utter AC, McBride JM. Effect of cluster set configurations on power clean technique. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(5):488&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23121475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi A, Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo R. Effects of cluster vs. traditional plyometric training sets on maximal-intensity exercise performance. Medicina. 2016;52(1):41&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26987499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Ibanez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Hakkinen K, Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, et al. Differential effects of strength training leading to failure versus not to failure on hormonal responses, strength, and muscle power gains. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100(5):1647&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16410373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. BMJ. 2009;339:b2535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2714657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covidence systematic review software, Veritas Health Innovation, Melbourne, Australia. Available at http://www.covidence.org .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Waldron M, Ismail H, Giallauria F, Vigorito C, Cornelissen V, et al. Validation of a new tool for the assessment of study quality and reporting in exercise training studies: TESTEX. Int J Evid Based Healthc. 2015;13(1):9&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25734864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson D, Turner R. Power analysis for random-effects meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2017;8(3):290&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28378395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5590730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315(7109):629&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2127453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood JA. Methodology for dealing with duplicate study effects in a meta-analysis. Organ Res Methods. 2007;11(1):79&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG. Quantifying workloads in resistance training: a brief review. Strength Cond J. 2010;10:31&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Mayo X, R&#xed;o-Rodr&#xed;guez D, Carballeira E, Fari&#xf1;as J, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Del-Olmo M. Inter-repetition rest training and traditional set configuration produce similar strength gains without cortical adaptations. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(15):1473&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26630355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Artacho AJ, Padial P, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, P&#xe9;rez-Castilla A, Feriche B. Influence of a cluster set configuration on the adaptations to short-term power training. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(4):930&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29570595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani S, Aminaei M, Amirseifadini M. Effects of plyometric and cluster resistance training on explosive power and maximum strength in karate players. Int J Appl Exerc Physiol. 2017;6:34&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd R, Centry R, Boatwright D. Effect of inter-repetition rest intervals in circuit weight training on PWC170 during arm-kranking exercise. J Sport Med Phys Fit. 1988;28(4):336&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas-Aburto J, Jukic I, Chirosa-R&#xed;os LJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Janicijevic D, Barboza-Gonz&#xe1;lez P, et al. Effect of traditional, cluster, and rest redistribution set configurations on neuromuscular and perceptual responses during strength-oriented resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2020. (Epub ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korak JA, Paquette MR, Brooks J, Fuller DK, Coons JM. Effect of rest&#x2013;pause vs. traditional bench press training on muscle strength, electromyography, and lifting volume in randomized trial protocols. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(9):1891&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Khanmohammadi A, Asadi A, Haff GG. The effect of resistance training set configuration on strength, power, and hormonal adaptation in female volleyball players. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(2):154&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29017017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carneiro MAS, de Oliveira J&#xfa;nior GN, de Sousa JFR, Santagnello SB, Souza MVC, Orsatti FL. Effects of cluster training sets on muscle power and force&#x2013;velocity relationship in postmenopausal women. Sport Sci for Health. 2019;16:257&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Halaki M, Orr R, Mitchell L, Helms ER, Clarke J, et al. Effect of set-structure on upper-body muscular hypertrophy and performance in recreationally-trained males and females. J Strength Cond Res. 2020. (Epub ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fari&#xf1;as J, Mayo X, Giraldez-Garc&#xed;a MA, Carballeira E, Fernandez-Del-Olmo M, Rial-Vazquez J, et al. Set configuration in strength training programs modulates the cross education phenomenon. J Strength Cond Res. 2019. (Epud ahead of print).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Irish C, Roberts J, Tarr J, Jones DA. Fatigue is not a necessary stimulus for strength gains during resistance training. Br J Sports Med. 2002;36(5):370&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12351337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1724546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giessing J, Fisher J, Steele J, Rothe F, Raubold K, Eichmann B. The effects of low volume resistance training with and without advanced techniques in trained participants. J Sport Med Phys Fit. 2016;56(3):249&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Fern&#xe1;ndez-del-Olmo M, Mayo X, Fari&#xf1;as J, R&#xed;o-Rodr&#xed;guez D, Carballeira E, et al. Changes in the force-velocity mechanical profile after short resistance training programs differing in set configurations. J Appl Biomech. 2017;33(2):144&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, Tibana RA, de Araujo SE, da Cunha ND, de Oliveira RP, Camar&#xe7;o NF, et al. Strength and muscular adaptations after 6 weeks of rest&#x2013;pause vs. traditional multiple-sets resistance training in trained subjects. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:S113&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28617715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rial-V&#xe1;zquez J, Mayo X, Tufano JJ, Fari&#xf1;as J, R&#xfa;a-Alonso M, Iglesias-Soler E. Cluster vs. traditional training programmes: changes in the force&#x2013;velocity relationship. Sport Biomech. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1080/14763141.2020.1718197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2020.1718197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stragier S, Baudry S, Carpentier A, Duchateau J. Efficacy of a new strength training design: the 3/7 method. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(5):1093&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30756168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver JM, Kreutzer A, Jenke S, Phillips MD, Mitchell JB, Jones MT. Acute response to cluster sets in trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(11):2383&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26183257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira J, Dias MR, Lacio M, Schimitz G, Nascimento G, Panza P, et al. Resistance training with repetition to failure or not on muscle strength and perceptual responses. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2019;22:165&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbett TJ. The training&#x2014;injury prevention paradox: should athletes be training smarter and harder? Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(5):273&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4789704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Tufano JJ. Shorter but more frequent rest periods: no effect on velocity and power compared to traditional sets not performed to failure. J Hum Kinet. 2019;66(1):257&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30988859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6458590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconcelos GC, Costa BDDV, Damorim IR, Santos TM, Cyrino ES, Junior DDL, et al. Do traditional and cluster-set resistance training systems alter the pleasure and effort perception in trained men? J Phys Educ Sport. 2019;19:823&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Conlon JA, Nimphius S, Oliver JM, Kreutzer A, Haff GG. Different cluster sets result in similar metabolic, endocrine, and perceptual responses in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(2):346&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28301435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Developing maximal neuromuscular power. Sports Med. 2011;41(1):17&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21142282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcazar J, Guadalupe-Grau A, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a FJ, Ara I, Alegre LM. Skeletal muscle power measurement in older people: a systematic review of testing protocols and adverse events. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2018;73(7):914&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29309534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrissey MC, Harman EA, Johnson MJ. Resistance training modes: specificity and effectiveness. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27(5):648&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7674868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MI, Gomes PS. Movement velocity in resistance training. Sports Med. 2003;33(6):427&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12744716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther B, Keogh J, Cronin J, Cook C. Possible stimuli for strength and power adaptation. Sports Med. 2006;36(3):215&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16526834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Lawrence MM, Utter AC, Triplett NT, Zwetsloot KA, McBride JM. Effect of inter-repetition rest on ratings of perceived exertion during multiple sets of the power clean. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(8):3141&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22215288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber C, Bellon C, Abbott H, Bingham GE. Roles of maximal strength and rate of force development in maximizing muscular power. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;38(1):71&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride JM, Kirby TJ, Haines TL, Skinner J. Relationship between relative net vertical impulse and jump height in jump squats performed to various squat depths and with various loads. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(4):484&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin JB, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, Brughelli M, Samozino P. When jump height is not a good indicator of lower limb maximal power output: theoretical demonstration, experimental evidence and practical solutions. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):999&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30805913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins ND, Housh TJ, Buckner SL, Bergstrom HC, Cochrane KC, Hill EC, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations after 2 and 4 weeks of 80% versus 30% 1 repetition maximum resistance training to failure. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(8):2174&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26848545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, Grgic J, Delcastillo K, Belliard R, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low-vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio FJ, Colado JC, Rhea MR, Bunker D, Triplett NT. The influence of strength and power on muscle endurance test performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(5):1482&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19620916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assuncao AR, Bottaro M, Ferreira-Junior JB, Izquierdo M, Cadore EL, Gentil P. The chronic effects of low-and high-intensity resistance training on muscular fitness in adolescents. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(8):e0160650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27509050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4979886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Sonmez G, Alvar BA. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(10):2909&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24714538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanchi NE, Lancha AH. Mechanical stimuli of skeletal muscle: Implications on mTOR/p70s6k and protein synthesis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102(3):253&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17940791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormick R, Vasilaki A. Age-related changes in skeletal muscle: changes to life-style as a therapy. Biogerontology. 2018;19(6):519&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30259289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6223729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rier HN, Jager A, Sleijfer S, Maier AB, Levin M-D. The prevalence and prognostic value of low muscle mass in cancer patients: a review of the literature. Oncologist. 2016;21(11):1396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27412391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5189631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Comfort P. Technical demands of strength training. In: Turner A, Comfort P, editors. Advanced strength and conditioning: an evidence-based approach. New York: Routledge; 2018. p. 249&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong H, Jiang Q, Shen D, Gao J. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation improves exercise capacity in adult patients with chronic lung disease: a meta-analysis of English studies. J Thorac Dis. 2018;10(12):6722&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30746217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6344727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones LW, Eves ND, Haykowsky M, Freedland SJ, Mackey JR. Exercise intolerance in cancer and the role of exercise therapy to reverse dysfunction. Lancet Oncol. 2009;10(6):598&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19482248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias-Soler E, Boullosa DA, Carballeira E, S&#xe1;nchez-Otero T, Mayo X, Castro-Gacio X, et al. Effect of set configuration on hemodynamics and cardiac autonomic modulation after high-intensity squat exercise. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2015;35(4):250&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24774862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro-Torres O, de Sousa AFM, Iglesias-Soler E, Fontes-Villalba M, Zouhal H, Carr&#xe9; F, et al. Lower cardiovascular stress during resistance training performed with inter-repetition rests in elderly coronary patients. Medicina. 2020;56(6):264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7353896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(3):367&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20861526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K, Deakin GB, Bentley DJ. Implications of impaired endurance performance following single bouts of resistance training: an alternate concurrent training perspective. Sports Med. 2017;47(11):2187&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branscheidt M, Kassavetis P, Anaya M, Rogers D, Huang HD, Lindquist MA, et al. Fatigue induces long-lasting detrimental changes in motor-skill learning. eLife. 2019;8:e40578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6443347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>