<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36871095</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of resistance training in hypoxia on muscle hypertrophy and strength development: a systematic review with meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3676</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3676</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3676</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-023-30808-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A systematic review and meta-analysis was conducted to determine the effects of resistance training under hypoxic conditions (RTH) on muscle hypertrophy and strength development. Searches of PubMed-Medline, Web of Science, Sport Discus and the Cochrane Library were conducted comparing the effect of RTH versus normoxia (RTN) on muscle hypertrophy (cross sectional area (CSA), lean mass and muscle thickness) and strength development [1-repetition maximum (1RM)]. An overall meta-analysis and subanalyses of training load (low, moderate or high), inter-set rest interval (short, moderate or long) and severity of hypoxia (moderate or high) were conducted to explore the effects on RTH outcomes. Seventeen studies met inclusion criteria. The overall analyses showed similar improvements in CSA (SMD [CIs]&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.17 [-&#x2009;0.07; 0.42]) and 1RM (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.13 [0.0; 0.27]) between RTH and RTN. Subanalyses indicated a medium effect on CSA for longer inter-set rest intervals and a small effect for moderate hypoxia and moderate loads favoring RTH. Moreover, a moderate effect for longer inter-set rest intervals and a trivial effect for severe hypoxia and moderate loads favoring RTH was found on 1RM. Evidence suggests that RTH employed with moderate loads (60-80% 1RM) and longer inter-set rest intervals (&#x2265;&#x2009;120&#xa0;s) enhances muscle hypertrophy and strength compared to normoxia. The use of moderate hypoxia (14.3-16% FiO<sub>2</sub>) seems to be somewhat beneficial to hypertrophy but not strength. Further research is required with greater standardization of protocols to draw stronger conclusions on the topic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benavente</LastName><ForeName>Cristina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5154-8602</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4979-5783</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, CUNY Lehman College, The Bronx, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Padial</LastName><ForeName>Paulino</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0847-7378</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feriche</LastName><ForeName>Bel&#xe9;n</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3933-6041</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Sport Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain. mbelen@ugr.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Sci Rep. 2023 Sep 20;13(1):15619. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-42611-2.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37730803</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049851" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastropoda</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000860" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoxia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009132" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>BJS serves on the scientific advisory board for Tonal Corporation, a manufacturer of fitness equipment. The other authors do not have any competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36871095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-30808-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-023-30808-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Faigenbaum AD, French DN, Lloyd RS, Kraemer WJ. Strength and Conditioning for Young Athletes. Routledge; 2019. Strength and power training for young athletes; pp. 131&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2004;36:674&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedmann B, et al. Effects of low-resistance/high-repetition strength training in hypoxia on muscle structure and gene expression. Pflugers Arch. 2003;446:742&#x2013;751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12861415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, et al. Effects of acute hypoxia on metabolic and hormonal responses to resistance exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1279&#x2013;1285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura A, et al. Hypoxia increases muscle hypertrophy induced by resistance training. Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 2010;5:497&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurobe K, et al. Effects of resistance training under hypoxic conditions on muscle hypertrophy and strength. Clin. Physiol. Funct. Imaging. 2015;35:197&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24690432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf6;rpel A, Peter B, Schega L. Effect of resistance training under normobaric hypoxia on physical performance, hematological parameters, and body composition in young and older people. Front. Physiol. 2020;11:335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7198789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Hamlin MJ, Ross JJ, Taylor R, Manimmanakorn N. Effects of low-load resistance training combined with blood flow restriction or hypoxia on muscle function and performance in netball athletes. J. Sci. Med. Sport. 2013;16:337&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22999393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Intermittent hypoxic resistance training: Does it provide added benefit? Front. Physiol. 2014;5:397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4195285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25352810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feriche B, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Morales-Artacho A, Padial P. Resistance training using different hypoxic training strategies: A basis for hypertrophy and muscle power development. Sports Med. 2017;3:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5357242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28315193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ikeda T, Homma T, Suzuki Y. Effects of low-intensity resistance exercise under acute systemic hypoxia on hormonal responses. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2012;26:611&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22310510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 2013;43:179&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23338987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ikeda T, Homma T, Suzuki Y. Responses of angiogenic regulators to resistance exercise under systemic hypoxia. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2021;35:436&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30199444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo D, et al. Acute physiological and performance responses to high-intensity resistance circuit training in hypoxic and normoxic conditions. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2017;31:1040&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inness MW, et al. Heavy resistance training in hypoxia enhances 1RM squat performance. Front. Physiol. 2016;7:502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5093137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27857693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo DJ, Scott BR, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias JA. The efficacy of resistance training in hypoxia to enhance strength and muscle growth: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2018;18:92&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29045191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L. Does normobaric hypoxic resistance training confer benefit over normoxic training in athletes? A narrative review. J. Sci. Sport Exerc. 2022;2022(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pae CU. Why systematic review rather than narrative review? Psychiatry Investig. 2015;12:417&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4504929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26207140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M, McKenzie J, Bossuyt P. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Syst. Rev. 2021;10:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, et al. Resistance training-induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. J. Physiol. 2016;594:5209&#x2013;5222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5023708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27219125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho J-Y, Kuo T-Y, Liu K-L, Dong X-Y, Tung K. Combining normobaric hypoxia with short-term resistance training has no additive beneficial effect on muscular performance and body composition. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2014;28:935&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohatgi, A. WebPlotDigitizer Version 4.5. Preprint at (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Altman D, G&#xf8;tzsche P. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher C, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys. Ther. 2003;83:713&#x2013;721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ. Res. Methods. 2008;11:364&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges, L. V. &amp; Olkin, I. Statistical methods for meta&#x2010;analysis (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrer M, Cuijpers P, Furukawa TA, Ebert DD. Doing Meta-Analysis With R: A Hands-On Guide. Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC Press; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DerSimonian R, Lair N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clin. Trials. 1986;7:177&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3802833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, et al. Slow and steady, or hard and fast? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies comparing body composition changes between interval training and moderate intensity continuous training. Sports. 2021;9:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8619923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34822354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amrhein V, Greenland S, McShane B. Scientists rise up against statistical significance. Nature. 2019;567:305&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McShane BB, Gal D, Gelman A, Robert C, Tackett JL. Abandon statistical significance. Am. Stat. 2019;73:235&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol. Bull. 1992;112:155&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315:629&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J., Thomas, J., Chandler, J., Cumpston, M. &amp; Li, T. <i>Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions</i> (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor Package. J. Stat. Softw. 2010;36:1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Development Core Team. R: A language and environment for statistical computing. Preprint at (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, et al. Effects of resistance training combined with vascular occlusion or hypoxia on neuromuscular function in athletes. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2013;113:1767&#x2013;1774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23412543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo D, et al. Muscle architecture and neuromuscular changes after high-resistance circuit training in hypoxia. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2019;35:3035&#x2013;3040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Guardado I, et al. Effects of strength training under hypoxic conditions on muscle performance, body composition and haematological variables. Biol. Sport. 2020;37:121&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chycki J, et al. Neuroendocrine responses and body composition changes following resistance training under normobaric hypoxia. J. Hum. Kinet. 2016;53:91&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5260579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28149414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda A, Kon M, Matsubayashi T, Suzuki Y. Short-term intermittent hypoxic resistance training does not impair osteogenic response in sea level residents. High Alt. Med. Biol. 2020;21:160&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32013568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Doorslaer de ten Ryen S, et al. Higher strength gain after hypoxic vs normoxic resistance training despite no changes in muscle thickness and fractional protein synthetic rate. FASEB J. 2021;35:e21773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34324735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo B, Miles C, Sims S, Driller M. The effect of resistance training in a hypoxic chamber on physical performance in elite rugby athletes. High Alt. Med. Biol. 2018;19:28&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29161094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan B, Lai X, Yi L, Wang Y, Hu Y. Effects of five-week resistance training in hypoxia on hormones and muscle strength. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2016;30:184&#x2013;8011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26691409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Guardado I, et al. Effects of high-intensity resistance circuit-based training in hypoxia on body composition and strength performance. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 2019;19:941&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30638154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, et al. Effects of systemic hypoxia on human muscular adaptations to resistance exercise training. Physiol. Rep. 2014;2:e12033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24907297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fashi M, Ahmadizad S. Short-term hypoxic resistance training improves muscular performance in untrained males. Sci. Sports. 2021 doi: 10.1016/j.scispo.2020.10.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2020.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2010;24:2857&#x2013;2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Intermittent hypoxic resistance training: Is metabolic stress the key moderator ? Med. Hypotheses. 2015;84:145&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25547781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary P, et al. Chronic hypobaric hypoxia mediated skeletal muscle atrophy: Role of ubiquitin-proteasome pathway and calpains. Mol. Cell Biochem. 2012;364:101&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22215202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R, Thome R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med. 2007;37:225&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17326698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavoian D, Ampomah K, Amano S, Law TD, Clark BC. Changes in DXA-derived lean mass and MRI-derived cross-sectional area of the thigh are modestly associated. Sci. Rep. 2019;9:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6624257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31296891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alix-Fages C, Del Vecchio A, Baz-Valle E, Santos-Concejero J, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C. The role of the neural stimulus in regulating skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2022;122:1111&#x2013;1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35138447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am. J. Phys. Med. 1979;58:115&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">453338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaister M. Multiple sprint work: Physiological responses, mechanisms of fatigue and the influence of aerobic fitness. Sports Med. 2005;35:757&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16138786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: A systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48:137&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GP, Debevec T. CrossTalk proposal: Barometric pressure, independent of PO2, is the forgotten parameter in altitude physiology and mountain medicine. J. Physiol. 2020;598:893&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32053239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>