<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32168178</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Comparison Between Total Body and Split Routine Resistance Training Programs in Trained Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1520</StartPage><EndPage>1526</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1520-1526</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003573</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bartolomei, S, Nigro, F, Malagoli Lanzoni, I, Masina, F, Di Michele, R, and Hoffman, JR. A comparison between total body and split routine resistance training programs in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 35(6): 1520-1526, 2021-The purpose of the present investigation was to compare the effects of total body (TB) versus split routine (SR) resistance training workouts on maximal strength and muscle hypertrophy in trained men. Twenty-one resistance-trained men were randomly assigned to either a TB (TB: age = 24.1 &#xb1; 4.4 years; body mass = 78.7 &#xb1; 11.3 kg; body height = 177.0 &#xb1; 3.9 cm) or the SR group (SR: age = 24.9 &#xb1; 4.2 years; body mass = 79.2 &#xb1; 9.5 kg; body height = 175.2 &#xb1; 6.0 cm). Both groups performed a 10-week resistance training program. Isokinetic bench press at 75 and 25 cm&#xb7;s-1 (ISOK75 and ISOK25, respectively), isometric bench press (ISOBP), isometric squat (ISOSQ), and one repetition maximum BP and SQ assessments were performed before and after training. Muscle thickness of the pectoralis major (PECMT), superior part of trapezius (TRAPMT), and vastus lateralis (VLMT) muscles was also evaluated at the same timepoints using ultrasonography. Improvements were observed in both groups for all strength assessments and muscle thicknesses. Only changes in ISOK25 were significantly (p = 0.015) greater in TB than in SR, while significantly greater (p = 0.037) changes in VLMT were detected in SR compared with TB. Results indicated that a TB training paradigm may be more appropriate for maximal strength improvement, while an SR training protocol may be more optimal in stimulating muscle growth in experienced, resistance-trained men.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bartolomei</LastName><ForeName>Sandro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Neuromotor Sciences, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nigro</LastName><ForeName>Federico</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Life Quality Studies, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malagoli Lanzoni</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Life Quality Studies, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masina</LastName><ForeName>Federico</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Life Quality Studies, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Michele</LastName><ForeName>Rocco</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Neuromotor Sciences, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Jay R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Biology, Ariel University, Ariel, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32168178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202106000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amirthalingam T, Mavros Y, Wilson GC, et al. Effects of a modified German volume training program on muscular hypertrophy and strength. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3109&#x2013;3119, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Di Michele RD, Merni F. Effects of self-selected music on maximal bench press strength and strength endurance. Percept Mot Skills 120: 714&#x2013;721, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Totti V, Griggio F, et al. Upper-Body resistance exercise reduces time to recover after a high-volume bench press protocol in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 2021;35(Suppl 1):S180&#x2013;S187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Sadres E, Church DD, et al. Comparison of the recovery response from high-intensity and high-volume resistance exercise in trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 1287&#x2013;1298, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder AW, Chilibeck PD, Webber CE, Sale DG. Comparison of whole and split weight training routines in young women. Can J Appl Physiol 19: 185&#x2013;199, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Burke DG. Effect of short-term equal-volume resistance training with different workout frequency on muscle mass and strength in untrained men and women. J Strength Cond Res 21: 204&#x2013;207, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun RJ, Gai CM, Aguilar D, et al. Training volume, not frequency, indicative of maximal strength adaptations to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1207&#x2013;1213, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Barcelos C, N&#xf3;brega SR, et al. Individual muscle hypertrophy and strength responses to high vs. low resistance training frequencies. J Strength Cond Res 33: 897&#x2013;901, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, et al. Frequency: The overlooked resistance training variable for inducing muscle hypertrophy? Sports Med 47: 799&#x2013;805, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans EM, Rowe DA, Misic MM, Prior BM, Arngr&#xed;msson SA. Skinfold prediction equation for athletes developed using a four-component model. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 2006&#x2013;2011, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everett G. Olympic Weightlifting: A Complete Guide for Athletes and Coaches. Sunnyvale, CA: Catalyst Athletics, 2009. pp. 230&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer W. Designing Resistance Training Programs, 4E. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2014. pp. 225&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC, Schilling BK, Staron RS, et al. Muscle fiber characteristics and performance correlates of male Olympic-style weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res 17: 746&#x2013;754, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Hoffman JR, Townsend JR, et al. Intramuscular anabolic signaling and endocrine response following high volume and high intensity resistance exercise protocols in trained men. Physiol Rep 3: pii: e12466, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto KA, Ishii NA, Kizuka TO, Takamatsu KA. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 955&#x2013;963, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotshalk LA, Loebel CC, Nindl BC, et al. Hormonal responses of multiset versus single-set heavy-resistance exercise protocols. Can J Appl Physiol 22: 244&#x2013;255, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green SB, Salkind NJ, Jones TM. Using SPSS for Windows; Analyzing and Understanding Data. Prentice Hall PTR, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, et al. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 1207&#x2013;1220, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1609&#x2013;1617, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J. Physiological Aspects of Sport Training and Performance. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2014. pp. 120&#x2013;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Kraemer WJ, Fry AC, Deschenes M, Kemp M. The effects of self-selection for frequency of training in a winter conditioning program for football. J Strength Cond Res 4: 76&#x2013;82, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Campbell BI, et al. Early-phase adaptations to a split-body, linear periodization resistance training program in college-aged and middle-aged men. J Strength Cond Res 23: 962&#x2013;971, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Newton RU. Training for muscular power. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am 11: 341&#x2013;368, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Gonzalez AM, et al. Exercise-induced hormone elevations are related to muscle growth. J Strength Cond Res 31: 45&#x2013;53, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLester JR, Bishop E, Guilliams ME. Comparison of 1 day and 3 days per week of equal-volume resistance training in experienced subjects. J Strength Cond Res 14: 273&#x2013;281, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochi E, Maruo M, Tsuchiya Y, et al. Higher training frequency is important for gaining muscular strength under volume-matched training. Front Physiol 9: 744, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan C, Meaney J, Boyle G, Gormley J, Stokes M. The validity of rehabilitative ultrasound imaging for measurement of trapezius muscle thickness. Man Ther 14: 572&#x2013;578, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2585&#x2013;2601, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Burkett LN, Ball SD. A meta-analysis to determine the dose response for strength development. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 456&#x2013;464, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effects of resistance training frequency on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 1689&#x2013;1697, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, et al. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2909&#x2013;2918, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Influence of resistance training frequency on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1821&#x2013;1829, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Sands WA, Stone ME. Weightlifting: Program design. Strength Cond J 28: 10&#x2013;17, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med 37: 225&#x2013;264, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Klemp A, Dolan C, et al. Novel resistance training&#x2013;specific rating of perceived exertion scale measuring repetitions in reserve. J Strength Cond Res 30: 267&#x2013;275, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fujita S, Ogasawara R, Sato Y, Abe T. Effects of low-intensity bench press training with restricted arm muscle blood flow on chest muscle hypertrophy: A pilot study. Clin Physiol Funct Imag 30: 338&#x2013;343, 2010.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>