<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29795731</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Baseline Muscle Strength and Size Measures on Training Adaptations in Resistance-trained Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>198</StartPage><EndPage>213</EndPage><MedlinePgn>198-213</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The influence of baseline strength or muscle size on adaptations to training is not well-understood. Comparisons between novice and advanced lifters, and between stronger and weaker experienced-lifters, have produced conflicting results. This study examined the effect of baseline muscle strength and size on subsequent adaptations in resistance-trained individuals following a traditional high-volume, short-rest resistance training protocol. Fourteen resistance-trained men (24.0&#xb1;2.7 y; 90.1&#xb1;11.7 kg; 169.9&#xb1;29.0 cm) completed pre-training (PRE) ultrasound measurements of muscle cross-sectional area (CSA) in the rectus femoris (RF), vastus lateralis (VL), pectoralis major, and triceps brachii (TRI) prior to strength assessments (e.g., one-repetition maximum strength bench press and back-squat). Post-training (POST) assessments were completed following 8-wks (4 d&#xb7;wk<sup>-1</sup>) of resistance training. Comparisons were made between stronger (STR) and weaker (WKR) participants, and between larger (LGR) and smaller (SMR) participants, based upon PRE-muscle strength and size, respectively. When groups were based on upper-body strength, repeated measures analysis of variance indicated a significant group &#xd7; time interaction where greater improvements in bench press strength were observed in WKR (12.5&#xb1;8.6%, p = 0.013) compared to STR (1.3&#xb1;5.4%, p=0.546). Within this comparison, STR also possessed more resistance training experience than WKR (mean difference=3.1 y, p=0.002). No other differences in experience or adaptations to training were observed. These data suggest that following a short-duration training program (8-weeks), baseline size and strength have little impact on performance gains in resistance-trained individuals who possess similar years of experience. However, when training experience is different, baseline strength may affect adaptations.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mangine</LastName><ForeName>Gerald T</ForeName><Initials>GT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science and Sport Management, Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Adam M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Professions, Hofstra University, Hempstead, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Townsend</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Nutrition Science, Lipscomb University, Nashville, TN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wells</LastName><ForeName>Adam J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beyer</LastName><ForeName>Kyle S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miramonti</LastName><ForeName>Amelia A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratamess</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health &amp; Exercise Science, The College of New Jersey, Ewing, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stout</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Jay R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training experience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">short-duration resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength adaptations</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5955287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/UGMJ3157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adams GR, Bamman MM. Characterization and regulation of mechanical loading-induced compensatory muscle hypertrophy. Comp Physiol. 2012;2(4):2829&#x2013;2870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23720267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Muscle hypertrophy, hormonal adaptations and strength development during strength training in strength-trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89(6):555&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen D, Whitehead N, Yeung E. Mechanisms of stretch-induced muscle damage in normal and dystrophic muscle: role of ionic changes. J Physiol. 2005;567(3):723&#x2013;735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16002444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appleby B, Newton RU, Cormie P. Changes in strength over a 2-year period in professional rugby union players. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(9):2538&#x2013;2546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22076095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle T, Earle R, Wathen M. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Human Kinetics; 2008. Resistance Training; pp. 381&#x2013;410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DG. 10-year changes in upper body strength and power in elite professional rugby league players&#x2014;The effect of training age, stage, and content. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(2):285&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23358318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DG, Newton RU. Adaptations in upper-body maximal strength and power output resulting from long-term resistance training in experienced strength-power athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):541&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomstrand E, Eliasson J, Karlsson HK, K&#xf6;hnke R. Branched-chain amino acids activate key enzymes in protein synthesis after physical exercise. J Nutr. 2006;136(1):269S&#x2013;273S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobbert M, Gerritsen K, Litjens M, Van Soest A. Why is countermovement jump height greater than squat jump height? Occupational Health and Industrial Medicine. 1997;2(36):93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8933491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Nosaka K, Braun B. Muscle function after exercise-induced muscle damage and rapid adaptation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24(5):512&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1569847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Influence of strength on magnitude and mechanisms of adaptation to power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(8):1566&#x2013;1581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20639724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidsen PK, Gallagher IJ, Hartman JW, Tarnopolsky MA, Dela F, Helge JW, Timmons JA, Phillips SM. High responders to resistance exercise training demonstrate differential regulation of skeletal muscle microRNA expression. J Appl Physiol. 2011;110(2):309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21030674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>deVries HA. &#x201c;Efficiency of electrical activity&#x201d; as a physiological measure of the functional state of muscle tissue. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 1968;47(1):10&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5644315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WJ. Effects of exercise on senescent muscle. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2002;403:S211&#x2013;S220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12394471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher IJ, Scheele C, Keller P, Nielsen AR, Remenyi J, Fischer CP, Roder K, Babraj J, Wahlestedt C, Hutvagner G. Integration of microRNA changes in vivo identifies novel molecular features of muscle insulin resistance in type 2 diabetes. Genome Med. 2010;2(2):9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2847700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20353613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Nimphius S. Training principles for power. Strength and Conditioning Journal. 2012;34(6):2&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. 4th Edition. Human kinetics; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, Komi P. Changes in isometric force-and relaxation-time, electromyographic and muscle fibre characteristics of human skeletal muscle during strength training and detraining. Acta Physiol Scand. 1985;125(4):573&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4091001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Komi P, Tesch P. Effect of combined concentric and eccentric strength training and detraining on force-time, muscle fiber and metabolic characteristics of leg extensor muscles. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 1981;3:50&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR. Human Kinetics. 2006. Norms for Fitness, Performance, and Health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR. Physiological Aspects of Sport Training and Performance. 2nd ed. Human Kinetics; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Kang J. Performance changes during a college playing career in NCAA division III football athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(9):2351&#x2013;2357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, Price TB, Hoffman EP, Angelopoulos TJ, Gordon PM, Moyna NM, Pescatello LS, Visich PS. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(6):964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Gonzalez AM, Townsend JR, Wells AJ, Jajtner AR, Beyer KS, Boone CH, Miramonti AA, Wang R. The effect of training volume and intensity on improvements in muscular strength and size in resistance-trained men. Physiological Reports. 2015;3(8):e12472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26272733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzetti SA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, Duncan ND, Ratamess NA, G&#xd3;mez AL, Newton RU, H&#xc4;kkinen K, Fleck SJ. The influence of direct supervision of resistance training on strength performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(6):1175&#x2013;1184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10862549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moberg M, Apr&#xf3; W, Ekblom B, van Hall G, Holmberg H-C, Blomstrand E. Activation of mTORC1 by leucine is potentiated by branched-chain amino acids and even more so by essential amino acids following resistance exercise. Am J Physiol-Cell Physiology. 2016;310(11):C874&#x2013;C884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27053525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T. Neuromuscular adaptations during the acquisition of muscle strength, power and motor tasks. J Biomech. 1993;26:95&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8505356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 1979;58(3):115&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">453338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim J-s, Mayhew DL, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Potent myofiber hypertrophy during resistance training in humans is associated with satellite cell-mediated myonuclear addition: a cluster analysis. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(6):1736&#x2013;1742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Short-term training: When do repeated bouts of resistance exercise become training? Can J Appl Physiol. 2000;25(3):185&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10932036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pistilli EE, Devaney JM, Gordish-Dressman H, Bradbury MK, Seip RL, Thompson PD, Angelopoulos TJ, Clarkson PM, Moyna NM, Pescatello LS. Interleukin-15 and interleukin-15R&#x3b1; SNPs and associations with muscle, bone, and predictors of the metabolic syndrome. Cytokine. 2008;43(1):45&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2593832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18514540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ploutz LL, Tesch PA, Biro RL, Dudley GA. Effect of resistance training on muscle use during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76(4):1675&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8045847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ, Triplett NT. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Faigenbaum AD, Hoffman JR, Kang J. Self-selected resistance training intensity in healthy women: the influence of a personal trainer. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(1):103&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riechman SE, Balasekaran G, Roth SM, Ferrell RE. Association of interleukin-15 protein and interleukin-15 receptor genetic variation with resistance exercise training responses. J Appl Physiol. 2004;97(6):2214&#x2013;2219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15531573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low-vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;2963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, Hester GM, Sellers J, Nooner JL, Schnaiter JA, Bond-Williams KE, Carter AS, Ross CL. Longer Interset Rest Periods Enhance Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy in Resistance-Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(7):1805&#x2013;1812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimomura Y, Murakami T, Nakai N, Nagasaki M, Harris RA. Exercise promotes BCAA catabolism: effects of BCAA supplementation on skeletal muscle during exercise. J Nutr. 2004;134(6):1583S&#x2013;1587S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron R, Karapondo D, Kraemer W, Fry A, Gordon S, Falkel J, Hagerman F, Hikida R. Skeletal muscle adaptations during early phase of heavy-resistance training in men and women. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76(3):1247&#x2013;1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8005869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmons JA. Variability in training-induced skeletal muscle adaptation. J Appl Physiol. 2011;110(3):846&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3069632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21030666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toigo M, Boutellier U. New fundamental resistance exercise determinants of molecular and cellular muscle adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;97(6):643&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenburgh HH. Motion into mass: how does tension stimulate muscle growth? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1987;19(5 Suppl):S142&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3316913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>