<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40249908</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Without Fail: Muscular Adaptations in Single-Set Resistance Training Performed to Failure or with Repetitions-in-Reserve.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2021</StartPage><EndPage>2031</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2021-2031</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003728</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study compared the effects of single-set resistance training performed with maximal effort (failure) versus submaximal effort on muscular adaptations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty-two young, resistance-trained men and women were randomly assigned to one of two parallel groups: a group that trained to failure on all exercises (FAIL) or a submaximal effort group (2-RIR) that trained with two repetitions in reserve for the same exercises. Participants performed a single set of nine exercises targeting all major muscle groups per session, twice weekly for 8 wk. We assessed pre-post study changes in muscle thickness for the biceps brachii, triceps brachii, and quadriceps femoris, along with measures of muscular strength, power, endurance, and ability to estimate RIR in the bench press and squat.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Results indicated that both FAIL and 2-RIR elicited appreciable gains in most of the assessed outcomes. Several measures of hypertrophy tended to favor FAIL, although absolute differences between conditions were generally modest. Increases in countermovement jump height favored FAIL, but with no clear statistical support for either the null or alternative hypothesis. Increases in strength and local muscular endurance were similar between conditions. Participants demonstrated greater accuracy in estimating RIR for the bench press compared with the squat and improved their accuracy over the intervention, particularly for the bench press.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings suggest that single-set routines can be a time-efficient strategy for promoting muscular adaptations in resistance-trained individuals, even when transitioning from higher-volume programs. Training to failure in single-set routines may modestly enhance some measures of muscle hypertrophy and power, but not strength or local muscle endurance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hermann</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohan</LastName><ForeName>Adam E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Enes</LastName><ForeName>Alysson</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sapuppo</LastName><ForeName>Max</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pi&#xf1;ero</LastName><ForeName>Alec</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zamanzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Arman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coleman</LastName><ForeName>Max</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korakakis</LastName><ForeName>Patroklos Androulakis</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolf</LastName><ForeName>Milo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Refalo</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition (IPAN), School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Deakin University, Geelong, VIC, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swinton</LastName><ForeName>Paul A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise, School of Health Sciences, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, Applied Muscle Development Lab, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MINIMUM EFFECTIVE DOSE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MUSCLE HYPERTROPHY</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PROXIMITY TO FAILURE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SET END POINT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STRENGTH</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TIME-EFFICIENT TRAINING</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40249908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202509000-00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen VM, Norum M, Schoenfeld BJ, Fimland MS. No time to lift? Designing time-efficient training programs for strength and hypertrophy: a narrative review. Sports Med . 2021;51(10):2079&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoare E, Stavreski B, Jennings GL, Kingwell BA. Exploring motivation and barriers to physical activity among active and inactive Australian adults. Sports (Basel) . 2017;5(3):47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyde ET, Whitfield GP, Omura JD, Fulton JE, Carlson SA. Trends in meeting the physical activity guidelines: muscle-strengthening alone and combined with aerobic activity, United States, 1998&#x2013;2018. J Phys Act Health . 2021;18(S1):S37&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Hamilton DL, Daly RM. Minimal-dose resistance training for improving muscle mass, strength, and function: a narrative review of current evidence and practical considerations. Sports Med . 2022;52(3):463&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith D, Bruce-Low S. Strength training methods and the work of Arthur Jones. J Exerc Physiol Online . 2004;7(6):52&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Fisher J, Grgic J, et al. Resistance training recommendations to maximize muscle hypertrophy in an athletic population: position stand of the IUSCA. Int J Strength Cond . 2021;1(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Helms ER, Hamilton DL, Fyfe JJ. Influence of resistance training proximity-to-failure, determined by repetitions-in-reserve, on neuromuscular fatigue in resistance-trained males and females. Sports Med Open . 2023;9(1):10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Helms ER, Trexler ET, Hamilton DL, Fyfe JJ. Influence of resistance training proximity-to-failure on skeletal muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2023;53(3):649&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Sabol F. Effects of resistance training performed to repetition failure or non-failure on muscular strength and hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci . 2022;11(2):202&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Klemp A, Dolan C, et al. Novel resistance training-specific rating of perceived exertion scale measuring repetitions in reserve. J Strength Cond Res . 2016;30(1):267&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Helms ER, Robinson ZP, Hamilton DL, Fyfe JJ. Similar muscle hypertrophy following eight weeks of resistance training to momentary muscular failure or with repetitions-in-reserve in resistance-trained individuals. J Sports Sci . 2024;42(1):85&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J. Does training to failure maximize muscle hypertrophy? Strength Cond J . 2019;41(5):108&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2017;14:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotkin D, Coleman M, Van Every D, et al. Progressive overload without progressing load? The effects of load or repetition progression on muscular adaptations. PeerJ . 2022;10:e14142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT, editors. Essentials of Strength and Conditioning . 3rd ed. Champaign (IL): Human Kinetics; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent CM, Green JM, Bishop PA, et al. A practical approach to monitoring recovery: development of a perceived recovery status scale. J Strength Cond Res . 2011;25(3):620&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barakat C, Barroso R, Alvarez M, et al. The effects of varying glenohumeral joint angle on acute volume load, muscle activation, swelling, and echo-intensity on the biceps brachii in resistance-trained individuals. Sports (Basel) . 2019;7(9):204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Loftin M, Abe T. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci . 2012;4(4):217&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Libardi CA, et al. Resistance training-induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. J Physiol . 2016;594(18):5209&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biazon TMPC, Ugrinowitsch C, Soligon SD, et al. The association between muscle deoxygenation and muscle hypertrophy to blood flow restricted training performed at high and low loads. Front Physiol . 2019;10:446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Remmert JF, Pelland JC, et al. Accuracy of intraset repetitions-in-reserve predictions during the bench press exercise in resistance-trained male and female subjects. J Strength Cond Res . 2024;38(3):e78&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Steele J. Heavier and lighter load resistance training to momentary failure produce similar increases in strength with differing degrees of discomfort. Muscle Nerve . 2017;56(4):797&#x2013;803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira V, Voci SM, Mendes-Netto RS, da Silva DG. The relative validity of a food record using the smartphone application MyFitnessPal. Nutr Diet . 2018;75(2):219&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing . Vienna (Austria): R Core Team. Available from: https://www.R-project.org/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Schoot R, Depaoli S, King R, et al. Bayesian statistics and modelling. Nat Rev Methods Primers . 2021;14(1):1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruschke JK, Liddell TM. The Bayesian new statistics: hypothesis testing, estimation, meta-analysis, and power analysis from a Bayesian perspective. Psychon Bull Rev . 2018;25(1):178&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn S. Testing for baseline balance in clinical trials. Stat Med . 1994;13(17):1715&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland JM, Altman DG. Comparisons against baseline within randomised groups are often used and can be highly misleading. Trials . 2011;12:264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinton PA, Burgess K, Hall A, et al. Interpreting magnitude of change in strength and conditioning: effect size selection, threshold values and Bayesian updating. J Sports Sci . 2022;40(18):2047&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickerstaff V, Ambler G, Omar RZ. A comparison of methods for analysing multiple outcome measures in randomised controlled trials using a simulation study. Biom J . 2021;63(3):599&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin M. When to adjust alpha during multiple testing: a consideration of disjunction, conjunction, and individual testing. Synthese . 2021;199:10969&#x2013;1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinton PA, Murphy A. Comparative effect size distributions in strength and conditioning and implications for future research: a meta-analysis. SportRxiv . 2022. doi:10.51224/SRXIV.202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51224/SRXIV.202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MD, Wagenmakers EJ. Bayesian cognitive modeling: a practical course . Cambridge (UK): Cambridge University Press; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkner PC. An R package for Bayesian multilevel models using stan. J Stat Softw . 2017;80(1):1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depaoli S, van de Schoot R. Improving transparency and replication in Bayesian statistics: the WAMBS-checklist. Psychol Methods . 2017;22(2):240&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depaoli S, Winter SD, Visser M. The importance of prior sensitivity analysis in Bayesian statistics: demonstrations using an interactive shiny app. Front Psychol . 2020;11:608045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson ZP, Pelland JC, Remmert JF, et al. Exploring the dose&#x2013;response relationship between estimated resistance training proximity to failure, strength gain, and muscle hypertrophy: a series of meta-regressions. Sports Med . 2024;54(9):2209&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Serafini PR, Stratton MT, Olmos AA, VanDusseldorp TA, Feito Y. Effect of the repetitions-in-reserve resistance training strategy on bench press performance, perceived effort, and recovery in trained men. J Strength Cond Res . 2022;36(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Ghayomzadeh M, Farrell SN, Davies TB, Sabag A. Influence of total repetitions per set on local muscular endurance: a systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. Sci Sports . 2022;37(5&#x2013;6):405&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira AF, Umpierre D, Teodoro JL, et al. Effects of resistance training performed to failure or not to failure on muscle strength, hypertrophy, and power output: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res . 2021;35(4):1165&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaun GZ, Bamman MM, Alberton CL. High-velocity resistance training as a tool to improve functional performance and muscle power in older adults. Exp Gerontol . 2021;156:111593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remmert JF, Laurson KR, Zourdos MC. Accuracy of predicted intraset repetitions in reserve (RIR) in single- and multi-joint resistance exercises among trained and untrained men and women. Percept Mot Skills . 2023;130(3):1239&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halperin I, Malleron T, Har-Nir I, et al. Accuracy in predicting repetitions to task failure in resistance exercise: a scoping review and exploratory meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2022;52(2):377&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Goldsmith JA, Helms ER, et al. Proximity to failure and total repetitions performed in a set influences accuracy of intraset repetitions in reserve-based rating of perceived exertion. J Strength Cond Res . 2021;35(Suppl 1):S158&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(6):1206&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petancevski EL, Inns J, Fransen J, Impellizzeri FM. The effect of augmented feedback on the performance and learning of gross motor and sport-specific skills: s systematic review. Psychol Sport Exerc . 2022;63(2):102277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orssatto LBR, Diefenthaeler F, Vargas M, Rossato M, de la Rocha Freitas C. Dissimilar perceptual response between trained women and men in resistance training to concentric failure: a quasi-experimental study. J Bodyw Mov Ther . 2020;24(4):527&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>