<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39652733</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison Between Eccentric vs. Concentric Muscle Actions On Hypertrophy: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>115</StartPage><EndPage>134</EndPage><MedlinePgn>115-134</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004981</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>da Silva, LSL, Gon&#xe7;alves, LdS, Alves Campos, PH, Benjamim, CJR, Tasinafo J&#xfa;nior, MF, de Lima, LCR, Bueno J&#xfa;nior, CR, and Alves, CPdL. Comparison between eccentric vs. concentric muscle actions on hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 39(1): 115-134, 2025-Different physiological mechanisms of sarcomere activity during eccentric (ECC) and concentric (CON) muscle actions led to investigations into muscle hypertrophy outcomes, but conclusions remain elusive. We aimed to investigate the effects of ECC vs. CON muscle actions on muscle hypertrophy in apparently healthy adults through a systematic review with meta-analysis. The searches were conducted on EMBASE, MEDLINE, Cochrane Library, Web of Science, Scopus, and SPORTDiscus databases. To be eligible for inclusion, studies had to: (a) be randomized/controlled trials; (b) investigate the effects of CON vs. ECC resistance training programs in apparently healthy adults; (c) assess hypertrophy outcomes using direct imaging for cross-sectional area, muscle thickness, or muscle volume. A total of 15,778 studies were identified, and 26 (682 subjects included in the meta-analysis) met the inclusion criteria. The main findings indicated no statistical difference between ECC vs. CON on hypertrophy measurements (0.285 [95% CI: -0.131 to 0.701]; p = 0.179; I2: 84.4%; GRADE: very low). Subgroup meta-analysis analyzing possible hypertrophy outcome moderators as age (18-59 years old and &#x2265;60 years old) and weeks of intervention duration (&gt;8 weeks) did not reveal differences between ECC vs. CON. Subgroup analysis revealed an effect favoring the ECC for the upper limb muscles (p = 0.018), &#x2264;8 weeks of intervention (p = 0.046), muscle thickness assessment (p = 0.0352), and isokinetic contraction (p = 0.0251). Our findings suggest similar hypertrophy between ECC and CON muscle actions in apparently healthy adults. However, it appears that the muscles of the upper limbs, shorter interventions, hypertrophy assessment method, and the contraction type may favor ECC muscle actions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo Santos Lopes</ForeName><Initials>LSL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7028-1352</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto Medical School, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gon&#xe7;alves</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo da Silva</ForeName><Initials>LDS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto Medical School, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alves Campos</LastName><ForeName>Pedro Henrique</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto (EEFERP/USP), University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benjamim</LastName><ForeName>C&#xed;cero Jonas Rodrigues</ForeName><Initials>CJR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto Medical School, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tasinafo J&#xfa;nior</LastName><ForeName>Marcio Fernando</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto (EEFERP/USP), University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Lima</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo Coelho Rabello</ForeName><Initials>LCR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto (EEFERP/USP), University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bueno J&#xfa;nior</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Roberto</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto Medical School, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto (EEFERP/USP), University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ribeirao Preto College of Nursing, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo (EERP/USP), Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, SP, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alves</LastName><ForeName>Charles Phillipe de Lucena</ForeName><Initials>CPL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program in Epidemiology at Federal University of Pelotas, Pelotas, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Agency>Coordena&#xc3;&#xa7;&#xc3;&#xa3;o de Aperfei&#xc3;&#xa7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xc3;-vel Superior</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Agency>Coordena&#xc3;&#xa7;&#xc3;&#xa3;o de Aperfei&#xc3;&#xa7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xc3;-vel Superior</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Agency>Coordena&#xc3;&#xa7;&#xc3;&#xa3;o de Aperfei&#xc3;&#xa7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xc3;-vel Superior</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Agency>Coordena&#xc3;&#xa7;&#xc3;&#xa3;o de Aperfei&#xc3;&#xa7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xc3;-vel Superior</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Agency>Coordena&#xc3;&#xa7;&#xc3;&#xa3;o de Aperfei&#xc3;&#xa7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xc3;-vel Superior</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Agency>Coordena&#xc3;&#xa7;&#xc3;&#xa3;o de Aperfei&#xc3;&#xa7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xc3;-vel Superior</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39652733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202501000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, B&#xfc;ttner F, Andrade R, et al. Implementing the 27 PRISMA 2020 statement items for systematic reviews in the sport and exercise medicine, musculoskeletal rehabilitation and sports science fields: The PERSiST (implementing prisma in exercise, rehabilitation, sport medicine and SporTs science) guidance. Br J Sports Med 56: 175&#x2013;195, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baptista R, Onzi E, Goulart N, et al. Effects of concentric versus eccentric strength training on the elderly's knee extensor structure and function. J Exerc Physiol Online 19: 120&#x2013;132, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benford J, Hughes J, Waldron M, Theis N. Concentric versus eccentric training: Effect on muscle strength, regional morphology, and architecture. Translational Sports Med 4: 46&#x2013;55, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol 103: 1565&#x2013;1575, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg JP, Docherty D. The effects of accentuated eccentric loading on strength, muscle hypertrophy, and neural adaptations in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 16: 25&#x2013;32, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brynnel A, Hernandez Y, Kiss B, et al. Downsizing the molecular spring of the giant protein titin reveals that skeletal muscle titin determines passive stiffness and drives longitudinal hypertrophy. Elife 7: 1&#x2013;27, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buker N, Savkin R, Suzer A, Akkaya N. Effect of eccentric and concentric squat exercise on quadriceps thickness and lower extremity performance in healthy young males. Acta Gymnica 51: 1&#x2013;7, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Izal M, Pallar&#xe9;s JG, et al. Muscle conduction velocity, strength, neural activity, and morphological changes after eccentric and concentric training. Scand J Med Sci Sports 24: e343&#x2013;e352, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caserotti P, Aagaard P, Puggaard L. Changes in power and force generation during coupled eccentric-concentric versus concentric muscle contraction with training and aging. Eur J Appl Physiol 103: 151&#x2013;161, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Hsieh SS. Effects of a 7-day eccentric training period on muscle damage and inflammation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 1732&#x2013;1738, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Hubal MJ. Exercise-induced muscle damage in humans. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 81: S52&#x2013;S69, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Beato M, Bertinato L, Milanese C, Venturelli M, Schena F. Including the eccentric phase in resistance training to counteract the effects of detraining in women: A randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 36: 3023&#x2013;3031, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G, Schena F. Eccentric resistance training increases and retains maximal strength, muscle endurance, and hypertrophy in trained men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 41: 1184&#x2013;1189, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J, Pearson S, Ross A, McGuigan M. Chronic adaptations to eccentric training: A systematic review. Sports Med 47: 917&#x2013;941, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duhig SJ, Bourne MN, Buhmann RL, et al. Effect of concentric and eccentric hamstring training on sprint recovery, strength and muscle architecture in inexperienced athletes. J Sci Med Sport 22: 769&#x2013;774, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Siemionow V, Sahgal V, Xiong F, Yue GH. Distinct brain activation patterns for human maximal voluntary eccentric and concentric muscle actions. Brain Res 1023: 200&#x2013;212, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Chilibeck PD. The effects of eccentric and concentric training at different velocities on muscle hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 578&#x2013;586, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, Rahbek S, Vendelbo M, et al. Whey protein hydrolysate augments tendon and muscle hypertrophy independent of resistance exercise contraction mode. Scand J Med Sci Sports 24: 788&#x2013;798, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Atherton PJ, Reeves ND, et al. Architectural, functional and molecular responses to concentric and eccentric loading in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol 210: 642&#x2013;654, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Reeves ND, Narici MV. Skeletal muscle remodeling in response to eccentric vs. concentric loading: Morphological, molecular, and metabolic adaptations. Front Physiol 8: 1&#x2013;16, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Newton RU, Walker S, et al. Effects of upper body eccentric versus concentric strength training and detraining on maximal force, muscle activation, hypertrophy and serum hormones in women. J Sports Sci Med 21: 200&#x2013;213, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Roberts MD. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol 10: 1&#x2013;23, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog W. The mysteries of eccentric muscle action. J Sport Health Sci 7: 253&#x2013;254, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog W. The multiple roles of titin in muscle contraction and force production. Biophys Rev 10: 1187&#x2013;1199, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog W, Schappacher G, DuVall M, Leonard TR, Herzog JA. Residual force enhancement following eccentric contractions: A new mechanism involving titin. Physiology 31: 300&#x2013;312, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higbie EJ, Cureton KJ, Warren GL III, Prior BM. Effects of concentric and eccentric training on muscle strength, cross-sectional area, and neural activation. J Appl Physiol 81: 2173&#x2013;2181, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Li T, Deeks J. Choosing effect measures and computing estimates of effect. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.3. Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, eds. Cochrane, pp. 143&#x2013;173, http://www.training.cochrane.org/handbook (2022, Acessed August 18, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hody S, Croisier J-L, Bury T, Rogister B, Leprince P. Eccentric muscle contractions: Risks and benefits. Front Physiol 10: 1&#x2013;18, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones D, Rutherford O. Human muscle strength training: The effects of three different regimens and the nature of the resultant changes. J Physiol 391: 1&#x2013;11, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidgell DJ, Frazer AK, Daly RM, et al. Increased cross-education of muscle strength and reduced corticospinal inhibition following eccentric strength training. Neuroscience 300: 566&#x2013;575, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DY, Oh SL, Lim J-Y. Applications of eccentric exercise to improve muscle and mobility function in older adults. Ann Geriatr Med Res 26: 4&#x2013;15, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Ko JB, Farthing JP, Butcher SJ. Investigation of supraspinatus muscle architecture following concentric and eccentric training. J Sci Med Sport 18: 378&#x2013;382, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krentz JR, Farthing JP. Neural and morphological changes in response to a 20-day intense eccentric training protocol. Eur J Appl Physiol 110: 333&#x2013;340, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaStayo P, Marcus R, Dibble L, Frajacomo F, Lindstedt S. Eccentric exercise in rehabilitation: Safety, feasibility, and application. J Appl Physiol 116: 1426&#x2013;1434, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Higgins JPT, Deeks JJ, et al. Collecting data. In: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, eds. Cochrane, 6.3. 2019, pp. 94&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Shan X, Otsuka S, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Neuromuscular adaptations to work-matched maximal eccentric versus concentric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 50: 1629&#x2013;1640, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S, Mart&#xed;n-Rivera F, Nosaka K, Beato M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gallego J, de Paz JA. Effects of submaximal and supramaximal accentuated eccentric loading on mass and function. Front Physiol 14: 1&#x2013;13, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP. Recent advances in the understanding of the repeated bout effect: The protective effect against muscle damage from a single bout of eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports 13: 88&#x2013;97, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meader N, King K, Llewellyn A, et al. A checklist designed to aid consistency and reproducibility of GRADE assessments: Development and pilot validation. Syst Rev 3: 1&#x2013;9, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Young M, Phillips SM. Similar increases in muscle size and strength in young men after training with maximal shortening or lengthening contractions when matched for total work. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1587&#x2013;1592, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL, Pinto MD, Nosaka K, Steele J. The eccentric:concentric strength ratio of human skeletal muscle in vivo: Meta-analysis of the influences of sex, age, joint action, and velocity. Sports Med 53: 1125&#x2013;1136, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osternig LR. Isokinetic dynamometry: Implications for muscle testing and rehabilitation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 14: 45&#x2013;80, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 372: 1&#x2013;9, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paschalis V, Nikolaidis MG, Theodorou AA, Giakas G, Jamurtas AZ, Koutedakis Y. Eccentric exercise affects the upper limbs more than the lower limbs in position sense and reaction angle. J Sports Sci 28: 33&#x2013;43, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollard CW, Opar DA, Williams MD, Bourne MN, Timmins RG. Razor hamstring curl and Nordic hamstring exercise architectural adaptations: Impact of exercise selection and intensity. Scand J Med Sci Sports 29: 706&#x2013;715, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proske U, Morgan DL. Muscle damage from eccentric exercise: Mechanism, mechanical signs, adaptation and clinical applications. J Physiol 537: 333&#x2013;345, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan JI, Franchi MV, Gharahdaghi N, et al. Muscle and tendon adaptations to moderate load eccentric vs. concentric resistance exercise in young and older males. GeroScience 43: 1567&#x2013;1584, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remaud A, Cornu C, Gu&#xe9;vel A. Neuromuscular adaptations to 8-week strength training: Isotonic versus isokinetic mode. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 59&#x2013;69, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal R. Defining research results. In: Meta-Analytic Procedures for Social Research. R. Rosenthal, ed. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE Publications, Inc. pp. 13-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruas CV, Pinto RS, Haff GG, Lima CD, Brown LE. Effects of different combinations of concentric and eccentric resistance training programs on traditional and alternative hamstrings-to-quadriceps ratios. Sports 7: 1&#x2013;14, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryschon TW, Fowler MD, Wysong RE, Anthony A-R, Balaban RS. Efficiency of human skeletal muscle in vivo: Comparison of isometric, concentric, and eccentric muscle action. J Appl Physiol 83: 867&#x2013;874, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos Junior ERT, de Salles BF, Dias I, Ribeiro AS, Sim&#xe3;o R, Willardson JM. Classification and determination model of resistance training status. Strength Cond J 43: 77&#x2013;86, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Yoshida R, Kiyono R, et al. Cross-education and detraining effects of eccentric vs. concentric resistance training of the elbow flexors. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 13: 1&#x2013;12, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Yoshida R, Murakoshi F, et al. Comparison between concentric-only, eccentric-only, and concentric&#x2013;eccentric resistance training of the elbow flexors for their effects on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol 122: 2607&#x2013;2614, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Vigotsky AD, Franchi MV, Krieger JW. Hypertrophic effects of concentric vs. eccentric muscle actions: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2599&#x2013;2608, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seger JY, Arvidsson B, Thorstensson A, Seger JY. Specific effects of eccentric and concentric training on muscle strength and morphology in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 79: 49&#x2013;57, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;en&#x131;&#x15f;&#x131;k S&#xc7;, Akova B, &#x15e;ekir U, G&#xfc;r H. Effects of muscle architecture on eccentric exercise induced muscle damage responses. J Sports Sci Med 20: 655&#x2013;664, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata K, Takizawa K, Nosaka K, Mizuno M. Effects of prolonging eccentric phase duration in parallel back-squat training to momentary failure on muscle cross-sectional area, squat one repetition maximum, and performance tests in university soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 35: 668&#x2013;674, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata K, Yamaguchi T, Takizawa K, Nosaka K. Comparison in repetitions to failure between concentric-only and eccentric-only dumbbell arm curl exercise at four different relative intensities. J Strength Cond Res 37: 1754&#x2013;1760, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Waldron M, Ismail H, et al. Validation of a new tool for the assessment of study quality and reporting in exercise training studies: Testex. Int J Evid Based Healthc 13: 9&#x2013;18, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souron R, Nosaka K, Jubeau M. Changes in central and peripheral neuromuscular fatigue indices after concentric versus eccentric contractions of the knee extensors. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 805&#x2013;816, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tecchio P, Raiteri BJ, Hahn D. Eccentric exercise &#x2260; eccentric contraction. J Appl Physiol (1985) 136: 954&#x2013;965, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Ruddy JD, Presland J, et al. Architectural changes of the biceps femoris long head after concentric or eccentric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 499&#x2013;508, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomalka A. Eccentric muscle contractions: From single muscle fibre to whole muscle mechanics. Pflugers Arch 475: 421&#x2013;435, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;nl&#xfc; G, &#xc7;evikol C, Meleko&#x11f;lu T. Comparison of the effects of eccentric, concentric, and eccentric-concentric isotonic resistance training at two velocities on strength and muscle hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 34: 337&#x2013;344, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikne H, Refsnes PE, Ekmark M, Medb&#xf8; JI, Gundersen V, Gundersen K. Muscular performance after concentric and eccentric exercise in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 38: 1770&#x2013;1781, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>What Works Clearinghouse. What Works Clearinghouse procedures and standards handbook, version 5.0. U.S. Department of Education, Institute of Education Sciences, National Center for Education Evaluation and Regional Assistance (NCEE). https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/Handbooks . 2020. Accessed August 18, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisdom KM, Delp SL, Kuhl E. Use it or lose it: Multiscale skeletal muscle adaptation to mechanical stimuli. Biomech Model Mechanobiol 14: 195&#x2013;215, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>