<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33312280</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>74</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of the Strap Rewind Height During a Conical Pulley Exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>109</StartPage><EndPage>118</EndPage><MedlinePgn>109-118</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2020-0018</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The use of flywheel devices has increased in popularity within resistance training programs. However, little is known about modifiable variables which may affect power output responses, as the rope length and the height level used in a conical pulley device. The aim of this study was to assess the influence of using three different rope lengths (1.5, 2.5 and 3.5 meters) and four different height levels (L1, L2, L3 and L4) on concentric peak power (PPconc), eccentric peak power (PPecc) and eccentric overload (eccentric/concentric PP ratio; EO) during conical pulley exercises (i.e. seated and stand-up row). A total of 29 recreationally trained subjects (25.3&#xb1;7.1 years; 1.74&#xb1;0.06 m; 72.5&#xb1;8.3 kg) took part in the study. Testing sessions consisted of 1 set of 10 repetitions under each condition; experiment 1: seated row exercise using the three different rope lengths; experiment 2: stand-up row exercise using four different height levels of the conical pulley. Results from experiment 1 did not show differences between rope lengths, although a trend for greater PPecc (ES=0.36-0.38) and EO (ES=0.40-0.41) was found when using longer rope lengths (2.5 and 3.5). Experiment 2 showed significant increases in both PPconc and PPecc as the height level used was closer to the cone base (L4). In contrast, EO values were significantly greater when using upper height levels (L1). These results suggest that the height level used during conical pulley exercises highly influences power output responses. Therefore, this variable should be carefully managed depending on the training goal (e.g. power vs hypertrophy).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Rafael Sabido, Jose Luis Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3;, Adri&#xe1;n Garc&#xed;a-Valverde, Pablo Marco, Pablo Asencio, published by Sciendo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabido</LastName><ForeName>Rafael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Sport Research Center, Miguel Hern&#xe1;ndez University, Elche, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3;</LastName><ForeName>Jose Luis</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, Isabel I University, Burgos, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Valverde</LastName><ForeName>Adri&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidad de Almer&#xed;a, Almer&#xed;a, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marco</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Sport Research Center, Miguel Hern&#xe1;ndez University, Elche, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asencio</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Sciences, Sport Research Center, Miguel Hern&#xe1;ndez University, Elche, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eccentric overload</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flywheel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power output</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2020-0018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Askling C, Karlsson J, Thorstensson A. Hamstring injury occurrence in elite soccer players after strength training with eccentric overload. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2003;13:244&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12859607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Madruga-Parera M, Piqueras-Sanchiz F, Moreno-P&#xe9;rez V, Romero-Rodriguez D. Acute effect of eccentric overload exercises on change of direction performance and lower-limb muscle contractile function. J Strength Cond Res. 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31490430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Sale DG. Velocity specificity of resistance training. Sports Med. 1993;15:374&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8341872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazek D, Stastny P, Maszczyk A, Krawczyk M, Matykiewicz P, Petr M. Systematic review of intra-abdominal and intrathoracic pressures initiated by the Valsalva manoeuvre during high-intensity resistance exercises. Biol Sport. 2019;36(4):373&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31938009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CH, Chen YS, Wang YT, Tseng WC, Ye X. Effects of preconditioning hamstring resistance exercises on repeated sprinting-induced muscle damage in female soccer players. Biol Sport. 2018;35(3):269&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6224846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30449945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Developing maximal neuromuscular power. Sport Med. 2011;41:125146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21244105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, de la Torre A, Pradas F, Sa&#xf1;udo B, Carrasco L, Mateo-Cortes J, Dom&#xed;nguez-Cobo S, Fernandes O, Gonzalo-Skok O. Effects of eccentric overload bout on change of direction and performance in soccer players. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36:308&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25525954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, Sa&#xf1;udo B, Carrasco L, Mateo-Cortes J, Dom&#xed;nguez-Cobo S, Fernandes O, Del Ojo JJ, Gonzalo-Skok O. Effects of 10-week eccentric overload training on kinetic parameters during change of direction in football players. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:1380&#x2013;1387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26963941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Hoyo M, Sa&#xf1;udo B, Carrasco L, Dom&#xed;nguez-Cobo S, Mateo-Cortes J, Cadenas-S&#xe1;nchez MM, Nimphius S. Effects of traditional versus horizontal inertial flywheel power training on common sport-related tasks. J Hum Kinet. 2015;47:155&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26557200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J, Pearson S, Ross A, McGuigan M. Chronic adaptations to eccentric training: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2016;47:917&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27647157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Lundberg TR, Alvarez-Alvarez L, De Paz JA. Muscle damage responses and adaptations to eccentric-overload resistance exercise in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:1075&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24519446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC. The role of resistance exercise intensity on muscle fibre adaptations. Sports Med. 2004;34:663&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15335243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalo-Skok O, Tous-Fajardo J, Valero-Campo C, Berzosa C, Bataller AV, Arjol-Serrano JL, Moras G, Mendez-Villanueva A. Eccentric-overload training in team-sport functional performance: constant bilateral vertical versus variable unilateral multidirectional movements. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12:951&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27967273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalo-Skok O, Moreno-Azze A, Arjol-Serrano JL, Tous-Fajardo J, Bishop C. A comparison of three different unilateral strength training strategies to enhance jumping performance and decrease inter-limb assymetries in soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perf. 2019;6:1256&#x2013;1264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30860411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Aranda LM, Su&#xe1;rez-Arrones LM. Effects of inertial settings on power, force, work and eccentric overload during flywheel resistance exercise in women and men. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:16531661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S, Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez D, de Paz JA. Functional and muscle-size effects of flywheel resistance training with eccentric-overload in professional handball players. J Hum Kinet. 2017;60:133&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5765793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29339993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S, Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez D, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Moreira OC, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gallego J, de Paz JA. Skeletal muscle functional and structural adaptations after eccentric overload flywheel resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2017;20:943&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28385560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maszczyk A, Wilk M, Krzysztofik M. The effects of resistance training experience on movement characteristics in the bench press exercise. Biol Sport. 2020;37(1):79&#x2013;83. et al.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7075231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moras G, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Vald&#xe9;s B, V&#xe1;zquez-Guerrero J, Tous-Fajardo J, Exel J, Sampaio J. Entropy measures detect increased movement variability in resistance training when elite rugby players use the ball. J Sci Med Sports. 2018;21:1286&#x2013;1292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29804653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moras G, V&#xe1;zquez-Guerrero J, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Vald&#xe9;s B, Rosas-Casals M, Weakley J, Jones B, Sampaio J. Structure of force variability during squats performed with an inertial flywheel device under stable versus unstable surfaces. Hum Mov Sci. 2019;66:497&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31203019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noork&#xf5;iv M, Nosaka K, Blazevich AJ. Neuromuscular adaptations associated with knee joint angle-specific force change. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46:1525&#x2013;1537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24504427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L, Fluckey JD, Pozzo M, Tesch PA. Resistance training using eccentric overload induces early adaptations in skeletal muscle size. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102:271&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17926060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nu&#xf1;ez F, de Hoyo M, L&#xf3;pez A, Sa&#xf1;udo B, Otero-Esquina C, Sanchez H, Gonzalo-Skok O. Eccentric-concentric ratio: a key factor for defining strength training in soccer. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40:796&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31434138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nu&#xf1;ez FJ, S&#xe1;ez de Villarreal E. Does flywheel paradigm training improve muscle volume and force? A Meta-Analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:3177&#x2013;3186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29068866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez FJ, Suarez-Arrones LJ, Cater P, Mendez-Villaneva A. The high-pull exercise: a comparison between a versapulley flywheel device and the free weight. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12:527&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27705034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piqueras-Sanchiz F, Mart&#xed;n-Rodr&#xed;guez S, Mart&#xed;nez-Aranda LM, Ribeiro-Lopes T, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a O, Nakamura FY. Effects of moderate vs. high iso-inertial loads on power, velocity, work and hamstring contractile function after flywheel resistance exercise. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0211700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6366769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30730959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:918&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabido R, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Pereira-Gerbert GT. Influence of different inertial loads on basic training variables during the flywheel squat exercise. Int J Sports Physiol Perf. 2018;13:482&#x2013;489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabido R, Pombero L, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL. Differential effects of low vs high inertial loads during an eccentric-overload training intervention in rugby union players: A preliminary study. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2019;59:1805&#x2013;1811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30990262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;gaard K, Christensen H, Jensen BR, Finsen L, Sj&#xf8;gaard G. Motor control and kinetics during low level concentric and eccentric contractions in man. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1996;101:453&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8913200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timon R, Allemano S, Camacho-Carde&#xf1;osa M, Camacho-Carde&#xf1;osa A, Martinez-Guardado I, Olcina G. Post-activation potentiation on squat jump following two different protocols: traditional vs. inertial flywheel. J Hum Kinet. 2019;69:271&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31666909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tous-Fajardo J, Maldonado RA, Quintana JM, Pozzo M, Tesch PA. The flywheel leg curl machine: offering eccentric overload for hamstring development. Int J Sports Physiol Perf. 2006;1:293&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez-Guerrero J, Moras G, Baeza J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Jim&#xe9;nez S. Force outputs during squats performed using a rotational inertia device under stable versus unstable conditions with different loads. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0154346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4844129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27111766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>