<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36703264</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Similar patterns of tendon regional hypertrophy after low-load blood flow restriction and high-load resistance training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>848</StartPage><EndPage>856</EndPage><MedlinePgn>848-856</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.14321</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Recent evidence indicates that low-load blood flow restriction (LL-BFR) training elicits an anabolic response in tendinous tissue. The purpose of the present study was to investigate the hypertrophic pattern induced in the Achilles tendon by LL-BFR, in comparison with the regional hypertrophy typically observed with conventional high-load (HL) resistance training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">N&#xa0;=&#xa0;40 male participants were randomly and concealed allocated to one of two groups: LL-BFR training (20-35% one-repetition maximum/1RM) or HL training (70-85% 1RM). The training was completed three times per week for a total of 14&#x2009;weeks. Before and after the training period, Achilles tendon morphology was assessed using magnetic resonance imaging along the entire tendon length. Additionally, dynamic strength measures of the plantar flexors were evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In line with previous findings, dynamic plantar flexion strength was improved to a comparable extent in both groups (LL-BFR: 43.6%; HL: 43.5%). The results also confirmed significant increases in Achilles tendon cross-sectional area with LL-BFR (+5.2%). Moreover, they revealed that the hypertrophic pattern obtained with LL-BFR was similar to regional changes seen with conventional HL training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The present findings point towards the notion that despite the low loads being applied, LL-BFR training induces Achilles tendon hypertrophy by potentiating anabolic responses in the same regions as with conventional high-load training. Future studies are needed to (i) focus on the potential mechanisms underlying these tendon morphology changes and (ii) apply and evaluate LL-BFR training in clinical populations to validate these results in rehabilitative settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science In Sports published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Centner</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6839-4438</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Praxisklinik Rennbahn, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jerger</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2697-7568</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lauber</LastName><ForeName>Benedikt</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Movement Sciences, University of Fribourg, Fribourg, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seynnes</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friedrich</LastName><ForeName>Till</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lolli</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gollhofer</LastName><ForeName>Albert</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K&#xf6;nig</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Sports Science and University Sports, Institute for Nutrition, Exercise and Health, University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Nutritional Science, Institute for Nutrition, Exercise and Health, University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000125" MajorTopicYN="Y">Achilles Tendon</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Achilles tendon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-sectional area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">one-repetition maximum</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36703264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Lauber B. A systematic review and meta-analysis on neural adaptations following blood flow restriction training: what we know and what we Don't know. Front Physiol. 2020;11:887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(13):1003-1011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol. 2019;10:533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm S, Mersmann F, Arampatzis A. Human tendon adaptation in response to mechanical loading: a systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise intervention studies on healthy adults. Sports Med Open. 2015;1(1):7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(2):361-378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, Chacon-Mikahil MP, Cavaglieri CR, et al. Effect of concurrent training with blood flow restriction in the elderly. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36(5):395-399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Jerger S, Lauber B, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction and high-load resistance training induce comparable changes in patellar tendon properties. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;54:582-589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Lauber B, Seynnes OR, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction training induces similar morphological and mechanical Achilles tendon adaptations compared with high-load resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2019;127(6):1660-1667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongsgaard M, Reitelseder S, Pedersen TG, et al. Region specific patellar tendon hypertrophy in humans following resistance training. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2007;191(2):111-121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, Erskine RM, Maganaris CN, et al. Training-induced changes in structural and mechanical properties of the patellar tendon are related to muscle hypertrophy but not to strength gains. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2009;107(2):523-530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arampatzis A, Karamanidis K, Albracht K. Adaptational responses of the human Achilles tendon by modulation of the applied cyclic strain magnitude. J Exp Biol. 2007;210(Pt 15):2743-2753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H, Tsunoda N, Kanehisa H. Effects of training on muscle and tendon in knee extensors and plantar flexors in vivo. J Appl Biomech. 2010;26(3):316-323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Conceicao MS, et al. Comparisons between low-intensity resistance training with blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training on quadriceps muscle mass and strength in elderly. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(4):1071-1076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. 2nd ed. Human Kinetics; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Ferguson RA. Enhancing strength and postocclusive calf blood flow in older people with training with blood-flow restriction. J Aging Phys Act. 2011;19(3):201-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey I, Berg A, Grathwohl D, Keul J. Freiburg questionnaire of physical activity--development, evaluation and application. Soz Praventivmed. 1999;44(2):55-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: a Language and Environment for Statistical Computing [Computer Program]. R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grubbs FE. Sample criteria for testing outlying observations. Ann Math Stat. 1950;21(1):27-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyerberg EW. Clinical Prediction Models - A Practical Approach to Development, Validation, and Updating. Springer; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Wiegel P, Gollhofer A, K&#xf6;nig D. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49(1):95-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Komuro T, Ishiguro N, et al. Effects of low-load resistance training with vascular occlusion on the mechanical properties of muscle and tendon. J Appl Biomech. 2006;22(2):112-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang D, Jiang Z, Zhang Y, et al. Effect of young extrinsic environment stimulated by hypoxia on the function of aged tendon stem cell. Cell Biochem Biophys. 2014;70(2):967-973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakatani T, Marui T, Hitora T, Doita M, Nishida K, Kurosaka M. Mechanical stretching force promotes collagen synthesis by cultured cells from human ligamentum flavum via transforming growth factor-beta1. J Orthop Res. 2002;20(6):1380-1386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark RAF, McCoy GA, Folkvord JM, McPherson JM. TGF-&#x3b2;1 stimulates cultured human fibroblasts to proliferate and produce tissue-like fibroplasia: a fibronectin matrix-dependent event. J Cell Physiol. 1997;170(1):69-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuddeford T, Brumitt J. IN-season rehabilitation program using blood flow restriction therapy for two decathletes with patellar tendinopathy: a CASE report. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15(6):1184-1195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skovlund SV, Aagaard P, Larsen P, et al. The effect of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction on chronic patellar tendinopathy - a case series. Transl Sports Med. 2020;3(4):342-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yow BG, Tennent DJ, Dowd TC, Loenneke JP, Owens JG. Blood flow restriction training after Achilles tendon rupture. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2018;57(3):635-638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Wilson G, Carlyon B. Generality versus specificity: a comparison of dynamic and isometric measures of strength and speed-strength. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;68(4):350-355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mouser JG, Loenneke JP. Practicing the test produces strength equivalent to higher volume training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(9):1945-1954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gronfeldt BM, Lindberg Nielsen J, Mieritz RM, Lund H, Aagaard P. Effect of blood-flow restricted vs heavy-load strength training on muscle strength: systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30:837-848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508-3523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Neya M, Ochi E, Nakazato K, Sato Y, Ishii N. Cross-transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(2):258-263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenroth L, Sefa S, Arokoski J, T&#xf6;yr&#xe4;s J. Does magnetic resonance imaging provide superior reliability for Achilles and Patellar tendon cross-sectional area measurements compared with ultrasound imaging? Ultrasound Med Biol. 2019;45(12):3186-3198.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>