<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41379528</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength Adaptations Induced by Back Squat and Leg Extension Resistance Exercises.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>367</StartPage><EndPage>376</EndPage><MedlinePgn>367-376</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005338</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kassiano, W, Costa, B, Kunevaliki, G, Lisboa, F, Prado, A, Alves, L, Tricoli, I, Stavinski, N, Francssuel, J, and Cyrino, ES. Comparison of muscle hypertrophy and strength adaptations induced by back squat and leg extension resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): 367-376, 2026-Exercise selection affects muscular adaptations (e.g., strength gains and muscle hypertrophy). The purpose of this study was to compare changes in strength and muscle size between the back squat and leg extension resistance exercises. Sixty-three untrained young women were randomly allocated to perform the Smith machine back squat (SQ, n = 30) or leg extension (LE, n = 33) exercises. Subjects performed 3 sets of 8-12 repetitions maximum (RM) per session, 2 d&#xb7;wk -1 , for 8 weeks. Muscle thickness of the rectus femoris (RF) and vastus lateralis (VL) was measured at the proximal, middle, and distal sites. Strength was assessed through 3 repetitions maximum (3RM) tests in the back squat (3RM-SQ) and leg extension (3RM-LE) exercises. The LE experienced greater increases in the 3 RF sites (proximal: +11.4% vs. +2.0%; middle: +12.3% vs. +5.7%; distal: 17.5% vs. +7.9%; all p &lt; 0.001). Conversely, the SQ showed greater increases in VL at the distal site (+18.2% vs. +11.2%; p &lt; 0.001). Smith machine back squat induced greater increases in 3RM-SQ (+46.7 vs. 21.3%; p &lt; 0.001), but no between-group difference was observed in 3RM-LE increases (SQ = +19.8% vs. LE = +23.4%; p = 0.824). Based on our results, the leg extension induce greater rectus femoris hypertrophy, while the back squat promotes greater vastus lateralis hypertrophy, particularly at the distal site. The back squat training seems to be more effective for increasing squat strength, but both exercises are likely similarly effective for increasing leg extension strength.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassiano</LastName><ForeName>Witalo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0868-8634</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Bruna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State University of Northern Paran&#xe1;, Jacarezinho, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunevaliki</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lisboa</LastName><ForeName>Felipe</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prado</LastName><ForeName>Aline</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alves</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tricoli</LastName><ForeName>Ian</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stavinski</LastName><ForeName>Nat&#xe3;</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Francsuel</LastName><ForeName>Jarlisson</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Paran&#xe1;, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007866" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leg</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise selection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quadriceps</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41379528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomquist K, Langberg H, Karlsen S, et al. Effect of range of motion in heavy load squatting on muscle and tendon adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2133&#x2013;2142, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand&#xe3;o L, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, et al. Varying the order of combinations of single- and multi-joint exercises differentially affects resistance training adaptations. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1254&#x2013;1263, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Collier SR, Manini TM, Ploutz-Snyder LL. Sex differences in muscle fatigability and activation patterns of the human quadriceps femoris. Eur J Appl Physiol 94: 196&#x2013;206, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa B, Kassiano W, Nunes JP, et al. Does performing different resistance exercises for the same muscle group induce non-homogeneous hypertrophy? Int J Sports Med 42: 803&#x2013;811, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Angelino D, Hatfield DL, et al. Differing hypertrophy patterns from open and closed kinetic chain training affect quadriceps femoris center of mass and moment of inertia. Front Physiol 14(1074705): 1&#x2013;12, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Sakaguchi M, Akagi R, Kawakami Y. Unique activation of the quadriceps femoris during single- and multi-joint exercises. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1031&#x2013;1041, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enes A, Oneda G, Leonel DF, et al. The effects of squat variations on strength and quadriceps hypertrophy adaptations in recreationally trained females. Eur J Sport Sci 24: 6&#x2013;15, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escamilla RF, Fleisig GS, Zheng N, et al. Biomechanics of the knee during closed kinetic chain and open kinetic chain exercises. Med Sci Sports Exerc 30: 556&#x2013;569, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland J, Morris B. Variable-cam resistance training machines: Do they match the angle&#x2014;Torque relationship in humans? J Sports Sci 26: 163&#x2013;169, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3085&#x2013;3092, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner MJ, Altman DG. Confidence intervals rather than P values: Estimation rather than hypothesis testing. Br Med J 292: 746&#x2013;750, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Costa B, Kunevaliki G, et al. Muscle hypertrophy and strength adaptations to systematically varying resistance exercises. Res Q Exerc Sport 96: 371&#x2013;381, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Costa B, Nunes JP, et al. Which ROMs lead to Rome? A systematic review of the effects of range of motion on muscle hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 37: 1135&#x2013;1144, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Costa BDV, Kunevaliki G, et al. Distinct muscle growth and strength adaptations after preacher and incline biceps curl. Int J Sports Med 46: 334&#x2013;343, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Nunes JP, Costa B, et al. Does varying resistance exercises promote superior muscle hypertrophy and strength gains? A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1753&#x2013;1762, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of squat training with different depths on lower limb muscle volumes. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 1933&#x2013;1942, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Garc&#xed;a-Guti&#xe9;rrez MT, Mandi&#x107; M, Lilja M, Fernandez-Gonzalo R. Regional and muscle-specific adaptations in knee extensor hypertrophy using flywheel versus conventional weight-stack resistance exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 44: 827&#x2013;833, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Meng H, Yuhang W, et al. Greater hamstrings muscle hypertrophy but similar damage protection after training at long versus short muscle lengths. Med Sci Sports Exerc 53: 825&#x2013;837, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Wu Y, Huang M, et al. Triceps brachii hypertrophy is substantially greater after elbow extension training performed in the overhead versus neutral arm position. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 1240&#x2013;1250, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon GE, Morse CI, Burden A, Winwood K, Onamb&#xe9;l&#xe9; GL. Impact of range of motion during ecologically valid resistance training protocols on muscle size, subcutaneous fat, and strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 245&#x2013;255, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon GE, Morse CI, Burden A, Winwood K, Onamb&#xe9;l&#xe9; GL. Muscular adaptations and insulin-like growth factor-1 responses to resistance training are stretch-mediated. Muscle Nerve 49: 108&#x2013;119, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster DT, Cronin J, McGuigan M. Forms of variable resistance training. Strength Cond J 31: 50&#x2013;64, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehls K, Grubbs B, Jin Y, Coons J. Electromyography comparison of sex differences during the back squat. J Strength Cond Res 36: 310&#x2013;313, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigro F, Bartolomei S. A comparison between the squat and the deadlift for lower body strength and power training. J Hum Kinet 73: 145&#x2013;152, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 724&#x2013;735, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ploutz-Snyder LL, Convertino VA, Dudley GA. Resistance exercise-induced fluid shifts: Change in active muscle size and plasma volume. Am J Physiol 269: R536&#x2013;R543, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, do Nascimento MA, Salvador EP, et al. Reliability of one-repetition maximum test in untrained young adult men and women. Isokinet Exerc Sci 22: 175&#x2013;182, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Santos ED, Nunes JP, et al. A brief review on the effects of the squat exercise on lower-limb muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J 45: 58&#x2013;66, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberger A, Beijer &#xc5;, Johannes B, et al. Changes in muscle cross-sectional area, muscle force, and jump performance during 6 weeks of progressive whole-body vibration combined with progressive, high intensity resistance training. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 17: 38&#x2013;49, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Schoenfeld BJ, Ocetnik S, et al. Strength, body composition, and functional outcomes in the squat versus leg press exercises. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 58: 263&#x2013;270, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Squatting kinematics and kinetics and their application to exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res 24: 3497&#x2013;3506, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semmler JG. Motor unit synchronization and neuromuscular performance. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 30: 8&#x2013;14, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stien N, Pedersen H, Ravn&#xf8;y AH, Andersen V, Saeterbakken AH. Training specificity performing single-joint vs. multi-joint resistance exercises among physically active females: A randomized controlled trial. PLoS One 15(5 e0233540): 1&#x2013;12, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub RK, Powers CM. A biomechanical review of the squat exercise: Implications for clinical practice. Int J Sports Phys Ther 19: 490&#x2013;501, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky A, Bryanton M. Relative muscle contributions to net joint moments in the barbell back squat. In: Conference: American Society of Biomechanics 40th Annual Meeting. Raleigh, NC: North Carolina State University, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Ema R, Miyamoto N, Kawakami Y. Inter- and intramuscular differences in training-induced hypertrophy of the quadriceps femoris: Association with muscle activation during the first training session. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 37: 405&#x2013;412, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Kouzaki M, Moritani T. Non-uniform surface electromyographic responses to change in joint angle within rectus femoris muscle. Muscle Nerve 50: 794&#x2013;802, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Hartmann H, Sander A, et al. The impact of back squat and leg-press exercises on maximal strength and speed-strength parameters. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1205&#x2013;1212, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabaleta-Korta A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Pe&#xf1;a E, Torres-Unda J, Garbisu-Hualde A, Santos-Concejero J. The role of exercise selection in regional muscle hypertrophy: A randomized controlled trial. J Sports Sci 39: 2298&#x2013;2304, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>