<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36840460</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2228-5806</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cell journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cell J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>PAX7 and MyoD Proteins Expression in Response to Eccentric and Concentric Resistance Exercise in Active Young Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>135</StartPage><EndPage>142</EndPage><MedlinePgn>135-142</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.22074/cellj.2022.557440.1055</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">696801</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Satellite cells play an important role in muscle regeneration, which this process can be affected by different genes including PAX7 and MyoD. Exercise training known as an important strategy for mediating the satellite cell's function. Therefore, the main purpose of the present study is to investigate the changes in PAX7 and MyoD protein expression in response to eccentric and concentric resistance exercise in healthy young men.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this semi-experimental and cross-sectional study, 10 healthy men (age range 18-30 years old) participated. They were randomly divided into two equal groups (n=5) to perform one of two high-intensity eccentric or concentric knee extensions muscle contraction protocols. The contractions included a maximum of 12 sets of 10 repetitions, with a 30 second rest time interval between sets. PAX7 and MyoD protein expression was assessed using Immunohistochemistry analysis from the Vastus Lateralis muscle needle biopsy samples that have been taken 24 hours before and 3 to 4 hours after the end of the exercise protocol.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We observed that the PAX7 protein expression level increased significantly after eccentric (47.75%) and concentric (39.21%) (P=0.01) intervention. While, the MyoD protein expression level reduced (38.14%) significantly following acute eccentric resistance exercise (P=0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">It seems that eccentric or concentric muscular contraction modulates the expression of PAX7 and MyoD protein expression in the skeletal muscle, with further effects observed in eccentric resistance exercise.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karimi Majd</LastName><ForeName>Somayeh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gholami</LastName><ForeName>Mandana</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000000189604123</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazgir</LastName><ForeName>Behzad</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Research Center, Life Style Institute, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Cell J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101566618</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2228-5806</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concentric Contraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MyoD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PAX7</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Exercise</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36840460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9968375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22074/cellj.2022.557440.1055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">696801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Egan B, Zierath JR. Exercise metabolism and the molecular regulation of skeletal muscle adaptation. Cell Metab. 2013;17(2):162&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23395166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(1-2):50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maleiner B, Tomasch J, Heher P, Spadiut O, R&#xfc;nzler D, Fuchs C. The importance of biophysical and biochemical stimuli in dynamic skeletal muscle models. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1130&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6113794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30246791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Grant Mouser J, Mattocks KT, Abe T, et al. Correlations do not show cause and effect: not even for changes in muscle size and strength. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28819744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Postexercise hypertrophic adaptations: a reexamination of the hormone hypothesis and its applicability to resistance training program design. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(6):1720&#x2013;1730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hody S, Croisier JL, Bury T, Rogister B, Leprince P. Eccentric Muscle contractions: risks and benefits. Front Physiol. 2019;10:536&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6510035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31130877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan PW, Chandler JM, Cavanaugh DK, Johnson KR, Buehler AG. Mode and speed specificity of eccentric and concentric exercise training. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1989;11(2):70&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18796927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer RR, Durand RJ, Hollander DB, Tryniecki JL, Hebert EP, Castracane VD. Ghrelin and other glucoregulatory hormone responses to eccentric and concentric muscle contractions. Endocrine. 2004;24(1):93&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15249708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Vechetti-J&#xfa;nior IJ, Alves de Souza RW, Castan EP, Milanezi- Aguiar RC, Padovani CR, et al. Myogenin, MyoD and IGF-I regulate muscle mass but not fiber-type conversion during resistance training in rats. Int J Sports Med. 2013;34(4):293&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23059557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seale P, Sabourin LA, Girgis-Gabardo A, Mansouri A, Gruss P, Rudnicki MA. Pax7 is required for the specification of myogenic satellite cells. Cell. 2000;102(6):777&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11030621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishido M, Kami K, Masuhara M. Localization of MyoD, myogenin and cell cycle regulatory factors in hypertrophying rat skeletal muscles. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;180(3):281&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14962010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustofa M, Mintaroem K, Endharti A. Effect of endurance treadmill training on mIGF-1 expression and PAX 7 satellite cell in rat muscle tissues. Res J Life Sci. 2018;5(2):83&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya Y, Nakazato K, Ochi E. Contralateral repeated bout effect after eccentric exercise on muscular activation. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(9):1997&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29987366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Newton RU, Walker S, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Krapi S, Rekola R, et al. Effects of upper body eccentric versus concentric strength training and detraining on maximal force, muscle activation, hypertrophy and serum hormones in women. J Sports Sci Med. 2022;21(2):200&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9157521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35719226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durand RJ, Castracane VD, Hollander DB, Tryniecki JL, Bamman MM, O&#x2019;Neal S, et al. Hormonal responses from concentric and eccentric muscle contractions. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(6):937&#x2013;943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Chilibeck PD. The effects of eccentric and concentric training at different velocities on muscle hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89(6):578&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12756571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadzadeh S, Gholami M, Soheili Sh, Ghazalian F. The effect of eight weeks aerobic training and omega3 ingestion on the levels of adipsin and insulin resistance in overweight and obese women. Women&#x2019;s Health Bulletin. 2021;8(3):134&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh JK, Faulkner SH, Turner MC, Nimmo MA. Satellite cell response to concurrent resistance exercise and high-intensity interval training in sedentary, overweight/obese, middle-aged individuals. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118(2):225&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5767196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29071380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Sawan S, Hodson N, Babits P, Malowany JM, Kumbhare D, Moore DR. Satellite cell and myonuclear accretion is related to training-induced skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy in young males and females. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2021;131(3):871&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefer G, Rauner G, Yablonka-Reuveni Z, Benayahu D. Reduced satellite cell numbers and myogenic capacity in aging can be alleviated by endurance exercise. PLoS One. 2010;5(10):e13307&#x2013;e13307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20967266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Damas F, Phillips SM, Selistre-de-Araujo HS, Cornachione AS, Stotzer US, et al. Resistance training variable manipulations are less relevant than intrinsic biology in affecting muscle fiber hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2022;32(5):821&#x2013;832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35092084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Phillips SM, Babraj JA, Smith K, Rennie MJ. Myofibrillar and collagen protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle in young men after maximal shortening and lengthening contractions. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288(6):E1153&#x2013;E1159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15572656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Reeves ND, Narici MV. Skeletal Muscle remodeling in response to eccentric vs.concentric loading: morphological, molecular, and metabolic adaptations. Front Physiol. 2017;8:447&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28725197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petkov S, Brenmoehl J, Langhammer M, Hoeflich A, R&#xf6;ntgen M. Myogenic precursor cells show faster activation and enhanced differentiation in a male mouse model selected for advanced endurance exercise performance. Cells. 2022;11(6):1001&#x2013;1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8947336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35326452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensky NE, Sims JK, Dieli-Conwright CM, Sattler FR, Rice JC, Schroeder ET. Exercise does not influence myostatin and follistatin messenger RNA expression in young women. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(2):522&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2818823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20124796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Nelson MJ. Myosin heavy-chain mRNA expression after a single session of heavy-resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34(8):1262&#x2013;1269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12165680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Heinichen M, Wirth K, Schmidtbleicher D, Steinacker JM. Response of growth and myogenic factors in human skeletal muscle to strength training. Br J Sports Med. 2008;42(12):989&#x2013;993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18308879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psilander N, Damsgaard R, Pilegaard H. Resistance exercise alters MRF and IGF-I mRNA content in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2003;95(3):1038&#x2013;1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12716875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K, Andersen JL, Schjerling P. Are exercise-induced genes induced by exercise? FASEB J. 2005;19(1):94&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15516373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed M, Orrell RW, Cobbold M, Goldspink G, Harridge SD. Expression of IGF-I splice variants in young and old human skeletal muscle after high resistance exercise. J Physiol. 2003;547(Pt 1):247&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2342624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvorning T, Andersen M, Brixen K, Schjerling P, Suetta C, Madsen K. Suppression of testosterone does not blunt mRNA expression of myoD, myogenin, IGF, myostatin or androgen receptor post strength training in humans. J Physiol. 2007;578(Pt 2):579&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2075150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritzen AM, Th&#xf8;gersen FD, Qadri KAN, Krag T, Sveen ML, Vissing J, et al. Preserved capacity for adaptations in strength and muscle regulatory factors in elderly in response to resistance exercise training and deconditioning. J Clin Med. 2020;9(7):2188&#x2013;2188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7408999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32664402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, McCarthy JJ, Fry CS, Esser KA, Rasmussen BB. Aging differentially affects human skeletal muscle microRNA expression at rest and after an anabolic stimulus of resistance exercise and essential amino acids. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295(6):E1333&#x2013;E1340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2603551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18827171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyata T, Tanaka S, Tachino K. MyoD and myogenin mRNA levels after single session of treadmill exercise in rat skeletal muscle. J Phys Ther Sci. 2009;21(1):81&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathi M, Gharakanlou R. The effect of one session resistance exercise on hdac4 gene expression in slow and fast twitch muscles of male wistar rats. Journal of Ilam University of Medical Sciences. 2016;24(2):149&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanizadeh M, Ali Azarbayjani M, Peeri M, Matin Homaeee H. Effects of a single session of eccentric or concentric resistance exercise on relative expression of BDNF, PAX7 and IGF-1 in young men. Nutr Food Sci Res. 2021;8(1):11&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawke TJ, Garry DJ. Myogenic satellite cells: physiology to molecular biology. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2001;91(2):534&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charg&#xe9; SB, Rudnicki MA. Cellular and molecular regulation of muscle regeneration. Physiol Rev. 2004;84(1):209&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legerlotz K, Smith HK. Role of MyoD in denervated, disused, and exercised muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2008;38(3):1087&#x2013;1100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18642380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Maltzahn J, Jones AE, Parks RJ, Rudnicki MA. Pax7 is critical for the normal function of satellite cells in adult skeletal muscle. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2013;110(41):16474&#x2013;16479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24065826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>