<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23133756</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2090-2832</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2012</Volume><PubDate><Year>2012</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of vascular medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Vasc Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Blood flow restricted exercise and vascular function.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>543218</StartPage><MedlinePgn>543218</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">543218</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2012/543218</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It is established that regular aerobic training improves vascular function, for example, endothelium-dependent vasodilatation and arterial stiffness or compliance and thereby constitutes a preventative measure against cardiovascular disease. In contrast, high-intensity resistance training impairs vascular function, while the influence of moderate-intensity resistance training on vascular function is still controversial. However, aerobic training is insufficient to inhibit loss in muscular strength with advancing age; thus, resistance training is recommended to prevent sarcopenia. Recently, several lines of study have provided compelling data showing that exercise and training with blood flow restriction (BFR) leads to muscle hypertrophy and strength increase. As such, BFR training might be a novel means of overcoming the contradiction between aerobic and high-intensity resistance training. Although it is not enough evidence to obtain consensus about impact of BFR training on vascular function, available evidences suggested that BFR training did not change coagulation factors and arterial compliance though with inconsistence results in endothelial function. This paper is a review of the literature on the impact of BFR exercise and training on vascular function, such as endothelial function, arterial compliance, or other potential factors in comparison with those of aerobic and resistance training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horiuchi</LastName><ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Yamanashi Institute of Environmental Sciences, Kami-yoshida 5597, Fuji-yoshida, Yamanashi 4030005, Japan ; Northern Regions, Life long Sports Research Center, Hokusho University, Bunkyoudai 23, Ebetsu, Hokkaido 0698511, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okita</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Vasc Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101542608</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-2824</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2012</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23133756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3485988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/543218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Osler W. The Principles and Practice of Medicine. New York, NY, USA: D. Appletion and Company; 1892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacher J, Guerin AP, Pannier B, Marchais SJ, Safar ME, London GM. Impact of aortic stiffness on survival in end-stage renal disease. Circulation. 1999;99(18):2434&#x2013;2439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10318666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakatta EG. Age-associated cardiovascular changes in health: impact on cardiovascular disease in older persons. Heart Failure Reviews. 2002;7(1):29&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11790921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent S, Boutouyrie P, Asmar R, et al. Aortic stiffness is an independent predictor of all-cause and cardiovascular mortality in hypertensive patients. Hypertension. 2001;37(5):1236&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11358934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattelmair J, Pertman J, Ding EL, Kohl HW, III, Haskell W, Lee IM. Dose response between physical activity and risk of coronary heart disease: a meta-analysis. Circulation. 2011;124(7):789&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3158733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21810663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sesso HD, Paffenbarger RS, Lee IM. Physical activity and coronary heart disease in men: the Harvard Alumni Health Study. Circulation. 2000;102(9):975&#x2013;980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10961960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee IM, Paffenbarger RS., Jr. Physical activity and stroke incidence: the Harvard Alumni Health Study. Stroke. 1998;29(10):2049&#x2013;2054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9756580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendel-Vos GCW, Schuit AJ, Feskens EJM, et al. Physical activity and stroke. A meta-analysis of observational data. International Journal of Epidemiology. 2004;33(4):787&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15166195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharon Plowman A, Denise Smith L. Exercise Physiology for Health, Fitness, and Performance. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;S Guideline for Exercise Testing and Prescription. 7th edition. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, Dinenno FA, Monahan KD, Clevenger CM, DeSouza CA, Seals DR. Aging, habitual exercise, and dynamic arterial compliance. Circulation. 2000;102(11):1270&#x2013;1275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10982542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinenno FA, Seals DR, Desouza CA, Tanaka H. Age-related decreases in basal limb blood flow in humans: time course, determinants and habitual exercise effects. Journal of Physiology. 2001;531(2):573&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11230528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Haskell WL, Ades PA, et al. Resistance exercise in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: 2007 update: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association Council on Clinical Cardiology and Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism. Circulation. 2007;116(5):572&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17638929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. Position stand: progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyachi M, Kawano H, Sugawara J, et al. Unfavorable effects of resistance training on central arterial compliance: a randomized intervention study. Circulation. 2004;110(18):2858&#x2013;2863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15492301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Martel GF, Ivey FM, et al. High-volume, heavy-resistance strength training and muscle damage in young and older women. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2000;88(3):1112&#x2013;1118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10710410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Yasuda T, Midorikawa T, et al. Skeletal muscle size and circulating IGF-1 are increased after two weeks of twice daily "KAATSU" resistance training. International Journal of KAATSU Training Research. 2005;1(1):6&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Neya M, Ochi E, Nakazato K, Sato Y, Ishii N. Cross-transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2008;40(2):258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Burgomaster KA, Schofield LM, Gibala MJ, Sale DG, Phillips SM. Neuromuscular adaptations in human muscle following low intensity resistance training with vascular occlusion. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2004;92(4-5):399&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinohara M, Kouzaki M, Yoshihisa T, Fukunaga T. Efficacy of tourniquet ischemia for strength training with low resistance. European Journal of Applied Physiology and Occupational Physiology. 1998;77(1-2):189&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9459541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Sato Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with vascular occlusion on muscle function in athletes. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2002;86(4):308&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11990743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Tanaka Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2000;88(6):2097&#x2013;2106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Tsuruta T, Ishii N. Cooperative effects of exercise and occlusive stimuli on muscular function in low-intensity resistance exercise with moderate vascular occlusion. Japanese Journal of Physiology. 2004;54(6):585&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15760491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Sato Y. Muscle size and strength are increased following walk training with restricted venous blood flow from the leg muscle, Kaatsu-walk training. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2006;100(5):1460&#x2013;1466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Merode T, Hick PJJ, Hoeks APG, Rahn KH, Reneman RS. Carotid artery wall properties in normotensive and borderline hypertensive subjects of various ages. Ultrasound in Medicine and Biology. 1988;14(7):563&#x2013;569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3059645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirai T, Sasayama S, Kawasaki T, Yagi SI. Stiffness of systemic arteries in patients with myocardial infarction. A noninvasive method to predict severity of coronary atherosclerosis. Circulation. 1989;80(1):78&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2610739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett DK, Evans GW, Riley WA. Arterial stiffness: a new cardiovascular risk factor? American Journal of Epidemiology. 1994;140(8):669&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7942769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka H, DeSouza CA, Seals DR. Absence of age-related increase in central arterial stiffness in physically active women. Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology. 1998;18(1):127&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9445266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avolio AP, Fa-Quan D, Wei-Qiang L. Effects of aging on arterial distensibility in populations with high and low prevalence of hypertension: comparison between urban and rural communities in China. Circulation. 1985;71(2):202&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3965165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dart AM, Kingwell BA. Pulse pressure&#x2014;a review of mechanisms and clinical relevance. Journal of the American College of Cardiology. 2001;37(4):975&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11263624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodes RJ, Lakatta EG, McNeil CT. Another modifiable risk factor for cardiovascular disease? Some evidence points to arterial stiffness. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society. 1995;43(5):581&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7730544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blacher J, Asmar R, Djane S, London GM, Safar ME. Aortic pulse wave velocity as a marker of cardiovascular risk in hypertensive patients. Hypertension. 1999;33(5):1111&#x2013;1117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10334796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakatta EG. Age-associated cardiovascular changes in health: impact on cardiovascular disease in older persons. Heart Failure Reviews. 2002;7(1):29&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11790921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattace-Raso FUS, Van Der Cammen TJM, Hofman A, et al. Arterial stiffness and risk of coronary heart disease and stroke: the Rotterdam Study. Circulation. 2006;113(5):657&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton-Tyrrell K, Najjar SS, Boudreau RM, et al. Elevated aortic pulse wave velocity, a marker of arterial stiffness, predicts cardiovascular events in well-functioning older adults. Circulation. 2005;111(25):3384&#x2013;3390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15967850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen TW, Staessen JA, Torp-Pedersen C, et al. Prognostic value of aortic pulse wave velocity as index of arterial stiffness in the general population. Circulation. 2006;113(5):664&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao ST, Hobbs JT, Irvine WT. Ankle systolic pressure measurements in arterial disease affecting the lower extremities. British Journal of Surgery. 1969;56(9):676&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5808379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenland P, Abrams J, Aurigemma GP, et al. Prevention Conference V: beyond secondary prevention: identifying the high-risk patient for primary prevention: noninvasive tests of atherosclerotic burden: Writing Group III. Circulation. 2000;101(1):E16&#x2013;E22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10618318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouriel K, McDonnell AE, Metz CE, Zarins CK. A critical evaluation of stress testing in the diagnosis of peripheral vascular disease. Surgery. 1982;91(6):686&#x2013;693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7079971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koji Y, Tomiyama H, Ichihashi H, et al. Comparison of ankle-brachial pressure index and pulse wave velocity as markers of the presence of coronary artery disease in subjects with a high risk of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. American Journal of Cardiology. 2004;94(7):868&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15464667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safar ME, London GM. Therapeutic studies and arterial stiffness in hypertension: recommendations of the European Society of Hypertension. Journal of Hypertension. 2000;18(11):1527&#x2013;1535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11081763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent S, Cockcroft J, Van Bortel L, et al. Expert consensus document on arterial stiffness: methodological issues and clinical applications. European Heart Journal. 2006;27(21):2588&#x2013;2605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17000623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asmar R. Pulse wave velocity: principle and measurement. In: Asmar R, editor. Arterial Stiffness and Pulse Wave Velocity: Clinical Application. Amsterdam, The Netherlands: Elsevier; 1999. pp. 25&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerin AP, Blacher J, Pannier B, Marchais SJ, Safar ME, London GM. Impact of aortic stiffness attenuation on survival of patients in end-stage renal failure. Circulation. 2001;103(7):987&#x2013;992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11181474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent S, Boutouyrie P, Asmar R, et al. Aortic stiffness is an independent predictor of all-cause and cardiovascular mortality in hypertensive patients. Hypertension. 2001;37(5):1236&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11358934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meaume S, Benetos A, Henry OF, Rudnichi A, Safar ME. Aortic pulse wave velocity predicts cardiovascular mortality in subjects &gt;70 years of age. Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology. 2001;21(12):2046&#x2013;2050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11742883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deanfield JE, Halcox JP, Rabelink TJ. Endothelial function and dysfunction: testing and clinical relevance. Circulation. 2007;115(10):1285&#x2013;1295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17353456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deanfield J, Donald A, Ferri C, et al. Endothelial function and dysfunction. Part I: methodological issues for assessment in the different vascular beds: a statement by the working group on endothelin and endothelial factors of the European society of hypertension. Journal of Hypertension. 2005;23(1):7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15643116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyke KE, Tschakovsky ME. The relationship between shear stress and flow-mediated dilatation: implications for the assessment of endothelial function. Journal of Physiology. 2005;568(2):357&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16051630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thijssen DHJ, Black MA, Pyke KE, et al. Assessment of flow-mediated dilation in humans: a methodological and physiological guideline. American Journal of Physiology. 2011;300(1):H2&#x2013;H12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20952670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokce N, Keaney JF, Hunter LM, Watkins MT, Menzoian JO, Vita JA. Risk stratification for postoperative cardiovascular events via noninvasive assessment of endothelial function: a prospective study. Circulation. 2002;105(13):1567&#x2013;1572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11927524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokce N, Keaney JF, Hunter LM, et al. Predictive value of noninvasively determined endothelial dysfunction for long-term cardiovascular events in patients with peripheral vascular disease. Journal of the American College of Cardiology. 2003;41(10):1769&#x2013;1775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12767663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widlansky ME, Gokce N, Keaney JF, Vita JA. The clinical implications of endothelial dysfunction. Journal of the American College of Cardiology. 2003;42(7):1149&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14522472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot LA, Morrell CH, Metter EJ, Fleg JL. Comparison of cardiorespiratory fitness versus leisure time physical activity as predictors of coronary events in men aged &lt; or = 65 years and &gt;65 years. American Journal of Cardiology. 2002;89(10):1187&#x2013;1192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12008173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams PT. Physical fitness and activity as separate heart disease risk factors: a meta-analysis. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2001;33(5):754&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11323544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaitkevicius PV, Fleg JL, Engel JH, et al. Effects of age and aerobic capacity on arterial stiffness in healthy adults. Circulation. 1993;88(4):1456&#x2013;1462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8403292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt-Trucksass A, Schmid A, Brunner C, et al. Arterial properties of the carotid and femoral artery in endurance-trained and paraplegic subjects. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2000;89(5):1956&#x2013;1963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuki T, Maeda S, Iemitsu M, et al. Vascular endothelium-derived factors and arterial stiffness in strength- and endurance-trained men. American Journal of Physiology. 2007;292(2):H786&#x2013;H791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16997889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuki T, Maeda S, Iemitsu M, et al. Relationship between arterial stiffness and athletic training programs in young adult men. American Journal of Hypertension. 2007;20(9):967&#x2013;973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17765138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingwell BA, Cameron JD, Gillies KJ, Jennings GL, Dart AM. Arterial compliance may influence baroreflex function in athletes and hypertensives. American Journal of Physiology. 1995;268(1):H411&#x2013;H418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7840291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakiyama T, Sugawara J, Murakami H, Maeda S, Kuno S, Matsuda M. Effects of short-term endurance training on aortic distensibility in young males. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2005;37(2):267&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15692323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshizawa M, Maeda S, Miyaki A, et al. Additive beneficial effects of lactotripeptides intake with regular exercise on endothelium-dependent dilatation in postmenopausal women. American Journal of Hypertension. 2010;23(4):368&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20075849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron JD, Dart AM. Exercise training increases total systemic arterial compliance in humans. American Journal of Physiology. 1994;266(2):H693&#x2013;H701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8141370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugawara J, Hayashi K, Yokoi T, et al. Brachial-ankle pulse wave velocity: an index of central arterial stiffness? Journal of Human Hypertension. 2005;19(5):401&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15729378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier SR, Kanaley JA, Carhart R, et al. Effect of 4 weeks of aerobic or resistance exercise training on arterial stiffness, blood flow and blood pressure in pre- and stage-1 hypertensives. Journal of Human Hypertension. 2008;22(10):678&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18432253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi Y, Sasaki S, Kurisu S, et al. Regular aerobic exercise augments endothelium-dependent vascular relaxation in normotensive as well as hypertensive subjects: role of endothelium-derived nitric oxide. Circulation. 1999;100(11):1194&#x2013;1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10484540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto C, Nishioka K, Umemura T, et al. Acute moderate-intensity exercise induces vasodilation through an increase in nitric oxide bioavailiability in humans. American Journal of Hypertension. 2007;20(8):825&#x2013;830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17679027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Filippis E, Cusi K, Ocampo G, et al. Exercise-induced improvement in vasodilatory function accompanies increased insulin sensitivity in obesity and type 2 diabetes mellitus. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2006;91(12):4903&#x2013;4910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17018657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hambrecht R, Wolf A, Gielen S, et al. Effect of exercise on coronary endothelial function in patients with coronary artery disease. New England Journal of Medicine. 2000;342(7):454&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10675425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner AW, Sieminski DJ, Montgomery PS. Physical activity is related to ankle/brachial index in subjects without peripheral arterial occlusive disease. Angiology. 1997;48(10):883&#x2013;891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9342967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feinstein SB, Voci P, Pizzuto F. Noninvasive surrogate markers of atherosclerosis. American Journal of Cardiology. 2002;89(5):31C&#x2013;43C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11900717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Arnett DK, Bank A, et al. Arterial distensibility and physical activity in the ARIC study. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2001;33(12):2065&#x2013;2071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt-Trucks&#xe4;ss A, Grathwohl D, Frey I, et al. Relation of leisure-time physical activity to structural and functional arterial properties of the common carotid artery in male subjects. Atherosclerosis. 1999;145(1):107&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10428301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlachopoulos C, Kardara D, Anastasakis A, et al. Arterial stiffness and wave reflections in marathon runners. American Journal of Hypertension. 2010;23(9):974&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20489686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Tuxen D, Sale DG. Arterial blood pressure response to heavy resistance exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1985;58(3):785&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3980383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrofsky JS, Lind AR. Aging, isometric strength and endurance, and cardiovascular responses to static effort. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1975;38(1):91&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1110248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa T, Spina RJ, Martin WH, et al. Effects of aging, sex, and physical training on cardiovascular responses to exercise. Circulation. 1992;86(2):494&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1638717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stratton JR, Levy WC, Cerqueira MD, Schwartz RS, Abrass IB. Cardiovascular responses to exercise: effects of aging and exercise training in healthy men. Circulation. 1994;89(4):1648&#x2013;1655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8149532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertovic DA, Waddell TK, Gatzka CD, Cameron JD, Dart AM, Kingwell BA. Muscular strength training is associated with low arterial compliance and high pulse pressure. Hypertension. 1999;33(6):1385&#x2013;1391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10373221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawano H, Tanimoto M, Yamamoto K, et al. Resistance training in men is associated with increased arterial stiffness and blood pressure but does not adversely affect endothelial function as measured by arterial reactivity to the cold pressor test. Experimental Physiology. 2008;93(2):296&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17911355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyachi M, Donato AJ, Yamamoto K, et al. Greater age-related reductions in central arterial compliance in resistance-trained men. Hypertension. 2003;41(1):130&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12511542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan KS, Jae SY, Echols GH, Lepine NR, Fernhall B. Arterial stiffness and wave reflection following exercise in resistance-trained men. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2007;39(5):842&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17468584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVan AE, Umpierre D, Lin HF, et al. Habitual resistance exercise and endothelial ischemia-reperfusion injury in young adults. Atherosclerosis. 2011;219(1):191&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21840524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SA, Das E, Wang J, Pritchard K, Gutterman DD. Resistance and aerobic exercise protects against acute endothelial impairment induced by a single exposure to hypertension during exertion. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2011;110(4):1013&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21252216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Heffernan KS, Ranadive S, Jae SY, Fernhall B. Muscular strength is inversely associated with aortic stiffness in young men. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2010;42(9):1619&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakobowchuk M, McGowan CL, De Groot PC, et al. Effect of whole body resistance training on arterial compliance in young men. Experimental Physiology. 2005;90(4):645&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15849230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fjeldstad AS, Bemben MG, Bemben DA. Resistance training effects on arterial compliance in premenopausal women. Angiology. 2009;60(6):750&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19218270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poelkens F, Rakobowchuk M, Burgomaster KA, Hopman MTE, Phillips SM, MacDonald MJ. Effect of unilateral resistance training on arterial compliance in elderly men. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism. 2007;32(4):670&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17622281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley JD, Mcmillan V, Figueroa A. Resistance exercise training does not affect postexercise hypotension and wave reflection in women with fibromyalgia. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism. 2011;36(2):254&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21609287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP, Beck DT, Braith RW. Progressive resistance training without volume increases does not alter arterial stiffness and aortic wave reflection. Experimental Biology and Medicine. 2007;232(9):1228&#x2013;1235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17895531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP, Pierce GL, Howe KS, Mering MC, Braith RW. Effect of resistance training on arterial wave reflection and brachial artery reactivity in normotensive postmenopausal women. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2007;100(4):403&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17394009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakobowchuk M, McGowan CL, De Groot PC, Hartman JW, Phillips SM, MacDonald MJ. Endothelial function of young healthy males following whole body resistance training. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2005;98(6):2185&#x2013;2190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15677730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anton MM, Cortez-Cooper MY, DeVan AE, Neidre DB, Cook JN, Tanaka H. Resistance training increases basal limb blood flow and vascular conductance in aging humans. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2006;101(5):1351&#x2013;1355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16840576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanimoto M, Kawano H, Gando Y, et al. Low-intensity resistance training with slow movement and tonic force generation increases basal limb blood flow. Clinical Physiology and Functional Imaging. 2009;29(2):128&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19207416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copeland SR, Mills MC, Lerner JL, Crizer MF, Thompson CW, Sullivan JM. Hemodynamic effects of aerobic vs resistance exercise. Journal of Human Hypertension. 1996;10(11):747&#x2013;753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9004105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsley JD, Figueroa A. Effects of resistance exercise training on resting and post-exercise forearm blood flow and wave reflection in overweight and obese women. Journal of Human Hypertension. 2012;26(11):684&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21918541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AD, Ahuja KD, Almond JB, Robertson IK, Ball MJ. Progressive resistance training might improve vascular function in older women but not in older men. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport. In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22695137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heffernan KS, Fahs CA, Iwamoto GA, et al. Resistance exercise training reduces central blood pressure and improves microvascular function in African American and white men. Atherosclerosis. 2009;207(1):220&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19410255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vona M, Codeluppi GM, Iannino T, Ferrari E, Bogousslavsky J, Von Segesser LK. Effects of different types of exercise training followed by detraining on endothelium-dependent dilation in patients with recent myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2009;119(12):1601&#x2013;1608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawano H, Tanaka H, Miyachi M. Resistance training and arterial compliance: keeping the benefits while minimizing the stiffening. Journal of Hypertension. 2006;24(9):1753&#x2013;1759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16915024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa A, Park SY, Seo DY, Sanchez-Gonzalez MA, Baek YH. Combined resistance and endurance exercise training improves arterial stiffness, blood pressure, and muscle strength in postmenopausal women. Menopause. 2011;18(9):981&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeda S, Otsuki T, Iemitsu M, et al. Effects of leg resistance training on arterial function in older men. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2006;40(10):867&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16920770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortez-Cooper MY, Anton MM, DeVan AE, Neidre DB, Cook JN, Tanaka H. The effects of strength training on central arterial compliance in middle-aged and older adults. European Journal of Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation. 2008;15(2):149&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18391640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshizawa M, Maeda S, Miyaki A, et al. Effect of 12 weeks of moderate-intensity resistance training on arterial stiffness: a randomised controlled trial in women aged 32&#x2013;59 years. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2009;43(8):615&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18927168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson TP, Dengel DR, Leon AS, Schmitz KH. Moderate resistance training and vascular health in overweight women. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2006;38(9):1558&#x2013;1564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Effect of low-intensity resistance training on arterial function. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2011;111(5):743&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20972878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean AS, Libonati JR, Madonna D, Ratcliffe SJ, Margulies KB. Resistance training improves vasoreactivity in end-stage heart failure patients on inotropic support. Journal of Cardiovascular Nursing. 2011;26(3):218&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21263349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratley R, Nicklas B, Rubin M, et al. Strength training increases resting metabolic rate and norepinephrine levels in healthy 50- to 65-yr-old men. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1994;76(1):133&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8175496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raastad T, Glomsheller T, Bj&#xf8;ro T, Hall&#xe9;n J. Changes in human skeletal muscle contractility and hormone status during 2 weeks of heavy strength training. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2001;84(1-2):54&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11394254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Failla M, Grappiolo A, Emanuelli G, et al. Sympathetic tone restrains arterial distensibility of healthy and atherosclerotic subjects. Journal of Hypertension. 1999;17(8):1117&#x2013;1123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10466467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T, Masuhara M, Ikuta K. Upper but not lower limb resistance training increases arterial stiffness in humans. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2009;107(2):127&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19533164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seals DR, Victor RG. Regulation of muscle sympathetic nerve activity during exercise in humans. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews. 1991;19:313&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1936089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2007;103(3):903&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manini TM, Clark BC. Blood flow restricted exercise and skeletal muscle health. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews. 2009;37(2):78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19305199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce JR, Clark BC, Ploutz-Snyder LL, Kanaley JA. Growth hormone and muscle function responses to skeletal muscle ischemia. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2006;101(6):1588&#x2013;1595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16888046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takano H, Morita T, Iida H, et al. Hemodynamic and hormonal responses to a short-term low-intensity resistance exercise with the reduction of muscle blood flow. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2005;95(1):65&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15959798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2000;88(1):61&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Morita N, et al. Intramuscular metabolism during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2009;106(4):1119&#x2013;1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19213931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Ferguson RA. Increase in calf post-occlusive blood flow and strength following short-term resistance exercise training with blood flow restriction in young women. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2010;108(5):1025&#x2013;1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20012448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2010;108(5):1199&#x2013;1209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gundermann DM, Fry CS, Dickinson JM, et al. Reactive hyperemia is not responsible for stimulating muscle protein synthesis following blood flow restriction exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2012;112(9):1520&#x2013;1528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3362234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22362401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada S, Okita K, Suga T, et al. Low-intensity exercise can increase muscle mass and strength proportionally to enhanced metabolic stress under ischemic conditions. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2012;113(2):199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22628373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor LH, Weisbrod CJ, O&#x2019;Driscoll G, Green DJ. Measuring peripheral resistance and conduit arterial structure in humans using Doppler ultrasound. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2005;98(6):2311&#x2013;2315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Seo DI, et al. Effect of different types of resistance exercise on arterial compliance and calf blood flow. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2011;111(12):2969&#x2013;2975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21445603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson IB, Qasem A, McEniery CM, Webb DJ, Avolio AP, Cockcroft JR. Nitric oxide regulates local arterial distensibility in vivo. Circulation. 2002;105(2):213&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11790703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutouyrie P, Lacolley P, Girerd X, Beck L, Safar M, Laurent S. Sympathetic activation decreases medium-sized arterial compliance in humans. American Journal of Physiology. 1994;267(4):H1368&#x2013;H1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7943382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Sherk VD, Bemben MG, Bemben DA. Effects of short-term, low-intensity resistance training with vascular restriction on arterial compliance in untrained young men. International Journal of KAATSU Training Research. 2009;5(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM, Hoffman RL, et al. Relative safety of 4 weeks of blood flow-restricted resistance exercise in young, healthy adults. Scandinavia Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports. 2011;21(5):653&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6152804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21917016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Loenneke JP, et al. Effect of different types of lower body resistance training on arterial compliance and calf blood flow. Clinical Physiology and Functional Imaging. 2012;32(1):45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22152078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki-Sunaga M, Naito H, Abe T. Effects of high-intensity and blood flow-restricted low-intensity resistance training on carotid arterial compliance: role of blood pressure during training sessions. European Journal of Applied Physiology. In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22618304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossow LM, Fahs CA, Sherk VD, Seo DI, Bemben DA, Bemben MG. The effect of acute blood-flow-restricted resistance exercise on postexercise blood pressure. Clinical Physiology and Functional Imaging. 2011;31(6):429&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21981453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenney MJ, Scals DR. Postexercise hypotension: key features, mechanisms, and clinical significance. Hypertension. 1993;22(5):653&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8225525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliwill JR. Mechanisms and clinical implications of post-exercise hypotension in humans. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews. 2001;29(2):65&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11337825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Miyachi M, Nakajima T, Abe T. Effects of 10 weeks walk training with leg blood flow reduction on carotid arterial compliance and muscle size in the elderly adults. Angiology. 2011;62(1):81&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker BA, Kalasky MJ, Proctor DN. Evidence for sex differences in cardiovascular aging and adaptive responses to physical activity. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2010;110(2):235&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2929283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20480371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreau KL, Donato AJ, Seals DR, DeSouza CA, Tanaka H. Regular exercise, hormone replacement therapy and the age-related decline in carotid arterial compliance in healthy women. Cardiovascular Research. 2003;57(3):861&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Sakamaki M, Fujita S, et al. Effects of low-intensity walk training with restricted leg blood flow on muscle strength and aerobic capacity in older adults. Journal of Geriatric Physical Therapy. 2010;33(1):34&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20503732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans C, Vance S, Brown M. Short-term resistance training with blood flow restriction enhances microvascular filtration capacity of human calf muscles. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2010;28(9):999&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20544482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renzi CP, Tanaka H, Sugawara J. Effects of leg blood flow restriction during walking on cardiovascular function. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2010;42(4):726&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2888901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Credeur DP, Hollis BC, Welsch MA. Effects of handgrip training with venous restriction on brachial artery vasodilation. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2010;42(7):1296&#x2013;1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2903220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt JE, Walton LA, Ferguson RA. Brachial artery modifications to blood flow-restricted handgrip training and detraining. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2012;112(6):956&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22174400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xf6;rstermann U. Endothelial NO synthase as a source of NO and superoxide. European Journal of Clinical Pharmacology. 2006;62(13):5&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi Y, Noma K, Yoshizumi M, Kihara Y. Endothelial function and oxidative stress in cardiovascular diseases. Circulation Journal. 2009;73(3):411&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19194043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heitzer T, Schlinzig T, Krohn K, Meinertz T, M&#xfc;nzel T. Endothelial dysfunction, oxidative stress, and risk of cardiovascular events in patients with coronary artery disease. Circulation. 2001;104(22):2673&#x2013;2678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11723017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer RJ, Fry AC, Falvo MJ, Moore CA. Protein carbonyls are acutely elevated following single set anaerobic exercise in resistance trained men. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport. 2007;10(6):411&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16949870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer RJ, Falvo MJ, Fry AC, Schilling BK, Smith WA, Moore CA. Oxidative stress response in trained men following repeated squats or sprints. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2006;38(8):1436&#x2013;1442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16888457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomer RJ, Goldfarb AH, Wideman L, McKenzie MJ, Consitt LA. Effects of acute aerobic and anaerobic exercise on blood markers of oxidative stress. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2005;19(2):276&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson MB, Hosick PA, Mccaulley GO, et al. The effect of resistance exercise on humoral markers of oxidative stress. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2008;40(3):542&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18379219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Goldfarb AH, Rescino MH, Hegde S, Patrick S, Apperson K. Eccentric exercise effect on blood oxidative-stress markers and delayed onset of muscle soreness. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2002;34(3):443&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAnulty SR, McAnulty LS, Nieman DC, Morrow JD, Utter AC, Dumke CL. Effect of resistance exercise and carbohydrate ingestion on oxidative stress. Free Radical Research. 2005;39(11):1219&#x2013;1224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16298748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride JM, Kraemer WJ, Triplett-McBride T, Sebastianelli W. Effect of resistance exercise on free radical production. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 1998;30(1):67&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellsten Y, Hansson HA, Johnson L, Frandsen U, Sj&#xf6;din B. Increased expression of xanthine oxidase and insulin-like growth factor I (IGF-I) immunoreactivity in skeletal muscle after strenuous exercise in humans. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica. 1996;157(2):191&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8800359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb AH, Garten RS, Chee PDM, et al. Resistance exercise effects on blood glutathione status and plasma protein carbonyls: influence of partial vascular occlusion. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2008;104(5):813&#x2013;819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18661144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrin PB. Mechanical factors associated with the development of intimal and medial thickening in vein grafts subjected to arterial pressure: a model of arteries exposed to hypertension. Hypertension. 1995;26(1):38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7607730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrosielski DA, Greenway FL, Welsh DA, Jazwinski SM, Welsch MA. Modification of vascular function after handgrip exercise training in 73- to90-yr-old men. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2009;41(7):1429&#x2013;1435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2903213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19516158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CL, Visocchi A, Faulkner M, et al. Isometric handgrip training improves local flow-mediated dilation in medicated hypertensives. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2006;98(4):355&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16924526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CL, Levy AS, Millar PJ, et al. Acute vascular responses to isometric handgrip exercise and effects of training in persons medicated for hypertension. American Journal of Physiology. 2006;291(4):H1797&#x2013;H1802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16648182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornig B, Maier V, Drexler H. Physical training improves endothelial function in patients with chronic heart failure. Circulation. 1996;93(2):210&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8548890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz SD, Yuen J, Bijou R, Lejemtel TH. Training improves endothelium-dependent vasodilation in resistance vessels of patients with heart failure. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1997;82(5):1488&#x2013;1492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9134897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinoway LI, Shenberger J, Wilson J. A 30-day forearm work protocol increases maximal forearm blood flow. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1987;62(3):1063&#x2013;1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3571063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alomari MA, Welsch MA, Prisby RD, Lee CM, Wood RH. Modification of forearm vascular function following short-term handgrip exercise training. International Journal of Sports Medicine. 2001;22(5):361&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11510873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bank AJ, Shammas RA, Mullen K, Chuang PP. Effects of short-term forearm exercise training on resistance vessel endothelial function in normal subjects and patients with heart failure. Journal of Cardiac Failure. 1998;4(3):193&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9754590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CL, Levy AS, McCartney N, MacDonald MJ. Isometric handgrip training does not improve flow-mediated dilation in subjects with normal blood pressure. Clinical Science. 2007;112(7-8):403&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17140398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Cable NT, Fox C, Rankin JM, Taylor RR. Modification of forearm resistance vessels by exercise training in young men. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1994;77(4):1829&#x2013;1833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7836206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown MD. Exercise and coronary vascular remodelling in the healthy heart. Experimental Physiology. 2003;88(5):645&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12955165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior BM, Lloyd PG, Yang HT, Terjung RL. Exercise-induced vascular remodeling. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews. 2003;31(1):26&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delp MD, McAllister RM, Laughlin MH. Exercise training alters endothelium-dependent vasoreactivity of rat abdominal aorta. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1993;75(3):1354&#x2013;1363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delp MD, Laughlin MH. Time course of enhanced endothelium-mediated dilation in aorta of trained rats. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 1997;29(11):1454&#x2013;1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9372482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sessa WC, Pritchard K, Seyedi N, Wang J, Hintze TH. Chronic exercise in dogs increases coronary vascular nitric oxide production and endothelial cell nitric oxide synthase gene expression. Circulation Research. 1994;74(2):349&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7507417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D, Huang A, Koller A, Kaley G. Short-term daily exercise activity enhances endothelial NO synthesis in skeletal muscle arterioles of rats. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1994;76(5):2241&#x2013;2247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7520432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen JD, Geaghan JP, Greenway F, Welsch MA. Time course of improved flow-mediated dilation after short-term exercise training. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2003;35(5):847&#x2013;853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12750596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinken TM, Thijssen DHJ, Black MA, Cable NT, Green DJ. Time course of change in vasodilator function and capacity in response to exercise training in humans. Journal of Physiology. 2008;586(20):5003&#x2013;5012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2614057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18755749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke AP, Farb A, Malcom GT, Liang YH, Smialek J, Virmani R. Coronary risk factors and plaque morphology in men with coronary disease who died suddenly. New England Journal of Medicine. 1997;336(18):1276&#x2013;1282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9113930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Kurano M, Takano H, et al. Effects of low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction on coagulation system in healthy subjects. Clinical Physiology and Functional Imaging. 2010;30(3):210&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20175789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima T, Takano H, Kurano M, et al. Effects of KAATSU training on haemostasis in healthy subjects. International Journal of KAATSU Research. 2007;3(1):11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herren T, Bartsch P, Haeberli A, Straub PW. Increased thrombin-antithrombin III complexes after 1&#x2009;h of physical exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1992;73(6):2499&#x2013;2504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1490963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall&#xe9;n NH, Goodall AH, Li N, Hjemdahl P. Activation of haemostasis by exercise, mental stress and adrenaline: effects on platelet sensitivity to thrombin and thrombin generation. Clinical Science. 1999;97(1):27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10369791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilberg T, Eichler E, Gl&#xe4;ser D, Prasa D, St&#xfc;rzebecher J, Gabriel HHW. Blood coagulation and fibrinolysis before and after exhaustive exercise in patients with IDDM. Thrombosis and Haemostasis. 2003;90(6):1065&#x2013;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14652638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilberg T, Gl&#xe4;ser D, Reckhart C, Prasa D, St&#xfc;rzebecher J, Gabriel HHW. Blood coagulation and fibrinolysis after long-duration treadmill exercise controlled by individual anaerobic threshold. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2003;90(5-6):639&#x2013;642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12883904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima T, Kurano M, Iida H, et al. Use and safety of KAATSU training: results of a national survey. International Journal of KAATSU Training Research. 2006;2(1):5&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi Y, Yoshizumi M. Exercise and endothelial function: role of endothelium-derived nitric oxide and oxidative stress in healthy subjects and hypertensive patients. Pharmacology and Therapeutics. 2004;102(1):87&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shweiki D, Itin A, Soffer D, Keshet E. Vascular endothelial growth factor induced by hypoxia may mediate hypoxia-initiated angiogenesis. Nature. 1992;359(6398):843&#x2013;845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1279431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein I, Neeman M, Shweiki D, Itin A, Keshet E. Stabilization of vascular endothelial growth factor mRNA by hypoxia and hypoglycemia and coregulation with other ischemia-induced genes. Molecular and Cellular Biology. 1995;15(10):5363&#x2013;5368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC230785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7565686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson RS, Noyszewski EA, Kendrick KF, Leigh JS, Wagner PD. Myoglobin O2 desaturation during exercise. Evidence of limited O2 transport. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 1995;96(4):1916&#x2013;1926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC185828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7560083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>