<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37964694</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2865</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiotherapy research international : the journal for researchers and clinicians in physical therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiother Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of blood flow restriction for increasing the strength of the ischiocrural muscles in anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation: A case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2059</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2059</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pri.2059</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The hamstring muscles have a key function in the stability of the knee, limiting the anterior translation of the tibia. Therefore, to better perform rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) surgery, it is important to develop a specific program based on hamstring strength recovery. It is possible to increase strength and muscle hypertrophy through high load exercises (HL); the recommended load is about 60%-80% of a maximum repetition (MR). Although low-load resistance training (LL) is ineffective at reproducing these values, the use of Blood Flow Restriction (BFR) with LL exercises appears to allow athletes to increase strength and muscle hypertrophy. This could limit functional decline and mitigate muscle atrophy allowing to optimize the recovery path and load management in post-operative patients. Recent scientific evidence, as far as the increasingly frequent use of BFR in rehabilitation and sports rehabilitation is concerned, suggests that these devices could represent one of the most significant innovations in the physiotherapy field. The aim of this study was to increase the strength of the hamstrings in the early phases of ACL rehabilitation with an LL-BFR training protocol for speeding up the development of adequate muscle strength.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE DESCRIPTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The patient, a 25-year-old male professional footballer, suffered from ACL injury during a football match, and after three months, he underwent a reconstruction ACL surgery with medial Hamstring tendon autograft. The athlete engaged a pre-operative program to restore a full active and passive knee range of motion and increase muscular strength. The first rehabilitation phase was supported by the adoption of BFR for hamstring strengthening, starting from the sixth week post-surgery (T0). A complete assessment of posterior hamstring muscles was performed through a hand-held dynamometer and load detection platforms. Three different types of exercises, focusing on the hamstring muscles, were chosen. Two further assessments were performed over time (T1 ant T2), highlighting different changes that occurred.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Interesting results showed a significant increase between T0 and T1 for all the assessed outcomes; in this case an average increase in strength of 59.87% between the beginning and the end of 4&#xa0;weeks rehabilitation protocol was obtained in the first interval (T0-T1), while only 25.26% resulted in the second interval (T1-T2). However, the collected data should be considered with caution due to some limitations: the single experience of a single patient can hardly be generalized. Moreover, the reliance on isometric measurement of maximal strength and the absence of a direct strength measurement of the hamstrings during squat remain questionable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The final results suggest the capacity of the LL-BFR exercises to recreate a condition of a high intensity muscular effort with respect to load management, especially after surgery. This highlights the need to further investigate BFR adoption as it allows the patients to speed up their rehabilitation goals in developing adequate muscle strength.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ceccarelli</LastName><ForeName>Claudio</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3657-4597</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Private Practice, Massa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andreani</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8281-4443</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Health Science "Vincenzo Tiberio", University of Molise C/daTappino c/o Cardarelli Hospital, Campobasso, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soave</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Private Practice, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salomon</LastName><ForeName>Mattia</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5315-4236</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences and Translational Medicine, University of Roma "Tor Vergata" c/o Medicine and Surgery School, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neurosciences, University of Roma "Sapienza Roma", Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maselli</LastName><ForeName>Filippo</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9683-9975</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neurosciences, University of Roma "Sapienza Roma", Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiother Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9612022</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1358-2267</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016118" MajorTopicYN="N">Anterior Cruciate Ligament</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059549" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007719" MajorTopicYN="N">Knee Joint</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070633" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hamstring Muscles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flood restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hamstrings</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37964694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.2059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Anderson, A. B., Owens, J. G., Patterson, S. D., Dickens, J. F., &amp; LeClere, L. E. (2019). Blood flow restriction therapy: From development to applications. Sports Medicine and Arthroscopy Review, 27(3), 119-123. https://doi.org/10.1097/JSA.0000000000000240</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobes &#xc1;lvarez, C., Issa-Khozouz Santamar&#xed;a, P., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Mat&#xed;as, R., Pecos-Mart&#xed;n, D., Achalandabaso-Ochoa, A., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Carnero, S., Mart&#xed;nez-Amat, A., &amp; Gallego-Izquierdo, T. (2020). Comparison of blood flow restriction training versus non-occlusive training in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction or knee osteoarthritis: A systematic review. Journal of Clinical Medicine, 10(1), 68. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10010068</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman, E. N., Elshaar, R., Milligan, H., Jue, G., Mohr, K., Brown, P., Watanabe, D. M., &amp; Limpisvasti, O. (2019). Proximal, distal, and contralateral effects of blood flow restriction training on the lower extremities: A randomized controlled trial. Sport Health, 11(2), 149-156. https://doi.org/10.1177/1941738118821929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinlee, A. W., Dickenson, S. B., Hunter-Giordano, A., &amp; Snyder-Mackler, L. (2022). ACL reconstruction rehabilitation: Clinical data, biologic healing, and criterion-based milestones to inform a return-to-sport guideline. Sport Health, 14(5), 770-779. https://doi.org/10.1177/19417381211056873</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe, M., Danelon, F., La Rosa, G., Nanni, G., Stride, M., &amp; Della Villa, F. (2021). Recommendations for hamstring function recovery after ACL reconstruction. Sports Medicine, 51(4), 607-624. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-020-01400-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carleton, H. A., &amp; Webb, M. L. (2012). The case report in context. Yale J Biol Med, 85(1), 93-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cori, C. F., &amp; Cori, G. T. (1929). Glycogen formation in the liver from d- and l-lactic acid. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 81(2), 389-403. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0021-9258(18)83822-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducatti, M. H. M., Waiteman, M. C., Botta, A. F. B., Lopes, H. D. S., Glaviano, N. R., Azevedo, F. M., &amp; Briani, R. V. (2021). Knee flexor strenght, rate of torque development and flexibility in woman and men with patellofemoral pain: Relationship with pain and the performance in the single leg bridge test. Physical Therapy in Sport, 50, 166-172. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.05.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Encarnaci&#xf3;n-Mart&#xed;nez, A., Garc&#xed;a-Gallart, A., Sanchis-Sanchis, R., Jimenez-Perez, I., Priego-Quesada, J. I., &amp; P&#xe9;rez-Soriano, P. (2022). Higher hamstrings strength and stability are related to lower kinematics alteration during running after central and peripheral fatigue. Sensors, 22(5), 1990. https://doi.org/10.3390/s22051990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay, S. R., &amp; Grindem, H. (2019). Evidence-based recommendations for the management of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) rupture. Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Rheumatology, 33(1), 33-47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.berh.2019.01.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman, K. B., D'Amato, M. J., Nedeff, D. D., Kaz, A., &amp; Bach, B. R., Jr. (2003). Arthroscopic anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A metaanalysis comparing patellar tendon and hamstring tendon autografts. The American Journal of Sports Medicine, 31(1), 2-11. https://doi.org/10.1177/03635465030310011501</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnier, J. J., Kienle, G., Altman, D. G., Moher, D., Sox, H., &amp; Riley, D., &amp; CARE Group. (2013). The CARE guidelines: Consensus-based clinical case reporting guideline development. Global Advances in Health and Medicine, 2(5), 38-43. https://doi.org/10.7453/gahmj.2013.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem, H., Snyder-Mackler, L., Moksnes, H., Engebretsen, L., &amp; Risberg, M. A. (2016). Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: The Delaware-oslo ACL cohort study. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 50(13), 804-808. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-096031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harput, G., Kilinc, H. E., Ozer, H., Baltaci, G., &amp; Mattacola, C. G. (2015). Quadriceps and hamstring strength recovery during early neuromuscular rehabilitation after ACL hamstrings-tendon autograft reconstruction. Journal of Sport Rehabilitation, 24(4), 398-404. https://doi.org/10.1123/jsr.2014-0224</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano, M., Katoh, M., Gomi, M., &amp; Arai, S. (2020). Validity and reliability of isometric knee extension muscle strength measurement using a belt-stabilized hand-held dynamometer: A comparison with the measurement using an isokinetic dynamometer in a sitting posture. Journal of Physical Therapy Science, 32(2), 120-124. https://doi.org/10.1589/jpts.32.120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, W., Zhang, Y., Yao, Z., &amp; Ma, L. (2016). Clinical examination of anterior cruciate ligament rupture: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Orthopaedica et Traumatologica Turcica, 50(1), 22-31. https://doi.org/10.3944/AOTT.2016.14.0283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes, L., Paton, B., Rosenblatt, B., Gissane, C., &amp; Patterson, S. D. (2017). Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: A systematic review and meta-analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 51(13), 1003-1011. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-097071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes, L., Rosenblatt, B., Haddad, F., Gissane, C., McCarthy, D., Clarke, T., Ferris, G., Dawes, J., Paton, B., &amp; Patterson, S. D. (2019). Comparing the effectiveness of blood flow restriction and traditional heavy load resistance training in the post-surgery rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients: A UK national health service randomised controlled trial. Sports Medicine, 49(11), 1787-1805. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-019-01137-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humes, C., Aguero, S., Chahla, J., &amp; Foad, A. (2020). Blood flow restriction and its function in post-operative anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction therapy: Expert opinion. Archives of Bone and Joint Surgery, 8(5), 570-574. https://doi.org/10.22038/abjs.2020.42068.2145</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins, S. M., Guzman, A., Gardner, B. B., Bryant, S. A., Del Sol, S. R., McGahan, P., &amp; Chen, J. (2022). Rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament injury: Review of current literature and recommendations. Current Reviews in Musculoskeletal Medicine, 15(3), 170-179. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12178-022-09752-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee, M. B., Buckner, S. L., Mouser, J. G., Mattocks, K. T., Dankel, S. J., Abe, T., Bell, Z. W., Bentley, J. P., Jeremy, P., &amp; Loenneke, J. P. (2018). Muscle adaptations to high-load training and very low-load training with and without blood flow restriction. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 1448. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2018.01448</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin, A., Drobni&#x10d;, M., Mar&#x161;, T., Mi&#x161;, K., Petri&#x10d;, M., Weber, D., Tomc &#x17d;argi, T., Martin&#x10d;i&#x10d;, D., &amp; Pirkmajer, S. (2021). Functional and molecular adaptations of quadriceps and hamstring muscle to blood Flow restricted training in patient with ACL rupture. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 31(8), 1636-1646. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.13968</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keays, S. L., Bullock-Saxton, J. E., Newcombe, P., &amp; Bullock, M. I. (2006). The effectiveness of a pre-operative home-based physiotherapy programme for chronic anterior cruciate ligament deficiency. Physiotherapy Research International, 11(4), 204-218. https://doi.org/10.1002/pri.341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilgas, M. A., Lytle, L. L. M., Drum, S. N., &amp; Elmer, S. J. (2019). Exercise with blood flow restriction to improve quadriceps function long after ACL recostruction. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 40(10), 650-656. https://doi.org/10.1055/a-0961-1434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilinc, B. E., Kara, A., Camur, S., Oc, Y., &amp; Celik, H. (2015). Isokinetic dynamometer evaluation of the effects of early thig diameter difference on thigh muscle strength in patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with hamstring tendon graft. Journal of Exercise Rehabilitation, 11(2), 95-100. https://doi.org/10.12965/jer.150100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrath, J. M., Vertullo, C. J., Kennedy, B. A., Bush, H. S., Barrett, R. S., &amp; Lloyd, D. G. (2016). Morphologic characteristics and strength of the hamstring muscle remain altered at 2 years after use of a hamstring tendon graft in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. The American Journal of Sports Medicine, 44(10), 2589-2598. https://doi.org/10.1177/0363546516651441</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz, D. S., Bailey, L., Wilk, K. E., Mangine, R. E., Head, P., Grindstaff, T. L., &amp; Morrison, S. (2021). Blood flow restriction training. Journal of Athletic Training, 56(9), 937-944. https://doi.org/10.4085/418-20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y., Patel, B. H., Kym, C., Nwachukwu, B. U., Beletksy, A., Forsythe, B., &amp; Chahla, J. (2020). Perioperative blood flow restriction rehabilitation in patients undergoing ACL reconstruction: A systematic review. Orthopaedic Journal of Sports Medicine, 8(3), 2325967120906822. https://doi.org/10.1177/2325967120906822</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks, K. T., Jessee, M. B., Mouser, J. G., Dankel, S. J., Buckner, S. L., Bell, Z. W., Owens, J. G., Abe, T., &amp; Loenneke, J. P. (2018). The application of blood flow restriction: Lessons from the laboratory. Current Sports Medicine Reports, 17(4), 129-134. https://doi.org/10.1249/JSR.0000000000000473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meierbachtol, A., Obermeier, M., Yungtum, W., Bottoms, J., Paur, E., Nelson, B. J., Tompkins, M., &amp; Chmielewski, T. L. (2022). Advanced training enhances readiness to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Journal of Orthopaedic Research, 40(1), 191-199. https://doi.org/10.1002/jor.25072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulford, J. S., Hutchinson, S. E., &amp; Hang, J. R. (2013). Outcomes for primary anterior cruciate reconstruction with the quadriceps autograft: A systematic review. Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy, 21(8), 1882-1888. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-012-2212-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento, D., Rolnick, N., Neto, I., Severin, R., &amp; Beal, F. (2022). A useful blood flow restriction training risk stratification for exercise and rehabilitation. Frontiers in Physiology, 13, 808622. https://doi.org/10.3389/FPHYS.2022.808622</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen, J. L., Aagaard, P., Prokhorova, T. A., Nygaard, T., Bech, R. D., Suetta, C., &amp; Frandsen, U. (2017). Blood flow restricted training leads to myocellular macrophage infiltration and upregulation of heat shock proteins, but no apparent muscle damage. The Journal of Physiology, 595(14), 4857-4873. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP273907</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta, H., Kurosawa, H., Ikeda, H., Iwase, Y., Satou, N., &amp; Nakamura, S. (2003). Low-load resistance muscular training with moderate restriction of blood flow after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Acta Orthopaedica Scandinavica, 74(1), 62-68. https://doi.org/10.1080/00016470310013680</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson, S., Hughes, L., Head, P., Warmington, S., &amp; Brandner, C. (2017). Blood flow restriction training: A novel approach to augment clinical rehabilitation: How to do it. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 51(23), 1648-1649. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2017-097738</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson, S. D., Hughes, L., Warmington, S., Burr, J., Scott, B. R., Owens, J., Abe, T., Nielsen, J. L., Libardi, C. A., Laurentino, G., Neto, G. R., Brandner, C., Martin-Hernandez, J., &amp; Loenneke, J. (2019). Blood flow restriction exercise: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 533. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2019.00533</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson, S. J., &amp; Hussain, S. R. (2015). A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Medicine, 45(2), 187-200. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-014-0264-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccoli, A., Rossettini, G., Cecchetto, S., Viceconti, A., Ristori, D., Turolla, A., Maselli, F., &amp; Testa, M. (2018). Effect of attentional focus instructions on motor learning and performance of patients with central nervous system and musculoskeletal disorders: A systematic review. Journal of Functional Morphology and Kinesiology, 3(3), 40. https://doi.org/10.3390/jfmk3030040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riaz, O., Aqil, A., Mannan, A., Hossain, F., Ali, M., Chakrabarty, G., &amp; Radcliffe, G. (2018). Quadriceps tendon-bone or patellar tendon-bone autografts when reconstructing the anterior cruciate ligament: A meta-analysis. Clinical Journal of Sport Medicine, 28(3), 316-324. https://doi.org/10.1097/JSM.0000000000000451</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld, B. J. (2010). The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research, 24(10), 2857-2872. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e840f3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherman, D. A., Glaviano, N. R., &amp; Norte, G. E. (2021). Hamstrings neuromuscular function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Medicine, 51(8), 1751-1769. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-021-01433-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoenfeld, B. J., Grgic, J., Van Every, D. W., &amp; Plotkin, D. L. (2021). Loading reccomendations for muscle strenght, hypertrophy, and local endurance: A Re-examination of the repetition continuum. Sport (Basel), 9(2), 32. https://doi.org/10.3390/sports9020032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sokal, P. A., Norris, R., Maddox, T. W., &amp; Oldershaw, R. A. (2022). The diagnostic accuracy of clinical tests for anterior cruciate ligament tears are comparable but the lachman test has been previously overestimated: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy, 30(10), 3287-3303. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-022-06898-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solie, B. S., Eggleston, G. G., Schwery, N. A., Doney, C. P., Kiely, M. T., &amp; Larson, C. M. (2023). Clinic and home-based exercise with blood flow restriction resolves thigh muscle atrophy after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with the bone-patellar tendon-bone autograft: A case report. Healthcare, 11(13), 1885. https://doi.org/10.3390/healthcare11131885</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada, Y., Takazawa, H., &amp; Ishii, N. (2000). Applications of vascular occlusion diminish disuse atrophy of knee extensor muscles. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 32(12), 2035-2039. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005768-200012000-00011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada, Y., Takazawa, H., Sato, Y., Takebayashi, S., Tanaka, Y., &amp; Ishii, N. (2000). Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology, 88(6), 2097-2106. https://doi.org/10.1152/jappl.2000.88.6.2097</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tennent, D. J., Burns, T. C., Johnson, A. E., Owens, J. G., &amp; Hyden, C. M. (2018). Blood flow restriction training for postoperative lower-extremity weakness: A report of three cases. Current Sports Medicine Reports, 17(4), 119-122. https://doi.org/10.1249/JSR.0000000000000470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Testa, M., &amp; Rossettini, G. (2016). Enhance placebo, avoid nocebo: How contextual factors affect physiotherapy outcomes. Manual Therapy, 24, 65-74. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.math.2016.04.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Essen, C., McCallum, S., Eriksson, K., &amp; Barenius, B. (2022). Minimal graft site morbidity using autogenous semitendinosus graft from the uninjured leg: A randomized controlled trial. Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy, 30(5), 1639-1645. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00167-021-06686-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wald&#xe9;n, M., H&#xe4;gglund, M., Magnusson, H., &amp; Ekstrand, J. (2016). ACL injuries in men's professional football: A 15-year prospective study on time trends and return-to-play rates reveals only 65% of players still play at the top level 3 years after ACL rupture. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 50(12), 744-750. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2015-095952</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortman, R. J., Brown, S. M., Savage-Elliott, I., Finley, Z. J., &amp; Mulcahey, M. K. (2021). Blood flow restriction training for athletes: A systematic review. The American Journal of Sports Medicine, 49(7), 1938-1944. https://doi.org/10.1177/0363546520964454</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Wang, X., &amp; Wang, J. (2022). Effect of blood flow restriction combined with low-intensity training on the lower limbs muscle strength and function in older adults: A meta- analysis. Experimental Gerontology, 164, 111827. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exger.2022.111827</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>