<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31009425</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Blood Flow Restriction Does Not Attenuate Short-Term Detraining-Induced Muscle Size and Strength Losses After Resistance Training With Blood Flow Restriction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2082</StartPage><EndPage>2088</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2082-2088</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003148</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Teixeira, EL, de Salles Painelli, V, Silva-Batista, C, de Souza Barros, T, Longo, AR, Lasevicius, T, Schoenfeld, BJ, Aihara, AY, and de Almeida Peres, B. Blood flow restriction does not attenuate short-term detraining-induced muscle size and strength losses after resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Strength Cond Res 35(8): 2082-2088, 2021-After a short-term resistance training with blood flow restriction (BFR), we investigated the effects of 12 days of detraining (DET), without an exercise stimulus, on quadriceps cross-sectional area (QCSA) and muscle strength (1 repetition maximum [1RM]), with 1 leg receiving daily intermittent BFR during DET vs. the same nonexercise condition without BFR (CON) in the contralateral leg. Both subjects' legs were evaluated for QCSA and 1RM before (PRE) and after (POST) both legs being unilaterally submitted to 3 weeks (4 days per week) of low-load (3 sets of 15 repetitions, 30% 1RM) resistance training with BFR. The DET period started immediately after POST, where each leg was randomly submitted to a daily intermittent BFR protocol or CON, without any associated exercise stimulus. Quadriceps cross-sectional area and 1RM were reassessed after DET. Both legs at CON and BFR conditions increased QCSA (6.3 and 6.8%, respectively; both p &lt; 0.0001) and 1RM (9.5 and 10.1%, respectively; both p &lt; 0.05) from PRE to POST. Both legs at CON and BFR conditions reduced QCSA (-4.6 and 4.9%, respectively; both p &lt; 0.0001) and 1RM (-9.0 and -8.2%, respectively; both p &lt; 0.05) from POST to DET, with no significant differences between conditions (p &gt; 0.05). We conclude that muscle strength and hypertrophy gains obtained in 3 weeks of resistance training with BFR are not maintained after 12 days of DET. Moreover, the application of BFR, without an associated exercise stimulus, does not attenuate such losses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Emerson L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Salles Painelli</LastName><ForeName>Vitor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva-Batista</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Arts, Sciences and Humanities, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Souza Barros</LastName><ForeName>Talita</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longo</LastName><ForeName>Ariel R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lasevicius</LastName><ForeName>Thiago</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Cuny Lehman College, Bronx, New York; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aihara</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9; Y</ForeName><Initials>AY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>America's Diagnostics S/A, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Almeida Peres</LastName><ForeName>Bergson</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Strength Training Study and Research Group, Institute of Health Sciences, Paulista University, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006439" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202108000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. Accurate assessment of muscular strength and power, ASEP procedures recommendation. JEPonline 4: 1&#x2013;21, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel CS, James MC, Bamman MM. Exercise dosing to retain resistance training adaptations in young and older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1177&#x2013;1187, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Some Issues in Power Analysis. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 531&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellefsen S, Hammarstr&#xf5;m D, Strand TA, et al. Blood flow-restricted strength training displays high functional and biological efficacy in women: A within-subject comparison with high-load strength training. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Cmp Physiol 309: 767&#x2013;779, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatouros IG, Kambas A, Katrabasas I, et al. Strength training and detraining effects on muscular strength, anaerobic power, and mobility of inactive older men are intensity dependent. Br J Sports Med 39: 776&#x2013;780, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Appl Physiol 108: 1199&#x2013;1209, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Q, Sugiyama Y, Kamiya A, Shamsuzzaman AS, Mano T. Responses of muscle sympathetic nerve activity to lower body positive pressure. Am J Physiol 275: 1254&#x2013;1259, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol 103: 903&#x2013;910, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita T, Brechue WF, Kurita K, Sato Y, Abe T. Increased muscle volume and strength following six days of low-intensity resistance training with restricted muscle blood flow. Int J Kaatsu Train Res 4: 1&#x2013;8, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson JN, Halliday D, Morrison WL, et al. Decrease in human quadriceps muscle protein turnover consequent upon leg immobilization. Clin Sci (Lond) 72: 503&#x2013;509, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glover EI, Phillips SM, Oates BR, et al. Immobilization induces anabolic resistance in human myofibrillar protein synthesis with low and high dose amino acid infusion. J Physiol 586: 6049&#x2013;6061, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gundermann DM, Walker DK, Reidy PT, et al. Activation of mTORC1 signaling and protein synthesis in human muscle following blood flow restriction exercise is inhibited by rapamycin. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 306: 1198&#x2013;1204, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawada S, Ishii N. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy after chronic restriction of venous blood flow in rats. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 1144&#x2013;1150, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Komuro T, Ishiguro N, et al. Effects of low-load resistance training with vascular occlusion on the mechanical properties of muscle and tendon. J Appl Biomech 22: 112&#x2013;119, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota A, Sakuraba K, Sawaki K, Sumide T, Tamura Y. Prevention of disuse musclar weakness by restriction of blood flow. Med Sci Sports Exerc 40: 529&#x2013;534, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota A, Sakuraba K, Koh S, Ogura Y, Tamura Y. Blood flow restriction by low compressive force prevents disuse muscular weakness. J Sci Med Sport 14: 95&#x2013;99, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Loenneke JP, Teixeira EL, et al. The effect of cuff width on muscle adaptations after blood flow restriction training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 920&#x2013;925, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, Aoki MS, Soares AG, Neves M Jr, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc 44: 406&#x2013;412, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino GC, et al. Effects of exercise intensity and occlusion pressure after 12 weeks of resistance training with blood-flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 2471&#x2013;2480, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 361&#x2013;378, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Thiebaud RS, et al. The acute muscle swelling effects of blood flow restriction. Acta Physiol Hung 99: 400&#x2013;410, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Mar&#xed;n PJ, Zourdos MC, Bemben MG. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: A meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1849&#x2013;1859, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manini TM, Vincent KR, Leeuwenburgh CL, et al. Myogenic and proteolytic mRNA expression following blood flow restricted exercise. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 201: 255&#x2013;263, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, McGlory C, Gibala MJ, Phillips SM. Investigating human skeletal muscle physiology with unilateral exercise models: When one limb is more powerful than two. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 42: 563&#x2013;570, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Detraining: Loss of training-induced physiological and performance adaptations. Part I: Short term insufficient training stimulus. Sports Med 30: 79&#x2013;87, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, et al. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Physiol 590: 4351&#x2013;4361, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Kobayashi K, Tsutaki A, et al. mTOR signaling response to resistance exercise is altered by chronic resistance training and detraining in skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 114: 934&#x2013;940, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos AR, Neves MT Jr, Gualano B, et al. Blood flow restricted resistance training attenuates myostatin gene expression in a patient with inclusion body myositis. Biol Sport 31: 121&#x2013;124, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz J, Stultz J, Burr JF. The efficacy of blood flow restricted exercise: A systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 19: 669&#x2013;675, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Morita N, et al. Dose effect on intramuscular metabolic stress during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol 108: 1563&#x2013;1567, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Takada S, et al. Effect of multiple set on intramuscular metabolic stress during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 3915&#x2013;3920, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh YA, Arnold RS, Lassegue B, et al. Cell transformation by the superoxide-generating oxidade Mox1. Nature 401: 79&#x2013;82, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki YJ, Ford GD. Redox regulation of signal transduction in cardiac and smooth muscle. J Mol Cell Cardiol 31: 345&#x2013;353, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Ishii N. Applications of vascular occlusion diminish disuse atrophy of knee extensor muscles. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 2035&#x2013;2039, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira EL, Barroso R, Silva-Batista C, et al. Blood flow restriction increases metabolic stress but decreases muscle activation during high-load resistance exercise. Muscle Nerve 57: 107&#x2013;111, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, et al. Comparisons between low-intensity resistance training with blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training on quadriceps muscle mass and strength in elderly. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1071&#x2013;1076, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Abe T, Sato Y, et al. Muscle fiber cross-sectional area is increased after two weeks of twice daily KAATSU-resistance training. Int J Kaatsu Train Res 1: 65&#x2013;70, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Sato Y, Yamasoba T, Nakajima T. Effects of detraining after blood flow-restricted low-intensity training on muscle size and strength in older adults. Aging Clin Exp Res 26: 561&#x2013;564, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Effects of detraining after blood flow-restricted low-intensity concentric or eccentric training on muscle size and strength. J Physiol Sci 65: 139&#x2013;144, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Loenneke JP, Ogasawara R, Abe T. Effects of short-term detraining following blood flow restricted low-intensity training on muscle size and strength. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 71&#x2013;75, 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>