<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">21984538</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-1539</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>302</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physiology. Heart and circulatory physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The coronary circulation in exercise training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>H10</StartPage><EndPage>H23</EndPage><MedlinePgn>H10-23</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1152/ajpheart.00574.2011</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Exercise training (EX) induces increases in coronary transport capacity through adaptations in the coronary microcirculation including increased arteriolar diameters and/or densities and changes in the vasomotor reactivity of coronary resistance arteries. In large animals, EX increases capillary exchange capacity through angiogenesis of new capillaries at a rate matched to EX-induced cardiac hypertrophy so that capillary density remains normal. However, after EX coronary capillary exchange area is greater (i.e., capillary permeability surface area product is greater) at any given blood flow because of altered coronary vascular resistance and matching of exchange surface area and blood flow distribution. The improved coronary capillary blood flow distribution appears to be the result of structural changes in the coronary tree and alterations in vasoreactivity of coronary resistance arteries. EX also alters vasomotor reactivity of conduit coronary arteries in that after EX, &#x3b1;-adrenergic receptor responsiveness is blunted. Of interest, &#x3b1;- and &#x3b2;-adrenergic tone appears to be maintained in the coronary microcirculation in the presence of lower circulating catecholamine levels because of increased receptor responsiveness to adrenergic stimulation. EX also alters other vasomotor control processes of coronary resistance vessels. For example, coronary arterioles exhibit increased myogenic tone after EX, likely because of a calcium-dependent PKC signaling-mediated alteration in voltage-gated calcium channel activity in response to stretch. Conversely, EX augments endothelium-dependent vasodilation throughout the coronary arteriolar network and in the conduit arteries in coronary artery disease (CAD). The enhanced endothelium-dependent dilation appears to result from increased nitric oxide bioavailability because of changes in nitric oxide synthase expression/activity and decreased oxidant stress. EX also decreases extravascular compressive forces in the myocardium at rest and at comparable levels of exercise, mainly because of decreases in heart rate and duration of systole. EX does not stimulate growth of coronary collateral vessels in the normal heart. However, if exercise produces ischemia, which would be absent or minimal under resting conditions, there is evidence that collateral growth can be enhanced. While there is evidence that EX can decrease the progression of atherosclerotic lesions or even induce the regression of atherosclerotic lesions in humans, the evidence of this is not strong due to the fact that most prospective trials conducted to date have included other lifestyle changes and treatment strategies by necessity. The literature from large animal models of CAD also presents a cloudy picture concerning whether EX can induce the regression of or slow the progression of atherosclerotic lesions. Thus, while evidence from research using humans with CAD and animal models of CAD indicates that EX increases endothelium-dependent dilation throughout the coronary vascular tree, evidence that EX reverses or slows the progression of lesion development in CAD is not conclusive at this time. This suggests that the beneficial effects of EX in CAD may not be the result of direct effects on the coronary artery wall. If this suggestion is true, it is important to determine the mechanisms involved in these beneficial effects.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laughlin</LastName><ForeName>M Harold</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Missouri, Columbia, 65211, USA. laughlinm@missouri.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowles</LastName><ForeName>Douglas K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duncker</LastName><ForeName>Dirk J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>HL-52490</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100901228</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0363-6135</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003324" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Artery Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003326" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coronary Circulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003331" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Vessels</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000294" MajorTopicYN="N">innervation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006439" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008833" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microcirculation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21984538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3334245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00574.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ajpheart.00574.2011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anversa P, Levicky V, Beghi C, McDonald SL, Kikkawa Y. Morphometry of exercise-induced right ventricular hypertrophy in the rat. Circ Res 52: 57&#x2013;64, 1983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6848210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bache RJ. Effects of hypertrophy on the cornary circulation. Prog Cardiovasc Dis 30: 403&#x2013;440, 1988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2966968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bache RJ, Dai XZ, Schwartz JS, Homans DC. Role of adenosine in coronary vasodilation during exercise. Circ Res 62: 846&#x2013;853, 1988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3349577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbier J, Reland S, Ville N, Rannou-Bekono F, Wong S, Carre F. The effects of exercise training on myocardial adrenergic and muscarinic receptors. Clin Auton Res 16: 61&#x2013;65, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16477498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnard RJ, Duncan HW, Baldwin KM, Grimditch G, Buckberg DD. Effects of intensive exercise training on myocardial performance and coronary blood flow. J Appl Physiol 49: 444&#x2013;449, 1980</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7204167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baur TS, Brodowicz GR, Lamb DR. Indomethacin suppresses the coronary flow response to hypoxia in exercise trained and sedentary rats. Cardiovasc Res 24: 733&#x2013;736, 1990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2224940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belardinelli R, Georgiou D, Ginzton L, Cianci G, Purcaro A. Effects of moderate exercise training on thallium uptake and contractile response to low-dose dobutamine of dysfunctional myocardium in patients with ischemic cardiomyopathy. Circulation 97: 553&#x2013;561, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9494025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belardinelli R, Paolini I, Cianci G, Piva R, Georgiou D, Purcaro A. Exercise training intervention after coronary angioplasty: the ETICA trial. J Am Coll Cardiol 37: 1891&#x2013;1900, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11401128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell RD, Rasmussen RL. Exercise and the myocardial capillary-fiber ratio during growth. Growth 38: 237&#x2013;244, 1974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4413354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair SN, Church TS. The fitness, obesity, and health equation: is physical activity the common denominator? JAMA 292: 1232&#x2013;1234, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15353537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist CG, Saltin B. Cardiovascular adaptations to physical training. Annu Rev Physiol 45: 169&#x2013;189, 1983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6221687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloor CM, Leon AS. Interaction of age and exercise on the heart and its blood supply. Lab Invest 22: 160&#x2013;165, 1970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5416694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloor CM, White FC, Sanders TM. Effects of exercise on collateral development in myocardial ischemia in pigs. J Appl Physiol 56: 656&#x2013;665, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6706773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolter CP, Hughson RL, Critz JB. Intrinsic rate and cholinergic sensitivity of isolated atria from trained and sedentary rats. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med 144: 364&#x2013;367, 1973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4771582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bove AA, Dewey JD. Proximal coronary vasomotor reactivity after exercise training in dogs. Circulation 71: 620&#x2013;625, 1985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3971531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bove AA, Hultgren PB, Ritzer TF, Carey RA. Myocardial blood flow and hemodynamic responses to exercise training in dogs. J Appl Physiol 46: 571&#x2013;578, 1979</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">438029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowles DK, Hu Q, Laughlin MH, Sturek M. Exercise training increases L-type calcium current density in coronary smooth muscle. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 275: H2159&#x2013;H2169, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9843816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Bowles DK, Laughlin MH, Sturek M.
Exercise training increases K<sup>+</sup>-channel contribution to regulation of coronary arterial tone. J Appl Physiol
84: 1225&#x2013;1233, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9516188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowles DK, Wamhoff BR. Coronary smooth muscle adaptation to exercise: does it play a role in cardioprotection? Acta Physiol Scand 178: 117&#x2013;121, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12780385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breisch EA, White FC, Nimmo LE, McKirnan MD, Bloor CM. Exercise-induced cardiac hypertrophy: a correlation of blood flow and microvasculature. J Appl Physiol 60: 1259&#x2013;1267, 1986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2939050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown MD. Exercise and coronary vascular remodelling in the healthy heart. Exp Physiol 88: 645&#x2013;658, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12955165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burt JJ, Jackson R. The effects of physical exercise on the coronary collateral circulation of dogs. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 5: 203&#x2013;206, 1965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5861599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttrick PM, Levite HA, Schaible TF, Ciambrone G, Scheuer J. Early increases in coronary vascular reserve in exercised rats are independent of cardiac hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol 59: 1861&#x2013;1865, 1985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2934365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttrick PM, Scheuer J. Physiologic, biochemical, and coronary adaptation to exercise conditioning. Cardiol Clin 5: 259&#x2013;270, 1987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2953417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey RA, Santamore WP, Michele JJ, Bove AA. Effects of endurance training on coronary resistance in dogs. Med Sci Sports Exerc 15: 355&#x2013;359, 1983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6645861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlsson S, Ljungqvist A, Tornling G, Unge G. The myocardial capillary vasculature in repeated physical exercise. Acta Pathol Microbiol Scand A 86: 117&#x2013;119, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">696314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casscells W, Naghavi M, Willerson JT. Vulnerable atherosclerotic plaque: a multifocal disease. Circulation 107: 2072&#x2013;2075, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12719287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerretelli P, Di Prampero PE. Gas exchange in exercise. In: Handbook of Physiology. The Respiratory System, Gas Exchange. Bethesda, MD: Am. Physiol. Soc., 1987, sect. 3, vol. IV, chapt. 16, p. 297&#x2013;340</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen JP, Larsen OA, Trap-Jensen J. Physical training in the management of coronary artery disease. Circulation 40: 143&#x2013;154, 1969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5796786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MV. Coronary vascular reserve in the greyhound with left ventricular hypertrophy. Cardiovasc Res 20: 182&#x2013;194, 1986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2939956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MV. Lack of effect of propranolol on canine coronary collateral development during progressive coronary stenosis and occlusion. Cardiovasc Res 27: 249&#x2013;254, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8472276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MV. Training in dogs with normal coronary arteries: lack of effect on collateral development. Cardiovasc Res 24: 121&#x2013;128, 1990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2328517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MV, Yipintsoi T, Malhotra A, Penpargkul S, Scheuer J. Effect of exercise on collateral development in dogs with normal coronary arteries. J Appl Physiol 45: 797&#x2013;805, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">215585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currens JH, White PD. Half a century of running. Clinical, physiologic and autopsy findings in the case of Clarence DeMar (&#x201c;Mr Marathon&#x201d;). N Engl J Med 265: 988&#x2013;993, 1961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13882716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delp MD, McAllister RM, Laughlin MH. Exercise training alters endothelium-dependent vasoreactivity of rat abdominal aorta. J Appl Physiol 75: 1354&#x2013;1363, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiCarlo SE, Blair RW, Bishop VS, Stone HL. Daily exercise enhances coronary resistance vessel sensitivity to pharmacological activation. J Appl Physiol 66: 421&#x2013;428, 1989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2563725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiCarlo SE, Blair RW, Bishop VS, Stone HL. Role of beta 2-adrenergic receptors on coronary resistance during exercise. J Appl Physiol 64: 2287&#x2013;2293, 1988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2900233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd-o JM, Gwirtz PA. Cardiac response to acute coronary artery occlusion in exercise-trained dogs. Med Sci Sports Exerc 24: 1245&#x2013;1251, 1992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1435176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncker DJ, Bache RJ. Regulation of coronary blood flow during exercise. Physiol Rev 88: 1009&#x2013;1086, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncker DJ, Van Zon NS, Crampton M, Herrlinger S, Homans DC, Bache RJ. Coronary pressure-flow relationship and exercise: contributions of heart rate, contractility, and alpha 1-adrenergic tone. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 266: H795&#x2013;H810, 1994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8141381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein RW. Effect of exercise and coronary artery narrowing on coronary collateral circulation. Circ Res 5: 230&#x2013;235, 1957</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13427133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Edwards JM, Neeb ZP, Alloosh MA, Long X, Bratz IN, Peller CR, Byrd JP, Kumar S, Obukhov AG, Sturek M.
Exercise training decreases store-operated Ca<sup>2+</sup> entry associated with metabolic syndrome and coronary atherosclerosis. Cardiovasc Res
85: 631&#x2013;640, 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2802199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19744946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehsani AA, Hagberg JM, Hickson RC. Rapid changes in left ventricular dimensions and mass in response to physical conditioning and deconditioning. Am J Cardiol 42: 52&#x2013;56, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">677037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favret F, Henderson KK, Clancy RL, Richalet JP, Gonzalez NC. Exercise training alters the effect of chronic hypoxia on myocardial adrenergic and muscarinic receptor number. J Appl Physiol 91: 1283&#x2013;1288, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11509527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleenor BS, Bowles DK. Exercise training decreases the size and alters the composition of the neointima in a porcine model of percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty (PTCA). J Appl Physiol 107: 937&#x2013;945, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19556453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogarty JA, Muller-Delp JM, Delp MD, Mattox ML, Laughlin MH, Parker JL. Exercise training enhances vasodilation responses to vascular endothelial growth factor in porcine coronary arterioles exposed to chronic coronary occlusion. Circulation 109: 664&#x2013;670, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank A. Experimentelle herzhypertrophie. Z Ges Exp Med 115, 1950</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin BA. Exercise training and coronary collateral circulation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 23: 648&#x2013;653, 1991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1886472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gielen S, Schuler G, Adams V. Cardiovascular effects of exercise training: molecular mechanisms. Circulation 122: 1221&#x2013;1238, 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20855669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gielen S, Schuler G, Hambrecht R. Exercise training in coronary artery disease and coronary vasomotion. Circulation 103: e1&#x2013;e6, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11136704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin KL, Laughlin MH, Parker JL. Exercise training improves endothelium-mediated vasorelaxation after chronic coronary occlusion. J Appl Physiol 87: 1948&#x2013;1956, 1999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10562641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin KL, Woodman CR, Price EM, Laughlin MH, Parker JL. Endothelium-mediated relaxation of porcine collateral-dependent arterioles is improved by exercise training. Circulation 104: 1393&#x2013;1398, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11560855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwirtz PA, Stone HL. Coronary vascular response to adrenergic stimulation in exercise-conditioned dogs. J Appl Physiol 57: 315&#x2013;320, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6469800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagg U, Wandt B, Bergstrom G, Volkmann R, Gan Lm. Physical exercise capacity is associated with coronary and peripheral vascular function in healthy young adults. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 289: H1627&#x2013;H1634, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15937100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkila J. Studies on the myocardial capillary concentration in cardiac hypertrophy due to training; an experimental study with guinea pigs. Ann Med Exp Biol Fenn 33: 1&#x2013;82, 1955</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13327558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hambrecht R, Niebauer J, Marburger C, Grunze M, Kalberer B, Hauer K, Schlierf G, Kubler W, Schuler G. Various intensities of leisure time physical activity in patients with coronary artery disease: effects on cardiorespiratory fitness and progression of coronary atherosclerotic lesions. J Am Coll Cardiol 22: 468&#x2013;477, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8335816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hambrecht R, Wolf A, Gielen S, Linke A, Hofer J, Erbs S, Schoene N, Schuler G. Effect of exercise on coronary endothelial function in patients with coronary artery disease. N Engl J Med 342: 454&#x2013;460, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10675425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond HK, White FC, Brunton LL, Longhurst JC. Association of decreased myocardial beta-receptors and chronotropic response to isoproterenol and exercise in pigs following chronic dynamic exercise. Circ Res 60: 720&#x2013;726, 1987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3036395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannukainen JC, Janatuinen T, Toikka JO, Jarvisalo MJ, Heinonen OJ, Kapanen J, Nagren K, Nuutila P, Kujala UM, Kaprio J, Knuuti J, Kalliokoski KK. Myocardial and peripheral vascular functional adapation to exercise training. Scand J Med Sci Sports 17: 139&#x2013;147, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17394475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harri MN. Physical training under the influence of beta-blockade in rats. II. Effects on vascular reactivity. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 42: 151&#x2013;157, 1979</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">230962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell W, Alderman E, Fair J, Maron D, Mackey S, Superko H, Williams P, Johnstone I, Champagne M, Krauss R. Effects of intensive multiple risk factor reduction on coronary atherosclerosis and clinical cardiac events in men and women with coronary artery disease. The Stanford Coronary Risk Intervention Project (SCRIP). Circulation 89: 975&#x2013;990, 1994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8124838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Sims C, Myll J, Bortz WM, Goar FG, Alderman EL. Coronary artery size and dilating capacity in ultradistance runners. Circulation 87: 1076&#x2013;1082, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8462135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Heaps C, Bowles DK, Sturek M, Laughlin MH, Parker JL.
Enhanced L-type Ca<sup>2+</sup> channel current density in coronary smooth muscle of exercise-trained pigs is compensated to limit myoplasmic free Ca<sup>2+</sup> accumulation. J Physiol
528: 435&#x2013;445, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaps CL, Mattox ML, Kelly KA, Meininger CJ, Parker JL. Exercise training increases basal tone in arterioles distal to chronic coronary occlusion. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 290: H1128&#x2013;H1135, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4004092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16243909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaps CL, Sturek M, Rapps JA, Laughlin MH, Parker JL. Exercise training restores adenosine-induced relaxation in coronary arteries distal to chronic occlusion. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 278: H1984&#x2013;H1992, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10843897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaton WH, Marr KC, Capurro NL, Goldstein RE, Epstein SE. Beneficial effect of physical training on blood flow to myocardium perfused by chronic collaterals in the exercising dog. Circulation 27: 575&#x2013;581, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">624167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinonen I, Nesterov SV, Liukko K, Kemppainen J, N&#xe5;gren K, Luotolahti M, Virsu P, Oikonen V, Nuutila P, Kujala UM, Kainulainen H, Boushel R, Knuuti J, Kalliokoski KK. Myocardial blood flow and adenosine A2A receptor density in endurance athletes and untrained men. J Physiol 586: 5193&#x2013;5202, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2652164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18772204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiss HW, Barmeyer J, Wink J, Hell G, Cerny FJ, Keul J, Reindell H. Studies on the regulation of myocardial blood flow in man. I. Training effects on blood flow and metabolism of the healthy heart at rest and during standardized heavy exercise. Basic Res Cardiol 71: 658&#x2013;675, 1976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1016196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson KK, Turk JR, Rush JW, Laughlin MH. Endothelial function in coronary arterioles from pigs with early-stage coronary disease induced by high-fat, high-cholesterol diet: effect of exercise. J Appl Physiol 97: 1159&#x2013;1168, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15208294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heusch G. Adenosine and maximum coronary vasodilation in humans: myth and misconceptions in the assessment of coronary reserve. Basic Res Cardiol 105: 1&#x2013;5, 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19941145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildick-Smith DJ, Johnson PJ, Wisbey CR, Winter EM, Shapiro LM. Coronary flow reserve is supranormal in endurance athletes: an adenosine transthoracic echocardiographic study. Heart 84: 383&#x2013;389, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1729440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10995406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ishibashi Y, Duncker DJ, Zhang J, Bache RJ.
ATP-sensitive K<sup>+</sup> channels, adenosine, and nitric oxide-mediated mechanisms account for coronary vasodilation during exercise. Circ Res
82: 346&#x2013;359, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9486663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs TB, Bell RD, McClements JD. Exercise, age and the development of the myocardial vasculature. Growth 48: 148&#x2013;157, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6469048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson LR, Rush JW, Turk JR, Price EM, Laughlin MH. Short-term exercise training increases ACh-induced relaxation and eNOS protein in porcine pulmonary arteries. J Appl Physiol 90: 1102&#x2013;1110, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11181626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou NP, Kostomitsopoulos N, Kapelouzou A, Moustardas P, Katsimpoulas M, Giagini A, Dede E, Boudoulas H, Konstantinides S, Karayannacos PE, Liapis CD. Effects of exercise training on the severity and composition of atherosclerotic plaque in apoE-deficient mice. J Vasc Res 48: 347&#x2013;356, 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaer A, Meyer C, Wachtell K, Olsen MH, Ibsen H, Opie L, Holm S, Hesse B. Positron emission tomographic evaluation of regulation of myocardial perfusion in physiological (elite athletes) and pathological (systemic hypertension) left ventricular hypertrophy. Am J Cardiol 96: 1692&#x2013;1698, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16360359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight DR, Stone HL. Alteration of ischemic cardiac function in normal heart by daily exercise. J Appl Physiol 55: 52&#x2013;60, 1983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6885585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koerner JE, Terjung RL. Effect of physical training on coronary collateral circulation of the rat. J Appl Physiol 52: 376&#x2013;387, 1982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7061291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korzick DH, Laughlin MH, Bowles DK. Alterations in PKC signaling underlie enhanced myogenic tone in exercise-trained porcine coronary resistance arteries. J Appl Physiol 96: 1425&#x2013;1432, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14672961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozakova M, Galetta F, Gregorini L, Bigalli G, Franzoni F, Giusti C, Palombo C. Coronary vasodilator capacity and epicardial vessel remodeling in physiological and hypertensive hypertrophy. Hypertension 36: 343&#x2013;349, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10988262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozakova M, Paterni M, Bartolomucci F, Morizzo C, Rossi G, Galetta F, Palombo C. Epicardial coronary artery size in hypertensive and physiologic left ventricular hypertrophy. Am J Hypertens 20: 279&#x2013;284, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17324740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramsch DM, Aspen AJ, Abramowitz BM, Kreimendahl T, Hood WB., Jr Reduction of coronary atherosclerosis by moderate conditioning exercise in monkeys on an atherogenic diet. N Engl J Med 305: 1483&#x2013;1489, 1981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7300873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakka TA, Venalainen JM, Rauramaa R, Salonen R, Tuomilehto J, JT Relation of leisure-time physical activity and cardiorespiratory fitness to the risk of acute myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med 330: 1549&#x2013;1554, 1994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8177243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH. Coronary transport reserve in normal dogs. J Appl Physiol 57: 551&#x2013;561, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6088451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH. Effects of exercise training on coronary transport capacity. J Appl Physiol 58: 468&#x2013;476, 1985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3920188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH. Endothelium-mediated control of coronary vascular tone after chronic exercise training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 27: 1135&#x2013;1144, 1995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7476057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH. Joseph B. Wolfe Memorial lecture. Physical activity in prevention and treatment of coronary disease: the battle line is in exercise vascular cell biology. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 352&#x2013;362, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15076775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Diana JN. Myocardial transcapillary exchange in the hypertrophied heart of the dog. Am J Physiol 229: 838&#x2013;846, 1975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">129013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Diana JN, Tipton CM. Effects of exercise training on coronary reactive hyperemia and blood flow in the dog. J Appl Physiol 45: 604&#x2013;610, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">711578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Korthuis RJ, Duncker DJ, Bache RJ. Control of blood flow to cardiac and skeletal muscle during exercise. In: Handbook of Physiology. Exercise: Regulation and Integration of Multiple Systems. Bethesda, MD: Am. Physiol. Soc., 1996, sect. 12, chapt. 16, p. 705&#x2013;769</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Muller JM. Vasoconstrictor responses of coronary resistance arteries in exercise-trained pigs. J Appl Physiol 84: 884&#x2013;889, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9480947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Overholser KA, Bhatte MJ. Exercise training increases coronary transport reserve in miniature swine. J Appl Physiol 67: 1140&#x2013;1149, 1989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2551878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Pollock JS, Amann JF, Hollis ML, Woodman CR, Price EM. Training induces nonuniform increases in eNOS content along the coronary arterial tree. J Appl Physiol 90: 501&#x2013;510, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Tomanek RJ. Myocardial capillarity and maximal capillary diffusion capacity in exercise-trained dogs. J Appl Physiol 63: 1481&#x2013;1486, 1987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3693184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Turk JR, Schrage WG, Woodman CR, Price EM. Influence of coronary artery diameter on eNOS protein content. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 284: H1307&#x2013;H1312, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12595288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Welshons WV, Sturek M, Rush JW, Turk JR, Taylor JA, Judy BM, Henderson KK, Ganjam VK. Gender, exercise training, and eNOS expression in porcine skeletal muscle arteries. J Appl Physiol 95: 250&#x2013;264, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12626483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBlanc J, Boulay M, Dulac S, Jobin M, Labrie A, Rousseau-Migneron S. Metabolic and cardiovascular responses to norepinephrine in trained and nontrained human subjects. J Appl Physiol 42: 166&#x2013;173, 1977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">838642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon AS, Bloor CM. The effect of complete and partial deconditioning on exercise-induced cardiovascular changes in the rat. Adv Cardiol 18: 81&#x2013;92, 1976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">136175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon AS, Bloor CM. Effects of exercise and its cessation on the heart and its blood supply. J Appl Physiol 24: 485&#x2013;490, 1968</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4230645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang IY, Hamra M, Stone HL. Maximum coronary blood flow and minimum coronary resistance in exercise-trained dogs. J Appl Physiol 56: 641&#x2013;647, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6706772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang IY, Stone HL. Changes in diastolic coronary resistance during submaximal exercise in conditioned dogs. J Appl Physiol 54: 1057&#x2013;1062, 1983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6853281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang IY, Stone HL, Gwirtz PA. Effect of beta 1-receptor blockade on coronary resistance in partially trained dogs. Med Sci Sports Exerc 19: 382&#x2013;388, 1987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2821340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang IY, Stone HL. Effect of exercise conditioning on coronary resistance. J Appl Physiol 53: 631&#x2013;636, 1982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7129984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Link RP, Pedersoli WM, Safanie AH. Effect of exercise on development of atherosclerosis in swine. Atherosclerosis 15: 107&#x2013;122, 1972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5062500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linke A, Adams V, Schulze PC, Erbs S, Gielen S, Fiehn E, Mobius-Winkler S, Schubert A, Schuler G, Hambrecht R. Antioxidative effects of exercise training in patients with chronic heart failure: increase in radical scavenger enzyme activity in skeletal muscle. Circulation 111: 1763&#x2013;1770, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15809365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linke A, Erbs S, Hambrecht R. Exercise and the coronary circulation&#x2014;alterations and adaptations in coronary artery disease. Prog Cardiovasc Dis 48: 270&#x2013;284, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16517248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ljungqvist A, Unge G. Capillary proliferative activity in myocardium and skeletal muscle of exercised rats. J Appl Physiol 43: 306&#x2013;307, 1977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">893288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann SJ, Krakoff LR, Felton K, Yeager K. Cardiovascular responses to infused epinephrine: effect of the state of physical conditioning. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol 6: 339&#x2013;343, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6200725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron BJ. Structural features of the athlete heart as defined by echocardiography. J Am Coll Cardiol 7: 190&#x2013;203, 1986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2934463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin WH, 3rd, Spina RJ, Korte E, Ogawa T. Effects of chronic and acute exercise on cardiovascular beta-adrenergic responses. J Appl Physiol 71: 1523&#x2013;1528, 1991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1661725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllister RM, Laughlin MH. Short-term exercise training alters responses of porcine femoral and brachial arteries. J Appl Physiol 82: 1438&#x2013;1444, 1997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9134890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElroy CL, Gissen SA, Fishbein MC. Exercise-induced reduction in myocardial infarct size after coronary artery occlusion in the rat. Circulation 57: 958&#x2013;962, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">639217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohlenkamp S, Bose D, Mahabadi AA, Heusch G, Erbel R. On the paradox of exercise: coronary atherosclerosis in an apparently healthy marathon runner. Nat Clin Pract Cardiovasc Med 4: 396&#x2013;401, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17589430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller JM, Myers PR, Laughlin MH. Exercise training alters myogenic responses in porcine coronary resistance arteries. J Appl Physiol 75: 2677&#x2013;2682, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8125889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller JM, Myers PR, Laughlin MH. Vasodilator responses of coronary resistance arteries of exercise- trained pigs. Circulation 89: 2308&#x2013;2314, 1994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8181157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napoli C, Williams-Ignarro S, de Nigris F, Lerman LO, D'Armiento FP, Crimi E, Byrns RE, Casamassimi A, Lanza A, Gombos F, Sica V, Ignarro LJ. Physical training and metabolic supplementation reduce spontaneous atherosclerotic plaque rupture and prolong survival in hypercholesterolemic mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 103: 10479&#x2013;10484, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1502483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16801544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neill WA, Nakornchai V, Oxendine J, Paul MS. Effect of beta-adrenergic suppression by propranolol on coronary collateral development in response to chronic coronary ischemia in dogs. Circulation 59: 280&#x2013;285, 1979</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">215339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neill WA, Oxendine JM. Exercise can promote coronary collateral development without improving perfusion of ischemic myocardium. Circulation 60: 1513&#x2013;1519, 1979</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">498479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niebaurer J, Hambrecht R, Marburger C, Hauer K, Velich T, von Hodenberg E, Schlierf G, Kubler W, Schuler G. Impact of intensive physical exercise and low-fat diet on collateral vessel formation in stable angina pectoris and angiographically confirmed coronary artery disease. Am J Cardiol 76: 771&#x2013;775, 1995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7572652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutter DO, Fuller EO. The role of isolated cardiac muscle preparations in the study of training effects on the heart. Med Sci Sports 9: 239&#x2013;245, 1977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">604719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okabe T, Kishimoto C, Murayama T, Yokode M, Kita T. Effects of exercise on the development of atherosclerosis in apolipoprotein E-deficient mice. Exp Clin Cardiol 11, 276&#x2013;279, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2274844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18651017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okabe TA, Shimada K, Hattori M, Murayama T, Yokode M, Kita T, Kishimoto C. Swimming reduces the severity of atherosclerosis in apolipoprotein E deficient mice by antioxidant effects. Cardiovasc Res 74: 537&#x2013;545, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17374527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oltman CL, Parker JL, Adams HR, Laughlin MH. Effects of exercise training on vasomotor reactivity of porcine coronary arteries. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 263: H372&#x2013;H382, 1992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1510134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oltman CL, Parker JL, Laughlin MH. Endothelium-dependent vasodilation of proximal coronary arteries from exercise-trained pigs. J Appl Physiol 79: 33&#x2013;40, 1995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7559239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ornish D, Brown SE, Scherwitz LW, Billings JH, Armstrong WT, Ports TA, McLanahan SM, Kirkeeide RL, Brand RJ, Gould KL. Can lifestyle changes reverse coronary heart disease? The Lifestyle Heart Trial. Lancet 336: 129&#x2013;133, 1990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1973470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overholser KA, Bhatte MJ, Laughlin MH. Modeling the effect of flow heterogeneity on coronary permeability-surface area. J Appl Physiol 71: 758&#x2013;769, 1991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1938750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker JL, Mattox ML, Laughlin MH. Contractile responsiveness of coronary arteries from exercise-trained rats. J Appl Physiol 83: 434&#x2013;443, 1997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9262438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccia A, Spataro A, Granata M, Biffi A, Caselli G, Alabiso A. Coronary arteries in physiological hypertrophy: echocardiographic evidence of increased proximal size in elite athletes. Int J Sports Med 11: 120&#x2013;126, 1990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2140109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penpargkul S, Scheuer J. The effect of physical training upon the mechanical and metabolic performance of the rat heart. J Clin Invest 49: 1859&#x2013;1868, 1970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC322675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5456797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petren T, Sj&#xf6;strand T, Sylven B. Der influss des trainings auf die haufigkeit der capillaren in herz- und skeltenmuskulatur. Arbeitsphysiologie 9: 376&#x2013;386, 1930</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petren T, Sylven B. Weitere untersuchungen uber den Einfluss des Trainings auf die Kapillarisierung der Herzmuskulator. Morphol Jahrb 80: 439&#x2013;444, 1937</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radvan J, Choudhury L, Sheridan DJ, Camici PG. Comparison of coronary vasodilator reserve in elite rowing athletes versus hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol 80: 1621&#x2013;1623, 1997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9416953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raven PB, Rohm-Young D, Blomqvist CG. Physical fitness and cardiovascular response to lower body negative pressure. J Appl Physiol 56: 138&#x2013;144, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6693313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro F, Alves AJ, Duarte JA, Oliveira J. Is exercise training an effective therapy targeting endothelial dysfunction and vascular wall inflammation? Int J Cardiol 141: 214&#x2013;221, 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19896741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Robles JC, Sturek M, Parker JL, Heaps CL.
Ca<sup>2+</sup> sensitization and PKC contribute to exercise training-enhanced contractility in porcine collateral-dependent coronary arteries. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol
300: H1201&#x2013;H1209, 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21297028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers PJ, Miller TD, Bauer BA, Brum JM, Bove AA, Vanhoutte PM. Exercise training and responsiveness of isolated coronary arteries. J Appl Physiol 71: 2346&#x2013;2351, 1991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1723405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth DA, White CD, Podolin DA, Mazzeo RS. Alterations in myocardial signal transduction due to aging and chronic dynamic exercise. J Appl Physiol 84: 177&#x2013;184, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9451633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth DM, White FC, Nichols ML, Dobbs SL, Longhurst JC, Bloor CM. Effect of long-term exercise on regional myocardial function and coronary collateral development after gradual coronary artery occlusion in pigs. Circulation 82: 1778&#x2013;1789, 1990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2225376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JW, Laughlin MH, Woodman CR, Price EM. SOD-1 expression in pig coronary arterioles is increased by exercise training. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 279: H2068&#x2013;H2076, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11045939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JW, Turk JR, Laughlin MH. Exercise training regulates SOD-1 and oxidative stress in porcine aortic endothelium. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 284: H1378&#x2013;H1387, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12595293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sable DL, Brammell HL, Sheehan MW, Nies AS, Gerber J, Horwitz LD. Attenuation of exercise conditioning by beta-adrenergic blockade. Circulation 65: 679&#x2013;684, 1982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7060245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders M, White FC, Peterson TM, Bloor CM. Effects of endurance exercise on coronary collateral blood flow in miniature swine. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 234: H614&#x2013;H619, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">645928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheel KW, Ingram LA, Wilson JL. Effects of exercise on the coronary and collateral vasculature of beagles with and without coronary occlusion. Circ Res 48: 523&#x2013;530, 1981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7460222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffer MG, Verdouw PD. Decreased incidence of ventricular fibrillation after an acute coronary artery ligation in exercised pigs. Basic Res Cardiol 78: 298&#x2013;309, 1983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6615402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheuer J, Stezoski SW. Effect of physical training on the mechanical and metabolic response of the rat heart to hypoxia. Circ Res 30: 418&#x2013;429, 1972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5013858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheuer J, Tipton CM. Cardiovascular adaptations to physical training. Annu Rev Physiol 39: 221&#x2013;251, 1977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">139843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler G, Hambrecht R, Schlierf G, Neibauer J, Hauer K, Neumann J, Hoberg E, Drinkmann A, Bacher F, Grunze M. Regular physical exercise and low-fat diet. Effects on progression of coronary artery disease. Circulation 86: 1&#x2013;11, 1992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1617762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz SM. Smooth muscle migration in atherosclerosis and restenosis. J Clin Invest 100: S87&#x2013;S89, 1997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9413408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz SM, deBlois D, O'Brien ER. The intima: soil for atherosclerosis and restenosis. Circ Res 77: 445&#x2013;465, 1995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7641318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada K, Kishimoto C, Okabe Ta Hattori M, Murayama T, Yokode M, Kita T. Exercise training reduces severity of atherosclerosis in apolipoprotein e knockout mice via nitric oxide. Circ J 71: 1147&#x2013;1151, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17587726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spear KL, Koerner JE, Terjung RL. Coronary blood flow in physically trained rats. Cardiovasc Res 12: 135&#x2013;143, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">647717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stehno-Bittel L, Laughlin MH, Sturek M. Exercise training alters Ca release from coronary smooth muscle sarcoplasmic reticulum. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 259: H643&#x2013;H647, 1990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2386234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stehno-Bittel L, Laughlin MH, Sturek M. Exercise training depletes sarcoplasmic reticulum calcium in coronary smooth muscle. J Appl Physiol 71: 1764&#x2013;1773, 1991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1761472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson JA, Feleki V, Rechnitzer P, Beaton JR. Effect of exercise on coronary tree size in the rat. Circ Res 15: 265&#x2013;269, 1964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14211808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone HL. Coronary flow, myocardial oxygen consumption, and exercise training in dogs. J Appl Physiol 49: 759&#x2013;768, 1980</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7429900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symons JD, Pitsillides KF, Longhurst JC. Chronic reduction of myocardial ischemia does not attenuate coronary collateral development in miniswine. Circulation 86: 660&#x2013;671, 1992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1638730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tepperman J, Pearlman D. Effects of exercise and anemia on coronary arteries of small animals as revealed by the corrosion-cast technique. Circ Res 9: 576&#x2013;584, 1961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13775935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DP. Effects of acute and chronic exercise on myocardial ultrastructure. Med Sci Sports Exerc 17: 546&#x2013;553, 1985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3906344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson MA, Henderson KK, Woodman CR, Turk JR, Rush JW, Price E, Laughlin MH. Exercise preserves endothelium-dependent relaxation in coronary arteries of hypercholesterolemic male pigs. J Appl Physiol 96: 1114&#x2013;1126, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14617527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD. Exercise for patients with coronary artery and/or coronary heart disease. In: Exercise and Sports Cardiology, edited by Thompson PD. New York: McGraw-Hill, 2001, chapt. 16, p. 354&#x2013;370</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD. Exercise prescription and proscription for patients with coronary artery disease. Circulation 112: 2354&#x2013;2363, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16216979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD, Buchner D, Pina IL, Balady GJ, Williams MA, Marcus BH, Berra K, Blair SN, Costa F, Franklin B, Fletcher GF, Gordon NF, Pate RR, Rodriguez BL, Yancey AK, Wenger NK. Exercise and physical activity in the prevention and treatment of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: a statement from the council on clinical cardiology (subcommittee on exercise, rehabilitation, and prevention) and the council on nutrition, physical activity, and metabolism (subcommittee on physical activity). Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 23: E42&#x2013;E49, 2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xf6;rner W. Trainingsversuche an Hunden. III. Histologische Beobachtungen und Herz- und Skeletmuskeln. Arbeitphysiologie 8: 359&#x2013;370, 1935</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomanek RJ. Effects of age and exercise on the extent of the myocardial capillary bed. Anat Rec 167: 55&#x2013;62, 1970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5447368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tune JD, Richmond KN, Gorman MW, Olsson RA, Feigl EO. Adenosine is not responsible for local metabolic control of coronary blood flow in dogs during exercise. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 278: H74&#x2013;H84, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10644586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk JR, Laughlin MH. Physical activity and atherosclerosis: which animal model?. Can J Appl Physiol 29: 657&#x2013;683, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15536667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unge G, Carlsson S, Ljungqvist A, Tornling G, Adolfsson J. The proliferative activity of myocardial capillary wall cells in variously aged swimming-exercised rats. Acta Pathol Microbiol Scand A 87: 15&#x2013;17, 1979</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">154282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Restorff W, Holtz J, Bassenge E. Exercise induced augmentation of myocardial oxygen extraction in spite of normal coronary dilatory capacity in dogs. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch 372: 181&#x2013;185, 1977</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">564040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachtlova M, Rakusan K, Poupa O. The coronary terminal vascular bed in the heart of the hare (Lepus europeus) and the rabbit (Oryctolagus domesticus). Physiol Bohemoslov 14: 328&#x2013;331, 1965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5836360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachtlova M, Rakusan K, Roth Z, Poupa O. The terminal vascular bed of the myocardium in the wild rat (Rattus norvegicus) and the laboratory rat (Rattus norvegicus lab.). Physiol Bohemoslov 16: 548&#x2013;554, 1967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4234105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wamhoff BR, Bowles DK, Dietz NJ, Hu Q, Sturek M.
Exercise training attenuates coronary smooth muscle phenotypic modulation and nuclear Ca<sup>2+</sup> signaling. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol
283: H2397&#x2013;H2410, 2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wolin MS, Hintze TH. Chronic exercise enhances endothelium-mediated dilation of epicardial coronary artery in conscious dogs. Circ Res 73: 829&#x2013;838, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8403254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White FC, Bloor CM, McKirnan MD, Carroll SM. Exercise training in swine promotes growth of arteriolar bed and capillary angiogenesis in heart. J Appl Physiol 85: 1160&#x2013;1168, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9729595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White FC, McKirnan MD, Breisch EA, Guth BD, Liu YM, Bloor CM. Adaptation of the left ventricle to exercise-induced hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol 62: 1097&#x2013;1110, 1987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2952629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams JK, Kaplan JR, Suparto IH, Fox JL, Manuck SB. Effects of exercise on cardiovascular outcomes in monkeys with risk factors for coronary heart disease. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 23: 864&#x2013;871, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12649090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams RS. Role of receptor mechanisms in the adaptive response to habitual exercise. Am J Cardiol 55: 68D&#x2013;73D, 1985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3993551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windecker S, Allemann Y, Billinger M, Pohl T, Hutter D, Orsucci T, Blaga L, Meier B, Seiler C. Effect of endurance training on coronary artery size and function in healthy men: an invasive followup study. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 282: H2216&#x2013;H2223, 2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12003831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodman CR, Muller JM, Laughlin MH, Price EM. Induction of nitric oxide synthase mRNA in coronary resistance arteries isolated from exercise-trained pigs. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 273: H2575&#x2013;H2579, 1997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9435589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodman CR, Turk JR, Rush JW, Laughlin MH. Exercise attenuates the effects of hypercholesterolemia on endothelium-dependent relaxation in female porcine coronary arteries. J Appl Physiol 96: 1105&#x2013;1113, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12959954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyatt HL, Mitchell JH. Influences of physical conditioning and deconditioning on coronary vasculature of dogs. J Appl Physiol 45: 619&#x2013;625, 1978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">101496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyatt HL, Mitchell JH. Influences of physical training on the heart of dogs. Circ Res 35: 883&#x2013;889, 1974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4430081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang AL, Jen CJ, Chen HI. Effects of high-cholesterol diet and parallel exercise training on the vascular function of rabbit aortas: a time course study. J Appl Physiol 95: 1194&#x2013;1200, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12754174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yipintsoi T, Rosenkrantz J, Codini MA, Scheuer J. Myocardial blood flow responses to acute hypoxia and volume loading in physically trained rats. Cardiovasc Res 14: 50&#x2013;57, 1980</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6153926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young CG, Knight CA, Vickers KC, Westbrook D, Madamanchi NR, Runge MS, Ischiropoulos H, Ballinger SW. Differential effects of exercise on aortic mitochondria. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 288: H1683&#x2013;H1689, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15550530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandrino F, Molinari G, Smeraldi A, Odaglia G, Masperone MA, Sardanelli F. Magnetic resonance imaging of athlete's heart: myocardial mass, left ventricular function, and cross-sectional area of the coronary arteries. Eur Radiol 10: 319&#x2013;325, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10663764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanesco A, Antunes E. Effects of exercise training on the cardiovascular system: Pharmacological approaches. Pharmacol Ther 114: 307&#x2013;317, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17512599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>