<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37171517</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiological Responses and Adaptations to Lower Load Resistance Training: Implications for Health and Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>28</StartPage><MedlinePgn>28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">28</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-023-00578-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Resistance training is a method of enhancing strength, gait speed, mobility, and health. However, the external load required to induce these benefits is a contentious issue. A growing body of evidence suggests that when lower load resistance training [i.e., loads&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;50% of one-repetition maximum (1RM)] is completed within close proximity to concentric failure, it can serve as an effective alternative to traditional higher load (i.e., loads&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;70% of 1RM) training and in many cases can promote similar or even superior physiological adaptations. Such findings are important given that confidence with external loads and access to training facilities and equipment are commonly cited barriers to regular resistance training. Here, we review some of the mechanisms and physiological changes in response to lower load resistance training. We also consider the evidence for applying lower loads for those at risk of cardiovascular and metabolic diseases and those with reduced mobility. Finally, we provide practical recommendations, specifically that to maximize the benefits of lower load resistance training, high levels of effort and training in close proximity to concentric failure are required. Additionally, using lower loads 2-3 times per week with 3-4 sets per exercise, and loads no lower than 30% of 1RM can enhance muscle hypertrophy and strength adaptations. Consequently, implementing lower load resistance training can be a beneficial and viable resistance training method for a wide range of fitness- and health-related goals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weakley</LastName><ForeName>Jonathon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7892-4885</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, 211.1.26, Brisbane, QLD, Australia. Jonathon.weakley@acu.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia. Jonathon.weakley@acu.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carnegie Applied Rugby Research (CARR) Centre, Carnegie School of Sport, Leeds Beckett University, Leeds, UK. Jonathon.weakley@acu.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ljungberg</LastName><ForeName>Johanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Queensland Diamantina Institute, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halson</LastName><ForeName>Shona L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Behavioural and Health Sciences, Australian Catholic University, 211.1.26, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Performance, Recovery, Injury and New Technologies (SPRINT) Research Centre, Australian Catholic University, Brisbane, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Stuart M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, L8S 4K1, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise prescription</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>JW, JL, SLH, and SMP declare they have no competing interests. BJS serves on the scientific advisory board for Tonal Corporation, a manufacturer of fitness equipment.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37171517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10182225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00578-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-023-00578-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ratamess N, Alvar BA, Evetouch T, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Andrews RJ, West DW, Little JP, Cochran AJ, Hector AJ, et al. Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub-fractional synthetic responses in men. J Phys. 2012;590(2):351&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22106173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devries MC, Breen L, Von Allmen M, Macdonald MJ, Moore DR, Offord EA, et al. Low-load resistance training during step-reduction attenuates declines in muscle mass and strength and enhances anabolic sensitivity in older men. Phys Rep. 2015;3(8):e12493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26265753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J App Physiol. 2012;113(1):71&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, Mazara N, Mcglory C, Quadrilatero J, et al. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol. 2016;121(1):129&#x2013;138. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00154.2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00154.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4967245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohl HW, Craig CL, Lambert EV, Inoue S, Alkandari JR, Leetongin G, et al. The pandemic of physical inactivity: global action for public health. The Lancet. 2012;380(9838):294&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(12)60898-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(12)60898-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes RE, Lubans DR, Karunamuni N, Kennedy S, Plotnikoff R. Factors associated with participation in resistance training: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(20):1466&#x2013;1472. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-096950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28404558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health DO. Australia's physical activity and sedentary behaviour guidelines for adults (18&#x2013;64 years) Canberra: Department of Health; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Recommended levels of physical activity for adults aged 18&#x2013;64 years. Geneva: World Health Organisation; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennie JA, Pedisic Z, Van Uffelen JGZ, Charity MJ, Harvey JT, Banting LK, et al. Pumping iron in australia: prevalence, trends and sociodemographic correlates of muscle strengthening activity participation from a national sample of 195,926 adults. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(4):e0153225. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0153225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0153225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4847788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27119145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Staples AW, Atherton PJ, Baker JM, Moore DR, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS ONE. 2010;5(8):e12033. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0012033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins NDM, Miramonti AA, Hill EC, Smith CM, Cochrane-Snyman KC, Housh TJ, et al. Greater neural adaptations following high- vs. low-load resistance training. Front Physiol. 2017;8:331. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2017.00331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5447067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28611677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C, Kim HJ, Morton RW, Harris R, Phillips SM, Jeong TS, et al. Resistance exercise&#x2013;induced changes in muscle phenotype are load dependent. Med Sci Sport Exerc. 2019;51(12):2578&#x2013;2585. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31306302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva-Batista C, Barros TS, Aihara AY, Brendon H, et al. Muscle failure promotes greater muscle hypertrophy in low-load but not in high-load resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2019 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs. volitional interruption at high-and low-intensities on muscle mass and strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(1):162&#x2013;169. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low-vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;2963. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Farias Zuniga A, Mohammad IYZ, Jones A, Mcglory C, et al. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. J Physiol. 2019;597(17):4601&#x2013;4613. doi: 10.1113/JP278056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP278056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson D, Gallagher P, Harber M, Hollon C, Trappe S. Mitogen-activated protein kinase (mapk) pathway activation: effects of age and acute exercise on human skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2003;547(3):977&#x2013;987. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2002.036673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2002.036673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2342728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Semmler JG, Enoka RM. Training adaptations in the behavior of human motor units. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101(6):1766&#x2013;1775. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00543.2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00543.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16794023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Ogborn D, Phillips SM. Motor unit recruitment cannot be inferred from surface emg amplitude and basic reporting standards must be adhered to. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(3):657&#x2013;658. doi: 10.1007/s00421-015-3314-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3314-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26705245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Longing for a longitudinal proxy: acutely measured surface emg amplitude is not a validated predictor of muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2022;52(2):193&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01619-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01619-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35006527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Triplett NT. Program design for resistance training. In: Haff GG, Triplett NT, editors. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2015. p. 457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Junior RM, Barreira J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Barroso R. Muscle hypertrophy and strength gains after resistance training with different volume-matched loads: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2022;47(4):357&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2021-0515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2021-0515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35015560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, Roschel H, Tavares LD, De Souza EO, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(6):772&#x2013;780. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2018.1450898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1450898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29564973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs High-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;3523. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm L, Reitelseder S, Pedersen TG, Doessing S, Petersen SG, Flyvbjerg A, et al. Changes in muscle size and mhc composition in response to resistance exercise with heavy and light loading intensity. J Appl Physiol. 2008;105(5):1454&#x2013;1461. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.90538.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.90538.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18787090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Wilson G, Carlyon B. Generality versus specificity: a comparison of dynamic and isometric measures of strength and speed-strength. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;68(4):350&#x2013;355. doi: 10.1007/BF00571456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00571456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8055895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Van Every DW, Plotkin DL. Loading recommendations for muscle strength, hypertrophy, and local endurance: a re-examination of the repetition continuum. Sports. 2021;9(2):32. doi: 10.3390/sports9020032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports9020032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7927075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33671664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netreba A, Popov D, Bravyy Y, Lyubaeva E, Terada M, Ohira T, et al. Responses of knee extensor muscles to leg press training of various types in human. Ross Fiziol Zh Im I M Sechenova. 2013;99(3):406&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23789443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinogradova OL, Popov DV, Netreba AI, Tsvirkun DV, Kurochkina NS, Bachinin AV, et al. Optimization of training: development of a new partial load mode of strength training. Fiziol Cheloveka. 2013;39(5):71&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25509874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Vigotsky AD, Grgic J, Haun C, Contreras B, Delcastillo K, et al. Do the anatomical and physiological properties of a muscle determine its adaptive response to different loading protocols? Physiol Rep. 2020;8(9):e14427. doi: 10.14814/phy2.14427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.14427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32342648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M, Goodpaster BH, Kritchevsky SB, Newman AB, Nevitt M, Rubin SM, et al. Muscle mass, muscle strength, and muscle fat infiltration as predictors of incident mobility limitations in well-functioning older persons. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2005;60(3):324&#x2013;333. doi: 10.1093/gerona/60.3.324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/60.3.324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M, Kritchevsky SB, Goodpaster BH, Newman AB, Nevitt M, Stamm E, et al. Leg muscle mass and composition in relation to lower extremity performance in men and women aged 70 to 79: the health, aging and body composition study. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50(5):897&#x2013;904. doi: 10.1046/j.1532-5415.2002.50217.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1532-5415.2002.50217.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcleod JC, Stokes T, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise training as a primary countermeasure to age-related chronic disease. Front Physiol. 2019;10:645. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2019.00645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Simonsick EM, Naydeck BL, Boudreau RM, Kritchevsky SB, Nevitt MC, et al. Association of long-distance corridor walk performance with mortality, cardiovascular disease, mobility limitation, and disability. J Am Med Assoc. 2006;295(17):2018&#x2013;2026. doi: 10.1001/jama.295.17.2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.295.17.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16670410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadczak AD, Makwana N, Luscombe-Marsh N, Visvanathan R, Schultz TJ. Effectiveness of exercise interventions on physical function in community-dwelling frail older people: an umbrella review of systematic reviews. JBI Database Syst Rev Implement Rep. 2018;16(3):752&#x2013;775. doi: 10.11124/JBISRIR-2017-003551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/JBISRIR-2017-003551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29521871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevett C, Moncion K, Phillips S, Richardson J, Tang A. The role of resistance training in mitigating risk for mobility disability in community-dwelling older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehab. 2022;103:2023&#x2013;2035. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2022.04.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2022.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35504310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vries NM, Van Ravensberg CD, Hobbelen JS, Olde Rikkert MG, Staal JB, Nijhuis-Van Der Sanden MW. Effects of physical exercise therapy on mobility, physical functioning, physical activity and quality of life in community-dwelling older adults with impaired mobility, physical disability and/or multi-morbidity: a meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev. 2012;11(1):136&#x2013;149. doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2011.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2011.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lustosa LP, Silva JP, Coelho FM, Pereira DS, Parentoni AN, Pereira LS. Impact of resistance exercise program on functional capacity and muscular strength of knee extensor in pre-frail community-dwelling older women: a randomized crossover trial. Rev Bras Fisioter. 2011;15(4):318&#x2013;324. doi: 10.1590/S1413-35552011000400010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1413-35552011000400010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21971726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiebaud D, Jacot E, Defronzo RA, Maeder E, Jequier E, Felber JP. The effect of graded doses of insulin on total glucose uptake, glucose oxidation, and glucose storage in man. Diabetes. 1982;31(11):957&#x2013;963. doi: 10.2337/diacare.31.11.957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.31.11.957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6757014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloszy JO. Exercise-induced increase in muscle insulin sensitivity. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99(1):338&#x2013;343. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00123.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00123.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16036907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon BA, Benson AC, Bird SR, Fraser SF. Resistance training improves metabolic health in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2009;83(2):157&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2008.11.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2008.11.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19135754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang P, Swardfager W, Fernandes D, Laredo S, Tomlinson G, Oh PI, et al. Finding the optimal volume and intensity of resistance training exercise for type 2 diabetes: the forte study, a randomized trial. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2017;130:98&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2017.05.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2017.05.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28601003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association AH. American heart association recommendations for physical activity in adults and kids. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamada M, Shiroma EJ, Buring JE, Miyachi M, Lee IM. Strength training and all-cause, cardiovascular disease, and cancer mortality in older women: a cohort study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2017;6(11):e007677. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.117.007677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.117.007677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5721806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29089346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macdougall JD, Tuxen D, Sale DG, Moroz JR, Sutton JR. Arterial blood pressure response to heavy resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1985;58(3):785&#x2013;790. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1985.58.3.785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1985.58.3.785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3980383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollings M, Mavros Y, Freeston J, Fiatarone SM. The effect of progressive resistance training on aerobic fitness and strength in adults with coronary heart disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2017;24(12):1242&#x2013;1259. doi: 10.1177/2047487317713329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2047487317713329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28578612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srikanthan P, Horwich TB, Tseng CH. Relation of muscle mass and fat mass to cardiovascular disease mortality. Am J Cardiol. 2016;117(8):1355&#x2013;1360. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2016.01.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2016.01.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26949037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Sui X, Lobelo F, Morrow JR, Jr, Jackson AW, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, et al. Association between muscular strength and mortality in men: prospective cohort study. BMJ. 2008;337(7661):a439. doi: 10.1136/bmj.a439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.a439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2453303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Wijndaele K, Lee DC, Sharp SJ, Wareham N, Brage S. Independent and joint associations of grip strength and adiposity with all-cause and cardiovascular disease mortality in 403,199 adults: the UK biobank study. Am J Clin Nutr. 2017;106(3):773&#x2013;782. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.117.156851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.117.156851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6101209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28793990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Smart NA. Exercise training for blood pressure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Heart Assoc. 2013;2(1):e004473. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.112.004473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.112.004473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3603230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23525435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lira FS, Yamashita AS, Uchida MC, Zanchi NE, Gualano B, Martins E, et al. Low and moderate, rather than high intensity strength exercise induces benefit regarding plasma lipid profile. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2010;2(1):1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1186/1758-5996-2-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-5996-2-31</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2888772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20492685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikholeslami Vatani D, Ahmadi S, Ahmadi Dehrashid K, Gharibi F. Changes in cardiovascular risk factors and inflammatory markers of young, healthy, men after six weeks of moderate or high intensity resistance training. J Sports Med Phys Fit. 2011;51(4):695&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22212275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ. Higher effort, rather than higher load, for resistance exercise-induced activation of muscle fibres. J Physiol. 2019;597(18):4691&#x2013;4692. doi: 10.1113/JP278627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP278627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31389011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. High-and low-load resistance training: interpretation and practical application of current research findings. Sports Med. 2017;47(3):393&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0602-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0602-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27480764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrow J, Steele J, Behm DG, Skivington M, Fisher JP. Lighter-load exercise produces greater acute-and prolonged-fatigue in exercised and non-exercised limbs. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2021;92(3):369&#x2013;379. doi: 10.1080/02701367.2020.1734521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2020.1734521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32401690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Andersen CH, Zebis MK, Mortensen OS, Andersen LL. Muscle activation strategies during strength training with heavy loading vs. repetitions to failure. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(7):1897&#x2013;1903. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318239c38e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318239c38e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21986694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Goldsmith JA, Helms ER, Trepeck C, Halle JL, Mendez KM, et al. Proximity to failure and total repetitions performed in a set influences accuracy of intraset repetitions in reserve-based rating of perceived exertion. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:S158&#x2013;S165. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Reardon G, Fitzgerald J, Drinkwater E. The effect of 5, 10, and 20 repetition maximums on the recovery of voluntary and evoked contractile properties. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16(2):209&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11991772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>