<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26272733</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-817X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiological reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of training volume and intensity on improvements in muscular strength and size in resistance-trained men.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e12472</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14814/phy2.12472</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This investigation compared the effect of high-volume (VOL) versus high-intensity (INT) resistance training on stimulating changes in muscle size and strength in resistance-trained men. Following a 2-week preparatory phase, participants were randomly assigned to either a high-volume (VOL; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;14, 4&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;10-12 repetitions with ~70% of one repetition maximum [1RM], 1-min rest intervals) or a high-intensity (INT; n&#xa0;=&#xa0;15, 4&#xa0;&#xd7;&#xa0;3-5 repetitions with ~90% of 1RM, 3-min rest intervals) training group for 8&#xa0;weeks. Pre- and posttraining assessments included lean tissue mass via dual energy x-ray absorptiometry, muscle cross-sectional area and thickness of the vastus lateralis (VL), rectus femoris (RF), pectoralis major, and triceps brachii muscles via ultrasound images, and 1RM strength in the back squat and bench press (BP) exercises. Blood samples were collected at baseline, immediately post, 30&#xa0;min post, and 60&#xa0;min postexercise at week 3 (WK3) and week 10 (WK10) to assess the serum testosterone, growth hormone (GH), insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF1), cortisol, and insulin concentrations. Compared to VOL, greater improvements (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) in lean arm mass (5.2&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;2.9% vs. 2.2&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;5.6%) and 1RM BP (14.8&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;9.7% vs. 6.9&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;9.0%) were observed for INT. Compared to INT, area under the curve analysis revealed greater (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) GH and cortisol responses for VOL at WK3 and cortisol only at WK10. Compared to WK3, the GH and cortisol responses were attenuated (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) for VOL at WK10, while the IGF1 response was reduced (P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) for INT. It appears that high-intensity resistance training stimulates greater improvements in some measures of strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men during a short-term training period.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2015 The Authors. Physiological Reports published by Wiley Periodicals, Inc. on behalf of the American Physiological Society and The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mangine</LastName><ForeName>Gerald T</ForeName><Initials>GT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Jay R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida jay.hoffman@ucf.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Adam M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Townsend</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wells</LastName><ForeName>Adam J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jajtner</LastName><ForeName>Adam R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beyer</LastName><ForeName>Kyle S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boone</LastName><ForeName>Carleigh H</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miramonti</LastName><ForeName>Amelia A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>LaMonica</LastName><ForeName>Michael B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukuda</LastName><ForeName>David H</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ratamess</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health &amp; Exercise Science, The College of New Jersey, Ewing, New Jersey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stout</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Exercise Physiology and Wellness, University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101607800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-817X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anabolic hormones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26272733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">3/8/e12472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML. Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2000;81:174&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10638374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle T, Earle R. Wathen M. Resistance training. In: Baechle T, Earle R, editors; Essentials of strength training and conditioning. IL: Human Kinetics, Champaign; 2008. pp. 381&#x2013;411. 3rd ed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Shipp JR, Jiang J, Gower BA, Hunter GR, Goodman A, et al. Mechanical load increases muscle IGF-I and androgen receptor mRNA concentrations in humans. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2001;280:E383&#x2013;E390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11171591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell G, Syrotuik D, Martin T, Burnham R. Quinney H. Effect of concurrent strength and endurance training on skeletal muscle properties and hormone concentrations in humans. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2000;81:418&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben M. Use of diagnostic ultrasound for assessing muscle size. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2002;16:103&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg H, Tedner B. Tesch P. Changes in lower limb muscle cross-sectional area and tissue fluid volume after transition from standing to supine. Acta Physiol. Scand. 1993;148:379&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8213193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, Woodhouse L, Casaburi R, Singh AB, Bhasin D, Berman N, et al. Testosterone dose-response relationships in healthy young men. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2001;281:E1172&#x2013;E1181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11701431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg JE. Docherty D. The effects of accentuated eccentric loading on strength, muscle hypertrophy, and neural adaptations in trained individuals. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2002;16:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength testing&#x2014;predicting a one-rep max from reps-to-fatigue. J. Phys. Educ. Recreat. Dance. 1993;64:88&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buresh R, Berg K. French J. The effect of resistive exercise rest interval on hormonal response, strength, and hypertrophy with training. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2009;23:62&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19077743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgomaster KA, Moore DR, Schofield LM, Phillips SM, Sale DG. Gibala MJ. Resistance training with vascular occlusion: metabolic adaptations in human muscle. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2003;35:1203&#x2013;1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12840643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o M, Radaelli R, Pinto RS, Baroni BM, et al. Echo intensity is associated with skeletal muscle power and cardiovascular performance in elderly men. Exp. Gerontol. 2012;47:473&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22525196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman DW, Newton M, McGuigan MR. Nosaka K. Comparison between old and young men for responses to fast velocity maximal lengthening contractions of the elbow flexors. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2008;104:531&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18584196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Lin K-Y, Chen H-L, Lin M-J. Nosaka K. Comparison in eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage among four limb muscles. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2011;111:211&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20852880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Nosaka K. Braun B. Muscle function after exercise-induced muscle damage and rapid adaptation. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 1992;24:512&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1569847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: L. Erlbaum Associates; 1988. pp. 284&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther B, Cronin J, Keogh J. Cook C. The salivary testosterone and cortisol response to three loading schemes. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2008;22:250&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley MA. Matt KS. Hormonal regulation of skeletal muscle hypertrophy in rats: the testosterone to cortisol ratio. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 1996;73:66&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8861671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Nagasawa M, Yanagisawa O, Kizuka T, Ishii N. Takamatsu K. Muscular adaptations to combinations of high-and low-intensity resistance exercises. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2004;18:730&#x2013;737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory SM, Spiering BA, Alemany JA, Tuckow AP, Rarick KR, Staab JS, et al. Exercise-induced insulin-like growth factor I system concentrations after training in women. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2013;45:420&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23034644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA. Chow C-M. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2013;27:1609&#x2013;1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22990567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K. Pakarinen A. Acute hormonal responses to two different fatiguing heavy-resistance protocols in male athletes. J. Appl. Physiol. 1993;74:882&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8458810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, Newton RU. Alen M. Basal concentrations and acute responses of serum hormones and strength development during heavy resistance training in middle-aged and elderly men and women. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 2000;55:B95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10737684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed M, Lange K, Andersen J, Schjerling P, Kjaer M, Harridge S, et al. The effect of recombinant human growth hormone and resistance training on IGF-I mRNA expression in the muscles of elderly men. J. Physiol. 2004;555:231&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1664832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14565994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasani-Ranjbar S, Far ES, Heshmat R, Rajabi H. Kosari H. Time course responses of serum GH, insulin, IGF-1, IGFBP1, and IGFBP3 concentrations after heavy resistance exercise in trained and untrained men. Endocrine. 2012;41:144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21983797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E, Somjen G. Carpenter DO. Functional significance of cell size in spinal motoneurons. J.&#xa0;Neurophysiol. 1965;28:560&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14328454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Merletti R, Stegeman D, Blok J, Rau G, et al. European recommendations for surface electromyography. The Netherlands: Roessingh Research and Development; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR. Norms for fitness, performance, and health. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics Pub Incorporated; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Klatt M, Faigenbaum AD, Ross RE, Tranchina NM, et al. Comparison between different off-season resistance training programs in Division III American college football players. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2009;23:11&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichinose Y, Kanehisa H, Ito M, Kawakami Y. Fukunaga T. Morphological and functional differences in the elbow extensor muscle between highly trained male and female athletes. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 1998;78:109&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9694308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iida K, Itoh E, Kim D-S, Del Rincon JP, Coschigano KT, Kopchick JJ, et al. Muscle mechano growth factor is preferentially induced by growth hormone in growth hormone-deficient lit/lit mice. J. Physiol. 2004;560:341&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1665252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15308683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi P, Viitasalo J, Rauramaa R. Vihko V. Effect of isometric strength training on mechanical, electrical, and metabolic aspects of muscle function. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 1978;40:45&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">569576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ. A series of studies-the physiological basis for strength training in American football: fact over philosophy. J. Strength Cond. Res. 1997;11:131&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ. Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med. 2005;35:339&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Marchitelli L, Gordon SE, Harman E, Dziados JE, Mello R, et al. Hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise protocols. J. Appl. Physiol. 1990;69:1442&#x2013;1450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2262468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess N, Fry AC, Triplett-Mcbride T, Koziris LP, Bauer JA, et al. Influence of resistance training volume and periodization on physiological and performance adaptations in collegiate women tennis players. Am. J. Sports Med. 2000;28:626&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11032216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx J, Ratamess N, Nindl B, Gotshalk L, Volek J. Dohi K. The effects of single-set vs. periodized multiple-set resistance training on muscular performance and hormonal concentrations in women. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2001;33:635&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11283441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Fleck SJ, Dickinson A. Kraemer WJ. Acute and chronic hormonal responses to resistance training designed to promote muscle hypertrophy. Can. J. Appl. Physiol. 1999;24:96&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCaulley GO, McBride JM, Cormie P, Hudson MB, Nuzzo JL, Quindry JC, et al. Acute hormonal and neuromuscular responses to hypertrophy, strength and power type resistance exercise. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2009;105:695&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19066934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, O&#x2019;Reilly CE, Phillips SM, Tarnopolsky MA. Parise G. Co-expression of IGF-1 family members with myogenic regulatory factors following acute damaging muscle-lengthening contractions in humans. J. Physiol. 2008;586:5549&#x2013;5560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18818249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Bellamy L, Parise G, Baker SK. Phillips SM. Muscular and systemic correlates of resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. PLoS One. 2013;8:e78636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3793973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24130904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller N, Jorgensen JO, Moller J, Orskov L, Ovesen P, Schmitz O, et al. Metabolic effects of growth hormone in humans. Metabolism. 1995;44:33&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7476309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T. Neuromuscular adaptations during the acquisition of muscle strength, power and motor tasks. J. Biomech. 1993;26:95&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8505356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T. deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am. J. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 1979;58:115&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">453338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nindl BC, Kraemer WJ, Marx JO, Arciero PJ, Dohi K, Kellogg MD, et al. Overnight responses of the circulating IGF-I system after acute, heavy-resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 2001;90:1319&#x2013;1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11247930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ, et al. American college of sports medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schakman O, Kalista S, Barbe C, Loumaye A. Thissen J. Glucocorticoid-induced skeletal muscle atrophy. Int. J. Biochem. Cell Biol. 2013;45:2163&#x2013;2172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23806868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Alvar BA. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J. Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:2909&#x2013;2918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24714538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder ET, Villanueva M, West DD. Phillips SM. Are acute post-resistance exercise increases in testosterone, growth hormone, and IGF-1 necessary to stimulate skeletal muscle anabolism and hypertrophy? Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2013;45:2044&#x2013;2051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24136137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab R, Johnson GO, Housh TJ, Kinder JE. Weir J. Acute effects of different intensities of weight lifting on serum testosterone. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 1993;25:1381&#x2013;1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8107546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering BA, Kraemer WJ, Anderson JM, Armstrong LE, Nindl BC, Volek JS, et al. Effects of elevated circulating hormones on resistance exercise-induced Akt signaling. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2008;40:1039&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18461003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyfault JP, Carper MJ, Richmond SR, Hulver MW. Potteiger JA. Effects of liquid carbohydrate ingestion on markers of anabolism following high-intensity resistance exercise. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2004;18:174&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Rasmussen BB, Miller SL, Wolf SE, Owens-Stovall SK, Petrini BE, et al. Timing of amino acid-carbohydrate ingestion alters anabolic response of muscle to resistance exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2001;281:E197&#x2013;E206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11440894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toigo M. Boutellier U. New fundamental resistance exercise determinants of molecular and cellular&#xa0;muscle adaptations. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2006;97:643&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhelder WP, Radomski MW. Goode RC. Growth hormone responses during intermittent weight lifting exercise in men. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 1984;53:31&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6542499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>deVries HA. &#x201c;Efficiency of electrical activity&#x201d; as a physiological measure of the functional state of muscle tissue. Am. J. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 1968;47:10&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5644315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir JP. Quantifying test-retest reliability using the intraclass correlation coefficient and the SEM. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2005;19:231&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW. Phillips SM. Associations of exercise-induced hormone profiles and gains in strength and hypertrophy in a large cohort after weight training. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2012;112:2693&#x2013;2702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3371329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22105707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Kujbida GW, Moore DR, Atherton P, Burd NA, Padzik JP, et al. Resistance exercise-induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J. Physiol. 2009;587:5239&#x2013;5247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19736298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Tang JE, Moore DR, Staples AW, Holwerda AM, et al. Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J. Appl. Physiol. 2010;108:60&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Grant EJ, Correia CE. Phillips SM. Hypertrophy with unilateral resistance exercise occurs without increases in endogenous anabolic hormone concentration. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2006;98:546&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16972050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>