<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38595233</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of Split Versus Full-Body Resistance Training on Strength and Muscle Growth: A Systematic Review With Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1330</StartPage><EndPage>1340</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1330-1340</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004774</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ramos-Campo, DJ, Benito-Peinado, PJ, Caravaca, LA, Rojo-Tirado, MA, and Rubio-Arias, J&#xc1;. Efficacy of split versus full-body resistance training on strength and muscle growth: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 38(7): 1330-1340, 2024-No previous study has systematically compared the effect of 2 resistance training routines commonly used to increase muscle mass and strength (i.e., split [Sp] and full-body [FB] routines). Our objective was to conduct a systematic review and meta-analysis following PRISMA guidelines to compare the effects on strength gains and muscle growth in healthy adults. 14 studies (392 subjects) that compared Sp and FB routines in terms of strength adaptations and muscle growth were included. Regarding the effects of the Sp or FB routine on both bench press and lower limbs strength, the magnitude of the change produced by both routines was similar (bench press: mean difference [MD] = 1.19; [-1.28, 3.65]; p = 0.34; k = 14; lower limb: MD = 2.47; [-2.11, 7.05]; p = 0.29; k = 14). Concerning the effect of the Sp vs. FB routine on muscle growth, similar effects were observed after both routines in the cross-sectional area of the elbow extensors (MD = 0.30; [-2.65, 3.24]; p = 0.84; k = 4), elbow flexors (MD = 0.17; [-2.54, 2.88]; p = 0.91; k = 5), vastus lateralis (MD = -0.08; [-1.82, 1.66]; p = 0.93; k = 5), or lean body mass (MD = -0.07; [-1.59, 1.44]; p = 0.92; k = 6). In conclusion, the present systematic review and meta-analysis provides solid evidence that the use of Sp or FB routines within a resistance training program does not significantly impact either strength gains or muscle hypertrophy when volume is equated. Consequently, individuals are free to confidently select a resistance training routine based on their personal preferences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramos-Campo</LastName><ForeName>Domingo J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LFE Research Group, Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Science (INEF), Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benito-Peinado</LastName><ForeName>Pedro J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LFE Research Group, Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Science (INEF), Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andreu-Caravaca</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Physiology Department, Faculty of Health Sciences, UCAM Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica San Antonio de Murcia, Murcia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Facultad de Deporte. UCAM Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de Murcia, Murcia, Spain; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rojo-Tirado</LastName><ForeName>Miguel A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LFE Research Group, Department of Health and Human Performance, Faculty of Physical Activity and Sport Science (INEF), Universidad Polit&#xe9;cnica de Madrid, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubio-Arias</LastName><ForeName>Jacobo &#xc1;</ForeName><Initials>J&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Research Center, Department of Education, Faculty of Educational Sciences, University of Almer&#xed;a, Almer&#xed;a, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035002" MajorTopicYN="N">Lower Extremity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024510" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Development</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38595233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202407000-00020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Gindan YY, Hankey CR, Leslie W, Govan L, Lean MEJ. Predicting muscle mass from anthropometry using magnetic resonance imaging as reference: A systematic review. Nutr Rev 72: 113&#x2013;126, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Nigro F, Malagoli Lanzoni I, et al. A comparison between total body and split routine resistance training programs in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 35: 1520&#x2013;1526, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito PJ, Cupeiro R, Ramos-Campo DJ, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias J. A systematic review with meta-analysis of the effect of resistance training on whole-body muscle growth in healthy adult males. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 1285, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodie D, Moscrip V, Hutcheon R. Body composition measurement: A review of hydrodensitometry, anthropometry, and impedance methods. Nutrition 14: 296&#x2013;310, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder AW, Chilibeck PD, Webber CE, Sale DG. Comparison of whole and split weight training routines in young women. Can J Appl Physiol 19: 185&#x2013;199, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Junior RM, Barreira J, et al. Muscle hypertrophy and strength gains after resistance training with different volume-matched loads: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Appl Physiol Nutr Metabol 47: 357&#x2013;368, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther BT, Heke T, Keogh J. The effects of two equal-volume training protocols upon strength, body composition and salivary hormones in male rugby union players. Biol Sport 33: 111&#x2013;116, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, et al. Frequency: The overlooked resistance training variable for inducing muscle hypertrophy? Sports Med 47: 799&#x2013;805, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evangelista AL, Braz TV, La Scala Teixeira CV, et al. Split or full-body workout routine: Which is best to increase muscle strength and hypertrophy? Einstein (Sao Paulo). 2021;19:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco CMC, Carneiro MAS, de Sousa JFR, Gomes GK, Orsatti FL. Influence of high- and low-frequency resistance training on lean body mass and muscle strength gains in untrained men. J Strength Cond Res 35: 2089&#x2013;2094, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC, Schilling BK, Staron RS, et al. Muscle fiber characteristics and performance correlates of male Olympic-style weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res 17: 746&#x2013;754, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes GK, Franco CM, Nunes PRP, Orsatti FL. High-frequency resistance training is not more effective than low-frequency resistance training in increasing muscle mass and strength in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33(Suppl 1): S130&#x2013;S139, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez PP, Zabala EL, Brahim MB. Split versus full-body strength training workouts in untrained people. A randomised study. Arch Med Deporte 37:78&#x2013;83, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, et al. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 1207&#x2013;1220, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1609&#x2013;1617, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstrom AD, Marshall PW, Halaki M, Hackett DA. The effect of resistance training in women on dynamic strength and muscular hypertrophy: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med 50: 1075&#x2013;1093, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Smith R, Aulet M, et al. Appendicular skeletal muscle mass: Measurement by dual-photon absorptiometry. Am J Clin Nutr 52: 214&#x2013;218, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al.; Cochrane Bias Methods Group, Cochrane Statistical Methods Group. The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ (Online) 343: d5928, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen E, van den Tillaar R. Effects of training frequency on muscular strength for trained men under volume matched conditions. PeerJ 9: e10781, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Campbell BI, et al. Early-phase adaptations to a split-body, linear periodization resistance training program in college-aged and middle-aged men. J Strength Cond Res 23: 962&#x2013;971, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 674&#x2013;688, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, et al. Similar muscular adaptations in resistance training performed two versus three days per week. J Hum Kinet 68: 135&#x2013;143, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthie JR. Bioimpedance measurements of human body composition: Critical analysis and outlook. Expert Rev Med Devices 5: 239&#x2013;261, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Int J Surg. 88: 105906, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen H, Fimland MS, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. A randomized trial on the efficacy of split-body versus full-body resistance training in non-resistance trained women. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 14: 1&#x2013;9, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2585&#x2013;2601, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva DRP, et al. Effect of two- versus three-way split resistance training routines on body composition and muscular strength in bodybuilders: A pilot study. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 25: 559&#x2013;565, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2857&#x2013;2872, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger J. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci 37: 1286&#x2013;1295, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Effects of resistance training frequency on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 46: 1689&#x2013;1697, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1985&#x2013;1987, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, et al. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2909&#x2013;2918, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Tiryaki-Sonmez G. Influence of resistance training frequency on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1821&#x2013;1829, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas MH, Burns SP. Increasing lean mass and strength: A comparison of high frequency strength training to lower frequency strength training. Int J Exerc Sci 9: 159&#x2013;167, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trutschnigg B, Kilgour RD, Reinglas J, et al. Precision and reliability of strength (Jamar vs. Biodex handgrip) and body composition (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry vs. bioimpedance analysis) measurements in advanced cancer patients. Appl Physiol Nutr Metabol 33: 1232&#x2013;1239, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace BC, Dahabreh IJ, Trikalinos TA, et al. Closing the gap between methodologists and end-users: R as a computational back-end. J Stat Software. 2012;49:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward LC. Segmental bioelectrical impedance analysis: An update. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 15: 424&#x2013;429, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaroni RS, Brigatto FA, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. High resistance-training frequency enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33(Suppl 1): S140&#x2013;S151, 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>