<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">31809457</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Is Performing Repetitions to Failure Less Important Than Volume for Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1237</StartPage><EndPage>1248</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1237-1248</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003438</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lacerda, LT, Marra-Lopes, RO, Diniz, RCR, Lima, FV, Rodrigues, SA, Martins-Costa, HC, Bemben, MG, and Chagas, MH. Is performing repetitions to failure less important than volume for muscle hypertrophy and strength? J Strength Cond Res 34(5): 1237-1248, 2020-The aim of this study was to investigate the effects of muscle failure (MF) or not to MF (NMF) training on strength and muscle hypertrophy relative gains (average and individual data). Ten men untrained in resistance training participated in the study. Each leg was allocated in 1 of 2 unilateral training protocols (MF or NMF with equal volume) on knee extension exercise. Both protocols were performed with 3-4 sets, 3 minutes' rest, and 55-60% of one repetition maximum (1RM). Rectus femoris and vastus lateralis muscles cross-sectional area (CSA), maximal muscle strength (1RM and maximal voluntary isometric contraction), and muscular endurance (maximum number of repetition) were assessed before and after 14 weeks. In addition, neuromuscular activation by normalized root mean square of the electromyographic signal (EMGRMS) was measured in 2nd and 35th training sessions. The average results showed that both training protocols were similarly effective in inducing increases in strength and muscle hypertrophy gains. However, individual analysis data suggest that NMF protocol with equal volume may promote similar or even greater muscle hypertrophy (vastus lateralis) and muscular endurance performance when compared with MF protocol. Also, normalized EMGRMS responses analyzed during 2nd and 35th sessions were similar in MF and NMF protocols for rectus femoris and vastus lateralis muscles. In conclusion, MF and NMF protocol conducted with the same total repetition numbers produced similar maximal muscle strength performance and neuromuscular activation. Nevertheless, NMF training could be a more appropriate strategy to increase muscle hypertrophy (vastus lateralis) and muscular endurance performance in untrained individuals when compared with MF.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lacerda</LastName><ForeName>Lucas T</ForeName><Initials>LT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marra-Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo O</ForeName><Initials>RO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diniz</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo C R</ForeName><Initials>RCR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lima</LastName><ForeName>Fernando V</ForeName><Initials>FV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigues</LastName><ForeName>Sara A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martins-Costa</LastName><ForeName>Hugo C</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bemben</LastName><ForeName>Michael G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Exercise Science, University of Oklahoma, Norman, Oklahoma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chagas</LastName><ForeName>Mauro H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weight Training Laboratory, School of Physical Education, Physiotherapy and Occupational Therapy, Federal University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="N">Rest</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31809457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202005000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Antonio J. Nonuniform response of skeletal muscle to heavy resistance training: Can bodybuilders induce regional muscle hypertrophy? J Strength Cond Res 14: 102&#x2013;113, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck T. The importance of a priori sample size estimation in strength and conditioning research. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2323&#x2013;2337, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardi M, Solomonow M, Nguyen G, Smith A, Baratta R. Motor unit recruitment strategy changes with skill acquisition. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 74: 52&#x2013;59, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer KS, Fukuda DH, Boone CH, et al. Short-term unilateral resistance training results in cross education of strength without changes in muscle size, activation, or endocrine response. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1213&#x2013;1223, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolster DR, Crozier SJ, Kimball SR, Jefferson LS. AMP-activated protein kinase suppresses protein synthesis in rat skeletal muscle through down-regulated mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) signaling. J Biol Chem 277: 23977&#x2013;23980, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Andrews RJ, West DWD, et al. Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub-fractional synthetic responses in men. J Physiol 590: 351&#x2013;362, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Pinto RS, Lhullier FLR, et al. Physiological effects of concurrent training in elderly men. Int J Sports Med 31: 689&#x2013;697, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Barcelos C, N&#xf3;brega SR, et al. Individual muscle hypertrophy and strength responses to high vs. low resistance training frequencies. J Strength Cond Res 33: 897&#x2013;901, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva LXN, Teodoro JL, Menger E, et al. Repetitions to failure versus not to failure during concurrent training in healthy elderly men: A randomized clinical trial. Exp Gerontol 108: 18&#x2013;27, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of training leading to repetition failure on muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sport Med 46: 487&#x2013;502, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sport Med 48: 499&#x2013;505, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Blossom D, Steele J. A comparison of volume-equated knee extensions to failure, or not to failure, upon rating of perceived exertion and strength adaptations. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 41: 168&#x2013;174, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. Evidence based resistance training. Med Sport 17: 217&#x2013;235, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gearhart RE, Goss FL, Lagally KM, et al. Standardized scaling procedures for rating perceived exertion during resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res 15: 320&#x2013;325, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gie&#x3b2;sing J, Fisher J, Steele J, et al. The effects of low-volume resistance training with and without advanced techniques in trained subjects. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 56: 249&#x2013;258, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Am&#xe9;zqueta I, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Izal M, et al. Blood lactate and sEMG at different knee angles during fatiguing leg press exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1349&#x2013;1358, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Halaki M, Chow C-M. A novel scale to assess resistance-exercise effort. J Sports Sci 30: 1405&#x2013;1413, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardie DG. Sensing of energy and nutrients by AMP-activated protein kinase. Am J Clin Nutr 93: 891S&#x2013;896S, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 10: 361&#x2013;374, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Lambert NJ, Hill JP. Greater cross education following training with muscle lengthening than shortening. Med Sci Sports Exerc 29: 107&#x2013;112, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Gabarren M, Exp&#xf3;sito R, Garc&#xed;a-Pallar&#xe9;s J, et al. Concurrent endurance and strength training not to failure optimizes performance gains. Med Sci Sport Exerc 42: 1191&#x2013;1199, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Iba&#xf1;ez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, et al. Differential effects of strength training leading to failure versus not to failure on hormonal responses, strength, and muscle power gains. J Appl Physiol 100: 1647&#x2013;1656, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller JL, Housh TJ, Hill EC, et al. Neuromuscular responses of recreationally active women during a sustained, submaximal isometric leg extension muscle action at a constant perception of effort. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 2499&#x2013;2508, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W, Ratamess N. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med 35: 339&#x2013;361, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerda LT, Costa CG, Lima FV, et al. Longer concentric action increases muscle activation and neuromuscular fatigue responses in protocols equalized by repetition duration. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1629&#x2013;1639, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerda LT, Martins-Costa HC, Diniz RCR, et al. Variations in repetition duration and repetition numbers influence muscular activation and blood lactate response in protocols equalized by time under tension. J Strength Cond Res 30: 251&#x2013;258, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 772&#x2013;780, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Gonzalez AM, et al. The effect of training volume and intensity on improvements in muscular strength and size in resistance-trained men. Physiol Rep 3: e12472, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martorelli S, Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, et al. Strength training with repetitions to failure does not provide additional strength and muscle hypertrophy gains in young women. Eur J Transl Myol 27: 113&#x2013;120, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, et al. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol 121: 129&#x2013;138, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn J, Herbert RD, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral resistance training: A meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol 96: 1861&#x2013;1866, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach KA, Bagley JR. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy with concurrent exercise training: Contrary evidence for an interference effect. Sport Med 46: 1029&#x2013;1039, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura A, Sugita M, Kato K, et al. Hypoxia increases muscle hypertrophy induced by resistance training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 5: 497&#x2013;508, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs. volitional interruption at high- and low-intensities on muscle mass and strength. J Strength Cond Res 32: 162&#x2013;169, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noorkoiv M, Nosaka K, Blazevich AJ. Assessment of quadriceps muscle cross-sectional area by ultrasound extended-field-of-view imaging. Eur J Appl Physiol 109: 631&#x2013;639, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, Tibana R, Sousa E, et al. Strength and muscular adaptations following 6 weeks of rest-pause versus traditional multiple-sets resistance training in trained subjects. J Strength Cond Res 33(suppl 1): S113&#x2013;S121, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney K, Herbert R, Balnave R. Fatigue contributes to the strength train stimulus. Med Sci Sports Exerc 26: 1160&#x2013;1164, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakamoto A, Sinclair PJ. Effect of movement velocity on the relationship between training load and the number of repetitions of bench press. J Strength Cond Res 112: 1015&#x2013;1025, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Influence of exercise and training on motor unit activation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 15: 95&#x2013;151, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos WDND, Vieira CA, Bottaro M, et al. Resistance training performed to failure or not to failure results in similar total volume, but with different fatigue and discomfort levels. J Strength Cond Res, 2019. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med 43: 179&#x2013;194, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Does training to failure maximize muscle hypertrophy? Strength Cond J 41: 108&#x2013;113, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock MS, Beck TW, Defreitas JM. Effects of fatigue on motor unit firing rate versus recruitment threshold relationships. Muscle Nerve 45: 100&#x2013;109, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Andersen CH, et al. Muscle activation strategies during strength training with heavy loading vs. repetitions to failure. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1897&#x2013;1903, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Lehman GJ, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Interpreting signal amplitudes in surface electromyography studies in sport and rehabilitation sciences. Front Physiol 8: 1&#x2013;15, 2018.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>