<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36620189</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Varying Load Intensity on Skeletal Muscle Damage Between Two Isovolumic Resistance Exercise Bouts.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1212</StartPage><EndPage>1221</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1212-1221</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>There are limited data comparing the efficacy of resistance loads within the hypertrophy range for promoting muscular growth, particularly when similar training volumes are utilized. The purpose of this study was to determine if two similar volume-loads, utilizing different intensities, would produce dissimilar muscular damage and inflammation. Eleven resistance-trained, college-aged males participated in this study. After testing 1RM barbell squats, participants completed two similar volume-load barbell squat sessions at two different resistance loads (67% and 85% of 1RM) on two separate visits. Venous blood samples were collected at baseline and one hour after completion of each exercise session. Plasma was isolated and analyzed for myoglobin and C-reactive protein (CRP) expression via ELISA. Plasma myoglobin expression was significantly elevated above baseline (BASE) values only after the 85% of 1RM (HHL) session (p =0.031), though the 67% (LHL) trial (p = 0.054; &#x3b7;<sup>2</sup> = 0.647) was approaching significance (BASE: 1.42&#xb1;.12 ng/mL; LHL: 4.65&#xb1;1.13 ng/mL; HHL: 5.00&#xb1;1.01 ng/mL). No changes in plasma CRP were observed. Despite attempts to equate volumes between resistances, mean total volume-load was significantly higher during the 67% of 1RM trial than during the 85% trial. Resistance loads at 85% of 1RM inflict significantly increased muscle damage over baseline values, even when significantly less total volume was lifted during the 85% trial. Individuals looking to maximize strength and hypertrophy during general training or during rehabilitation may benefit from these findings when determining the appropriate training load.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Winchester</LastName><ForeName>Lee J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morris</LastName><ForeName>Cody E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Studies, University of Alabama-Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allen</LastName><ForeName>Patton</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Recreation &amp; Sport, Western Kentucky University, Bowling Green, KY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiczynski</LastName><ForeName>Teresa L</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Recreation &amp; Sport, Western Kentucky University, Bowling Green, KY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arnett</LastName><ForeName>Scott W</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Recreation &amp; Sport, Western Kentucky University, Bowling Green, KY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyons</LastName><ForeName>T Scott</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of North Alabama, Florence, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">volume-matched</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36620189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9799231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/HXMP5676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-15-4-1212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American college of sports medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizheh N, Jaafari M. The effect of a single bout circuit resistance exercise on homocysteine, hs-crp and fibrinogen in sedentary middle aged men. Iran J Basic Med Sci. 2011;14(6):568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3586852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23493183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, Ragg KE, Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Staron RS. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(1):50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Libardi CA, Vechin FC, Lixandrao ME, Jannig PR, Costa LA, Bacurau AV, Snijders T, Parise G. Resistance training-induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. J Physiol. 2016;594(18):5209&#x2013;5222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5023708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27219125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eftestol E, Egner IM, Lunde IG, Ellefsen S, Andersen T, Sjaland C, Gundersen K, Bruusgaard JC. Increased hypertrophic response with increased mechanical load in skeletal muscles receiving identical activity patterns. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2016;311(4):C616&#x2013;C629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27488660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink J, Kikuchi N, Nakazato K. Effects of rest intervals and training loads on metabolic stress and muscle hypertrophy. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2018;38(2):261&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28032435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. 4th edition. Human kinetics; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Osburn SC, Mumford PW, Roberson PA, Romero MA, Fox CD, Johnson CA, Parry HA, Kavazis AN. Muscle fiber hypertrophy in response to 6 weeks of high-volume resistance training in trained young men is largely attributed to sarcoplasmic hypertrophy. PLoS One. 2019;14(6):e0215267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31166954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasapis C, Thompson PD. The effects of physical activity on serum c-reactive protein and inflammatory markers: A systematic review. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;45(10):1563&#x2013;1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15893167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konopka AR, Harber MP. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy after aerobic exercise training. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2014;42(2):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4523889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24508740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, French DN. Resistance training for health and performance. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2002;1(3):165&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12831709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mair J. Tissue release of cardiac markers: from physiology to clinical applications. Chem Lab Med. 1999;37(11&#x2013;12):1077&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10726815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113(1):71&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical issues relating to scientific discovery in exercise science. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybo L, Girard O, Mohr M, Knez W, Voss S, Racinais S. Markers of muscle damage and performance recovery after exercise in the heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(5):860&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips T, Childs AC, Dreon DM, Phinney S, Leeuwenburgh C. A dietary supplement attenuates il-6 and crp after eccentric exercise in untrained males. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(12):2032&#x2013;2037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14652498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodenburg J, Bar P, De Boer R. Relations between muscle soreness and biochemical and functional outcomes of eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74(6):2976&#x2013;2983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8365997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayers SP, Clarkson PM. Short-term immobilization after eccentric exercise. Part ii: Creatine kinase and myoglobin. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(5):762&#x2013;768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12750585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2857&#x2013;2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron R, Malicky E, Leonardi M, Falkel J, Hagerman F, Dudley G. Muscle hypertrophy and fast fiber type conversions in heavy resistance-trained women. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1990;60(1):71&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2311599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steensberg A, van Hall G, Osada T, Sacchetti M, Saltin B, Pedersen BK. Production of interleukin-6 in contracting human skeletal muscles can account for the exercise-induced increase in plasma interleukin-6. J Physiol. 2000;529:237&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11080265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone WJ, Coulter SP. Strength/endurance effects from three resistance training protocols with women. J Strength Cond Res. 1994;8(4):231&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber CB, Vigotsky A, Nuckols G, Haun CT. Exercise-induced myofibrillar hypertrophy is a contributory cause of gains in muscle strength. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):993&#x2013;997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31016546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidball JG, Villalta SA. Regulatory interactions between muscle and the immune system during muscle regeneration. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2010;298(5):R1173&#x2013;R1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20219869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>