<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30789575</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of a Supplementary Periodized Complex Strength Training and Tapering Period on Postactivation Potentiation of Sport-Specific Explosive Performance in Adolescent National-Level Fencers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1662</StartPage><EndPage>1670</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1662-1670</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002967</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kontochristopoulos, N, Bogdanis, GC, Paradisis, G, and Tsolakis, C. Effect of a supplementary periodized complex strength training and tapering period on postactivation potentiation of sport-specific explosive performance in adolescent national-level fencers. J Strength Cond Res 35(6): 1662-1670, 2021-This study examined the effects of strength training and tapering on countermovement jump (CMJ), change of direction (COD), and step-lunge (SL) after a conditioning activity in adolescent fencers. Twenty fencers (age: 15.8 &#xb1; 1.2 years) were randomly assigned to experimental (EXP, n = 10) group and control (CON, n = 10) group. EXP and CON groups performed 8 weeks of fencing training (4 times per week), while EXP group performed a supplementary strength training program twice per week, including a hypertrophy (first 2 weeks) and a complex strength training period (6 weeks). A 14-day tapering period with reduced training volume was then applied in both groups. Conditioning activity consisted of 3 &#xd7; 3 seconds of maximal voluntary isometric contraction (MVIC; half-squat; knee angle = 90&#xb0;), followed by either CMJ or COD or SL performance measurements in 3 different testing sessions 24 hours apart. There was no performance enhancement in all tests for both EXP and CON groups, after the conditioning MVIC before training (p &gt; 0.05). After training, half-squat dynamic strength (1 repetition maximum [1RM]) was significantly increased only in the EXP group (from 74.8 &#xb1; 20.0 to 127.0 &#xb1; 28.9 kg, p = 0.001) and maintained after tapering. After tapering, baseline CMJ height was significantly increased only in the EXP group (from 27.2 &#xb1; 4.6 to 30.9 &#xb1; 3.8 cm, p = 0.003). Contrary to our hypothesis, the increase in 1RM and CMJ was not followed by a postactivation potentiation enhancement in all tests (p &gt; 0.05), possibly because of the relatively low strength and jumping performance of fencers. Thus, adolescent high-level fencers do not exhibit a performance increase after MVIC, and this was not modified by the supplementary strength training protocol used.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kontochristopoulos</LastName><ForeName>Nikolaos</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sports Science, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogdanis</LastName><ForeName>Gregory C</ForeName><Initials>GC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paradisis</LastName><ForeName>Giorgos</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsolakis</LastName><ForeName>Charilaos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202106000-00025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P. Training-induced changes in neural function. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 31: 61&#x2013;67, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW, Wathen D. Resistance Training. In: Baechle, TR, Earle, RW, eds. 3rd, ed. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2008 pp. 381&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batista MAB, Roschel H, Barroso R, Ugrinowitsch C, Tricoli V. Influence of strength training background on postactivation potentiation response. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2496&#x2013;2502, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop C, Turner AN, Cree J, Maloney S, Marshall J, Jarvis P. Postactivation potentiation and change of direction speed in elite academy rugby players. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1551&#x2013;1556, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis GC, Tsoukos A, Veligekas P, Tsolakis C, Terzis G. Effects of muscle action type with equal impulse of conditioning activity on postactivation potentiation. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2521&#x2013;2528, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosco C, Komi PV. Mechanical characteristics and fiber composition of human leg extensor muscles. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 41: 275&#x2013;284, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu LZF, Fry AC, Weiss LW, et al. Postactivation potentiation response in athletic and recreationally trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 17: 671&#x2013;677, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Chaouachi A, Driss T, et al. The effect of training at the same time of day and tapering period on the diurnal variation of short exercise performances. J Strength Cond Res 26: 697&#x2013;708, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Santos JF, Valenzuela TH, Franchini E. Can different conditioning activities and rest intervals affect the acute performance of taekwondo turning kick? J Strength Cond Res 29: 1640&#x2013;1647, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durnin JV, Rahaman MM. The assessment of the amount of fat in the human body from measurements of skinfold thickness. Br J Nutr 21: 681&#x2013;689, 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourgoulis V, Aggeloussis N, Kasimatis P, Mavromatis G, Garas A. Effect of a submaximal half-squats warm-up program on vertical jumping ability. J Strength Cond Res 17: 342&#x2013;344, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guilhem G, Giroux C, Couturier A, Chollet D, Rabita G. Mechanical and muscular coordination patterns during a high-level fencing assault. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 341&#x2013;350, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada T, Sale DG, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA. Interaction of fibre type, potentiation and fatigue in human knee extensor muscles. Acta Physiol Scand 178: 165&#x2013;173, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgson M, Docherty D, Robbins D. Post-activation potentiation: Underlying physiology and implications for motor performance. Sports Med 35: 585&#x2013;595, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingle L, Sleap M, Tolfrey K. The effect of a complex training and detraining programme on selected strength and power variables in early pubertal boys. J Sports Sci 24: 987&#x2013;997, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Iba&#xf1;ez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, et al. Detraining and tapering effects on hormonal responses and strength performance. J Strength Cond Res 21: 768&#x2013;775, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobal R, Loturco I, Barroso R, et al. Effects of different combinations of strength, power, and plyometric training on the physical performance of elite young soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1468&#x2013;1476, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loturco I, Nakamura FY, Kobal R, et al. Training for power and speed: Effects of increasing or decreasing jump squat velocity in elite young soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2771&#x2013;2779, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miarka B, Del Vecchio FB, Franchini E. Acute effects and postactivation potentiation in the Special Judo Fitness Test. J Strength Cond Res 25: 427&#x2013;431, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negra Y, Chaabene H, Hammami M, et al. Agility in young athletes. J Strength Cond Res 31: 727&#x2013;735, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Gomez J, Olmedillas H, Delgado-Guerra S, et al. Effects of weight lifting training combined with plyometric exercises on physical fitness, body composition, and knee extension velocity during kicking in football. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 33: 501&#x2013;510, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyne DB, Mujika I, Reilly T. Peaking for optimal performance: Research limitations and future directions. J Sports Sci 27: 195&#x2013;202, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rassier DE, Macintosh BR. Coexistence of potentiation and fatigue in skeletal muscle. Braz J Med Biol Res 33: 499&#x2013;508, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redondo JC, Alonso CJ, Sedano S, de Benito AM. Effects of a 12-week strength training program on experimented fencers' movement time. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3375&#x2013;3384, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rixon KP, Lamont HS, Bemben MG. Influence of type of muscle contraction, gender, and lifting experience on postactivation potentiation performance. J Strength Cond Res 21: 500&#x2013;505, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roi GS, Bianchedi D. The science of fencing: Implications for performance and injury prevention. Sports Med 38: 465&#x2013;481, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Postactivation potentiation: Role in human performance. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 30: 138&#x2013;143, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott DJ, Ditroilo M, Marshall PA. Complex training: The effect of exercise selection and training status on postactivation potentiation in rugby league players. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2694&#x2013;2703, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz LB, de Villarreal ES, Haff GG. The temporal profile of postactivation potentiation is related to strength level. J Strength Cond Res 28: 706&#x2013;715, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiteri T, Newton RU, Binetti M, et al. Mechanical determinants of faster change of direction and agility performance in female basketball athletes. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2205&#x2013;2214, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stasinaki A-N, Gloumis G, Spengos K, et al. Muscle strength, power, and morphologic adaptations after 6 Weeks of compound vs. complex training in healthy men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2559&#x2013;2569, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talpey SW, Young WB, Saunders N. The acute effects of conventional, complex, and contrast protocols on lower-body power. J Strength Cond Res 28: 361&#x2013;366, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas L, Mujika I, Busso T. A model study of optimal training reduction during pre-event taper in elite swimmers. J Sports Sci 26: 643&#x2013;652, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Bishop D. Factors modulating post-activation potentiation and its effect on performance of subsequent explosive activities. Sports Med 39: 147&#x2013;166, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsimachidis C, Patikas D, Galazoulas C, Bassa E, Kotzamanidis C. The post-activation potentiation effect on sprint performance after combined resistance/sprint training in junior basketball players. J Sports Sci 31: 1117&#x2013;1124, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsolakis C, Bogdanis GC, Nikolaou A, Zacharogiannis E. Influence of type of muscle contraction and gender on postactivation potentiation of upper and lower limb explosive performance in elite fencers. J Sport Sci Med 10: 577&#x2013;583, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsolakis C, Douvis A, Tsigganos G, Zacharogiannis E, Smirniotou A. Acute effects of stretching on flexibility, power and sport specific performance in fencers. J Hum Kinet 26: 105&#x2013;114, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoukos A, Bogdanis GC, Terzis G, Veligekas P. Acute improvement of vertical jump performance after isometric squats depends on knee angle and vertical jumping ability. J Strength Cond Res 30: 2250&#x2013;2257, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner A, Miller S, Stewart P, et al. Strength and conditioning for fencing. Strength Cond J 35: 1&#x2013;9, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AN, Marshall G, Phillips J, et al. Physical characteristics underpinning repetitive lunging in fencing. J Strength Cond Res 30: 3134&#x2013;3139, 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>