<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38689583</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>91</Volume><Issue>Spec Issue</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Importance of Recovery in Resistance Training Microcycle Construction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>205</StartPage><EndPage>223</EndPage><MedlinePgn>205-223</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/jhk/186659</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Systemic resistance training aims to enhance performance by balancing stress, fatigue and recovery. While fatigue is expected, insufficient recovery may temporarily impair performance. The aim of this review was to examine evidence regarding manipulation of resistance training variables on subsequent effects on recovery and performance. PubMed, Medline, SPORTDiscus, Scopus and CINAHL were searched. Only studies that investigated recovery between resistance training sessions were selected, with a total of 24 articles included for review. Training to failure may lengthen recovery times, potentially impairing performance; however, it may be suitable if implemented strategically ensuring adequate recovery between sessions of similar exercises or muscle groups. Higher volumes may increase recovery demands, especially when paired with training to failure, however, with wide variation in individual responses, it is suggested to start with lower volume, monitor recovery, and gradually increase training volume if appropriate. Exercises emphasising the lower body, multi-joint movements, greater muscle recruitment, eccentric contractions, and/or the lengthened position may require longer recovery times. Adjusting volume and frequency of these exercises can affect recovery demands depending on the goals and training logistics. Daily undulating programming may maximise performance on priority sessions while maintaining purposeful and productive easy days. For example, active recovery in the form of training opposing muscle groups, light aerobic cardio, or low-volume power-type training may improve recovery and potentially elicit a post activation potentiation priming effect compared to passive recovery. However, it is possible that training cessation may be adequate for allowing sufficient recovery prior to sessions of importance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Academy of Physical Education in Katowice.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sousa</LastName><ForeName>Colby A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-3798-3065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zourdos</LastName><ForeName>Michael C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3265-7683</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science and Health Promotion, Muscle Physiology Laboratory, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Storey</LastName><ForeName>Adam G</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1522-9302</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helms</LastName><ForeName>Eric R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4849-9336</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Performance Research Institute New Zealand (SPRINZ), Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Science and Health Promotion, Muscle Physiology Laboratory, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38689583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11057610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/jhk/186659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">186659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abaidia, A. E., Delecroix, B., Leduc, C., Lamblin, J., McCall, A., Baquet, G., and Dupont, G. (2017). Effects of a Strength Training Session After an Exercise Inducing Muscle Damage on Recovery Kinetics. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 31(1), 115&#x2013;125. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27227793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, V., Paulsen, G., Stien, N., Baarholm, M., Seynnes, O., and Saeterbakken, A. H. (2021). Resistance Training With Different Velocity Loss Thresholds Induce Similar Changes in Strengh and Hypertrophy. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 38(3), e135&#x2013;e142. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000004067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000004067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34100789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman, M. M., Petrella, J. K., Kim, J. S., Mayhew, D. L., and Cross, J. M. (2007). Cluster analysis tests the importance of myogenic gene expression during myofiber hypertrophy in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 102(6), 2232&#x2013;2239. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00024.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00024.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17395765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett, A. (2006). Using recovery modalities between training sessions in elite athletes: does it help? Sports Medicine, 36(9), 781&#x2013;796. 10.2165/00007256-200636090-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636090-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartholomew, J. B., Stults-Kolehmainen, M. A., Elrod, C. C., and Todd, J. S. (2008). Strength gains after resistance training: the effect of stressful, negative life events. Journal of Strength and Conditoning Research, 22(4), 1215&#x2013;1221. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318173d0bf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318173d0bf</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei, S., Sadres, E., Church, D. D., Arroyo, E., Gordon, J. A., III, Varanoske, A. N., . . . Hoffman, J. R. (2017). Comparison of the recovery response from high-intensity and high-volume resistance exercise in trained men. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 117(7), 1287&#x2013;1298. 10.1007/s00421-017-3598-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3598-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28447186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei, S., Totti, V., Griggio, F., Malerba, C., Ciacci, S., Semprini, G., and Di Michele, R. (2019). Upper-Body Resistance Exercise Reduces Time to Recover After a High-Volume Bench Press Protocol in Resistance-Trained Men. Journal of Strength and Conditoning Research, 35(Suppl 1), S180&#x2013;S187. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002960</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei, S., Zaniboni, F., Verzieri, N., and Hoffman, J. R. (2023). New Perspectives in Resistance Training Periodization: Mixed Session vs. Block Periodized Programs in Trained Men. Journal of Strength and Conditoning Research, 37(3), 537&#x2013;545. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000004465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000004465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36727999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle, E., Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez, C., Alix-Fages, C., and Santos-Concejero, J. (2022). A Systematic Review of The Effects of Different Resistance Training Volumes on Muscle Hypertrophy. Journal of Human Kinetics, 81, 199&#x2013;210. 10.2478/hukin-2022-0017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2022-0017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8884877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35291645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck, K. L., Thomson, J. S., Swift, R. J., and von Hurst, P. R. (2015). Role of nutrition in performance enhancement and postexercise recovery. Open Access Journal of Sports Medicine, 6, 259&#x2013;267. 10.2147/oajsm.S33605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/oajsm.S33605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belcher, D. J., Sousa, C. A., Carzoli, J. P., Johnson, T. K., Helms, E., Visavadiya, N. P., . . . Zourdos, M. C. (2019). Time Course of Recovery is Similar for the Back Squat, Bench Press, and Deadlift in Well-Trained Males. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism, 44(10), 1033&#x2013;1042. 10.1139/apnm-2019-0004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2019-0004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30779596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird, S. P. (2013). Sleep, Recovery, and Athletic Performance: A Brief Review and Recommendations. Strength and Conditioning Journal (Lippincott Williams and Wilkins), 35(5), 43&#x2013;47. 10.1519/ssc.0b013e3182a62e2f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0b013e3182a62e2f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop, P. A., Jones, E., and Woods, A. K. (2008). Recovery from training: A brief review. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research (Lippincott Williams and Wilkins), 22(3), 1015&#x2013;1024. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816eb518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816eb518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, S. J., Child, R. B., Day, S. H., and Donnelly, A. E. (1997). Exercise-induced skeletal muscle damage and adaptation following repeated bouts of eccentric muscle contractions. Journal of Sports Science, 15(2), 215&#x2013;222. 10.1080/026404197367498</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404197367498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9258852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burt, D. G., and Twist, C. (2011). The effects of exercise-induced muscle damage on cycling time-trial performance. Journal of Strength and Conditoning Research, 25(8), 2185&#x2013;2192. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e86148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e86148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21572353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho, L., Junior, R., Barreira, J., Schoenfeld, B., Orazem, J., and Barroso, R. (2022). Muscle hypertrophy and strength gains after resistance training with different volume matched loads: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Applied Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism, 47(4), 357&#x2013;368. 10.1139/apnm-2021-0515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2021-0515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35015560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung, K., Hume, P., and Maxwell, L. (2003). Delayed onset muscle soreness : treatment strategies and performance factors. Sports Medicine, 33(2), 145&#x2013;164. 10.2165/00007256-200333020-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200333020-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson, P. M., Nosaka, K., and Braun, B. (1992). Muscle function after exercise-induced muscle damage and rapid adaptation. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 24(5), 512&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1569847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson, P. M., and Sayers, S. P. (1999). Etiology of Exercise-Induced Muscle Damage. Canadian Journal of Applied Physiology, 24(3), 234&#x2013;248. 10.1139/h99-020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h99-020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10364418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke, D. M., Haischer, M. H., Carzoli, J. P., Bazyler, C. D., Johnson, T. K., Varieur, R., . . . Zourdos, M. C. (2019). Body Mass and Femur Length Are Inversely Related to Repetitions Performed in the Back Squat in Well-Trained Lifters. Journal of Strength and Conditoning Research, 33(3), 890&#x2013;895. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30640306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currier, B. S., McLeod, J. C., Banfield, L., Beyene, J., Welton, N. J., D'Souza, A. C., . . . Phillips, S. M. (2023). Resistance training prescription for muscle strength and hypertrophy in healthy adults: a systematic review and Bayesian network meta-analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 57(18), 1211&#x2013;1220. 10.1136/bjsports-2023-106807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37414459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbert, M., Haff, G. G., Arent, S. M., Ripley, N., McMahon, J. J., Evans, M., and Comfort, P. (2021). Effects of Variations in Resistance Training Frequency on Strength Development in Well-Trained Populations and Implications for In-Season Athlete Training: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Sports Medicine, 51(9), 1967&#x2013;1982. 10.1007/s40279-021-01460-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01460-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas, F., Barcelos, C., N&#xf3;brega, S. R., Ugrinowitsch, C., Lixandr&#xe3;o, M. E., Santos, L., . . . Libardi, C. A. (2019). Individual Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength Responses to High vs. Low Resistance Training Frequencies. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 33(4), 897&#x2013;901. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000002864</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30289872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dourado, M. A. A., Vieira, D. C. L., Boullosa, D., and Bottaro, M. (2023). Different time course recovery of muscle edema within the quadriceps femoris and functional performance after single-vs multi-joint exercises. Biology of Sport, 40(3), 767&#x2013;774. 10.5114/biolsport.2023.119984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.119984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10286608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37398959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuy, O., Douzi, W., Theurot, D., Bosquet, L., and Dugue, B. (2018). An Evidence-Based Approach for Choosing Post-exercise Recovery Techniques to Reduce Markers of Muscle Damage, Soreness, Fatigue, and Inflammation: A Systematic Review With Meta-Analysis. Frontiers of Physiology, 9, 403. 10.3389/fphys.2018.00403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.00403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29755363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans, J. W. (2019). Periodized Resistance Training for Enhancing Skeletal Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength: A Mini-Review. Frontiers of Physiology, 10, 13. 10.3389/fphys.2019.00013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6351492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30728780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck, S. J. (1999). Periodized Strength Training: A Critical Review. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 13(1), 82&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe, J. J., Broatch, J. R., Trewin, A. J., Hanson, E. D., Argus, C. K., Garnham, A. P., . . . Petersen, A. C. (2019). Cold water immersion attenuates anabolic signalling and skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy, but not strength gain, following whole-body resistance training. Journal of Applied Physiology, 127(5), 1403&#x2013;1418. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00127.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00127.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31513450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Ramos, A., Torrej&#xf3;n, A., Feriche, B., Morales-Artacho, A. J., P&#xe9;rez-Castilla, A., Padial, P., and Haff, G. G. (2018). Prediction of the Maximum Number of Repetitions and Repetitions in Reserve From Barbell Velocity. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 13(3), 353&#x2013;359. 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28771050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo, J. J., Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell, D., S&#xe1;nchez-Medina, L., Ribas, J., L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez, C., Mora-Custodio, R., . . . Pareja-Blanco, F. (2016). Short-term Recovery Following Resistance Exercise Leading or not to Failure. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 37(4), 295&#x2013;304. 10.1055/s-0035-1564254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0035-1564254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic, J., Schoenfeld, B. J., Davies, T. B., Lazinica, B., Krieger, J. W., and Pedisic, Z. (2018). Effect of Resistance Training Frequency on Gains in Muscular Strength: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Medicine, 48(5), 1207&#x2013;1220. 10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic, J., Schoenfeld, B. J., and Latella, C. (2019). Resistance training frequency and skeletal muscle hypertrophy: A review of available evidence. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 22(3), 361&#x2013;370. 10.1016/j.jsams.2018.09.223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2018.09.223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30236847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic, J., Schoenfeld, B. J., Orazem, J., and Sabol, F. (2022). Effects of resistance training performed to repetition failure or non-failure on muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Sport and Health Science, 11(2), 202&#x2013;211. 10.1016/j.jshs.2021.01.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2021.01.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff, G. G. (2000). Roundtable Discussion: Machines Versus Free Weights. Strength and Conditioning Journal, 22(6), 18&#x2013;30. https://journals.lww.com/nsca-scj/fulltext/2000/12000/roundtable_discussion__machines_versus_free.4.aspx; accessed on 22 February 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haischer, M. H., Carzoli, J. P., Cooke, D. M., Pelland, J. C., Remmert, J. F., and Zourdos, M. C. (2023). Predicting Total Back Squat Repetitions from Repetition Velocity and Velocity Loss. Journal of Human Kinetics, 87, 167&#x2013;178. 10.5114/jhk/162021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/jhk/162021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10203840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37229411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammert, W., Kataoka, R., Vasenina, E., Ibrahim, A., and Buckner, S. (2021). Is &#x201c;periodization programming&#x201d; periodization or programming? Journal of Trainology, 10, 20&#x2013;24. 10.17338/trainology.10.2_20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17338/trainology.10.2_20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held, S., Hecksteden, A., Meyer, T., and Donath, L. (2021). Improved Strength and Recovery After Velocity-Based Training: A Randomized Controlled Trial. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 16(8), 1185&#x2013;1193. 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33547265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helland, C., Midttun, M., Saeland, F., Haugvad, L., Schafer Olstad, D., Solberg, P. A., and Paulsen, G. (2020). A strength-oriented exercise session required more recovery time than a power-oriented exercise session with equal work. PeerJ, 8, e10044. 10.7717/peerj.10044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.10044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7532781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33062443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms, E. R., Kwan, K., Sousa, C. A., Cronin, J. B., Storey, A. G., and Zourdos, M. C. (2020). Methods for Regulating and Monitoring Resistance Training. Journal of Human Kinetics, 74, 23&#x2013;42. 10.2478/hukin-2020-0011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickmott, L. M., Chilibeck, P. D., Shaw, K. A., and Butcher, S. J. (2022). The Effect of Load and Volume Autoregulation on Muscular Strength and Hypertrophy: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Medicine Open, 8(1), 9. 10.1186/s40798-021-00404-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-021-00404-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8762534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35038063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornsby, W. G., Fry, A. C., Haff, G. G., and Stone, M. H. (2020). Addressing the Confusion within Periodization Research. Journal of Functional Morphology and Kinesiology, 5(3), 68. 10.3390/jfmk5030068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk5030068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson, G., Brandon, R., and Hunter, A. M. (2016). The Response to and Recovery From Maximum-Strength and-Power Training in Elite Track and Field Athletes. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 11(3), 356&#x2013;362. 10.1123/ijspp.2015-0235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26308090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal, M. J., Gordish-Dressman, H., Thompson, P. D., Price, T. B., Hoffman, E. P., Angelopoulos, T. J., . . . Clarkson, P. M. (2005). Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 37(6), 964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judelson, D. A., Maresh, C. M., Farrell, M. J., Yamamoto, L. M., Armstrong, L. E., Kraemer, W. J., . . . Anderson, J. M. (2007). Effect of hydration state on strength, power, and resistance exercise performance. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 39(10), 1817&#x2013;1824. 10.1249/mss.0b013e3180de5f22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e3180de5f22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic, Castilla, A. P., Ramos, A. G., Van Hooren, B., McGuigan, M. R., and Helms, E. R. (2023a). The Acute and Chronic Effects of Implementing Velocity Loss Thresholds During Resistance Training: A Systematic Review, Meta-Analysis, and Critical Evaluation of the Literature. Sports Medicine, 53(1), 177&#x2013;214. 10.1007/s40279-022-01754-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01754-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36178597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic, Prnjak, K., McGuigan, M. R., and Helms, E. R. (2023b). One Velocity Loss Threshold Does Not Fit All: Consideration of Sex, Training Status, History, and Personality Traits When Monitoring and Controlling Fatigue During Resistance Training. Sports Medicine Open, 9(1), 80. 10.1186/s40798-023-00626-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00626-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10480128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37668949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotikangas, J., Walker, S., Toivonen, S., Peltonen, H., and Hakkinen, K. (2022). Acute Neuromuscular and Hormonal Responses to Power, Strength, and Hypertrophic Protocols and Training Background. Frontiers in Sports and Active Living, 4, 919228. 10.3389/fspor.2022.919228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.919228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9329926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35911374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, M. H., Siedler, M. R., Lamadrid, P., Ford, S., Smith, T., SanFilippo, G., . . . Campbell, B. I. (2022). Sex Differences May Exist for Performance Fatigue but Not Recovery After Single-Joint Upper-Body and Lower-Body Resistance Exercise. Journal of Strength and Conditoning Research, 36(6), 1498&#x2013;1505. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35333210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macarilla, C. T., Sautter, N. M., Robinson, Z. P., Juber, M. C., Hickmott, L. M., Cerminaro, R. M., . . . Zourdos, M. C. (2022). Accuracy of Predicting One-Repetition Maximum from Submaximal Velocity in The Barbell Back Squat and Bench Press. Journal of Human Kinetics, 82, 201&#x2013;212. 10.2478/hukin-2022-0046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2022-0046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mika, A., Mika, P., Fernhall, B., and Unnithan, V. B. (2007). Comparison of recovery strategies on muscle performance after fatiguing exercise. American Journal of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 86(6), 474&#x2013;481. 10.1097/PHM.0b013e31805b7c79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0b013e31805b7c79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17515687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moesgaard, L., Beck, M. M., Christiansen, L., Aagaard, P., and Lundbye-Jensen, J. (2022). Effects of Periodization on Strength and Muscle Hypertrophy in Volume-Equated Resistance Training Programs: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Sports Medicine, 52(7), 1647&#x2013;1666. 10.1007/s40279-021-01636-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01636-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35044672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro, R., P&#xe9;rez, C. E., Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez, R., de la Cruz-S&#xe1;nchez, E., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo, J. J., S&#xe1;nchez-Medina, L., and Pallar&#xe9;s, J. G. (2017). Time course of recovery following resistance training leading or not to failure. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 117(12), 2387&#x2013;2399. 10.1007/s00421-017-3725-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3725-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28965198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika, I. (2009). Tapering and Peaking for Optimal Performance. Human Kinetics. https://books.google.com/books?id=CbNxygAACAAJ</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosaka, K., and Newton, M. (2002). Concentric or eccentric training effect on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 34(1), 63&#x2013;69. 10.1097/00005768-200201000-00011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200201000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco, F., Alcazar, J., S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as, J., Cornejo-Daza, P. J., Piqueras-Sanchiz, F., Mora-Vela, R., &#x2026; Alegre, L. M. (2020). Velocity Loss as a Critical Variable Determining the Adaptations to Strength Training. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(8), 1752&#x2013;1762. 10.1249/mss.0000000000002295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000002295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32049887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco, F., Rodriguez Rosell, D., S&#xe1;nchez-Medina, L., Sanchis-Moysi, J., Dorado, C., Mora Custodio, R., &#x2026; Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo, J. (2016). Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports, 27(7), 724&#x2013;735. 10.1111/sms.12678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27038416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco, F., Villalba-Fern&#xe1;ndez, A., Cornejo-Daza, P. J., S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as, J., and Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo, J. J. (2019). Time Course of Recovery Following Resistance Exercise with Different Loading Magnitudes and Velocity Loss in the Set. Sports (Basel), 7(3), 59. 10.3390/sports7030059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7030059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30836680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake, J. M., Neubauer, O., Della Gatta, P. A., and Nosaka, K. (2017a). Muscle damage and inflammation during recovery from exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 122(3), 559&#x2013;570. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00971.2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00971.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28035017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake, J. M., Roberts, L. A., Figueiredo, V. C., Egner, I., Krog, S., Aas, S. N., . . . Raastad, T. (2017b). The effects of cold water immersion and active recovery on inflammation and cell stress responses in human skeletal muscle after resistance exercise. Journal of Physiology, 595(3), 695&#x2013;711. 10.1113/JP272881</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP272881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5285720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27704555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisk, S. S., and Stone, M. H. (2003). Periodization Strategies. Strength and Conditioning Journal, 25(6), 19&#x2013;37. https://journals.lww.com/nsca-scj/fulltext/2003/12000/periodization_strategies.5.aspx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritchard, H. J., Barnes, M. J., Stewart, R. J. C., Keogh, J. W. L., and McGuigan, M. R. (2018). Short-Term Training Cessation as a Method of Tapering to Improve Maximal Strength. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 32(2), 458&#x2013;465. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001803</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29369954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raastad, T., and Hallen, J. (2000). Recovery of skeletal muscle contractility after high-and moderate-intensity strength exercise. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 82(3), 206&#x2013;214. 10.1007/s004210050673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10929214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raeder, C., Wiewelhove, T., Simola, R. &#xc1;. D. P., Kellmann, M., Meyer, T., Pfeiffer, M., and Ferrauti, A. (2016). Assessment of Fatigue and Recovery in Male and Female Athletes After 6 Days of Intensified Strength Training. Journal of Strength and Conditoning Research, 30(12), 3412&#x2013;3427. http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=cmedm&amp;AN=27093538&amp;site=ehost-live</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27093538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston, G. W., Kilgore, L., Wyatt, F. B., and Baker, J. S. (2017). The Effect of Weekly Set Volume on Strength Gain: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Medicine, 47(12), 2585&#x2013;2601. 10.1007/s40279-017-0762-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0762-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28755103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston, G. W., Kilgore, L., Wyatt, F. B., Buchan, D., and Baker, J. S. (2018). Weekly Training Frequency Effects on Strength Gain: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Medicine Open, 4(1), 36. 10.1186/s40798-018-0149-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-018-0149-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6081873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo, M. C., Helms, E. R., Trexler, E. T., Hamilton, D. L., and Fyfe, J. J. (2023). Influence of Resistance Training Proximity-to-Failure on Skeletal Muscle Hypertrophy: A Systematic Review with Meta-analysis. Sports Medicine, 53(3), 649&#x2013;665. 10.1007/s40279-022-01784-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01784-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36334240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea, M. R., Ball, S. D., Phillips, W. T., and Burkett, L. N. (2002). A comparison of linear and daily undulating periodized programs with equated volume and intensity for strength. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 16(2), 250&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11991778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, L. A., Raastad, T., Markworth, J. F., Figueiredo, V. C., Egner, I. M., Shield, A., . . . Peake, J. M. (2015). Post-exercise cold water immersion attenuates acute anabolic signalling and long-term adaptations in muscle to strength training. Journal of Physiology, 593(18), 4285&#x2013;4301. 10.1113/JP270570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP270570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26174323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken, A. H., and Fimland, M. S. (2013). Muscle force output and electromyographic activity in squats with various unstable surfaces. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 27(1), 130&#x2013;136. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182541d43</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182541d43</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22450254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands, W., Stone, M., and Stone, M. (2007). Principles and Practice of Resistance Training. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 1995. 10.5040/9781492596875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5040/9781492596875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos, W. D. N. D., Vieira, C. A., Bottaro, M., Nunes, V. A., Ramirez-Campillo, R., Steele, J., Fisher, J. P., and Gentil, P. (2021). Resistance Training Performed to Failure or Not to Failure Results in Similar Total Volume, but With Different Fatigue and Discomfort Levels. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 35(5), 1372&#x2013;1379. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002915</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30615007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld, B., and Grgic, J. (2018). Evidence-Based Guidelines for Resistance Training Volume to Maximize Muscle Hypertrophy. Strength and Conditioning Journal, 40(4), 107&#x2013;112. 10.1519/ssc.0000000000000363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld, B. J., Contreras, B., Krieger, J., Grgic, J., Delcastillo, K., Belliard, R., and Alto, A. (2019). Resistance Training Volume Enhances Muscle Hypertrophy but Not Strength in Trained Men. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 51(1), 94&#x2013;103. 10.1249/mss.0000000000001764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0000000000001764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spierer, D. K., Goldsmith, R., Baran, D. A., Hryniewicz, K., and Katz, S. D. (2004). Effects of active vs. passive recovery on work performed during serial supramaximal exercise tests. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 25(2), 109&#x2013;114. 10.1055/s-2004-819954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2004-819954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14986193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis, S. K., Mujika, I., Zwetsloot, K. A., Gentles, J. A., Stone, M. H., and Bazyler, C. D. (2022). The Effects of 3 vs. 5 Days of Training Cessation on Maximal Strength. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 36(3), 633&#x2013;640. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis, S. K., Zwetsloot, K. A., Mujika, I., Stone, M. H., and Bazyler, C. D. (2021). Skeletal Muscle Adaptations and Performance Outcomes Following a Step and Exponential Taper in Strength Athletes. Frontiers in Physiology, 12, 735932. 10.3389/fphys.2021.735932</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.735932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8582352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34777004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoukos, A., Veligekas, P., Brown, L. E., Terzis, G., and Bogdanis, G. C. (2018). Delayed effects of a low-volume, power-type resistance exercise session on explosive performance. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research (Lippincott Williams and Wilkins), 32(3), 643&#x2013;650. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28291764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira, A. F., Umpierre, D., Teodoro, J. L., Lisboa, S. C., Baroni, B. M., Izquierdo, M., and Cadore, E. L. (2021). Effects of Resistance Training Performed to Failure or Not to Failure on Muscle Strength, Hypertrophy, and Power Output: A Systematic Review With Meta-Analysis. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 35(4), 1165&#x2013;1175. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000003936</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000003936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf, M., Patroklos, A.-K., James, F., Brad, S., and James, S. (2023). Partial Vs Full Range of Motion Resistance Training: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. International Journal of Strength and Conditioning, 3(1), 118&#x2013;139. 10.47206/ijsc.v3i1.182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47206/ijsc.v3i1.182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyland, T. P., Van Dorin, J. D., and Reyes, G. F. (2015). Postactivation Potentation Effects From Accommodating Resistance Combined With Heavy Back Squats on Short Sprint Performance. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 29(11), 3115&#x2013;3123. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000000991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000000991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25968229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarrouk, N., Rebai, H., Yahia, A., Souissi, N., Hug, F., and Dogui, M. (2011). Comparison of Recovery Strategies on Maximal Force-Generating Capacity and Electromyographic Activity Level of the Knee Extensor Muscles. Journal of Athletic Training (National Athletic Trainers' Association), 46(4), 386&#x2013;394. http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=s3h&amp;AN=65922781&amp;site=ehost-live</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3419150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos, M. C., Jo, E., Khamoui, A. V., Lee, S. R., Park, B. S., Ormsbee, M. J., &#x2026; Kim, J. S. (2016). Modified Daily Undulating Periodization Model Produces Greater Performance Than a Traditional Configuration in Powerlifters. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 30(3), 784&#x2013;791. 10.1519/jsc.0000000000001165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>