<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34351728</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does Varying Repetition Tempo in a Single-Joint Lower Body Exercise Augment Muscle Size and Strength in Resistance-Trained Men?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2162</StartPage><EndPage>2168</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2162-2168</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003953</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pearson, J, Wadhi, T, Barakat, C, Aube, D, Schoenfeld, BJ, Andersen, JC, Barroso, R, Ugrinowitsch, C, and De Souza, EO. Does varying repetition tempo in a single-joint lower body exercise augment muscle size and strength in resistance-trained men? J Strength Cond Res 36(8): 2162-2168, 2022-This study compared the effects of FAST and SLOW eccentric repetition tempo in a single exercise volume-matched intervention on muscle thickness (MT) and strength in resistance-trained men. Using a within-subject design, 13 subjects had each leg randomly assigned to SLOW (1-0-3) or FAST (1-0-1) repetition tempo. Subjects underwent an 8-week strength-training (ST) intervention performed twice weekly. Unilateral leg-extension one repetition-maximum (1RM) and anterior thigh MT at the proximal (MTP) and distal (MTD) portions were assessed via ultrasound imaging at baseline and after 8 weeks of RT. Rating of perceived exertion (RPE) assessments of the training sessions (i.e., 16 per leg) were averaged for further analysis. Both legs similarly increased MTP (estimated differences: FAST: 0.24 cm, 3.6%; SLOW: 0.20 cm, 3.1%). However, for MTD, analysis of covariance analysis showed a leg effect ( p = 0.02) in which absolute pre-to-post change was greater in FAST compared with SLOW (estimated differences: FAST 0.23 cm, 5.5%; SLOW: 0.13 cm, 2.2%). For 1RM, both legs similarly increased maximum strength (estimated differences: FAST: 9.1 kg, 17.0%; SLOW: 10.4 kg, 22.1%, p &#x2264; 0.0001). The SLOW group had a higher RPE than FAST (8.59 vs. 7.98, p = 0.002). Despite differences in RPE, our results indicate that both repetition tempos produced similar muscular adaptations. However, they also suggest that the FAST tempo may provide a small hypertrophic advantage at the distal quadriceps. From a practical standpoint, strength and conditioning professionals may implement a FAST tempo at least in one single-joint exercise during an 8-week training period to enhance regional hypertrophic adaptations in trained individuals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pearson</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wadhi</LastName><ForeName>Tanuj</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barakat</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aube</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andersen</LastName><ForeName>Jody C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barroso</LastName><ForeName>Renato</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, University of Campinas, Campinas, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugrinowitsch</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Adaptations to Strength Training, School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Souza</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo O</ForeName><Initials>EO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013848" MajorTopicYN="N">Thigh</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202208000-00014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aube D, Wadhi T, Rauch J, et al. Progressive resistance training volume: Effects on muscle thickness, mass, and strength adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 36: 600&#x2013;607, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 50&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on dynamic muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 1603&#x2013;1617, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza EO, Tricoli V, Rauch J, et al. Different patterns in muscular strength and hypertrophy adaptations in untrained individuals undergoing nonperiodized and periodized strength regimens. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1238&#x2013;1244, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Newton RU, Cormie P, Blazevich AJ. Inhomogeneous quadriceps femoris hypertrophy in response to strength and power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 2389&#x2013;2397, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan AD, Winchester JB, Foster C, McGuigan MR. Using session RPE to monitor different methods of resistance exercise. J Sports Sci Med 5: 289&#x2013;295, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2691&#x2013;2703, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing JP, Chilibeck PD. The effects of eccentric and concentric training at different velocities on muscle hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 578&#x2013;586, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finni T, Havu M, Sinha S, Usenius JP, Cheng S. Mechanical behavior of the quadriceps femoris muscle tendon unit during low-load contractions. J Appl Physiol 104: 1320&#x2013;1328, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Atherton PJ, Reeves ND, et al. Architectural, functional and molecular responses to concentric and eccentric loading in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol 210: 642&#x2013;654, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Longo S, Mallinson J, et al. Muscle thickness correlates to muscle cross&#x2010;sectional area in the assessment of strength training-induced hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports 28: 846&#x2013;853, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedmann B, Kinscherf R, Vorwald S, et al. Muscular adaptations to computer-guided strength training with eccentric overload. Acta Physiol Scand 182: 77&#x2013;88, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Davies TB, Orr R, Kuang K, Halaki M. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on muscle-specific hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 473&#x2013;482, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Klatt M, et al. Comparison between different off-season resistance training programs in Division III American college football players. J Strength Cond Res 23: 11&#x2013;19, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Barrier J, Beard D, et al. Greater initial adaptations to submaximal muscle lengthening than maximal shortening. J Appl Physiol 81: 1677&#x2013;1682, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Hill JP, Houmard JA, et al. Adaptive responses to muscle lengthening and shortening in humans. J Appl Physiol 80: 765&#x2013;772, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, et al. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 964&#x2013;972, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennis E, Verschueren SM, Bogaerts A, et al. Long-term impact of strength training on muscle strength characteristics in older adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 94: 2054&#x2013;2060, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Nindl BC, Ratamess NA, et al. Changes in muscle hypertrophy in women with periodized resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 697&#x2013;708, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Pinto RS, Radaelli R, et al. Benefits of resistance training in physically frail elderly: A systematic review. Aging Clin Exp Res 30: 889&#x2013;899, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Shan X, Otsuka S, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Neuromuscular adaptations to work-matched maximal eccentric versus concentric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 50: 1629&#x2013;1640, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzilger R, Bohm S, Mersmann F, Arampatzis A. Effects of lengthening velocity during eccentric training on vastus lateralis muscle hypertrophy. Front Physiol 10: 957, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mike JN, Cole N, Herrera C, et al. The effects of eccentric contraction duration on muscle strength, power production, vertical jump, and soreness. J Strength Cond Res 31: 773&#x2013;786, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholson G, Ispoglou T, Bissas A. The impact of repetition mechanics on the adaptations resulting from strength-, hypertrophy- and cluster-type resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1875&#x2013;1888, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L, Fluckey JD, Pozzo M, Tesch PA. Resistance training using eccentric overload induces early adaptations in skeletal muscle size. Eur J Appl Physiol 102: 271&#x2013;281, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira PEA, Motoyama YL, Esteves GJ, et al. Resistance training with slow speed of movement is better for hypertrophy and muscle strength gains than fast speed of movement. Int J Appl Exerc Physiol 5: 37&#x2013;43, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauch JT, Ugrinowitsch C, Barakat CI, et al. Auto-regulated exercise selection training regimen produces small increases in lean body mass and maximal strength adaptations in strength-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1133&#x2013;1140, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli MC, N&#xf3;brega SR, Santanielo N, et al. Muscle hypertrophy response is affected by previous resistance training volume in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1153&#x2013;1157, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2857&#x2013;2872, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low-vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Krieger JW. Effect of repetition duration during resistance training on muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 45: 577&#x2013;585, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Vigotsky AD, Franchi MV, Krieger JW. Hypertrophic effects of concentric vs. eccentric muscle actions: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 2599&#x2013;2608, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Wilson JM, Lowery RP, Krieger JW. Muscular adaptations in low- versus high-load resistance training: A meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 16: 1&#x2013;10, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepstone TN, Tang JE, Dallaire S, et al. Short-term high- vs. low-velocity isokinetic lengthening training results in greater hypertrophy of the elbow flexors in young men. J Appl Physiol 98: 1768&#x2013;1776, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata K, Takizawa K, Nosaka K, Mizuno M. Effects of prolonging eccentric phase duration in parallel back-squat training to momentary failure on muscle cross-sectional area, squat one repetition maximum, and performance tests in university soccer players. J Strength Cond Res 35: 668&#x2013;674, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins RG, Ruddy JD, Presland J, et al. Architectural changes of the biceps femoris long head after concentric or eccentric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 499&#x2013;508, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomeleri CM, Ribeiro AS, Nunes JP, et al. Influence of resistance training exercise order on muscle strength, hypertrophy, and anabolic hormones in older women: A randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res 34: 3103&#x2013;3109, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unlu G, Cevikol C, Melekoglu T. Comparison of the effects of eccentric, concentric, and eccentric-concentric isotonic resistance training at two velocities on strength and muscle hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 34: 337&#x2013;344, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawakami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy: Its relation to muscle activation in training session. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 2158&#x2013;2165, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Sugisaki N, et al. Association between regional differences in muscle activation in one session of resistance exercise and in muscle hypertrophy after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1569&#x2013;1576, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang LQ, Wang G, Nuber GW, Press JM, Koh JL. In vivo load sharing among the quadriceps components. J Orthop Res 21: 565&#x2013;571, 2003.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>