<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25413329</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-817X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiological reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance exercise increases active MMP and &#x3b2;1-integrin protein expression in skeletal muscle.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e12212</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14814/phy2.12212</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recent studies indicate that matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) and critical linkage proteins in the extracellular matrix (ECM) regulate skeletal muscle mass, although the effects of resistance training (RT) on protein expression and activity are unclear. Thus, the purpose of the present study was to investigate the effects of RT on MMP activity and expression of ECM-related proteins. Ten male Sprague-Dawley rats were randomly assigned to 1 bout (1B) or 18 bouts (18B) of electrical stimulation. The right gastrocnemius muscle was isometrically contracted via percutaneous electrical stimulation (five sets of 5 sec stimulation &#xd7; five contractions/set with 5 sec interval between contractions and 3 min rest between sets) once (1B) or every other day for 5 weeks (18B). The left leg served as a control. Activity of MMP-2 and MMP-9, determined via gelatin zymography, was increased (P &lt; 0.05) immediately after 1B. However, MMP activation was not evident following 18B. No changes in collagen IV, laminin &#x3b1;2, &#x3b1;7-integrin, or ILK protein expression were detected immediately following 1B or 18B. However, &#x3b2;1-integrin protein expression was significantly increased (P &lt; 0.05) with 18B. Our results suggest that resistance exercise activates MMPs during the initial phase of RT but this response is attenuated with continuation of RT.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2014 The Authors. Physiological Reports published by Wiley Periodicals, Inc. on behalf of the American Physiological Society and The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ogasawara</LastName><ForeName>Riki</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan Faculty of Sport and Health Science, Ritsumeikan University, Shiga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakazato</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Health and Sport Science, Nippon Sport Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Koji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Health Science, Ritsumeikan University, Shiga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boppart</LastName><ForeName>Marni D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Community Health, Beckman Institute for Advanced Science and Technology, University of Illinois, Urbana, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujita</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Health Science, Ritsumeikan University, Shiga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101607800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-817X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gelatinases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">integrin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mTOR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25413329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4255818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2/11/e12212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alameddine H. S. 2012. Matrix metalloproteinases in skeletal muscles: friends or foes? Neurobiol. Dis.; 48:508-518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22885251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boppart M. D., Burkin D. J., Kaufman S. J. 2006. Alpha7beta1&#x2010;integrin regulates mechanotransduction and prevents skeletal muscle injury. Am. J. Physiol. Cell Physiol.; 290:C1660-C1665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16421207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boppart M. D., Volker S. E., Alexander N., Burkin D. J., Kaufman S. J. 2008. Exercise promotes alpha7 integrin gene transcription and protection of skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol.; 295:R1623-R1630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2584868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18784336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmeli E., Moas M., Reznick A. Z., Coleman R. 2004. Matrix metalloproteinases and skeletal muscle: a brief review. Muscle Nerve; 29:191-197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14755482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmeli E., Moas M., Lennon S., Powers S. K. 2005. High intensity exercise increases expression of matrix metalloproteinases in fast skeletal muscle fibres. Exp. Physiol.; 90:613-619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15833756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahiya S., Bhatnagar S., Hindi S. M., Jiang C., Paul P. K., Kuang S. 2011. Elevated levels of active matrix metalloproteinase&#x2010;9 cause hypertrophy in skeletal muscle of normal and dystrophin&#x2010;deficient mdx mice. Hum. Mol. Genet.; 20:4345-4359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21846793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deus A. P., Bassi D., Simoes R. P., Oliveira C. R., Baldissera V., Marqueti Rde C. 2012. MMP(&#x2010;2) expression in skeletal muscle after strength training. Int. J. Sports Med.; 33:137-141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22095325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillies A. R., Lieber R. L. 2011. Structure and function of the skeletal muscle extracellular matrix. Muscle Nerve; 44:318-331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3177172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21949456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grounds M. D., Sorokin L., White J. 2005. Strength at the extracellular matrix&#x2010;muscle interface. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports; 15:381-391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16293150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X. Y., Wang W., Komulainen J., Koskinen S. O., Kovanen V., Vihko V. 1999. Increased mRNAs for procollagens and key regulating enzymes in rat skeletal muscle following downhill running. Pflugers Arch.; 437:857-864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10370063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeier K. M., Olesen J. L., Haddad F., Langberg H., Kjaer M., Baldwin K. M. 2007. Expression of collagen and related growth factors in rat tendon and skeletal muscle in response to specific contraction types. J. Physiol.; 582:1303-1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2075262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17540706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klossner S., Li R., Ruoss S., Durieux A. C., Fluck M. 2013. Quantitative changes in focal adhesion kinase and its inhibitor, FRNK, drive load&#x2010;dependent expression of costamere components. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol.; 305:R647-R657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23904105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koskinen S. O., Wang W., Ahtikoski A. M., Kjaer M., Han X. Y., Komulainen J. 2001. Acute exercise induced changes in rat skeletal muscle mRNAs and proteins regulating type IV collagen content. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol.; 280:R1292-R1300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11294746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koskinen S. O., Heinemeier K. M., Olesen J. L., Langberg H., Kjaer M. 2004. Physical exercise can influence local levels of matrix metalloproteinases and their inhibitors in tendon&#x2010;related connective tissue. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 96:861-864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14506093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kragstrup T. W., Kjaer M., Mackey A. L. 2011. Structural, biochemical, cellular, and functional changes in skeletal muscle extracellular matrix with aging. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports; 21:749-757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22092924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonoudakis D., Singh M., Mohajer R., Mohajer P., Fata J. E., Campbell K. P. 2010. Dystroglycan controls signaling of multiple hormones through modulation of STAT5 activity. J. Cell Sci.; 123:3683-3692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2964112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20940259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Milner D. J., Boppart M. D., Ross R. S., Kaufman S. J. 2012. Beta1d chain increases alpha7beta1 integrin and laminin and protects against sarcolemmal damage in mdx mice. Hum. Mol. Genet.; 21:1592-1603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3298282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22180459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall J. L., Chou E., Oh J., Kwok A., Burkin D. J., Crosbie&#x2010;Watson R. H. 2012. Dystrophin and utrophin expression require sarcospan: loss of alpha7 integrin exacerbates a newly discovered muscle phenotype in sarcospan&#x2010;null mice. Hum. Mol. Genet.; 21:4378-4393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3459462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22798625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew D. L., Kim J. S., Cross J. M., Ferrando A. A., Bamman M. M. 2009. Translational signaling responses preceding resistance training&#x2010;mediated myofiber hypertrophy in young and old humans. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 107:1655-1662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew D. L., Hornberger T. A., Lincoln H. C., Bamman M. M. 2011. Eukaryotic initiation factor 2B epsilon induces cap&#x2010;dependent translation and skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J. Physiol.; 589:3023-3037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3139084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21486778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehan R. S., Greybeck B. J., Emmons K., Byrnes W. C., Allen D. L. 2011. Matrix metalloproteinase&#x2010;9 deficiency results in decreased fiber cross&#x2010;sectional area and alters fiber type distribution in mouse hindlimb skeletal muscle. Cells Tissues Organs; 194:510-520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3238033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milkiewicz M., Haas T. L. 2005. Effect of mechanical stretch on HIF&#x2010;1{alpha} and MMP&#x2010;2 expression in capillaries isolated from overloaded skeletal muscles: laser capture microdissection study. Am. J. Physiol. Heart Circ. Physiol.; 289:H1315-H1320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15894575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milkiewicz M., Mohammadzadeh F., Ispanovic E., Gee E., Haas T. L. 2007. Static strain stimulates expression of matrix metalloproteinase&#x2010;2 and VEGF in microvascular endothelium via JNK&#x2010; and ERK&#x2010;dependent pathways. J. Cell. Biochem.; 100:750-761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17031856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizunoya W., Wakamatsu J., Tatsumi R., Ikeuchi Y. 2008. Protocol for high&#x2010;resolution separation of rodent myosin heavy chain isoforms in a mini&#x2010;gel electrophoresis system. Anal. Biochem.; 377:111-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18358820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader G. A., von Walden F., Liu C., Lindvall J., Gutmann L., Pistilli E. E. 2014. Resistance exercise training modulates acute gene expression during human skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 116:693-702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24458751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R., Kobayashi K., Tsutaki A., Lee K., Abe T., Fujita S. 2013a. mTOR signaling response to resistance exercise is altered by chronic resistance training and detraining in skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 114:934-940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23372143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R., Yasuda T., Ishii N., Abe T. 2013b. Comparison of muscle hypertrophy following 6&#x2010;month of continuous and periodic strength training. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol.; 113:975-985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramaswamy K. S., Palmer M. L., van der Meulen J. H., Renoux A., Kostrominova T. Y., Michele D. E. 2011. Lateral transmission of force is impaired in skeletal muscles of dystrophic mice and very old rats. J. Physiol.; 589:1195-1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21224224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rullman E., Rundqvist H., Wagsater D., Fischer H., Eriksson P., Sundberg C. J. 2007. A single bout of exercise activates matrix metalloproteinase in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 102:2346-2351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17255365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rullman E., Norrbom J., Stromberg A., Wagsater D., Rundqvist H., Haas T. 2009. Endurance exercise activates matrix metalloproteinases in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 106:804-812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence H. J., Dhillon A. S., James M., Winder S. J. 2004. Dystroglycan, a scaffold for the ERK&#x2010;MAP kinase cascade. EMBO Rep.; 5:484-489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1299052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron R. S., Kraemer W. J., Hikida R. S., Fry A. C., Murray J. D., Campos G. E. 1999. Fiber type composition of four hindlimb muscles of adult Fisher 344 rats. Histochem. Cell Biol.; 111:117-123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10090572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G., Spengos K., Mascher H., Georgiadis G., Manta P., Blomstrand E. 2010. The degree of p70 S6k and S6 phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle in response to resistance exercise depends on the training volume. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol.; 110:835-843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20617335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urso M. L., Scrimgeour A. G., Chen Y. W., Thompson P. D., Clarkson P. M. 2006. Analysis of human skeletal muscle after 48 h immobilization reveals alterations in mRNA and protein for extracellular matrix components. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 101:1136-1148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16763108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welinder C., Ekblad L. 2011. Coomassie staining as loading control in Western blot analysis. J. Proteome Res.; 10:1416-1419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21186791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y., Zhou Y., Jarrett H. W. 2009. Dystrophin glycoprotein complex&#x2010;associated Gbetagamma subunits activate phosphatidylinositol&#x2010;3&#x2010;kinase/Akt signaling in skeletal muscle in a laminin&#x2010;dependent manner. J. Cell. Physiol.; 219:402-414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2820875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19117013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou K., Meador B. M., Johnson B., Huntsman H. D., Mahmassani Z., Valero M. C. 2011. The alpha(7)beta(1)&#x2010;integrin increases muscle hypertrophy following multiple bouts of eccentric exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985); 111:1134-1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21817112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>