<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39932234</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Low-Load Blood Flow Restriction Training and High-Load Resistance Training on Quadriceps Strength, Dynamic Stability, and Functional Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>111</StartPage><EndPage>119</EndPage><MedlinePgn>111-119</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001330</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Blood flow restriction (BFR) is a method used to affix a pneumatic cuff to the uppermost part of a leg. Blood flow restriction is often combined with low load-blood flow restriction training (LL-BFRt) to enhance strength and promote muscle hypertrophy. Therefore, this research aimed to examine the effect of LL-BFRt, sham LL-BFRt, and high load-resistance training (HL-Rt) on quadriceps strength (QS), dynamic stability, and functional performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Single-blinded randomized trial method.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">A private physical therapy clinic in Bali, Indonesia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data were collected from 63 basketball and rugby players assigned to 3 intervention groups, namely, LL-BFRt, sham LL-BFRt, and HL-Rt, through block randomization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INDEPENDENT VARIABLES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Each participant received intervention consisting of 45-minute sessions twice per week for 8 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Quadriceps strength, star excursion balance test (SEBT), and single-leg hop test (SLHT) were evaluated in baseline, 4 weeks, and 8 weeks of the intervention period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In LL-BFRt and HL-Rt groups, QS, SEBT, and SLHT scores were significantly improved during 8-week intervention period, except in sham LL-BFRt group. Furthermore, there was a significant improvement in LL-BFRt ( QS: 9.2-33.5 Newton; SEBT: 1.2-11.1 cm; SLHT: 1.3-9.8 cm, P -values &lt; 0.05) and HL-Rt groups ( QS: 15.4-35.9 Newton; SEBT: 2.2-9.0 cm; SLHT: 4.5-15.8 cm, P &lt; 0.05) compared with sham LL-BFRt.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The improvements attained by participants using LL-BFRt and HL-Rt were comparable and capable of improving QS, SEBT, and SLHT more than sham LL-BFRt.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">NCT05951036.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adhitya</LastName><ForeName>I Putu Gde Surya</ForeName><Initials>IPGS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Medicine, Universitas Udayana, Denpasar, Bali, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aryana</LastName><ForeName>I Gusti Ngurah Wien</ForeName><Initials>IGNW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic and Traumatology, College of Medicine and Professor Ngoerah General Hospital, Universitas Udayana, Denpasar, Bali, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurniawati</LastName><ForeName>Ida</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Histology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universitas Warmadewa, Denpasar, Bali, Indonesia ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thanaya</LastName><ForeName>Sayu Aryantari Putri</ForeName><Initials>SAP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, College of Medicine, Universitas Udayana, Denpasar, Bali, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Utama</LastName><ForeName>Made Bang Redy</ForeName><Initials>MBR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Coaching, Faculty of Sport Science, Universitas Negeri Jakarta, East Jakarta, Jakarta, Indonesia .</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05951036</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>B/255.183/UN14.4.A/PT.01.03/2024&amp;2025</GrantID><Agency>Research and Community Service Institutions, Universitas Udayana, Bali, Indonesia</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Flow Restriction Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076604" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Functional Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001490" MajorTopicYN="N">Basketball</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="N">Football</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007214" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Indonesia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dynamic stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hop test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quadriceps strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39932234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-990000000-00289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Palmieri-Smith RM, Kreinbrink J, Ashton-Miller JA, et al. Quadriceps inhibition induced by an experimental knee joint effusion affects knee joint mechanics during a single-legged drop landing. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35:1269&#x2013;1275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Park G, Kuo L-T, et al. The effects of pain on quadriceps strength, joint proprioception and dynamic balance among women aged 65 to 75 years with knee osteoarthritis. BMC Geriatr. 2018;18:245&#x2013;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaviano NR, Saliba S. Relationship between lower-extremity strength and subjective function in individuals with patellofemoral pain. J Sport Rehabil. 2018;27:327&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welling W, Benjaminse A, Seil R, et al. Low rates of patients meeting return to sport criteria 9 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective longitudinal study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2018;26:3636&#x2013;3644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Snyder-Mackler L, Moksnes H, et al. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: the Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:804&#x2013;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hislop AC, Collins NJ, Tucker K, et al. Does adding hip exercises to quadriceps exercises result in superior outcomes in pain, function and quality of life for people with knee osteoarthritis? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:263&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiffler MR, Bell DR, Sanfilippo JL, et al. Star excursion balance test anterior asymmetry is associated with injury status in division I collegiate athletes. J Orthopa Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47:339&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan GF, Delahunt E, O'Sullivan E, et al. Star excursion balance test performance and application in elite junior rugby union players. Phys Ther Sport. 2014;15:249&#x2013;253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler RJ, Lehr ME, Fink ML, et al. Dynamic balance performance and noncontact lower extremity injury in college football players: an initial study. Sports Health. 2013;5:417&#x2013;422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman EN, Elshaar R, Milligan H, et al. Proximal, distal, and contralateral effects of blood flow restriction training on the lower extremities: a randomized controlled trial. Sports Health. 2019;11:149&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladlow P, Coppack RJ, Dharm-Datta S, et al. Low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction improves clinical outcomes in musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a single-blind randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JC, Domingos-Gomes JR, Freitas ED, et al. Physiological and perceptual responses to aerobic exercise with and without blood flow restriction. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:2479&#x2013;2485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domingos E, Polito MD. Blood pressure response between resistance exercise with and without blood flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Life Sci. 2018;209:122&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnsen T, Wernbom M, L&#xf8;vstad A, et al. Delayed myonuclear addition, myofiber hypertrophy, and increases in strength with high-frequency low-load blood flow restricted training to volitional failure. J Appl Physiol. 2019;126:578&#x2013;592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhitya I, Wibawa A, Aryana I, et al. Predictors of lower knee function improvement two years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Phys Sportsmed. 2024;52:239&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Queiros VS, Dantas M, Neto GR, et al. Application and side effects of blood flow restriction technique: a cross-sectional questionnaire survey of professionals. Medicine. 2021;100:e25794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz J, Stultz J, Burr JF. The efficacy of blood flow restricted exercise: a systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19:669&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts B. The 1RM (one Rep Max) calculator. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew JL, Johnson BD, LaMonte MJ, et al. Accuracy of prediction equations for determining one repetition maximum bench press in women before and after resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1570&#x2013;1577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evin HA, Mahoney SJ, Wagner M, et al. Limb occlusion pressure for blood flow restricted exercise: variability and relations with participant characteristics. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;47:78&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesnak J, Anderson D, Farmer B, et al. Validity of hand-held dynamometry in measuring quadriceps strength and rate of torque development. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2019;14:180&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan GF, Fullam K, Delahunt E, et al. A comparison between performance on selected directions of the star excursion balance test and the Y balance test. J Athl Train. 2012;47:366&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustsson J, Thomee R, Linden C, et al. Single leg hop testing following fatiguing exercise: reliability and biomechanical analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2006;16:111&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werasirirat P, Yimlamai T. Effect of supervised rehabilitation program combined with blood flow restriction training on muscle activation and postural control in athletes with chronic ankle instability: a randomized controlled trial. J Phys Educ Sport. 2022;22:1145&#x2013;1154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Kilduff LP, Beaven CM. Improving strength and power in trained athletes with 3 weeks of occlusion training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2014;9:166&#x2013;172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences New York. NY: Academic; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A, Drobni&#x10d; M, Mar&#x161; T, et al. Functional and molecular adaptations of quadriceps and hamstring muscles to blood flow restricted training in patients with ACL rupture. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31:1636&#x2013;1646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A, Strazar K. Frequent low load ischemic resistance exercise to failure enhances muscle oxygen delivery and endurance capacity. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:e231&#x2013;e241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Semmler JG, Enoka RM. Training adaptations in the behavior of human motor units. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:1766&#x2013;1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petschnig R, Baron R, Albrecht M. The relationship between isokinetic quadriceps strength test and hop tests for distance and one-legged vertical jump test following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1998;28:23&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon J, Lee J, Hong J, et al. Correlation of eccentric strength of the knee extensors and knee proprioception with dynamic postural control. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2022;35:309&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones MD, Wewege MA, Hackett DA, et al. Sex differences in adaptations in muscle strength and size following resistance training in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51:503&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkin KA, MacNeil RG, Dirain M, et al. Blood flow restriction enhances post&#x2013;resistance exercise angiogenic gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:2077&#x2013;2083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:406&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103:903&#x2013;910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:1199&#x2013;1209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fujita T, Miyagi Y, et al. Electromyographic responses of arm and chest muscle during bench press exercise with and without KAATSU. Int J KAATSU Train Res. 2006;2:15&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, et al. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:2097&#x2013;2106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Shan X, Otsuka S, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations to work-matched maximal eccentric versus concentric training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50:1629&#x2013;1640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J, Pearson S, Ross A, et al. Eccentric exercise: physiological characteristics and acute responses. Sports Med. 2017;47:663&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabido R, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Botella J, et al. Effects of adding a weekly eccentric-overload training session on strength and athletic performance in team-handball players. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17:530&#x2013;538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley LK, Lepley AS, Onate JA, et al. Eccentric exercise to enhance neuromuscular control. Sports Health. 2017;9:333&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt M, Hoppeler HH. Eccentric exercise: mechanisms and effects when used as training regime or training adjunct. J Appl Physiol. 2014;116:1446&#x2013;1454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Rosenblatt B, Haddad F, et al. Comparing the effectiveness of blood flow restriction and traditional heavy load resistance training in the post-surgery rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients: a UK national health service randomised controlled trial. Sports Med. 2019;49:1787&#x2013;1805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ. Are the hypertrophic adaptations to high and low-load resistance training muscle fiber type specific? Front Physiol. 2018;9:402.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>