<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41379532</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Comparison Between Synergist and Nonsynergist Resistance Training Schemes in Recreationally Trained Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>377</StartPage><EndPage>385</EndPage><MedlinePgn>377-385</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005336</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Gon&#xe7;alves Dias, W, Benvenutti Bueno de Camargo, J, Volpi Braz, T, Rodrigues Batista, D, Oenning Col, L, Prestes, J, and Ricardo Lopes, C. A comparison between synergist and nonsynergist resistance training schemes in recreationally trained men. J Strength Cond Res 40(4): 377-385, 2026-The aim of the present study was to compare the effects of 2 different resistance training (RT) schemes (synergist [SN] and nonsynergist [NS]) on both muscle strength and hypertrophy outcomes in recreationally trained subjects. The sample included 22 men that were assigned to 2 experimental groups: NS (push/pull and pull/push exercises, n = 12; age: 20.5 &#xb1; 2.3 years; total body mass: 75.1 &#xb1; 8.2 kg; height: 179.8 &#xb1; 7.8 cm; experience in RT: 2.4 &#xb1; 1.4 years) and SN (pull/pull and push/push exercises, n = 10; age: 22.1 &#xb1; 3.2 years; total body mass: 82.7 &#xb1; 11.7 kg; height: 175.0 &#xb1; 7.0 cm; experience in RT: 3.2 &#xb1; 1.5 years). Muscle thickness assessments of the triceps brachialis, biceps brachialis, pectoralis major, and one repetition-maximum testing in the bench press and lat pull-down exercises were performed before and after the 8-week intervention period. The total load lifted during each week also was calculated. Both groups displayed significant increases in muscle strength and thickness (NS and SN, p &lt; 0.05), with no significant difference observed between the groups for the dependent variables assessed (all p &gt; 0.05). Therefore, the present study suggests that individuals aiming to increase muscle strength and size may benefit from both training schemes, taking into account personal preferences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gon&#xe7;alves Dias</LastName><ForeName>Wellington</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Sciences, Methodist University of Piracicaba, Piracicaba, SP - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benvenutti Bueno de Camargo</LastName><ForeName>J&#xfa;lio</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Human Motricity, Federal University of Sao Carlos, Sao Carlos, SP - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Volpi Braz</LastName><ForeName>Tiago</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Americana, Department of Physical Education, Americana, SP - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodrigues Batista</LastName><ForeName>Danilo</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Phorte Faculty, Department of Resistance Training, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oenning Col</LastName><ForeName>Luan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine of Jundiai, Department of Molecular Biology, Jundiai, SP - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prestes</LastName><ForeName>Jonato</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Catholic University of Brazilia, Brazilia, DF - Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ricardo Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Catholic Pontifical University of Campinas, Campinas, SP - Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">split routine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper limb</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41379532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Balsalobre-Fernandez C, Alix-Fages C, Santos-Concejero J. A systematic review of the effects of different resistance training volumes on muscle hypertrophy. J Hum Kinet 81: 199&#x2013;210, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Braz TV, Zanini T, et al. Effect of resistance training frequency on neuromuscular performance and muscle morphology after 8 weeks in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2104&#x2013;2116, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Lima LEdM, Germano MD, et al. High resistance-training volume enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 36: 22&#x2013;30, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook MS, Wilkinson DJ, Mitchell WK, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy adaptations predominate in the early stages of resistance exercise training, matching deuterium oxide-derived measures of muscle protein synthesis and mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 signaling. FASEB J 29: 4485&#x2013;4496, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit M. The numbers will love you back in return-I promise. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 551&#x2013;554, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castanheira RPM, Ferreira-Junior JB, Celes RS, et al. Effects of synergist vs. non synergist split resistance training routines on acute neuromuscular performance in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3482&#x2013;3488, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, et al. Frequency: The overlooked resistance training variable for inducing muscle hypertrophy? Sports Med 47: 799&#x2013;805, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mouser JG, Mattocks KT, et al. The widespread misuse of effect sizes. J Sci Med Sport 20: 446&#x2013;450, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Simao R, Miranda F, et al. Rest interval between sets in strength training. Sports Med 39: 765&#x2013;777, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Longo S, Mallinson J, et al. Muscle thickness correlates to muscle cross-sectional area in the assessment of strength training-induced hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports 28: 846&#x2013;853, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genner KM, Weston M. A comparison of workload quantification methods in relation to physiological responses to resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2621&#x2013;2627, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes GK, Franco CM, Nunes PRP, Orsatti FL. High-frequency resistance training is not more effective than low-frequency resistance training in increasing muscle mass and strength in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33: S130&#x2013;S139, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1609&#x2013;1617, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, et al.; American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 34: 364&#x2013;380, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 674&#x2013;688, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, et al. Similar muscular adaptations in resistance training performed two versus three days per week. J Hum Kinet 68: 135&#x2013;143, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JW, Hong SU, Lee JH, Park SY. Estimation of validity of A-mode ultrasound for measurements of muscle thickness and muscle quality. Bioeng (Basel) 11: 1&#x2013;13, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehman GJ, Buchan DD, Lundy A, Myers N, Nalborczyk A. Variations in muscle activation levels during traditional latissimus dorsi weight training exercises: An experimental study. Dyn Med 3: 1&#x2013;5, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves RP, Vechin FC, Teixeira EL, et al. Effect of different training frequencies on maximal strength performance and muscle hypertrophy in trained individuals-a within-subject design. PLoS One 17: 1&#x2013;14, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Loftin M, Abe T. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci 4: 217&#x2013;220, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro G, de Aguiar RA, Penteado R, et al. A-mode ultrasound reliability in fat and muscle thickness measurement. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1610&#x2013;1617, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simao R, Farinatti PdTV, Polito MD, Maior AS, Fleck SJ. Influence of exercise order on the number of repetitions performed and perceived exertion during resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 19: 152&#x2013;156, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares S, Ferreira-Junior JB, Pereira MC, et al. Dissociated time course of muscle damage recovery between Single- and multi-joint exercises in highly resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2594&#x2013;2599, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Perco JG, Moore DR, Wilkinson SB, Phillips SM. Resistance training alters the response of fed state mixed muscle protein synthesis in young men. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 294: R172&#x2013;R178, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaroni RS, Brigatto FA, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. High resistance-training frequency enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33: S140&#x2013;S151, 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>