<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33344005</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2159-2896</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of sports physical therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Sports Phys Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>EFFECT OF BLOOD FLOW RESTRICTION TRAINING ON MUSCULAR PERFORMANCE, PAIN AND VASCULAR FUNCTION.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>892</StartPage><EndPage>900</EndPage><MedlinePgn>892-900</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.26603/ijspt20200892</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Blood flow restriction (BFR) training enhances muscular strength and hypertrophy in several populations including older adults and injured athletes. However, the efficacy of emerging BFR technologies on muscular adaptations, vascular health, and pain is unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this study was to examine muscular performance, pain and vascular function in response to eight weeks of BFR compared to traditional resistance training and a control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Randomized control trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty-one overtly healthy participants (age: 23&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4y, 65% female) underwent eight weeks of supervised high load resistance training (RES), low load resistance training with BFR (BFR) or no training (control, CON). RES and BFR (with pneumatic bands) performed seven upper and lower body exercises, two to three sessions per week at 60% and 30% of one-repetition maximum (1RM), respectively. Twenty-four hours post-exercise, general muscle soreness was assessed via a visual analog scale (VAS) and present pain intensity (PPI) of the McGill Pain Questionnaire. At baseline and after eight weeks, participants underwent one-repetition maximum (1RM), and flow-mediated dilation (FMD) testing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At baseline all groups exhibited similar muscle strength and endurance and vascular function. At the end of training, RES and BFR groups significantly increased muscle strength (1RM) to a similar magnitude as compared to the CON group (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001), but did not alter body composition. FMD significantly increased in RES and BFR groups compared to CON group (<i>p</i> = 0.006). VAS and PPI were similar between RES and BFR groups throughout the exercise sessions until VAS decreased in the BFR group after the last session compared to the RES group (<i>p</i> = 0.02).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Compared to RES, BFR resulted in similar muscular performance (strength and endurance) and vascular improvements at a lower exercise intensity, suggesting BFR is an effective alternative to high load resistance training. Further longitudinal studies may gain greater understanding regarding general muscle pain and soreness when using BFR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Therapy, Level 2.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 by the Sports Physical Therapy Section.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Early</LastName><ForeName>Kate S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Sciences, Columbus State University, Columbus, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rockhill</LastName><ForeName>Mallory</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Sciences, Columbus State University, Columbus, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bryan</LastName><ForeName>Alicia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Sciences, Columbus State University, Columbus, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tyo</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Sciences, Columbus State University, Columbus, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buuck</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Southern Rehab and Sports Medicine, Columbus, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGinty</LastName><ForeName>Josh</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Southern Rehab and Sports Medicine, Columbus, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Sports Phys Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101553140</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2159-2896</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Movement system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular function</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20200892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijspt20200892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hughes L Paton B Rosenblatt B Gissane C Patterson SD. Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(13):1003-1011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28259850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP Wilson JM Marin PJ Zourdos MC Bemben MG. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: a meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(5):1849-1859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21922259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteley R. Blood flow restriction training in rehabilitation: A useful adjunct or Lucy's latest trick? J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2019;49(5):294-298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine, Riebe D Ehrman JK Liguori G Magal M. ACSM's guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Tenth Edition ed. Philidelphia: Wolters Kluwer; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y Takazawa H Sato Y Takebayashi S Tanaka Y Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2000;88(6):2097-2106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T Fujita S Ogasawara R Sato Y Abe T. Effects of low-intensity bench press training with restricted arm muscle blood flow on chest muscle hypertrophy: A pilot study. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2010;30(5):338-343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ Hussain SR. A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2015;45(2):187-200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korakakis V Whiteley R Epameinontidis K. Blood flow restriction induces hypoalgesia in recreationally active adult male anterior knee pain patients allowing therapeutic exercise loading. Phys Ther Sport. 2018;32:235-243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29879638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y Nakamura Y Aruga S Onda T Miyazaki S Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(1):61-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L Patterson SD Haddad F, et al. Examination of the comfort and pain experienced with blood flow restriction training during post-surgery rehabilitation of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients: A UK National Health Service trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;39:90-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korakakis V Whiteley R Giakas G. Low load resistance training with blood flow restriction decreases anterior knee pain more than resistance training alone: A pilot randomised controlled trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2018;34:121-128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30268966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles L Webster KE McClelland J Cook JL. Quadriceps strengthening with and without blood flow restriction in the treatment of patellofemoral pain: A double-blind randomised trial. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(23):1688-1694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28500081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles LV Tebbutt SJ Carlsten C Koehle MS. The effect of low and high-intensity cycling in diesel exhaust on flow-mediated dilation, circulating NOx, endothelin-1 and blood pressure. PLoS One. 2018;13(2):e0192419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5821322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29466393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryk FF Dos Reis AC Fingerhut D, et al. Exercises with partial vascular occlusion in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2016;24(5):1580-1586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26971109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi M Okita K. Blood flow restricted exercise and vascular function. Int J Vasc Med. 2012;2012:543218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3485988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23133756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyachi M Kawano H Sugawara J, et al. Unfavorable effects of resistance training on central arterial compliance: a randomized intervention study. Circulation. 2004;110(18):2858-2863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15492301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP Pierce GL Howe KS Mering MC Braith RW. Effect of resistance training on arterial wave reflection and brachial artery reactivity in normotensive postmenopausal women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100(4):403-408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17394009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Credeur DP Hollis BC Welsch MA. Effects of handgrip training with venous restriction on brachial artery vasodilation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(7):1296-1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2903220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt JE Galea D Tufft G Bunce D Ferguson RA. Time course of regional vascular adaptations to low load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol. 2013;115(3):403-411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23703116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakobowchuk M McGowan CL de Groot PC Hartman JW Phillips SM MacDonald MJ. Endothelial function of young healthy males following whole body resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98(6):2185-2190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15677730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ras RT Streppel MT Draijer R Zock PL. Flow-mediated dilation and cardiovascular risk prediction: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2013;168(1):344-351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23041097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badrov MB Freeman SR Zokvic MA Millar PJ McGowan CL. Isometric exercise training lowers resting blood pressure and improves local brachial artery flow-mediated dilation equally in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(7):1289-1296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27137950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getty AK Wisdo TR Chavis LN, et al. Effects of circuit exercise training on vascular health and blood pressure. Prev Med Rep. 2018;10:106-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5966513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29850395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early KS Stewart A Johannsen N Lavie CJ Thomas JR Welsch M. The effects of exercise training on brachial artery flow-mediated dilation: A meta-analysis. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2017;37(2):77-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28033167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeno FP Ramis TR Farinha JB de Lemos LS Medeiros NDS Ribeiro JL. Acute effects of strength exercise with blood flow restriction on vascular function of young healthy males. J Vasc Bras. 2018;17(2):122-127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6205709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30377421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warburton D Jamnik S. Shephard R. Gledhill N. The 2019 Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire for everyone (PAR-Q+) and electronic Physical Activity Readiness Medical Examination (ePARmed-X+). Health Fit J of Canada. 2018;11(4):80-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomization. http://randomization.com/. Accessed 09-05-2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thijssen DH Black MA Pyke KE, et al. Assessment of flow-mediated dilation in humans: A methodological and physiological guideline. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2011;300(1):H2-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20952670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleather DJ Guthrie SR. Quantifying delayed-onset muscle soreness: A comparison of unidimensional and multidimensional instrumentation. J Sports Sci. 2007;25(8):845-850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17474037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knutzen KM Pendergrast BA Lindsey B Brilla LR. The effect of high resistance weight training on reported pain in older adults. J Sports Sci Med. 2007;6(4):455-460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3794485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melzack R. The McGill Pain Questionnaire: Major properties and scoring methods. Pain. 1975;1(3):277-299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1235985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H Neya M Ochi E Nakazato K Sato Y Ishii N. Cross-transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(2):258-263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HR Min KW Ahn HJ et al. Effects of aerobic exercise vs. resistance training on endothelial function in women with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Metab J. 2011;35(4):364-373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3178697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21977456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGowan CL Visocchi A Faulkner M, et al. Isometric handgrip training improves local flow-mediated dilation in medicated hypertensives. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;99(3):227-234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17106718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto T Masuhara M Ikuta K. Effect of low-intensity resistance training on arterial function. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(5):743-748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20972878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambic T Novakovic M Tomazin K Strojnik V Jug B. Blood flow restriction resistance exercise improves muscle strength and hemodynamics, but not vascular function in coronary artery disease patients: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol. 2019;10:656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs ME Hackney KJ Martin D, et al. Acute vascular and cardiovascular responses to blood flow-restricted exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(8):1489-1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24389514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>