<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34100789</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance Training With Different Velocity Loss Thresholds Induce Similar Changes in Strength and Hypertrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e135</StartPage><EndPage>e142</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e135-e142</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004067</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Andersen, V, Paulsen, G, Stien, N, Baarholm, M, Seynnes, O, and Saeterbakken, AH. Resistance training with different velocity loss thresholds induce similar changes in strengh and hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 38(3): e135-e142, 2024-The aim of this study was to compare the effects of 2 velocity-based resistance training programs when performing resistance training with matched training volume. Ten resistance-trained adults volunteered (age, 23 &#xb1; 4.3 years; body mass, 68 &#xb1; 8.9 kg; and height, 171 &#xb1; 8 cm) with a mean resistance training experience of 4.5 years. A within person, between leg design was used. For each subject, the legs were randomly assigned to either low velocity loss (LVL) threshold at 15% or high velocity loss (HVL) threshold at 30% velocity loss. Leg press and leg extension were trained unilaterally twice per week over a period of 9 weeks. Before and after the intervention, both legs were tested in 1 repetition maximum (RM) (kg), maximal voluntary contraction (MVC) (N), rate of force development (N&#xb7;s -1 ), average velocity (m&#xb7;s -1 ), and power output (W) at 30, 45, 60, and 75% of 1 RM (all in unilateral leg press). Furthermore, muscle thickness (mm) of the vastus lateralis and rectus femoris, pennation angle (&#xb0;) of the vastus lateralis, and the fascicle length (mm) of the vastus lateralis were measured using ultrasound imaging. The data were analyzed using mixed-design analysis of variance. No differences between the legs in any of the variables were found; however, both low and HVL were effective for increasing 1 RM (ES = 1.25-1.82), MVC (effect size [ES] = 0.42-0.64), power output (ES = 0.31-0.86), and muscle thickness (ES = 0.24-0.51). In conclusion, performing velocity-based resistance training with low and HVL with equal training volume resulted in similar effects in maximal and explosive strength in addition to muscular adaptations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andersen</LastName><ForeName>Vidar</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Arts and Sports, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paulsen</LastName><ForeName>G&#xf8;ran</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stien</LastName><ForeName>Nicolay</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Arts and Sports, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baarholm</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Arts and Sports, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seynnes</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeterbakken</LastName><ForeName>Atle Hole</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Arts and Sports, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34100789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202403000-00032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersen V, Pedersen H, Fimland MS, et al. Acute effects of elastic bands as resistance or assistance on EMG, kinetics, and kinematics during deadlift in resistance-trained men. Front Sports Active Living 2: 598284, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benavides-Ubric A, Diez-Fernandez DM, Rodriguez-Perez MA, Ortega-Becerra M, Pareja-Blanco F. Analysis of the load-velocity relationship in deadlift exercise. J Sports Sci Med 19: 452&#x2013;459, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness: A review of the acute programme variables. Sports Med 35: 841&#x2013;851, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Wilson CJ, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias JA. Effects of resistance training movement pattern and velocity on isometric muscular rate of force development: A systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. Sports Med 50: 943&#x2013;963, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Phillips SM. Bigger weights may not beget bigger muscles: Evidence from acute muscle protein synthetic responses after resistance exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 37: 551&#x2013;554, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantrell GS, Schilling BK, Paquette MR, Murlasits Z. Maximal strength, power, and aerobic endurance adaptations to concurrent strength and sprint interval training. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 763&#x2013;771, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Taylor JL, Gandevia SC. Recovery of central and peripheral neuromuscular fatigue after exercise. J Appl Physiol 122: 1068&#x2013;1076, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o F, Fernandes J, Lewis M, Gonzal&#xe9;z-Badillo JJ, Jimen&#xe9;z-Reyes P. Movement velocity as a measure of exercise intensity in three lower limb exercises. J Sports Sci 34: 1099&#x2013;1106, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: Morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med 37: 145&#x2013;168, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galiano C, Pareja-Blanco F, Hidalgo de Mora J, Saez de Villarreal E. Low-velocity loss induces similar strength gains to moderate-velocity loss during resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 36: 340-345, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Sanchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga EM, Pareja-Blanco F. Maximal intended velocity training induces greater gains in bench press performance than deliberately slower half-velocity training. Eur J Sport Sci 14: 772&#x2013;781, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Sanchez-Medina L. Movement velocity as a measure of loading intensity in resistance training. Int J Sports Med 31: 347&#x2013;352, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, et al. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 48: 1207&#x2013;1220, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Latella C. Resistance training frequency and skeletal muscle hypertrophy: A review of available evidence. J Sci Med Sport 22: 361&#x2013;370, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes LJ, Banyard HG, Dempsey AR, Peiffer JJ, Scott BR. Using load-velocity relationships to quantify training-induced fatigue. J Strength Cond Res 33: 762&#x2013;773, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA. Changes in the force-velocity relationship of fatigued muscle: Implications for power production and possible causes. J Physiol 588: 2977&#x2013;2986, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovanovi&#x107; M, Flanagan EP. Researched applications of velocity based strength training. J Aust Strength Cond 22: 58&#x2013;69, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamori N, Newton RU. Velocity specificity of resistance training: Actual movement velocity versus intention to move explosively. Strength Cond J 28: 86&#x2013;91, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Carroll TJ. Cross education: Possible mechanisms for the contralateral effects of unilateral resistance training. Sports Med 37: 1&#x2013;14, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, et al. Rate of force development: Physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1091&#x2013;1116, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methenitis S, Mpampoulis T, Spiliopoulou P, et al. Muscle fiber composition, jumping performance, and rate of force development adaptations induced by different power training volumes in females. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 45: 996&#x2013;1006, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, Cornejo-Daza PJ, et al. Effects of velocity loss in the bench press exercise on strength gains, neuromuscular adaptations and muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports 30: 2154&#x2013;2166, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, S&#xc1;nchez-Valdepe&#xd1;as J, et al. Velocity loss as a critical variable determining the adaptations to strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 52: 1752&#x2013;1762, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Sanchez-Medina L, et al. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on athletic performance, strength gains and muscle adaptations. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 724&#x2013;735, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Sanchez-Medina L, Suarez-Arrones L, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Effects of velocity loss during resistance training on performance in professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 12: 512&#x2013;519, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Villalba-Fernandez A, Cornejo-Daza PJ, Sanchez-Valdepenas J, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Time course of recovery following resistance exercise with different loading magnitudes and velocity loss in the set. Sports (Basel) 7: 59, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Castilla A, Garcia-Ramos A, Padial P, Morales-Artacho AJ, Feriche B. Effect of different velocity loss thresholds during a power-oriented resistance training program on the mechanical capacities of lower-body muscles. J Sports Sci 36: 1331&#x2013;1339, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plautard M, Guilhem G, Fohanno V, et al. Comparison of two methodological approaches for the mechanical analysis of single-joint isoinertial movement using a customised isokinetic dynamometer. Sports Biomech 17: 287&#x2013;302, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plisk SS, Stone MH. Periodization strategies. Strength Cond J 25: 19&#x2013;37, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2585&#x2013;2601, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res 18: 918&#x2013;920, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodiles-Guerrero L, Pareja-Blanco F, Leon-Prados JA. Effect of velocity loss on strength performance in bench press using a weight stack machine. Int J Sports Med 41: 921&#x2013;928, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Rosell D, Yanez-Garcia JM, Mora-Custodio R, et al. Velocity-based resistance training: Impact of velocity loss in the set on neuromuscular performance and hormonal response. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 45: 817&#x2013;828, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell KW, Quinney HA, Hazlett CB, Hillis D. Knee muscle strength in elite male gymnasts. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 22: 10&#x2013;17, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1725&#x2013;1734, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Perez CE, Pallares JG. Velocity- and power-load relationships of the bench pull vs. bench press exercises. Int J Sports Med 35: 209&#x2013;216, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Moreno M, Cornejo-Daza PJ, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Pareja-Blanco F. Effects of velocity loss during body mass prone-grip pull-up training on strength and endurance performance. J Strength Cond Res 34: 911&#x2013;917, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger J. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci 37: 1286&#x2013;1295, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, Cronin NJ. Simple Muscle Architecture Analysis (SMA): An ImageJ macro tool to automate measurements in B-mode ultrasound scans. PLoS One 15: e0229034, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med 46: 1419&#x2013;1449, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson SW, Rogerson D, Ruddock A, Barnes A. The effectiveness of two methods of prescribing load on maximal strength development: A systematic review. Sports Med 50: 919&#x2013;938, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Mann B, Banyard H, et al. Velocity-based training: From theory to application. Strength Cond J43: 31&#x2013;49, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley J, Ramirez-Lopez C, McLaren S, et al. The effects of 10%, 20%, and 30% velocity loss thresholds on kinetic, kinematic, and repetition characteristics during the barbell back squat. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 15: 180&#x2013;188, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med 37: 225&#x2013;264, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>