<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33795920</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>&#x3b2;-hydroxy-&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate supplementation benefits the effects of resistance training on body fat reduction via increased irisin expression in white adipose tissue.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>113</StartPage><EndPage>121</EndPage><MedlinePgn>113-121</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2020.97671</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The effects of resistance training (RT) associated with calcium &#x3b2;-hydroxy&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate (CaHMB) supplementation on the body composition and gene expression of cytokines related to skeletal muscle hypertrophy and adipose tissue metabolism were studied in rats. Male Wistar rats were divided into four groups of 12 animals: sedentary control (SC); sedentary supplemented (SS); resistance training control (RTC) and resistance training supplemented (RTS). Rats from RTC and RTS groups were submitted to an RT programme and those from SS and RTS groups received 1 mL of CaHMB (320 mg kg<sup>-1</sup> day<sup>-1</sup>) by gavage, for 8 weeks. We evaluated: body composition; plasma lipid profile; the gene expression of interleukin (IL)-6, IL-10, IL-15 and fibronectin type III domain-containing protein 5 (FNDC-5) in skeletal muscle, and IL-6, mitochondrial uncoupling protein 1 (UCP-1) in white adipose tissue (WAT); and the concentration of irisin in WAT. Compared to RTC alone, the combination of CaHMB with RT (RTS) further reduced abdominal circumference (5.3%), Lee index (2.4%), fat percentage (24.4%), plasma VLDL cholesterol (16.8%) and triglycerides (17%) and increased the gene expression of FNDC-5 (78.9%) and IL-6 (47.4%) in skeletal muscle and irisin concentration (26.9%) in WAT. Neither RT nor CaHMB affected the protein percentage or the gene expression of IL-6 and UCP-1 in WAT and IL-10, IL-15 in skeletal muscle. In conclusion, CaHMB supplementation increased the beneficial effects of RT on body fat reduction and was associated with muscular genic expression of IL-6 and FNDC-5 and irisin concentration in WAT, despite the lack of change in protein mass and maximal strength.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Termedia.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guedes</LastName><ForeName>Juliano M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Health, Universidade Federal de Vi&#xe7;osa, Vi&#xe7;osa, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peluzio</LastName><ForeName>Maria do Carmo G</ForeName><Initials>MDCG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Health, Universidade Federal de Vi&#xe7;osa, Vi&#xe7;osa, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rathmacher</LastName><ForeName>John A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MTI BioTech, Iowa State University Research Park, Ames, IA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Iowa State University, Ames, IA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leal</LastName><ForeName>Tiago F</ForeName><Initials>TF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Universidade Federal de Vi&#xe7;osa, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J&#xfa;nior</LastName><ForeName>Miguel A Carneiro</ForeName><Initials>MAC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Universidade Federal de Vi&#xe7;osa, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Diego M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Universidade Federal de Vi&#xe7;osa, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Leandro L</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Biology, Universidade Federal de Vi&#xe7;osa, Vi&#xe7;osa, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Natali</LastName><ForeName>Ant&#xf4;nio J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Universidade Federal de Vi&#xe7;osa, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HMB</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Irisin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Juliano Magalh&#xe3;es Guedes, Maria do Carmo Gouveia Pel&#xfa;zio, John A. Rathmacher, Tiago Ferreira Leal, Miguel Ara&#xfa;jo Carneiro J&#xfa;nior, Diego Milhomem de Carvalho, Leandro Licursi de Oliveira and Ant&#xf4;nio Jos&#xe9; Natali declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7996383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.97671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">97671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Celis-Morales CA, Welsh P, Lyall DM, Steell L, Petermann F, Anderson J, et al. Associations of grip strength with cardiovascular, respiratory, and cancer outcomes and all cause mortality: prospective cohort study of half a million UK Biobank participants. BMJ. 2018; 361:k1651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5939721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29739772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, McKellar SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Henselmans M, Helms E, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(6):376&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM. Progression Models in Resistance Training for Healthy Adults. ACSM&#x2013;American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009; 41(3): 687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egerman MA, Glass DJ. Signaling pathways controlling skeletal muscle mass. Crit Rev Biochem Mol Biol. 2014; 49(1):59&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24237131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reisi J, Ghaedi K, Rajabi H, Marandi SM. Can resistance exercise alter irisin levels and expression profiles of FNDC5 and UCP1 in rats? Asian J Sports Med. 2016; 7(4):35205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5259672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28144410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK. Muscles and their myokines. J Exp Biol. 2011; 214:337&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21177953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hall G, Steensberg A, Sacchetti M, Fischer C, Keller C, Schjerling P, et al. Interleukin-6 stimulates lipolysis and fat oxidation in humans. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003; 88(7):3005&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12843134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steensberg A, Fischer CP, Keller C, M&#xf8;ller K, Pedersen BK. IL-6 enhances plasma IL-1ra, IL-10, and cortisol in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2003; 285(2):433&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12857678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano AL, Baeza-Raja B, Perdiguero E, Jard&#xed; M, Mu&#xf1;oz-C&#xe1;noves P. Interleukin-6 is an essential regulator of satellite cell-mediated skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell Metab. 2008; 7(1):33&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18177723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carb&#xf3; N, L&#xf3;pez-Soriano J, Costelli P, Alvarez B, Busquets S, Baccino FM, et al. Interleukin-15 mediates reciprocal regulation of adipose and muscle mass: a potential role in body weight control. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2001; 1526(1):17&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11287118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn LS, Anderson BG, Strait-Bodey L, Stroud AM, Argiles JM. Oversecretion of interleukin-15 from skeletal muscle reduces adiposity. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008; 296(1):191&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2636988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostr&#xf6;m P, Wu J, Jedrychowski MP, Korde A, Ye L, Lo JC, et al. A PGC1-&#x3b1;-dependent myokine that drives brown-fat-like development of white fat and thermogenesis. Nature. 2012; 481(7382):463&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3522098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22237023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oelmann S, Nauck M, V&#xf6;lzke H, Bahls M, Friedrich N. Circulating Irisin Concentrations Are Associated with a Favourable Lipid Profile in the General Population. Plos One. 2016; 11(4):e0154319. 10.1371/journal.pone.0154319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0154319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4851367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27128661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Fitschen PPJ, Campbell B, Wilson GJ, Zanchi N, Taylor L, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB). J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013; 10(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23374455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JJM, Lowery RP, Joy JM, Andersen JC, Wilson SMC, Jeffrey R Stout JRet al. The effects of 12 weeks of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate free acid supplementation on muscle mass, strength, and power in resistance trained individuals: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Eur. J Appl. Physiol. 2014; 114(6):1217&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4019830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24599749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissen S, Sharp R, Ray M, Rathmacher JA, Rice D, Fuller Jr JC, et al. Effect of leucine metabolite b-hydroxy b-methylbutyrate on muscle metabolism during resistance-exercise training. J Appl Physiol. 1996; 81(5):2095&#x2013;2104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8941534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vukovich MD, Stubbs NB, Bohlken RM. Body composition in 70-year old adults responds to dietary b-hydroxy-bmethylbutyrate (HMB) similar to that of young adults. J Nutr. 2001; 131(7):2049&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11435528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Fukuda DH, Kendall KL , Smith-Ryan AE, Moon JR, Hoffman JR. Beta-Hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) supplementation and resistance exercise significantly reduce abdominal adiposity in healthy elderly men. Exp Gerontol. 2015; 64: 33&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira FJ, Matias CN, Monteiro CP, Valamatos MJ, Reis JF, Tavares F. Leucine metabolites do not enhance training-induced performance or muscle thickness. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018; 51(1):56&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30102677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakubowski JS, Wong EPT , Nunes EA, Noguchi KS, Vandeweerd JK, Murphy KT, et al. Equivalent hypertrophy and strength gains in HMB-or leucine-supplemented men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018; 51(1):65&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eley H L, Russell ST, Baxter JH, Mukerji P, Tisdale MJ. Signaling pathways initiated by b-hydroxy-b-methylbutyrate to attenuate the depression of protein synthesis in skeletal muscle in response to cachectic stimuli. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007; 293(4):E923&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith HJ, Mukerji P, Tisdale MJ. Attenuation of proteasome-induced proteolysis in skeletal muscle by b-hydroxy-b-methylbutyrate in cancer-induced muscle loss. Cancer Res. 2005; 65(1):277&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15665304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eley H L, Russell ST, Tisdale MJ. Attenuation of depression of muscle protein synthesis induced by lipopolysaccharide, tumor necrosis factor and angiotensin II by b-hydroxy-bmethylbutyrate. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008; 295:E1409&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18854427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eley HL, Russell ST, Tisdale MJ. Mechanism of attenuation of muscle protein degradation induced by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and angiotensin II by beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008; 295(6): E1417&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18840762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stancliffe RA. Role of Beta-Hydroxy- Beta-Methylbutyrate (HMB) in Leucine Stimulation of Mitochondrial Biogenesis and Fatty Acid Oxidation. Masters Theses. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baggett B, Bruckbauer A, Zemel M. Synergistic Effects of Leucine and its Metabolites with Polyphenols on Irisin in Myotubes and Diet-induced Obese Mice. FASEB J. 2013;27(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JJM, Fitschen PPJ, Campbell B, Wilson GJ, Zanchi N, Taylor L, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB). J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013; 10(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23374455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson JS, Watson PE, Rowlands DS. Effects of nine weeks of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate supplementation on strength and body composition in resistance trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2009; 23(3):827&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19387396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva VR, Belozo FL, Micheletti TO, Conrado M, Stout JR, Pimentel GD, et al. &#x3b2;-Hydroxy&#x3b2;-Methylbutyrate Free acid supplementation may improve recovery and muscle adaptations after resistance training: a systematic review. Nutr Res. 2017; 45:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29037326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portal S, Zadik Z, Rabinowitz J, Pilz-Burstein R, Adler-Portal D, Meckel Y, et al. The effect of HMB supplementation on body composition, fitness, hormonal and inflammatory mediators in elite adolescent volleyball players: a prospective randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011; 111(9):2261&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21327797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X, Duan Y, Yao K, Li F, Hou Y, Wu G, et al. &#x3b2;-Hydroxy&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate, mitochondrial biogenesis, and skeletal muscle health. Amino Acids. 2016; 48(3):653&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirvani H, Rahmati-Ahmadabad S, Broom DR, Mirnejad R. Eccentric resistance training and &#x3b2;-hydroxy&#x3b2;methylbutyrate free acid affects muscle PGC-1&#x3b1; expression and serum irisin, nesfatin-1 and resistin in rats. J Exp Bio. 2019;222(10):198424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31085594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo S, Barauna V, J&#xfa;nior M, Bozi L, Drummond L, Natali A, et al. Resistance training regulates cardiac function through modulation of miRNA-214. Int J Mol Sci. 2015; 16(12):6855&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4424992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25822872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rios L, Del RJ, Silva Da KA, Rodrigues AC, Soares PNP, Gomes TNP, et al. Enhanced femoral neck strength in response to weightlifting exercise training in maturing male rats. ISMJ. 2013;14(3):155&#x2013;67. https://hdl.handle.net/10520/EJC142366</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki T, Uchiyama S, Nakano S. A weight-lifting exercise model for inducing hypertrophy in the hindlimb muscles of rats. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992; 24(8):881&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1406173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro CH da J, Gerlinger-Romero F, Guimar&#xe3;es-Ferreira L, de Souza-Jr AL, Vitzel KF, Nachbar RT, et al. Metabolic and functional effects of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) supplementation in skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012; 112(7):2531&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22075640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter JH, Carlos JL, Thurmond J, Rehani RN, Bultman J, Frost D. Dietary toxicity of calcium &#x3b2;-hydroxy&#x3b2;-methyl butyrate (CaHMB). Food Chem Toxicol. 2005; 43(12):1731&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16006030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MO. Determination of the surface area of the white rat with application to the expression of metabolic results. Am J Physiol. 1929; 89(1):24&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novelli ELB, Diniz YS, Galhardi CM, Ebaid GMX, Rodrigues HG, Mani F, et al. Anthropometrical parameters and markers of obesity in rats. Lab Anim. 2007; 41(1):111&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17234057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AOAC (1998) Official Method of Analysis. 15th Edition, Association of Official Analytical Chemists, Washington DC.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livak KJ, Schmittgen TD. Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2-DDCt method. Methods. 2001; 25:402&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedewald WT, Levy RI, Fredrickson DS. Estimation of the concentration of low-density lipoprotein cholesterol in plasma, without use of the preparative ultracentrifuge. Clin Chem. 1972;18(6):499&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4337382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost PH, Havel RJ. Rationale for use of non-high-density lipoprotein cholesterol rather than low-density lipoprotein cholesterol as a tool for lipoprotein cholesterol screening and assessment of risk and therapy. Am J Cardiol. 1998; 81(4A):26B-31B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9526810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioural sciences. 2nd ed. Hillsdale (NJ): Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen P, Marino F, Melehan K, Guelfi KJ, Duffield R, Skein M. High-intensity interval exercise induces greater acute changes in sleep, appetite-related hormones, and free-living energy intake than does moderate-intensity continuous exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2019; 44(5):557&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30332549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tominaga T, Ma S, Saitou K, Suzuki K. Glucose Ingestion Inhibits Endurance Exercise-Induced IL-6 Producing Macrophage Infiltration in Mice Muscle. Nutrients. 2019; 11(7): 149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6682949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31262006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roca-Rivada A, Castelao C, Senin LL, Landrove MO, Baltar J, Bel&#xe9;n Crujeiras A, et al. FNDC5/irisin is not only a myokine but also an adipokine. PLoS One. 2013; 8(4): e60563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23593248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reisi J, Rajabi H, Ghaedi K, Seyed-Mohammad M, Mohammad-Reza D. Effect of Acute Resistance Training on Plasma Irisin Protein Level and Expression of Muscle FNDC5 and Adipose Tissue UCP1 Genes in Male Rats. IUMS. 2013; 31256:1657&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro CHJ, Guimar&#xe3;es-Ferreira L, Gerlinger-Romero F, Curi R. An Overview on Beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) Supplementation in Skeletal Muscle Function and Sports Performance. In: Nutrition and Enhanced Sports Performance. Elsevier; 2013; 1(47): 455&#x2013;63. 10.1016/B978-0-12-396454-0.00047-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-396454-0.00047-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostr&#xf6;m P, Wu J, Jedrychowski MP, Korde A, Ye L, Lo JC, et al. A PGC1-&#x3b1;-dependent myokine that drives brown-fat-like development of white fat and thermogenesis. Nature. 2012; 481(7382):463&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3522098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22237023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norheim F, Langleite TM, Hjorth M, Holen T, Kielland A, Stadheim HK, et al. The effects of acute and chronic exercise on PGC-1 &#x3b1;, irisin and browning of subcutaneous adipose tissue in humans. FEBS J. 2014; 281(3):739&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24237962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin C, Liu J, Zhang J, Zhu D, Wang H, Xiong L, et al. Irisin improves fatty acid oxidation and glucose utilization in type 2 diabetes by regulating the AMPK signaling pathway. Int J Obes. 2016; 40(3):443&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26403433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So WY, Leung PS. Irisin ameliorates hepatic glucose/lipid metabolism and enhances cell survival in insulin-resistant human HepG2 cells through adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase signaling. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2016; 78:237&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27452313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan ND, Williams DA, Lynch GS. Adaptations in rat skeletal muscle following long-term resistance exercise training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1998; 77(4):372&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9562367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ, Evans WJ. Strength and power training: physiological mechanisms of adaptation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1996; 24:363&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8744256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Impact of progressive resistance training on lipids and lipoproteins in adults: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Prev Med. 2009; 48(1):9&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19013187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott KJ, Sale C, Cable NT. Effects of resistance training and detraining on muscle strength and blood lipid profiles in postmenopausal women. Br J Sports Med. 2002; 36(5):340&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12351331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Taat B, Suzuki K. A Review of the effects of leucine metabolite (&#x3b2;-Hydroxy&#x3b2;-methylbutyrate) supplementation and resistance training on inflammatory markers: A new approach to oxidative stress. Antioxidants. 2018; 7(10):148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6210682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30347824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>