<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36157335</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Manipulating Resistance Training Variables to Induce Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy: A Brief Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>910</StartPage><EndPage>933</EndPage><MedlinePgn>910-933</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The regular practice of resistance training (RT) has been shown to induce relevant increases in both muscle strength and size. In order to maximize these adaptations, the proper manipulation of RT variables is warranted. In this sense, the aim of the present study was to review the available literature that has examined the application of the acute training variables and their influence on strength and morphological adaptations of healthy young adults. The information presented in this study may represent a relevant approach to proper training design. Therefore, strength and conditioning coaches may acquire a fundamental understanding of RT-variables and the relevance of their practical application within exercise prescription.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE Camargo</LastName><ForeName>J&#xfa;lio Benvenutti Bueno</ForeName><Initials>JBB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Piracicaba, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brigatto</LastName><ForeName>Felipe Alves</ForeName><Initials>FA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Piracicaba, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaroni</LastName><ForeName>Rafael Sakai</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Piracicaba, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trindade</LastName><ForeName>Thiago Barbosa</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Brasilia, DF, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Germano</LastName><ForeName>Mois&#xe9;s Diego</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Piracicaba, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Junior</LastName><ForeName>Antonio Carlos Tavares</ForeName><Initials>ACT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sao Paulo State University, School of Science, Bauru, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Thiago Pires</ForeName><Initials>TP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Julio de Mesquita Filho" State University, Rio Claro, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhanguera University Center, Leme, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Claretiano University Center, Rio Claro, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marchetti</LastName><ForeName>Paulo Henrique</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Human Performance Department, Montana State University Billings, Billings, MT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prestes</LastName><ForeName>Jonato</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Brasilia, DF, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Charles Ricardo</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Piracicaba, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty Adventist of Hortol&#xe2;ndia, Hortol&#xe2;ndia, SP, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">size</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thickness</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9458289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/VYUB3717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-15-4-910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM American College of Sports. Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams GR, Bamman MM. Characterization and regulation of mechanical loading-induced compensatory muscle hypertrophy. Compr Physiol. 2012;2(4):2829&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23720267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Short vs. long rest period between the sets in hypertrophic resistance training: Influence on muscle strength, size, and hormonal adaptations in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(3):572&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA. Crescent pyramid and drop-set systems do not promote greater strength gains, muscle hypertrophy, and changes on muscle architecture compared with traditional resistance training in well-trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(2):359&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artero EG, Lee DC, Ruiz JR, Sui X, Ortega FB, Church TS, et al. A prospective study of muscular strength and all-cause mortality in men with hypertension. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;57(18):1831&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3098120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aube D, Wadhi T, Rauch J, Anand A, Barakat C, Pearson J, et al. Progressive Resistance Training Volume: Effects on Muscle Thickness, Mass, and Strength Adaptations in Resistance-Trained Individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(3):600&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avelar A, Ribeiro AS, Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Papst RR, Trindade MC, de C, et al. Effects of order of resistance training exercises on muscle hypertrophy in young adult men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2019;44(4):420&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30248269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsamo S, Tibana RA, Nascimento DDC, Franz CB, Lyons S, Faigenbaum A, et al. Exercise order influences number of repetitions and lactate levels but not perceived exertion during resistance exercise in adolescents. Res Sport Med. 2013;21(4):293&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24067116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho M, Gentil P, Raiol R, Fisher J, Steele J, Coswig V. Influence of Adding Single-Joint Exercise to a Multijoint Resistance Training Program in Untrained Young Women. J strength Cond Res. 2020;34(8):2214&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29781936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Fontes-Villalba M, Santos-Concejero J. Total Number of Sets as a Training Volume Quantification Method for Muscle Hypertrophy: A Systematic Review. J strength Cond Res. 2021;35(3):870&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottaro M, Martins B, Gentil P, Wagner D. Effects of rest duration between sets of resistance training on acute hormonal responses in trained women. J Sci Med Sport. 2009;12(1):73&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18093876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand&#xe3;o L, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, Silva-Batista C, Brendon H, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Varying the Order of Combinations of Single- and Multi-Joint Exercises Differentially Affects Resistance Training Adaptations. J strength Cond Res. 2020;34(5):1254&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Braz TV, Zanini TC, da C, Germano MD, Aoki MS, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effect of Resistance Training Frequency on Neuromuscular Performance and Muscle Morphology After 8 Weeks in Trained Men. J strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2104&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29528962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Braz TV, Zanini TCC, Germano MD, Aoki MS, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effect of Resistance Training Frequency on Neuromuscular Performance and Muscle Morphology After 8 Weeks in Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2104&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29528962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Lima LE, de M, Germano MD, Aoki MS, Braz TV, Lopes CR. High Resistance-Training Volume Enhances Muscle Thickness in Resistance-Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(1):22&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31868813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Abe T, Loenneke JP. Resistance exercise and sports performance: The minority report. Med Hypotheses. 2018;113:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29523284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, West DWD, Staples AW, Cain NE, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol. 2010;588(16):3119&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DWD, Staples AW, Atherton PJ, Baker JM, Moore DR, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS One. 2010;5(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GER, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(1&#x2013;2):50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves TS, De Campos Biazon TMP, Dos Santos LME, Libardi CA. Effects of resistance training with controlled versus self-selected repetition duration on muscle mass and strength in untrained men. PeerJ. 2020;2020(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7061915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32185108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claflin DR, Larkin LM, Cederna PS, Horowitz JF, Alexander NB, Cole NM, et al. Effects of high- and low-velocity resistance training on the contractile properties of skeletal muscle fibers from young and older humans. J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(4):1021&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun RJ, Gai CM, Aguilar D, Bove D, Dolan J, Vargas A, et al. Training volume, not frequency, indicative of maximal strength adaptations to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(5):1207&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29324578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa DA, Brigatto FA, Braz TV, de Camargo JBB, Aoki MS, Marchetti PHLC. Twice-daily sessions result in a greater muscle strength and a similar muscle hypertrophy compared to once-daily session in resistance-trained men. J Sport Med Phys Fit. 2022;62(3):324&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33634677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Angleri V, Phillips SM, Witard OC, Ugrinowitsch C, Santanielo N, et al. Myofibrillar protein synthesis and muscle hypertrophy individualized responses to systematically changing resistance training variables in trained young men. J Appl Physiol. 2019;127(3):806&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31268828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Barcelos C, N&#xf3;brega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Santos LMED, et al. Individual Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength Responses to High vs.Low Resistance Training Frequencies. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(4):897&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30289872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Counts BR, et al. Frequency: The Overlooked Resistance Training Variable for Inducing Muscle Hypertrophy? Sport Med. 2017;47(5):799&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies T, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of Training Leading to Repetition Failure on Muscular Strength: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sport Med. 2016;46(4):487&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26666744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(11):2691&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23949789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Jones DA, Williams AG, Stewart CE, Degens H. Inter-individual variability in the adaptation of human muscle specific tension to progressive resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(6):1117&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20703498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farinatti PTV, Geraldes AAR, Bottaro MF, Lima MVIC, Albuquerque RB, Fleck SJ. Effects of different resistance training frequencies on the muscle strength and functional performance of active women older than 60 years. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(8):2225&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23168371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Author&#x2019;s Reply to Souza et al: Comment on: &#x201c;Volume for Muscle Hypertrophy and Health Outcomes: The Most Effective Variable in Resistance Training&#x201d;. Sport Med. 2018;48(5):1285&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29396782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca FS, Costa BD, de V, Ferreira MEC, Paes S, de Lima D, Junior, Kassiano W, et al. Acute effects of equated volume-load resistance training leading to muscular failure versus non-failure on neuromuscular performance. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2020;18(2):94&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7327779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32636891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Fran&#xe7;a HS, Branco PAN, Guedes DP, Junior, Gentil P, Steele J, Teixeira CVLS. The effects of adding single-joint exercises to a multi-joint exercise resistance training program on upper body muscle strength and size in trained men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2015;40(8):822&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26244600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fischer B, Martorelli AS, Lima RM, Bottaro M. Effects of equal-volume resistance training performed one or two times a week in upper body muscle size and strength of untrained young men. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2015;55(3):144&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24732784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fisher J, Steele J, Campos MH, Silva MH, Paoli A, et al. Effects of equal-volume resistance training with different training frequencies in muscle size and strength in trained men. PeerJ. 2018;2018(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6016534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29942690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Soares SRS, Pereira MC, da Cunha RR, Martorelli SS, Martorelli AS, et al. Effect of adding single-joint exercises to a multi-joint exercise resistance-training program on strength and hypertrophy in untrained subjects. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2013;38(3):341&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23537028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilson H, Schakman O, Kalista S, Lause P, Tsuchida K, Thissen JP. Follistatin induces muscle hypertrophy through satellite cell proliferation and inhibition of both myostatin and activin. Am J Physiol - Endocrinol Metab. 2009;297(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19435857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes GK, Franco CM, Nunes PRP, Orsatti FL. High-Frequency Resistance Training Is Not More Effective Than Low-Frequency Resistance Training in Increasing Muscle Mass and Strength in Well-Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:S130&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Ribas J, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez C, Mora-Custodio R, et al. Short-term Recovery Following Resistance Exercise Leading or not to Failure. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37(4):295&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez JM, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Colomer-Poveda D, Tvarijonaviciute A, Cer&#xf3;n J, Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, et al. Resistance Training to Failure vs. Not to Failure: Acute and Delayed Markers of Mechanical, Neuromuscular, and Biochemical Fatigue. J strength Cond Res. 2021;35(4):886&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Kraemer RR, Honda Y, Takamatsu K. Hormonal and metabolic responses to slow movement resistance exercise with different durations of concentric and eccentric actions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;106(5):731&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19430944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Sabol F. Effects of resistance training performed to repetition failure or non-failure on muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Heal Sci. 2021 S2095-2546(21)00007-7. Online ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Kallinen M. Distribution of strength training volume into one or two daily sessions and neuromuscular adaptations in female athletes. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1994;34(2):117&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8187678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A. Serum hormones in male strength athletes during intensive short term strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1991;63(3&#x2013;4):194&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1761007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Valkeinen H, Alen M. Selective muscle hypertrophy, changes in EMG and force, and serum hormones during strength training in older women. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91(2):569&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Mobley CB, Osburn SC, Mumford PW, Roberson PA, et al. Pre-training skeletal muscle fiber size and predominant fiber type best predict hypertrophic responses to 6 weeks of resistance training in to previously trained young men. Front Physiol. 2019;10(3):297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30971942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E. Relation between size of neurons and their susceptibility to discharge. Science. 1957;126(3287):1345&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13495469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, Price TB, Hoffman EP, Angelopoulos TJ, et al. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(6):964&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Costa B, de Lima-J&#xfa;nior D, Gantois P, de Souza Fonseca F, de Sousa Fortes L. Revisiting the relationship between resistance training dose and strength gains: what is the real role of volume? J Trainology. 2021;10(2):10&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ, Dziados JE, et al. Changes in hormonal concentrations after different heavy resistance exercise protocols in women. J Appl Physiol. 1993;75(2):594&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Marchitelli L, Gordon SE, Harman E, Dziados JE, Mello R, et al. Hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise protocols. J Appl Physiol. 1990;69(4):1442&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2262468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of Resistance Training: Progression and Exercise Prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36(4):674&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of 4, 8 and 12 Repetition Maximum Resistance Training Protocols on Muscle Volume and Strength. J strength Cond Res. 2021;35(4):879&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerda LT, Costa CG, Lima FV, Martins-Costa HC, Diniz RCR, Andrade AGP, et al. Longer concentric action increases muscle activation and neuromuscular fatigue responses in protocols equalized by repetition duration. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(6):1629&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28737588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerda LT, Marra-Lopes RO, Diniz RCR, Lima FV, Rodrigues SA, Martins-Costa HC, et al. Is Performing Repetitions to Failure Less Important Than Volume for Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength? J strength Cond Res. 2020;34(5):1237&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31809457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacerda LT, Martins-Costa HC, Diniz RCR, Lima FV, Andrade AGP, Tourino FD, et al. Variations in Repetition Duration and Repetition Numbers Influence Muscular Activation and Blood Lactate Response in Protocols Equalized by Time Under Tension. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(1):251&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26691414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva-Batista C, Barros T, de S, Aihara AY, Brendon H, et al. Muscle Failure Promotes Greater Muscle Hypertrophy in Low-Load but Not in High-Load Resistance Training. J Strength Cond Res Publish. 2022;36(2):346&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, Roschel H, Tavares LD, De Souza EO, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(6):772&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29564973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, Roschel H, Tavares LD, De Souza EO, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(6):772&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29564973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo AR, Silva-Batista C, Pedroso K, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Volume Load Rather Than Resting Interval Influences Muscle Hypertrophy During High-Intensity Resistance Training. J Strength Cond Res Publish. 2020;19(7):246&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Trajano GS, et al. Resistance Training Load Effects on Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength Gain: Systematic Review and Network Meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(6):1206&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Redd MJ, Gonzalez AM, Townsend JR, Wells AJ, Jajtner AR, et al. Resistance training does not induce uniform adaptations to quadriceps. PLoS One. 2018;13(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6116919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30161137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannarino P, Matta T, Lima J, Sim&#xe3;o R, Freitas de Salles B. Single-Joint Exercise Results in Higher Hypertrophy of Elbow Flexors Than Multijoint Exercise. J Strength Cond Res Publish. 2022;35(10):2677&#x2013;2681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31268995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martorelli S, Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, Celes R, Martorelli A, Cleto VA, et al. Strength training with repetitions to failure does not provide additional strength and muscle hypertrophy gains in young women. Eur J Transl Myol. 2017;27(2):6339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5505097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28713535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Dickinson A, Pattany PM, Fleck SJ. Muscle fiber hypertrophy, hyperplasia, and capillary density in college men after resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81(5):2004&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8941522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda H, Fleck SJ, Sim&#xe3;o R, Barreto AC, Dantas EHM, Novaes J. Effect of two different rest period lengths on the number of repetitions performed during resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(4):1032&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mookerjee S, Ratamess N. Comparison of Strength Differences and Joint Action Durations between Full and Partial Range-of-Motion Bench Press Exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13(1):76&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, P&#xe9;rez CE, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R, de la Cruz-S&#xe1;nchez E, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Time course of recovery following resistance training leading or not to failure. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(12):2387&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28965198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, Mazara N, McGlory C, Quadrilatero J, et al. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol. 2016;121(1):129&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4967245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Farias Zuniga A, Mohammad IYZ, Jones A, McGlory C, et al. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. J Physiol. 2019;597(17):4601&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura Y, Tanaka K, Yabushita N, Sakai T, Shigematsu R. Effects of exercise frequency on functional fitness in older adult women. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2007;44(2):163&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16730813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical Issues Relating to Scientific Discovery in Exercise Science. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Barroso R, Ugrinowitsch C, Da Costa JLF, Alvarez IF, Barcelos C, et al. Self-selected vs. fixed repetition duration: Effects on number of repetitions and muscle activation in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(9):2419&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29481458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Grgic J, Cunha PM, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, de Salles BF, et al. What influence does resistance exercise order have on muscular strength gains and muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;21(2):149&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Low-Load Bench Press Training to Fatigue Results in Muscle Hypertrophy Similar to High-Load Bench Press Training. Int J Clin Med. 2013;04(02):114&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohno Y, Ando K, Ito T, Suda Y, Matsui Y, Oyama A, et al. Lactate stimulates a potential for hypertrophy and regeneration of mouse skeletal muscle. Nutrients. 2019;11(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30999708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Kubota A, Natsume T, Loenneke JP, Abe T, Machida S, et al. Effects of drop sets with resistance training on increases in muscle CSA, strength, and endurance: a pilot study. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(6):691&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28532248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Wolfe RR. Resistance training reduces the acute exercise-induced increase in muscle protein turnover. Am J Physiol - Endocrinol Metab. 1999;276(139-1):118&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi R. Effect of different rest intervals on the exercise volume completed during squat bouts. J Sport Sci Med. 2005;4(4):361&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3899651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24501549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rantanen T, Avlund K, Suominen H, Schroll M, Fr&#xe4;ndin K, Pertti E. Muscle strength as a predictor of onset of ADL dependence in people aged 75 years. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2002;14(3 Suppl):10&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12475129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Falvo MJ, Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Faigenbaum AD, Kang J. The effect of rest interval length on metabolic responses to the bench press exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100(1):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17237951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva DRP, Pina FLC, Guariglia DA, Porto M, et al. Effect of two-Versus three-Way split resistance training routines on body composition and muscular strength in bodybuilders: A pilot study. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2015;25(6):559&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26008801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Haun CT, Mobley CB, Mumford PW, Romero MA, Roberson PA, et al. Physiological differences between low versus high skeletal muscle hypertrophic responders to resistance exercise training: Current perspectives and future research directions. Front Physiol. 2018 JUL 9;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6039846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30022953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de salles BF, Sim&#xe3;o R, Miranda F, Novaes JSWJ. Rest Interval between Sets in Strength Training. Sport Med. 2009;39(9):765&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19691365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Polito MD, Goessler KF, Mannarino P, Matta TT, Sim&#xe3;o R. Effects of fixed vs. self-suggested rest between sets in upper and lower body exercises performance. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16(8):927&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27050709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Sim&#xe3;o R, Miranda H, Bottaro M, Fontana F, Willardson JM. Strength increases in upper and lower body are larger with longer inter-set rest intervals in trained men. J Sci Med Sport. 2010;13(4):429&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19811949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson JA, Groeller H. Is repetition failure critical for the development of muscle hypertrophy and strength? Scand J Med Sci Sport. 2016;26(4):375&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25809472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santanielo N, N&#xf3;brega SR, Scarpelli MC, Alvarez IF, Otoboni GB, Pintanel L, et al. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs non-failure on strength, hypertrophy and muscle architecture in trained individuals. Biol Sport. 2020;37(4):333&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saric J, Lisica D, Orlic I, Grgic J, Krieger JW, Vuk S, et al. Resistance training frequencies of 3 and 6 times per week produce similar muscular adaptations in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:S122&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli MC, N&#xf3;brega SR, Santanielo N, Alvarez IF, Otoboni GB, Ugrinowitsch C, et al. Muscle Hypertrophy Response Is Affected by Previous Resistance Training Volume in Trained Individuals. J Strength Cond Res Publish pub ahead of print. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32108724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2857&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, Grgic J, Delcastillo K, Belliard R, et al. Resistance Training Volume Enhances Muscle Hypertrophy but Not Strength in Trained Men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(1):94&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, Grgic J, Delcastillo K, Belliard R, et al. Resistance Training Volume Enhances Muscle Hypertrophy but Not Strength in Trained Men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(1):94&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. High-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, Hester GM, Sellers J, Nooner JL, et al. Longer interset rest periods enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(7):1805&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Petersen MD, Contreras B, Sonmez GT, Alvar BA. Effects of Different Volume-Equated Resistance Training Loading Strategies on Muscular Adaptations in Well-Trained Men. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(10):2909&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24714538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuenke MD, Herman JR, Gliders RM, Hagerman FC, Hikida RS, Rana SR, et al. Early-phase muscular adaptations in response to slow-speed versus traditional resistance-training regimens. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(10):3585&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senna GW, Willardson JM, Scudese E, Sim&#xe3;o R, De Oliveira CQ, De Oliveira Lima J, et al. Multi- to Single-Joint or the Reverse Exercise Order does not Affect Pectoralis Major Workout Performance. J Hum Kinet. 2019;66(1):223&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6458580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30988856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sforzo GA, Touey PR. Manipulating Exercise Order Affects Muscular Performance during a Resistance Exercise Training Session. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10(1):20&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Farinatti PDTV, Polito MD, Maior AS, Fleck SJ. Influence of exercise order on the number of repetitions performed and perceived exertion during resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(1):152&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Polito M, Freitas de Salles B, Marinho DA, Garrido ND, Junior ERTS, et al. Acute and Long-Term Comparison of Fixed vs. Self-Selected Rest Interval Between Sets on Upper-Body Strength. J Strength Cond Res Publish. 2022;36(2):540&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Spineti J, de Salles BF, Oliveira LF, Matta T, Miranda F, et al. Influence of exercise order on maximum strength and muscle thickness in untrained men. J Sport Sci Med. 2010;9(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spineti J, De Salles BF, Rhea MR, Lavigne D, Matta T, Miranda F, et al. Influence of exercise order on maximum strength and muscle volume in nonlinear periodized resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(11):2962&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20938358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Mortensen OS, Jakobsen MD, Andersen LL, Andersen CH, Zebis MK. Muscle activation strategies during strength training with heavy loading vs. repetitions to failure. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(7):1897&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21986694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares LD, de Souza EO, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino GC, Roschel H, Aihara AY, et al. Effects of different strength training frequencies during reduced training period on strength and muscle cross-sectional area. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(6):665&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28316261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Andersen V, Saeterbakken AH. Comparison of muscle activation and kinematics during free-weight back squats with different loads. PLoS One. 2019;14(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6521994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31095625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawakami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy: Its relation to muscle activation in training session. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(11):2158&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23657165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Sugisaki N, Murata K, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y, et al. Association between regional differences in muscle activation in one session of resistance exercise and in muscle hypertrophy after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(4):1569&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21858666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DWD, Burd NA, Tang JE, Moore DR, Staples AW, Holwerda AM, et al. Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108(1):60&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DWD, Kujbida GW, Moore DR, Atherton P, Burd NA, Padzik JP, et al. Resistance exercise-induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J Physiol. 2009;587(21):5239&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19736298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM. A brief review: Factors affecting the length of the rest interval between resistance exercise sets. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(4):978&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. A comparison of 3 different rest intervals on the exercise volume completed during a workout. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(1):23&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue FL, Karsten B, Larumbe-Zabala E, Seijo M, Naclerio F. Comparison of 2 weekly-equalized volume resistance-training routines using different frequencies on body composition and performance in trained males. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2018;43(5):475&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29216446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaroni RS, Brigatto FA, Schoenfeld BJ, Braz TV, Benvenutti JC, Germano MD, et al. High Resistance-Training Frequency Enhances Muscle Thickness in Resistance-Trained Men. J strength Cond Res. 2019;33:S140&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31260419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>