<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40696603</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>29</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of blood flow restriction training in adolescents: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e43084</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e43084</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e43084</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000043084</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Blood flow restriction training (BFRT) involves applying external compression to the limbs to restrict venous blood return during low-intensity exercise, thereby promoting improvements in muscle mass and strength. Originally developed decades ago, BFRT has gained renewed interest in recent years, with applications spanning rehabilitation medicine, aerospace, and general fitness. However, its use in adolescents remains limited and under-researched. This narrative review aims to summarize the current understanding of the effects, mechanisms, and practical applications of BFRT in adolescents, with a focus on muscle health, physical performance, and training safety. A comprehensive review of recent literature was conducted, focusing on BFRT-related physiological mechanisms, including metabolic stress, anabolic hormone responses, muscle fiber recruitment, protein synthesis regulation, myostatin suppression, and cell swelling. Relevant studies on adolescent populations were analyzed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of BFRT in this age group. BFRT appears to promote muscle hypertrophy, strength, endurance, and neuromuscular adaptations in adolescents, with reduced injury risk compared to high-load training. Individualized arterial occlusion pressure settings enhance both the safety and effectiveness of BFRT. Applications span general fitness, athletic performance enhancement, and injury rehabilitation. BFRT offers a promising, low-risk alternative to traditional resistance training for adolescents, supporting safe and effective physical development. Its integration into youth fitness and rehabilitation programs by educators, healthcare providers, and sports organizations may offer substantial benefits for adolescent health and performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhen-Lei</ForeName><Initials>ZL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5508-6428</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Hubei University of Education, Wuhan, Hubei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Tian-Shu</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Sports Medicine and Rehabilitation, Beijing Sports University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Shuang-Feng</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Sports Medicine and Rehabilitation, Beijing Sports University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Si-Zhuo</ForeName><Initials>SZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, International Equestrian school, Wuhan Business University, Wuhan, Hubei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Ji-Lai</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Medicine, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>You-Qing</ForeName><Initials>YQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Hubei University of Education, Wuhan, Hubei Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Li-Ping</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Sports Medicine and Rehabilitation, Beijing Sports University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>18YJC890032</GrantID><Agency>Humanities and social science research Foundation of Ministry of Education of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Flow Restriction Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-load exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40696603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12282689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000043084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202507180-00031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Qin F, Song Y, Nassis GP, et al. Physical activity, screen time, and emotional well-being during the 2019 novel coronavirus outbreak in China. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:5170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32709003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozlenia D, Domaradzki J. Effects of combination movement patterns quality and physical performance on injuries in young athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:8872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8196781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34064201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prue J, Roman DP, Giampetruzzi NG, et al. Side effects and patient tolerance with the use of blood flow restriction training after ACL reconstruction in adolescents: a pilot study. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2022;17:347&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8975582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35391873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt J, Ahmed Z. Blood flow restriction training and its use in rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med. 2024;13:6265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11508829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39458215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Li B, Yang W, et al. The effects and mechanisms of blood flow restriction training. China Sport Sci. 2019;39:71&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>May AK, Russell AP, Della Gatta PA, Warmington SA. Muscle adaptations to heavy-load and blood flow restriction resistance training methods. Front Physiol. 2022;13:837697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35185627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A, Song J, Chang B. Experimental study on the effect of muscle blood flow restriction training on antioxidant capacity of speed skaters. J Guangzhou Inst Phys Educ. 2007;27:86&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Li Z, Wei W, Zhao Z, Chen C, Huang J. Empirical study on the effect of lower limb compression strength training for high-level male handball players. Chin Sports Sci Technol. 2019;55:30&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Dyar KA, Ciciliot S, Blaauw B, Sandri M. Mechanisms regulating skeletal muscle growth and atrophy. FEBS J. 2013;280:4294&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23517348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 2013;43:179&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23338987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ, Hussain SR. A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2015;45:187&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves GV, Kraemer RR, Hollander DB, et al. Comparison of hormone responses following light resistance exercise with partial vascular occlusion and moderately difficult resistance exercise without occlusion. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2006;101:1616&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16902061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velloso CP. Regulation of muscle mass by growth hormone and IGF-I. Br J Pharmacol. 2008;154:557&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2439518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18500379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Z, Hailing S, Mei Z, Bo B, Bing S. Research progress on the correlation between growth hormone/insulin-like growth factor-1 and malnutrition in children. Chin J Child Health. 2021;29:734&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:955&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabero-Garrido R, Gragera-Vela M, Del Corral T, Hernandez-Martin M, Plaza-Manzano G, Lopez-de-Uralde-Villanueva I. Effects of low-load blood flow restriction training on muscle anabolism biomarkers and thrombotic biomarkers compared with traditional training in healthy adults older than 60 years: systematic review and meta-analysis. Life (Basel). 2024;14:411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10971244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38541735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2007;103:903&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:406&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2010;108:1199&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawada S, Ishii N. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy after chronic restriction of venous blood flow in rats. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1144&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16015131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidhu SK, Weavil JC, Thurston TS, et al. Fatigue-related group III/IV muscle afferent feedback facilitates intracortical inhibition during locomotor exercise. J Physiol. 2018;596:4789&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6166070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30095164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmet D, Roberts J, Yao KV. Update on preventing overuse injuries in youth athletes. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep. 2022;10:248&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nancekievill D, Seaman K, Bouchard DR, Thomson AM, S&#xe9;n&#xe9;chal M. Impact of exercise with blood flow restriction on muscle hypertrophy and performance outcomes in men and women. PLoS One. 2025;20:e0301164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11774385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39874353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Abe T, Bemben MG. The anabolic benefits of venous blood flow restriction training may be induced by muscle cell swelling. Med Hypotheses. 2012;78:151&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22051111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Orientation Programme on Adolescent Health for Health Care Providers. World Health Organization; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu Y, Qiao YC, Fan YZ. Effects of compression training on muscle morphology and function in subjects: a meta-analysis. J Capital Inst Phys Educ. 2020;32:25&#x2013;34+86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luebbers PE, Witte EV, Oshel JQ, Butler MS. Effects of practical blood flow restriction training on adolescent lower-body strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2674&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29084094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Liu S, Sun P, Li W, Lian Z. Effects of different pressure blood flow restriction combined with low-intensity resistance training on lower limb muscle and cardiopulmonary function in college students. Chin J Appl Physiol. 2020;36:595&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33719265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Mar&#xed;n PJ, Zourdos MC, Bemben MG. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: a meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:1849&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21922259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, et al. ; American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:364&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatela P, Reis JF, Mendonca GV, Avela J, Mil-Homens P. Acute effects of exercise under different levels of blood-flow restriction on muscle activation and fatigue. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:985&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27017495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pignanelli C, Petrick HL, Keyvani F, et al. Low-load resistance training to task failure with and without blood flow restriction: muscular functional and structural adaptations. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2020;318:R284&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7052604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert B, Hedt C, Daum J, et al. Blood flow restriction training for the shoulder: a case for proximal benefit. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49:2716&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34110960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini Kakhak SA, Kianigul M, Haghighi AH, Nooghabi MJ, Scott BR. Performing soccer-specific training with blood flow restriction enhances physical capacities in youth soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;36:1972&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32732777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Y, Guo L. A study on the effect of running with lower limb compression on the athletic performance of tennis players. J Southwest Normal Univ (Natl Sci Ed). 2018;43:167&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie Y. Study on the effect of lower limb compression combined with running on tennis players&#x2019; training. Contemp Sports Technol. 2020;10:28&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Rotarius T, Scheuermann BW. The effect of eccentric exercise with blood flow restriction on neuromuscular activation, microvascular oxygenation, and the repeated bout effect. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:1005&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28324168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira A, Gadelha AB, Ferreira-Junior JB, et al. Session rating of perceived exertion following resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2015;35:323&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che T, Li Z, Zhao Z, Wei W, Sun K, Chen C. Effects of Low-intensity bench press combined with compression training on muscle activation and subjective fatigue. J Chengdu Univ Phys Educ. 2022;48:123&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che T, Yang T, Liang Y, Li Z. Effects of lower extremity low-intensity compression half squat training on muscle activation and subjective fatigue of core muscle groups. Sports Sci. 2021;41:59&#x2013;66,78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman EN, Elshaar R, Milligan H, et al. Proximal, distal, and contralateral effects of blood flow restriction training on the lower extremities: a randomized controlled trial. Sports Health. 2019;11:149&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30638439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K, Wei W, Zhao Z. Differences of muscle activity between blood flow-restricted and unrestricted areas during low-intensity compression training of the lower extremity. China Sports Sci Technol. 2019;55:14&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivany E, Lane DA, Dan GA, et al. Antithrombotic therapy for stroke prevention in patients with atrial fibrillation who survive an intracerebral haemorrhage: results of an EHRA survey. Europace. 2021;23:806&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Zhao Z, Wang Z, Gao J, Zhu X. Effects of short-term compression strength training on body composition and cardiovascular function in adult men. J Beijing Sport Univ. 2020;43:132&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhao Z, Wang M, Chen C, Wei W, Liang Y. Effects of 4-week compression training on body composition and maximum strength of male handball players. China Sports Sci Technol. 2019;55:37&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Ma C, Wang J, Gu Y, Gao Y. Effects of 40% of maximum oxygen uptake intensity cycling combined with blood flow restriction training on body composition and serum biomarkers of Chinese college students with obesity. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;19:168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8750492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Tomaru T, Nakajima T. Thigh muscle size and vascular function after blood flow-restricted elastic band training in older women. Oncotarget. 2016;7:33595&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5085105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27244884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Fukuda T, et al. Muscle size and arterial stiffness after blood flow-restricted low-intensity resistance training in older adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23730848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Uchida Y, et al. Effects of low-load, elastic band resistance training combined with blood flow restriction on muscle size and arterial stiffness in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2015;70:950&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24917178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Hamlin MJ, Ross JJ, Taylor R, Manimmanakorn N. Effects of low-load resistance training combined with blood flow restriction or hypoxia on muscle function and performance in netball athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2013;16:337&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22999393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1003&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28259850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A, Drobnic M, Mars T, et al. Functional and molecular adaptations of quadriceps and hamstring muscles to blood flow restricted training in patients with ACL rupture. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31:1636&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33837592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Killinger B, Lauver JD, Donovan L, Goetschius J. The effects of blood flow restriction on muscle activation and hypoxia in individuals with chronic ankle instability. J Sport Rehabil. 2020;29:633&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31094639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson AB, Owens JG, Patterson SD, Dickens JF, LeClere LE. Blood flow restriction therapy: from development to applications. Sports Med Arthrosc. 2019;27:119&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31361722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>