<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33898988</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2624-9367</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in sports and active living</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Sports Act Living</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Post-exercise Cold Water Immersion Effects on Physiological Adaptations to Resistance Training and the Underlying Mechanisms in Skeletal Muscle: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>660291</StartPage><MedlinePgn>660291</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">660291</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fspor.2021.660291</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Post-exercise cold-water immersion (CWI) is a popular recovery modality aimed at minimizing fatigue and hastening recovery following exercise. In this regard, CWI has been shown to be beneficial for accelerating post-exercise recovery of various parameters including muscle strength, muscle soreness, inflammation, muscle damage, and perceptions of fatigue. Improved recovery following an exercise session facilitated by CWI is thought to enhance the quality and training load of subsequent training sessions, thereby providing a greater training stimulus for long-term physiological adaptations. However, studies investigating the long-term effects of repeated post-exercise CWI instead suggest CWI may attenuate physiological adaptations to exercise training in a mode-specific manner. Specifically, there is evidence post-exercise CWI can attenuate improvements in physiological adaptations to resistance training, including aspects of maximal strength, power, and skeletal muscle hypertrophy, without negatively influencing endurance training adaptations. Several studies have investigated the effects of CWI on the molecular responses to resistance exercise in an attempt to identify the mechanisms by which CWI attenuates physiological adaptations to resistance training. Although evidence is limited, it appears that CWI attenuates the activation of anabolic signaling pathways and the increase in muscle protein synthesis following acute and chronic resistance exercise, which may mediate the negative effects of CWI on long-term resistance training adaptations. There are, however, a number of methodological factors that must be considered when interpreting evidence for the effects of post-exercise CWI on physiological adaptations to resistance training and the potential underlying mechanisms. This review outlines and critiques the available evidence on the effects of CWI on long-term resistance training adaptations and the underlying molecular mechanisms in skeletal muscle, and suggests potential directions for future research to further elucidate the effects of CWI on resistance training adaptations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Petersen and Fyfe.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petersen</LastName><ForeName>Aaron C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport, Victoria University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fyfe</LastName><ForeName>Jackson J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Deakin University, Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition (IPAN), School of Exercise and Nutrition Science, Geelong, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Sports Act Living</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101765780</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2624-9367</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adaptation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cold-water immersion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular responses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8060572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.660291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P., Andersen J. L., Dyhre-Poulsen P., Leffers A. M., Wagner A., Magnusson S. P., et al. (2001). A mechanism for increased contractile strength of human pennate muscle in response to strength training: changes in muscle architecture. J Physiol. 534(Pt. 2):613&#x2013;623. 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.t01-1-00613.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.t01-1-00613.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11454977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams G. R., Hather B. M., Baldwin K. M., Dudley A. G. (1993). Skeletal muscle myosin heavy chain composition and resistance training. J. Appl. Physiol. 74, 911&#x2013;915. 10.1152/jappl.1993.74.2.911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.74.2.911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8458814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikari A. S., Singh B. N., Rao K. S., Rao M. C. (2011). &#x3b1;B-crystallin, a small heat shock protein, modulates NF-&#x3ba;B activity in a phosphorylation-dependent manner and protects muscle myoblasts from TNF-&#x3b1; induced cytotoxicity. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1813, 1532&#x2013;1542. 10.1016/j.bbamcr.2011.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbamcr.2011.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21640763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asfour H. A., Allouh M. Z., Said S. R. (2018). Myogenic regulatory factors: the orchestrators of myogenesis after 30 years of discovery. Exp. Biol. Med. 243, 118&#x2013;128. 10.1177/1535370217749494</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1535370217749494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5788151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29307280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae K. A., An N. Y., Kwon Y. W., Kim C., Yoon C. S., Park S. C., et al. (2003). Muscle fibre size and capillarity in Korean diving women. Acta Physiol. Scand. 179, 167&#x2013;172. 10.1046/j.1365-201X.2003.01185.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-201X.2003.01185.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14510780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey D. M., Erith S. J., Griffin P. J., Dowson A., Brewer D. S., Gant N., et al. (2007). Influence of cold-water immersion on indices of muscle damage following prolonged intermittent shuttle running. J. Sports Sci. 25, 1163&#x2013;1170. 10.1080/02640410600982659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410600982659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17654228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett A. (2006). Using recovery modalities between training sessions in elite athletes: does it help? Sports Med. 36, 781&#x2013;796. 10.2165/00007256-200636090-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636090-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beere H. M., Wolf B. B., Cain K., Mosser D. D., Mahboubi A., Kuwana T., et al. (2000). Heat-shock protein 70 inhibits apoptosis by preventing recruitment of procaspase-9 to the Apaf-1 apoptosome. Nat. Cell Biol. 2, 469&#x2013;475. 10.1038/35019501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/35019501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10934466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G., Tipton K. D., Klein S., Wolfe R. R. (1997). An abundant supply of amino acids enhances the metabolic effect of exercise on muscle protein. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 273, E122&#x2013;129. 10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine S. C., Baehr L. M. (2014). Skeletal muscle atrophy and the E3 ubiquitin ligases MuRF1 and MAFbx/atrogin-1. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metabol. 307, E469&#x2013;E484. 10.1152/ajpendo.00204.2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00204.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4166716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25096180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine S. C., Stitt T. N., Gonzalez M., Kline W. O., Stover G. L., Bauerlein R., et al. (2001). Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy <i>in vivo</i>. Nat. Cell Biol. 3, 1014&#x2013;1019. 10.1038/ncb1101-1014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncb1101-1014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongers K. S., Fox D. K., Ebert S. M., Kunkel S. D., Dyle M. C., Bullard S. A., et al. (2013). Skeletal muscle denervation causes skeletal muscle atrophy through a pathway that involves both Gadd45a and HDAC4. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 305, E907&#x2013;E915. 10.1152/ajpendo.00380.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00380.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3798708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23941879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broatch J. R., Petersen A., Bishop J. D. (2017). Cold-water immersion following sprint interval training does not alter endurance signaling pathways or training adaptations in human skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 313, R372&#x2013;R384. 10.1152/ajpregu.00434.2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00434.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broatch J. R., Petersen A., Bishop J. D. (2018). The influence of post-exercise cold-water immersion on adaptive responses to exercise: a review of the literature. Sports Med. 48, 1369&#x2013;1387. 10.1007/s40279-018-0910-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0910-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29627884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner S. L., Jessee M. B., Mattocks K. T., Mouser J. G., Counts B. R., Dankel S. J., et al. (2017). Determining strength: a case for multiple methods of measurement. Sports Med. 47, 193&#x2013;195. 10.1007/s40279-016-0580-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0580-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson J. A., Nettleton D., Reecy M. J. (2002). Differential gene expression in the rat soleus muscle during early work overload-induced hypertrophy. Faseb J. 16, 207&#x2013;209. 10.1096/fj.01-0544fje</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.01-0544fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11744623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellani J. W., Young A. J. (2016). Human physiological responses to cold exposure: acute responses and acclimatization to prolonged exposure. Autonomic Neurosci. 196, 63&#x2013;74. 10.1016/j.autneu.2016.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2016.02.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26924539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocks M., Shaw C. S., Shepherd S. O., Fisher J. P., Ranasinghe A. M., Barker T. A., et al. (2014). Effect of resistance training on microvascular density and eNOS content in skeletal muscle of sedentary men. Microcirculation 21, 738&#x2013;746. 10.1111/micc.12155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/micc.12155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24976488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P., McGuigan M. R., Newton U. R. (2011). Developing maximal neuromuscular power: part 1&#x2013;biological basis of maximal power production. Sports Med. 41, 17&#x2013;38. 10.2165/11537690-000000000-00000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11537690-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21142282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csapo R., Gumpenberger M., Wessner B. (2020). Skeletal muscle extracellular matrix - what do we know about its composition, regulation, and physiological roles? A narrative review. Front. Physiol. 11:253. 10.3389/fphys.2020.00253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7096581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32265741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Antona G., Lanfranconi F., Pellegrino M. A., Brocca L., Adami R., Rossi R., et al. (2006). Skeletal muscle hypertrophy and structure and function of skeletal muscle fibres in male body builders. J. physiol. 570(Pt 3): 611&#x2013;27. 10.1113/jphysiol.2005.101642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2005.101642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1479884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A., Casolo A., Negro F., Scorcelletti M., Bazzucchi I., Enoka R., et al. (2019a). The increase in muscle force after 4 weeks of strength training is mediated by adaptations in motor unit recruitment and rate coding. J. Physiol. 597:1873&#x2013;87. 10.1113/JP277250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP277250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6441907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30727028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vecchio A., Negro F., Holobar A., Casolo A., Folland J. P., Felici F., et al. (2019b). You are as fast as your motor neurons: speed of recruitment and maximal discharge of motor neurons determine the maximal rate of force development in humans. J. Physiol. 597, 2445&#x2013;2456. 10.1113/JP277396</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP277396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30768687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico M. J., Kostek M. C., Johns J., Hurley B. F., Conway M. J. (2008). Can dual energy X-ray absorptiometry provide a valid assessment of changes in thigh muscle mass with strength training in older adults? Eur. J. Clin. Nutr. 62, 1372&#x2013;1378. 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd S. L., Hain B., Senf S. M., Judge R. A. (2009). Hsp27 inhibits IKK&#x3b2;-induced NF-&#x3ba;B activity and skeletal muscle atrophy. FASEB J. 23, 3415&#x2013;3423. 10.1096/fj.08-124602</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.08-124602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2747674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dokladny K., Myers O. B., Moseley L. P. (2015). Heat shock response and autophagy&#x2014;cooperation and control. Autophagy 11, 200&#x2013;213. 10.1080/15548627.2015.1009776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15548627.2015.1009776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4502786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25714619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dons B., Bollerup K., Bonde-Petersen F., Hancke S. (1979). The effect of weight-lifting exercise related to muscle fiber composition and muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 40, 95&#x2013;106. 10.1007/BF00421155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00421155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">428373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond M. J., Fry C. S., Glynn E. L., Dreyer H. C., Dhanani S., Timmerman K. L., et al. (2009). Rapamycin administration in humans blocks the contraction-induced increase in skeletal muscle protein synthesis. J. Physiol. 587(Pt 7):1535&#x2013;46. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.163816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.163816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Souza R. F., Zeng N., Markworth J. F., Figueiredo V. C., Roberts L. A., Raastad T., et al. (2018). Divergent effects of cold water immersion versus active recovery on skeletal muscle fiber type and angiogenesis in young men. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 314, R824&#x2013;R833. 10.1152/ajpregu.00421.2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00421.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29466686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp J. E., Hatfield D. L., Sherman A., Lee E. C., Kraemer J. W. (2019). Cold-water immersion blunts and delays increases in circulating testosterone and cytokines post-resistance exercise. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 119, 1901&#x2013;1907. 10.1007/s00421-019-04178-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-019-04178-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31222379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert S. M., Dyle M. C., Kunkel S. D., Bullard S. A., Bongers K. S., Fox D. K., et al. (2012). Stress-induced skeletal muscle Gadd45a expression reprograms myonuclei and causes muscle atrophy. J. Biol. Chem. 287, 27290&#x2013;27301. 10.1074/jbc.M112.374777</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M112.374777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3431665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22692209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine R. M., Jones D. A., Maffulli N., Williams A. G., Stewart C. E., Degens H. (2011). What causes <i>in vivo</i> muscle specific tension to increase following resistance training?
Exp. Physiol. 96, 145&#x2013;155. 10.1113/expphysiol.2010.053975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2010.053975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20889606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmarck B., Andersen J. L., Olsen S., Richter E. A., Mizuno M., Kjaer M. (2001). Timing of postexercise protein intake is important for muscle hypertrophy with resistance training in elderly humans. J. Physiol. 535(Pt 1):301&#x2013;311. 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00301.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00301.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11507179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eston R., Peters D. (1999). Effects of cold water immersion on the symptoms of exercise-induced muscle damage. J. Sports Sci. 17, 231&#x2013;238. 10.1080/026404199366136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404199366136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10362390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo V. C., Caldow M. K., Massie V., Markworth J. F., Cameron-Smith D., Blazevich J. A. (2015). Ribosome biogenesis adaptation in resistance training-induced human skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 309, E72&#x2013;E83. 10.1152/ajpendo.00050.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00050.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25968575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo V. C., Roberts L. A., Markworth J. F., Barnett M. P., Coombes J. S., Raastad T., et al. (2016). Impact of resistance exercise on ribosome biogenesis is acutely regulated by post-exercise recovery strategies. Physiol. Rep. 4:e12670. 10.14814/phy2.12670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26818586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foldvari M., Clark M., Laviolette L. C., Bernstein M. A., Kaliton D., Castaneda C., et al. (2000). Association of muscle power with functional status in community-dwelling elderly women. J. Gerontol. Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 55, M192&#x2013;M199. 10.1093/gerona/55.4.M192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/55.4.M192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10811148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland J. P., Williams A. G. (2007). The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 37, 145&#x2013;168. 10.2165/00007256-200737020-00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737020-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala M. S., Jajtner A. R., Townsend J. R., Gonzalez A. M., Wells A. J., Oliveira L. P., et al. (2015). Leukocyte IGF-1 receptor expression during muscle recovery. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 47, 92&#x2013;99. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000392</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24870578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frohlich M., Faude O., Klein M., Pieter A., Emrich E., Meyer T. (2014). Strength training adaptations after cold-water immersion. J. Strength Cond Res. 28, 2628&#x2013;2633. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24552795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry C. S., Lee J. D., Jackson J. R., Kirby T. J., Stasko S. A., Liu H., et al. (2014). Regulation of the muscle fiber microenvironment by activated satellite cells during hypertrophy. FASEB J. 28, 1654&#x2013;1665. 10.1096/fj.13-239426</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.13-239426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24376025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs C. J., Kouw I. W. K., Churchward-Venne T. A., Smeets J. S. J., Senden J. M., Lichtenbelt W., et al. (2020). Postexercise cooling impairs muscle protein synthesis rates in recreational athletes. J. Physiol. 598, 755&#x2013;772. 10.1113/JP278996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP278996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7028023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31788800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S., Rasmussen B. B., Cadenas J. G., Grady J. J., Volpi E. (2006). Effect of insulin on human skeletal muscle protein synthesis is modulated by insulin-induced changes in muscle blood flow and amino acid availability. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 291, E745&#x2013;E754. 10.1152/ajpendo.00271.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00271.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2804964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16705054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe J. J., Bishop D. J., Bartlett J. D., Hanson E. D., Anderson M. J., Garnham A. P., et al. (2018). Enhanced skeletal muscle ribosome biogenesis, yet attenuated mTORC1 and ribosome biogenesis-related signalling, following short-term concurrent versus single-mode resistance training. Sci. Rep. 8:560. 10.1038/s41598-017-18887-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-18887-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5766515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29330460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe J. J., Broatch J. R., Trewin A. J., Hanson E. D., Argus C. K., Garnham A. P., et al. (2019). Cold water immersion attenuates anabolic signaling and skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy, but not strength gain, following whole-body resistance training. J. Appl. Physiol. 127, 1403&#x2013;1418. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00127.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00127.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31513450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goll D. E., Neti G., Mares S. W., Thompson F. V. (2008). Myofibrillar protein turnover: the proteasome and the calpains. J. Anim. Sci. 86(14 Suppl):E19&#x2013;E35. 10.2527/jas.2007-0395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/jas.2007-0395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17709792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez A. M., Fragala M. S., Jajtner A. R., Townsend J. R., Wells A. J., Beyer K. S., et al. (2014a). Effects of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate free acid and cold water immersion on expression of CR3 and MIP-1beta following resistance exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol/ 306, R483&#x2013;R489. 10.1152/ajpregu.00542.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00542.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24500432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez A. M., Stout J. R., Jajtner A. R., Townsend J. R., Wells A. J., Beyer K. S., et al. (2014b). Effects of beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate free acid and cold water immersion on post-exercise markers of muscle damage. Amino Acids 46, 1501&#x2013;1511. 10.1007/s00726-014-1722-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-014-1722-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24639242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodall S., Howatson G. (2008). The effects of multiple cold water immersions on indices of muscle damage. J. Sports Sci. Med. 7, 235&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman C. A., Frey J. W., Mabrey D. M., Jacobs B. L., Lincoln H. C., You J. S., et al. (2011). The role of skeletal muscle mTOR in the regulation of mechanical load-induced growth. J. Physiol. 589(Pt 22):5485&#x2013;5501. 10.1113/jphysiol.2011.218255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2011.218255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3240886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21946849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregson W., Black M. A., Jones H., Milson J., Morton J., Dawson B., et al. (2011). Influence of cold water immersion on limb and cutaneous blood flow at rest. Am. J. Sports Med. 39, 1316&#x2013;1323. 10.1177/0363546510395497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510395497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21335348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grisbrook T. L., Elliott C. M., Edgar D. W., Wallman K. E., Wood F. M., Reid L. S. (2013). Burn-injured adults with long term functional impairments demonstrate the same response to resistance training as uninjured controls. Burns 39, 680&#x2013;686. 10.1016/j.burns.2012.09.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.burns.2012.09.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23021312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halson S. L., Bartram J., West N., Stephens J., Argus C. K., Driller M. W., et al. (2014). Does hydrotherapy help or hinder adaptation to training in competitive cyclists? Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 46, 1631&#x2013;1639. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24504431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun C. T., Vann C. G., Roberts B. M., Vigotsky A. D., Schoenfeld B. J., Roberts D. M. (2019). A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol. 10:247. 10.3389/fphys.2019.00247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6423469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloway T. M., Snijders T., Van Kranenburg J. L. J. C., Van L.oon, Verdijk L. B. (2018). Temporal response of angiogenesis and hypertrophy to resistance training in young men. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 50, 36&#x2013;45. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28846563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houston M. E., Froese E. A., Valeriote S. P., Green H. J., Ranney A. D. (1983). Muscle performance, morphology and metabolic capacity during strength training and detraining: a one leg model. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 51, 25&#x2013;35. 10.1007/BF00952534</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00952534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6684028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howatson G., Goodall S., van Someren A. K. (2009). The influence of cold water immersions on adaptation following a single bout of damaging exercise. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 105, 615&#x2013;621. 10.1007/s00421-008-0941-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-008-0941-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19034491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi J. J., Ahtiainen J. P., Kaasalainen T., P&#xf6;llanen E., Hakkinen K., Alen M., et al. (2007). Postexercise myostatin and activin IIb mRNA levels: effects of strength training. Med. Sci. Sports Exercise 39, 289&#x2013;297. 10.1249/01.mss.0000241650.15006.6e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000241650.15006.6e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihsan M., Watson G., Lipski M., Abbiss R. C. (2013). Influence of postexercise cooling on muscle oxygenation and blood volume changes. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 45, 876&#x2013;882. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31827e13a2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31827e13a2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingram J., Dawson B., Goodman C., Wallman K., Beilby J. (2009). Effect of water immersion methods on post-exercise recovery from simulated team sport exercise. J. Sci. Med. Sport. 12, 417&#x2013;421. 10.1016/j.jsams.2007.12.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2007.12.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18547863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jajtner A. R., Hoffman J. R., Gonzalez A. M., Worts P. R., Fragala M. S., Stout R. J. (2015). Comparison of the effects of electrical stimulation and cold-water immersion on muscle soreness after resistance exercise. J. Sport Rehabil. 24, 99&#x2013;108. 10.1123/jsr.2013-0113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2013-0113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24622577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakeman J. R., Macrae R., Eston R. (2009). A single 10-min bout of cold-water immersion therapy after strenuous plyometric exercise has no beneficial effect on recovery from the symptoms of exercise-induced muscle damage. Ergonomics 52, 456&#x2013;460. 10.1080/00140130802707733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140130802707733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19401897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh T. J., Escobedo J. (2004). Cytoskeletal disruption and small heat shock protein translocation immediately after lengthening contractions. Am. J. Physiol. Cell Physiol. 286, C713&#x2013;C722. 10.1152/ajpcell.00341.2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00341.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14627610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W. J., Ratamess N. A. (2004). Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 36, 674&#x2013;688. 10.1249/01.MSS.0000121945.36635.61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000121945.36635.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruschitz R., Wallner-Liebmann S. J., Hamlin M. J., Moser M., Ludvik B., Schnedl W. J., et al. (2013). Detecting body fat-A weighty problem BMI versus subcutaneous fat patterns in athletes and non-athletes. PLoS ONE 8:e72002. 10.1371/journal.pone.0072002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0072002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3753354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku Z., Yang J., Menon V., Thomason B. D. (1995). Decreased polysomal HSP-70 may slow polypeptide elongation during skeletal muscle atrophy. Am. J. Physiol. 268(6 Pt 1):C1369&#x2013;C1374. 10.1152/ajpcell.1995.268.6.C1369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1995.268.6.C1369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7611354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H., Natsui H., Akimoto T., Yanagi K., Ohshima N., Kono I. (2005). Effects of cryotherapy after contusion using real-time intravital microscopy. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 37, 1093&#x2013;1098. 10.1249/01.mss.0000169611.21671.2e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000169611.21671.2e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16015124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J. H., Han E. Y., Kang M. S., Kawano F., Kim H. J., Ohira Y., et al. (2004). Effects of 20-week intermittent cold-water-immersion on phenotype and myonuclei in single fibers of rat hindlimb muscles. Jpn. J. Physiol. 54, 331&#x2013;337. 10.2170/jjphysiol.54.331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2170/jjphysiol.54.331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15631688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine J. A., Abboud L., Barry M., Reed J. E., Sheedy P. F., Jensen D. M. (2000). Measuring leg muscle and fat mass in humans: comparison of CT and dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry. J. Appl. Physiol. 88, 452&#x2013;456. 10.1152/jappl.2000.88.2.452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.2.452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10658010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindquist S. (1986). The heat-shock response. Annu. Rev. Biochem. 55, 1151&#x2013;1191. 10.1146/annurev.bi.55.070186.005443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.bi.55.070186.005443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2427013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke J. P., Buckner S. L., Dankel S. J., Abe T. (2019). Exercise-induced changes in muscle size do not contribute to exercise-induced changes in muscle strength. Sports Med. 49, 987&#x2013;991. 10.1007/s40279-019-01106-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01106-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis E., Raue U., Yang Y., Jemiolo B., Trappe S. (2007). Time course of proteolytic, cytokine, and myostatin gene expression after acute exercise in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 103, 1744&#x2013;1751. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00679.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00679.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey A. L., Kjaer M. (2017). Connective tissue regeneration in skeletal muscle after eccentric contraction-induced injury. J. Appl. Physiol. 122, 533&#x2013;540. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00577.2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00577.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27562842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maden-Wilkinson T. M., Balshaw T. G., Massey G. J., Folland P. J. (2021). Muscle architecture and morphology as determinants of explosive strength. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 121, 1099&#x2013;1110. 10.1007/s00421-020-04585-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-020-04585-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7966212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maden-Wilkinson T. M., Degens H., Jones D. A., McPhee S. J. (2013). Comparison of MRI and DXA to measure muscle size and age-related atrophy in thigh muscles. J. Musculoskelet. Neuronal Interact 13, 320&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23989253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestroni L., Read P., Bishop C., Papadopoulos K., Suchomel T. J., Comfort P., et al. (2020). The benefits of strength training on musculoskeletal system health: practical applications for interdisciplinary care. Sports Med. 50, 1431&#x2013;1450. 10.1007/s40279-020-01309-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01309-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32564299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malta E. S., Dutra Y. M., Broatch J. R., Bishop D. J., Zagatto M. A. (2020). The effects of regular cold-water immersion use on training-induced changes in strength and endurance performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 51:161&#x2013;74. 10.1007/s40279-020-01362-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01362-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mawhinney C., Jones H., Joo C. H., Low D. A., Green D. J., Gregson W. (2013). Influence of cold-water immersion on limb and cutaneous blood flow after exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 45, 2277&#x2013;2285. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31829d8e2e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31829d8e2e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24240118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mawhinney C., Jones H., Low D. A., Green D. J., Howatson G., Gregson W. (2017). Influence of cold-water immersion on limb blood flow after resistance exercise. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 17, 519&#x2013;529. 10.1080/17461391.2017.1279222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1279222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28100130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy J. J., Mula J., Miyazaki M., Erfani R., Garrison K., Farooqui A. B., et al. (2011). Effective fiber hypertrophy in satellite cell-depleted skeletal muscle. Development 138, 3657&#x2013;3666. 10.1242/dev.068858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dev.068858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milan G., Romanello V., Pescatore F., Armani A., Paik J.-H., Frasson L., et al. (2015). Regulation of autophagy and the ubiquitin&#x2013;proteasome system by the FoxO transcriptional network during muscle atrophy. Nat. Communicat. 6:6670. 10.1038/ncomms7670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms7670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4403316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25858807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery P. G., Pyne D. B., Cox A. J., Hopkins W. G., Minahan C. L., Hunt H. P. (2008). Muscle damage, inflammation, and recovery interventions during a 3-day basketball tournament. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 8, 241&#x2013;250. 10.1080/17461390802251844</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461390802251844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrissey M. C., Harman E. A., Johnson J. M. (1995). Resistance training modes: specificity and effectiveness. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 27, 648&#x2013;660. 10.1249/00005768-199505000-00006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-199505000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7674868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici M. V., Hoppeler H., Kayser B., Landoni L., Claassen H., Gavardi C., et al. (1996). Human quadriceps cross-sectional area, torque and neural activation during 6 months strength training. Acta Physiol. Scand. 157, 175&#x2013;186. 10.1046/j.1365-201X.1996.483230000.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-201X.1996.483230000.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8800357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble E. G., Milne K. J., Melling W. C. (2008). Heat shock proteins and exercise: a primer. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 33, 1050&#x2013;1065. 10.1139/H08-069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/H08-069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18923583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohnishi N., Yamane M., Uchiyama N., Shirasawa S., Kosaka M., Shiono H., et al. (2004). Adaptive changes in muscular performance and circulation by resistance training with regular cold application. J. Thermal Biol. 29:839&#x2013;843. 10.1016/j.jtherbio.2004.08.069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtherbio.2004.08.069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D., Leveritt M., Lonergan A., Abernethy P. (2001). Adaptation to chronic eccentric exercise in humans: the influence of contraction velocity. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 85, 466&#x2013;471. 10.1007/s004210100467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210100467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11606016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D. J., Quigley B. M. (1997). Effect of cryotherapy on muscle soreness and strength following eccentric exercise. Int. J. Sports Med. 18, 588&#x2013;593. 10.1055/s-2007-972686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-972686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9443590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pansarasa O., Rinaldi C., Parente V., Miotti D., Capodaglio P, Bottinelli R. (2009). Resistance training of long duration modulates force and unloaded shortening velocity of single muscle fibres of young women. J. Electromyogr. Kinesiol. 19:e290&#x2013;e300. 10.1016/j.jelekin.2008.07.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2008.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18801662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parouty J., Al Haddad H., Quod M., Lepretre P. M., Ahmaidi S., Buchheit M. (2010). Effect of cold water immersion on 100-m sprint performance in well-trained swimmers. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 109, 483&#x2013;490. 10.1007/s00421-010-1381-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1381-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20162301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G., Vissing K., Kalhovde J. M., Ugelstad I., Bayer M. L., Kadi F., et al. (2007). Maximal eccentric exercise induces a rapid accumulation of small heat shock proteins on myofibrils and a delayed HSP70 response in humans. Am. J. Physiol. Regulat. Integrat. Comparat. Physiol. 293, R844&#x2013;R853. 10.1152/ajpregu.00677.2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00677.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17522120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake J., Peiffer J. J., Abbiss C. R., Nosaka K., Okutsu M., Laursen P. B., et al. (2008). Body temperature and its effect on leukocyte mobilization, cytokines and markers of neutrophil activation during and after exercise. Eur. J. Appl Physiol. 102, 391&#x2013;401. 10.1007/s00421-007-0598-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0598-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17962974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake J. M., Markworth J. F., Cumming K. T., Aas S. N., Roberts L. A., Raastad T., et al. (2020). The effects of cold water immersion and active recovery on molecular factors that regulate growth and remodeling of skeletal muscle after resistance exercise. Front Physiol. 11:737. 10.3389/fphys.2020.00737</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7339943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32695024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake J. M., Roberts L. A., Figueiredo V. C., Egner I., Krog S., Aas S. N., et al. (2017). The effects of cold water immersion and active recovery on inflammation and cell stress responses in human skeletal muscle after resistance exercise. J. Physiol. 595, 695&#x2013;711. 10.1113/JP272881</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP272881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5285720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27704555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiffer J. J., Abbiss C. R., Watson G., Nosaka K., Laursen B. P. (2009). Effect of cold-water immersion duration on body temperature and muscle function. J. Sports Sci. 27, 987&#x2013;993. 10.1080/02640410903207424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410903207424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19847682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella J. K., Kim J., Mayhew D. L., Cross J. M., Bamman M. M. (2008). Potent myofiber hypertrophy during resistance training in humans is associated with satellite cell-mediated myonuclear addition: a cluster analysis. J. Appl. Physiol. 104, 1736&#x2013;1742. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01215.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01215.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrofsky J. S., Laymon M. (2009). Heat transfer to deep tissue: the effect of body fat and heating modality. J. Med. Eng. Technol. 33, 337&#x2013;348. 10.1080/03091900802069547</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03091900802069547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19440919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Tipton K. D., Aarsland A., Wolf S. E., Wolfe R. R. (1997). Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 273, E99&#x2013;E107. 10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E99</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E99</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poppendieck W., Wegmann M., Hecksteden A., Darup A., Schimpchen J, Skorski S., et al. (2020). Does cold-water immersion after strength training attenuate training adaptation? Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 20:1&#x2013;7. 10.1123/ijspp.2019-0965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2019-0965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pournot H., Bieuzen F., Duffield R., Lepretre P. M., Cozzolino C., Hausswirth C. (2011). Short term effects of various water immersions on recovery from exhaustive intermittent exercise. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 111, 1287&#x2013;1295. 10.1007/s00421-010-1754-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1754-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21132438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts L. A., Nosaka K., Coombes J. S., Peake M. J. (2014). Cold water immersion enhances recovery of submaximal muscle function after resistance exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 307, R998&#x2013;R1008. 10.1152/ajpregu.00180.2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00180.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25121612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts L. A., Raastad T., Markworth J. F., Figueiredo V. C., Egner I. M., Shield A., et al. (2015). Post-exercise cold water immersion attenuates acute anabolic signalling and long-term adaptations in muscle to strength training. J. Physiol. 593, 4285&#x2013;4301. 10.1113/JP270570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP270570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26174323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowsell G. J., Coutts A. J., Reaburn P., Hill-Haas S. (2011). Effect of post-match cold-water immersion on subsequent match running performance in junior soccer players during tournament play. J. Sports Sci. 29, 1&#x2013;6. 10.1080/02640414.2010.512640</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2010.512640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21077001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford O. M., Jones D. A. (1986). The role of learning and coordination in strength training. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 55, 100&#x2013;105. 10.1007/BF00422902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00422902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S., Reggiani C. (2011). Fiber types in mammalian skeletal muscles. Physiol. Rev. 91, 1447&#x2013;1531. 10.1152/physrev.00031.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00031.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22013216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellwood K. L., Brukner P., Williams D., Nicol A., Hinman R. (2007). Ice-water immersion and delayed-onset muscle soreness: a randomised controlled trial. Br. J. Sports Med. 41, 392&#x2013;397. 10.1136/bjsm.2006.033985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2006.033985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17261562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senf S. M., Dodd S. L., McClung J. M., Judge R. A. (2008). Hsp70 overexpression inhibits NF-&#x3ba;B and Foxo3a transcriptional activities and prevents skeletal muscle atrophy. FASEB J. 22, 3836&#x2013;3845. 10.1096/fj.08-110163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.08-110163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6137947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18644837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skurvydas A., Sipaviciene S., Krutulyte G., Gailiuniene A., Stasiulis A., Mamkus G., et al. (2006). Cooling leg muscles affects dynamics of indirect indicators of skeletal muscle damage. J. Back Musculoskel. Rehabil. 19, 141&#x2013;151. 10.3233/BMR-2006-19406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-2006-19406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith D. J. (2003). A framework for understanding the training process leading to elite performance. Sports Med. 33, 1103&#x2013;1126. 10.2165/00007256-200333150-00003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200333150-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14719980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T., Smeets J. S., van Kranenburg J., Kies A. K., van Loon L. J., Verdijk B. L. (2016). Changes in myonuclear domain size do not precede muscle hypertrophy during prolonged resistance-type exercise training. Acta Physiol. 216, 231&#x2013;239. 10.1111/apha.12609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.12609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26407634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stacey D. L., Gibala M. J., Martin Ginis K. A., Timmons W. B. (2010). Effects of recovery method after exercise on performance, immune changes, psychological outcomes. J. Orthop. Sports Phys. Ther. 40, 656&#x2013;665. 10.2519/jospt.2010.3224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2010.3224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley J., Buchheit M., Peake M. J. (2012). The effect of post-exercise hydrotherapy on subsequent exercise performance and heart rate variability. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 112, 951&#x2013;961. 10.1007/s00421-011-2052-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2052-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21710292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron R. S., Karapondo D. L., Kraemer W. J., Fry A. C., Gordon S. E., Falkel J. E., et al. (1994). Skeletal muscle adaptations during early phase of heavy-resistance training in men and women. J. Appl. Physiol. 76, 1247&#x2013;1255. 10.1152/jappl.1994.76.3.1247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1994.76.3.1247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8005869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron R. S., Malicky E. S., Leonardi M. J., Falkel J. E., Hagerman F. C., Dudley A. G. (1990). Muscle hypertrophy and fast fiber type conversions in heavy resistance-trained women. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 60, 71&#x2013;79. 10.1007/BF00572189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00572189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2311599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel T. J., Nimphius S., Stone H. M. (2016). The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med. 46, 1419&#x2013;1449. 10.1007/s40279-016-0486-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0486-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber C. B., Vigotsky A., Nuckols G., Haun T. C. (2019). Exercise-induced myofibrillar hypertrophy is a contributory cause of gains in muscle strength. Sports Med. 49:993&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s40279-019-01107-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01107-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31016546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorstensson A. B., Hult&#xe9;n von D&#xf6;beln W., Karlsson J. (1976). Effect of strength training on enzyme activities and fibre characteristics in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol. Scand. 96, 392&#x2013;398. 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1976.tb10207.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1976.tb10207.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">179278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmerman K. L., Lee J. L., Fujita S., Dhanani S., Dreyer H. C., Fry C. S., et al. (2010). Pharmacological vasodilation improves insulin-stimulated muscle protein anabolism but not glucose utilization in older adults. Diabetes 59, 2764&#x2013;2771. 10.2337/db10-0415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db10-0415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20724580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trappe T. A., White F., Lambert C. P., Cesar D., Hellerstein M., Evans J. W. (2002). Effect of ibuprofen and acetaminophen on postexercise muscle protein synthesis. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metabol. 282, E551&#x2013;E556. 10.1152/ajpendo.00352.2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00352.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11832356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urso M. L. (2013). Anti-inflammatory interventions and skeletal muscle injury: benefit or detriment? J. Appl. Physiol. 115, 920&#x2013;928. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00036.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00036.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23539314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaile J., Halson S., Gill N., Dawson B. (2008). Effect of hydrotherapy on the signs and symptoms of delayed onset muscle soreness. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 102, 447&#x2013;455. 10.1007/s00421-007-0605-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0605-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17978833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconsuelo A., Milanesi L, Boland R. (2010). Participation of HSP27 in the antiapoptotic action of 17beta-estradiol in skeletal muscle cells. Cell Stress Chaperones 15, 183&#x2013;192. 10.1007/s12192-009-0132-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12192-009-0132-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2866980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk L. B., Snijders T., Holloway T. M. J, Ank V. L., et al. (2016). Resistance training increases skeletal muscle capillarization in healthy older men. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 48, 2157&#x2013;2164. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27327032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versey N. G., Halson S. L., Dawson T. B. (2013). Water immersion recovery for athletes: effect on exercise performance and practical recommendations. Sports Med. 43, 1101&#x2013;1130. 10.1007/s40279-013-0063-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0063-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23743793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K., McGee S. L., Farup J., Kj&#xf8;lhede T., Vendelbo M. H., Jessen N. (2013). Differentiated mTOR but not AMPK signaling after strength vs endurance exercise in training-accustomed individuals. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 23, 355&#x2013;366. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01395.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01395.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters T. J., Constable S. H. (1993). Intermittent cold exposure causes a muscle-specific shift in the fiber type composition in rats. J. Appl. Physiol. 75, 264&#x2013;267. 10.1152/jappl.1993.75.1.264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.75.1.264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8376271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Yu T., Huang P. (2016). Post-translational modifications of FOXO family proteins (Review). Mol. Med. Rep. 14, 4931&#x2013;4941. 10.3892/mmr.2016.5867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/mmr.2016.5867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27779663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcock I. M., Cronin J. B., Hing A. W. (2006). Physiological response to water immersion: a method for sport recovery? Sports Med. 36, 747&#x2013;765. 10.2165/00007256-200636090-00003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200636090-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson S. B., Phillips S. M., Atherton P. J., Patel R., Yarasheski K. E., Tarnopolsky M. A., et al. (2008). Differential effects of resistance and endurance exercise in the fed state on signalling molecule phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human muscle. J. Physiol. 586, 3701&#x2013;3717. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.153916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.153916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2538832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18556367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamane M., Ohnishi N., Matsumoto T. (2015). Does regular post-exercise cold application attenuate trained muscle adaptation? Int. J. Sports Med. 36, 647&#x2013;653. 10.1055/s-0034-1398652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0034-1398652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25760154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamane M., Teruya H., Nakano M., Ogai R., Ohnishi N., Kosaka M. (2006). Post-exercise leg and forearm flexor muscle cooling in humans attenuates endurance and resistance training effects on muscle performance and on circulatory adaptation. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 96, 572&#x2013;580. 10.1007/s00421-005-0095-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-005-0095-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16372177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T., Delafontaine P. (2020). Mechanisms of IGF-1-mediated regulation of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and atrophy. Cells 9:1970. 10.3390/cells9091970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells9091970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7564605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32858949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Thompson J. R. (1997). Regulation of protein turnover by glutamine in heat-shocked skeletal myotubes. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1357, 234&#x2013;242. 10.1016/S0167-4889(97)00035-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0167-4889(97)00035-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9223627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>