<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35438660</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does Varying Resistance Exercises Promote Superior Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength Gains? A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1753</StartPage><EndPage>1762</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1753-1762</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004258</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kassiano, W, Nunes, JP, Costa, B, Ribeiro, AS, Schoenfeld, BJ, and Cyrino, ES. Does varying resistance exercises promote superior muscle hypertrophy and strength gains? A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 36(6): 1753-1762, 2022-Fitness professionals routinely employ a variety of resistance training exercises in program design as a strategy to enhance muscular adaptations. However, it remains uncertain whether such an approach offers advantages over a fixed-exercise selection. The objective of this review was to review the effects of exercise variation on muscle hypertrophy and strength. A search of the literature was conducted using PubMed/MEDLINE, Scopus, and Web of Science databases. Eight studies were identified as meeting inclusion criteria. The combined total sample of the studies was N = 241, comprising all young men. The methodological quality of included studies was considered "good" and "excellent" based on the Physiotherapy Evidence Database Scale. The available studies indicate that varying exercise selection can influence muscle hypertrophy and strength gains. Some degree of systematic variation seems to enhance regional hypertrophic adaptations and maximize dynamic strength, whereas excessive, random variation may compromise muscular gains. We conclude that exercise variation should be approached systematically with a focus on applied anatomical and biomechanical constructs; on the contrary, employing different exercises that provide a redundant stimulus, as well as excessive rotation of different exercises (i.e., high frequency of change), may actually hinder muscular adaptations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassiano</LastName><ForeName>Witalo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Bruna</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, University of Northern of Paran&#xe0;, Londrina, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Sciences Department, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, State University of Londrina, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35438660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202206000-00040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerenhouts D, D'Hondt E. Using machines or free weights for resistance training in novice males? A randomized parallel trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health 17: 7848, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J. Nonuniform response of skeletal muscle to heavy resistance training: Can bodybuilders induce regional muscle hypertrophy? J Strength Cond Res 14: 102&#x2013;113, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, B&#xfc;ttner F, Andrade R, et al. Implementing the 27 PRISMA 2020 statement items for systematic reviews in the sport and exercise medicine, musculoskeletal rehabilitation and sports science fields: The PERSiST (implementing Prisma in exercise, rehabilitation, sport medicine and SporTs science) guidance. Br J Sports Med 56: 175&#x2013;195, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Schoenfeld BJ, Torres-Unda J, Santos-Concejero J, Balsalobre-Fernandez C. The effects of exercise variation in muscle thickness, maximal strength and motivation in resistance trained men. PLoS One 14: e0226989, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand&#xe3;o L, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, et al. Varying the order of combinations of single- and multi-joint exercises differentially affects resistance training adaptations. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1254&#x2013;1263, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Determining strength: A case for multiple methods of measurement. Sports Med 47: 193&#x2013;195, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Kuehne TE, Yitzchaki N, et al. The generality of strength adaptation. J Trainol 8: 5&#x2013;8, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Junior RM, Truffi G, et al. Is stronger better? Influence of a strength phase followed by a hypertrophy phase on muscular adaptations in resistance-trained men. Res Sports Med 29: 536&#x2013;546, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves SFN, Rocha-J&#xda;nior VA, Encarna&#xc7;&#xc3;o IGA, et al. Effects of horizontal and incline bench press on neuromuscular adaptations in untrained young men. Int J Exerc Sci 13: 859&#x2013;872, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Collier SR, Manini TM, Ploutz-Snyder LL. Sex differences in muscle fatigability and activation patterns of the human quadriceps femoris. Eur J Appl Physiol 94: 196&#x2013;206, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson PM, Hubal MJ. Exercise-induced muscle damage in humans. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 81: S52&#x2013;S69, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JA. Power primer. Psychol Bull 112: 155&#x2013;159, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa BDV, Kassiano W, Nunes JP, et al. Does performing different resistance exercises for the same muscle group induce non-homogeneous hypertrophy? Int J Sports Med 42: 803&#x2013;811, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa BDV, Kassiano W, Nunes JP, et al. Does varying resistance exercises for the same muscle group promote greater strength gains? J Strength Cond Res 2021. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duehring MD, Feldmann CR, Ebben WP. Strength and conditioning practices of United States high school strength and conditioning coaches. J Strength Cond Res 23: 2188&#x2013;2203, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2691&#x2013;2703, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JW. Periodized resistance training for enhancing skeletal muscle hypertrophy and strength: A mini-review. Front Physiol 10: 13, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Steele J, Smith D, Gentil P. Periodization for optimizing strength and hypertrophy: The forgotten variables. J Trainol 7: 10&#x2013;15, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3085&#x2013;3092, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA. Training, supplementation, and pharmacological practices of competitive male bodybuilders across training phases. J Strength Cond Res 36: 963&#x2013;970, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1609&#x2013;1617, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, et al. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol 10: 247, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK. Sex differences in human fatigability: Mechanisms and insight to physiological responses. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 210: 768&#x2013;789, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK. Sex differences in fatigability of dynamic contractions. Exp Physiol 101: 250&#x2013;255, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Yata H. Effects of squat training with different depths on lower limb muscle volumes. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 1933&#x2013;1942, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Teo WP, Drinkwater EJ, Kendall K, Haff GG. The acute neuromuscular responses to cluster set resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 49: 1861&#x2013;1877, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Meng H, Yuhang W, et al. Greater hamstrings muscle hypertrophy but similar damage protection after training at long versus short muscle lengths. Med Sci Sports Exerc 53: 825&#x2013;837, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster DT, Cronin J, McGuigan M. Forms of variable resistance training. Strength Cond J 31: 52&#x2013;63, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehls K, Grubbs B, Jin Y, Coons J. Electromyography comparison of sex differences during the back squat. J Strength Cond Res 36: 310&#x2013;313, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods 11: 364&#x2013;386, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigro F, Bartolomei S. A comparison between the squat and the deadlift for lower body strength and power training. J Hum Kinet 73: 145&#x2013;152, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Costa BDV, Kassiano W, et al. Different foot positioning during calf training to induce portion-specific gastrocnemius muscle hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2347&#x2013;2351, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Grgic J, Cunha PM, et al. What influence does resistance exercise order have on muscular strength gains and muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci 21: 149&#x2013;157, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Kassiano W, Costa BDV, et al. Equating resistance-training volume between programs focused on muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med 51: 1171&#x2013;1178, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Ribeiro AS, Schoenfeld BJ, Cyrino ES. Comment on: &#x201c;Comparison of periodized and non-periodized resistance training on maximal strength: A meta-analysis&#x201d;. Sports Med 48: 491&#x2013;494, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 372: n71, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa GF, Lima FV, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Partial range of motion training elicits favorable improvements in muscular adaptations when carried out at long muscle lengths. Eur J Sport Sci: 1&#x2013;11, 2021. Epub ahead of print.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauch JT, Ugrinowitsch C, Barakat CI, et al. Auto-regulated exercise selection training regimen produces small increases in lean body mass and maximal strength adaptations in strength-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1133&#x2013;1140, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi FE, Schoenfeld BJ, Ocetnik S, et al. Strength, body composition, and functional outcomes in the squat versus leg press exercises. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 58: 263&#x2013;270, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Yoshida R, Ryosuke K, et al. Elbow joint angles in elbow flexor unilateral resistance exercise training determine its effects on muscle strength and thickness of trained and non-trained arms. Front Physiol 12: 734509, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Accentuating muscular development through active insufficiency and passive tension. Strength Cond J 24: 20&#x2013;22, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Fisher J, Grgic J, et al. Resistance training recomendations to maximize muscle hypertrophy in an athletic population: Position stand of the IUSCA. Int J Strength Cond 1: 1&#x2013;30, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J. Effects of range of motion on muscle development during resistance training interventions: A systematic review. SAGE Open Med 8: 2050312120901559, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shurley JP, Ednie AJ, Rudebeck TJ. Strength and conditioning practices of head coaches of male and female interscholastic sport teams. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1894&#x2013;1902, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Potteiger JA, Pierce KC, et al. Comparison of the effects of three different weight-training programs on the one repetition maximum squat. J Strength Cond Res 14: 332&#x2013;337, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: Training considerations. Sports Med 48: 765&#x2013;785, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valamatos MJ, Tavares F, Santos RM, Veloso AP, Mil-Homens P. Influence of full range of motion vs. equalized partial range of motion training on muscle architecture and mechanical properties. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 1969&#x2013;1983, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Hartmann H, Sander A, et al. The impact of back squat and leg-press exercises on maximal strength and speed-strength parameters. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1205&#x2013;1212, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youdas JW, Hollman JH, Hitchcock JR, Hoyme GJ, Johnsen JJ. Comparison of hamstring and quadriceps femoris electromyographic activity between men and women during a single-limb squat on both a stable and labile surface. J Strength Cond Res 21: 105&#x2013;111, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabaleta-Korta A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Pe&#xf1;a E, Santos-Concejero J. Regional hypertrophy, the inhomogeneous muscle growth: A systematic review. Strength Cond J 42: 94&#x2013;101, 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>