<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41427667</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Training Specificity Versus Structural Adaptation Paradox: Differential Effects of Isokinetic Concentric and Eccentric Resistance Training on Muscle Architecture and Function in Young Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70166</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70166</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.70166</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It remains unclear whether muscle functional adaptations to concentric (CON-RT) and eccentric (ECC-RT) resistance training are most specific to their exercise characteristics or the structural adaptations they evoke. In this study, the effects of CON-RT and ECC-RT programs matched for relative intensity and work on regional hypertrophy, muscle architecture, and function were compared, and associations between the outcomes were explored. Twelve trained young men (25.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.6&#x2009;years) completed 18 isokinetic ankle dorsiflexion exercise sessions over 6&#x2009;weeks: CON-RT in one leg and ECC-RT in the other (2-4 sets, 6-10 maximal repetitions, 10&#xb0;/s). Tibialis anterior size and architecture (ultrasound imaging) and maximum voluntary dorsiflexion function (isokinetic dynamometry) were assessed. Muscle thickness increased similarly between conditions and across proximal-distal regions (8%), pennation angle increased more with CON-RT (8%) than ECC-RT (4%), and fascicle length increased only after ECC-RT (6%). Functional adaptations were more closely associated with specific structural adaptations than with contraction mode, velocity, or angle. Isometric torque increased similarly in both conditions overall (8%), but CON-RT improved only at shorter muscle lengths and shifted the peak torque angle leftward, whereas ECC-RT improved at both shorter and longer lengths and broadened the torque-angle plateau, which was correlated with fascicle length increases. ECC-RT produced greater increases in both eccentric (13%) and concentric torques (17%) than CON-RT (3%, 9%, respectively), and changes were similar across velocities. Changes in pennation angle were associated with dynamic strength changes. These findings suggest that muscle function adapts to the structural changes induced by training, regardless of the training mode used.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8144-5906</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nosaka</LastName><ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7373-4994</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blazevich</LastName><ForeName>Anthony J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1664-1614</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Edith Cowan University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019415" MajorTopicYN="N">Torque</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lengthening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle gear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle geometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rate of force development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcomerogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shortening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stretch&#x2010;shortening cycle</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41427667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.70166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>R. L. Lieber and S. R. Ward, &#x201c;Skeletal Muscle Design to Meet Functional Demands,&#x201d; Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society, B: Biological Sciences 366, no. 1570 (2011): 1466&#x2013;1476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Rockenfeller, M. G&#xfc;nther, C. J. Clemente, and T. J. M. Dick, &#x201c;Rethinking the Physiological Cross&#x2010;Sectional Area of Skeletal Muscle Reveals the Mechanical Advantage of Pennation,&#x201d; Royal Society Open Science 11, no. 9 (2024): 240037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Hinks, M. V. Franchi, and G. A. Power, &#x201c;The Influence of Longitudinal Muscle Fascicle Growth on Mechanical Function,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology 133, no. 1 (2022): 87&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Van Hooren, P. Aagaard, A. Monte, and A. J. Blazevich, &#x201c;The Role of Pennation Angle and Architectural Gearing to Rate of Force Development in Dynamic and Isometric Muscle Contractions,&#x201d; Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports 34, no. 5 (2024): e14639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. J. Blazevich, W. Herzog, and J. P. Nunes, &#x201c;Triggering Sarcomerogenesis: Examining Key Stimuli and the Role Attributed to Eccentric Training&#x2014;Historical, Systematic, and Meta&#x2010;Analytic Review,&#x201d; Journal of Sport and Health Science 14 (2025): 101073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. V. Franchi, N. D. Reeves, and M. V. Narici, &#x201c;Skeletal Muscle Remodeling in Response to Eccentric vs. Concentric Loading: Morphological, Molecular, and Metabolic Adaptations,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 8 (2017): 447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. J. Blazevich, D. Cannavan, D. R. Coleman, and S. Horne, &#x201c;Influence of Concentric and Eccentric Resistance Training on Architectural Adaptation in Human Quadriceps Muscles,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology 103, no. 5 (2007): 1565&#x2013;1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. I. Quinlan, M. V. Franchi, N. Gharahdaghi, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Muscle and Tendon Adaptations to Moderate Load Eccentric vs. Concentric Resistance Exercise in Young and Older Males,&#x201d; GeroScience 43, no. 4 (2021): 1567&#x2013;1584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen and G. A. Power, &#x201c;Modifiability of the History Dependence of Force Through Chronic Eccentric and Concentric Biased Resistance Training,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology 126, no. 3 (2018): 647&#x2013;657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Benford, J. Hughes, M. Waldron, and N. Theis, &#x201c;Concentric Versus Eccentric Training: Effect on Muscle Strength, Regional Morphology, and Architecture,&#x201d; Translational Sports Medicine 4, no. 1 (2021): 46&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. G. Timmins, J. D. Ruddy, J. Presland, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Architectural Changes of the Biceps Femoris Long Head After Concentric or Eccentric Training,&#x201d; Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 48, no. 3 (2016): 499&#x2013;508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. V. Franchi, P. J. Atherton, N. D. Reeves, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Architectural, Functional and Molecular Responses to Concentric and Eccentric Loading in Human Skeletal Muscle,&#x201d; Acta Physiologica 210, no. 3 (2014): 642&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. J. Blazevich, N. D. Gill, and S. Zhou, &#x201c;Intra&#x2010; and Intermuscular Variation in Human Quadriceps Femoris Architecture Assessed In&#xa0;Vivo,&#x201d; Journal of Anatomy 209, no. 3 (2006): 289&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Ando, K. Nosaka, A. Tomita, K. Watanabe, A. J. Blazevich, and H. Akima, &#x201c;Vastus Intermedius vs Vastus Lateralis Fascicle Behaviors During Maximal Concentric and Eccentric Contractions,&#x201d; Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports 28, no. 3 (2018): 1018&#x2013;1026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. J. Blazevich, N. D. Gill, R. Bronks, and R. U. Newton, &#x201c;Training&#x2010;Specific Muscle Architecture Adaptation After 5&#x2010;Wk Training in Athletes,&#x201d; Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 35, no. 12 (2003): 2013&#x2013;2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. Nunes, A. J. Blazevich, B. J. Schoenfeld, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Determining Changes in Muscle Size and Architecture Following Exercise Training: One Site Does Not Fit All,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 38, no. 4 (2024): 787&#x2013;790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. A. Spiering, B. C. Clark, B. J. Schoenfeld, S. A. Foulis, and S. M. Pasiakos, &#x201c;Maximizing Strength: The Stimuli and Mediators of Strength Gains and Their Application to Training and Rehabilitation,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 37, no. 4 (2023): 919&#x2013;929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. A. Maffiuletti, P. Aagaard, A. J. Blazevich, J. Folland, N. Tillin, and J. Duchateau, &#x201c;Rate of Force Development: Physiological and Methodological Considerations,&#x201d; European Journal of Applied Physiology 116, no. 6 (2016): 1091&#x2013;1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. J. Schoenfeld, &#x201c;The Mechanisms of Muscle Hypertrophy and Their Application to Resistance Training,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 24, no. 10 (2010): 2857&#x2013;2872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. R. Moore, M. Young, and S. M. Phillips, &#x201c;Similar Increases in Muscle Size and Strength in Young Men After Training With Maximal Shortening or Lengthening Contractions When Matched for Total Work,&#x201d; European Journal of Applied Physiology 112, no. 4 (2012): 1587&#x2013;1592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Maeo, X. Shan, S. Otsuka, H. Kanehisa, and Y. Kawakami, &#x201c;Neuromuscular Adaptations to Work&#x2010;Matched Maximal Eccentric Versus Concentric Training,&#x201d; Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 50, no. 8 (2018): 1629&#x2013;1640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. L. Jeng, G. K. Thawait, J. Y. Kwon, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Relative Strengths of the Calf Muscles Based on MRI Volume Measurements,&#x201d; Foot &amp; Ankle International 33, no. 5 (2012): 394&#x2013;399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Roig, K. O'Brien, G. Kirk, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Effects of Eccentric Versus Concentric Resistance Training on Muscle Strength and Mass in Healthy Adults: A Systematic Review With Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 43, no. 8 (2009): 556&#x2013;568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. Nunes, W. Kassiano, B. Costa, J. L. Mayhew, A. S. Ribeiro, and E. S. Cyrino, &#x201c;Equating Resistance&#x2010;Training Volume Between Programs Focused on Muscle Hypertrophy,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 51, no. 6 (2021): 1171&#x2013;1178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. J. Schoenfeld, D. Ogborn, A. D. Vigotsky, M. V. Franchi, and J. W. Krieger, &#x201c;Hypertrophic Effects of Concentric vs. Eccentric Muscle Actions: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 31, no. 9 (2017): 2599&#x2013;2608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Y. Kim, J. B. Ko, J. P. Farthing, and S. J. Butcher, &#x201c;Investigation of Supraspinatus Muscle Architecture Following Concentric and Eccentric Training,&#x201d; Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport 18, no. 4 (2015): 378&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. W. Jorgenson, S. M. Phillips, and T. A. Hornberger, &#x201c;Identifying the Structural Adaptations That Drive the Mechanical Load&#x2010;Induced Growth of Skeletal Muscle: A Scoping Review,&#x201d; Cells 9, no. 7 (2020): 1658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. D. Roberts, C. T. Haun, C. G. Vann, S. C. Osburn, and K. C. Young, &#x201c;Sarcoplasmic Hypertrophy in Skeletal Muscle: A Scientific &#x201c;Unicorn&#x201d; or Resistance Training Adaptation?,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 11 (2020): 816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Eng, E. Azizi, and T. J. Roberts, &#x201c;Structural Determinants of Muscle Gearing During Dynamic Contractions,&#x201d; Integrative and Comparative Biology 58, no. 2 (2018): 207&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. P. Purslow, &#x201c;The Structure and Role of Intramuscular Connective Tissue in Muscle Function,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 11 (2020): 495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Herzog, &#x201c;Why Are Muscles Strong, and Why Do They Require Little Energy in Eccentric Action?,&#x201d; Journal of Sport and Health Science 7, no. 3 (2018): 255&#x2013;264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. F. Davis, A. W. Khir, L. Barber, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Mechanisms of Adaptation for Muscle Fascicle Length Changes With Exercise: Implications for Spastic Muscle,&#x201d; Medical Hypotheses 144 (2020): 110199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Douglas, S. Pearson, A. Ross, and M. McGuigan, &#x201c;Chronic Adaptations to Eccentric Training: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 47, no. 5 (2017): 917&#x2013;941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. A. Pincheira, M. A. Boswell, M. V. Franchi, S. L. Delp, and G. A. Lichtwark, &#x201c;Biceps Femoris Long Head Sarcomere and Fascicle Length Adaptations After 3&#x2009;Weeks of Eccentric Exercise Training,&#x201d; Journal of Sport and Health Science 11, no. 1 (2022): 43&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. H. Andrews, S. A. Pai, R. D. Gurchiek, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Multiscale Hamstring Muscle Adaptations Following 9&#x2009;Weeks of Eccentric Training,&#x201d; Journal of Sport and Health Science 14, no. 100996 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Hinks, M. V. Franchi, and G. A. Power, &#x201c;Ultrasonographic Measurements of Fascicle Length Overestimate Adaptations in Serial Sarcomere Number,&#x201d; Experimental Physiology 108, no. 10 (2023): 1308&#x2013;1324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. J. Blazevich, N. D. Gill, N. Deans, and S. Zhou, &#x201c;Lack of Human Muscle Architectural Adaptation After Short&#x2010;Term Strength Training,&#x201d; Muscle and Nerve 35, no. 1 (2007): 78&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. D. Pinto, K. Nosaka, J. M. Wakeling, and A. J. Blazevich, &#x201c;Human in Vivo Medial Gastrocnemius Gear During Active and Passive Muscle Lengthening: Effect of Inconsistent Methods and Nomenclature on Data Interpretation,&#x201d; Biology Open 12, no. 9 (2023): bio060023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Hortob&#xe1;gyi, N. J. Lambert, and J. P. Hill, &#x201c;Greater Cross Education Following Training With Muscle Lengthening Than Shortening,&#x201d; Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 29, no. 1 (1997): 107&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. W. Bell, V. Wong, R. W. Spitz, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Contraction History of the Muscle and Strength Change: Lessons Learned From Unilateral Training Models,&#x201d; Physiological Measurement 41, no. 1 (2020): 01TR01.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. D. Shin, J. A. Hodgson, V. R. Edgerton, and S. Sinha, &#x201c;In Vivo Intramuscular Fascicle&#x2010;Aponeuroses Dynamics of the Human Medial Gastrocnemius During Plantarflexion and Dorsiflexion of the Foot,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology 107, no. 4 (2009): 1276&#x2013;1284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Fukutani, T. Isaka, and W. Herzog, &#x201c;Evidence for Muscle Cell&#x2010;Based Mechanisms of Enhanced Performance in Stretch&#x2010;Shortening Cycle in Skeletal Muscle,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 11 (2021): 609553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Kumagai, T. Abe, W. F. Brechue, T. Ryushi, S. Takano, and M. Mizuno, &#x201c;Sprint Performance Is Related to Muscle Fascicle Length in Male 100&#x2010;m Sprinters,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology 88, no. 3 (2000): 811&#x2013;816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Herzog, &#x201c;History Dependence of Skeletal Muscle Force Production: Implications for Movement Control,&#x201d; Human Movement Science 23, no. 5 (2004): 591&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Herzog, &#x201c;Mechanisms of Enhanced Force Production in Lengthening (Eccentric) Muscle Contractions,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physiology 116, no. 11 (2014): 1407&#x2013;1417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. D. Hyldahl, T. Olson, T. Welling, L. Groscost, and A. C. Parcell, &#x201c;Satellite Cell Activity Is Differentially Affected by Contraction Mode in Human Muscle Following a Work&#x2010;Matched Bout of Exercise,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 5 (2014): 485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. J. Blazevich, D. Cannavan, S. Horne, D. R. Coleman, and P. Aagaard, &#x201c;Changes in Muscle Force&#x2010;Length Properties Affect the Early Rise of Force in Vivo,&#x201d; Muscle and Nerve 39, no. 4 (2009): 512&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. Windhorst, &#x201c;Muscle Proprioceptive Feedback and Spinal Networks,&#x201d; Brain Research Bulletin 73, no. 4&#x2013;6 (2007): 155&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Trezise and A. J. Blazevich, &#x201c;Anatomical and Neuromuscular Determinants of Strength Change in Previously Untrained Men Following Heavy Strength Training,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 10 (2019): 1001.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>