<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40625817</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1735-3955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ARYA atherosclerosis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ARYA Atheroscler</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Heart failure is the most negative consequence of CABG surgery (importance of exercise rehabilitation approach).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>59</StartPage><EndPage>74</EndPage><MedlinePgn>59-74</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.48305/arya.2025.42587.2953</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Statistics indicate that approximately 25,000 open-heart surgeries are performed annually in Iran, with coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) surgeries accounting for 50-60% of these procedures. Although CABG offers numerous benefits to patients with coronary artery disease (CAD), some cases have reported negative consequences, such as heart failure (HF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study explored several influential blood indices related to HF following CABG surgery using manuscripts extracted from PubMed, Scopus, and Google Scholar. The analysis focused on indicators that can exacerbate HF, including fibrotic factors such as catecholamines and the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS).Conversely, it also investigated anti-fibrotic factors, including adrenomedullin (ADM), the natriuretic peptide system (NPS), NP-converting enzymes, and NP receptors. Additionally, the study evaluated the impact of various exercise training programs on these variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Some fibrotic factors, such as catecholamines and the RAAS, contrast with anti-fibrosis factors, including NPs, their producing enzymes, receptors, production and excretion processes, ADM, and others. Research suggests these elements can be positively influenced by exercise rehabilitation.This study highlights the beneficial effects of exercise rehabilitation, specifically in reducing fibrotic factors and enhancing anti-fibrosis factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">All types of exercise training-including endurance, resistance, and combined training, in both continuous and interval modes with moderate and high intensity-can delay fibrotic pathways after surgery and prevent subsequent adverse structural (pathologic hypertrophy) and functional changes in the heart, such as HF.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zare Karizak</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Persian Gulf University, Boushehr, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>ARYA Atheroscler</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101487337</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1735-3955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Fibrotic Factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CABG Surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrotic Factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Failure</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declares no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40625817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12229169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48305/arya.2025.42587.2953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ghalamghash R, Goosheh B, Emrani A, Keyhani MR. Effects of cardiac rehabilitation programs on functional capacity following valvular heart surgery. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2007;27(5):346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siribaddana S. Cardiac dysfunction in the CABG patient. Curr Opin Pharmacol. 2012 Apr;12(2):166&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22325854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piepoli MF, Davos C, Francis DP, Coats AJ. ExTraMATCH Collaborative Exercise training meta-analysis of trials in patients with chronic heart failure (ExTraMATCH) BMJ. 2004 Jan;328(7433)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC318480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14729656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dendale P, Berger J, Hansen D, Vaes J, Benit E, Weymans M. Cardiac rehabilitation reduces the rate of major adverse cardiac events after percutaneous coronary intervention. Eur J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2005 Jun;4(2):113&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15904881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conraads VM, Beckers PJ. Exercise training in heart failure: practical guidance. Heart. 2010 Dec;96(24):2025&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21088125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valkeinen H, Aaltonen S, Kujala UM. Effects of exercise training on oxygen uptake in coronary heart disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010 Aug;20(4):545&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20492590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishitani M, Shimada K, Masaki M, Sunayama S, Kume A, Fukao K, et al. Effect of cardiac rehabilitation on muscle mass, muscle strength, and exercise tolerance in diabetic patients after coronary artery bypass grafting. J Cardiol. 2013 Mar;61(3):216&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23332345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghashghaei FE, Sadeghi M, Marandi SM, Ghashghaei SE. Exercise-based cardiac rehabilitation improves hemodynamic responses after coronary artery bypass graft surgery. ARYA Atheroscler. 2012 Winter;7(4):151&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3413083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23205048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer P, Gayda M, Juneau M, Nigam A. High-intensity aerobic interval exercise in chronic heart failure. Curr Heart Fail Rep. 2013 Jun;10(2):130&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23397179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bili&#x144;ska M, Kosydar-Piechna M, Mikulski T, Piotrowicz E, G&#x105;siorowska A, Piotrowski W, et al. Influence of aerobic training on neurohormonal and hemodynamic responses to head-up tilt test and on autonomic nervous activity at rest and after exercise in patients after bypass surgery. Cardiol J. 2013;20(1):17&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23558806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisl&#xf8;ff U, St&#xf8;ylen A, Loennechen JP, Bruvold M, Rognmo &#xd8;, Haram PM, et al. Superior cardiovascular effect of aerobic interval training versus moderate continuous training in heart failure patients: a randomized study. Circulation. 2007 Jun;115(24):3086&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17548726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omar Z, Latif F. Impact of Renal Dysfunction and Peripheral Arterial Disease on Post-Operative Outcomes After Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting [Internet] Artery Bypass. InTech. 2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farkouh ME, Boden WE, Bittner V, Muratov V, Hartigan P, Ogdie M, et al. Risk factor control for coronary artery disease secondary prevention in large randomized trials. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013 Apr;61(15):1607&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23500281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zile MR, Desantis SM, Baicu CF, Stroud RE, Thompson SB, McClure CD, et al. Plasma biomarkers that reflect determinants of matrix composition identify the presence of left ventricular hypertrophy and diastolic heart failure. Circ Heart Fail. 2011 May;4(3):246&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4071931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21350055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinh QN, Drummond GR, Sobey CG, Chrissobolis S. Roles of inflammation, oxidative stress, and vascular dysfunction in hypertension. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:406960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4124649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25136585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borlaug BA, Paulus WJ. Heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment. Eur Heart J. 2011 Mar;32(6):670&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21138935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stansfield WE, Ranek M, Pendse A, Schisler JC, Wang S, Pulinilkunnil T, Willis MS. The pathophysiology of cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure. In: Willis MS, Homeister JW, Stone JR, editors. Cellular and Molecular Pathobiology of Cardiovascular Disease. 1st ed. London: Academic Press; 2014. pp. 51&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preeshagul I, Gharbaran R, Jeong KH, Abdel-Razek A, Lee LY, Elman E, Suh KS. Potential biomarkers for predicting outcomes in CABG cardiothoracic surgeries. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2013 Jul;8:178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3726492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23866777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichiki T, Boerrigter G, Huntley BK, Sangaralingham SJ, McKie PM, Harty GJ, et al. Differential expression of the pro-natriuretic peptide convertases corin and furin in experimental heart failure and atrial fibrosis. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2013 Jan;304(2):R102&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23152112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horio T, Kawano Y. Bio-molecular markers for cardiovascular disease: significance of natriuretic peptides and adrenomedullin. Korean Circ J. 2008 Oct;38(10):507&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Bierig M, Devereux RB, Flachskampf FA, Foster E, Pellikka PA, et al. Recommendations for chamber quantification. Eur J Echocardiogr. 2006 Mar;7(2):79&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16458610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare Karizak S, Kashef M, Gaeini AA, Nejatian M. The comparison of two protocol of interval and continues aerobic training on level of concentric pathologic hypertrophy and cardiac function in patients after coronary artery bypass grafting surgery. J Pract Stud Biosci Sport. 2017;5(9):9&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lymperopoulos A, Rengo G, Koch WJ. Adrenergic nervous system in heart failure: pathophysiology and therapy. Circ Res. 2013 Aug;113(6):739&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3843360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23989716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayer G, Bhat G. The renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system and heart failure. Cardiol Clin. 2014 Feb;32(1):21&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24286576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu W, Zhou PH, Zhang XB, Xu CG, Wang W. Plasma concentrations of adrenomedullin and natriuretic peptides in patients with essential hypertension. Exp Ther Med. 2015 May;9(5):1901&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4471800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26136912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare Karizak S, Kashef M, Nejatian M, Hamid R. Variations of plasma adrenomedullin, ventricular ejection fraction and resting rate pressure product, following rehabilitation programs of interval and continuous training after coronary artery bypass grafting surgery. J Res Sport Rehabil. 2021;8(16):15&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minamino N, Horio T, Nishikimi T. Natriuretic peptides in the cardiovascular system. In: Kastin AJ, editor. Handbook of Biologically Active Peptides. 1st ed. San Diego: Academic Press; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm J. Markers of hemodynamic state and heart failure as predictors for outcome in cardiac surgery: with special reference to mixed venous oxygen saturation and natriuretic peptides [dissertation] Link&#xf6;ping: Link&#xf6;ping University Electronic Press; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koivisto, E. Characterization of signaling pathways in cardiac hypertrophic response. Oulu : University of Oulu; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi K, Ikeda T, Itoh H, Ueyama K, Hosoda K, Ogawa Y, et al. C-type natriuretic peptide induces redifferentiation of vascular smooth muscle cells with accelerated reendothelialization. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2001 Jun;21(6):930&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11397699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horio T, Tokudome T, Maki T, Yoshihara F, Suga S, Nishikimi T, et al. Gene expression, secretion, and autocrine action of C-type natriuretic peptide in cultured adult rat cardiac fibroblasts. Endocrinology. 2003 Jun;144(6):2279&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12746286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulus WJ, Brutsaert DL, Gillebert TC, Rademakers FE, Sys SU, Leite-Moreira AF, et al. How to diagnose diastolic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 1998;19(7):990&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkel DM, Glockner J, Miller WL. Association of myocardial fibrosis, B-type natriuretic peptide, and cardiac magnetic resonance parameters of remodeling in chronic ischemic cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2012 Feb;109(3):390&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishikimi T, Kuwahara K, Nakao K. Current biochemistry, molecular biology, and clinical relevance of natriuretic peptides. J Cardiol. 2011 Mar;57(2):131&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sartipy U, Alb&#xe5;ge A, Larsson PT, Insulander P, Lindblom D. Changes in B-type natriuretic peptides after surgical ventricular restoration. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2007 May;31(5):922&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17321144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter LR, Yoder AR, Flora DR, Antos LK, Dickey DM. Natriuretic peptides: their structures, receptors, physiologic functions and therapeutic applications. Handb Exp Pharmacol. 2009;(191):341&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4855512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19089336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichiki T, Huntley BK, Heublein DM, Sandberg SM, McKie PM, Martin FL, et al. Corin is present in the normal human heart, kidney, and blood, with pro-B-type natriuretic peptide processing in the circulation. Clin Chem. 2011 Jan;57(1):40&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21075870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong N, Chen S, Wang W, Zhou Y, Wu Q. Corin in clinical laboratory diagnostics. Clin Chim Acta. 2012 Feb;413(3-4):378&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3246062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22093942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenov AG, Tamm NN, Seferian KR, Postnikov AB, Karpova NS, Serebryanaya DV, Koshkina EV, Krasnoselsky MI, Katrukha AG. Processing of pro-B-type natriuretic peptide: furin and corin as candidate convertases. Clin Chem. 2010 Jul;56(7):1166&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20489134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Wu F, Pan J, Morser J, Wu Q. Furin-mediated processing of Pro-C-type natriuretic peptide. J Biol Chem. 2003 Jul;278(28):25847&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12736257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois CM, Blanchette F, Laprise MH, Leduc R, Grondin F, Seidah NG. Evidence that furin is an authentic transforming growth factor-beta1-converting enzyme. Am J Pathol. 2001 Jan;158(1):305&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1850265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11141505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare Karizak S, Kashef M, Gaeini AA. The Comparison of Eight Weeks Interval and Continuous Training on PRO-BNP/ CORIN System in Coronary Artery Disease Patients after CABG Surgery. Sport Physio, 2017;9(33):131&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yandle TG, Richards AM. B-type Natriuretic Peptide circulating forms: Analytical and bioactivity issues. Clin Chim Acta. 2015 Aug;: 195&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26160054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huntley BK, Sandberg SM, Heublein DM, Sangaralingham SJ, Burnett JC Jr, Ichiki T. Pro-B-type natriuretic peptide-1-108 processing and degradation in human heart failure. Circ Heart Fail. 2015 Jan;8(1):89 &#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4303547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25339504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Wu Q. Corin in natriuretic peptide processing and hypertension. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2014 Feb;16(2):415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3941447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24407448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macheret F, Boerrigter G, McKie P, Costello-Boerrigter L, Lahr B, Heublein D, et al. Pro-B-type natriuretic peptide(1-108) circulates in the general community: plasma determinants and detection of left ventricular dysfunction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011 Mar 22;57(12):1386&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3927966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21414536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marney AM, Brown NJ, Tamboli R, Abumrad N. Changes in B-type natriuretic peptide and BMI following Roux-en-Y gastric bypass surgery. Diabetes Care. 2014 Apr;37(4):e70 &#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3964493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24652734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare Karizak S, Kashef M, Gaeini AA, Nejatian M. Impact of high intensity interval and moderate continuous training on plasma ratios of ProBNP1-108/BNP1-32 and NT-pro-BNP1-76/BNP1-32 after coronary artery bypass grafting surgery. Front Physiol. 2023 ;14:1114813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10030057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36960152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groenning BA, Nilsson JC, Sondergaard L, Kjaer A, Larsson HB, Hildebrandt PR. Evaluation of impaired left ventricular ejection fraction and increased dimensions by multiple neurohumoral plasma concentrations. Eur J Heart Fail. 2001 Dec;3(6):699&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnaswamy P, Lubien E, Clopton P, Koon J, Kazanegra R, Wanner E, Gardetto N, Garcia A, DeMaria A, Maisel AS. Utility of B-natriuretic peptide levels in identifying patients with left ventricular systolic or diastolic dysfunction. Am J Med. 2001 Sep;111(4):274&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11566457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi M, Garakyaraghi M, Khosravi M, Taghavi M, Sarrafzadegan N, Roohafza H. The impacts of cardiac rehabilitation program on echocardiographic parameters in coronary artery disease patients with left ventricular dysfunction. Cardiol Res Pract. 2013;2013:201713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3891233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24459599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimannejad K, Nouzari Y, Ahsani A, Nejatian M, Sayehmiri K. Evaluation of the effect of cardiac rehabilitation on left ventricular diastolic and systolic function and cardiac chamber size in patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention. J Tehran Heart Cent. 2014;9(2):54&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4389192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thow, M. Exercise leadership in cardiac rehabilitation: an evidence-based approach. John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiraud T, Nigam A, Gremeaux V, Meyer P, Juneau M, Bosquet L. High-intensity interval training in cardiac rehabilitation. Sports Med. 2012 Jul;42(7):587&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22694349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinkham M. Health promotion in cardiac rehabilitation patients through the use of a high-intensity interval training protocol. World J Cardiovasc Dis. 2014;4(10):493&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, Little JP, Macdonald MJ, Hawley JA. Physiological adaptations to low-volume, high-intensity interval training in health and disease. J Physiol. 2012 Mar;590(5):1077&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyward VH. Advanced fitness assessment and exercise prescription. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise. 1992;24(2):278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock ML, Franklin BA, Balady GJ, Chaitman BL, Fleg JL, Fletcher B, et al. AHA Science Advisory. Resistance exercise in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: benefits, rationale, safety, and prescription: An advisory from the Committee on Exercise, Rehabilitation, and Prevention, Council on Clinical Cardiology, American Heart Association; Position paper endorsed by the American College of Sports Medicine. Circulation. 101(7):828&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conraads VM, Beckers P, Vaes J, Martin M, Van Hoof V, De Maeyer C, et al. Combined endurance/resistance training reduces NT-proBNP levels in patients with chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2004 Oct;25(20):1797&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15474694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schult&#xe9; B, Nieborak L, Leclercq F, Villafa&#xf1;e JH, S&#xe1;nchez Romero EA, Corbellini C. The Comparison of High-Intensity Interval Training Versus Moderate-Intensity Continuous Training after Coronary Artery Bypass Graft: A Systematic Review of Recent Studies. J Cardiovasc Dev Dis. 2022 Sep;9(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9604034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36286280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafiee N, Kordi N, Gadruni K, SalehFard Z, Jung F, Heidari N. Cardiac rehabilitation in coronary artery bypass grafting patients: Effect of eight weeks of moderate-intensity continuous training versus high-intensity interval training. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2023;83(3):305&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36683497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakuchaya T, Pachuashvili NV, Dzhitava TG, Kuular AM, Filatova AG, Bockeria LA. P633 Comparative analysis of exercise programmes with aerobic moderate and high-intensity interval training in patients after coronary artery bypass grafting. Eur Heart J. 2019;40(Suppl_1):ehz747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghardashi-Afousi A, Holisaz MT, Shirvani H, Pishgoo B. The effects of low-volume high-intensity interval versus moderate intensity continuous training on heart rate variability, and hemodynamic and echocardiography indices in men after coronary artery bypass grafting: A randomized clinical trial study. ARYA Atheroscler. 2018 Nov;14(6):260&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31143227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LJ, Randers MB, Hansen PR, Hornstrup T, Schmidt JF, Dvorak J, et al. Structural and functional cardiac adaptations to 6 months of football training in untrained hypertensive men. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014 Aug;:24 Suppl 1:27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24903081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnet CS, Liu X, Body SC, Collard CD, Shernan SK, Muehlschlegel JD, et al. Plasma corin decreases after coronary artery bypass graft surgery and is associated with postoperative heart failure: a pilot study. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2015 Apr;29(2):374&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4394899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25649697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladysheva IP, Wang D, McNamee RA, Houng AK, Mohamad AA, Fan TM, et al. Corin overexpression improves cardiac function, heart failure, and survival in mice with dilated cardiomyopathy. Hypertension. 2013 Feb;61(2):327&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3728819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23232642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara Fernandes J, Serrano CV Jr, Toledo F, Hunziker MF, Zamperini A, Teo FH, et al. Acute and chronic effects of exercise on inflammatory markers and B-type natriuretic peptide in patients with coronary artery disease. Clin Res Cardiol. 2011 Jan;100(1):77&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20835904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox AA, Marcantonio ER, Collard CD, Thoma M, Perry TE, Shernan SK, et al. Increased peak postoperative B-type natriuretic peptide predicts decreased longer-term physical function after primary coronary artery bypass graft surgery. Anesthesiology. 2011 Apr;114(4):807&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3063715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21427536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitsavos C, Chrysohoou C, Koutroumbi M, Aggeli C, Kourlaba G, Panagiotakos D, et al. The impact of moderate aerobic physical training on left ventricular mass, exercise capacity and blood pressure response during treadmill testing in borderline and mildly hypertensive males. Hellenic J Cardiol. 2011 Jan-Feb;52(1):6&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Steele M. Systematic review of the effect of aerobic and resistance exercise training on systemic brain natriuretic peptide (BNP) and N-terminal BNP expression in heart failure patients. Int J Cardiol. 2010 Apr;140(3):260&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19664831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong N, Chen S, Yang J, He L, Liu P, Zheng D, et al. Plasma soluble corin in patients with heart failure. Circ Heart Fail. 2010 Mar;3(2):207&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2879139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20061521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart K. Effect of exercise on blood pressure in older persons: a randomized controlled trial. Archives of internal medicine. 2005;165(7):756&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15824294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronson S, Boisvert D, Lapp W. Isolated systolic hypertension is associated with adverse outcomes from coronary artery bypass grafting surgery. Anesth Analg. 2002 May;94(5):1079&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11973166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkridge AM, Heublein DM, Bergen HR 3rd, Cataliotti A, Burnett JC Jr, Muddiman DC. Quantitative mass spectral evidence for the absence of circulating brain natriuretic peptide (BNP-32) in severe human heart failure. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005 Nov;102(48):17442&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1297688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16293687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>