<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">20618358</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-097X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical physiology and functional imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Physiol Funct Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of low-intensity bench press training with restricted arm muscle blood flow on chest muscle hypertrophy: a pilot study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>338</StartPage><EndPage>343</EndPage><MedlinePgn>338-343</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/j.1475-097X.2010.00949.x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Single-joint resistance training with blood flow restriction (BFR) results in significant increases in arm or leg muscle size and single-joint strength. However, the effect of multijoint BFR training on both blood flow restricted limb and non-restricted trunk muscles remain poorly understood. To examine the impact of BFR bench press training on hypertrophic response to non-restricted (chest) and restricted (upper-arm) muscles and multi-joint strength, 10 young men were randomly divided into either BFR training (BFR-T) or non-BFR training (CON-T) groups. They performed 30% of one repetition maximal (1-RM) bench press exercise (four sets, total 75 reps) twice daily, 6 days week(-1) for 2 weeks. During the exercise session, subjects in the BFR-T group placed elastic cuffs proximally on both arms, with incremental increases in external compression starting at 100 mmHg and ending at 160 mmHg. Before and after the training, triceps brachii and pectoralis major muscle thickness (MTH), bench press 1-RM and serum anabolic hormones were measured. Two weeks of training led to a significant increase (P&lt;0.05) in 1-RM bench press strength in BFR-T (6%) but not in CON-T (-2%). Triceps and pectoralis major MTH increased 8% and 16% (P&lt;0.01), respectively, in BFR-T, but not in CON-T (-1% and 2%, respectively). There were no changes in baseline concentrations of anabolic hormones in either group. These results suggest that BFR bench press training leads to significant increases in muscle size for upper arm and chest muscles and 1-RM strength.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasuda</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Frontier Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujita</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Frontier Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ogasawara</LastName><ForeName>Riki</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Frontier Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiaki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Frontier Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abe</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Frontier Sciences, The University of Tokyo, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Physiol Funct Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101137604</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-0961</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007564" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Japan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood supply</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010369" MajorTopicYN="N">Pectoralis Muscles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood supply</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014111" MajorTopicYN="N">Tourniquets</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034941" MajorTopicYN="N">Upper Extremity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-097X.2010.00949.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kondo M, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. Prediction equations for body composition of Japanese adults by B-mode ultrasound. Am J Hum Biol (1994); 6: 613-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kawakami Y, Suzuki Y, Gunji A, Fukunaga T. Effects of 20&#x2003;days bed rest on muscle morphology. J Gravit Physiol (1997); 4: S10-S14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol (2000); 81: 174-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Yasuda T, Midorikawa T, Sato Y, Kearns CF, Inoue K, Koizumi K, Ishii N. Skeletal muscle size and circulating IGF-1 are increased after two weeks of twice daily &#x201c;KAATSU&#x201d; resistance training. Int J KAATSU Training Res (2005); 1: 6-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Sato Y. Muscle size and strength are increased following walk training with restricted venous blood flow from the leg muscle, Kaatsu-walk training. J Appl Physiol (2006); 100: 1460-1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borst SE, DeHoyos DV, Grazarella L, Vincent K, Pollock BH, Lowenthal DT, Pollock ML. Effects of resistance training on insulin-like growth factor-I and IGF binding proteins. Med Sci Sports Exerc (2001); 41: 648-653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Daly RM, Owen N, Jolley D, De Courten M, Shaw J, Zimmet P. High-intensity resistance training improves glycemic control in older patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care (2002); 25: 1729-1736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiatarone MA, Marks EC, Ryan ND, Meredith CN, Lipsitz LA, Evans WJ. High-intensity strength training in nonagenarians. Effects on skeletal muscle. JAMA (1990); 263: 3029-3034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florini JR, Ewton DZ, Coolican SA. Growth hormone and insulin-like growth factor system in myogenesis. Endocr Rev (1996); 17: 481-517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Meredith CN, O&#x2019;Reilly KP, Knuttgen HG, Evans WJ. Strength conditioning in older men: skeletal muscle hypertrophy and improved function. J Appl Physiol (1988); 64: 1038-1044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, Cadenas JG, Dreyer HC, Sato Y, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol (2007); 103: 903-910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita T, Brechue WF, Kurita K, Sato Y, Abe T. Increased muscle volume and strength following six days of low-intensity resistance training with restricted muscle blood flow. Int J KAATSU Training Res (2008); 4: 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb AH, Garten RS, Chee PD, Cho C, Reeves GV, Hollander DB, Thomas C, Aboudehen KS, Francois M, Kraemer RR. Resistance exercise effects on blood glutathione status and plasma protein carbonyls: influence of partial vascular occlusion. Eur J Appl Physiol (2008); 104: 813-819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillet C, Boirie Y. Insulin resistance: a contributing factor to age-related muscle loss? Diabates Metab (2005); 31: 5S20-5S26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Neya M, Ochi E, Nakazato K, Sato Y, Ishii N. Cross-transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc (2008); 40: 258-263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx JO, Ratamess NA, Nindl BC, Gotshalk LA, Volek JS, Dohi K, Bush JA, Gomez AL, Mazzetti SA, Fleck SJ, Hakkinen K, Newton RU, Kraemer WJ. Low-volume circuit versus high-volume periodized resistance training in women. Med Sci Sports Exerc (2001); 33: 635-643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyatani M, Kanehisa H, Ito M, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. The accuracy of volume estimates using ultrasound muscle thickness measurements in different muscle groups. Eur J Appl Physiol (2004); 91: 264-272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves GV, Kraemer RR, Hollander DB, Clavier J, Thomas C, Francois M, Castracane VD. Comparison of hormone responses following light resistance exercise with partial vascular occlusion and moderately difficult resistance exercise without occlusion. J Appl Physiol (2006); 101: 1616-1622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol (2000a); 88: 61-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Tanaka Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol (2000b); 88: 2097-2106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Sato Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with vascular occlusion on muscle function in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol (2002); 86: 308-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M, Kritchevsky SB, Goodpaster BH, Newman AB, Nevitt M, Stamm E, Harris TB. Leg muscle mass and composition in relation to lower extremity performance in men and women aged 70 to 79: The Health, Aging and Body Composition Study. J Am Geriatr Soc (2002); 50: 897-904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fujita T, Miyagi Y, Kubota Y, Sato Y, Nakajima T, Bemben MG, Abe T. Electromyographic responses of arm and chest muscle during bench press exercise with and without KAATSU. Int J KAATSU Training Res (2006); 2: 15-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Brechue WF, Fujita T, Sato Y, Abe T. Muscle activation during low-intensity muscle contractions with restricted blood flow. J Sports Sci (2009); 27: 479-489.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>