<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">25289940</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The order of exercise during concurrent training for rehabilitation does not alter acute genetic expression, mitochondrial enzyme activity or improvements in muscle function.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e109189</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e109189</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e109189</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0109189</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Concurrent exercise combines different modes of exercise (e.g., aerobic and resistance) into one training protocol, providing stimuli meant to increase muscle strength, aerobic capacity and mass. As disuse is associated with decrements in strength, aerobic capacity and muscle size concurrent training is an attractive modality for rehabilitation. However, interference between the signaling pathways may result in preferential improvements for one of the exercise modes. We recruited 18 young adults (10 &#x2642;, 8 &#x2640;) to determine if order of exercise mode during concurrent training would differentially affect gene expression, protein content and measures of strength and aerobic capacity after 2 weeks of knee-brace induced disuse. Concurrent exercise sessions were performed 3x/week for 6 weeks at gradually increasing intensities either with endurance exercise preceding (END&gt;RES) or following (RES&gt;END) resistance exercise. Biopsies were collected from the vastus lateralis before, 3 h after the first exercise bout and 48 h after the end of training. Concurrent exercise altered the expression of genes involved in mitochondrial biogenesis (PGC-1&#x3b1;, PRC, PPAR&#x3b3;), hypertrophy (PGC-1&#x3b1;4, REDD2, Rheb) and atrophy (MuRF-1, Runx1), increased electron transport chain complex protein content, citrate synthase and mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase enzyme activity, muscle mass, maximum isometric strength and VO 2peak. However, the order in which exercise was completed (END&gt;RES or RES&gt;END) only affected the protein content of mitochondrial complex II subunit. In conclusion, concurrent exercise training is an effective modality for the rehabilitation of the loss of skeletal muscle mass, maximum strength, and peak aerobic capacity resulting from disuse, regardless of the order in which the modes of exercise are performed.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacNeil</LastName><ForeName>Lauren G</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glover</LastName><ForeName>Elisa</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergstra</LastName><ForeName>T Graham</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Safdar</LastName><ForeName>Adeel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarnopolsky</LastName><ForeName>Mark A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada; Department of Medicine, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>365655-2009</GrantID><Agency>Canadian Institutes of Health Research</Agency><Country>Canada</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015870" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gene Expression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005786" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008931" MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondria, Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="N">enzymology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063269" MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondrial Turnover</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009142" MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal Physiological Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009929" MajorTopicYN="N">Organ Size</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25289940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4188604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0109189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-14-14412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>D'Antona G, Pellegrino MA, Adami R, Rossi R, Carlizzi CN, et al. (2003) The effect of ageing and immobilization on structure and function of human skeletal muscle fibres. J Physiol 552: 499&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14561832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Patton JF, Gordon SE, Harman EA, Deschenes MR, et al. (1995) Compatibility of high-intensity strength and endurance training on hormonal and skeletal muscle adaptations. J Appl Physiol (1985) 78: 976&#x2013;989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7775344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Lira VA, Greene NP (2012) Exercise training-induced regulation of mitochondrial quality. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 40: 159&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22732425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Donato DM, West DW, Churchward-Venne TA, Breen L, Baker SK, et al. (2014) Influence of aerobic exercise intensity on myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis in young men during early and late postexercise recovery. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 306: E1025&#x2013;1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4010655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24595306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harber MP, Konopka AR, Douglass MD, Minchev K, Kaminsky LA, et al. (2009) Aerobic exercise training improves whole muscle and single myofiber size and function in older women. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 297: R1452&#x2013;1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3774188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19692660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Gustafsson T, Tesch PA (2012) Aerobic exercise alters skeletal muscle molecular responses to resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 44: 1680&#x2013;1688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22460475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creer A, Gallagher P, Slivka D, Jemiolo B, Fink W, et al. (2005) Influence of muscle glycogen availability on ERK1/2 and Akt signaling after resistance exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 99: 950&#x2013;956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15879168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA (2009) Molecular responses to strength and endurance training: are they incompatible? Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 34: 355&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19448698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkner BA, Tesch PA (2004) Knee extensor and plantar flexor muscle size and function following 90 days of bed rest with or without resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 93: 294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15338217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell EL, Seynnes OR, Bottinelli R, McPhee JS, Atherton PJ, et al. (2013) Skeletal muscle adaptations to physical inactivity and subsequent retraining in young men. Biogerontology 14: 247&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23666342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg HE, Tesch PA (1996) Changes in muscle function in response to 10 days of lower limb unloading in humans. Acta Physiol Scand 157: 63&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8735655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen J, Morelli V (2011) Aging and exercise. Clin Geriatr Med 27: 661&#x2013;671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22062447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN, Wayne SJ, Waters DL, Janssen I, Gallagher D, et al. (2004) Sarcopenic obesity predicts instrumental activities of daily living disability in the elderly. Obes Res 12: 1995&#x2013;2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15687401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvid L, Aagaard P, Justesen L, Bayer ML, Andersen JL, et al. (2010) Effects of aging on muscle mechanical function and muscle fiber morphology during short-term immobilization and subsequent retraining. J Appl Physiol (1985) 109: 1628&#x2013;1634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20864557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda N, Glover EI, Phillips SM, Isfort RJ, Tarnopolsky MA (2005) Sex-based differences in skeletal muscle function and morphology with short-term limb immobilization. J Appl Physiol 99: 1085&#x2013;1092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer MD, Selby A, Atherton P, Smith K, Seynnes OR, et al. (2007) The temporal responses of protein synthesis, gene expression and cell signalling in human quadriceps muscle and patellar tendon to disuse. J Physiol 585: 241&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17901116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abadi A, Glover EI, Isfort RJ, Raha S, Safdar A, et al. (2009) Limb immobilization induces a coordinate down-regulation of mitochondrial and other metabolic pathways in men and women. PLoS One 4: e6518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2716517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19654872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhihetty PJ, O'Leary MF, Chabi B, Wicks KL, Hood DA (2007) Effect of denervation on mitochondrially mediated apoptosis in skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 102: 1143&#x2013;1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17122379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, Gorostiaga E, Izquierdo M, et al. (2003) Neuromuscular adaptations during concurrent strength and endurance training versus strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 42&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12627304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC (1980) Interference of strength development by simultaneously training for strength and endurance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 45: 255&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7193134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton PJ, Babraj J, Smith K, Singh J, Rennie MJ, et al. (2005) Selective activation of AMPK-PGC-1alpha or PKB-TSC2-mTOR signaling can explain specific adaptive responses to endurance or resistance training-like electrical muscle stimulation. FASEB J 19: 786&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15716393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balabinis CP, Psarakis CH, Moukas M, Vassiliou MP, Behrakis PK (2003) Early phase changes by concurrent endurance and strength training. J Strength Cond Res 17: 393&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JP, Pozniak MA, Agre JC (2002) Neuromuscular adaptations to concurrent strength and endurance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 34: 511&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JP, Agre JC, Graf BK, Pozniak MA, Vailas AC (1995) Compatibility of adaptive responses with combining strength and endurance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 27: 429&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7752872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Rhea MR, Wilson SM, Loenneke JP, et al. (2012) Concurrent training: a meta-analysis examining interference of aerobic and resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2293&#x2013;2307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Andersen JL (2010) Effects of strength training on endurance capacity in top-level endurance athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports 20 Suppl 2 39&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20840561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Pilegaard H, Garnham AP, O'Brien BJ, Hawley JA (2009) Consecutive bouts of diverse contractile activity alter acute responses in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol 106: 1187&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glover EI, Yasuda N, Tarnopolsky MA, Abadi A, Phillips SM (2010) Little change in markers of protein breakdown and oxidative stress in humans in immobilization-induced skeletal muscle atrophy. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 35: 125&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oates BR, Glover EI, West DW, Fry JL, Tarnopolsky MA, et al. (2010) Low-volume resistance exercise attenuates the decline in strength and muscle mass associated with immobilization. Muscle Nerve 42: 539&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20658567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Jemiolo B, Edge J, Garnham AP, Trappe SW, et al. (2009) Effect of consecutive repeated sprint and resistance exercise bouts on acute adaptive responses in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 297: R1441&#x2013;1451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19692661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safdar A, Little JP, Stokl AJ, Hettinga BP, Akhtar M, et al. (2011) Exercise increases mitochondrial PGC-1alpha content and promotes nuclear-mitochondrial cross-talk to coordinate mitochondrial biogenesis. J Biol Chem 286: 10605&#x2013;10617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21245132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruas JL, White JP, Rao RR, Kleiner S, Brannan KT, et al. (2012) A PGC-1alpha isoform induced by resistance training regulates skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell 151: 1319&#x2013;1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3520615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23217713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson U, Scarpulla RC (2001) Pgc-1-related coactivator, a novel, serum-inducible coactivator of nuclear respiratory factor 1-dependent transcription in mammalian cells. Mol Cell Biol 21: 3738&#x2013;3749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC87014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11340167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpulla RC (2002) Nuclear activators and coactivators in mammalian mitochondrial biogenesis. Biochim Biophys Acta 1576: 1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12031478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psilander N, Wang L, Westergren J, Tonkonogi M, Sahlin K (2010) Mitochondrial gene expression in elite cyclists: effects of high-intensity interval exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 110: 597&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20571821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Psilander N, Tonkonogi M, Ding S, Sahlin K (2009) Similar expression of oxidative genes after interval and continuous exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 2136&#x2013;2144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19915506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Mascher H, Psilander N, Blomstrand E, Sahlin K (2011) Resistance exercise enhances the molecular signaling of mitochondrial biogenesis induced by endurance exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 111: 1335&#x2013;1344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21836044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathai AS, Bonen A, Benton CR, Robinson DL, Graham TE (2008) Rapid exercise-induced changes in PGC-1alpha mRNA and protein in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 105: 1098&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18653753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortensen OH, Plomgaard P, Fischer CP, Hansen AK, Pilegaard H, et al. (2007) PGC-1beta is downregulated by training in human skeletal muscle: no effect of training twice every second day vs. once daily on expression of the PGC-1 family. J Appl Physiol (1985) 103: 1536&#x2013;1542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17690194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S, Yao J, Howe AA, Menke BM, Sivitz WI, et al. (2012) Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma decouples fatty acid uptake from lipid inhibition of insulin signaling in skeletal muscle. Mol Endocrinol 26: 977&#x2013;988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3355543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22474127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loviscach M, Rehman N, Carter L, Mudaliar S, Mohadeen P, et al. (2000) Distribution of peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors (PPARs) in human skeletal muscle and adipose tissue: relation to insulin action. Diabetologia 43: 304&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park KS, Ciaraldi TP, Abrams-Carter L, Mudaliar S, Nikoulina SE, et al. (1997) PPAR-gamma gene expression is elevated in skeletal muscle of obese and type II diabetic subjects. Diabetes 46: 1230&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9200661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofer A, Lei K, Johannessen CM, Ellisen LW (2005) Regulation of mTOR and cell growth in response to energy stress by REDD1. Mol Cell Biol 25: 5834&#x2013;5845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1168803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15988001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fingar DC, Salama S, Tsou C, Harlow E, Blenis J (2002) Mammalian cell size is controlled by mTOR and its downstream targets S6K1 and 4EBP1/eIF4E. Genes Dev 16: 1472&#x2013;1487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC186342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12080086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corradetti MN, Guan KL (2006) Upstream of the mammalian target of rapamycin: do all roads pass through mTOR? Oncogene 25: 6347&#x2013;6360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17041621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gingras AC, Raught B, Sonenberg N (2001) Regulation of translation initiation by FRAP/mTOR. Genes Dev 15: 807&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11297505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimball SR, Do AN, Kutzler L, Cavener DR, Jefferson LS (2008) Rapid turnover of the mTOR complex 1 (mTORC1) repressor REDD1 and activation of mTORC1 signaling following inhibition of protein synthesis. J Biol Chem 283: 3465&#x2013;3475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18070882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murakami T, Hasegawa K, Yoshinaga M (2011) Rapid induction of REDD1 expression by endurance exercise in rat skeletal muscle. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 405: 615&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21272563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugarolas J, Lei K, Hurley RL, Manning BD, Reiling JH, et al. (2004) Regulation of mTOR function in response to hypoxia by REDD1 and the TSC1/TSC2 tumor suppressor complex. Genes Dev 18: 2893&#x2013;2904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC534650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15545625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ydfors M, Fischer H, Mascher H, Blomstrand E, Norrbom J, et al. (2013) The truncated splice variants, NT-PGC-1alpha and PGC-1alpha4, increase with both endurance and resistance exercise in human skeletal muscle. Physiol Rep 1: e00140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3871455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24400142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Norrbom J, Fischer H, Tesch PA, et al.. (2014) Truncated splice variant PGC-1alpha4 is not associated with exercise-induced human muscle hypertrophy. Acta Physiol (Oxf).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24800995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock KL, Gramm C, Rothstein L, Clark K, Stein R, et al. (1994) Inhibitors of the proteasome block the degradation of most cell proteins and the generation of peptides presented on MHC class I molecules. Cell 78: 761&#x2013;771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8087844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favier FB, Benoit H, Freyssenet D (2008) Cellular and molecular events controlling skeletal muscle mass in response to altered use. Pflugers Arch 456: 587&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18193272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YW, Gregory CM, Scarborough MT, Shi R, Walter GA, et al. (2007) Transcriptional pathways associated with skeletal muscle disuse atrophy in humans. Physiol Genomics 31: 510&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17804603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson T, Osterlund T, Flanagan JN, von Walden F, Trappe TA, et al. (2010) Effects of 3 days unloading on molecular regulators of muscle size in humans. J Appl Physiol (1985) 109: 721&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20538844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha TF, Moreira JBN, Paixao NA, Campos JC, Monteiro AWA, et al. (2012) Aerobic exercise training upregulates skeletal muscle calpain and ubiquitin-proteasome systems in healthy mice. Journal of Applied Physiology 112: 1839&#x2013;1846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leger B, Cartoni R, Praz M, Lamon S, Deriaz O, et al. (2006) Akt signalling through GSK-3beta, mTOR and Foxo1 is involved in human skeletal muscle hypertrophy and atrophy. J Physiol 576: 923&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1890416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16916907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanetti RJ, Zacharewicz E, Della Gatta P, Garnham A, Russell AP, et al. (2014) Ageing has no effect on the regulation of the ubiquitin proteasome-related genes and proteins following resistance exercise. Front Physiol 5: 30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3907707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanetti RJ, Lamon S, Rahbek SK, Farup J, Zacharewicz E, et al.. (2014) Influence of divergent exercise contraction mode and whey protein supplementation on atrogin-1, MuRF1 and FOXO1/3A in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24458747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koncarevic A, Jackman RW, Kandarian SC (2007) The ubiquitin-protein ligase Nedd4 targets Notch1 in skeletal muscle and distinguishes the subset of atrophies caused by reduced muscle tension. FASEB J 21: 427&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17172638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batt J, Bain J, Goncalves J, Michalski B, Plant P, et al. (2006) Differential gene expression profiling of short and long term denervated muscle. FASEB J 20: 115&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16291642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plant PJ, Brooks D, Faughnan M, Bayley T, Bain J, et al. (2010) Cellular markers of muscle atrophy in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol 42: 461&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19520920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Blagden C, Fan J, Nowak SJ, Taniuchi I, et al. (2005) Runx1 prevents wasting, myofibrillar disorganization, and autophagy of skeletal muscle. Genes Dev 19: 1715&#x2013;1722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1176009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandri M (2010) Autophagy in skeletal muscle. FEBS Lett 584: 1411&#x2013;1416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20132819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildey GM, Howe PH (2009) Runx1 is a co-activator with FOXO3 to mediate transforming growth factor beta (TGFbeta)-induced Bim transcription in hepatic cells. J Biol Chem 284: 20227&#x2013;20239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2740449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19494111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki N, Motohashi N, Uezumi A, Fukada S, Yoshimura T, et al. (2007) NO production results in suspension-induced muscle atrophy through dislocation of neuronal NOS. J Clin Invest 117: 2468&#x2013;2476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1952622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17786240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>