<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25392697</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-6302</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>Suppl 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental health insights</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Health Insights</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Volitional Weight-Lifting in Rats Promotes Adaptation via Performance and Muscle Morphology prior to Gains in Muscle Mass.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>9</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4137/EHI.S15257</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Investigation of volitional animal models of resistance training has been instrumental in our understanding of adaptive training. However, these studies have lacked reactive force measurements, a precise performance measure, and morphological analysis at a distinct phase of training - when initial strength gains precede muscle hypertrophy. Our aim was to expose rats to one month of training (70 or 700 g load) on a custom-designed weight-lifting apparatus for analysis of reactive forces and muscle morphology prior to muscle hypertrophy. Exclusively following 700 g load training, forces increased by 21% whereas muscle masses remained unaltered. For soleus (SOL) and tibialis anterior (TA) muscles, 700 g load training increased muscle fiber number per unit area by &#x223c;20% and decreased muscle fiber area by &#x223c;20%. Additionally, number of muscle fibers per section increased by 18% for SOL muscles. These results establish that distinct morphological alterations accompany early strength gains in a volitional animal model of load-dependent adaptive resistance training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rader</LastName><ForeName>Erik P</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>G Roger</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chetlin</LastName><ForeName>Robert D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Morgantown, WV, USA. ; West Virginia University School of Medicine, Department of Neurology, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wirth</LastName><ForeName>Oliver</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baker</LastName><ForeName>Brent A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Health Insights</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101488505</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-6302</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fiber cross-sectional area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fiber number</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">operant conditioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stereology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25392697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4216651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4137/EHI.S15257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ehi-suppl.1-2014-001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>HSE  The health and safety executive statistics 2012/13. 2013.  [Accessed February 2, 2014].  Available at  http://www.hse.gov.uk/statistics/overall/hssh1213.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolf AD, Erwin J, March L. The need to address the burden of musculoskeletal conditions. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2012;26(2):183&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22794094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher S, Heberger JR. Examining the interaction of force and repetition on musculoskeletal disorder risk: a systematic literature review. Hum Factors. 2013;55(1):108&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4495348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23516797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punnett L, Wegman DH. Work-related musculoskeletal disorders: the epidemiologic evidence and the debate. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2004;14(1):13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14759746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutlip RG, Baker BA, Geronilla KB, et al. Chronic exposure to stretch-shortening contractions results in skeletal muscle adaptation in young rats and maladaptation in old rats. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2006;31(5):573&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17111012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonyea WJ, Ericson GC. An experimental model for the study of exercise-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol. 1976;40(4):630&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">132418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho KW, Roy RR, Tweedle CD, Heusner WW, Van Huss WD, Carrow RE. Skeletal muscle fiber splitting with weight-lifting exercise in rats. Am J Anat. 1980;157(4):433&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7405877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki T, Uchiyama S, Nakano S. A weight-lifting exercise model for inducing hypertrophy in the hindlimb muscles of rats. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24(8):881&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1406173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klitgaard H. A model for quantitative strength training of hindlimb muscles of the rat. J Appl Physiol. 1988;64(4):1740&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3379005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanchi NE, de Siqueira Filho MA, Lira FS, et al. Chronic resistance training decreases MuRF-1 and Atrogin-1 gene expression but does not modify Akt, GSK-3beta and p70S6 K levels in rats. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;106(3):415&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19306017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanchi NE, Lira FS, Seelaender M, Lancha-Jr AH. Experimental chronic low-frequency resistance training produces skeletal muscle hypertrophy in the absence of muscle damage and metabolic stress markers. Cell Biochem Funct. 2010;28(3):232&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20373468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Vechetti-J&#xfa;nior IJ, Alves de Souza RW, et al. Myogenin, MyoD and IGF-I regulate muscle mass but not fiber-type conversion during resistance training in rats. Int J Sports Med. 2013;34(4):293&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23059557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki T, Uchiyama Y, Akatsuka A. Plasticity and physiological role of stem cells derived from skeletal muscle interstitium: contribution to muscle fiber hyperplasia and therapeutic use. Curr Pharm Des. 2010;16(8):956&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20041822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki T, Akatsuka A, Tokunaga M, Ishige K, Uchiyama S, Shiraishi T. Morphological and biochemical evidence of muscle hyperplasia following weight-lifting exercise in rats. Am J Physiol. 1997;273(1 pt 1):C246&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klitgaard H, Brunet A, Maton B, Lamaziere C, Lesty C, Monod H. Morphological and biochemical changes in old rat muscles: effect of increased use. J Appl Physiol. 1989;67(4):1409&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2793742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giddings CJ, Gonyea WJ. Morphological observations supporting muscle fiber hyperplasia following weight-lifting exercise in cats. Anat Rec. 1992;233(2):178&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1605384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med. 1979;58(3):115&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">453338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA, Rutherford OM. Human muscle strength training: the effects of three different regimens and the nature of the resultant changes. J Physiol. 1987;391:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1192197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3443943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, de Boer M, Narici MV. Early skeletal muscle hypertrophy and architectural changes in response to high-intensity resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2007;102(1):368&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17053104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie A, Kamen G. Short-term training adaptations in maximal motor unit firing rates and afterhyperpolarization duration. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41(5):651&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19941348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fling BW, Christie A, Kamen G. Motor unit synchronization in FDI and biceps brachii muscles of strength-trained males. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2009;19(5):800&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18691906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin L, Cafarelli E. Transcranial magnetic stimulation during resistance training of the tibialis anterior muscle. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2007;17(4):446&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16891123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claassen H, Gerber C, Hoppeler H, Luthi JM, Vock P. Muscle filament spacing and short-term heavy-resistance exercise in humans. J Physiol. 1989;409:491&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1190456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2585299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Phillips SM, Babraj JA, Smith K, Rennie MJ. Myofibrillar and collagen protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle in young men after maximal shortening and lengthening contractions. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288(6):E1153&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15572656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37(2):145&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Selvanayagam VS, Riek S, Semmler JG. Neural adaptations to strength training: moving beyond transcranial magnetic stimulation and reflex studies. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2011;202(2):119&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21382178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth O, Gregory EW, Cutlip RG, Miller GR. Control and quantitation of voluntary weight-lifting performance of rats. J Appl Physiol. 2003;95(1):402&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ator N. Subjects and instrumentation. Amsterdam: Elsevier; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker BA, Mercer RR, Geronilla KB, Kashon ML, Miller GR, Cutlip RG. Stereological analysis of muscle morphology following exposure to repetitive stretch-shortening cycles in a rat model. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2006;31(2):167&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16604135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker BA, Hollander MS, Kashon ML, Cutlip RG. Effects of glutathione depletion and age on skeletal muscle performance and morphology following chronic stretch-shortening contraction exposure. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108(3):619&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19882165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker BA, Hollander MS, Mercer RR, Kashon ML, Cutlip RG. Adaptive stretch-shortening contractions: diminished regenerative capacity with aging. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33(6):1181&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker BA, Rao KM, Mercer RR, et al. Quantitative histology and MGF gene expression in rats following SSC exercise in vivo. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(3):463&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16540833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker BA, Mercer RR, Geronilla KB, Kashon ML, Miller GR, Cutlip RG. Impact of repetition number on muscle performance and histological response. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1275&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira RF, Foltran FA, Albuquerque-Sendin F, Mancini MC, Coury HJ. Comparison of randomized and non-randomized controlled trials evidence regarding the effectiveness of workplace exercise on musculoskeletal pain control. Work. 2012;41(suppl 1):4782&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22317457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverstein B, Clark R. Interventions to reduce work-related musculoskeletal disorders. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2004;14(1):135&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14759759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Hoppeler H, Kayser B, et al. Human quadriceps cross-sectional area, torque and neural activation during 6 months strength training. Acta Physiol Scand. 1996;157(2):175&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8800357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Grumbt WH, Gonyea WJ, Stray-Gundersen J. Contrasts in muscle and myofibers of elite male and female bodybuilders. J Appl Physiol. 1989;67(1):24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2759948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Larsson L. Muscle hypertrophy in bodybuilders. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1982;49(3):301&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6890445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Sale DG, Elder GC, Sutton JR. Muscle ultrastructural characteristics of elite powerlifters and bodybuilders. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1982;48(1):117&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7199447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson L, Tesch PA. Motor unit fibre density in extremely hypertrophied skeletal muscles in man. Electrophysiological signs of muscle fibre hyperplasia. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1986;55(2):130&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan B, Bouillot E, Bengoetxea A, Noel P, Kahn A, Cheron G. Adaptive motor strategy for squatting in spastic diplegia. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 1999;3(4):159&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10476364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffren M, Ishikawa M, Komi PV. Age-related neuromuscular function during drop jumps. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103(4):1276&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17690197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy RR, Wilson R, Edgerton VR. Architectural and mechanical properties of the rat adductor longus: response to weight-lifting training. Anat Rec. 1997;247(2):170&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9025996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carolan B, Cafarelli E. Adaptations in coactivation after isometric resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 1992;73(3):911&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1400055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramaswamy KS, Palmer ML, van der Meulen JH, et al. Lateral transmission of force is impaired in skeletal muscles of dystrophic mice and very old rats. J Physiol. 2011;589(pt 5):1195&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21224224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Street SF. Lateral transmission of tension in frog myofibers: a myofibrillar network and transverse cytoskeletal connections are possible transmitters. J Cell Physiol. 1983;114(3):346&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6601109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Taylor CC, Sjostrom M. What is the cause of the ageing atrophy? Total number, size and proportion of different fiber types studied in whole vastus lateralis muscle from 15- to 83-year-old men. J Neurol Sci. 1988;84:2&#x2013;3. 275&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3379447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheard PW, Anderson RD. Age-related loss of muscle fibres is highly variable amongst mouse skeletal muscles. Biogerontology. 2012;13(2):157&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22048817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millay DP, Sargent MA, Osinska H, et al. Genetic and pharmacologic inhibition of mitochondrial-dependent necrosis attenuates muscular dystrophy. Nat Med. 2008;14(4):442&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18345011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannaccone S, Quattrini A, Smirne S, et al. Connective tissue proliferation and growth factors in animal models of Duchenne muscular dystrophy. J Neurol Sci. 1995;128(1):36&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7722532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendler L, Pinter S, Kiricsi M, Baka Z, Dux L. Regeneration of reinnervated rat soleus muscle is accompanied by fiber transition toward a faster phenotype. J Histochem Cytochem. 2008;56(2):111&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2324173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker BA, Cutlip RG. Skeletal muscle injury versus adaptation with aging: novel insights on perplexing paradigms. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2010;38(1):10&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20016294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>