<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35790622</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Are Trainees Lifting Heavy Enough? Self-Selected Loads in Resistance Exercise: A Scoping Review and Exploratory Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2909</StartPage><EndPage>2923</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2909-2923</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-022-01717-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Traditionally, the loads in resistance training are prescribed as a percentage of the heaviest load that can be successfully lifted once (i.e., 1 Repetition Maximum [1RM]). An alternative approach is to allow trainees to self-select the training loads. The latter approach has benefits, such as allowing trainees to exercise according to their preferences and negating the need for periodic 1RM tests. However, in order to better understand the utility of the self-selected load prescription approach, there is a need to examine what loads trainees select when given the option to do so.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Examine what loads trainees self-select in resistance training sessions as a percentage of their 1RM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">Scoping review and exploratory meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH AND INCLUSION">We conducted a systematic literature search with PubMed, Web of Science, and Google Scholar in September 2021. We included studies that (1) were published in English in a peer-reviewed journal or as a MSc or Ph.D. thesis; (2) had healthy trainees complete at least one resistance-training session, composed of at least one set of one exercise in which they selected the loads; (3) trainees completed a 1RM test for the exercises that they selected the loads for. Eighteen studies were included in our main meta-analysis model with 368 participants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Our main model indicated that on average participants select loads equal to 53% of their 1RM (95% credible interval [CI] 49-58%). There was little moderating effect of training experience, age, sex, timing of the 1RM test (before or after the selected load RT session), number of sets, number of repetitions, and lower versus upper body exercises. Participants did tend to select heavier loads when prescribed lower repetitions, and vice versa (logit(yi)&#x2009;=&#x2009;&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.09 [95% CI&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.16 to&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.03]). Note that in most of the analyzed studies, participants received vague instructions regarding how to select the loads, and only completed a single session with the self-selected loads.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Participants selected loads equal to an average of 53% of 1RM across exercises. Lifting such a load coupled with a low-medium number of repetitions (e.g., 5-15) can sufficiently stimulate hypertrophy and increase maximal strength for novices but may not apply for more advanced trainees. Lifting such a load coupled with a higher number of repetitions and approaching or reaching task failure can be sufficient for muscle hypertrophy, but less so for maximal strength development, regardless of trainees' experience. The self-selected load prescription approach may bypass certain limitations of the traditional approach, but requires thought and further research regarding how, for what purposes, and with which populations it should be implemented.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steele</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Health, and Social Sciences, Solent University, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malleron</LastName><ForeName>Tomer</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion, School of Public Health, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sylvan Adams Sports Institute, Tel Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Har-Nir</LastName><ForeName>Itai</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion, School of Public Health, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sylvan Adams Sports Institute, Tel Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Androulakis-Korakakis</LastName><ForeName>Patroklos</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Health, and Social Sciences, Solent University, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolf</LastName><ForeName>Milo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Health, and Social Sciences, Solent University, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fisher</LastName><ForeName>James P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Health, and Social Sciences, Solent University, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halperin</LastName><ForeName>Israel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2254-2698</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion, School of Public Health, Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel. ihalperin@tauex.tau.ac.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sylvan Adams Sports Institute, Tel Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel. ihalperin@tauex.tau.ac.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017770" MajorTopicYN="N">Lifting</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35790622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01717-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-022-01717-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abad CCC, Prado ML, Ugrinowitsch C, Tricoli V, Barroso R. Combination of general and specific warm-ups improves leg-press one repetition maximum compared with specific warm-up in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:2242&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21544000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves RC, Prestes J, Souza-Junior TP, Follador L, Lopes WA, Silva SG. Acute effect of weight training at a self-selected intensity on affective responses in obese adolescents. J Exerc Physiol Online. 2014;17:66&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription (American College of Sports Medicine), 10th edition. LWW; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa-Netto S, Acelino-E-Porto OS, Almeida MB. Self-selected resistance exercise load: implications for research and prescription. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:S166&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29112055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;rkner P-C. brms: an&#xa0;R&#xa0;package for Bayesian multilevel models using&#xa0;stan. J Stat Softw 2017; 80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskard ANL, Jacobs KA, Eltoukhy MM, Strand KL, Villanueva L, Desai PP, Signorile JF. Optimal approach to load progressions during strength training in older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:2224&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31107348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun RJ, Gai CM, Walters J, Brannon AR, Kilpatrick MW, D&#x2019;Agostino DP, Campbell BI. Comparison of powerlifting performance in trained men using traditional and flexible daily undulating periodization. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:283&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28129275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Segundo VH, Rebou&#xe7;as GM, Renee T, de Medeiros HJ, Knackfuss MI. Self-selected intensity by controlled hypertensive older women during a weight training session. IOSR-JSPE. 2016;3:09&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dello Iacono A, Beato M, Halperin I. Self-selecting the number of repetitions in potentiation protocols: enhancement effects on jumping performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;16:353&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias MRC, Sim&#xe3;o R, Saavedra FJF, Buzzachera CF, Fleck S. Self-selected training load and RPE during resistance and aerobic training among recreational exercisers. Percept Mot Skills. 2018;125:769&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29726740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias MRC, Sim&#xe3;o RF, Saavedra FJF, Ratamess NA. Influence of a personal trainer on self-selected loading during resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:1925&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27676273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douma JC, Weedon JT. Analysing continuous proportions in ecology and evolution: a practical introduction to beta and Dirichlet regression. Methods Ecol Evol 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsangedy HM, Krause MP, Krinski K, Alves RC, Chao CHN, da Silva SG. Is the self-selected resistance exercise intensity by older women consistent with the American College of Sports Medicine guidelines to improve muscular fitness? J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:1877&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23792939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsangedy HM, Krinski K, Machado DGS, Agr&#xed;cola PMD, Okano AH, da Silva SG. Self-selected intensity, ratings of perceived exertion, and affective responses in sedentary male subjects during resistance training. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28:1795&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27390418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4932059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsangedy HM, Machado DGDS, Krinski K, Duarte DO, Nascimento PH, Amorim DE, Oliveira GT, Santos TM, Hargreaves EA, Parfitt G. Let the pleasure guide your resistance training intensity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50:1472&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29432325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsangedy HM, Oliveira GTA, Machado DGS, Tavares MPM, Ara&#xfa;jo AO, Krinski K, Browne RAV, da Silva SG. Effects of self-selected resistance training on physical fitness and psychophysiological responses in physically inactive older women: a randomized controlled study. Percept Mot Skills. 2021;128:467&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33115322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emanuel A, Rozen Smukas II, Halperin I. An analysis of the perceived causes leading to task-failure in resistance-exercises. PeerJ. 2020;8: e9611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33194334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7391967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evmenenko A, Teixeira DS. The circumplex model of affect in physical activity contexts: a systematic review. Int J Sport Exerc Psychol 2022; 20:168&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faries MD, Lutz R. Self-selected intensity and adherence in a campus recreation center with novice, female weight lifters: a preliminary investigation. RSJ. 2016;40:56&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. High- and low-load resistance training: interpretation and practical application of current research findings. Sports Med. 2017;47:393&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27480764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Steele J. Heavier and lighter load resistance training to momentary failure produce similar increases in strength with differing degrees of discomfort. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:797&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28006852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focht BC, Garver MJ, Cotter JA, Devor ST, Lucas AR, Fairman CM. Affective responses to acute resistance exercise performed at self-selected and imposed loads in trained women. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:3067&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26506060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focht BC. Perceived exertion and training load during self-selected and imposed-intensity resistance exercise in untrained women. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21:183&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, Franklin BA, Lamonte MJ, Lee I-M, Nieman DC, Swain DP, American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner MJ, Altman DG. Confidence intervals rather than P values: estimation rather than hypothesis testing. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed). 1986;292:746&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3082422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass SC, Ahmad S, Gabler T. Effectiveness of a 2-week strength training learning intervention on self-selected weight-training intensity. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:2443&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32732772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass SC, Stanton DR. Self-selected resistance training intensity in novice weightlifters. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:324&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass SC. Effect of a learning trial on self-selected resistance training load. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1025&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham T, Cleather DJ. Autoregulation by &#x201c;Repetitions in Reserve&#x201d; leads to greater improvements in strength over a 12-week training program than fixed loading. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35:2451&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Test-retest reliability of the one-repetition maximum (1RM) strength assessment: a systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2020;6:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7367986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall EE, Ekkekakis P, Petruzzello SJ. Is the relationship of RPE to psychological factors intensity-dependent? Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37:1365&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16118584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halperin I, Chapman DW, Martin DT, Lewthwaite R, Wulf G. Choices enhance punching performance of competitive kickboxers. Psychol Res. 2017;81:1051&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Byrnes RK, Cooke DM, Haischer MH, Carzoli JP, Johnson TK, Cross MR, Cronin JB, Storey AG, Zourdos MC. RPE vs. percentage 1RM loading in periodized programs matched for sets and repetitions. Front Physiol. 2018;9:247&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29628895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5877330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Cross MR, Brown SR, Storey A, Cronin J, Zourdos MC. Rating of perceived exertion as a method of volume autoregulation within a periodized program. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32:1627&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29786623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay M. tidybayes: Tidy data and geoms for Bayesian models. R package version 3.0. 0. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmler W, Kohl M, Fr&#xf6;hlich M, Jakob F, Engelke K, von Stengel S, Schoene D. Effects of high-intensity resistance training on osteopenia and sarcopenia parameters in older men with osteosarcopenia-one-year results of the randomized controlled franconian osteopenia and sarcopenia trial (FrOST). J Bone Miner Res. 2020;35:1634&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32270891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:674&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruschke JK, Liddell TM. The Bayesian new statistics: hypothesis testing, estimation, meta-analysis, and power analysis from a Bayesian perspective. Psychon Bull Rev. 2018;25:178&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28176294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Xu C. Arcsine-based transformations for meta-analysis of proportions: pros, cons, and alternatives. Health Sci Rep. 2020;3: e178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32728636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7384291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Trajano GS, Teodoro JL, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pinto RS. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:1206&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mouser JG, Loenneke JP. Practicing the test produces strength equivalent to higher volume training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49:1945&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara JM, Stearne DJ. Flexible nonlinear periodization in a beginner college weight training class. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:17&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20042923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McShane BB, Gal D, Gelman A, Robert C, Tackett JL. Abandon statistical significance. Am Stat. 2019;73:235&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, Mazara N, McGlory C, Quadrilatero J, Baechler BL, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol. 2016;121:129&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4967245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewiadomski W, Laskowska D, G&#x105;siorowska A, Cybulski G, Strasz A, Langfort J. Determination and prediction of one repetition maximum (1RM): safety considerations. J Hum Kinet. 2008;19:109&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen TL. The composer of plots [R package patchwork version 1.1.1]. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portugal EMM, Lattari E, Santos TM, Deslandes AC. Affective responses to prescribed and self-selected strength training intensities. Percept Mot Skills. 2015;121:465&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Faigenbaum AD, Hoffman JR, Kang J. Self-selected resistance training intensity in healthy women: the influence of a personal trainer. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:103&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauch JT, Ugrinowitsch C, Barakat CI, Alvarez MR, Brummert DL, Aube DW, Barsuhn AS, Hayes D, Tricoli V, De Souza EO. Auto-regulated exercise selection training regimen produces small increases in lean body mass and maximal strength adaptations in strength-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:1133&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Hamilton DL, Paval DR, Gallagher IJ, Feros SA, Fyfe JJ. Influence of resistance training load on measures of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and improvements in maximal strength and neuromuscular task performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2021;39:1723&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Landers DM, Alvar BA, Arent SM. The effects of competition and the presence of an audience on weight lifting performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17:303&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sands WA, Wurth JJ, Hewit JK. Basics of strength and conditioning manual. Colorado Springs: National Strength and Conditioning Association; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos WM, Junior ACT, Braz TV, Lopes CR, Brigatto FA, Dos Santos JW. Resistance-trained individuals can underestimate the intensity of the resistance training session: an analysis among genders, training experience, and exercises. J Strength Cond Res. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Van Every DW, Plotkin DL. Loading recommendations for muscle strength, hypertrophy, and local endurance: a re-examination of the repetition continuum. Sports (Basel) 2021; 9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:2954&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciwheel. Sciwheel. Sciwheel Limited, 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh H, Hockwald A, Drake N, Avedesian J, Lee S-P, Wulf G. Maximal force production requires OPTIMAL conditions. Hum Mov Sci. 2020;73: 102661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32741751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8188754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart C, Steele J, Gentil P, Giessing J, Fisher JP. Fatigue and perceptual responses of heavier- and lighter-load isolated lumbar extension resistance exercise in males and females. PeerJ. 2018;6: e4523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29576983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5858602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabo A. Acute psychological benefits of exercise performed at self-selected workloads: implications for theory and practice. J Sports Sci Med. 2003;2:77&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24627659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3942640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira PJ, Carra&#xe7;a EV, Markland D, Silva MN, Ryan RM. Exercise, physical activity, and self-determination theory: a systematic review. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2012;9:78&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22726453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3441783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiggemann CL, Pietta-Dias C, Schoenell MCW, Noll M, Alberton CL, Pinto RS, Kruel LFM. Rating of perceived exertion as a method to determine training loads in strength training in elderly women: A randomized controlled study. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021; 18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vale AF, Carneiro JA, Jardim PCV, Jardim TV, Steele J, Fisher JP, Gentil P. Acute effects of different resistance training loads on cardiac autonomic modulation in hypertensive postmenopausal women. J Transl Med. 2018;16:240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6117915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor Package. J Stat Softw 2010; 36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace BC, Small K, Brodley CE, Lau J, Trikalinos TA. Deploying an interactive machine learning system in an evidence-based practice center: Abstrackr. In: Proceedings of the 2nd ACM SIGHIT symposium on International health informatics - IHI'&#xa0;' &#x2019;12. New York, New York, USA: ACM Press, 2012: 819</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warton DI, Hui FKC. The arcsine is asinine: the analysis of proportions in ecology. Ecology. 2011;92:3&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21560670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson K, Halperin I, Aguilera-Castells J, Dello Iacono A. A comparison between predetermined and self-selected approaches in resistance training: effects on power performance and psychological outcomes among elite youth athletes. PeerJ. 2020;8: e10361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33240664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7666817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H, Chang W. An implementation of the grammar of graphics. http:www.ggplot2org; 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>