<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40168063</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise Intensity and Rest Intervals Effects on Intracellular Signals and Anabolic Response of Skeletal Muscle to Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1695</StartPage><EndPage>1703</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1695-1703</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004209</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Moro, T, Monaco, L, Naro, F, Reggiani, C, and Paoli, A. Exercise intensity and rest intervals effects on intracellular signals and anabolic response of skeletal muscle to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 38(10): 1695-1703, 2024-Resistance training (RT) is one of the most important stimuli for muscle hypertrophy, and it may play also an important role on weight loss and fatty acids oxidation. Clearly, RT affects anabolic pathways, but the differences among various training techniques has been poorly investigated. We sought to compare the effect of 2 different intensities of training: high-intensity interval resistance training (HIIRT) and traditional resistance training (TRT), on muscle signaling pathway. Nine young healthy subjects performed HIIRT and TRT protocol on 2 different occasions and with different legs on leg extension. High-intensity interval resistance training technique consisted of 3 sets of 6 repetitions (reps) at 6 repetition maximum and then 20 seconds of rest and 2 or 3 repetitions (until exhaustion) repeated for 3 times with 2'30&#x2033; rest between sets, whereas TRT consisted of 3 sets of 15 reps with 75 seconds of rest between sets. Biopsies from the vastus lateralis were taken at baseline (pre), immediately (0 hours) at the end of training, and 6 hours (6 h) and 24 hours (24 h) after training. Western blot and real-time polymerase chain reaction messenger RNA (mRNA) analysis were performed to assess muscle signaling pathway activation. In both protocols, rpS6 phosphorylation significantly increased at 6 hours (p &lt; 0.05). Traditional resistance training showed a significant increase at 24 hours of AMPK phosphorylation compared with HIIRT (p &lt; 0.05), whereas no significant differences between groups were found for other proteins. mRNA analysis showed no differences between protocols except for striated muscle activator of Rho signaling. The manipulation of resistance training intensity through incomplete/short recovery does not induce different molecular anabolic and metabolic responses compared with a TRT method.Trial Registration number: NCT04163120 retrospectively registered.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moro</LastName><ForeName>Tatiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Nutrition and Exercise Physiology Laboratory, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monaco</LastName><ForeName>Lucia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Pharmacology, Sapienza University, Roma, Italy ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naro</LastName><ForeName>Fabio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DAHFMO Unit of Histology and Medical Embryology, Sapienza University, Roma, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reggiani</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Nutrition and Exercise Physiology Laboratory, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paoli</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0474-4229</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Nutrition and Exercise Physiology Laboratory, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04163120</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.31</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D055372">AMP-Activated Protein Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009124">Muscle Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D038601">Ribosomal Protein S6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058570">TOR Serine-Threonine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055372" MajorTopicYN="N">AMP-Activated Protein Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="Y">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009124" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010766" MajorTopicYN="N">Phosphorylation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012146" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rest</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D038601" MajorTopicYN="N">Ribosomal Protein S6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="Y">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058570" MajorTopicYN="N">TOR Serine-Threonine Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40168063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202410000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Nyman K, Huhtaniemi I, et al. Effects of resistance training on testosterone metabolism in younger and older men. Exp Gerontol 69: 148&#x2013;158, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports M. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baeza-Raja B, Mu&#xf1;oz-C&#xe1;noves P. p38 MAPK-induced nuclear factor-kappaB activity is required for skeletal muscle differentiation: role of interleukin-6. Mol Biol Cell 15: 2013&#x2013;2026, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC. mTOR signaling and the molecular adaptation to resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 38: 1950&#x2013;1957, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolster DR, Crozier SJ, Kimball SR, Jefferson LS. AMP-activated protein kinase suppresses protein synthesis in rat skeletal muscle through down-regulated mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) signaling. J Biol Chem 277: 23977&#x2013;23980, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol 588: 3119&#x2013;3130, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Phillips SM. Bigger weights may not beget bigger muscles: Evidence from acute muscle protein synthetic responses after resistance exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 37: 551&#x2013;554, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZP, Stephens TJ, Murthy S, et al. Effect of exercise intensity on skeletal muscle AMPK signaling in humans. Diabetes 52: 2205&#x2013;2212, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorme TL, Watkins AL. Technics of progressive resistance exercise. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 29: 263&#x2013;273, 1948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febbraio MA, Pedersen BK. Muscle-derived interleukin-6: Mechanisms for activation and possible biological roles. FASEB J 16: 1335&#x2013;1347, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink J, Kikuchi N, Yoshida S, Terada K, Nakazato K. Impact of high versus low fixed loads and non-linear training loads on muscle hypertrophy, strength and force development. Springerplus 5: 698, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganassi M, Badodi S, Ortuste Quiroga HP, et al. Myogenin promotes myocyte fusion to balance fibre number and size. Nat Commun 9: 4232, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala M. Molecular responses to high-intensity interval exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 34: 428&#x2013;432, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, McGee SL, Garnham AP, et al. Brief intense interval exercise activates AMPK and p38 MAPK signaling and increases the expression of PGC-1alpha in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 106: 929&#x2013;934, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed M, Orrell RW, Cobbold M, Goldspink G, Harridge SD. Expression of IGF-I splice variants in young and old human skeletal muscle after high resistance exercise. J Physiol 547: 247&#x2013;254, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardie DG. AMPK: Positive and negative regulation, and its role in whole-body energy homeostasis. Curr Opin Cell Biol 33: 1&#x2013;7, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA, Hargreaves M, Joyner MJ, Zierath JR. Integrative biology of exercise. Cell 159: 738&#x2013;749, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill M, Wernig A, Goldspink G. Muscle satellite (stem) cell activation during local tissue injury and repair. J Anat 203: 89&#x2013;99, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson JR, Mula J, Kirby TJ, et al. Satellite cell depletion does not inhibit adult skeletal muscle regrowth following unloading-induced atrophy. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 303: C854&#x2013;C861, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller C, Steensberg A, Hansen AK, et al. Effect of exercise, training, and glycogen availability on IL-6 receptor expression in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 99: 2075&#x2013;2079, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Impact of resistance loading on myostatin expression and cell cycle regulation in young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 288: E1110&#x2013;E1119, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korak JA, Paquette MR, Brooks J, Fuller DK, Coons JM. Effect of rest-pause vs. traditional bench press training on muscle strength, electromyography, and lifting volume in randomized trial protocols. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 1891&#x2013;1896, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamon S, Wallace MA, Stefanetti RJ, et al. Regulation of the STARS signaling pathway in response to endurance and resistance exercise and training. Pflugers Arch 465: 1317&#x2013;1325, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Fry CS, Mula J, et al. Aged muscle demonstrates fiber-type Adaptations in response to mechanical overload, in the absence of myofiber hypertrophy, independent of satellite cell abundance. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 71: 461&#x2013;467, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little JP, Safdar A, Bishop D, Tarnopolsky MA, Gibala MJ. An acute bout of high-intensity interval training increases the nuclear abundance of PGC-1&#x3b1; and activates mitochondrial biogenesis in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 300: R1303&#x2013;R1310, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Norrbom J, et al. Truncated splice variant PGC-1alpha4 is not associated with exercise-induced human muscle hypertrophy. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 212: 142&#x2013;151, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, Phillips SM. Exercise and the regulation of skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci 135: 153&#x2013;173, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKendry J, Perez-Lopez A, McLeod M, et al. Short inter-set rest blunts resistance exercise-induced increases in myofibrillar protein synthesis and intracellular signalling in young males. Exp Physiol 101: 866&#x2013;882, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Cameron-Smith D, Phillips SM. What is the relationship between the acute muscle protein synthetic response and changes in muscle mass? J Appl Physiol 118: 495&#x2013;4970, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 113: 71&#x2013;77, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mounier R, Lantier L, Leclerc J, et al. Important role for AMPKalpha1 in limiting skeletal muscle cell hypertrophy. FASEB J 23: 2264&#x2013;2273, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedergaard A, Vissing K, Overgaard K, Kjaer M, Schjerling P. Expression patterns of atrogenic and ubiquitin proteasome component genes with exercise: Effect of different loading patterns and repeated exercise bouts. J Appl Physiol (1985) 103: 1513&#x2013;1522, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A. Resistance training: The multifaceted side of exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 302: e387, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Moro T, Bianco A. Lift weights to fight overweight. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35; 1&#x2013;6, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Moro T, Marcolin G, et al. High-Intensity Interval Resistance Training (HIRT) influences resting energy expenditure and respiratory ratio in non-dieting individuals. J Transl Med 10: 237, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Pacelli QF, Toniolo L, Miotti D, Reggiani C. Latissimus dorsi fine needle muscle biopsy: A novel and efficient approach to study proximal muscles of upper limbs. J Surgical Research 164: e257&#x2013;e263, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK, Febbraio MA. Point: Interleukin-6 does have a beneficial role in insulin sensitivity and glucose homeostasis. J Appl Physiol 102: 814&#x2013;816, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruas JL, White JP, Rao RR, et al. A PGC-1&#x3b1; isoform induced by resistance training regulates skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell 151: 1319&#x2013;1331, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano AL, Baeza-Raja B, Perdiguero E, Jard&#xed; M, Mu&#xf1;oz-C&#xe1;noves P. Interleukin-6 is an essential regulator of satellite cell-mediated skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell Metab 7: 33&#x2013;44, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, Giessing J, Gentil P. Clarity in reporting terminology and definitions of set endpoints in resistance training. Muscle Nerve 56: 368&#x2013;374, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Delecluse C, Coudyzer W, Boonen S, Bautmans I. Strength training at high versus low external resistance in older adults: Effects on muscle volume, muscle strength, and force-velocity characteristics. Exp Gerontol 48: 1351&#x2013;1361, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White JP, Wrann CD, Rao RR, et al. G protein-coupled receptor 56 regulates mechanical overload-induced muscle hypertrophy. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 111: 15756&#x2013;15761, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson D, Gallagher P, Harber M, Hollon C, Trappe S. Mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK) pathway activation: Effects of age and acute exercise on human skeletal muscle. J Physiol 547: 977&#x2013;987, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Nelson MJ. Myosin heavy-chain mRNA expression after a single session of heavy-resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 34: 1262&#x2013;1269, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Creer A, Jemiolo B, Trappe S. Time course of myogenic and metabolic gene expression in response to acute exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 98: 1745&#x2013;1752, 2005.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>