<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38288383</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Acute Impacts of Resistance Training Performed with and without Blood Flow Restriction on Lower Body Muscular Power.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1320</StartPage><EndPage>1333</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1320-1333</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The American College of Sports Medicine recommends resistance training using at least 70% one repetition maximum to improve muscular strength and hypertrophy; however, these intensities may not be safe for all populations. A training technique that has been reported to elicit increases in strength and muscle size uses low intensity resistance training or low load training in combination with blood flow restriction (BFR) to the working muscle. Although the acute effects of BFR on muscle strength and size are well established, the effects of BFR on muscular power are not definitively known. Resistance trained males (<i>n</i> = 14) completed three experimental sessions in which lower body power output and vertical jump height were measured pre and post exercise protocol. The barbell back squat was performed with either low load and blood flow restriction, high load (90% 1 RM, HL), or control (CON). A significant mean difference between pre (<i>M</i> = 46.35 &#xb1; 5.61 cm) and post (<i>M</i> = 43.63 &#xb1; 4.59 cm) vertical jump heights following 15 repetitions at 20% 1 RM with BFR was observed (<i>p</i> = 0.034), but not with HL or a CON. A decrement in vertical jump height was experienced after an acute bout of BFR with low load resistance exercise. Low load resistance exercise with BFR or high intensity resistance exercise may not be beneficial as part of a warm-up to acutely enhance vertical jump or power output.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faller</LastName><ForeName>Justin M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Athletic Training, Springfield College, Springfield, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kinesiology, Sport Studies, &amp; Physical Education, SUNY Brockport, Brockport, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thompson</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Athletic Training, Springfield College, Springfield, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sotir</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Athletic Training, Springfield College, Springfield, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Breakthrough Performance Coaching LLC, Ipswich, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ives</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Physiological Sciences, Skidmore College, Saratoga Spring, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood flow restriction training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power output</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">warm up</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10824296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/GJPZ7510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-16-6-1320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Beekley MD, Hinata S, Koizumi K, Sato Y. Day-to-day change in muscle strength and MRI-measured skeletal muscle size during 7 days KAATSU resistance training: a case study. Int J KAATSU Train Res. 2005;1(2):71&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kawamoto K, Yasuda T, Kearns CF, Midorikawa T, Sato Y. Eight days KAATSU-resistance training improved sprint but not jump performance in collegiate male track and field athletes. Int J KAATSU Train Res. 2005;1(1):19&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Sato Y. Muscle size and strength are increased following walk training with restricted venous blood flow from the leg muscle, KAATSU -walk training. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100(5):1460&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen D, Lamb G, Westerblad H. Skeletal muscle fatigue: cellular mechanisms. Physiol Rev. 2008;88(1):287&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18195089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle T, Earle R. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. Human Kinetics; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. Acute and long-term power responses to power training: observations on the training of an elite power athlete. Strength Cond J. 2001;23(1):47&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D. Acute effect of alternating heavy and light resistances on power output during upper-body complex power training. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(3):493&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12930175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatzopoulos DE, Michailidis CJ, Giannakos AK, Alexiou KC, Patikas DA, Antonopoulos CB, et al. postactivation potentiation effects after heavy resistance exercise on running speed. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(4):1278&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary CJ, Cook SB. Postactivation potentiation in blood flow&#x2013;restricted complex training. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(4):905&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31972826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiStasio TJ. Validation of the Brzycki and Epley equations for the 1 repetition maximum back squat test in Division I college football players. 2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, Cadenas JG, Dreyer HC, Sato Y, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103(3):903&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita T, Brechue WF, Kurita K, Sato Y, Abe T. Increased muscle volume and strength following six days of low-intensity resistance training with restricted muscle blood flow. Int J KAATSU Train Res. 2008;4(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gepfert M, Krzysztofik M, Kostrzewa M, Jarosz J, Trybulski R, Zajac A, et al. The acute impact of external compression on back squat performance in competitive athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(13):4674&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32610568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gossen ER, Sale DG. Effect of postactivation potentiation on dynamic knee extension performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2000;83(6):524&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11192060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen RL, Ebben WP. Kinetic analysis of complex training rest interval effect on vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(2):345&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12741876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawada S, Ishii N. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy after chronic restriction of venous blood flow in rats. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(7):1144&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16015131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent-Braun JA. Central and peripheral contributions to muscle fatigue in humans during sustained maximal effort. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1999;80(1):57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10367724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, Soderlund K, Relu MU, Ferguson RA, Bangsbo J. Heterogeneous recruitment of quadriceps muscle portions and fibre types during moderate intensity knee-extensor exercise: effect of thigh occlusion. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2009;19(4):576&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18627560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeSuer DA, McCormick JH, Mayhew JL, Wasserstein RL, Arnold MD. The accuracy of prediction equations for estimating 1-RM performance in the bench press, squat, and deadlift. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(4):211&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JJH, Kong PW. Effects of isometric and dynamic postactivation potentiation protocols on maximal sprint performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(10):2730&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23302751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthorne NP. Analysis of standing vertical jumps using a force platform. Am J Phys. 2001;69(11):1198&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Sherk VD, Thiebaud RS, Abe T, et al. Effects of cuff width on arterial occlusion: implications for blood flow restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(8):2903&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4133131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22143843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Kim D, Fahs CA, Thiebaud RS, Abe T, Larson RD, et al. Effects of exercise with and without different degrees of blood flow restriction on torque and muscle activation. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51(5):713&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25187395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Pujol TJ. The use of occlusion training to produce muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J. 2009;31(3):77&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson GJ, Wilson JM. A mechanistic approach to blood flow occlusion. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31(01):1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19885776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz D. Postactivation potentiation: an introduction. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2011;6(3):234&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3164001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21904700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowery RP, Joy JM, Loenneke JP, de Souza EO, Machado M, Dudeck JE, et al. Practical blood flow restriction training increases muscle hypertrophy during a periodized resistance training programme. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2014;34(4):317&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24188499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Hernandez J, Marin PJ, Menendez H, Ferrero C, Loenneke JP, Herrero AJ. Muscular adaptations after two different volumes of blood flow-restricted training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23(2):114&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwen JA, Owens JG, Jeyasurya J. Why is it crucial to use personalized occlusion pressures in blood flow restriction (BFR) rehabilitation? J Med Biol Eng. 2019;39(2):173&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer RA, Slade JM, Towse TF, Olive JL, Forbes SC. Phosphocreatine resynthesis during recovery after exercise with blood flow occlusion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(Supplement):S349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Burgomaster KA, Schofield LM, Gibala MJ, Sale DG, Phillips SM. Neuromuscular adaptations in human muscle following low intensity resistance training with vascular occlusion. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92(4&#x2013;5):399&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Sherman WM, Shibata M, Matsumoto T, Shinohara M. Oxygen availability and motor unit activity in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1992;64(6):552&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1618195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navalta JW, Stone WJ, Lyons TS. Ethical issues relating to scientific discovery in exercise science. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7523901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta H, Kurosawa H, Ikeda H, Iwase Y, Satou N, Nakamura S. Low-load resistance muscular training with moderate restriction of blood flow after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Acta Orthop Scand. 2003;74(1):62&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12635796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins DW. Postactivation potentiation and its practical applicability: a brief review. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(2):453&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugaya M, Yasuda T, Suga T, Okita K, Abe T. Change in intramuscular inorganic phosphate during multiple sets of blood flow-restricted low-intensity exercise. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2011;31(5):411&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21771263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumide T, Sakuraba K, Sawaki K, Ohmura H, Tamura Y. Effect of resistance exercise training combined with relatively low vascular occlusion. J Sci Med Sport Sports Med Aust. 2009;12(1):107&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(1):61&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Ishii N. Applications of vascular occlusion diminish disuse atrophy of knee extensor muscles. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(12):2035&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11128848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Tanaka Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(6):2097&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Till KA, Cooke C. The effects of postactivation potentiation on sprint and jump performance of male academy soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(7):1960&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weatherholt AM, Vanwye WR, Lohmann J, Owens JG. The effect of cuff width for determining limb occlusion pressure: a comparison of blood flow restriction devices. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12(3):136&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6355123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30761200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thomee R. Effects of vascular occlusion on muscular endurance in dynamic knee extension exercise at different submaximal loads. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(2):372&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Hisdal J, Raastad T. Contractile function and sarcolemmal permeability after acute low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(6):2051&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Krzysztofik M, Filip A, Szkudlarek A, Lockie RG, Zajac A. Does post-activation performance enhancement occur during the bench press exercise under blood flow restriction? Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(11):3752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32466396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Trybulski R, Krzysztofik M, Wojdala G, Campos Y, Zajac A, et al. Acute effects of different blood flow restriction protocols on bar velocity during the squat exercise. Front Physiol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8255669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortman RJ, Brown SM, Savage-Elliott I, Finley ZJ, Mulcahey MK. Blood flow restriction training for athletes: a systematic review. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(7):1938&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki M, Ozaki H, Sato Y, Abe T. Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(10):2525&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young WB, Jenner A, Griffiths K. Acute enhancement of power performance from heavy load squats. J Strength Cond Res. 1998;12(2):82&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>