<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32108724</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle Hypertrophy Response Is Affected by Previous Resistance Training Volume in Trained Individuals.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1153</StartPage><EndPage>1157</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1153-1157</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003558</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Scarpelli, MC, N&#xf3;brega, SR, Santanielo, N, Alvarez, IF, Otoboni, GB, Ugrinowitsch, C, and Libardi, CA. Muscle hypertrophy response is affected by previous resistance training volume in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 36(4): 1153-1157, 2022-The purpose of this study was to compare gains in muscle mass of trained individuals after a resistance training (RT) protocol with standardized (i.e., nonindividualized) volume (N-IND), with an RT protocol using individualized volume (IND). In a within-subject approach, 16 subjects had one leg randomly assigned to N-IND (22 sets&#xb7;wk-1, based on the number of weekly sets prescribed in studies) and IND (1.2 &#xd7; sets&#xb7;wk-1 recorded in training logs) protocols. Muscle cross-sectional area (CSA) was assessed by ultrasound imaging at baseline (Pre) and after 8 weeks (Post) of RT, and the significance level was set at p &lt; 0.05. Changes in the vastus lateralis CSA (difference from Pre to Post) were significantly higher for the IND protocol (p = 0.042; mean difference: 1.08 cm2; confidence interval [CI]: 0.04-2.11). The inferential analysis was confirmed by the CI of the effect size (0.75; CI: 0.03-1.47). Also, the IND protocol had a higher proportion of individuals with greater muscle hypertrophy than the typical error of the measurement (chi-square, p = 0.0035; estimated difference = 0.5, CI: 0.212-0.787). In conclusion, individualizing the weekly training volume of research protocols provides greater gains in muscle CSA than prescribing a group standard RT volume.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scarpelli</LastName><ForeName>Ma&#xed;ra C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>N&#xf3;brega</LastName><ForeName>Sanmy R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santanielo</LastName><ForeName>Natalia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alvarez</LastName><ForeName>Ieda F</ForeName><Initials>IF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otoboni</LastName><ForeName>Gabriele B</ForeName><Initials>GB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugrinowitsch</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32108724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202204000-00040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Muscle hypertrophy, hormonal adaptations and strength development during strength training in strength-trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 555&#x2013;563, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Short vs. long rest period between the sets in hypertrophic resistance training: Influence on muscle strength, size, and hormonal adaptations in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 19: 572&#x2013;582, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA. Crescent pyramid and drop-set systems do not promote greater strength gains, muscle hypertrophy, and changes on muscle architecture compared with traditional resistance training in well-trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 359&#x2013;369, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol 103: 1565&#x2013;1575, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandenburg JP, Docherty D. The effects of accentuated eccentric loading on strength, muscle hypertrophy, and neural adaptations in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 16: 25&#x2013;32, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Libardi CA, et al. Resistance training-induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. J Physiol 594: 5209&#x2013;5222, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalante G, Alencar M, Haddock B, Harvey P. The effects of phosphatidic acid supplementation on strength, body composition, muscular endurance, power, agility, and vertical jump in resistance trained men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 13: 24, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freiman JA, Chalmers TC, Smith H Jr, Kuebler RR. The importance of beta, the type II error and sample size in the design and interpretation of the randomized control trial. Survey of 71 &#x201c;negative&#x201d; trials. N Engl J Med 299: 690&#x2013;694, 1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Nagasawa M, Yanagisawa O, et al. Muscular adaptations to combinations of high- and low-intensity resistance exercises. J Strength Cond Res 18: 730&#x2013;737, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1609&#x2013;1617, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges L, Olkin I. Estimation of a single effect size: parametric and nonparametric methods. In: Statistical Methods for Meta-Analysis. New York, NY: Academic Press, 1985. pp. 75&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 674&#x2013;688, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise: A meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1890&#x2013;1901, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: A meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1150&#x2013;1159, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Bottaro M, et al. Vastus lateralis muscle cross sectional area ultrasonography validity for image-fitting in humans. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3293&#x2013;3297, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes CR, Aoki MS, Crisp AH, et al. The effect of different resistance training load schemes on strength and body composition in trained men. J Hum Kinet 58: 177&#x2013;186, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Gonzalez AM, et al. The effect of training volume and intensity on improvements in muscular strength and size in resistance-trained men. Physiol Rep 3: e12472, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PW, McEwen M, Robbins DW. Strength and neuromuscular adaptation following one, four, and eight sets of high intensity resistance exercise in trained males. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 3007&#x2013;3016, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzetti SA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, et al. The influence of direct supervision of resistance training on strength performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 32: 1175&#x2013;1184, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melville GW, Siegler JC, Marshall PW. Three and six grams supplementation of d-aspartic acid in resistance trained men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 12: 15, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melville GW, Siegler JC, Marshall PWM. The effects of d-aspartic acid supplementation in resistance-trained men over a three month training period: A randomised controlled trial. PLoS One 12: e0182630, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Robinson MJ, Fry JL, et al. Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men. Am J Clin Nutr 89: 161&#x2013;168, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, et al. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol 121: 129&#x2013;138, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Cuthill IC. Effect size, confidence interval and statistical significance: A practical guide for biologists. Biol Rev Camb Philos Soc 82: 591&#x2013;605, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobrega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs. Volitional interruption at high- and low-intensities on muscle mass and strength. J Strength Cond Res 32: 162&#x2013;169, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Buchan D, Baker JS. Weekly training frequency effects on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med Open 4: 36, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Ball SD, Phillips WT, Burkett LN. A comparison of linear and daily undulating periodized programs with equated volume and intensity for strength. J Strength Cond Res 16: 250&#x2013;255, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Haun CT, Mobley CB, et al. Physiological differences between low versus high skeletal muscle hypertrophic responders to resistance exercise training: Current perspectives and future research directions. Front Physiol 9: 834, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlumberger A, Stec J, Schmidtbleicher D. Single- vs. multiple-set strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res 15: 284&#x2013;289, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, et al. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 28: 2909&#x2013;2918, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2954&#x2013;2963, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Ogborn D, et al. Effects of varied versus constant loading zones on muscular adaptations in trained men. Int J Sports Med 37: 442&#x2013;447, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Contreras B, et al. A comparison of increases in volume load over 8 weeks of low-versus high-load resistance training. Asian J Sports Med 7: e29247, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, et al. Longer interset rest periods enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1805&#x2013;1812, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon A, Wilborn C, et al. Pre- versus post-exercise protein intake has similar effects on muscular adaptations. PeerJ 5: e2825, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SENIAM. Recommendations for sensor locations on individual muscles. Available at: http://seniam.org/sensor_location.htm . Accessed March 15, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thalacker-Mercer AE, Petrella JK, Bamman MM. Does habitual dietary intake influence myofiber hypertrophy in response to resistance training? A cluster analysis. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 34: 632&#x2013;639, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, et al. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 31: 1147&#x2013;1156, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Haff GG, Blazevich AJ, Newton RU. Acute elevations in serum hormones are attenuated after chronic training with traditional isoinertial but not accentuated eccentric loads in strength-trained men. Physiol Rep 5: e13241, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thomee R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med 37: 225&#x2013;264, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard OC, Jackman SR, Breen L, et al. Myofibrillar muscle protein synthesis rates subsequent to a meal in response to increasing doses of whey protein at rest and after resistance exercise. Am J Clin Nutr 99: 86&#x2013;95, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: Ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA 310: 2191&#x2013;2194, 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>