<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">19910330</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-1601</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>108</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of applied physiology (Bethesda, Md. : 1985)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Appl Physiol (1985)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>60</StartPage><EndPage>67</EndPage><MedlinePgn>60-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1152/japplphysiol.01147.2009</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of our study was to determine whether resistance exercise-induced elevations in endogenous hormones enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy with training. Twelve healthy young men (21.8 +/- 1.2 yr, body mass index = 23.1 +/- 0.6 kg/m(2)) trained their elbow flexors independently for 15 wk on separate days and under different hormonal milieu. In one training condition, participants performed isolated arm curl exercise designed to maintain basal hormone concentrations (low hormone, LH); in the other training condition, participants performed identical arm exercise to the LH condition followed immediately by a high volume of leg resistance exercise to elicit a large increase in endogenous hormones (high hormone, HH). There was no elevation in serum growth hormone (GH), insulin-like growth factor (IGF-1), or testosterone after the LH protocol but significant (P &lt; 0.001) elevations in these hormones immediately and 15 and 30 min after the HH protocol. The hormone responses elicited by each respective exercise protocol late in the training period were similar to the response elicited early in the training period, indicating that a divergent postexercise hormone response was maintained over the training period. Muscle cross-sectional area (CSA) increased by 12% in LH and 10% in HH (P &lt; 0.001) with no difference between conditions (condition x training interaction, P = 0.25). Similarly, type I (P &lt; 0.01) and type II (P &lt; 0.001) muscle fiber CSA increased with training with no effect of hormone elevation in the HH condition. Strength increased in both arms, but the increase was not different between the LH and HH conditions. We conclude that exposure of loaded muscle to acute exercise-induced elevations in endogenous anabolic hormones enhances neither muscle hypertrophy nor strength with resistance training in young men.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>West</LastName><ForeName>Daniel W D</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Dept. of Kinesiology, McMaster Univ., Hamilton, ON L8S4K1 Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burd</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Jason E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Daniel R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staples</LastName><ForeName>Aaron W</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holwerda</LastName><ForeName>Andrew M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baker</LastName><ForeName>Steven K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Stuart M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Appl Physiol (1985)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8502536</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0161-7567</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D045930">Anabolic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045930" MajorTopicYN="N">Anabolic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004550" MajorTopicYN="N">Elbow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01147.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01147.2009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adams GR. Autocrine/paracrine IGF-I and skeletal muscle adaptation. J Appl Physiol 93: 1159&#x2013;1167, 2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12183514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar K, Esser K. Phosphorylation of p70(S6k) correlates with increased skeletal muscle mass following resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 276: C120&#x2013;C127, 1999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, Storer TW, Berman N, Callegari C, Clevenger B, Phillips J, Bunnell TJ, Tricker R, Shirazi A, Casaburi R. The effects of supraphysiologic doses of testosterone on muscle size and strength in normal men. N Engl J Med 335: 1&#x2013;7, 1996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8637535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buresh R, Berg K, French J. The effect of resistive exercise rest interval on hormonal response, strength, and hypertrophy with training. J Strength Cond Res 23: 62&#x2013;71, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19077743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Herbert RD, Munn J, Lee M, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral strength training: evidence and possible mechanisms. J Appl Physiol 101: 1514&#x2013;1522, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17043329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Herbert RD, Munn J, Lee M, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral strength training: evidence and possible mechanisms. J Appl Physiol 101: 1514&#x2013;1522, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17043329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dill DB, Costill DL. Calculation of percentage changes in volumes of blood, plasma, and red cells in dehydration. J Appl Physiol 37: 247&#x2013;248, 1974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4850854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotshalk LA, Loebel CC, Nindl BC, Putukian M, Sebastianelli WJ, Newton RU, Hakkinen K, Kraemer WJ. Hormonal responses of multiset versus single-set heavy-resistance exercise protocols. Can J Appl Physiol 22: 244&#x2013;255, 1997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9189304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Pakarinen A. Acute hormonal responses to two different fatiguing heavy-resistance protocols in male athletes. J Appl Physiol 74: 882&#x2013;887, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8458810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen S, Kvorning T, Kjaer M, Sjogaard G. The effect of short-term strength training on human skeletal muscle: the importance of physiologically elevated hormone levels. Scand J Med Sci Sports 11: 347&#x2013;354, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman JW, Tang JE, Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Lawrence RL, Fullerton AV, Phillips SM. Consumption of fat-free fluid milk after resistance exercise promotes greater lean mass accretion than does consumption of soy or carbohydrate in young, novice, male weightlifters. Am J Clin Nutr 86: 373&#x2013;381, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, Price TB, Hoffman EP, Angelopoulos TJ, Gordon PM, Moyna NM, Pescatello LS, Visich PS, Zoeller RF, Seip RL, Clarkson PM. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 964&#x2013;972, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim PL, Staron RS, Phillips SM. Fasted-state skeletal muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise is altered with training. J Physiol 568: 283&#x2013;290, 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16051622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ. Endocrine responses to resistance exercise. In: Essentials of Strength and Conditioning , edited by Baechle TR, Earle RW. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2000, p. 91&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, Dudley GA, Dooly C, Feigenbaum MS, Fleck SJ, Franklin B, Fry AC, Hoffman JR, Newton RU, Potteiger J, Stone MH, Ratamess NA, Triplett-McBride T. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 34: 364&#x2013;380, 2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fry AC, Warren BJ, Stone MH, Fleck SJ, Kearney JT, Conroy BP, Maresh CM, Weseman CA, Triplett NT. Acute hormonal responses in elite junior weightlifters. Int J Sports Med 13: 103&#x2013;109, 1992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1555898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Marchitelli L, Gordon SE, Harman E, Dziados JE, Mello R, Frykman P, McCurry D, Fleck SJ. Hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise protocols. J Appl Physiol 69: 1442&#x2013;1450, 1990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2262468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Nindl BC, Marx JO, Gotshalk LA, Bush JA, Welsch JR, Volek JS, Spiering BA, Maresh CM, Mastro AM, Hymer WC. Chronic resistance training in women potentiates growth hormone in vivo bioactivity: characterization of molecular mass variants. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 291: E1177&#x2013;E1187, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16835404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med 35: 339&#x2013;361, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvorning T, Andersen M, Brixen K, Madsen K. Suppression of endogenous testosterone production attenuates the response to strength training: a randomized, placebo-controlled, and blinded intervention study. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 291: E1325&#x2013;E1332, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16868226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly LP, Handelsman DJ. Empirical estimation of free testosterone from testosterone and sex hormone-binding globulin immunoassays. Eur J Endocrinol 152: 471&#x2013;478, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15757865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall JD, Gibala MJ, Tarnopolsky MA, Macdonald JR, Interisano SA, Yarasheski KE. The time course for elevated muscle protein synthesis following heavy resistance exercise. Can J Appl Physiol 20: 480&#x2013;486, 1995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8563679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauras N. Growth hormone and sex steroids. Interactions in puberty. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 30: 529&#x2013;544, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11571929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall GE, Byrnes WC, Fleck SJ, Dickinson A, Kraemer WJ. Acute and chronic hormonal responses to resistance training designed to promote muscle hypertrophy. Can J Appl Physiol 24: 96&#x2013;107, 1999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Tang JE, Burd NA, Rerecich T, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Differential stimulation of myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic protein synthesis with protein ingestion at rest and after resistance exercise. J Physiol 587: 897&#x2013;904, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2669978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 273: E99&#x2013;E107, 1997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housch TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ, Triplett NT. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, Maresh CM, Vanheest JL, Sharman MJ, Rubin MR, French DN, Vescovi JD, Silvestre R, Hatfield DL, Fleck SJ, Deschenes MR. Androgen receptor content following heavy resistance exercise in men. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol 93: 35&#x2013;42, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15748830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 20: S135&#x2013;S145, 1988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3057313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering BA, Kraemer WJ, Anderson JM, Armstrong LE, Nindl BC, Volek JS, Maresh CM. Resistance exercise biology: manipulation of resistance exercise programme variables determines the responses of cellular and molecular signalling pathways. Sports Med 38: 527&#x2013;540, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18557656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering BA, Kraemer WJ, Vingren JL, Ratamess NA, Anderson JM, Armstrong LE, Nindl BC, Volek JS, Hakkinen K, Maresh CM. Elevated endogenous testosterone concentrations potentiate muscle androgen receptor responses to resistance exercise. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol 114: 195&#x2013;199, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19429451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart BG, Tarnopolsky MA, Hicks AL, McCartney N, Mahoney DJ, Staron RS, Phillips SM. Treadmill training-induced adaptations in muscle phenotype in persons with incomplete spinal cord injury. Muscle Nerve 30: 61&#x2013;68, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Manolakos JJ, Kujbida GW, Lysecki PJ, Moore DR, Phillips SM. Minimal whey protein with carbohydrate stimulates muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise in trained young men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 32: 1132&#x2013;1138, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18059587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tannerstedt J, Apro W, Blomstrand E. Maximal lengthening contractions induce different signaling responses in the type I and type II fibers of human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol 106: 1412&#x2013;1418, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19112158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzis G, Georgiadis G, Stratakos G, Vogiatzis I, Kavouras S, Manta P, Mascher H, Blomstrand E. Resistance exercise-induced increase in muscle mass correlates with p70S6 kinase phosphorylation in human subjects. Eur J Appl Physiol 102: 145&#x2013;152, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17874120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Kujbida GW, Moore D, Atherton PJ, Burd NA, Padzik JP, Delisio M, Tang JE, Parise G, Rennie MJ, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise-induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J Physiol 587: 5239&#x2013;5247, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19736298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Grant EJ, Correia CE, Phillips SM. Hypertrophy with unilateral resistance exercise occurs without increases in endogenous anabolic hormone concentration. Eur J Appl Physiol 98: 546&#x2013;555, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16972050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Macdonald MJ, Macdonald JR, Armstrong D, Phillips SM. Consumption of fluid skim milk promotes greater muscle protein accretion after resistance exercise than does consumption of an isonitrogenous and isoenergetic soy-protein beverage. Am J Clin Nutr 85: 1031&#x2013;1040, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17413102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarasheski KE, Campbell JA, Smith K, Rennie MJ, Holloszy JO, Bier DM. Effect of growth hormone and resistance exercise on muscle growth in young men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 262: E261&#x2013;E267, 1992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1550219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>