<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31989681</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-0844</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cell biochemistry and function</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cell Biochem Funct</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proteomic changes in skeletal muscle of aged rats in response to resistance training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>500</StartPage><EndPage>509</EndPage><MedlinePgn>500-509</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cbf.3497</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sarcopenia is a multifactorial process defined by loss of strength and skeletal muscle mass, which leads to a reduction in muscle cross-sectional area (CSA). Although resistance training (RT) has been indicated as a tool to counteract sarcopenia, the protein profile associated with skeletal muscle adaptations remains to be determined. We investigated the effects of 12&#x2009;weeks of RT on the skeletal muscle proteome profile and CSA of young and older rats. Twenty-four animals were divided into four groups: young sedentary or trained and older sedentary or trained (six animals per group). A 12-week RT protocol was performed, which consisted of climbing a vertical ladder. The proteins from the gastrocnemius were analysed by LC-ESI-MS/MS. One-hundred and thirty-one proteins were identified, of which 28 were assessed between the groups. Ageing induced an increase in proteins associated with the glycolytic pathway, transport and stress response, which represent crucial mechanisms for muscle adaptation. RT upregulated metabolic enzymes, anti-oxidant activity and transport proteins, besides increasing hypertrophy, regardless of age, suggesting a beneficial adaptation to mitigate age-related sarcopenia. RT reduced muscle atrophy through the regulation of stress response and by increasing proteins related to energy production and transport, which in turn might protect tissue damage arising from exercise and ageing. SIGNIFICANCE OF THE STUDY: Protein abundance levels related to the metabolic process and stress response were increased in the aged muscle. RT proved to be an important intervention capable of inducing significant effects on muscle proteome regardless of ageing, due to upregulation of glycolytic enzymes, and anti-oxidant and transport proteins. This effect could lead to a beneficial adaptation in muscle structure, cellular function and overall homeostasis maintenance. This study contributes to better understanding of the basic biology of ageing and clarifies more profoundly the molecular networks behind physiological adaptations promoted by exercise training. Therefore, the results open new perspectives and insights for studies based on transcriptomics, metabolomics and functional assays.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Sousa Neto</LastName><ForeName>Ivo Vieira</ForeName><Initials>IV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1479-5866</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias e Tecnologias em Sa&#xfa;de, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carvalho</LastName><ForeName>Marcia Mendes</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marqueti</LastName><ForeName>Rita de Cassia</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias e Tecnologias em Sa&#xfa;de, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias da Reabilita&#xe7;&#xe3;o, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almeida</LastName><ForeName>Jeeser Alves</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3409-8005</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pesquisa em Exerc&#xed;cio e Nutri&#xe7;&#xe3;o na Sa&#xfa;de e Rendimento Esportivo - PENSARE, Programa de P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias do Movimento, Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul - UFMS, Campo Grande, MS, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Kl&#xe9;ber de S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de An&#xe1;lises Prote&#xf4;micas e Bioqu&#xed;micas, P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias Gen&#xf4;micas e Biotecnologia, Universidade Cat&#xf3;lica de Bras&#xed;lia - UCB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barin</LastName><ForeName>Fabr&#xed;cio R</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias e Tecnologias em Sa&#xfa;de, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petriz</LastName><ForeName>Bernardo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de An&#xe1;lises Prote&#xf4;micas e Bioqu&#xed;micas, P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias Gen&#xf4;micas e Biotecnologia, Universidade Cat&#xf3;lica de Bras&#xed;lia - UCB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Ara&#xfa;jo</LastName><ForeName>Heloisa Sobreiro Selistre</ForeName><Initials>HSS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias Fisiol&#xf3;gicas, Universidade Federal de S&#xe3;o Carlos - UFSCar, S&#xe3;o Carlos, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franco</LastName><ForeName>Oct&#xe1;vio Luiz</ForeName><Initials>OL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de An&#xe1;lises Prote&#xf4;micas e Bioqu&#xed;micas, P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias Gen&#xf4;micas e Biotecnologia, Universidade Cat&#xf3;lica de Bras&#xed;lia - UCB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Biotecnologia, Universidade Cat&#xf3;lica Dom Bosco - UCDB, Campo Grande, MS, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durigan</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Luiz Quaglioti</ForeName><Initials>JLQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-Gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias e Tecnologias em Sa&#xfa;de, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Educa&#xe7;&#xe3;o F&#xed;sica, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Programa de P&#xf3;s-gradua&#xe7;&#xe3;o em Ci&#xea;ncias da Reabilita&#xe7;&#xe3;o, Universidade de Bras&#xed;lia - UnB, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Conselho Nacional de Desenvolvimento Cient&#xed;fico e Tecnol&#xf3;gico</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Coordena&#xe7;&#xe3;o de Aperfei&#xe7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xed;vel Superior</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cell Biochem Funct</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8305874</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0263-6484</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009124">Muscle Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000375" MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009124" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040901" MajorTopicYN="Y">Proteomics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Wistar</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LC-ESI-MS/MS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ageing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proteomic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbf.3497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>de Sousa Neto IV, Durigan JLQ, Guzzoni V, et al. Effects of resistance training on matrix metalloproteinase activity in skeletal muscles and blood circulation during aging. Front Physiol. 2018;9:190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gannon J, Ohlendieck K. Subproteomic analysis of basic proteins in aged skeletal muscle following offgel pre-fractionation. Mol Med Rep. 2012;5(4):993-1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connell K, Ohlendieck K. Proteomic DIGE analysis of the mitochondria-enriched fraction from aged rat skeletal muscle. Proteomics. 2009;9(24):5509-5524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnke BJ, Ramsey MW, Stabley JN, et al. Effects of aging and exercise training on skeletal muscle blood flow and resistance artery morphology. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2012;113(11):1699-1708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norheim F, Raastad T, Thiede B, Rustan AC, Drevon CA, Haugen F. Proteomic identification of secreted proteins from human skeletal muscle cells and expression in response to strength training. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;301(5):E1013-E1021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petriz BA, Gomes CP, Almeida JA, et al. The effects of acute and chronic exercise on skeletal muscle proteome. J Cell Physiol. 2017;232(2):257-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burniston JG, Hoffman EP. Proteomic responses of skeletal and cardiac muscle to exercise. Expert Rev Proteomics. 2011;8(3):361-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercauteren FG, Arckens L, Quirion R. Applications and current challenges of proteomic approaches, focusing on two-dimensional electrophoresis. Amino Acids. 2007;33(3):405-414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson MM, Dasari S, Konopka AR, et al. Enhanced protein translation underlies improved metabolic and physical adaptations to different exercise training modes in young and older humans. Cell Metab. 2017;25(3):581-592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JM, Lyu Y, Pletcher SD, Promislow DEL. Proteomics and metabolomics in ageing research: from biomarkers to systems biology. Essays Biochem. 2017;61(3):379-388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn R. Comparing rat's to human's age: how older is my rat in people years? Nutrition. 2005;21(6):775-777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peviani SM, Russo TL, Durigan JL, et al. Stretching and electrical stimulation regulate the metalloproteinase-2 in rat denervated skeletal muscle. Neurol Res. 2010;32(8):891-896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durigan JL, Delfino GB, Peviani SM, et al. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation alters gene expression and delays quadriceps muscle atrophy of rats after anterior cruciate ligament transection. Muscle Nerve. 2014;49(1):120-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delfino GB, Peviani SM, Durigan JL, et al. Quadriceps muscle atrophy after anterior cruciate ligament transection involves increased mRNA levels of atrogin-1, muscle ring finger 1, and myostatin. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2013;92(5):411-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibana RA, Franco OL, Cunha GV, et al. The effects of resistance training volume on skeletal muscle proteome. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10(7):1051-1066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung YG, Stanley ER. Rapid detergent removal from peptide samples with ethyl acetate for mass spectrometry analysis. Curr Protoc Protein Sci. 2010;59(1):16-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cury RCCS NF, Melo JR, Andre MSF, et al. Label free quantitative proteomics of Qualea grandiflora Mart. (Vochysiaceae) roots indicates an aluminium requirement for growth and development. BioRxiv. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1101/396093</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk D, Franceschini A, Wyder S, et al. STRING v10: protein-protein interaction networks, integrated over the tree of life. Nucleic Acids Res. 2015;43(Database issue):D447-D452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murgia M, Toniolo L, Nagaraj N, et al. Single muscle Fiber proteomics reveals Fiber-type-specific features of human muscle aging. Cell Rep. 2017;19(11):2396-2409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doran P, O'Connell K, Gannon J, Kavanagh M, Ohlendieck K. Opposite pathobiochemical fate of pyruvate kinase and adenylate kinase in aged rat skeletal muscle as revealed by proteomic DIGE analysis. Proteomics. 2008;8(2):364-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibebunjo C, Chick JM, Kendall T, et al. Genomic and proteomic profiling reveals reduced mitochondrial function and disruption of the neuromuscular junction driving rat sarcopenia. Mol Cell Biol. 2013;33(2):194-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ubaida-Mohien C, Gonzalez-Freire M, Lyashkov A, et al. Physical activity associated proteomics of skeletal muscle: being physically active in daily life may protect skeletal muscle from aging. Front Physiol. 2019;10:312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vander Heiden MG, Lunt SY, Dayton TL, et al. Metabolic pathway alterations that support cell proliferation. Colder Spring Harb Symp Quant Biol. 2011;76:325-334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abreu P. Bioenergetics mechanisms regulating muscle stem cell self-renewal commitment and function. Biomed Pharmacother. 2018;103:463-472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohlendieck K. Proteomics of skeletal muscle glycolysis. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2010;1804(11):2089-2101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori I, Russo G, Curcio F, et al. Oxidative stress, aging, and diseases. Clin Interv Aging. 2018;13:757-772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glippa O, Engstrom-Ost J, Kanerva M, Rein A, Vuori K. Oxidative stress and antioxidant defense responses in Acartia copepods in relation to environmental factors. PLoS One. 2018;13(4):e0195981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCord JM, Edeas MA. SOD, oxidative stress and human pathologies: a brief history and a future vision. Biomed Pharmacother. 2005;59(4):139-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi SY, Lu SY, Sivasubramaniyam T, et al. DJ-1 links muscle ROS production with metabolic reprogramming and systemic energy homeostasis in mice. Nat Commun. 2015;6:7415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Waddell JN, Kuang S, Bidwell CA. Park7 expression influences myotube size and myosin expression in muscle. PLoS One. 2014;9(3):e92030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducreux S, Gregory P, Schwaller B. Inverse regulation of the cytosolic Ca(2)(+) buffer parvalbumin and mitochondrial volume in muscle cells via SIRT1/PGC-1alpha axis. PLoS One. 2012;7(9):e44837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou TT, Johnson JD, Rall JA. Role of parvalbumin in relaxation of frog skeletal muscle. Adv Exp Med Biol 1993;332:141-151; discussion 151-143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Selby A, Rankin D, et al. Age-related differences in the dose-response relationship of muscle protein synthesis to resistance exercise in young and older men. J Physiol. 2009;587(1):211-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson D, Smith K, Babraj J, et al. Anabolic signaling deficits underlie amino acid resistance of wasting, aging muscle. FASEB J. 2005;19(3):422-424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Zhao Y, Shang X, Liu X, Ren H. Expression of carbonic anhydrase III and skeletal muscle remodeling following selective denervation. Mol Med Rep. 2017;16(6):8289-8294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Fiore A, Monti DM, Scaloni A, De Simone G, Monti SM. Protective role of carbonic anhydrases III and VII in cellular defense mechanisms upon redox unbalance. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2018;2018:2018306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Lin LL, Ho TC, Chen JJ. Investigating the adaptation of muscle oxygenation to resistance training for elders and young men using near-infrared spectroscopy. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(1):187-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burge CM. Hemoglobin in exercise adaptation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2010;38(2):41.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>