<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39898972</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>604</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiological mechanisms of neuromuscular impairment in diabetes-related complications: Can physical exercise help prevent it?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>707</StartPage><EndPage>734</EndPage><MedlinePgn>707-734</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP287589</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetes mellitus is a chronic disorder that progressively induces complications, compromising daily independence. Among these, diabetic neuropathy is particularly prevalent and contributes to substantial neuromuscular impairments in both types 1 and 2 diabetes. This condition leads to structural damage affecting both the central and peripheral nervous systems, resulting in a significant decline in sensorimotor functions. Alongside neuropathy, diabetic myopathy also contributes to muscle impairment and reduced motor performance, intensifying the neuromuscular decline. Diabetic neuropathy typically implicates neurogenic muscle atrophy, motoneuron loss and clustering of muscle fibres as a result of aberrant denervation-reinervation processes. These complications are associated with compromised neuromuscular junctions, where alterations occur in pre-synaptic vesicles, mitochondrial content and post-synaptic signalling. Neural damage is intensified by chronic hyperglycaemia and oxidative stress, exacerbating vascular dysfunction and reducing oxygen delivery. These complications imply a severe decline in neuromuscular performance, evidenced by reductions in maximal force and power output, rate of force development and muscle endurance. Furthermore, diabetes-related complications are compounded by age-related degenerative changes in long-term patients. Aerobic and resistance training offer promising approaches for managing blood glucose levels and neuromuscular function. Aerobic exercise promotes mitochondrial biogenesis and angiogenesis, supporting metabolic and cardiovascular health. Resistance training primarily enhances neural plasticity, muscle strength and hypertrophy, which are crucial factors for mitigating sarcopenia and preserving functional independence. This topical review examines current evidence on the physiological mechanisms underlying diabetic neuropathy and the potential impact of physical activity in counteracting this decline.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology &#xa9; 2025 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lecce</LastName><ForeName>Edoardo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2936-9456</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Exercise Physiology, Department of Movement, Human, and Health Sciences, University of 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bellini</LastName><ForeName>Alessio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5556-7536</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Exercise Physiology, Department of Movement, Human, and Health Sciences, University of 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greco</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-5237-9247</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Exercise Physiology, Department of Movement, Human, and Health Sciences, University of 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martire</LastName><ForeName>Fiorella</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-1123-0854</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Exercise Physiology, Department of Movement, Human, and Health Sciences, University of 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scotto di Palumbo</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Exercise Physiology, Department of Movement, Human, and Health Sciences, University of 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sacchetti</LastName><ForeName>Massimo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5365-5161</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Exercise Physiology, Department of Movement, Human, and Health Sciences, University of 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazzucchi</LastName><ForeName>Ilenia</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6017-1683</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Exercise Physiology, Department of Movement, Human, and Health Sciences, University of 'Foro Italico', Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003929" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetic Neuropathies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D048909" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Complications</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise physiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39898972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP287589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Aagaard, P., Suetta, C., Caserotti, P., Magnusson, S. P., &amp; Kj&#xe6;r, M. (2010). Role of the nervous system in sarcopenia and muscle atrophy with aging: Strength training as a countermeasure. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports, 20(1), 49&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta&#x2010;Manzano, P., Rodriguez&#x2010;Ayllon, M., Acosta, F., Niederseer, D., &amp; Niebauer, J. (2020). Beyond general resistance training. Hypertrophy versus muscular endurance training as therapeutic interventions in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Obesity Reviews, 21(6), e13007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, M. D., Choi, I. H., Kimpinski, K., Doherty, T. J., &amp; Rice, C. L. (2013). Motor unit loss and weakness in association with diabetic neuropathy in humans. Muscle and Nerve, 48(2), 298&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, M. D., Doherty, T. J., Rice, C. L., &amp; Kimpinski, K. (2016). Physiology in medicine: Neuromuscular consequences of diabetic neuropathy. Journal of Applied Physiology, 121(1), 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, M. D., Kimpinski, K., Doherty, T. J., &amp; Rice, C. L. (2014). Length dependent loss of motor axons and altered motor unit properties in human diabetic polyneuropathy. Clinical Neurophysiology, 125(4), 836&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, M. D., Kimpinski, K., Doherty, T. J., &amp; Rice, C. L. (2015). Decreased muscle endurance associated with diabetic neuropathy may be attributed partially to neuromuscular transmission failure. Journal of Applied Physiology, 118(8), 1014&#x2013;1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, M. D., Major, B., Kimpinski, K., Doherty, T. J., &amp; Rice, C. L. (2014). Skeletal muscle morphology and contractile function in relation to muscle denervation in diabetic neuropathy. Journal of Applied Physiology, 116(5), 545&#x2013;552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amthor, H., Nicholas, G., McKinnell, I., Kemp, C. F., Sharma, M., Kambadur, R., &amp; Patel, K. (2004). Follistatin complexes Myostatin and antagonises Myostatin&#x2010;mediated inhibition of myogenesis. Developmental Biology, 270(1), 19&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anagnostou, M., &amp; Hepple, R. (2020). Mitochondrial mechanisms of neuromuscular junction degeneration with aging. Cells, 9(1), 197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, H. (1999). Motor function in diabetic neuropathy. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica, 100(4), 211&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, H. (2012). Motor dysfunction in diabetes. Diabetes/Metabolism Research and Reviews, 28(Suppl 1), 89&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, H., Nielsen, S., Mogensen, C. E., &amp; Jakobsen, J. (2004). Muscle strength in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes, 53(6), 1543&#x2013;1548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, H., Poulsen, P. L., Mogensen, C. E., &amp; Jakobsen, J. (1996). Isokinetic muscle strength in long&#x2010;term IDDM patients in relation to diabetic complications. Diabetes, 45(4), 440&#x2013;445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, H., St&#xe5;lberg, E., Gjerstad, M. D., &amp; Jakobsen, J. (1998). Association of muscle strength and electrophysiological measures of reinnervation in diabetic neuropathy. Muscle and Nerve, 21(12), 1647&#x2013;1654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreassen, C. S., Jakobsen, J., &amp; Andersen, H. (2006). Muscle weakness: A progressive late complication in diabetic distal symmetric polyneuropathy. Diabetes, 55(3), 806&#x2013;812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashcroft, S. P., Stocks, B., Egan, B., &amp; Zierath, J. R. (2024). Exercise induces tissue&#x2010;specific adaptations to enhance cardiometabolic health. Cell Metabolism, 36(2), 278&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assar, M. E.l, Laosa, O., &amp; Ma&#xf1;as, L. R. (2019). Diabetes and frailty. Current Opinion in Clinical Nutrition and Metabolic Care, 22(1), 52&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avaltroni, P., Cappellini, G., Sylos&#x2010;Labini, F., Ivanenko, Y., &amp; Lacquaniti, F. (2024). Spinal maps of motoneuron activity during human locomotion: Neuromechanical considerations. Frontiers in Physiology, 15, 1389436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi, E., Negri, C., Zanolin, M. E., Milanese, C., Faccioli, N., Trombetta, M., Zoppini, G., Cevese, A., Bonadonna, R. C., Schena, F., Bonora, E., Lanza, M., &amp; Moghetti, P. (2012). Metabolic effects of aerobic training and resistance training in type 2 diabetic subjects: A randomized controlled trial (the RAED2 study). Diabetes Care, 35(4), 676&#x2013;682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badrah, M. H., Abdelaaty, T. A., Imbaby, S. A. E., Abdel&#x2010;Fattah, Y. H., Silim, W. M., &amp; El Feky, A. Y. (2022). The relationship between vascular endothelial growth factor&#x2010;A serum level and the severity of diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Egyptian Rheumatology and Rehabilitation, 49(1), 247&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahadoran, Z., Mirmiran, P., Kashfi, K., &amp; Ghasemi, A. (2023). Vascular nitric oxide resistance in type 2 diabetes. In Cell Death and Disease (Vol., 14, Issue 7). Springer Nature.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balducci, S., Iacobellis, G., Parisi, L., Di Biase, N., Calandriello, E., Leonetti, F., &amp; Fallucca, F. (2006). Exercise training can modify the natural history of diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Journal of Diabetes and Its Complications, 20(4), 216&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balducci, S., Zanuso, S., Nicolucci, A., Fernando, F., Cavallo, S., Cardelli, P., Fallucca, S., Alessi, E., Letizia, C., Jimenez, A., Fallucca, F., &amp; Pugliese, G. (2010). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory effect of exercise training in subjects with type 2 diabetes and the metabolic syndrome is dependent on exercise modalities and independent of weight loss. Nutrition, Metabolism and Cardiovascular Diseases, 20(8), 608&#x2013;617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballabh, P., Braun, A., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2004). The blood&#x2010;brain barrier: An overview: Structure, regulation, and clinical implications. Neurobiology of Disease, 16(1), 1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannister, K. (2019). Descending pain modulation: Influence and impact. Current Opinion in Physiology, 11, 62&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannister, K., &amp; Dickenson, A. H. (2017). The plasticity of descending controls in pain: Translational probing. The Journal of Physiology, 595(13), 4159&#x2013;4166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barakou, I., Sakalidis, K. E., Abonie, U. S., Finch, T., Hackett, K. L., &amp; Hettinga, F. J. (2023). Effectiveness of physical activity interventions on reducing perceived fatigue among adults with chronic conditions: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of randomised controlled trials. Scientific Reports, 13(1), 14582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu, R., Johnson, M. L., Kudva, Y. C., &amp; Basu, A. (2014). Exercise, hypoglycemia, and type 1 diabetes. In Diabetes Technology and Therapeutics (Vol., 16, Issue 6, pp. 331&#x2013;337). Mary Ann Liebert Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baynes, J. W. (1991). Role of oxidative stress in development of complications in diabetes. Diabetes, 40(4), 405&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzucchi, I., De Vito, G., Felici, F., Dewhurst, S., Sgadari, A., &amp; Sacchetti, M. (2015). Effect of exercise training on neuromuscular function of elbow flexors and knee extensors of type 2 diabetic patients. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology, 25(5), 815&#x2013;823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens, M., Gube, M., Chaabene, H., Prieske, O., Zenon, A., Broscheid, K. C., Schega, L., Husmann, F., &amp; Weippert, M. (2023). Fatigue and human performance: An updated framework. Sports Medicine, 53(1), 7&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigi, S., Shabkhiz, F., Kordi, M., Haghi&#x2010;Ashtiani, B., Hashemi&#x2010;Madani, N., &amp; Zmijewski, P. (2023). The effects of a 10&#x2010;week aerobic and unilateral lower extremity resistance training program on amplitude and nerve conduction velocity of sensory and motor nerves in diabetic patients with neuropathy. Journal of Human Kinetics, 87, 93&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellini, A., Nicol&#xf2;, A., Bulzom&#xec;, R., Bazzucchi, I., &amp; Sacchetti, M. (2021). The effect of different postprandial exercise types on glucose response to breakfast in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Nutrients, 13(5), 1440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellini, A., Nicol&#xf2;, A., Rocchi, J. E., Bazzucchi, I., &amp; Sacchetti, M. (2023). Walking attenuates postprandial glycemic response: What else can we do without leaving home or the office? International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 20(1), 253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellini, A., Scotto di Palumbo, A., Nicol&#xf2;, A., Bazzucchi, I., &amp; Sacchetti, M. (2024). Exercise prescription for postprandial glycemic management. Nutrients, 16(8), 1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensellam, M., Laybutt, D. R., &amp; Jonas, J. C. (2012). The molecular mechanisms of pancreatic &#x3b2;&#x2010;cell glucotoxicity: Recent findings and future research directions. Molecular and Cellular Endocrinology, 364(1&#x2013;2), 1&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilchak, J. N., Caron, G., &amp; C&#xf4;t&#xe9;, M. P. (2021). Exercise&#x2010;induced plasticity in signaling pathways involved in motor recovery after spinal cord injury. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 22(9), 4858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird, S. R., &amp; Hawley, J. A. (2017). Update on the effects of physical activity on insulin sensitivity in humans. British Medical Journal Open Sport and Exercise Medicine, 2(1), e000143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair, N. T., &amp; Bean, B. P. (2002). Roles of tetrodotoxin (TTX)&#x2010;sensitive Na+ current, TTX&#x2010;resistant Na+ current, and Ca2+ current in the action potentials of nociceptive sensory neurons. Journal of Neuroscience, 22(23), 10277&#x2013;10290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boul&#xe9;, N. G., Kenny, G. P., Haddad, E., Wells, G. A., &amp; Sigal, R. J. (2003). Meta&#x2010;analysis of the effect of structured exercise training on cardiorespiratory fitness in Type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetologia, 46(8), 1071&#x2013;1081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull, F. C., Al&#x2010;Ansari, S. S., Biddle, S., Borodulin, K., Buman, M. P., Cardon, G., Carty, C., Chaput, J. P., Chastin, S., Chou, R., Dempsey, P. C., Dipietro, L., Ekelund, U., Firth, J., Friedenreich, C. M., Garcia, L., Gichu, M., Jago, R., Katzmarzyk, P. T., &#x2026; Willumsen, J. F. (2020). World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. In British Journal of Sports Medicine (Vol., 54, Issue 24, pp. 1451&#x2013;1462). BMJ Publishingxbrk Group.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd, N. A., Andrews, R. J., West, D. W. D., Little, J. P., Cochran, A. J. R., Hector, A. J., Cashaback, J. G. A., Gibala, M. J., Potvin, J. R., Baker, S. K., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2012). Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub&#x2010;fractional synthetic responses in men. The Journal of Physiology, 590(2), 351&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calder&#xf3;n, J. C., Bola&#xf1;os, P., &amp; Caputo, C. (2014). The excitation&#x2010;contraction coupling mechanism in skeletal muscle. Biophysical Reviews, 6(1), 133&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaghan, B., &amp; Feldman, E. (2013). The metabolic syndrome and neuropathy: Therapeutic challenges and opportunities. Annals of Neurology, 74(3), 397&#x2013;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cefis, M., Chaney, R., Wirtz, J., M&#xe9;loux, A., Quiri&#xe9;, A., Leger, C., Prigent&#x2010;Tessier, A., &amp; Garnier, P. (2023). Molecular mechanisms underlying physical exercise&#x2010;induced brain BDNF overproduction. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 16, 1275924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceriello, A., Esposito, K., Inhant, M., Thorpe, J., &amp; Giuliano, D. (2010). Effect of acute hyperglycaemia, long&#x2010;term glycaemic control and insulin on endothelial dysfunction and inflammation in Type 1 diabetic patients with different characteristics. Diabetic Medicine, 27(8), 911&#x2013;917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceriello, A., &amp; Ihnat, M. (2010). &#x2018;Glycaemic variability&#x2019;: A new therapeutic challenge in diabetes and the critical care setting. Diabetic Medicine, 27(8), 862&#x2013;867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceriello, A., Quagliaro, L., Piconi, L., Assaloni, R., Da Ros, R., Maier, A., Esposito, K., &amp; Giugliano, D. (2004). Effect of postprandial hypertriglyceridemia and hyperglycemia on circulating adhesion molecules and oxidative stress generation and the possible role of simvastatin treatment. http://diabetesjournals.org/diabetes/article&#x2010;pdf/53/3/701/656831/zdb00304000701.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cernea, S., &amp; Raz, I. (2021). Management of diabetic neuropathy. Metabolism: Clinical and Experimental, 123, 154867.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, M. C., Park, C. R., Rhie, S. H., Shim, W. H., &amp; Kim, D. Y. (2019). Early treadmill exercise increases macrophage migration inhibitory factor expression after cerebral ischemia/reperfusion. Neural Regeneration Research, 14(7), 1230&#x2013;1236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavanelle, V., Boisseau, N., Otero, Y. F., Combaret, L., Dardevet, D., Montaurier, C., Delcros, G., Peltier, S. L., &amp; Sirvent, P. (2017). Effects of high&#x2010;intensity interval training and moderate&#x2010;intensity continuous training on glycaemic control and skeletal muscle mitochondrial function in db/db mice. Scientific Reports, 7(1), 204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Zhou, R., Feng, Y., &amp; Cheng, L. (2022). Molecular mechanisms of exercise contributing to tissue regeneration. Signal Transduction and Targeted Therapy, 7(1), 383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, S. E., &amp; Rush, E. B. (2012). Effect of a short&#x2010;duration, culturally tailored, community&#x2010;based diabetes self&#x2010;management intervention for korean immigrants: A pilot study. The Diabetes Educator, 38(3), 377&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow, L. S., Gerszten, R. E., Taylor, J. M., Pedersen, B. K., van Praag, H., Trappe, S., Febbraio, M. A., Galis, Z. S., Gao, Y., Haus, J. M., Lanza, I. R., Lavie, C. J., Lee, C. H., Lucia, A., Moro, C., Pandey, A., Robbins, J. M., Stanford, K. I., Thackray, A. E., &#x2026; Snyder, M. P. (2022). Exerkines in health, resilience and disease. Nature Reviews Endocrinology, 18(5), 273&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cigrovski Berkovic, M., Bilic&#x2010;Curcic, I., La Grasta Sabolic, L., Mrzljak, A., &amp; Cigrovski, V. (2021). Fear of hypoglycemia, a game changer during physical activity in type 1 diabetes mellitus patients. World Journal of Diabetes, 12(5), 569&#x2013;577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey, V. G., &amp; Hawley, J. A. (2017). Concurrent exercise training: Do opposites distract? In Journal of Physiology (Vol., 595, Issue 9, pp. 2883&#x2013;2896). Blackwell Publishing Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colberg, S. R., Sigal, R. J., Yardley, J. E., Riddell, M. C., Dunstan, D. W., Dempsey, P. C., Horton, E. S., Castorino, K., &amp; Tate, D. F. (2016). Physical activity/exercise and diabetes: A position statement of the American Diabetes Association. In Diabetes Care (Vol., 39, Issue 11, pp. 2065&#x2013;2079). American Diabetes Association Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppey, L. J., Davidson, E. P., Dunlap, J. A., Lund, D. D., &amp; Yorek, M. A. (2000). Slowing of motor nerve conduction velocity in streptozotocin&#x2010;induced diabetic rats is preceded by impaired vasodilation in arterioles that overlie the sciatic nerve. Experimental Diabesity Research, 1(2), 131&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Antona, G., Pellegrino, M. A., Adami, R., Rossi, R., Naccari Carlizzi, C., Canepari, M., Saltin, B., &amp; Bottinelli, R. (2003). The effect of ageing and immobilization on structure and function of human skeletal muscle fibres. The Journal of Physiology, 552(2), 499&#x2013;511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira, V. N., Bessa, A., Jorge, M. L. M. P., da Silva Oliveira, R. J., de Mello, M. T., de Agostini, G. G., Jorge, P. T., &amp; Espindola, F. S. (2012). The effect of different training programs on antioxidant status, oxidative stress, and metabolic control in type 2 diabetes. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism, 37(2), 334&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Vecchio, A., Enoka, R. M., &amp; Farina, D. (2024). Specificity of early motor unit adaptations with resistive exercise training. The Journal of Physiology, 602(12), 2679&#x2013;2688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Vecchio, A., Negro, F., Holobar, A., Casolo, A., Folland, J. P., Felici, F., &amp; Farina, D. (2019). You are as fast as your motor neurons: Speed of recruitment and maximal discharge of motor neurons determine the maximal rate of force development in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 597(9), 2445&#x2013;2456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delevatti, R. S., Bracht, C. G., Lisboa, S. D. C., Costa, R. R., Marson, E. C., Netto, N., &amp; Kruel, L. F. M. (2019). The role of aerobic training variables progression on glycemic control of patients with type 2 diabetes: A systematic review with meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Medicine &#x2010; Open, 5(1), 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes, M. R. (2019). Adaptations of the neuromuscular junction to exercise training. Current Opinion in Physiology, 10, 10&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixit, S., Maiya, A., &amp; Shastry, B. (2014). Effect of aerobic exercise on quality of life in population with diabetic peripheral neuropathy in type 2 diabetes: A single blind, randomized controlled trial. Quality of Life Research, 23(5), 1629&#x2013;1640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobson, J. L., McMillan, J., &amp; Li, L. (2014). Benefits of exercise intervention in reducing neuropathic pain. In Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience (Vol., 8, Issue 1 APR). Frontiers Research Foundation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Souza, D. M., Al&#x2010;Sajee, D., &amp; Hawke, T. J. (2013). Diabetic myopathy: Impact of diabetes mellitus on skeletal muscle progenitor cells. Frontiers in Physiology, 4, 379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubin, A. E., &amp; Patapoutian, A. (2010). Nociceptors: The sensors of the pain pathway. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 120(11), 3760&#x2013;3772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau, J., &amp; Enoka, R. M. (2011). Human motor unit recordings: Origins and insight into the integrated motor system. Brain Research, 1409, 42&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>English, A. W., Wilhelm, J. C., &amp; Ward, P. J. (2014). Exercise, neurotrophins, and axon regeneration in the PNS. Physiology, 29(6), 437&#x2013;445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka, R. M., &amp; Fuglevand, A. J. (2001). Motor unit physiology: Some unresolved issues. Muscle and Nerve, 24(1), 4&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada&#x2010;Bonilla, Y. C., Castro, P. A. T. S., Luna, G. L. F., Souza, A. B. A., Santos, G. S., Salvini, T. F., Leal, A. M. O., &amp; Russo, T. L. (2020). Reaching task performance is associated to neuromuscular junction adaptations in rats with induced diabetes mellitus. Brazilian Journal of Medical and Biological Research, 53(7), e8763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahim, M. A., El&#x2010;Sabban, F., &amp; Davidson, N. (1998). Muscle contractility decrement and correlated morphology during the pathogenesis of streptozotocin&#x2010;diabetic mice. Anatomical Record, 251(2), 240&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahim, M. A., Hasan, M. Y., &amp; Alshuaib, W. B. (2000). Early morphological remodeling of neuromuscular junction in a murine model of diabetes. Journal of Applied Physiology, 89(6), 2235&#x2013;2240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, F., Luo, Q., Ge, R. B., Lai, M. Y., Gong, Y. J., Kang, M., Ma, M. M., Zhang, L., Li, Y., Wang, Y. F., &amp; Peng, Y. D.e (2021). Decreased microstructural integrity of the central somatosensory tracts in diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism, 106(6), 1566&#x2013;1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina, D., &amp; Gandevia, S. (2024). The neural control of movement: A century of in vivo motor unit recordings is the legacy of Adrian and Bronk. The Journal of Physiology, 602(2), 281&#x2013;295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favretto, M. A., Andreis, F. R., Cossul, S., Negro, F., Oliveira, A. S., &amp; Marques, J. L. B. (2023). Differences in motor unit behavior during isometric contractions in patients with diabetic peripheral neuropathy at various disease severities. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology, 68, 102725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favretto, M. A., Cossul, S., Andreis, F. R., &amp; Marques, J. L. B. (2019). Evaluation of rate of muscular force development in type 2 diabetic individuals with and without diabetic peripheral neuropathy. International Federation for Medical and Biological Engineering Proceedings, 70(1), 31&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman, E. L., Callaghan, B. C., Pop&#x2010;Busui, R., Zochodne, D. W., Wright, D. E., Bennett, D. L., Bril, V., Russell, J. W., &amp; Viswanathan, V. (2019). Diabetic neuropathy. In Nature Reviews Disease Primers (Vol., 5, Issue 1). Nature Publishing Group.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman, E. L., Nave, K. A., Jensen, T. S., &amp; Bennett, D. L. H. (2017). New horizons in diabetic neuropathy: Mechanisms, bioenergetics, and pain. Neuron, 93(6), 1296&#x2013;1313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes, J. M., &amp; Cooper, M. E. (2013). Mechanisms of diabetic complications. Physiological Reviews, 93(1), 137&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis, G. J., Martinez, J. A., Liu, W. Q., Zochodne, D. W., Hanson, L. R., Frey, W. H., &amp; Toth, C. (2011). Motor end plate innervation loss in diabetes and the role of insulin. Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology, 70(5), 323&#x2013;339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritschi, C., &amp; Quinn, L. (2010). Fatigue in patients with diabetes: A review. Journal of Psychosomatic Research, 69(1), 33&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fueger, P. T., Li, C. Y., Ayala, J. E., Shearer, J., Bracy, D. P., Charron, M. J., Rottman, J. N., &amp; Wasserman, D. H. (2007). Glucose kinetics and exercise tolerance in mice lacking the GLUT4 glucose transporter. The Journal of Physiology, 582(2), 801&#x2013;812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia, S. C. (2001). Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiological Reviews, 81(4), 1725&#x2013;1789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia, S. C., Macefield, G., Burke, D., &amp; Mckenzie, D. K. (1990). Voluntary activation of human motor axons in the absence of muscle afferent feedback: The control of the deafferented hand. Brain, 113(5), 1563&#x2013;1581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia, C. C., Potian, J. G., Hognason, K., Thyagarajan, B., Sultatos, L. G., Souayah, N., Routh, V. H., &amp; McArdle, J. J. (2012). Acetylcholinesterase deficiency contributes to neuromuscular junction dysfunction in type 1 diabetic neuropathy. American Journal of Physiology &#x2010; Endocrinology and Metabolism, 303(4), E551&#x2013;E561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholami, F., Nikookheslat, S., Salekzamani, Y., Boule, N., &amp; Jafari, A. (2018). Effect of aerobic training on nerve conduction in men with type 2 diabetes and peripheral neuropathy: A randomized controlled trial. Neurophysiologie Clinique, 48(4), 195&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacco, F., &amp; Brownlee, M. (2010). Oxidative stress and diabetic complications. Circulation Research, 107(9), 1058&#x2013;1070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannopoulou, I., Fernhall, B., Carhart, R., Weinstock, R. S., Baynard, T., Figueroa, A., &amp; Kanaley, J. A. (2005). Effects of diet and/or exercise on the adipocytokine and inflammatory cytokine levels of postmenopausal women with type 2 diabetes. Metabolism: Clinical and Experimental, 54(7), 866&#x2013;875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giugliano, D., Ceriello, A., &amp; Paolisso, G. (1996). Oxidative stress and diabetic vascular complications. Diabetes Care, 19(3), 257&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goulding, R. P., Roche, D. M., Scott, S. N., Koga, S., Weston, P. J., &amp; Marwood, S. (2020). Limitations to exercise tolerance in type 1 diabetes: The role of pulmonary oxygen uptake kinetics and priming exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology, 128(5), 1299&#x2013;1309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen, B. B. L., Hamer, H. M., Snijders, T., Van Kranenburg, J., Frijns, D., Vink, H., &amp; Van Loon, L. J. C. (2014). Skeletal muscle capillary density and microvascular function are compromised with aging and type 2 diabetes. Journal of Applied Physiology, 116(8). https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00919.2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groover, A. L., Ryals, J. M., Guilford, B. L., Wilson, N. M., Christianson, J. A., &amp; Wright, D. E. (2013). Exercise&#x2010;mediated improvements in painful neuropathy associated with prediabetes in mice. Pain, 154(12), 2658&#x2013;2667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, Y., Qiu, Z. L., Liu, D. Z., Sun, G. L., Guan, Y. C., Hei, Z. Q., &amp; Li, X. (2018). Differential gene expression profiling of the sciatic nerve in type 1 and type 2 diabetic mice. Biomedical Reports, 9(4), 291&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haines, M. S., Leong, A., Porneala, B. C., Meigs, J. B., &amp; Miller, K. K. (2022). Association between muscle mass and diabetes prevalence independent of body fat distribution in adults under 50 years old. Nutrition and Diabetes, 12(1), 29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajer, G. R., van Haeften, T. W., &amp; Visseren, F. L. J. (2008). Adipose tissue dysfunction in obesity, diabetes, and vascular diseases. European Heart Journal, 29(24), 2959&#x2013;2971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halling, J. F., &amp; Pilegaard, H. (2020). PGC&#x2010;1&#x3b1;&#x2010;mediated regulation of mitochondrial function and physiological implications. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism, 45(9), 927&#x2013;936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid, W. S., Ahmed, H. S., Osman, M. A., &amp; Babiker, R. (2021). Nerve conduction and its correlations with duration of diabetes mellitus and glycosylated haemoglobin in type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Journal of Endocrinology, Metabolism and Diabetes of South Africa, 26(2), 46&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque, F., Reaz, M. B. I., Ali, S. H. M., Arsad, N., &amp; Chowdhury, M. E. H. (2020). Performance analysis of noninvasive electrophysiological methods for the assessment of diabetic sensorimotor polyneuropathy in clinical research: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis with trial sequential analysis. Scientific Reports, 10(1), 21770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding, J. L., Pavkov, M. E., Magliano, D. J., Shaw, J. E., &amp; Gregg, E. W. (2019). Global trends in diabetes complications: A review of current evidence. Diabetologia, 62(1), 3&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haxhi, J., &amp; Bellini, A. (2024). Esercizio fisico nel diabete mellito di tipo 1. L'Endocrinologo, 62, 436&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckman, C. J., &amp; Enoka, R. M. (2012). Motor unit. Comprehensive Physiology, 2(4), 2629&#x2013;2682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms, E. R., Cronin, J., Storey, A., &amp; Zourdos, M. C. (2016). Application of the repetitions in reserve&#x2010;based rating of perceived exertion scale for resistance training. Strength &amp; Conditioning Journal, 38(4), 42&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman, E. (1957). Relation between size of neurons and their susceptibility to discharge. Science, 126(3287), 1345&#x2013;1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hepple, R. T., &amp; Rice, C. L. (2016). Innervation and neuromuscular control in ageing skeletal muscle. In Journal of Physiology (Vol., 594, Issue 8, pp. 1965&#x2013;1978). Blackwell Publishing Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez, E. O., &amp; Camilo Vanegas, O. (2015). Diabetic myopathy and mechanisms of disease. Biochemistry &amp; Pharmacology: Open Access, 04(05), e179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heroux, M. E., Butler, A. A., Robertson, L. S., Fisher, G., &amp; Gandevia, S. C. (2022). Proprioception: A new look at an old concept. Journal of Applied Physiology, 132(3), 811&#x2013;814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks, C. W., &amp; Selvin, E. (2019). Epidemiology of peripheral neuropathy and lower extremity disease in diabetes. Current Diabetes Reports, 19(10), 86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilton, T. N., Tuttle, L. J., Bohnert, K. L., Mueller, M. J., &amp; Sinacore, D. R. (2008). Excessive adipose tissue infiltration in skeletal muscle in individuals with obesity, diabetes mellitus, and peripheral neuropathy: Association with performance and function. Physical Therapy, 88(11), 1336&#x2013;1344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, N., Sommers, M. S., &amp; Lucki, I. (2013). Effects of diabetes on hippocampal neurogenesis: Links to cognition and depression. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews, 37(8), 1346&#x2013;1362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holst, J. J. (2007). The physiology of glucagon&#x2010;like peptide 1. Physiological Reviews, 87(4), 1409&#x2013;1439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huebschmann, A. G., Kohrt, W. M., Herlache, L., Wolfe, P., Daugherty, S., Reusch, J. E., Bauer, T. A., &amp; Regensteiner, J. G. (2015). Type 2 diabetes exaggerates exercise effort and impairs exercise performance in older women. British Medical Journal Open Diabetes Research &amp; Care, 3(1), e000124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes, T. M., Ryan, C. M., Aizenstein, H. J., Nunley, K., Gianaros, P. J., Miller, R., Costacou, T., Strotmeyer, E. S., Orchard, T. J., &amp; Rosano, C. (2013). Frontal gray matter atrophy in middle aged adults with type 1 diabetes is independent of cardiovascular risk factors and diabetes complications. Journal of Diabetes and Its Complications, 27(6), 558&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huiberts, R. O., W&#xfc;st, R. C. I., &amp; van der Zwaard, S. (2024). Concurrent strength and endurance training: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis on the impact of sex and training status. In Sports Medicine (Vol., 54, Issue 2, pp. 485&#x2013;503). Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hur, J., O'Brien, P. D., Nair, V., Hinder, L. M., McGregor, B. A., Jagadish, H. V., Kretzler, M., Brosius, F. C., &amp; Feldman, E. L. (2016). Transcriptional networks of murine diabetic peripheral neuropathy and nephropathy: Common and distinct gene expression patterns. Diabetologia, 59(6), 1297&#x2013;1306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagodic, M. M., Pathirathna, S., Nelson, M. T., Mancuso, S., Joksovic, P. M., Rosenberg, E. R., Bayliss, D. A., Jevtovic&#x2010;Todorovic, V., &amp; Todorovic, S. M. (2007). Cell&#x2010;specific alterations of T&#x2010;type calcium current in painful diabetic neuropathy enhance excitability of sensory neurons. Journal of Neuroscience, 27(12), 3305&#x2013;3316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jingjing, T., Fan, J., &amp; Zhang, T. (2023). Mitochondria as a target for exercise&#x2010;mitigated type 2 diabetes. Journal of Molecular Histology, 54(6), 543&#x2013;557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra, S., &amp; Sahay, R. (2018). Diabetes fatigue syndrome. Diabetes Therapy, 9(4), 1421&#x2013;1429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyani, R. R., Metter, E. J., Egan, J., Golden, S. H., &amp; Ferrucci, L. (2015). Hyperglycemia predicts persistently lower muscle strength with aging. Diabetes Care, 38(1), 82&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanaley, J. A., Colberg, S. R., Corcoran, M. H., Malin, S. K., Rodriguez, N. R., Crespo, C. J., Kirwan, J. P., &amp; Zierath, J. R. (2022). Exercise/physical activity in individuals with type 2 diabetes: A consensus statement from the american college of sports medicine. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 54(2), 353&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karstoft, K., &amp; Pedersen, B. K. (2016). Exercise and type 2 diabetes: Focus on metabolism and inflammation. In Immunology and Cell Biology (Vol., 94, Issue 2, pp. 146&#x2013;150). Nature Publishing Group.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy, J. W., Hirshman, M. F., Gervino, E. V., Ocel, J. V., Forse, R. A., Hoenig, S. J., Aronson, D., Goodyear, L. J., &amp; Horton, E. S. (1999). Acute exercise induces GLUT4 translocation in skeletal muscle of normal human subjects and subjects with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes, 48(5), 1192&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura, I., Okazaki, M., &amp; Kimura, M. (1993). Streptozocin&#x2010;diabetes modifies acetylcholine release from mouse phrenic nerve terminal and presynaptic sensitivity to succinylcholine. The Japanese Journal of Pharmacology, 62(1), 35&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knudsen, J. R., Steenberg, D. E., Hingst, J. R., Hodgson, L. R., Henriquez&#x2010;Olguin, C., Li, Z., Kiens, B., Richter, E. A., Wojtaszewski, J. F. P., Verkade, P., &amp; Jensen, T. E. (2020). Prior exercise in humans redistributes intramuscular GLUT4 and enhances insulin&#x2010;stimulated sarcolemmal and endosomal GLUT4 translocation. Molecular Metabolism, 39, 100998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally, K. M., &amp; Robertson, R. J. (2006). Construct validity of the OMNI resistance exercise scale. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, 20(2), 252&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence, D. G., &amp; Locke, S. (1961). Motor nerve conduction velocity in diabetes. Archives of Neurology, 5(5). https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.1961.00450170021003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Corre, A., Caron, N., Turpin, N. A., &amp; Dalleau, G. (2023). Mechanisms underlying altered neuromuscular function in people with DPN. In European Journal of Applied Physiology (Vol., 123, Issue 7, pp. 1433&#x2013;1446). Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitzelar, B. N., &amp; Koltyn, K. F. (2021). Exercise and neuropathic pain: A general overview of preclinical and clinical research. Sports Medicine &#x2010; Open, 7(1), 21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leprivier, G., &amp; Rotblat, B. (2020). How does mTOR sense glucose starvation? AMPK is the usual suspect. Cell Death Discovery, 6(1), 27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesniewski, L. A., Miller, T. A., &amp; Armstrong, R. B. (2003). Mechanisms of force loss in diabetic mouse skeletal muscle. Muscle and Nerve, 28(4), 493&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., Yang, Y., Bai, J., Zhang, Y., Yang, H., Zhang, Y., &amp; Lv, H. (2022). Impaired vascular endothelial function is associated with peripheral neuropathy in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes, Metabolic Syndrome and Obesity, 15, 1437&#x2013;1449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Yuan, S., Zhang, J., Xu, F., &amp; Zhu, F. (2024). The effect of periodic resistance training on obese patients with type 2 diabetic nephropathy. Scientific Reports, 14(1), 2761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Liu, Y., Liu, S., Gao, M., Wang, W., Chen, K., Huang, L., &amp; Liu, Y. (2023). Diabetic vascular diseases: Molecular mechanisms and therapeutic strategies. Signal Transduction and Targeted Therapy, 8(1), 152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liddell, E. G. T., &amp; Sherrington, C. S. (1925). Recruitment and some other factors of reflex inhibition. Proceedings of the Royal Society of London, B97, 488&#x2013;518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J., Zhang, X., Sun, Y., Xu, H., Li, N., Wang, Y., Tian, X., Zhao, C., Wang, B., Zhu, B., &amp; Zhao, R. (2024). Exercise ameliorates muscular excessive mitochondrial fission, insulin resistance and inflammation in diabetic rats via irisin/AMPK activation. Scientific Reports, 14(1), 19174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby, C., &amp; Jacobs, R. A. (2016). Adaptations of skeletal muscle mitochondria to exercise training. Experimental Physiology, 101(1), 17&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, J., Zhu, H. Q., Gou, B., &amp; Zheng, Y. L. (2022). Mechanisms of exercise for diabetic neuropathic pain. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 14, 975453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, X. Q., Qin, J., Li, H. Y., Yan, X. L., Zhao, Y., &amp; Zhang, L. J. (2019). Role of exercise activity in alleviating neuropathic pain in diabetes via inhibition of the pro&#x2010;inflammatory signal pathway. Biological Research for Nursing, 21(1), 14&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti, N. A., Aagaard, P., Blazevich, A. J., Folland, J., Tillin, N., &amp; Duchateau, J. (2016). Rate of force development: Physiological and methodological considerations. In European Journal of Applied Physiology (Vol., 116, Issue 6, pp. 1091&#x2013;1116). Springer Verlag.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiorana, A., O'driscoll, G., Goodman, C., Taylor, R., &amp; Green, D. (2002). Combined aerobic and resistance exercise improves glycemic control and fitness in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice, 56(2), 115&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone, J. I. (2016). Diabetic central neuropathy: CNS damage related to hyperglycemia. Diabetes, 65(2), 355&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marques, M. J., &amp; Neto, H. S. (2002). Acetylcholine receptors and nerve terminal distribution at the neuromuscular junction of non&#x2010;obese diabetic mice. Anatomical Record, 267(2), 112&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez&#x2010;Valdes, E., Enoka, R. M., Holobar, A., McGill, K., Farina, D., Besomi, M., Hug, F., Falla, D., Carson, R. G., Clancy, E. A., Disselhorst&#x2010;Klug, C., van Die&#xeb;n, J. H., Tucker, K., Gandevia, S., Lowery, M., S&#xf8;gaard, K., Besier, T., Merletti, R., Kiernan, M. C., &#x2026; Hodges, P. W. (2023). Consensus for experimental design in electromyography (CEDE) project: Single motor unit matrix. Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology, 68, 102726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonnell, M. N., Buckley, J. D., Opie, G. M., Ridding, M. C., &amp; Semmler, J. G. (2013). A single bout of aerobic exercise promotes motor cortical neuroplasticity. Journal of Applied Physiology, 114(9), 1174&#x2013;1182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee, S., &amp; Hargreaves, M. (2020). Exercise adaptations: Molecular mechanisms and potential targets for therapeutic benefit. Nature Reviews Endocrinology, 16(9), 495&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGregor, C. E., &amp; English, A. W. (2019). The role of BDNF in peripheral nerve regeneration: Activity&#x2010;dependent treatments and Val66Met. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 12, 522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean, D. L., Fan, J., Higashijima, S. I., Hale, M. E., &amp; Fetcho, J. R. (2007). A topographic map of recruitment in spinal cord. Nature, 446(7131), 71&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meacham, K., Shepherd, A., Mohapatra, D. P., &amp; Haroutounian, S. (2017). Neuropathic pain: Central vs. peripheral mechanisms. Current Pain and Headache Reports, 21(6), 1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meex, R. C. R., Schrauwen&#x2010;Hinderling, V. B., Moonen&#x2010;Kornips, E., Schaart, G., Mensink, M., Phielix, E., van de Weijer, T., Sels, J. P., Schrauwen, P., &amp; Hesselink, M. K. C. (2010). Restoration of muscle mitochondrial function and metabolic flexibility in type 2 diabetes by exercise training is paralleled by increased myocellular fat storage and improved insulin sensitivity. Diabetes, 59(3), 572&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesinovic, J., Zengin, A., De Courten, B., Ebeling, P. R., &amp; Scott, D. (2019). Sarcopenia and type 2 diabetes mellitus: A bidirectional relationship. Diabetes, Metabolic Syndrome and Obesity, 12, 1057&#x2013;1072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messinger, R. B., Naik, A. K., Jagodic, M. M., Nelson, M. T., Lee, W. Y., Choe, W. J., Orestes, P., Latham, J. R., Todorovic, S. M., &amp; Jevtovic&#x2010;Todorovic, V. (2009). In vivo silencing of the CaV3.2 T&#x2010;type calcium channels in sensory neurons alleviates hyperalgesia in rats with streptozocin&#x2010;induced diabetic neuropathy. Pain, 145(1&#x2013;2), 184&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao, Y., Xie, L., Song, J., Cai, X., Yang, J., Ma, X., Chen, S., &amp; Xie, P. (2024). Unraveling the causes of sarcopenia: Roles of junction impairment and mitochondrial dysfunction. Physiological Reports, 12(1), e15917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minnock, D., Annibalini, G., Le Roux, C. W., Contarelli, S., Krause, M., Saltarelli, R., Valli, G., Stocchi, V., Barbieri, E., &amp; De Vito, G. (2020). Effects of acute aerobic, resistance and combined exercises on 24&#x2010;h glucose variability and skeletal muscle signalling responses in type 1 diabetics. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 120(12), 2677&#x2013;2691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minnock, D., Annibalini, G., Valli, G., Saltarelli, R., Krause, M., Barbieri, E., &amp; De Vito, G. (2022). Altered muscle mitochondrial, inflammatory and trophic markers, and reduced exercise training adaptations in type 1 diabetes. The Journal of Physiology, 600(6), 1281&#x2013;1282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaco, C. M. F., Gingrich, M. A., &amp; Hawke, T. J. (2019). Considering type 1 diabetes as a form of accelerated muscle aging. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 47(2), 98&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti, E., Sarto, F., Sartori, R., Zanchettin, G., L&#xf6;fler, S., Kern, H., Narici, M. V., &amp; Zampieri, S. (2023). C&#x2010;terminal agrin fragment as a biomarker of muscle wasting and weakness: A narrative review. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 14(2), 730&#x2013;744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno, C., d'Almeida, O. C., Gomes, L., Paiva, I., &amp; Castelo&#x2010;Branco, M. (2023). Regular physical activity moderates the adverse impact of type 2 diabetes on brain atrophy independently from HbA1c. Frontiers in Endocrinology, 14, 1135358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morettini, M., Palumbo, M. C., Sacchetti, M., Castiglione, F., &amp; Mazz&#xe0;, C. (2017). A system model of the effects of exercise on plasma Interleukin&#x2010;6 dynamics in healthy individuals: Role of skeletal muscle and adipose tissue. PLoS ONE, 12(7), e0181224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortensen, S. P., Winding, K. M., Iepsen, U. W., Munch, G. W., Marcussen, N., Hellsten, Y., Pedersen, B. K., &amp; Baum, O. (2019). The effect of two exercise modalities on skeletal muscle capillary ultrastructure in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports, 29(3), 360&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, T. D., Finan, B., Bloom, S. R., D'Alessio, D., Drucker, D. J., Flatt, P. R., Fritsche, A., Gribble, F., Grill, H. J., Habener, J. F., Holst, J. J., Langhans, W., Meier, J. J., Nauck, M. A., Perez&#x2010;Tilve, D., Pocai, A., Reimann, F., Sandoval, D. A., Schwartz, T. W., &#x2026; Tsch&#xf6;p, M. H. (2019). Glucagon&#x2010;like peptide 1 (GLP&#x2010;1). Molecular Metabolism, 30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmet.2019.09.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muramatsu, K. (2020). Diabetes mellitus&#x2010;related dysfunction of the motor system. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 21(20), 7485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio, F., Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;Romo, G., Barriopedro&#x2010;Moro, M. I., Nez, A. J., Alvar, B. A., &amp; Triplett, A. N. T. (2011). Control of resistance training intensity by the OMNI perceived exertion scale. Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research, 35, S89&#x2013;S94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesti, L., Pugliese, N. R., Sciuto, P., &amp; Natali, A. (2020). Type 2 diabetes and reduced exercise tolerance: A review of the literature through an integrated physiology approach. In Cardiovascular Diabetology (Vol., 19, Issue 1). BioMed Central Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, G. Y. Q., Loh, Z. W.&#x2010;L., Fann, D. Y., Mallilankaraman, K., Arumugam, T. V., &amp; Hande, M. P. (2024). Role of Mitogen&#x2010;Activated Protein (MAP) kinase pathways in metabolic diseases. Genome Integrity, 15, e20230003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nojima, H., Watanabe, H., Yamane, K., Kitahara, Y., Sekikawa, K., Yamamoto, H., Yokoyama, A., Inamizu, T., Asahara, T., &amp; Kohno, N. (2008). Effect of aerobic exercise training on oxidative stress in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Metabolism: Clinical and Experimental, 57(2), 170&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor, K., Spendiff, S., Lochm&#xfc;ller, H., &amp; Horvath, R. (2023). Mitochondrial mutations can alter neuromuscular transmission in congenital myasthenic syndrome and mitochondrial disease. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 24(10), 8505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen, D. B., Sacchetti, M., Dela, F., Ploug, T., &amp; Saltin, B. (2005). Glucose clearance is higher in arm than leg muscle in type 2 diabetes. The Journal of Physiology, 565(2), 555&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olver, T. D., McDonald, M. W., Gris&#xe9;, K. N., Dey, A., Allen, M. D., Medeiros, P. J., Lacefield, J. C., Jackson, D. N., Rice, C. L., James Melling, C. W., Noble, E. G., &amp; Shoemaker, J. K. (2014). Exercise training enhances insulin&#x2010;stimulated nerve arterial vasodilation in rats with insulin&#x2010;treated experimental diabetes. American Journal of Physiology &#x2010; Regulatory Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 306(12), R941&#x2013;950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, K. L., Stafford, L. K., McLaughlin, S. A., Boyko, E. J., Vollset, S. E., Smith, A. E., Dalton, B. E., Duprey, J., Cruz, J. A., Hagins, H., Lindstedt, P. A., Aali, A., Abate, Y. H., Abate, M. D., Abbasian, M., Abbasi&#x2010;Kangevari, Z., Abbasi&#x2010;Kangevari, M., Abd ElHafeez, S., Abd&#x2010;Rabu, R., &#x2026; Vos, T. (2023). Global, regional, and national burden of diabetes from 1990 to 2021, with projections of prevalence to 2050: A systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. The Lancet, 402(10397), 203&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orestes, P., Osuru, H. P., McIntire, W. E., Jacus, M. O., Salajegheh, R., Jagodic, M. M., Choe, W. J., Lee, J. H., Lee, S. S., Rose, K. E., Poiro, N., DiGruccio, M. R., Krishnan, K., Covey, D. F., Lee, J. H., Barrett, P. Q., Jevtovic&#x2010;Todorovic, V., &amp; Todorovic, S. M. (2013). Reversal of neuropathic pain in diabetes by targeting glycosylation of Cav3.2 T&#x2010;type calcium channels. Diabetes, 62(11), 3828&#x2013;3838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlando, G., Balducci, S., Bazzucchi, I., Pugliese, G., &amp; Sacchetti, M. (2016). Neuromuscular dysfunction in type 2 diabetes: Underlying mechanisms and effect of resistance training. In Diabetes/Metabolism Research and Reviews, 32(1), 40&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlando, G., Balducci, S., Bazzucchi, I., Pugliese, G., &amp; Sacchetti, M. (2017a). Muscle fatigability in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes/Metabolism Research and Reviews, 33(1). https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.2821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlando, G., Balducci, S., Bazzucchi, I., Pugliese, G., &amp; Sacchetti, M. (2017b). The impact of type 1 diabetes and diabetic polyneuropathy on muscle strength and fatigability. Acta Diabetologica, 54(6), 543&#x2013;550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlando, G., Balducci, S., Boulton, A. J. M., Degens, H., &amp; Reeves, N. D. (2022). Neuromuscular dysfunction and exercise training in people with diabetic peripheral neuropathy: A narrative review. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice, 183, 109183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;rstavik, K., Namer, B., Schmidt, R., Schmelz, M., Hilliges, M., Weidner, C., Carr, R. W., Handwerker, H., J&#xf8;rum, E., &amp; Torebj&#xf6;rk, H. E. (2006). Abnormal function of C&#x2010;fibers in patients with diabetic neuropathy. Journal of Neuroscience, 26(44), 11287&#x2013;11294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osseward, P. J., &amp; Pfaff, S. L. (2019). Cell type and circuit modules in the spinal cord. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 56, 175&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ossipov, M. H., Morimura, K., &amp; Porreca, F. (2014). Descending pain modulation and chronification of pain. Current Opinion in Supportive and Palliative Care, 8(2), 143&#x2013;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozougwu, O. (2013). The pathogenesis and pathophysiology of type 1 and type 2 diabetes mellitus. Journal of Physiology and Pathophysiology, 4(4), 46&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papagianni, G., Panayiotou, C., Vardas, M., Balaskas, N., Antonopoulos, C., Tachmatzidis, D., Didangelos, T., Lambadiari, V., &amp; Kadoglou, N. P. E. (2023). The anti&#x2010;inflammatory effects of aerobic exercise training in patients with type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Cytokine, 164, 156157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parasoglou, P., Rao, S., &amp; Slade, J. M. (2017). Declining skeletal muscle function in diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Clinical Therapeutics, 39(6), 1085&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen, B. K. (2017). Anti&#x2010;inflammatory effects of exercise: Role in diabetes and cardiovascular disease. European Journal of Clinical Investigation, 47(8), 600&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen, B. K., &amp; Saltin, B. (2015). Exercise as medicine &#x2010; Evidence for prescribing exercise as therapy in 26 different chronic diseases. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports, 25(S3), 1&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, B., Chen, Z., Ma, L., &amp; Dai, Y. (2015). Cerebral alterations of type 2 diabetes mellitus on MRI: A pilot study. Neuroscience Letters, 606, 100&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry, B. D., Caldow, M. K., Brennan&#x2010;Speranza, T. C., Sbaraglia, M., Jerums, G., Garnham, A., Wong, C., Levinger, P., Asrar Ul Haq, M., Hare, D. L., Price, S. R., &amp; Levinger, I. (2016). Muscle atrophy in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: Roles of inflammatory pathways, physical activity and exercise. Exercise Immunology Review, 22, 94&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picconi, F., Mataluni, G., Ziccardi, L., Parravano, M., Di Renzo, A., Ylli, D., Pasqualetti, P., Studer, V., Chioma, L., Marfia, G. A., &amp; Frontoni, S. (2018). Association between early neuroretinal dysfunction and peripheral motor unit loss in patients with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Journal of Diabetes Research, 2018, 9763507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto, A., Bergouignan, A., Dempsey, P., Roschel, H., Gualano, B., &amp; Dunstan, D. (2023). Physiology of sedentary behavior. Physiological Reviews, 103(4), 2561&#x2013;2622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittenger, G. L., Ray, M., Burcus, N. I., McNulty, P., Basta, B., &amp; Vinik, A. I. (2004). Intraepidermal nerve fibers are indicators of small&#x2010;fiber neuropathy in both diabetic and nondiabetic patients. Diabetes Care, 27(8), 1974&#x2013;1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pop&#x2010;Busui, R., Boulton, A. J. M., Feldman, E. L., Bril, V., Freeman, R., Malik, R. A., Sosenko, J. M., &amp; Ziegler, D. (2017). Diabetic neuropathy: A position statement by the American diabetes association. Diabetes Care, 40(1), 136&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praet, S. F. E., Van Loon, L. J. C., &amp; Praet, S. (2007). Optimizing the therapeutic benefits of exercise in Type 2 diabetes. Journal of Applied Physiology, 103, 1113&#x2013;1120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratt, J., De Vito, G., Narici, M., &amp; Boreham, C. (2021). Neuromuscular junction aging: A role for biomarkers and exercise. Journals of Gerontology &#x2010; Series A Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences, 76(4), 576&#x2013;585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratt, J., De Vito, G., Segurado, R., Pessanha, L., Dolan, J., Narici, M., &amp; Boreham, C. (2022). Plasma neurofilament light levels associate with muscle mass and strength in middle&#x2010;aged and older adults: Findings from GenoFit. Journal of Cachexia, Sarcopenia and Muscle, 13(3), 1811&#x2013;1820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior, S. J., Blumenthal, J. B., Katzel, L. I., Goldberg, A. P., &amp; Ryan, A. S. (2014). Increased skeletal muscle capillarization after aerobic exercise training and weight loss improves insulin sensitivity in adults with IGT. Diabetes Care, 37(5), 1469&#x2013;1475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proske, U., &amp; Gandevia, S. C. (2012). The proprioceptive senses: Their roles in signaling body shape, body position and movement, and muscle force. Physiological Reviews, 92(4), 1651&#x2013;1697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaisar, R., Javed, M., Khan, I. M., Ahmad, F., &amp; Karim, A. (2024). Metformin improves skeletal muscle and physical capacity by stabilizing neuromuscular junction in older adults. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics, 127, 105587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, C., Song, X., Wang, H., Yan, Y., &amp; Liu, B. (2022). The role of exercise&#x2010;induced myokines in promoting angiogenesis. Frontiers in Physiology, 13, 981577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racha, P., Selvam, S., Bose, B., Bantwal, G., &amp; Sambashivaiah, S. (2022). Circulating CTerminal agrin fragment: A potential marker for sarcopenia among type 2 diabetes. Indian Journal of Endocrinology and Metabolism, 26(4), 334&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramamurthy, B., H&#xf6;&#xf6;k, P., Jones, D., &amp; Larsson, L. (2001). Changes in myosin structure and function in response to glycation. The Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology Journal, 15(13), 2415&#x2013;2422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramamurthy, B., Jones, A. D., &amp; Larsson, L. (2003). Glutathione reverses early effects of glycation on myosin function. American Journal of Physiology &#x2010; Cell Physiology, 285(2), C419&#x2013;424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramji, N., Toth, C., Kennedy, J., &amp; Zochodne, D. W. (2007). Does diabetes mellitus target motor neurons? Neurobiology of Disease, 26(2), 301&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rask&#x2010;Madsen, C., &amp; King, G. L. (2013). Vascular complications of diabetes: Mechanisms of injury and protective factors. Cell Metabolism, 17(1), 20&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reske&#x2010;Nielsen, E., Lundb&#xe6;k, K., &amp; Rafaelsen, O. J. (1966). Pathological changes in the central and peripheral nervous system of young long&#x2010;term diabetics &#x2010; I. Diabetic encephalopathy. Diabetologia, 1(3&#x2013;4), 233&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reusch, J. E. B., Bridenstine, M., &amp; Regensteiner, J. G. (2013). Type 2 diabetes mellitus and exercise impairment. Reviews in Endocrine and Metabolic Disorders, 14(1), 77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter, E. A., &amp; Hargreaves, M. (2013). Exercise, GLUT4, and skeletal muscle glucose uptake. Physiological Reviews, 93, 993&#x2013;1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riddell, M. C., Gallen, I. W., Smart, C. E., Taplin, C. E., Adolfsson, P., Lumb, A. N., Kowalski, A., Rabasa&#x2010;Lhoret, R., McCrimmon, R. J., Hume, C., Annan, F., Fournier, P. A., Graham, C., Bode, B., Galassetti, P., Jones, T. W., Mill&#xe1;n, I. S., Heise, T., Peters, A. L., &#x2026; Laffel, L. M. (2017). Exercise management in type 1 diabetes: A consensus statement. The Lancet Diabetes and Endocrinology, 5(5), 377&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins, J. M., &amp; Gerszten, R. E. (2023). Exercise, exerkines, and cardiometabolic health: From individual players to a team sport. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 133(11), e168121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, M. D., McCarthy, J. J., Hornberger, T. A., Phillips, S. M., Mackey, A. L., Nader, G. A., Boppart, M. D., Kavazis, A. N., Reidy, P. T., Ogasawara, R., Libardi, C. A., Ugrinowitsch, C., Booth, F. W., &amp; Esser, K. A. (2023). Mechanisms of mechanical overload&#x2010;induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Current understanding and future directions. In Physiological reviews (Vol., 103, Issue 4, pp. 2679&#x2013;2757). NLM (Medline).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson, R. P., Harmon, J., Tran, P. O., Tanaka, Y., &amp; Takahashi, H. (2003). Perspectives in diabetes glucose toxicity in&#x2010;cells: Type 2 diabetes, good radicals gone bad, and the glutathione connection. Perspective in Diabetes, 52(3), 581&#x2013;587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodino&#x2010;Klapac, L. R., Haidet, A. M., Kota, J., Handy, C., Kaspar, B. K., &amp; Mendell, J. R. (2009). Inhibition of myostatin with emphasis on follistatin as a therapy for muscle disease. In Muscle and Nerve, 39(3), 283&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;hling, M., Herder, C., Roden, M., Stemper, T., &amp; M&#xfc;ssig, K. (2016). Effects of long&#x2010;term exercise interventions on glycaemic control in type 1 and type 2 diabetes: A systematic review. Experimental and Clinical Endocrinology and Diabetes, 124(8), 487&#x2013;494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossetti, L., Giaccari, A., &amp; Defronzo, R. A. (1990). Glucose toxicity. Diabetes Care, 13(6), 610&#x2013;630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacchetti, M. S., Balducci, S., Bazzucchi, I., Carlucci, F., Di Palumbo, A. S., Haxhi, J., Conti, F., Di Biase, N., Calandriello, E., &amp; Pugliese, G. (2013). Neuromuscular dysfunction in diabetes: Role of nerve impairment and training status. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 45(1), 52&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeedi, P., Petersohn, I., Salpea, P., Malanda, B., Karuranga, S., Unwin, N., Colagiuri, S., Guariguata, L., Motala, A. A., Ogurtsova, K., Shaw, J. E., Bright, D., &amp; Williams, R. (2019). Global and regional diabetes prevalence estimates for 2019 and projections for 2030 and 2045: Results from the International Diabetes Federation Diabetes Atlas, 9th edition. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice, 157, 107843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said, G. (2007). Diabetic neuropathy &#x2010; A review. Nature Clinical Practice Neurology, 3(6), 331&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salter, M. W., &amp; Beggs, S. (2014). Sublime microglia: Expanding roles for the guardians of the CNS. Cell, 158(1), 15&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sango, K., Mizukami, H., Horie, H., &amp; Yagihashi, S. (2017). Impaired axonal regeneration in diabetes. Perspective on the underlying mechanism from in vivo and in vitro experimental studies. Frontiers in Endocrinology, 8, 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwensfeier, L., Kreutz, T., &amp; Brinkmann, C. (2023). Is there a different rating of perceived exertion in men with type 2 diabetes mellitus? Journal of Diabetes and Metabolic Disorders, 22(2), 1399&#x2013;1404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvarajah, D., Kar, D., Khunti, K., Davies, M. J., Scott, A. R., Walker, J., &amp; Tesfaye, S. (2019). Diabetic peripheral neuropathy: Advances in diagnosis and strategies for screening and early intervention. The Lancet Diabetes and Endocrinology, 7(12), 938&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvarajah, D., Sloan, G., Teh, K., Wilkinson, I. D., Heiberg&#x2010;Gibbons, F., Awadh, M., Kelsall, A., Grieg, M., Pallai, S., &amp; Tesfaye, S. (2023). Structural brain alterations in key somatosensory and nociceptive regions in diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Diabetes Care, 46(4), 777&#x2013;785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvarajah, D., Wilkinson, I. D., Davies, J., Gandhi, R., &amp; Tesfaye, S. (2011). Central nervous system involvement in diabetic neuropathy. Current Diabetes Reports, 11(4), 310&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvarajah, D., Wilkinson, I. D., Emery, C. J., Harris, N. D., Shaw, P. J., Witte, D. R., Griffiths, P. D., &amp; Tesfaye, S. (2006). Early involvement of the spinal cord in diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Diabetes Care, 29(12), 2664&#x2013;2669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvarajah, D., Wilkinson, I. D., Maxwell, M., Davies, J., Sankar, A., Boland, E., Gandhi, R., Tracey, I., &amp; Tesfaye, S. (2014). Magnetic resonance neuroimaging study of brain structural differences in diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Diabetes Care, 37(6), 1681&#x2013;1688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sempere&#x2010;Bigorra, M., Juli&#xe1;n&#x2010;Rochina, I., &amp; Cauli, O. (2021). Differences and similarities in neuropathy in type 1 and 2 diabetes: A systematic review. Journal of Personalized Medicine, 11(3), 230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senefeld, J. W., Keenan, K. G., Ryan, K. S., D'Astice, S. E., Negro, F., &amp; Hunter, S. K. (2020). Greater fatigability and motor unit discharge variability in human type 2 diabetes. Physiological Reports, 8(13), e14503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok, W. P., Goodpaster, B. H., Strotmeyer, E. S., Kuller, L. H., Broudeau, R., Kammerer, C., de Rekeneire, N., Harris, T. B., Schwartz, A. V., Tylavsky, F. A., Yong&#x2010;Wook, C., &amp; Newman, A. B. (2007). Accelerated loss of skeletal muscle strength in older adults with type 2 diabetes: The health, aging, and body composition study. Diabetes Care, 30(6), 1507&#x2013;1512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seung, W. L., Kyoung, E. S., Dong, S. S., Sung, M. A., Eun, S. H., Dae, J. K., Moon, S. N., &amp; Lee, K. W. (2005). Alterations in peripheral blood levels of TIMP&#x2010;1, MMP&#x2010;2, and MMP&#x2010;9 in patients with type&#x2010;2 diabetes. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice, 69(2), 175&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shankarappa, S. A., Piedras&#x2010;Renter&#xed;a, E. S., &amp; Stubbs, E. B. (2011). Forced&#x2010;exercise delays neuropathic pain in experimental diabetes: Effects on voltage&#x2010;activated calcium channels. Journal of Neurochemistry, 118(2), 224&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw, J. E., Sicree, R. A., &amp; Zimmet, P. Z. (2010). Global estimates of the prevalence of diabetes for 2010 and 2030. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice, 87(1), 4&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherrington, C. S. (1906). The Integrative Action of the Nervous System. CT, Yale University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shun, C. T., Chang, Y. C., Wu, H. P., Hsieh, S. C., Lin, W. M., Lin, Y. H., Tai, T. Y., &amp; Hsieh, S. T. (2004). Skin denervation in type 2 diabetes: Correlations with diabetic duration and functional impairments. Brain, 127(7), 1593&#x2013;1605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sima, A. A. F., &amp; Brismar, T. (1985). Reversible diabetic nerve dysfunction: Structural correlates to electrophysiological abnormalities. Annals of Neurology, 18(1), 21&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, R., Kishore, L., &amp; Kaur, N. (2014). Diabetic peripheral neuropathy: Current perspective and future directions. Pharmacological Research, 80, 21&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf8;berg, K. A., Fr&#xf8;sig, C., Kj&#xf8;bsted, R., Sylow, L., Kleinert, M., Betik, A. C., Shaw, C. S., Kiens, B., Wojtaszewski, J. F. P., Rattigan, S., Richter, E. A., &amp; McConell, G. K. (2017). Exercise increases human skeletal muscle insulin sensitivity via coordinated increases in microvascular perfusion and molecular signaling. Diabetes, 66(6), 1501&#x2013;1510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;karabot, J., Brownstein, C. G., Casolo, A., Del Vecchio, A., &amp; Ansdell, P. (2021). The knowns and unknowns of neural adaptations to resistance training. In European Journal of Applied Physiology (Vol., 121, Issue 3, pp. 675&#x2013;685). Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, B. X., Azhar, L., Koo, G. K. Y., Marzolini, S., Gallagher, D., Swardfager, W., Chen, C., Ba, J., Herrmann, N., &amp; Lanct&#xf4;t, K. L. (2024). The effect of exercise on blood concentrations of angiogenesis markers in older adults: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Neurobiology of Aging, 135. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2023.12.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streckmann, F., Balke, M., Cavaletti, G., Toscanelli, A., Bloch, W., D&#xe9;card, B. F., Lehmann, H. C., &amp; Faude, O. (2022). Exercise and neuropathy: Systematic review with meta&#x2010;analysis. In Sports Medicine (Vol., 52, Issue 5, pp. 1043&#x2013;1065). Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, J.&#x2010;B., Zhao, L.&#x2010;H., Zhang, X.&#x2010;L., Cai, H.&#x2010;L., Huang, H.&#x2010;Y., Xu, F., Chen, T., &amp; Wang, X.&#x2010;Q. (2018). HbA1c variability and diabetic peripheral neuropathy in type 2 diabetic patients. Cardiovascular Diabetology, 17(1), 47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, W., Tao, M., Ma, L., Tang, K., Xiong, F., Dai, X., &amp; Qin, Y. (2023). Dose&#x2010;response relationships of resistance training in Type 2 diabetes mellitus: A meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. In Frontiers in Endocrinology (Vol., 14). Frontiers Media SA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, X., He, J., Cui, J., Li, H., &amp; Men, J. (2022). The effects of aerobic exercise combined with resistance training on inflammatory factors and heart rate variability in middle&#x2010;aged and elderly women with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Annals of Noninvasive Electrocardiology, 27(6), e12996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki, A., Yabu, A., &amp; Nakamura, H. (2022). Advanced glycation end products in musculoskeletal system and disorders. Methods (San Diego, California), 203, 179&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syeda, U. S. A., Battillo, D., Visaria, A., &amp; Malin, S. K. (2023). The importance of exercise for glycemic control in type 2 diabetes. American Journal of Medicine Open, 9, 100031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, A. M., Samad, O. A., Fischer, T. Z., Zhao, P., Persson, A. K., &amp; Waxman, S. G. (2012). Maladaptive dendritic spine remodeling contributes to diabetic neuropathic pain. Journal of Neuroscience, 32(20), 6795&#x2013;807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, Z. Y., Wang, P. X., Wei, S. Q., Traub, R. J., Li, J. F., &amp; Cao, D. Y. (2019). The role of descending pain modulation in chronic primary pain: Potential application of drugs targeting serotonergic system. Neural Plasticity, 2019, 1389296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada, M., Yasuda, H., &amp; Kikkawa, R. (1998). Delayed Wallerian degeneration and increased neurofilament phosphorylation in sciatic nerves of rats with streptozocin&#x2010;induced diabetes. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 155(1), 23&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treadway, J. L., James, D. E., Burcel, E., &amp; Ruderman, N. B. (1989). Effect of exercise on insulin receptor binding and kinase activity in skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology &#x2010; Endocrinology and Metabolism, 256(1), E138&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umpierre, D., Ribeiro, P. A. B., Kramer, C. K., Leit&#xe3;o, C. B., Zucatti, A. T. N., Azevedo, M. J., Gross, J. L., Ribeiro, J. P., &amp; Schaan, B. D. (2011). Physical activity advice only or structured exercise training and association with HbA1c levels in type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Journal of the American Medical Association, 305(17), 1790&#x2013;1799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valli, G., Wu, R., Minnock, D., Sirago, G., Annibalini, G., Casolo, A., Del Vecchio, A., Toniolo, L., Barbieri, E., &amp; de Vito, G. (2025). Can non&#x2010;invasive motor unit analysis reveal distinct neural strategies of force production in young with uncomplicated type 1 diabetes? European Journal of Applied Physiology, 12, 247&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dijk, J., &amp; Van Loon, L. J. C. (2015). Exercise strategies to optimize glycemic control in type 2 diabetes: A continuing glucose monitoring perspective. Diabetes Spectrum, 28(1), 24&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Ryckeghem, L., Keytsman, C., De Brandt, J., Verboven, K., Verbaanderd, E., Marinus, N., Franssen, W. M. A., Frederix, I., Bakelants, E., Petit, T., Jogani, S., Stroobants, S., Dendale, P., Bito, V., Verwerft, J., &amp; Hansen, D. (2022). Impact of continuous vs. interval training on oxygen extraction and cardiac function during exercise in type 2 diabetes mellitus. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 122(4), 875&#x2013;887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ved, N., da Vitoria Lobo, M. E., Bestall, S. M., Vidueira, C. L., Beazley&#x2010;Long, N., Ballmer&#x2010;Hofer, K., Hirashima, M., Bates, D. O., Donaldson, L. F., &amp; Hulse, R. P. (2018). Diabetes&#x2010;induced microvascular complications at the level of the spinal cord: A contributing factor in diabetic neuropathic pain. The Journal of Physiology, 596(16), 3675&#x2013;3693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe, K., Miyamoto, T., Tanaka, Y., Fukuda, K., &amp; Moritani, T. (2012). Type 2 diabetes mellitus patients manifest characteristic spatial EMG potential distribution pattern during sustained isometric contraction. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice, 97(3), 468&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, M., Gibbons, L. W., Mitchell, T. L., Kampert, J. B., Lee, C. D., &amp; Blair, S. N. (1999). The association between cardiorespiratory fitness and impaired fasting glucose and type 2 diabetes mellitus in men. Annals of Internal Medicine, 130(2), 89&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West, S. J., Bannister, K., Dickenson, A. H., &amp; Bennett, D. L. (2015). Circuitry and plasticity of the dorsal horn &#x2010; Toward a better understanding of neuropathic pain. Neuroscience, 300, 254&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, G. A., Wilkins, G. T., Cotter, J. D., Lamberts, R. R., Lal, S., &amp; Baldi, J. C. (2019). HIIT improves left ventricular exercise response in adults with type 2 diabetes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 51(6), 1099&#x2013;1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, K. H., Chow, M. B. C. Y., Lui, T. H., Cheong, Y. K., &amp; Tam, K. F. (2017). Denervation pseudohypertrophy of calf muscles associated with diabetic neuropathy. Radiology Case Reports, 12(4), 815&#x2013;820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolf, C. J. (2011). Central sensitization: Implications for the diagnosis and treatment of pain. Pain, 152(Suppl 3), S2&#x2013;S15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, G., Liu, B., Sun, Y., Du, Y., Snetselaar, L. G., Hu, F. B., &amp; Bao, W. (2018). Prevalence of diagnosed type 1 and type 2 diabetes among US adults in 2016 and 2017: Population based study. British Medical Journal (Online), 362, k1497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi, T., Kouzaki, K., Sasaki, K., &amp; Nakazato, K. (2024). Alterations in neuromuscular junction morphology with ageing and endurance training modulate neuromuscular transmission and myofibre composition. The Journal of Physiology, 603(1), 107&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamazaki, Y., Sato, D., Yamashiro, K., Nakano, S., Onishi, H., &amp; Maruyama, A. (2019). Acute low&#x2010;intensity aerobic exercise modulates intracortical inhibitory and excitatory circuits in an exercised and a non&#x2010;exercised muscle in the primary motor cortex. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C., Zhao, X., An, X., Zhang, Y., Sun, W., Zhang, Y., Duan, Y., Kang, X., Sun, Y., Jiang, L., &amp; Lian, F. (2023). Axonal transport deficits in the pathogenesis of diabetic peripheral neuropathy. Frontiers in Endocrinology, 14, 1136796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, D., Yang, Y., Li, Y., &amp; Han, R. (2019). Physical exercise as therapy for type 2 diabetes mellitus: From mechanism to orientation. Annals of Nutrition and Metabolism, 74(4), 313&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yapanis, M., James, S., Craig, M. E., O'Neal, D., &amp; Ekinci, E. I. (2022). Complications of diabetes and metrics of glycemic management derived from continuous glucose monitoring. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism, 107(6), e2221&#x2013;e2236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yardley, J. E., Kenny, G. P., Perkins, B. A., Riddell, M. C., Malcolm, J., Boulay, P., Khandwala, F., &amp; Sigal, R. J. (2012). Effects of performing resistance exercise before versus after aerobic exercise on glycemia in type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care, 35(4), 669&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yorek, M. S., Obrosov, A., Shevalye, H., Lupachyk, S., Harper, M. M., Kardon, R. H., &amp; Yorek, M. A. (2014). Effect of glycemic control on corneal nerves and peripheral neuropathy in streptozotocin&#x2010;induced diabetic C57Bl/6J mice. Journal of the Peripheral Nervous System, 19(3), 205&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, W., Knoops, K., Berendschot, T. T. J. M., Benedikter, B. J., Webers, C. A. B., Reutelingsperger, C. P. M., &amp; Gorgels, T. G. M. F. (2024). PGC&#x2010;1a mediated mitochondrial biogenesis promotes recovery and survival of neuronal cells from cellular degeneration. Cell Death Discovery, 10(1), 180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaccardi, F., O'Donovan, G., Webb, D. R., Yates, T., Kurl, S., Khunti, K., Davies, M. J., &amp; Laukkanen, J. A. (2015). Cardiorespiratory fitness and risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: A 23&#x2010;year cohort study and a meta&#x2010;analysis of prospective studies. Atherosclerosis, 243(1), 131&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacker, R. (2005). Strength training in diabetes management. Diabetes Spectrum, 18(2), 71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaharieva, D. P., &amp; Addala, A. (2022). Current and novel strategies to reduce fear of hypoglycemia as a barrier to physical activity in adults and youth with type 1 diabetes. Canadian Journal of Diabetes, 46(1), 1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang, Y., Jiang, D., Zhuang, X., &amp; Chen, S. (2023). Changes in the central nervous system in diabetic neuropathy. Heliyon, 9(8), e18368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanuso, S., Sacchetti, M., Sundberg, C. J., Orlando, G., Benvenuti, P., &amp; Balducci, S. (2017). Exercise in type 2 diabetes: Genetic, metabolic and neuromuscular adaptations. A review of the evidence. In British Journal of Sports Medicine (Vol., 51, Issue 21, pp. 1533&#x2013;1538). BMJ Publishing Group.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Shaw, M., &amp; Cherbuin, N. (2022). Association between Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus and Brain Atrophy: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis. Diabetes and Metabolism Journal, 46(5), 781&#x2013;802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. H., Hu, H. Y., Xiong, Y. C., Peng, C., Hu, L., Kong, Y. Z., Wang, Y. L., Guo, J. B., Bi, S., Li, T. S., Ao, L. J., Wang, C. H., Bai, Y. L., Fang, L., Ma, C., Liao, L. R., Liu, H., Zhu, Y., Zhang, Z. J., &#x2026; Wang, X. Q. (2021). Exercise for Neuropathic Pain: A Systematic Review and Expert Consensus. Frontiers in Medicine, 8, 756940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X., He, Q., Zeng, Y., &amp; Cheng, L. (2021). Effectiveness of combined exercise in people with type 2 diabetes and concurrent overweight/obesity: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. British Medical Journal Open, 11(10), e046252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, J., Hu, Z., Luo, Y., Liu, Y., Luo, W., Du, X., Luo, Z., Hu, J., &amp; Peng, S. (2024). Diabetic peripheral neuropathy: Pathogenetic mechanisms and treatment. Frontiers in Endocrinology, 14, 1265372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zochodne, D. W., Verge, V. M. K., Cheng, C., Sun, H., &amp; Johnston, J. (2001). Does diabetes target ganglion neurones? Progressive sensory neurone involvement in long&#x2010;term experimental diabetes. Brain, 124(11), 2319&#x2013;2334.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>