<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22203849</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1687-9635</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2011</Volume><PubDate><Year>2011</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Case reports in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Case Rep Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance exercise reduces skeletal muscle cachexia and improves muscle function in rheumatoid arthritis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>205691</StartPage><MedlinePgn>205691</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">205691</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2011/205691</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rheumatoid arthritis (RA) is a chronic, systemic, autoimmune, inflammatory disease associated with cachexia (reduced muscle and increased fat). Although strength-training exercise has been used in persons with RA, it is not clear if it is effective for reducing cachexia. A 46-year-old woman was studied to determine: (i) if resistance exercise could reverse cachexia by improving muscle mass, fiber cross-sectional area, and muscle function; and (2) if elevated apoptotic signaling was involved in cachexia with RA and could be reduced by resistance training. A needle biopsy was obtained from the vastus lateralis muscle of the RA subject before and after 16 weeks of resistance training. Knee extensor strength increased by 13.6% and fatigue decreased by 2.8% Muscle mass increased by 2.1%. Average muscle fiber cross-sectional area increased by 49.7%, and muscle nuclei increased slightly after strength training from 0.08 to 0.12 nuclei/&#x3bc;m(2). In addition, there was a slight decrease (1.6%) in the number of apoptotic muscle nuclei after resistance training. This case study suggests that resistance training may be a good tool for increasing the number of nuclei per fiber area, decreasing apoptotic nuclei, and inducing fiber hypertrophy in persons with RA, thereby slowing or reversing rheumatoid cachexia.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharif</LastName><ForeName>Salaheddin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Laboratory, West Virginia University School of Medicine, Morgantown, WV 26506-9227, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>James M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donley</LastName><ForeName>David A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilleland</LastName><ForeName>Diana L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonner</LastName><ForeName>Daniel E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCrory</LastName><ForeName>Jean L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hornsby</LastName><ForeName>W Guyton</ForeName><Initials>WG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Hua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lively</LastName><ForeName>Mathew W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hornsby</LastName><ForeName>Jo Ann A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alway</LastName><ForeName>Stephen E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Case Rep Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101512910</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22203849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3235946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2011/205691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Elkan AC, Engvall IL, Cederholm T, Hafstr&#xf6;m I. Rheumatoid cachexia, central obesity and malnutrition in patients with low-active rheumatoid arthritis: feasibility of anthropometry, Mini Nutritional Assessment and body composition techniques. European Journal of Nutrition. 2009;48(5):315&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19333642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkan A-C, H&#xe5;kansson N, Frosteg&#xe5;rd J, Cederholm T, Hafstr&#xf6;m I. Rheumatoid cachexia is associated with dyslipidemia and low levels of atheroprotective natural antibodies against phosphorylcholine but not with dietary fat in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: a cross-sectional study. Arthritis Research and Therapy. 2009;11(2, article R37)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2688183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19284557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Summers GD, Deighton CM, Rennie MJ, Booth AH. Rheumatoid cachexia: a clinical perspective. Rheumatology. 2008;47(8):1124&#x2013;1131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18448480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plasqui G. The role of physical activity in rheumatoid arthritis. Physiology and Behavior. 2008;94(2):270&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18234247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiori MG, Andreola S, Ladelli G, Scirea MR. Selective atrophy of the type IIb muscle fibers in rheumatoid arthritis and progressive systemic sclerosis (scleroderma). A biopsy histochemical study. European Journal of Rheumatology and Inflammation. 1983;6(2):168&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6673981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Grumbt WH, Gonyea WJ, Stray-Gundersen J. Contrasts in muscle and myofibers of elite male and female bodybuilders. Journal of Applied Physiology. 1989;67(1):24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2759948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns AP, McVeigh JG. A systematic review of the effects of dynamic exercise in rheumatoid arthritis. Rheumatology International. 2009;30(2):147&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19701638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parameswaran N, Patial S. Tumor necrosis factor-a signaling in macrophages. Critical Reviews in Eukaryotic Gene Expression. 2010;20(2):87&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3066460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21133840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Morissette MR, Siu PM. Aging and apoptosis in muscle. In: Masoro EJ, Austad S, editors. Handbook of the Biology of Aging. Amsterdam, The Netherlands: Elsevier; 2011. pp. 64&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siu PM, Alway SE. Response and adaptation of skeletal muscle to denervation stress: the role of apoptosis in muscle loss. Frontiers in Bioscience. 2009;14:432&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6355157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19273076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Siu PM. Nuclear apoptosis contributes to sarcopenia. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews. 2008;36(2):51&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2778230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18362685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett FC, Edworthy SM, Bloch DA, et al. The American rheumatism association 1987 revised criteria for the classification of rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 1988;31(3):315&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3358796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevoo MLL, Van &#x2019;T Hof MA, Kuper HH, Van Leeuwen MA, Van De Putte LBA, Van Riel PLCM. Modified disease activity scores that include twenty-eight-joint counts: development and validation in a prospective longitudinal study of patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 1995;38(1):44&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7818570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory JL, Salacinski AJ, Hunt SE, Greenspan SL. Thigh muscle strength in senior athletes and healthy controls. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2009;23(9):2430&#x2013;2436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4876434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19972628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory JL, Martin DF, Lowery RB, et al. Etiologic factors associated with Achilles tendinitis in runners. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 1999;31(10):1374&#x2013;1381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10527307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferketich AK, Kirby TE, Alway SE. Cardiovascular and muscular adaptations to combined endurance and strength training in elderly women. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica. 1998;164(3):259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9853013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson JM, Bryner RW, Sindler A, Frisbee JC, Alway SE. Mitochondrial apoptotic signaling is elevated in cardiac but not skeletal muscle in the obese Zucker rat and is reduced with aerobic exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2008;105(6):1934&#x2013;1943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18832755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson JM, Bryner RW, Alway SE. Satellite cell proliferation is reduced in muscles of obese Zucker rats but restored with loading. American Journal of Physiology. 2008;295(2):C521&#x2013;C528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2518421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18508911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siu PM, Pistilli EE, Butler DC, Alway SE. Aging influences cellular and molecular responses of apoptosis to skeletal muscle unloading. American Journal of Physiology. 2005;288(2):C338&#x2013;C349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15483226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Martyn JK, Ouyang J, Chaudhrai A, Murlasits ZS. Id2 expression during apoptosis and satellite cell activation in unloaded and loaded quail skeletal muscles. American Journal of Physiology. 2003;284(2):R540&#x2013;R549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Leeb G, Strehblow C, Schobersberger W, Haber P, Cauza E. The effects of strength and endurance training in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Clinical Rheumatology. 2010;30:623&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20931346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maradit-Kremers H, Nicola PJ, Crowson CS, Ballman KV, Gabriel SE. Cardiovascular death in rheumatoid arthritis: a population-based study. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2005;52(3):722&#x2013;732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15751097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maradit-Kremers H, Crowson CS, Nicola PJ, et al. Increased unrecognized coronary heart disease and sudden deaths in rheumatoid arthritis: a population-based cohort study. Arthritis and Rheumatism. 2005;52(2):402&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15693010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino T, Kusunoki N, Tanaka N, et al. Elevated serum levels of resistin, leptin, and adiponectin are associated with c-reactive protein and also other clinical conditions in rheumatoid arthritis. Internal Medicine. 2011;50(4):269&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21325757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provan SA, Angel K, Semb AG, et al. Early prediction of increased arterial stiffness in patients with chronic inflammation: a 15-year followup study of 108 patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Journal of Rheumatology. 2011;38(4):606&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21239744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowson CS, Myasoedova E, Davis JM, et al. Increased prevalence of metabolic syndrome associated with rheumatoid arthritis in patients without clinical cardiovascular disease. Journal of Rheumatology. 2011;38(1):29&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3014403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20952464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsios GS, Stavropoulos-Kalinoglou A, Treharne GJ, et al. Disease activity and low physical activity associate with number of hospital admissions and length of hospitalisation in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Research &amp; Therapy. 2011;13, article R108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3218923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21714856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aletaha D, Alasti F, Smolen JS. Rheumatoid arthritis near remission: clinical rather than laboratory inflammation is associated with radiographic progression. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases. 2011;70(11):1975&#x2013;1980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21803751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siu PM, Bryner RW, Murlasits Z, Alway SE. Response of XIAP, ARC, and FLIP apoptotic suppressors to 8 wk of treadmill running in rat heart and skeletal muscle. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2005;99(1):204&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15774698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>