<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37057671</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6519</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in clinical nutrition and metabolic care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Low carbohydrate availability impairs hypertrophy and anaerobic performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>347</StartPage><EndPage>352</EndPage><MedlinePgn>347-352</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000934</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Highlight contemporary evidence examining the effects of carbohydrate restriction on the intracellular regulation of muscle mass and anaerobic performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Low carbohydrate diets increase fat oxidation and decrease fat mass. Emerging evidence suggests that dietary carbohydrate restriction increases protein oxidation, thereby limiting essential amino acid availability necessary to stimulate optimal muscle protein synthesis and promote muscle recovery. Low carbohydrate feeding for 24&#x200a;h increases branched-chain amino acid (BCAA) oxidation and reduces myogenic regulator factor transcription compared to mixed-macronutrient feeding. When carbohydrate restriction is maintained for 8 to 12&#x200a;weeks, the alterations in anabolic signaling, protein synthesis, and myogenesis likely contribute to limited hypertrophic responses to resistance training. The blunted hypertrophic response to resistance training when carbohydrate availability is low does not affect muscle strength, whereas persistently low muscle glycogen does impair anaerobic output during high-intensity sprint and time to exhaustion tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Dietary carbohydrate restriction increases BCAA oxidation and impairs muscle hypertrophy and anaerobic performance, suggesting athletes who need to perform high-intensity exercise should consider avoiding dietary strategies that restrict carbohydrate.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Margolis</LastName><ForeName>Lee M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Military Nutrition.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasiakos</LastName><ForeName>Stefan M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance Divisions, U.S. Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Natick, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804399</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1363-1950</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004040">Dietary Carbohydrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000597">Amino Acids, Branched-Chain</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000693" MajorTopicYN="N">Anaerobiosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004040" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Carbohydrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050528" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet, Carbohydrate-Restricted</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000597" MajorTopicYN="N">Amino Acids, Branched-Chain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37057671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00075197-202307000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ludwig DS, Aronne LJ, Astrup A, et al. The carbohydrate-insulin model: a physiological perspective on the obesity pandemic. Am J Clin Nutr 2021; 114:1873&#x2013;1885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall KD, Farooqi IS, Friedman JM, et al. The energy balance model of obesity: beyond calories in, calories out. Am J Clin Nutr 2022; 115:1243&#x2013;1254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Wilson MA, Whitney CC, et al. Exercising with low muscle glycogen content increases fat oxidation and decreases endogenous, but not exogenous carbohydrate oxidation. Metabolism 2019; 97:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Whitfield J, Heikura IA, et al. Adaptation to a low carbohydrate high fat diet is rapid but impairs endurance exercise metabolism and performance despite enhanced glycogen availability. J Physiol 2021; 599:771&#x2013;790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukkar SG, Muscaritoli M. A clinical perspective of low carbohydrate ketogenic diets: a narrative review. Front Nutr 2021; 8:642628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Wilson MA, Whitney CC, et al. Initiating aerobic exercise with low glycogen content reduces markers of myogenesis but not mTORC1 signaling. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela PL, Castillo-Garcia A, Lucia A, Naclerio F. Effects of combining a ketogenic diet with resistance training on body composition, strength, and mechanical power in trained individuals: a narrative review. Nutrients 2021; 13:3083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy NE, Carrigan CT, Margolis LM. High-fat ketogenic diets and physical performance: a systematic review. Adv Nutr 2021; 12:223&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen MS, Holm L, Svart MV, et al. Effects of protein intake prior to carbohydrate-restricted endurance exercise: a randomized crossover trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2020; 17:7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillen JB, West DWD, Williamson EP, et al. Low-carbohydrate training increases protein requirements of endurance athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2019; 51:2294&#x2013;2301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Karl JP, Wilson MA, et al. Serum branched-chain amino acid metabolites increase in males when aerobic exercise is initiated with low muscle glycogen. Metabolites 2021; 11:828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwin JA, Church DD, Hatch-McChesney A, et al. Essential amino acid-enriched whey enhances postexercise whole-body protein balance during energy deficit more than iso-nitrogenous whey or a mixed-macronutrient meal: a randomized, crossover study. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwin JA, Church DD, Hatch-McChesney A, et al. Effects of high versus standard essential amino acid intakes on whole-body protein turnover and mixed muscle protein synthesis during energy deficit: a randomized, crossover study. Clin Nutr 2021; 40:767&#x2013;777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Cenci L, Pompei P, et al. Effects of two months of very low carbohydrate ketogenic diet on body composition, muscle strength, muscle area, and blood parameters in competitive natural body builders. Nutrients 2021; 13:374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster CC, van Boom KM, Armino N, et al. Reduced glucose tolerance and skeletal muscle GLUT4 and IRS1 content in cyclists habituated to a long-term low-carbohydrate, high-fat diet. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 2020; 30:210&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigh-Larsen JF, Ortenblad N, Spriet LL, et al. Muscle glycogen metabolism and high-intensity exercise performance: a narrative review. Sports Med 2021; 51:1855&#x2013;1874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond KM, Impey SG, Currell K, et al. Postexercise high-fat feeding suppresses p70S6K1 activity in human skeletal muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2016; 48:2108&#x2013;2117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao D, Villet O, Zhang Z, et al. Glucose promotes cell growth by suppressing branched-chain amino acid degradation. Nat Commun 2018; 9:2935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Angelis L, Balasubramanian S, Berghella L. Akt-mediated phosphorylation controls the activity of the Y-box protein MSY3 in skeletal muscle. Skelet Muscle 2015; 5:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Liu P, Hu Y, et al. Cold-Induced RNA-binding protein promotes glucose metabolism and reduces apoptosis by increasing AKT phosphorylation in mouse skeletal muscle under acute cold exposure. Front Mol Biosci 2021; 8:685993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragozzino E, Brancaccio M, Di Costanzo A, et al. 6-Bromoindirubin-3&#x2019;-oxime intercepts GSK3 signaling to promote and enhance skeletal muscle differentiation affecting miR-206 expression in mice. Sci Rep 2019; 9:18091.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litwiniuk A, Pijet B, Pijet-Kucicka M, et al. FOXO1 and GSK-3beta are main targets of insulin-mediated myogenesis in C2C12 muscle cells. PLoS One 2016; 11:e0146726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szwed A, Kim E, Jacinto E. Regulation and metabolic functions of mTORC1 and mTORC2. Physiol Rev 2021; 101:1371&#x2013;1426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holowaty MNH, Lees MJ, Abou Sawan S, et al. Leucine ingestion promotes mTOR translocation to the periphery and enhances total and peripheral RPS6 phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle. Amino Acids 2023; 55:253&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman JL, Carrigan CT, Margolis LM. Body composition changes in physically active individuals consuming ketogenic diets: a systematic review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18:41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulussen KJM, McKenna CF, Beals JW, et al. Anabolic resistance of muscle protein turnover comes in various shapes and sizes. Front Nutr 2021; 8:615849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henselmans M, Bjornsen T, Hedderman R, Varvik FT. The effect of carbohydrate intake on strength and resistance training performance: a systematic review. Nutrients 2022; 14:856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Allen JT, Hatch-McChesney A, Pasiakos SM. Coingestion of carbohydrate and protein on muscle glycogen synthesis after exercise: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2021; 53:384&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hearris MA, Hammond KM, Seaborne RA, et al. Graded reductions in preexercise muscle glycogen impair exercise capacity but do not augment skeletal muscle cell signaling: implications for CHO periodization. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2019; 126:1587&#x2013;1597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Freidenreich DJ, Saenz C, et al. Metabolic characteristics of keto-adapted ultra-endurance runners. Metabolism 2016; 65:100&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>