<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41234691</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiological adaptations and practical efficacy of different blood flow restriction resistance training modes in athletic populations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1683442</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1683442</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1683442</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2025.1683442</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Blood flow restriction resistance training enhances athletic adaptations via distinct mechano-metabolic pathways. This review synthesizes evidence comparing three blood flow restriction resistance training modalities: Low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction (using 20%-30% of one-repetition maximum) prioritizes metabolic stress (lactate and hydrogen ion accumulation, cellular swelling), activating growth hormone (GH)/insulin-like growth factor 1 (IGF-1)/mechanistic target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathways to promote type I muscle fiber hypertrophy, making it suitable for joint-sparing rehabilitation scenarios. Supplemental blood flow restriction resistance training programs combine high-load tension (utilizing 75%-90% of one-repetition maximum) with additional blood flow restriction to produce an acute synergistic effect. This method enhances the recruitment of type IIa/x muscle fibers and prolongs mTOR phosphorylation. Combined blood flow restriction resistance training employs alternating cycles of high-load phases (70%-85% 1RM) and blood flow restriction phases (hypoxia-inducible factor 1-alpha (HIF-1&#x3b1;)-mediated angiogenesis), optimizing phosphocreatine resynthesis and neural drive to achieve specialization of type IIx muscle fibers. Periodized application requires matching modalities with training phases: combined blood flow restriction training for hypertrophy during the preparatory phase, supplemental blood flow restriction training for strength maintenance during the competitive phase, and low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction for active recovery. This mechanistic framework supports evidence-based blood flow restriction resistance training programming to maximize athletic adaptations while mitigating injury risk.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 He, Zhu and Hu.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Chuang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Xi'an Binhe School, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Dinghuang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Athletic Performance, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yunzhou</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Athletic Performance, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41234691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12605898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1683442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1683442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T., Kawamoto K., Yasuda T., Kearns C. F., Midorikawa T., Sato Y. (2005). Eight days KAATSU-resistance training improved sprint but not jump performance in collegiate male track and field athletes. Int. J. KAATSU Train. Res. 1 (1), 19&#x2013;23. 10.3806/ijktr.1.19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3806/ijktr.1.19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Alvarez I. F., Damas F., Biazon T. M. P., Miquelini M., Doma K., Libardi C. A. (2020). Muscle damage responses to resistance exercise performed with high-load <i>versus</i> low-load associated with partial blood flow restriction in young women. Eur. J. Sport Sci.
20 (1), 125&#x2013;134. 10.1080/17461391.2019.1614680

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2019.1614680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31043129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M., Sidhu S. K., Weavil J. C., Mangum T. S., Venturelli M. (2015). Autonomic responses to exercise: group III/IV muscle afferents and fatigue. Auton. Neurosci. 188, 19&#x2013;23. 10.1016/j.autneu.2014.10.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2014.10.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4336599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25458423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornsen and Wernbom M., Wernbom M., L&#xf8;vstad A., Paulsen G., D'Souza R. F., Cameron-Smith D., et al. (2019a). Delayed myonuclear addition, myofiber hypertrophy, and increases in strength with high-frequency low-load blood flow restricted training to volitional failure. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 126 (3), 578&#x2013;592. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00397.2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00397.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30543499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornsen and Wernbom M., Wernbom M., Kirketeig A., Paulsen G., Samn&#xf8;y L., B&#xe6;kken L., et al. (2019b). Type 1 muscle fiber hypertrophy after blood flow-restricted training in powerlifters. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 51 (2), 288&#x2013;298. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001775</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30188363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C., Wiegel P., Gollhofer A., Konig D. (2019). Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in older individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 49 (1), 95&#x2013;108. 10.1007/s40279-018-0994-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0994-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6349784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che T., Li Z. Y., Yang T. L., Chen Z. T., Wang S. (2022). Effects of six-week low intensity KAATSU training combined with high intensity resistance training on core area and lower limb muscle strength in adolescent female wrestlers. J. Cap. Univ. Phys. Educ. Sports 34 (3), 333&#x2013;341. 10.14036/j.cnki.cn11-4513.2022.03.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14036/j.cnki.cn11-4513.2022.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary C. J., Herda T. J., Quick A. M., Herda A. A. (2022). Acute muscle swelling effects of a knee rehabilitation exercise performed with and without blood flow restriction. PLoS One 17 (12), e0278540. 10.1371/journal.pone.0278540</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0278540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9778495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36548274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook S. B., Murphy B. G., Labarbera K. E. (2013). Neuromuscular function after a bout of low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 45 (1), 67&#x2013;74. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31826c6fa8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31826c6fa8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22895371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counts B. R., Dankel S. J., Barnett B. E., Kim D., Mouser J. G., Allen K. M., et al. (2016). Influence of relative blood flow restriction pressure on muscle activation and muscle adaptation. Muscle Nerve 53 (3), 438&#x2013;445. 10.1002/mus.24756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.24756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26137897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuddeford T., Brumitt J. (2020). In-Season rehabilitation program using blood flow restriction therapy for two decathletes with patellar tendinopathy: a case report. Int. J. Sports Phys. Ther. 15 (6), 1184&#x2013;1195. 10.26603/ijspt20201184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20201184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diao K., Min X., Zhang T., Su Y., Ji C. (2025). The effects of blood flow restriction combined with low-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and pain during postoperative recovery in patients with knee injuries: a meta-analysis. Res. Sports Med., 1&#x2013;15. 10.1080/15438627.2025.2511110</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15438627.2025.2511110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40448940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong K., Tang J., Xu C., Gui W., Tian J., Chun B., et al. (2025). The effects of blood flow restriction combined with endurance training on athletes' aerobic capacity, lower limb muscle strength, anaerobic power and sports performance: a meta-analysis. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabil. 17 (1), 24. 10.1186/s13102-025-01072-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01072-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11847382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39987129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs C. A., Loenneke J. P., Thiebaud R. S., Rossow L. M., Kim D., Abe T., et al. (2015). Muscular adaptations to fatiguing exercise with and without blood flow restriction. Clin. Physiol. Funct. Imaging 35 (3), 167&#x2013;176. 10.1111/cpf.12141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng Y., Wu X., Zhang L. (2021). Effects of blood flow restriction training on blood perfusion and work ability of muscles in elite para-alpine skiers. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 41 (8), 489&#x2013;496. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002805</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34669671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg A. L., Etlinger J. D., Goldspink D. F., Jablecki C. (1975). Mechanism of work-induced hypertrophy of skeletal muscle. Med. Sci. Sports 7 (3), 185&#x2013;198. 10.1249/00005768-197500730-00016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-197500730-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">128681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanke A. A., Wiechmann K., Suckow P., Rolff S. (2020). Effectiveness of blood flow restriction training in competitive sports. Unfallchirurg 123 (3), 176&#x2013;179. 10.1007/s00113-020-00779-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00113-020-00779-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32030479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hostrup M., Cairns S. P., Bangsbo J. (2021). Muscle ionic shifts during exercise: implications for fatigue and exercise performance. Compr. Physiol. 11 (3), 1895&#x2013;1959. 10.1002/cphy.c190024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cphy.c190024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34190344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J., Park H. Y. (2024). Effect of blood flow restriction with low-intensity resistance training in patients with osteoarthritis and rheumatoid arthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis based on randomized controlled trials. Phys. Act. Nutr. 28 (1), 7&#x2013;19. 10.20463/pan.2024.0002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2024.0002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11079382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38719461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korkmaz E., Donmez G., Uzuner K., Babayeva N., Torgutalp S. S., Ozcakar L. (2022). Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscle strength and architecture. J. Strength Cond. Res. 36 (5), 1396&#x2013;1403. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32287091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino G. C., Ugrinowitsch C., Roschel H., Aoki M. S., Soares A. G., Neves M., Jr., et al. (2012). Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 44 (3), 406&#x2013;412. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318233b4bc</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318233b4bc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Zhao Z. G., Wang M. B., Chen C., Liang Y. J. (2019). Effect of 4 weeks KAATSU training on body composition and maximum strength of Male handball players. China Sport Sci. Technol. 55 (05), 37&#x2013;43. 10.16470/j.csst.2019045%WCNKI</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16470/j.csst.2019045%WCNKI</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R., Chee C. S., Kamalden T. F., Ramli A. S., Yang K. (2024). Effects of blood flow restriction training on sports performance in athletes: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J. Sports Med. Phys. Fit. 64 (1), 55&#x2013;65. 10.23736/S0022-4707.23.15220-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.23.15220-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37902798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke J. P., Fahs C. A., Rossow L. M., Abe T., Bemben M. G. (2012). The anabolic benefits of venous blood flow restriction training May be induced by muscle cell swelling. Med. Hypotheses 78 (1), 151&#x2013;154. 10.1016/j.mehy.2011.10.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2011.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22051111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubowitz J. H., Brand J. C., Rossi M. J. (2022). Comprehensive review of shoulder instability includes diagnosis, nonoperative management, bankart, latarjet, remplissage, glenoid bone-grafting, revision surgery, rehabilitation and return to play, and clinical Follow-Up. Arthroscopy 38 (2), 209&#x2013;210. 10.1016/j.arthro.2021.11.052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2021.11.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luebbers P. E., Fry A. C., Kriley L. M., Butler M. S. (2014). The effects of a 7-week practical blood flow restriction program on well-trained collegiate athletes. J. Strength Cond. Res. 28 (8), 2270&#x2013;2280. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24476782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luebbers P. E., Kriley L. M., Eserhaut D. A., Andre M. J., Butler M. S., Fry A. C. (2024). Salivary testosterone and cortisol responses to seven weeks of practical blood flow restriction training in collegiate American football players. Front. Physiol. 15, 1507445. 10.3389/fphys.2024.1507445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1507445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11750839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39844895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A., Hamlin M. J., Ross J. J., Taylor R., Manimmanakorn N. (2013). Effects of low-load resistance training combined with blood flow restriction or hypoxia on muscle function and performance in netball athletes. J. Sci. Med. Sport 16 (4), 337&#x2013;342. 10.1016/j.jsams.2012.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2012.08.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22999393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Hern&#xe1;ndez J., Mar&#xed;n P. J., Men&#xe9;ndez H., Ferrero C., Loenneke J. P., Herrero A. J. (2013). Muscular adaptations after two different volumes of blood flow-restricted training. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 23 (2), e114&#x2013;e120. 10.1111/sms.12036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell E. A., Martin N. R. W., Turner M. C., Taylor C. W., Ferguson R. A. (2019). The combined effect of sprint interval training and postexercise blood flow restriction on critical power, capillary growth, and mitochondrial proteins in trained cyclists. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 126 (1), 51&#x2013;59. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01082.2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01082.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30335575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouser J. G., Laurentino G. C., Dankel S. J., Buckner S. L., Jessee M. B., Counts B. R., et al. (2017). Blood flow in humans following low-load exercise with and without blood flow restriction. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 42 (11), 1165&#x2013;1171. 10.1139/apnm-2017-0102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2017-0102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28704612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyakayiru J., Fuchs C. J., Trommelen J., Smeets J. S. J., Senden J. M., Gijsen A. P., et al. (2019). Blood flow restriction only increases myofibrillar protein synthesis with exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc 51 (6), 1137&#x2013;1145. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001899</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6553970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30694972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira J., Campos Y., Leit&#xe3;o L., Arriel R., Novaes J., Vianna J. (2020). Does acute blood flow restriction with pneumatic and non-pneumatic non-elastic cuffs promote similar responses in blood lactate, growth hormone, and peptide hormone? J. Hum. Kinet. 74, 85&#x2013;97. 10.2478/hukin-2020-0016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson D., Hughes L., Warmington S., Burr J., Scott B. R., Owens J., et al. (2019). Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front. Physiology 10, 533. 10.3389/fphys.2019.00533</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6530612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson S. J., Hussain S. R. (2015). A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 45 (2), 187&#x2013;200. 10.1007/s40279-014-0264-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0264-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pignanelli C., Christiansen D., Burr J. F. (2021). Blood flow restriction training and the high-performance athlete: science to application. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 130 (4), 1163&#x2013;1170. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00982.2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00982.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope Z. K., Willardson J. M., Schoenfeld B. J. (2013). Exercise and blood flow restriction. J. Strength Cond. Res. 27 (10), 2914&#x2013;2926. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182874721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182874721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23364292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolnick N., Kamis O. (2023). Important methodological concern regarding the article &#x201c;Effect of Leg Half-Squat Training With Blood Flow Restriction Under Different External Loads on Strength and Vertical Jumping Performance in Well-Trained Volleyball Players&#x201d;: a letter to the editor. Dose Response 21 (2), 15593258231173494. 10.1177/15593258231173494</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15593258231173494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10141283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37123605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarfabadi P., Rizvi M. R., Sharma A., Sami W., Sajid M. R., Arora S., et al. (2023). Elevating athletic performance: maximizing strength and power in long jumpers through combined low-intensity blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training. Heliyon 9 (8), e19068. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e19068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e19068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10457511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37636460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J. (2013a). Postexercise hypertrophic adaptations: a reexamination of the hormone hypothesis and its applicability to resistance training program design. J. Strength Cond. Res. 27 (6), 1720&#x2013;1730. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828ddd53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828ddd53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J. (2013b). Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 43 (3), 179&#x2013;194. 10.1007/s40279-013-0017-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0017-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23338987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott B. R., Peiffer J. J., Goods P. S. R. (2017). The effects of supplementary low-load blood flow restriction training on morphological and performance-based adaptations in team sport athletes. J. Strength Cond. Res. 31 (8), 2147&#x2013;2154. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28737609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott B. R., Girard O., Rolnick N., McKee J. R., Goods P. S. R. (2023). An updated panorama of blood-flow-restriction methods. Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 18 (12), 1461&#x2013;1465. 10.1123/ijspp.2023-0135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2023-0135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37777193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz J., Stultz J., Burr J. F. (2016). The efficacy of blood flow restricted exercise: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Sci. Med. Sport 19 (8), 669&#x2013;675. 10.1016/j.jsams.2015.09.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.09.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith N. D. W., Scott B. R., Girard O., Peiffer J. J. (2022). Aerobic training with blood flow restriction for endurance athletes: potential benefits and considerations of implementation. J. Strength Cond. Res. 36 (12), 3541&#x2013;3550. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spangenburg E. E. (2005). SOCS-3 induces myoblast differentiation. J. Biol. Chem. 280 (11), 10749&#x2013;10758. 10.1074/jbc.M410604200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M410604200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15653674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su C., Zhang Z., Liang B., Zhou S., Long X. (2025). Effects of blood flow restriction combined with high-load training on muscle strength and sports performance in athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front. Physiol. 16, 1603568. 10.3389/fphys.2025.1603568</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1603568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12263612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40671707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y., Nakamura Y., Aruga S., Onda T., Miyazaki S., Ishii N. (2000). Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J. Appl. Physiology 88 (1), 61&#x2013;65. 10.1152/jappl.2000.88.1.61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.1.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugur B., Angin E., Kirmizigil B., Yolcu M. (2023). Blood flow restriction training on physical parameters in elite Male canoe athletes. Med. Baltim. 102 (41), e35252. 10.1097/MD.0000000000035252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000035252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10578733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37832066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F. , H., Fan Y., Zhang M., Fan Y. (2022). Effect of leg half-squat training with blood flow restriction under different external loads on strength and vertical jumping performance in well-trained volleyball players. Dose Response 20 (3), 15593258221123673. 10.1177/15593258221123673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15593258221123673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9500279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36158741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Li Z., Tongtong C., Zhang W., Li X. (2023). Effect of continuous and intermittent blood flow restriction deep-squat training on thigh muscle activation and fatigue levels in Male handball players. Sci. Rep. 13 (1), 19152. 10.1038/s41598-023-44523-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-44523-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10628241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37932313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M. B., Li Z. Y., Wei W. Z., Zhao Z. G., Chen C., Haung J. P. (2019). Empirical study of KAATSU training effect on lower limb of male elite handball player. China Sport Sci. Technol. 55 (05), 30&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M., Aagaard P. (2020). Muscle fibre activation and fatigue with low-load blood flow restricted resistance exercise-An integrative physiology review. Acta Physiol. (Oxf) 228 (1), e13302. 10.1111/apha.13302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.13302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31108025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M., Krzysztofik M., Gepfert M., Poprzecki S., Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A., Maszczyk A. (2018). Technical and training related aspects of resistance training using blood flow restriction in competitive sport - a review. J. Hum. Kinet. 65, 249&#x2013;260. 10.2478/hukin-2018-0101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2018-0101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6341949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30687436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortman R. J., Brown S. M., Savage-Elliott I., Finley Z. J., Mulcahey M. K. (2021). Blood flow restriction training for athletes: a systematic review. Am. J. Sports Med. 49 (7), 1938&#x2013;1944. 10.1177/0363546520964454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546520964454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamanaka T., Farley R. S., Caputo J. L. (2012). Occlusion training increases muscular strength in division IA football players. J. Strength Cond. Res. 26 (9), 2523&#x2013;2529. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823f2b0e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823f2b0e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22105051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Zhang P., Sevilla-Sanchez M., Zhou D., Cao J., He J., et al. (2022). Low-load blood flow restriction squat as conditioning activity within a contrast training sequence in high-level preadolescent trampoline gymnasts. Front. Physiol. 13, 852693. 10.3389/fphys.2022.852693</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.852693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35770193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T., Ogasawara R., Sakamaki M., Ozaki H., Sato Y., Abe T. (2011). Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 111 (10), 2525&#x2013;2533. 10.1007/s00421-011-1873-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1873-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Gao X., Gao L. (2025). Effects of blood flow restriction training on aerobic capacity and performance in endurance athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabil. 17 (1), 160. 10.1186/s13102-025-01194-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01194-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12217518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40605032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Xu K., Yin M., Duan B., Kong H., Xie Y., et al. (2025). Effects of blood flow restriction training in athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int. J. Sports Med. 46 (7), 467&#x2013;481. 10.1055/a-2537-5879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2537-5879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39933726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H., Liu J., Wei J., Chen H., Tang S., Zhou Z. (2022). The influence on post-activation potentiation exerted by different degrees of blood flow restriction and multi-levels of activation intensity. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health 19 (17), 10597. 10.3390/ijerph191710597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191710597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36078311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu D. H. (2021). Effects of blood flow restriction training on anaerobic capacity and lower limb strength in taekwondo athletes. Shanghai, China: Shanghai University of Sport.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C., Ding X., Chen M., Feng J., Zou J., Zhang L. (2025). Exercise-mediated skeletal muscle-derived IL-6 regulates bone metabolism: a new perspective on muscle-bone crosstalk. Biomolecules 15 (6), 893. 10.3390/biom15060893</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom15060893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12190190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40563533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>