<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36727999</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>New Perspectives in Resistance Training Periodization: Mixed Session vs. Block Periodized Programs in Trained Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>537</StartPage><EndPage>545</EndPage><MedlinePgn>537-545</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004465</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bartolomei, S, Zaniboni, F, Verzieri, N, and Hoffman, JR. New perspectives in resistance training periodization: mixed session vs. block periodized programs in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 37(3): 537-545, 2023-The purpose of this investigation was to compare the effects of 2 different periodized resistance training programs on maximal strength, power, and muscle architecture, in trained individuals. Twenty-two resistance-trained men were randomly assigned to either a mixed session training group (MSP; n = 11; age = 23.7 &#xb1; 2.6 years; body mass = 80.5 &#xb1; 9.8 kg; height = 175.5 &#xb1; 6.1 cm) or a block periodization group (BP; n = 11; age = 25.7 &#xb1; 4.6 years; body mass = 81.1 &#xb1; 10.7 kg; height = 176.8 &#xb1; 8.4 cm). Both training programs were 10 weeks in duration and were equated in volume. Each training session of the MSP focused on power, maximal strength, and hypertrophy, whereas each mesocycle within the BP focused on one of these components. Subjects were assessed for body composition, muscle architecture, maximal strength, and power. In addition, perceived training load, and training volume were calculated. Subjects in MSP experienced greater improvements in fat free mass ( p = 0.021), muscle thickness of the pectoralis and vastus lateralis ( p &lt; 0.05), and a greater improvement in 1RM bench press ( p &lt; 0.001; +8.6% in MSP and +2% in BP) than in BP. By contrast, BP resulted in greater improvements in vertical jump ( p = 0.022; +7.2%) compared with MSP (+1.2%). No significant differences were noted between the groups for perceived training load ( p = 0.362) nor training volume ( p = 0.169). Results of this study indicated that in a 10-week training study, MSP may enhance muscle hypertrophy and maximal strength to a greater extent than BP, with the same training volume and perceived training load. However, BP may be more effective for vertical jump improvement.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bartolomei</LastName><ForeName>Sandro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Neuromotor Sciences, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaniboni</LastName><ForeName>Federico</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Life Quality Studies, University of Bologna, Rimini, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verzieri</LastName><ForeName>Nicol&#xf2;</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Life Quality Studies, University of Bologna, Rimini, Italy; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffman</LastName><ForeName>Jay R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Ariel University, Ariel, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36727999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202303000-00001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kondo M, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. Prediction equations for body composition of Japanese adults by B-mode ultrasound. Am J Hum Biol 6: 161&#x2013;170, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostinho MF, Moreira A, Julio UF, et al. Monitoring internal training load and salivary immune-endocrine responses during an annual judo training periodization. J Exerc Rehab 13: 68&#x2013;75, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Hoffman JR, Merni F, Stout JR. A comparison of traditional and block periodized strength training programs in trained athletes. J Strength Cond Res 28: 990&#x2013;997, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Hoffman JR, Stout JR, Merni F. Effect of lower-body resistance training on upper-body strength adaptation in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 32: 13&#x2013;18, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Lanzoni IM, Fantozzi S, Cortesi M. A comparison between non-localized post-activation performance enhancements following resistance exercise for the upper and the lower body. Appl Sci 12: 1&#x2013;8, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Nigro F, Ruggeri S, Lanzoni IM, et al. Comparison between bench press throw and ballistic push-up tests to assess upper-body power in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res 32: 1503&#x2013;1510, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG. Use of diagnostic ultrasound for assessing muscle size. J Strength Cond Res 16: 103&#x2013;108, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Gill ND, Zhou S. Intra&#x2010; and intermuscular variation in human quadriceps femoris architecture assessed in vivo. J Anat 209: 289&#x2013;310, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borresen J, Lambert MI. The quantification of training load, the training response and the effect on performance. Sports Med 39: 779&#x2013;795, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brink MS, Visscher C, Coutts AJ, Lemmink KA. Changes in perceived stress and recovery in overreached young elite soccer players. Scand J Med Sci Sports 22: 285&#x2013;292, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cissik J, Hedrick A, Barnes M. Challenges applying the research on periodization. Strength Cond J 30: 45&#x2013;51, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G. Appropriate reporting of exercise variables in resistance training protocols: Much more than load and number of repetitions. Sports Med Open 8: 1&#x2013;11, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunanan AJ, DeWeese BH, Wagle JP, et al. The general adaptation syndrome: A foundation for the concept of periodization. Sports Med 48: 787&#x2013;797, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza Bezerra E, da Rosa Orssatto LB, De Moura BM, Willardson JM, Sim&#xe3;o R, Moro AR. Mixed session periodization as a new approach for strength, power, functional performance, and body composition enhancement in aging adults. J Strength Cond Res 32: 2795&#x2013;2806, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Enoka RM. Human motor unit recordings: Origins and insight into the integrated motor system. Brain Res 1409: 42&#x2013;61, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans EM, Rowe DA, Misic MM, Prior BM, Arngrisson SA. Skinfold prediction equation for athletes developed using a four-component model. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 2006&#x2013;2011, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Cond Res 15: 109&#x2013;115, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad M, Stylianides G, Djaoui L, Dellal A, Chamari K. Session-RPE method for training load monitoring: Validity, ecological usefulness, and influencing factors. Front Neurosci 11: 1&#x2013;14, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harries SK, Lubans DR, Callister R. Comparison of resistance training progression models on maximal strength in sub-elite adolescent rugby union players. J Sci Med Sport 19: 163&#x2013;169, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J. Physiological Aspects of Sport Training and Performance. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2014. p. 120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB. New horizons for the methodology and physiology of training periodization. Sports Med 40: 189&#x2013;206, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB. Periodization training from ancient precursors to structured block models. Kinesiology 2: 3&#x2013;9, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Fleck SJ. Optimizing Strength Training: Designing Nonlinear Periodization Workouts. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2007. pp. 12&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Hoffman JR, Gonzalez AM, et al. The effect of training volume and intensity on improvements in muscular strength and size in resistance&#x2010;trained men. Physiol Rep 3: e12472, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyatani M, Kanehisa H, Ito M, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. The accuracy of volume estimates using ultrasound muscle thickness measurements in different muscle groups. Eur J Appl Physiol 91: 264&#x2013;272, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moesgaard L, Beck MM, Christiansen L, Aagaard P, Lundbye-Jensen J. Effects of periodization on strength and muscle hypertrophy in volume-equated resistance training programs: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 19: 1&#x2013;21, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moura BM, Bezerra ED, Orssatto LB, Moro AR, Diefenthaeler F. Inter-individual rapid force improvements after mixed session and traditional periodization in aging adults: A randomized trial. J Sci Sport Exerc 3: 125&#x2013;137, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Sullivan C, Meaney J, Boyle G, Gormley J, Stokes M. The validity of rehabilitative ultrasound imaging for measurement of trapezius muscle thickness. Man Ther 14: 572&#x2013;578, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter K, Haff GG, Ramsey M, et al. Strength gains: Block versus daily undulating periodization weight training among track and field athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 7: 161&#x2013;169, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poliquin C. Five steps to increasing the effectiveness of your strength training program. Strength Cond J 10: 34&#x2013;39, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, &#xd8;fsteng SJ, Ellefsen S. Block periodization of strength and endurance training is superior to traditional periodization in ice hockey players. Scand J Med Sci Sports 29: 180&#x2013;188, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabido R, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Botella J, Jim&#xe9;nez-Leiva A, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Fern&#xe1;ndez J. Effects of block and daily undulating periodization on neuromuscular performance in young male handball players. Kinesiology 50: 97&#x2013;103, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Androulakis-Korakakis P, Carlson L, et al. The impact of coronavirus (COVID-19) related public-health measures on training behaviours of individuals previously participating in resistance training: A cross-sectional survey study. Sports Med 51: 1561&#x2013;1580, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens JP. Applied Multivariate Statistics for the Social Science (5th ed). New York, NY: Taylor and Francis, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, O'Bryant H, Garhammer J, McMillan J, Rozenek R. A theoretical model of strength training. Strength Cond J 4: 36&#x2013;39, 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis SK, Pritchard HJ, Mujika I, Gentles JA, Stone MH, Bazyler CD. Characterizing the tapering practices of United States and Canadian raw powerlifters. J Strength Cond Res 35: S26&#x2013;S35, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verchosanskij JV. Fundamentals of Special Strength Training in Sport. Moscow, Russia: Fizkultura I Sport 1977 (Translated from Charniga, AC). Livonia, MI: Sportivny Press, 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, Haff GG, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Newton RU. Moderate-load muscular endurance strength training did not improve peak power or functional capacity in older men and women. Front Physiol 8: 743, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, Peltonen H, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Medium-intensity, high-volume &#x201c;hypertrophic&#x201d; resistance training did not induce improvements in rapid force production in healthy older men. Age 37: 1&#x2013;10, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Klemp A, Dolan C, et al. Novel resistance training&#x2013;specific rating of perceived exertion scale measuring repetitions in reserve. J Strength Cond Res 30: 267&#x2013;275, 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>