<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34125411</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>No Time to Lift? Designing Time-Efficient Training Programs for Strength and Hypertrophy: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2079</StartPage><EndPage>2095</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2079-2095</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-021-01490-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lack of time is among the more commonly reported barriers for abstention from exercise programs. The aim of this review was to determine how strength training can be most effectively carried out in a time-efficient manner by critically evaluating research on acute training variables, advanced training techniques, and the need for warm-up and stretching. When programming strength training for optimum time-efficiency we recommend prioritizing bilateral, multi-joint exercises that include full dynamic movements (i.e. both eccentric and concentric muscle actions), and to perform a minimum of one leg pressing exercise (e.g. squats), one upper-body pulling exercise (e.g. pull-up) and one upper-body pushing exercise (e.g. bench press). Exercises can be performed with machines and/or free weights based on training goals, availability, and personal preferences. Weekly training volume is more important than training frequency and we recommend performing a minimum of 4 weekly sets per muscle group using a 6-15 RM loading range (15-40 repetitions can be used if training is performed to volitional failure). Advanced training techniques, such as supersets, drop sets and rest-pause training roughly halves training time compared to traditional training, while maintaining training volume. However, these methods are probably better at inducing hypertrophy than muscular strength, and more research is needed on longitudinal training effects. Finally, we advise restricting the warm-up to exercise-specific warm-ups, and only prioritize stretching if the goal of training is to increase flexibility. This review shows how acute training variables can be manipulated, and how specific training techniques can be used to optimize the training response: time ratio in regard to improvements in strength and hypertrophy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iversen</LastName><ForeName>Vegard M</ForeName><Initials>VM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5234-0360</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Nursing, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway. Vegard.m.iversen@ntnu.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuromedicine and Movement Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway. Vegard.m.iversen@ntnu.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Norum</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, Norum Helse AS, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fimland</LastName><ForeName>Marius S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuromedicine and Movement Science, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unicare Helsefort Rehabilitation Centre, Rissa, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Sports Med. 2022 Jun;52(6):1451-1452. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01592-w.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34784019</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Sports Med. 2022 Jun;52(6):1449-1450. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01591-x.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34784020</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Vegard M Iversen, Martin Norum, Brad J Schoenfeld and Marius S Fimland declare that they have no conflicts of interest relevant to the content of this review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34125411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8449772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01490-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-021-01490-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibbler WB, Kraemer WJ, et al. ACSM: Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sport Exer. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Haskell WL, Ades PA, Amsterdam EA, Bittner V, Franklin BA, et al. Resistance exercise in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: 2007 update: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association Council on Clinical Cardiology and Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism. Circulation. 2007;116(5):572&#x2013;584. doi: 10.1161/circulationaha.107.185214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.107.185214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17638929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO guidelines approved by the guidelines review committee. Global recommendations on physical activity for health. Geneva: World Health Organization. Copyright (c) World Health Organization 2010.; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guthold R, Stevens GA, Riley LM, Bull FC. Worldwide trends in insufficient physical activity from 2001 to 2016: a pooled analysis of 358 population-based surveys with 1&#xb7;9 million participants. Lancet Glob Health. 2018;6(10):e1077&#x2013;e1086. doi: 10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30357-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30357-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30193830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson WR. Worldwide survey of fitness trends for 2021. ACSM's Health Fit J. 2021;25(1):10&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1249/fit.0000000000000631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/fit.0000000000000631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley KS, Flippin KJ, Blom LC, Bolin JE, Hoover DL, Judge LW. Practices, Perceived benefits, and barriers to resistance training among women enrolled in college. Int J Exer Sci. 2018;11(5):226&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5955292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoare E, Stavreski B, Jennings GL, Kingwell BA. Exploring motivation and barriers to physical activity among active and inactive australian adults. Sports (Basel, Switzerland) 2017;5(3):47. doi: 10.3390/sports5030047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports5030047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, Franklin BA, Lamonte MJ, Lee IM, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sport Exer. 2011;43(7):1334&#x2013;1359. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213fefb.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213fefb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness: a review of the acute programme variables. Sports Med (Auckland, NZ) 2005;35(10):841&#x2013;851. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200535100-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535100-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16180944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Buchan D, Baker JS. Weekly training frequency effects on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;4(1):36. doi: 10.1186/s40798-018-0149-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-018-0149-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6081873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30076500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Krieger J. How many times per week should a muscle be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci. 2018 doi: 10.1080/02640414.2018.1555906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2018.1555906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, Lazinica B, Krieger JW, Pedisic Z. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(5):1207&#x2013;1220. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilen A, Hjelvang LB, Dall N, Kruse NL, Nordsborg NB. Adaptations to short, frequent sessions of endurance and strength training are similar to longer, less frequent exercise sessions when the total volume is the same. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(Suppl 11):S46&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000001110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26506198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilen A, Bay J, Bejder J, Breenfeldt Andersen A, Bonne TC, Larsen PD, et al. Impact of low-volume concurrent strength training distribution on muscular adaptation. J Sci Med Sport. 2020;23(10):999&#x2013;1004. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2020.03.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2020.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32371120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med (Auckland, NZ) 2018;48(3):499&#x2013;505. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0793-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0793-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29022275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Garzarella L, de Hoyos D, Pollock ML. Single versus multiple sets in long-term recreational weightlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(1):235&#x2013;242. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200001000-00035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200001000-00035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli RN, Otto RM. Strength training. Single versus multiple sets. Sports Med (Auckland, NZ). 1998;26(2):73&#x2013;84. doi: 10.2165/00007256-199826020-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199826020-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9777681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Androulakis-Korakakis P, Fisher JP, Steele J. The minimum effective training dose required to increase 1RM strength in resistance-trained men: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sport Med (Auckland, NZ) 2020;50(4):751&#x2013;765. doi: 10.1007/s40279-019-01236-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01236-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31797219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronnestad BR, Egeland W, Kvamme NH, Refsnes PE, Kadi F, Raastad T. Dissimilar effects of one- and three-set strength training on strength and muscle mass gains in upper and lower body in untrained subjects. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(1):157&#x2013;163. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200702000-00028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200702000-00028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17313291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Dutheil F, Jaekel P, Buchan DS, et al. Re-examination of 1- vs. 3-sets of resistance exercise for pre-spaceflight muscle conditioning: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2019;10:864. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2019.00864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6668575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31396092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(4):1150&#x2013;1159. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d4d436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d4d436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise: a meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(6):1890&#x2013;1901. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b370be.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b370be</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;1082. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2016.1210197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1210197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Scala Teixeira CV, Motoyama Y, de Azevedo P, Evangelista AL, Steele J, Bocalini DS. Effect of resistance training set volume on upper body muscle hypertrophy: are more sets really better than less? Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2018;38(5):727&#x2013;732. doi: 10.1111/cpf.12476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29024332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;3523. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000002200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes CR, Aoki MS, Crisp AH, de Mattos RS, Lins MA, da Mota GR, et al. The effect of different resistance training load schemes on strength and body composition in trained men. J Hum Kinet. 2017;58:177&#x2013;186. doi: 10.1515/hukin-2017-0081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hukin-2017-0081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5548165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28828088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;2963. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Steele J. Heavier and lighter load resistance training to momentary failure produce similar increases in strength with differing degrees of discomfort. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(4):797&#x2013;803. doi: 10.1002/mus.25537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28006852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Libardi CA. Is resistance training to muscular failure necessary? Front Physiol. 2016;7:10. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2016.00010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2016.00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26858654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford OM, Jones DA. The role of learning and coordination in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1986;55(1):100&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1007/BF00422902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00422902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Calder AW, Sale DG, Webber CE. A comparison of strength and muscle mass increases during resistance training in young women. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1998;77(1&#x2013;2):170&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9459538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Gentil P, Moro T, Marcolin G, Bianco A. Resistance training with single vs. multi-joint exercises at equal total load volume: effects on body composition, cardiorespiratory fitness, and muscle strength. Front Physiol. 2017;8:1105. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2017.01105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.01105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5744434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29312007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fisher J, Steele J. A review of the acute effects and long-term adaptations of single- and multi-joint exercises during resistance training. Sports Med (Auckland, NZ) 2017;47(5):843&#x2013;855. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0627-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0627-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27677913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Contreras B. Do single-joint exercises enhance functional fitness? Strength Cond J. 2012;34(1):63&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0b013e31823e82d7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0b013e31823e82d7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Haun C, Itagaki T, Helms ER. Calculating set-volume for the limb muscles with the performance of multi-joint exercises: implications for resistance training prescription. Sports. 2019;7(7):177. doi: 10.3390/sports7070177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7070177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31336594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli R. A critical analysis of the strength and conditioning association`s opinion that free weights are superior to machines for increasing muscular strength and power. Med Sport Pract. 2017;18:21&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG. Roundtable discussion: machines versus free weights. Strength Cond J. 2000;22(6):18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr ZY, Collins CL, Dawn CR. Epidemiology of weight training-related injuries presenting to united states emergency departments, 1990 to 2007. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38(4):765&#x2013;771. doi: 10.1177/0363546509351560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546509351560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Fimland MS. Effects of body position and loading modality on muscle activity and strength in shoulder presses. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(7):1824&#x2013;1831. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e318276b873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318276b873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23096062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, van den Tillaar R, Fimland MS. A comparison of muscle activity and 1-RM strength of three chest-press exercises with different stability requirements. J Sports Sci. 2011;29(5):533&#x2013;538. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2010.543916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2010.543916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21225489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: training considerations. Sports Med. 2018;48(4):765&#x2013;785. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0862-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0862-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;karabot J, Cronin N, Strojnik V, Avela J. Bilateral deficit in maximal force production. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(11):2057&#x2013;2084. doi: 10.1007/s00421-016-3458-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3458-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27582260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa E, Moreira A, Cavalcanti B, Krinski K, Aoki M. Effect of unilateral and bilateral resistance exercise on maximal voluntary strength, total volume of load lifted, and perceptual and metabolic responses. Biol Sport. 2015;32(1):35&#x2013;40. doi: 10.5604/20831862.1126326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/20831862.1126326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4314602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25729148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCurdy KW, Langford GA, Doscher MW, Wiley LP, Mallard KG. The effects of short-term unilateral and bilateral lower-body resistance training on measures of strength and power. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(1):9&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1519/14173.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/14173.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Anderson KG. The role of instability with resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):716&#x2013;722. doi: 10.1519/r-18475.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/r-18475.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergquist R, Iversen VM, Mork PJ, Fimland MS. Muscle activity in upper-body single-joint resistance exercises with elastic resistance bands vs. free weights. J Hum Kinet. 2018;61:5&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1515/hukin-2017-0137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hukin-2017-0137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5873332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29599855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboodarda SJ, Page PA, Behm DG. Muscle activation comparisons between elastic and isoinertial resistance: A meta-analysis. Clin Biomech (Bristol, Avon) 2016;39:52&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2016.09.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2016.09.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27681867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen VM, Mork PJ, Vasseljen O, Bergquist R, Fimland MS. Multiple-joint exercises using elastic resistance bands vs. conventional resistance-training equipment: a cross-over study. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017 doi: 10.1080/17461391.2017.1337229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1337229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28628370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calatayud J, Borreani S, Colado JC, Martin F, Tella V, Andersen LL. Bench press and push-up at comparable levels of muscle activity results in similar strength gains. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(1):246&#x2013;253. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24983847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrup E, Jakobsen MD, Andersen CH, Bandholm T, Thorborg K, Zebis MK, et al. Evaluation of elastic bands for lower extremity resistance training in adults with and without musculo-skeletal pain. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:353&#x2013;359. doi: 10.1111/sms.12187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25138624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes JSS, Machado AF, Micheletti JK, de Almeida AC, Cavina AP, Pastre CM. Effects of training with elastic resistance versus conventional resistance on muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. SAGE Open Med. 2019;7:2050312119831116. doi: 10.1177/2050312119831116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312119831116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6383082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30815258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Garcia-Masso X, Pellicer M, Alakhdar Y, Benavent J, Cabeza-Ruiz R. A comparison of elastic tubing and isotonic resistance exercises. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31(11):810&#x2013;817. doi: 10.1055/s-0030-1262808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0030-1262808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20703977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubans DR, Sheaman C, Callister R. Exercise adherence and intervention effects of two school-based resistance training programs for adolescents. Prev Med. 2010;50(1&#x2013;2):56&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2009.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2009.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20006641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klika B, Jordan C. High-intensity circuit training using body weight: maximum results with minimal investment. ACSM's Health Fit J. 2013;17(3):8&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1249/FIT.0b013e31828cb1e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/FIT.0b013e31828cb1e8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micielska K, Gmiat A, Zychowska M, Kozlowska M, Walentukiewicz A, Lysak-Radomska A, et al. The beneficial effects of 15 units of high-intensity circuit training in women is modified by age, baseline insulin resistance and physical capacity. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2019;152:156&#x2013;165. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2019.05.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2019.05.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31102684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K, Deakin GB, Ness KF. Kinematic and electromyographic comparisons between chin-ups and lat-pull down exercises. Sports Biomech. 2013;12(3):302&#x2013;313. doi: 10.1080/14763141.2012.760204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2012.760204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24245055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotarsky CJ, Christensen BK, Miller JS, Hackney KJ. Effect of progressive calisthenic push-up training on muscle strength and thickness. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(3):651&#x2013;659. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29466268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oranchuk DJ, Storey AG, Nelson AR, Cronin JB. Isometric training and long-term adaptations; effects of muscle length, intensity and intent: a systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018 doi: 10.1111/sms.13375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30580468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Enoka RM. Neural control of lengthening contractions. J Exp Biol. 2016;219(Pt 2):197&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1242/jeb.123158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.123158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26792331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Vigotsky AD, Franchi MV, Krieger JW. Hypertrophic effects of concentric vs. eccentric muscle actions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(9):2599&#x2013;2608. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000001983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28486337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL, Winett RA, Anderson ES, Wojcik JR, Loud RL, Cleggett E, et al. Effects of regular and slow speed resistance training on muscle strength. J Sport Med Phys Fit. 2001;41(2):154&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11447355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Krieger JW. Effect of repetition duration during resistance training on muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med (Auckland, NZ) 2015;45(4):577&#x2013;585. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0304-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0304-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Davies TB, Orr R, Kuang K, Halaki M. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on muscle-specific hypertrophy: a systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(4):473&#x2013;482. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2018.1434563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1434563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29431597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on dynamic muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med (Auckland, NZ) 2017;47(8):1603&#x2013;1617. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0676-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0676-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Sanchez-Medina L, Gorostiaga EM, Pareja-Blanco F. Maximal intended velocity training induces greater gains in bench press performance than deliberately slower half-velocity training. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;14(8):772&#x2013;781. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2014.905987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2014.905987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24734902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padulo J, Mignogna P, Mignardi S, Tonni F, D'Ottavio S. Effect of different pushing speeds on bench press. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33(5):376&#x2013;380. doi: 10.1055/s-0031-1299702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0031-1299702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48(1):137&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0788-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0788-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza TP, Jr., Fleck SJ, Sim&#xe3;o R, Dubas JP, Pereira B, de Brito Pacheco EM, , et al. Comparison between constant and decreasing rest intervals: influence on maximal strength and hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(7):1843&#x2013;1850. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ddae4a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ddae4a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza-Junior TP, Willardson JM, Bloomer R, Leite RD, Fleck SJ, Oliveira PR, et al. Strength and hypertrophy responses to constant and decreasing rest intervals in trained men using creatine supplementation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2011;8(1):17. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-8-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-8-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3215636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22032491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Triplett NT. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. 4. NSCA -National Strength &amp; Conditioning Association; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins DW, Young WB, Behm DG, Payne WR. Agonist-antagonist paired set resistance training: a brief review. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(10):2873&#x2013;2882. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181f00bfc.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181f00bfc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20733520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins DW, Young WB, Behm DG, Payne WR. Effects of agonist-antagonist complex resistance training on upper body strength and power development. J Sports Sci. 2009;27(14):1617&#x2013;1625. doi: 10.1080/02640410903365677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410903365677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19967584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antunes L, Bezerra EDS, Sakugawa RL, Dal Pupo J. Effect of cadence on volume and myoelectric activity during agonist-antagonist paired sets (supersets) in the lower body. Sports Biomech. 2018;17(4):502. doi: 10.1080/14763141.2017.1413130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2017.1413130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29370715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maia MF, Willardson JM, Paz GA, Miranda H. Effects of different rest intervals between antagonist paired sets on repetition performance and muscle activation. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(9):2529&#x2013;2535. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000000451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000000451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25148302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz GA, Robbins DW, de Oliveira CG, Bottaro M, Miranda H. Volume load and neuromuscular fatigue during an acute bout of agonist-antagonist paired-set vs. traditional-set training. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(10):2777&#x2013;2784. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000001059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Freitas MM, Paz GA, Miranda H, Lima V, Bentes CM, da Silva NJ, et al. Maximal repetition performance, rating of perceived exertion, and muscle fatigue during paired set training performed with different rest intervals. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2015;13(2):104&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1016/j.jesf.2015.08.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2015.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29541107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda H, Scudese E, Paz GA, Salerno VP, Vigario PDS, de Souza J, et al. Acute hormone responses subsequent to agonist-antagonist paired set vs. traditional straight set resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;34(6):1591&#x2013;1599. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000002633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29979283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley JJ, Till K, Read DB, Phibbs PJ, Roe G, Darrall-Jones J, et al. The effects of superset configuration on kinetic, kinematic, and perceived exertion in the barbell bench press. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;34(1):65&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000002179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000002179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28796130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weakley JJS, Till K, Read DB, Roe GAB, Darrall-Jones J, Phibbs PJ, et al. The effects of traditional, superset, and tri-set resistance training structures on perceived intensity and physiological responses. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(9):1877&#x2013;1889. doi: 10.1007/s00421-017-3680-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3680-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5556132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Can drop set training enhance muscle growth? Strength Cond J. 2018;40(6):95&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1519/ssc.0000000000000366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/ssc.0000000000000366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink J, Schoenfeld BJ, Kikuchi N, Nakazato K. Effects of drop set resistance training on acute stress indicators and long-term muscle hypertrophy and strength. J Sport Med Phys Fit. 2018;58(5):597&#x2013;605. doi: 10.23736/s0022-4707.17.06838-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/s0022-4707.17.06838-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28474868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Kubota A, Natsume T, Loenneke JP, Abe T, Machida S, et al. Effects of drop sets with resistance training on increases in muscle CSA, strength, and endurance: a pilot study. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(6):691&#x2013;696. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2017.1331042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2017.1331042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28532248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angleri V, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA. Crescent pyramid and drop-set systems do not promote greater strength gains, muscle hypertrophy, and changes on muscle architecture compared with traditional resistance training in well-trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(2):359&#x2013;369. doi: 10.1007/s00421-016-3529-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-016-3529-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Brown LE, Haff GG. Theoretical and practical aspects of different cluster set structures: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(3):848&#x2013;867. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000001581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PW, Robbins DA, Wrightson AW, Siegler JC. Acute neuromuscular and fatigue responses to the rest-pause method. J Sci Med Sport/Sports Med Aust. 2012;15(2):153&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2011.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2011.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21940213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, Tibana RA, de Araujo SE, da Cunha ND, de Oliveira RP, Camarco NF, et al. Strength and muscular adaptations following 6 weeks of rest-pause versus traditional multiple-sets resistance training in trained subjects. J Strength Cond Res. 2017 doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000001923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000001923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28617715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Alen M, Kallinen M, Newton RU, Kraemer WJ. Neuromuscular adaptation during prolonged strength training, detraining and re-strength-training in middle-aged and elderly people. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2000;83(1):51&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1007/s004210000248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210000248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Yasuda T, Ishii N, Abe T. Comparison of muscle hypertrophy following 6-month of continuous and periodic strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(4):975&#x2013;985. doi: 10.1007/s00421-012-2511-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-012-2511-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves JE, Pollock ML, Leggett SH, Braith RW, Carpenter DM, Bishop LE. Effect of reduced training frequency on muscular strength. Int J Sports Med. 1988;9(5):316&#x2013;319. doi: 10.1055/s-2007-1025031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-1025031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3246465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel CS, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Exercise dosing to retain resistance training adaptations in young and older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1177&#x2013;1187. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318207c15d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318207c15d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronnestad BR, Nymark BS, Raastad T. Effects of in-season strength maintenance training frequency in professional soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(10):2653&#x2013;2660. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31822dcd96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31822dcd96</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21873897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares LD, de Souza EO, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino GC, Roschel H, Aihara AY, et al. Effects of different strength training frequencies during reduced training period on strength and muscle cross-sectional area. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(6):665&#x2013;672. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2017.1298673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1298673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28316261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes MJ, Petterson A, Cochrane DJ. Effects of different warm-up modalities on power output during the high pull. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(10):976&#x2013;981. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2016.1206665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1206665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27398685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Romanzini M, Schoenfeld BJ, Souza MF, Avelar A, Cyrino ES. Effect of different warm-up procedures on the performance of resistance training exercises. Percept Mot Skills. 2014;119(1):133&#x2013;145. doi: 10.2466/25.29.PMS.119c17z7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2466/25.29.PMS.119c17z7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25153744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart D, Macaluso A, De Vito G. The effect of an active warm-up on surface EMG and muscle performance in healthy humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2003;89(6):509&#x2013;513. doi: 10.1007/s00421-003-0798-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-003-0798-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14551779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abad CC, Prado ML, Ugrinowitsch C, Tricoli V, Barroso R. Combination of general and specific warm-ups improves leg-press one repetition maximum compared with specific warm-up in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(8):2242&#x2013;2245. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e8611b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e8611b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21544000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrary JM, Ackermann BJ, Halaki M. A systematic review of the effects of upper body warm-up on performance and injury. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(14):935&#x2013;942. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2014-094228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-094228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25694615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP, Cosgrave CH. To stretch or not to stretch: the role of stretching in injury prevention and performance. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(2):169&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.01058.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2009.01058.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20030776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester JB, Nelson AG, Kokkonen J. A single 30-s stretch is sufficient to inhibit maximal voluntary strength. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2009;80(2):257&#x2013;261. doi: 10.1080/02701367.2009.10599560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2009.10599560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19650391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balle SS, Magnusson SP, McHugh MP. Effects of contract-relax vs static stretching on stretch-induced strength loss and length-tension relationship. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(6):764&#x2013;769. doi: 10.1111/sms.12399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25622920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa GM, Trajano GS, Dantas GAF, Silva BR, Vieira WHB. Chronic effects of static and dynamic stretching on hamstrings eccentric strength and functional performance: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;34(7):2031&#x2013;2039. doi: 10.1519/jsc.0000000000003080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/jsc.0000000000003080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30789583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H, Behm DG, Negra Y, Granacher U. Acute effects of static stretching on muscle strength and power: an attempt to clarify previous caveats. Front Physiol. 2019 doi: 10.3389/fphys.2019.01468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.01468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6895680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert RD, de Noronha M, Kamper SJ. Stretching to prevent or reduce muscle soreness after exercise. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;7:Cd004577. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD004577.pub3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD004577.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21735398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Peake JM. Do we need a cool-down after exercise? A narrative review of the psychophysiological effects and the effects on performance, injuries and the long-term adaptive response. Sports Med (Auckland, NZ) 2018;48(7):1575&#x2013;1595. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0916-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0916-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5999142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29663142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton SK, Whitehead JR, Brinkert RH, Caine DJ. Resistance training vs. static stretching: effects on flexibility and strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(12):3391&#x2013;3398. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31821624aa.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31821624aa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21969080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Fontes-Villalba M, Santos-Concejero J. Total number of sets as a training volume quantification method for muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2018 doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Cronin J, Storey A, Zourdos MC. Application of the repetitions in reserve-based rating of perceived exertion scale for resistance training. Strength Cond J. 2016;38(4):42&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4961270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27531969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>