<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37556026</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiology of Stretch-Mediated Hypertrophy and Strength Increases: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2055</StartPage><EndPage>2075</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2055-2075</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-023-01898-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Increasing muscle strength and cross-sectional area is of crucial importance to improve or maintain physical function in musculoskeletal rehabilitation and sports performance. Decreases in muscular performance are experienced in phases of reduced physical activity or immobilization. These decrements highlight the need for alternative, easily accessible training regimens for a sedentary population to improve rehabilitation and injury prevention routines. Commonly, muscle hypertrophy and strength increases are associated with resistance training, typically performed in a training facility. Mechanical tension, which is usually induced with resistance machines and devices, is known to be an important factor that stimulates the underlying signaling pathways to enhance protein synthesis. Findings from animal studies suggest an alternative means to induce mechanical tension to enhance protein synthesis, and therefore muscle hypertrophy by inducing high-volume stretching. Thus, this narrative review discusses mechanical tension-induced physiological adaptations and their impact on muscle hypertrophy and strength gains. Furthermore, research addressing stretch-induced hypertrophy is critically analyzed. Derived from animal research, the stretching literature exploring the impact of static stretching on morphological and functional adaptations was reviewed and critically discussed. No studies have investigated the underlying physiological mechanisms in humans yet, and thus the underlying mechanisms remain speculative and must be discussed in the light of animal research. However, studies that reported functional and morphological increases in humans commonly used stretching durations of&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;30&#xa0;min per session of the plantar flexors, indicating the importance of high stretching volume, if the aim is to increase muscle mass and maximum strength. Therefore, the practical applicability seems limited to settings without access to resistance training (e.g., in an immobilized state at the start of rehabilitation), as resistance training seems to be more time efficient. Nevertheless, further research is needed to generate evidence in different human populations (athletes, sedentary individuals, and rehabilitation patients) and to quantify stretching intensity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warneke</LastName><ForeName>Konstantin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4964-2867</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Exercise, Sport and Health, Leuphana University, Universit&#xe4;tsallee 1, 21335, L&#xfc;neburg, Deutschland, Germany. Konstantin.Warneke@aau.at.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Kinetics and Recreation, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, NL, Canada. Konstantin.Warneke@aau.at.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Science, Alpen-Adria University Klagenfurt, Klagenfurt, Germany. Konstantin.Warneke@aau.at.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lohmann</LastName><ForeName>Lars H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Sports Center, Carl von Ossietzky University Oldenburg, Oldenburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lima</LastName><ForeName>Camila D</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hollander</LastName><ForeName>Karsten</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Interdisciplinary Exercise Science and Sports Medicine, MSH Medical School Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Konrad</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Human Movement Science, Sport and Health, University of Graz, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Kinetics and Recreation, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, NL, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zech</LastName><ForeName>Astrid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Motion Science and Exercise Physiology, Friedrich Schiller University, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Masatoshi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, Nishi Kyushu University, Ozaki, Kanzaki, Saga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wirth</LastName><ForeName>Klaus</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Science, University of Applied Sciences Wiener Neustadt, Wiener Neustadt, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keiner</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science, German University of Health and Sport, Ismaning, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behm</LastName><ForeName>David G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Kinetics and Recreation, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, NL, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Stretching Exercises</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Konstantin Warneke, Lars H. Lohmann, Camila D. Lima, Karsten Hollander, Andreas Konrad, Astrid Zech, Masatoshi Nakamura, Klaus Wirth, Michael Keiner, and David G. Behm have no conflicts of interest that are directly related to the content of this article. There were no financial interests of any authors contributing to the paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37556026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01898-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-023-01898-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Husby VS, Foss OA, Husby OS, Winther SB. Randomized controlled trial of maximal strength training vs standard rehabilitation following total knee arthroplasty. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;54:371&#x2013;379. doi: 10.23736/S1973-9087.17.04712-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.17.04712-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28901118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestroni L, Read P, Bishop C, Turner A. Strength and power training in rehabilitation: underpinning principles and practical strategies to return athletes to high performance. Sports Med. 2020;50:239&#x2013;252. doi: 10.1007/s40279-019-01195-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01195-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31559567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stotz A, Maghames E, Mason J, Groll A, Zech A. Maximum isometric torque at individually-adjusted joint angles exceeds eccentric and concentric torque in lower extremity joint actions. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2022;14:13. doi: 10.1186/s13102-022-00401-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-022-00401-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8783437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35063013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: training considerations. Sports Med. 2018;48:765&#x2013;785. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0862-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0862-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams TD, Tolusso DV, Fedewa MV, Esco MR. Comparison of periodized and non-periodized resistance training on maximal strength: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47:2083&#x2013;2100. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0734-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0734-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28497285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisl&#xf8;ff U, Castagna C, Helgerud J, Jones R, Hoff J. Strong correlation of maximal squat strength with sprint performance and vertical jump height in elite soccer players. Br J Sports Med. 2004;38:285&#x2013;288. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2002.002071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2002.002071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:2954&#x2013;2963. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, Hester GM, Sellers J, Nooner JL, et al. Longer interset rest periods enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:1805&#x2013;1812. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. The dose-response relationship between resistance training volume and muscle hypertrophy: are there really still any doubts? J Sports Sci. 2017;35:1985&#x2013;1987. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2016.1243800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1243800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27805470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Hartmann H, Sander A, Mickel C, Szilvas E, Keiner M. The impact of back squat and leg-press exercises on maximal strength and speed-strength parameters. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:1205&#x2013;1212. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26439782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Atzor KR, Schmidtbleicher D. Ver&#xe4;nderungen der muskelmasse in abh&#xe4;ngigkeit von trainingsh&#xe4;ufigkeit und leistungsniveau. Dtsch Z Sportmed. 2007;58:178&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldspink G, Harridge S. Cellular and molecular aspects of adaptation in skeletal muscle. In: Komi PV, editor. Strength and power in sport. Oxford: Blackwell; 2nd edn. 2003: p. 231&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med. 2007;37:225&#x2013;264. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200737030-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737030-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17326698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG. Neuromuscular implications and applications of resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 1995;9:264&#x2013;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-Load resistance training: a systematic review and meta analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:3508&#x2013;3523. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, Vechin FC, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, Damas F, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:361&#x2013;378. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0795-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0795-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29043659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer WJ. Designing resistance training programs. 3. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson SJ, Christensen B, Gange K, Todden C, Hatterman-Valenti H, Albrecht JM. Chronic stretching during 2 weeks of immobilization decreases loss of girth, peak torque, and dorsiflexion range of motion. J Sport Rehabil. 2019;28:67&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1123/jsr.2017-0101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2017-0101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28952869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens JE, Walter GA, Okereke E, Scarborough MT, Esterhai JL, George SZ, et al. Muscle adaptations with immobilization and rehabilitation after ankle fracture. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:1695&#x2013;1701. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000142407.25188.05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000142407.25188.05</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15595289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch C, Greig C, Masud T, Wilson D, Jackson TA. COVID-19 and acute sarcopenia. Aging Dis. 2020;11:1345&#x2013;1351. doi: 10.14336/AD.2020.1014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14336/AD.2020.1014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33269092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayech A, Mejri MA, Makhlouf I, Mathlouthi A, Behm DG, Chaouachi A. Second wave of covid-19 global pandemic and athletes&#x2019; confinement: recommendations to better manage and optimize the modified lifestyle. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17228385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17228385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7696701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33198389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabene H, Prieske O, Herz M, Moran J, H&#xf6;hne J, Kliegl R, et al. Home-based exercise programmes improve physical fitness of healthy older adults: a PRISMA-compliant systematic review and meta-analysis with relevance for COVID-19. Ageing Res Rev. 2021;67:101265. doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2021.101265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2021.101265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira NL, Elsangedy HM, Tavares VDDO, Teixeira CVLS, Behm DG, Da Silva-Grigoletto ME. TrainingInHome: home-based training during COVID-19 (SARS-COV2) pandemic: physical exercise and behavior-based approach. Rev Bras Fisiol. 2020;19:9. doi: 10.33233/rbfe.v19i2.4006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33233/rbfe.v19i2.4006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short KR, Nair KS. Muscle protein metabolism and the sarcopenia of ageing. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2001;11:119&#x2013;127. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.11.s1.s119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.11.s1.s119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11915910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikberg S, S&#xf6;rl&#xe9;n N, Brand&#xe9;n L, Johansson J, Nordstr&#xf6;m A, Hult A, et al. Effects of resistance training on functional strength and muscle mass in 70-year-old individuals with pre-sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2019;20:28&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/j.jamda.2018.09.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2018.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhim HC, Tenforde A, Mohr L, Hollander K, Vogt L, Groneberg DA, et al. Association between physical activity and musculoskeletal pain: an analysis of international data from the ASAP survey. BMJ Open. 2022;12:e059525. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-059525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-059525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9486184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36123076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morie M, Reid KF, Miciek R, Lajevardi N, Choong K, Krasnoff JB, et al. Habitual physical activity levels are associated with performance in measures of physical function and mobility in older men. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010;58:1727&#x2013;1733. doi: 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03012.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03012.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2945416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20738436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotta K, Behnke BJ, Arjmandi B, Ghosh P, Chen B, Brooks R, et al. Daily muscle stretching enhances blood flow, endothelial function, capillarity, vascular volume and connectivity in aged skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2018;596:1903&#x2013;1917. doi: 10.1113/JP275459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP275459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5978284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29623692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros DM, Martini TF. Chronic effect of different types of stretching on ankle dorsiflexion range of motion: systematic review and meta-analysis. Foot (Edinburgh) 2018;34:28&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1016/j.foot.2017.09.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foot.2017.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29223884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford JA, Burns J, Buchbinder R, Landorf KB, Cook C. Does stretching increase ankle dorsiflexion range of motion? A systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40:870&#x2013;875. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2006.029348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2006.029348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young R, Nix S, Wholohan A, Bradhurst R, Reed L. Interventions for increasing ankle joint dorsiflexion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Foot Ankle Res. 2013;6:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1186/1757-1146-6-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1757-1146-6-46</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4176290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24225348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cayco CS, Labro AV, Gorgon E. Hold-relax and contract-relax stretching for hamstrings flexibility: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;35:3542&#x2013;3555. doi: 10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30423500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros DM, Cini A, Sbruzzi G, Lima CS. Influence of static stretching on hamstring flexibility in healthy young adults: systematic review and meta analysis. Physio Ther Theory Pract. 2016;32:438&#x2013;445. doi: 10.1080/09593985.2016.1204401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09593985.2016.1204401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27458757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Radaelli R, Taaffe DR, Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Trajano GS, et al. Resistance training load effects on muscle hypertrophy and strength gain: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:1206&#x2013;1216. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8126497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refalo MC, Hamilton DL, Paval DR, Gallagher IJ, Feros SA, Fyfe J. Influence of resistance training load on measures of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and improvements in maximal strength and neuromuscular task performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2021;39:1723&#x2013;1745. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2021.1898094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2021.1898094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh S, Daneshjoo A, Zahiri A, Anvar SH, Goudini R, Hicks JP, et al. Resistance training induces improvements in range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53:707&#x2013;722. doi: 10.1007/s40279-022-01804-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01804-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36622555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Ramirez-Campillo R, Mosc&#xe3;o J, Rocha T, Zacca R, Martins A, et al. Strength training versus stretching for improving range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Healthcare. 2021;9:427. doi: 10.3390/healthcare9040427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare9040427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahata K, Konrad A, Sato S, Kiyono R, Yoshida R, Fukaya T, et al. Effects of a high-volume static stretching programme on plantar-flexor muscle strength and architecture. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:1159&#x2013;1166. doi: 10.1007/s00421-021-04608-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04608-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Keiner M, Wagner C, Schmidt T, Wirth K, et al. Using long-duration static stretch training to counteract strength and flexibility deficits in moderately trained participants. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:13254. doi: 10.3390/ijerph192013254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192013254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9603712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36293831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Keiner M, Hillebrecht M, Schiemann S. Influence of one hour versus two hours of daily static stretching for six weeks using a calf-muscle-stretching orthosis on maximal strength. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(18):11621. doi: 10.3390/ijerph191811621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191811621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36141890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panidi I, Bogdanis GC, Terzis G, Donti A, Konrad A, Gaspari V, et al. Muscle architectural and functional adaptations following 12-weeks of stretching in adolescent female athletes. Front Physiol. 2021;12:701338. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.701338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.701338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8322691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34335307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Hiraizumi K, Kiyono R, Fukaya T, Nishishita S, Nunes JP, et al. The effects of static stretching programs on muscle strength and muscle architecture of the medial gastrocnemius. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:e0235679. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0235679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0235679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7347101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Yoshida R, Sato S, Yahata K, Murakami Y, Kasahara K, et al. Comparison between high- and low-intensity static stretching training program on active and passive properties of plantar flexors. Front Physiol. 2021;12:796497. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.796497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.796497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34975544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson CL, Kim BDH, Bourcet MR, Jones GR, Jakobi JM. Stretch training induces unequal adaptation in muscle fascicles and thickness in medial and lateral gastrocnemii. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27:1597&#x2013;1604. doi: 10.1111/sms.12822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28138986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Nakamura M, Ribeiro AS, Cunha PM, Cyrino ES. Does stretch training induce muscle hypertrophy in humans? A review of the literature. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2020;40:148&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1111/cpf.12622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31984621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2019;126:30&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00685.2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00685.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30335577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Woods NM. Exercise-induced signal transduction and gene regulation in skeletal muscle. J Sports Sci Med. 2002;1:103&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3979001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24748841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley G. Mechanical overload and skeletal muscle fiber hyperplasia: a meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol. 1985;1996(81):1584&#x2013;1588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8904572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Freund PA, Schiemann S. Long-lasting stretching induces muscle hypertrophy: a meta-analysis of animal studies. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2022. 10.1007/s42978-022-00191-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Gonyea WJ. Progressive stretch overload of skeletal muscle results in hypertrophy before hyperplasia. J Appl Physiol. 1993;75:1263&#x2013;1271. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1993.75.3.1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.75.3.1263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toigo M, Boutellier U. New fundamental resistance exercise determinants of molecular and cellular muscle adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;97:643&#x2013;663. doi: 10.1007/s00421-006-0238-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-006-0238-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fl&#xfc;ck M, Hoppeler H. Molecular basis of skeletal muscle plasticity-from gene to form and function. Rev Physiol Biochem Pharmacol. 2003;146:159&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1007/s10254-002-0004-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10254-002-0004-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12605307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fl&#xfc;ck M. Functional, structural and molecular plasticity of mammalian skeletal muscle in response to exercise stimuli. J Exp Biol. 2006;209:2239&#x2013;2248. doi: 10.1242/jeb.02149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.02149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16731801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:2857&#x2013;2872. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e840f3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e840f3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Does exercise-induced muscle damage play a role in skeletal muscle hypertrophy? J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:1441&#x2013;1453. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31824f207e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31824f207e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22344059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowles JR, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA, Sale DG, Roy BD, Yarascheski KE. The effects of acute passiv stretch on muscle protein synthesis in humans. Can J Appl Physiol. 2000;25:165&#x2013;180. doi: 10.1139/h00-012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h00-012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10932034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch GS, Schertzer JD, Ryall JG. Therapeutic approaches for muscle wasting disorders. Pharmacol Ther. 2007;113:261&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1016/j.pharmthera.2006.11.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2006.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17258813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch GS, Schertzer JD, Ryall JG. Anabolic agents for improving muscle regeneration and function after injury. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2008;35:852&#x2013;858. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1681.2008.04955.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1681.2008.04955.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18498534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saini A, Faulkner S, AlShanti N, Stewart C. Powerful signals for weak muscles. Ageing Res Rev. 2009;8:251&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19716529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Hawley JA. The molecular bases of training adaptation. Sports Med. 2007;37:737&#x2013;763. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200737090-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737090-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17722947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldspink G. Changes in muscle mass and phenotype and the expression of autocrine and systemic growth factors by muscle in response to stretch and overload. J Anat. 1999;194:323&#x2013;334. doi: 10.1046/j.1469-7580.1999.19430323.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1469-7580.1999.19430323.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1467932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10386770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Proud CG. Methods for studying signal-dependent regulation of translation factor activity. Methods Enzymol. 2007;431:113&#x2013;142. doi: 10.1016/S0076-6879(07)31007-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0076-6879(07)31007-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17923233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs CA, Sciascia AD. Factors that influence the efficacy of stretching programs for patients with hypomobility. Sports Health. 2011;3:520&#x2013;523. doi: 10.1177/1941738111415233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738111415233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23016052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoki MS, Miyabara EH, Soares AG, Saito ET, Moriscot AS. mTOR pathway inhibition attenuates skeletal muscle growth induced by stretching. Cell Tissue Res. 2006;324:149&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1007/s00441-005-0081-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00441-005-0081-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16408196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC, Stitt TN, Gonzalez M, Kline WO, Stover GL, Bauerlein R, et al. Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy in vivo. Nat Cell Biol. 2001;3:1014&#x2013;1019. doi: 10.1038/ncb1101-1014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncb1101-1014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Ikeda S, Ikoma K. Efficacy of passive repetitive stretching of skeletal muscle on myofiber hypertrophy and genetic suppression on MAFbx, MuRF1, and myostatin. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 2021;42:443&#x2013;451. doi: 10.1007/s10974-021-09609-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10974-021-09609-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34664159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uemichi K, Shirai T, Hanakita H, Takemasa T. Effect of mechanistic/mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 on mitochondrial dynamics during skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Physiol Rep. 2021;9:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.14814/phy2.14789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.14789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7931617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33660929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spangenburg EE, McBride TA. Inhibition of stretch-activated channels during eccentric muscle contraction attenuates p70S6K activation. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:129&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00619.2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00619.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16179399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasai N, Agata N, Inoue-Miyazu M, Kawakami K, Kobayashi K, Sokabe M, et al. Involvement of PI3K/Akt/TOR pathway in stretch-induced hypertrophy of myotubes. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:100&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1002/mus.21473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.21473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19768770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidall JG. Mechanical signal transduction in skeletal muscle growth and adaptation. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98:1900&#x2013;1908. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01178.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01178.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15829723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann U, Platen P, Niessen M, Mank D, Marzin T, Bartmus U, et al. Krafttraining im Nachwuchsleistungssport unter besonderer Ber&#xfc;cksichtigung von Ontogenese, biologischen Mechanismen und Terminologie. BISp; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer B. Dehnungsinterventionen im Spannungsfeld historischer Entwicklung, ritualisierter Anwendung, Meisterlehre und Wissenschaft; Eine Bestandsanalyse. Karlsruher Sportwissenschaftliche Beitr&#xe4;ge. 2017; p. 188&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marey E. Recherces experimentales sur la morphologie des muscles. C R Acad Sci. 1887;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabary JC, Tabary C, Tardieu C, Tardieu G, Goldspink G. Physiological and structural changes in the cat&#x2019;s soleus muscle due to immobilization at different length by plaster casts. J Physiol. 1972;244:231&#x2013;244. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.1972.sp009891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1972.sp009891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1331536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5039983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alder AB, Crawford GN, Edwards RG. The effect of limitation of movement on longitudinal growth. Proc R Soc Biol. 1958;B150:554&#x2013;562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13848767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams PE, Catanese T, Lucey EG, Goldspink G. The importance of stretch and contractile activity in the prevention of connective tissue accumulation in muscle. J Anat. 1988;158:109&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1261981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3225214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sola M, Christensen DL, Martin AW. Hypertrophy and hyperplasia of adult chicken anterior latissimus dorsi muscles following stretch with and without denervation. Exp Neurol. 1973;41:76&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1016/0014-4886(73)90182-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0014-4886(73)90182-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4270324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC. The role of resistance exercise intensity on muscle fibre adaptations. Sports Med. 2004;34(10):663&#x2013;679. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200434100-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200434100-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15335243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett JG, Holly RG, Ashmore CR. Stretch-induced growth in chicken wing muscles: biochemical and morphological characterization. Am J Physiol. 1980;239:C39&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.1980.239.1.C39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1980.239.1.C39</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6156603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holly RG, Barnett JG, Ashmore CR, Taylor RG, Molti PA. Stretch-induced growth in chicken wing muscles: a new model of stretch hypertrophy. Am J Physiol. 1980;238:C62&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.1980.238.1.C62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1980.238.1.C62</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7356012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooijmans CR, IntHout J, Ritskes-Hoitinga M, Rovers MM. Meta-analyses of animal studies: an introduction of a valuable instrument to further improve healthcare. ILAR J. 2014;55:418&#x2013;426. doi: 10.1093/ilar/ilu042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ilar/ilu042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4276598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25541544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Gonyea WJ. Role of muscle fiber hypertrophy and hyperplasia in intermittently stretched avian muscle. J Appl Physiol. 1993;259:1893&#x2013;1898. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1993.74.4.1893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.74.4.1893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8514707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy JM, Zak R, Gao L. Myosin expression in hypertrophied fast twitch and slow tonic muscles of normal and dystrophic chickens. Muscle Nerve. 1991;14:166&#x2013;177. doi: 10.1002/mus.880140212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.880140212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1825696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson JA, Alway SE. Stretch overload-induced satellite cell activation in slow tonic muscle from adult and aged Japanese quail. Am J Physiol. 1996;270:C578&#x2013;C584. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.1996.270.2.C578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1996.270.2.C578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8779922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester PK, Davis ME, Alway SE, Gonyea WJ. Satellite cell activation in the stretch-enlarged anterior latissimus dorsi muscle of the adult quail. Am J Cell Physiol. 1991;260:C206&#x2013;C212. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.1991.260.2.C206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1991.260.2.C206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1996607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates GP. The relationship between duration of stimulus per day and the extend of hypertrophy of slow-tonic skeletal muscle in the fowl, Gallus gallus. Comp Biochem Physiol. 1993;106A:755&#x2013;758. doi: 10.1016/0300-9629(93)90393-I.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0300-9629(93)90393-I</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7906634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Gonyea WJ, Progressive WJG. Progressive stretch overload of skeletal muscle results in hypertrophy before hyperplasia. J Appl Physiol. 1993;75:1263&#x2013;1271. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1993.75.3.1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.75.3.1263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE. Stretch induces non-uniform isomyosin expression in the quail anterior latissimus dorsi muscle. Anat Rec. 1993;237:7. doi: 10.1002/ar.1092370102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.1092370102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8214635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Winchester PK, Davis ME, Gonyea WJ. Regionalized adaptations and muscle fiber proliferation in stretch-induced enlargement. J Appl Physiol. 1989;66:771&#x2013;781. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1989.66.2.771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1989.66.2.771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2523374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankeny JR, Holly GR, Ashmore CR. Effects of graded duration of stretch on normal and dystrophic skeletal muscle. Muscle Nerve. 1983;6:269&#x2013;277. doi: 10.1002/mus.880060405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.880060405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6866007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE. Force and contractile characteristics after stretch overload in quail anterior latissimus dorsi muscle. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77:135&#x2013;141. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1994.77.1.135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1994.77.1.135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7961225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE. Contractile properties of aged avian muscle after stretch-overload. Mech Ageing Dev. 1994;73:97&#x2013;112. doi: 10.1016/0047-6374(94)90059-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0047-6374(94)90059-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8051957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson JA, Alway SE, Yamaguchi M. Time course of hypertrophic adaptations of the anterior latissimus dorsi muscle to stretch overload in aged Japanese quail. J Gerontol. 1995;50:B391&#x2013;B398. doi: 10.1093/gerona/50A.6.B391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/50A.6.B391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7583796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson JA, Yamaguchi M, Alway SE, Alway Hypertrophy SE. Hypertrophy and proliferation of skeletal muscle fibers from aged quail. J Appl Physiol. 1985;1995(78):293&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7713826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Alway SE. Adaptations of myonuclei to hypertrophy muscle fibers from aged quail. Mech Ageing Dev. 1996;88:185&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/0047-6374(96)01736-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0047-6374(96)01736-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8819101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews W, Jenkins RR, Gonyea WJ. Myosin isozyme expression in response to stretch-induced hypertrophy in the Japanese quail. Anat Rec. 1990;228:255&#x2013;261. doi: 10.1002/ar.1092280304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.1092280304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2260780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roman WJ, Alway SE. Stretch-induced transformations in myosin expression of quail anterior latissimus dorsi muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27:1494&#x2013;1499. doi: 10.1249/00005768-199511000-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-199511000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8587485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Summers PJ, Ashmore CR, Bang YU, Ellis S. Stretch-induced growth in chicken wing muscles: role of soluble growth-promoting factors. J Cell Physiol. 1985;125:288&#x2013;294. doi: 10.1002/jcp.1041250217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.1041250217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4055912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Gonyea WJ, Davis ME. Muscle fiber formation and fiber hypertrophy during the onset of stretch overload. Am J Physiol. 1990;259:C92&#x2013;102. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.1990.259.1.C92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1990.259.1.C92</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2142581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jaeger D, Joumaa V, Herzog W. Intermittent stretch training of rabbit plantarflexor muscles increases soleus mass and serial sarcomere number. J Appl Physiol. 2015;118:1467&#x2013;1473. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00515.2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00515.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26078433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutinho EL, Gomes ARS, Fran&#xe7;a CN, Oishi J, Salvini TF. Effect of passive stretching on the immobilized soleus muscle fiber morphology. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2004;37:1473&#x2013;1480. doi: 10.1590/S0100-879X2004001200011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0100-879X2004001200011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15558192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes ARS, Coutinho EL, Franca CN, Polonio J, Salvini TF. Effect of one stretch a week applied to the immobilized soleus muscle on rat muscle fiber morphology. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2004;37:1473&#x2013;1480. doi: 10.1590/S0100-879X2004001000005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0100-879X2004001000005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutinho EL, DeLuca C, Salvini TF, Vidal BC. Bouts of passive stretching after immobilization of the rat soleus muscle increase collagen macromolecular organization and muscle fiber area. Connect Tissue Res. 2006;47:278&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1080/03008200600995940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03008200600995940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17118750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayegh JF, Lajtha A. In vivo rates of protein synthesis in brain, muscle, and liver of five vertebrate species. Neurochem Res. 1989;11:1165&#x2013;1168. doi: 10.1007/BF00965625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00965625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2594146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garibotto G, Tessari P, Robaudo C, Zanetti M, Saffioti S, Vettore M, et al. Protein turnover in the kidney and the whole body in humans. Miner Electrolyte Metab. 1997;23:185&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9387113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas SR, Mil-Homens P. Effect of 8-week high-intensity stretching training on biceps femoris architecture. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:1737&#x2013;1740. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25486299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moltubakk MM, Villars FO, Magulas MM, Magnusson SP, Seynnes OR, Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J. Altered triceps surae muscle-tendon unit properties after 6 months of static stretching. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:1975&#x2013;1986. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akagi R, Takahashi H. Effect of a 5-week static stretching program on hardness of the gastrocnemius muscle. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:950&#x2013;957. doi: 10.1111/sms.12111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23944602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Brinkmann A, Hillebrecht M, Schiemann S. Influence of long-lasting static stretching on maximal strength, muscle thickness and flexibility. Front Physiol. 2022;13:878955. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2022.878955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.878955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35694390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Konrad A, Keiner M, Zech A, Nakamura M, Hillebrecht M, et al. Using daily stretching to counteract performance decreases as a result of reduced physical activity: a controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:15571. doi: 10.3390/ijerph192315571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192315571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9741422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36497646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Zech A, Wagner CM, Konrad A, Nakamura M, Keiner M, et al. Sex differences in stretch-induced hypertrophy, maximal strength and flexibility gains. Front Physiol. 2022;13:1078301. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2022.1078301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.1078301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9846774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36685189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Wirth K, Keiner M, Lohmann LH, Hillebrecht M, Brinkmann A, et al. Comparison of the effects of long-lasting static stretching and hypertrophy training on maximal strength, muscle thickness and flexibility in the plantar flexors. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123:1773&#x2013;1787. doi: 10.1007/s00421-023-05184-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05184-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10363083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Keiner M, Wohlann T, Lohmann LH, Schmitt T, Hillebrecht M, et al. Influence of long-lasting static stretching interventions on functional and morphological parameters in the plantar flexors: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37318350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Gonyea WJ. Muscle fiber splitting in stretch enlarged avian muscle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1994;26:973&#x2013;977. doi: 10.1249/00005768-199408000-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-199408000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7968431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno T. Combined effects of static stretching and electrical stimulation on joint range of motion and muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2694&#x2013;2703. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29023326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlann T, Warneke K, Hillebrecht M, Petersmann A, Ferrauti A, Schiemann S. Effects of daily static stretch training over 6 weeks on maximal strength, muscle thickness, contraction properties and flexibility. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1139065. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2023.1139065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2023.1139065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10149921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37139297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVol D, Rotwein P, Sadow L, Novakofski J, Bechtel PJ. Activation of insulin-like growth factor gene expression during work induced skeletal muscle growth in pituitary intact and hypophysectomized rats. Am J Physiol. 1990;259:E89&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2372054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashmore CR. Stretch-induced growth in chicken wing muscles: effects on hereditary muscular dystrophy. Am J Physiol. 1982;242:C178&#x2013;C183. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.1982.242.3.C178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1982.242.3.C178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7065168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent GJ, Sparrow MP. Changes in RNA, DNA and protein content and the rates of protein synthesis and degradation during hypertrophy of the anterior latissimus dorsi muscle of the adult fowl (Gallus domesticus) Growth. 1977;41:249&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">604181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble EG, Tang Q, Taylor PB. Protein synthesis in compensatory hypertrophy of rats plantaris. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 1984;62:1178&#x2013;1182. doi: 10.1139/y84-197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/y84-197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6498629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams PE, Goldspink G. Connective tissue changes in surgically overloaded muscle. Cell Tissue Res. 1981;221:465&#x2013;470. doi: 10.1007/BF00216749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00216749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7307065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R. Mechano-biology of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and regeneration: possible mechanism of stretch-induced activation of resident myogenic stem cells. Anim Sci. 2010;81:11&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1111/j.1740-0929.2009.00712.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1740-0929.2009.00712.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20163667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riss TL, Novakofski J, Bechtel PJ. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy in rats having growth hormone secreting tumors. J Appl Physiol. 1986;61:1732&#x2013;1735. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1986.61.5.1732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1986.61.5.1732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3781982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tegtbur U, Busse MW, Kubis HP. K&#xf6;rperliches training und zellul&#xe4;re anpassung des muskels. Unfallchirurg. 2009;112:365&#x2013;372. doi: 10.1007/s00113-009-1627-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00113-009-1627-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19308345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki YM, Takeda S. Mechanobiology in skeletal muscle: conversion of mechanical information into molecular signal. In: Noda M, editor, Mechanosensing biology. Springer, Tokyo. 10.1007/978-4-431-89757-6_4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparrow MP. Regression of skeletal muscle of chicken wing after stretch-induced hypertrophy. Am J Physiol. 1982;242:C333&#x2013;C338. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.1982.242.5.C333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.1982.242.5.C333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6177250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKoy G, Ashley W, Mander J, Yang SY, Williams N, Russel B, et al. Expression of insulin growth factor-1 splice variants and structural genes in rabbit skeletal muscle induced by stretch and stimulation. J Physiol. 1999;516:583&#x2013;592. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7793.1999.0583v.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.1999.0583v.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2269271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10087355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czerwinski SM, Martin JM, Bechtel PJ. Modulation of IGF mRNA abundance during stretch-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy and regression. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76:2026&#x2013;2030. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1994.76.5.2026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1994.76.5.2026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8063665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown CR, Palmer WK, Bechtel PJ. Effects of passive stretch on growth and regression of muscle from chickens of various ages. Comp Biochem Physiol. 1986;86:443&#x2013;448. doi: 10.1016/0300-9629(87)90522-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0300-9629(87)90522-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2881684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agata N, Sasai N, Inoue-Miyazu M, Kawakami K, Hayakawa K, Kobayashi K, et al. Repetitive stretch suppresses denervation-induced atrophy of soleus muscle in rats. Muscle Nerve. 2009;39:456&#x2013;462. doi: 10.1002/mus.21103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.21103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19260063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Hernandez J, Marin PJ, Men&#xe9;dez H, Ferrero C, Loenneke JP, Herrero AJ. Muscular adaptations after two different volumes of blood flow-restricted training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23:e114&#x2013;e120. doi: 10.1111/sms.12036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortman RJ, Brown SM, Savage-Elliot I, Finley ZJ, Mulcahey MK. Blood flow restriction training for athletes: a systematic review. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49:1938&#x2013;1944. doi: 10.1177/0363546520964454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546520964454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33196300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, Timmerman KL, Fujita S, Abe T, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:1199&#x2013;1209. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.01266.2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01266.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Mattocks KT, Dankel SJ, Abe T, et al. Muscle Adaptations to high-load training and very low-load training with and without blood flow restriction. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2018.01448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.01448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6198179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30386254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrier I. Does stretching improve performance? A systematic and critical review of the literature. Clin J Sport Med. 2004;14:267&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1097/00042752-200409000-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00042752-200409000-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15377965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros DM, Lima CS. Influence of chronic stretching on muscle performance: systematic review. Hum Mov Sci. 2017;54:220&#x2013;229. doi: 10.1016/j.humov.2017.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2017.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arntz F, Markov A, Behm DG, Behrens M, Negra Y, Nakamura M, et al. Chronic effects of static stretching exercises on muscle strength and power in healthy individuals across the lifespan: a systematic review with multi-level meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53:723&#x2013;745. doi: 10.1007/s40279-022-01806-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01806-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Nakamura M, Schoenfeld BJ, Cyrino ES. The data do not seem to support the effect of stretch training on increasing muscle thickness. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28:2767&#x2013;2768. doi: 10.1111/sms.13285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30144180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evangelista AL, De Souza EO, Moreira DCB, Alonso AC, Teixeira CVS, Wadhi T, et al. Interset stretching vs. traditional strength training: effects on muscle strength and size in untrained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:S159&#x2013;S166. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matos F, Amaral J, Martinez E, Can&#xe1;rio-Lemos R, Moreira T, Cavalcante J, et al. Changes in muscle thickness after 8 weeks of strength training, electromyostimulation and both combined in healthy young adults. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:3184. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19063184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19063184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8955636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35328871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aube D, Wadhi T, Rauch J, Anand A, Barakat C, Pearson J, et al. Progressive resistance training volume: effects on muscle thickness, mass, and strength adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;36:600&#x2013;607. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Wackerhage H, De Souza E. Inter-set stretch: a potential time-efficient strategy for enhancing skeletal muscle adaptations. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:1035190. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2022.1035190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.1035190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9706104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36457663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CH, Nosaka K, Chen HL, Lin MJ, Tseng KW, Chen TC. Effects of flexibility training on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:491&#x2013;500. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181f315ad.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181f315ad</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20689450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apostolopoulos N, Metsios GS, Flouris AD, Koutedakis Y, Wyon MA. The relevance of stretch intensity and position: a systematic review. Front Psych. 2015;6:1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26347668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Pijl R, Strom J, Conijn S, Lindqvist J, Labeit S, Granzier H, et al. Titin-based mechanosensing modulates muscle hypertrophy. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2018;9:947&#x2013;961. doi: 10.1002/jcsm.12319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6204599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29978560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Pijl RJ, Hudson B, Granzier-Nakajima T, Li F, Knottnerus AM, Smith J, et al. Deleting titin&#x2019;s C-terminal PEVK exons increases passive stiffness, alters splicing, and induces cross-sectional and longitudinal hypertrophy in skeletal muscle. Front Physiol. 2020;11:494. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2020.00494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.00494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7274174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32547410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim W, Park H. No significant correlation between the intensity of static stretching and subject&#x2019;s perception of pain. J Phys Ther Sci. 2017;29:1856&#x2013;1859. doi: 10.1589/jpts.29.1856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.29.1856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29184306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas SR, Mendes B, Le Sant G, Andrade RJ, Nordez A, Milanovic Z. Can chronic stretching change the muscle-tendon mechanical properties? A review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28:794&#x2013;806. doi: 10.1111/sms.12957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28801950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Tilp M. Increased range of motion after static stretching is not due to changes in muscle and tendon structures. Clin Biomech. 2014;29:636&#x2013;642. doi: 10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2014.04.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2014.04.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24856792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad A, Tilp M. Time course of muscle-tendon unit function and structure following three minutes of static stretching. J Sports Sci Med. 2020;19:52&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32132827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AG, Kokkonen J, Winchester JB, Kalani W, Peterson K, Kenly MS, et al. A 10-week stretching program increases strength in the contralateral muscle. J Cond Res. 2012;26:832&#x2013;836. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182281b41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182281b41</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22297415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkonen J, Nelson AG, Eldredge C, Winchester JB. Chronic static stretching improves exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1825&#x2013;1831. doi: 10.1249/mss.0b013e3181238a2b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e3181238a2b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo S, C&#xe8; E, Valentina Bisconti A, Rampichini S, Doria C, Borrelli M, et al. The effects of 12 weeks of static stretch training on the functional, mechanical, and architectural characteristics of the triceps surae muscle-tendon complex. Eur J Appl Physil. 2021;121:1743&#x2013;1758. doi: 10.1007/s00421-021-04654-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04654-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8144166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33687531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakao S, Ikezoe T, Nakamura M, Umegaki H, Fujita K, Umehara J, et al. Chronic effects of a static stretching program on hamstring strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;35:1924&#x2013;1929. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30694962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell SL, Bilodeau RLS, Cox MJ, Behm DG. Cross education training effects are evident with twice daily, self-administered band stretch training. J Sports Sci Med. 2019;18:544&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6683624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31427877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaRoche DP, Lussier MV, Roy SJ. Chronic stretching and voluntary muscle force. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:589&#x2013;596. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181636aef.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181636aef</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-aziem AA, Mohammad WS. Plantar-flexor static stretch training effect on eccentric and concentric peak torque: a comparative study of trained versus untrained subjects. J Hum Kinet. 2012;34:49&#x2013;58. doi: 10.2478/v10078-012-0063-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/v10078-012-0063-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3590825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23486840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betz TM, Wehrstein MI, Preisner F, Bendszus M, Friedmann-Bette B. Reliability and validity of a standardized ultrasound examination protocol to quantify vastus lateralis muscle. J Rehabil Med. 2021;53:jrm00212. doi: 10.2340/16501977-2854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/16501977-2854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8638746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34121129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>English C, Fisher L, Thoirs K. Reliability of real-time ultrasound for measuring skeletal muscle size in human limbs in vivo: a systematic review. Clin Rehabil. 2012;26:934&#x2013;944. doi: 10.1177/0269215511434994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215511434994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22324054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebert JJ, Koppenhaver SL, Parent EC, Fritz JM. A systematic review of the reliability of rehabilitative ultrasound imaging for the quantitative assessment of the abdominal and lumbar trunk muscles. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2009;34:848&#x2013;856. doi: 10.1097/BRS.0b013e3181ae625c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BRS.0b013e3181ae625c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG. Use of diagnostic ultrasound for assessing muscle size. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16:103&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander SE, Pollock AC, Lamon S. The effect of sex hormones on skeletal muscle adaptation in females. Eur J Sport Sci. 2022;22:1035&#x2013;1045. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2021.1921854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2021.1921854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33890831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JL, Brunetz MH, Chenier TC, McCammon MR, Houmard JA, Franklin ME, et al. The effects of static and ballistic stretching on delayed onset muscle soreness and creatine kinase. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1993;64:103&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1080/02701367.1993.10608784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.1993.10608784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8451526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xf6;llner AM, Abilez OJ, B&#xf6;l M, Kuhl E. Stretching skeletal muscle: chronic muscle lengthening through sarcomerogenesis. PLoS ONE. 2012;7:e45661. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0045661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0045661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23049683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruse A, Rivares C, Weide G, Tilp M, Jaspers RT. Stimuli for adaptations in muscle length and the length range of active force exertion: a narrative review. Front Physiol. 2021;12:742034. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.742034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.742034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8531727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34690815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>