<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38513182</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Determining Changes in Muscle Size and Architecture After Exercise Training: One Site Does Not Fit all.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>787</StartPage><EndPage>790</EndPage><MedlinePgn>787-790</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004722</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nunes, JP, Blazevich, AJ, Schoenfeld, BJ, Kassiano, W, Costa, BDV, Ribeiro, AS, Nakamura, M, Nosaka, K, and Cyrino, ES. Determining changes in muscle size and architecture after exercise training: One site does not fit all. J Strength Cond Res 38(4): 787-790, 2024-Different methods can be used to assess muscle hypertrophy, but the effects of training on regional changes in muscle size can be detected only using direct muscle measurements such as muscle thickness, cross-sectional area, or volume. Importantly, muscle size increases vary across regions within and between muscles after resistance training programs (i.e., heterogeneous, or nonuniform, muscle hypertrophy). Muscle architectural changes, including fascicle length and pennation angle, after resistance and stretch training programs are also region-specific. In this paper, we show that the literature indicates that a single-site measure of muscle shape does not properly capture the effects achieved after exercise training interventions and that conclusions concerning the magnitude of muscle adaptations can vary substantially depending on the muscle site to be examined. Thus, we propose that measurements of muscle size and architecture should be completed at multiple sites across regions between the agonist muscles within a muscle group and along the length of the muscles to provide an adequate picture of training effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8144-5906</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blazevich</LastName><ForeName>Anthony J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Sciences Department, CUNY Lehman College, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kassiano</LastName><ForeName>Witalo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Costa</LastName><ForeName>Bruna D V</ForeName><Initials>BDV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ribeiro</LastName><ForeName>Alex S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Research in Health Sciences, University of Northern Paran&#xe1;, Londrina, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Masatoshi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, Nishi Kyushu University, Saga, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nosaka</LastName><ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyrino</LastName><ForeName>Edilson S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition, and Exercise Laboratory, Physical Education and Sport Center, Londrina State University, Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38513182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202404000-00021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol 81: 174&#x2013;180, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Massey GJ, Folland JP. The human muscle size and strength relationship: Effects of architecture, muscle force, and measurement location. Med Sci Sports Exerc 53: 2140&#x2013;2151, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benford J, Hughes J, Waldron M, Theis N. Concentric versus eccentric training: Effect on muscle strength, regional morphology, and architecture. Transl Sports Med 4: 46&#x2013;55, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol 103: 1565&#x2013;1575, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Gill ND, Bronks R, Newton RU. Training-specific muscle architecture adaptation after 5-wk training in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 2013&#x2013;2022, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomquist K, Langberg H, Karlsen S, et al. Effect of range of motion in heavy load squatting on muscle and tendon adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2133&#x2013;2142, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonafiglia JT, Preobrazenski N, Gurd BJ, Egan B. A systematic review examining the approaches used to estimate interindividual differences in trainability and classify individual responses to exercise training. Front Physiol 12: 665044, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand&#xe3;o L, de Salles Painelli V, Lasevicius T, et al. Varying the order of combinations of single- and multi-joint exercises differentially affects resistance training adaptations. J Strength Cond Res 34: 1254&#x2013;1263, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Determining strength: A case for multiple methods of measurement. Sports Med 47: 193&#x2013;195, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa BDdV, Kassiano W, Nunes JP, et al. Does performing different resistance exercises induce non-homogeneous hypertrophy? Int J Sports Med 42: 803&#x2013;811, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Loenneke JP. A method to stop analyzing random error and start analyzing differential responders to exercise. Sports Med 50: 231&#x2013;238, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earp JE, Newton RU, Cormie P, Blazevich AJ. Inhomogeneous quadriceps femoris hypertrophy in response to strength and power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 2389&#x2013;2397, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Kanehisa H, Kawakami Y. Inhomogeneous architectural changes of the quadriceps femoris induced by resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 113: 2691&#x2013;2703, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonseca RM, Roschel H, Tricoli V, et al. Changes in exercises are more effective than in loading schemes to improve muscle strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3085&#x2013;3092, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Atherton PJ, Reeves ND, et al. Architectural, functional and molecular responses to concentric and eccentric loading in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol 210: 642&#x2013;654, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Raiteri BJ, Longo S, et al. Muscle architecture assessment: Strengths, shortcomings and new frontiers of in-vivo imaging techniques. Ultrasound Med Biol 44: 2492&#x2013;2504, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Ruoss S, Valdivieso P, et al. Regional regulation of focal adhesion kinase after concentric and eccentric loading is related to remodelling of human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol 223: e13056, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, et al. Selective muscle hypertrophy, changes in EMG and force, and serum hormones during strength training in older women. J Appl Physiol 91: 569&#x2013;580, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, et al. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: Size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol 10: 247, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higbie EJ, Cureton KJ, Warren GL, Prior BM. Effects of concentric and eccentric training on muscle strength, cross-sectional area, and neural activation. J Appl Physiol 81: 2173&#x2013;2181, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Housh DJ, Housh TJ, Johnson GO, Chu WK. Hypertrophic response to unilateral concentric isokinetic resistance training. J Appl Physiol 73: 65&#x2013;70, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Costa BDV, Kunevaliki G, et al. Greater gastrocnemius muscle hypertrophy after partial range of motion training performed at long muscle lengths. J Strength Cond Res 37: 1746&#x2013;1753, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassiano W, Nunes JP, Costa B, et al. Does varying resistance exercises promote superior muscle hypertrophy and strength gains? A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 36: 1753&#x2013;1762, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami Y, Abe T, Kuno SY, Fukunaga T. Training-induced changes in muscle architecture and specific tension. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 72: 37&#x2013;43, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krotkiewski M, Aniansson A, Grimby G, Bj&#xf6;rntorp P, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m L. The effect of unilateral isokinetic strength training on local adipose and muscle tissue morphology, thickness, and enzymes. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 42: 271&#x2013;281, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Huang M, Wu Y, et al. Greater hamstrings muscle hypertrophy but similar damage protection after training at long versus short muscle lengths. Med Sci Sports Exerc 53: 825&#x2013;837, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeo S, Wu Y, Huang M, et al. Triceps brachii hypertrophy is substantially greater after elbow extension training performed in the overhead versus neutral arm position. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 1240&#x2013;1250, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangine GT, Redd MJ, Gonzalez AM, et al. Resistance training does not induce uniform adaptations to quadriceps. PLoS One 13: e0198304, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matta T, Sim&#xe3;o R, de Salles BF, Spineti J, Oliveira LF. Strength training's chronic effects on muscle architecture parameters of different arm sites. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1711&#x2013;1717, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matta TT, Nascimento FX, Trajano GS, et al. Selective hypertrophy of the quadriceps musculature after 14 weeks of isokinetic and conventional resistance training. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 37: 137&#x2013;142, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matta TT, Nascimento FXMB, Fernandes IA, Oliveira LF. Heterogeneity of rectus femoris muscle architectural adaptations after two different 14-week resistance training programmes. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 210&#x2013;215, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon G, Morse CI, Burden A, Winwood K, Onamb&#xe9;l&#xe9; GL. Muscular adaptations and insulin-like growth factor-1 responses to resistance training are stretch-mediated. Muscle Nerve 49: 108&#x2013;119, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon GE, Morse CI, Burden A, Winwood K, Onamb&#xe9;l&#xe9; GL. Impact of range of motion during ecologically valid resistance training protocols on muscle size, subcutaneous fat, and strength. J Strength Cond Res 28: 245&#x2013;255, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Hoppeler H, Kayser B, et al. Human quadriceps cross-sectional area, torque and neural activation during 6 months strength training. Acta Physiol Scand 157: 175&#x2013;186, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Roi GS, Landoni L, Minetti AE, Cerretelli P. Changes in force, cross-sectional area and neural activation during strength training and detraining of the human quadriceps. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 59: 310&#x2013;319, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noork&#xf5;iv M, Nosaka K, Blazevich AJ. Neuromuscular adaptations associated with knee joint angle-specific force change. Med Sci Sports Exerc 46: 1525&#x2013;1537, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Costa BDV, Kassiano W, et al. Different foot positioning during calf training to induce portion-specific gastrocnemius muscle hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 34: 2347&#x2013;2351, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Pina FLC, Ribeiro AS, et al. Responsiveness to muscle mass gain following 12 and 24 weeks of resistance training in older women. Aging Clin Exp Res 33: 1071&#x2013;1078, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Nakamura M, et al. Does stretch training induce muscle hypertrophy in humans? A review of the literature. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 40: 148&#x2013;156, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panidi I, Bogdanis GC, Terzis G, et al. Muscle architectural and functional adaptations following 12-weeks of stretching in adolescent female athletes. Front Physiol 12: 701338, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa GF, Lima FV, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Partial range of motion training elicits favorable improvements in muscular adaptations when carried out at long muscle lengths. Eur J Sport Sci 22: 1250&#x2013;1260, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering C, Kiely J. Do non-responders to exercise exist&#x2014;And if so, what should we do about them? Sports Med 49: 1&#x2013;7, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincheira PA, Boswell MA, Franchi MV, Delp SL, Lichtwark GA. Biceps femoris long head sarcomere and fascicle length adaptations after 3 weeks of eccentric exercise training. J Sport Health Sci 11: 43&#x2013;49, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan JI, Franchi MV, Gharahdaghi N, et al. Muscle and tendon adaptations to moderate load eccentric vs. concentric resistance exercise in young and older males. GeroScience 43: 1567&#x2013;1584, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Santos ED, Nunes JP, et al. A brief review on the effects of the squat exercise on lower-limb muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J 45: 58&#x2013;66, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Haun CT, Mobley CB, et al. Physiological differences between low versus high skeletal muscle hypertrophic responders to resistance exercise training: Current perspectives and future research directions. Front Physiol 9: 834, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roman WJ, Fleckenstein J, Stray-Gundersen J, et al. Adaptations in the elbow flexors of elderly males after heavy-resistance training. J Appl Physiol 74: 750&#x2013;754, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato S, Yoshida R, Kiyono R, et al. Elbow joint angles in elbow flexor unilateral resistance exercise training determine its effects on muscle strength and thickness of trained and non-trained arms. Front Physiol 12: 734509, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson CL, Kim BDH, Bourcet MR, Jones GR, Jakobi JM. Stretch training induces unequal adaptation in muscle fascicles and thickness in medial and lateral gastrocnemii. Scand J Med Sci Sports 27: 1597&#x2013;1604, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trezise J, Blazevich AJ. Anatomical and neuromuscular determinants of strength change in previously untrained men following heavy strength training. Front Physiol 10: 1001, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valamatos MJ, Tavares F, Santos RM, Veloso AP, Mil-Homens P. Influence of full range of motion vs. equalized partial range of motion training on muscle architecture and mechanical properties. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 1969&#x2013;1983, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varovi&#x107; D, &#x17d;ganjer K, Vuk S, Schoenfeld BJ. Drop-set training elicits differential increases in non-uniform hypertrophy of the quadriceps in leg extension exercise. Sports 9: 119, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Than C, Brown JM. Methods matter: The relationship between strength and hypertrophy depends on methods of measurement and analysis. PeerJ 6: e5071, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Ema R, Miyamoto N, Kawakami Y. Inter- and intramuscular differences in training-induced hypertrophy of the quadriceps femoris: Association with muscle activation during the first training session. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 37: 405&#x2013;412, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Fukutani A, Kawakami Y, Yanai T. Nonuniform muscle hypertrophy: Its relation to muscle activation in training session. Med Sci Sports Exerc 45: 2158&#x2013;2165, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakahara T, Miyamoto N, Sugisaki N, et al. Association between regional differences in muscle activation in one session of resistance exercise and in muscle hypertrophy after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1569&#x2013;1576, 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>