<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28713459</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>57</Volume><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Bench Press Variations in Competitive Athletes on Muscle Activity and Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>61</StartPage><EndPage>71</EndPage><MedlinePgn>61-71</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/hukin-2017-0047</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of the study was to compare the EMG activity performing 6RM competition style bench press (flat bench-wide grip) with 1) medium and narrow grip widths on a flat bench and 1) inclined and declined bench positions with a wide grip. Twelve bench press athletes competing at national and international level participated in the study. EMG activity was measured in the pectoralis major, anterior and posterior deltoid, biceps brachii, triceps brachii and latissimus dorsi. Non-significant differences in activation were observed between the three bench positions with the exception of 58.5-62.6% lower triceps brachii activation, but 48.3-68.7% greater biceps brachii activation in the inclined bench compared with the flat and declined bench position. Comparing the three grip widths, non-significant differences in activations were observed, with the exception of 25.9-30.5% lower EMG activity in the biceps brachii using a narrow grip, compared to the medium and wide grip conditions. The 6-RM loads were 5.8-11.1% greater using a medium and wide grip compared to narrow grip width and 18.5-21.5% lower in the inclined bench position compared with flat and declined. Comparing the EMG activity during the competition bench press style with either the inclined and declined bench position (wide grip) or using a narrow and medium grip (flat bench), only resulted in different EMG activity in the biceps- and triceps brachii. The 6RM loads varied with each bench press variation and we recommend the use of a wide grip on a flat bench during high load hypertrophy training to bench press athletes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeterbakken</LastName><ForeName>Atle Hole</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Teacher Education and Sports, Sogn and Fjordane University College, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mo</LastName><ForeName>Dag-Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Teacher Education and Sports, Sogn and Fjordane University College, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scott</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Scott Studio, Pithers Yard, High St, Castle Cary, Somerset, BA7 7AN, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andersen</LastName><ForeName>Vidar</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Teacher Education and Sports, Sogn and Fjordane University College, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28713459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5504579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hukin-2017-0047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2017-0047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anderson KG, Behm DG. Maintenance of EMG activity and loss of force output with instability. J Strength and Cond Res. 2004;18:637&#x2013;640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett C, Kippers V, Turner P. Effects of variations of the bench press exercise on the EMG activity of five shoulder muslces. J Strength and Cond Res. 1995;9:222&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness: a review of the acute programme variables. Sports Med. 2005;35:841&#x2013;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16180944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarys JP. Electromyography in sports and occupational settings: an update of its limits and possibilities. Ergonomics. 2000;43(10):1750&#x2013;1762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11083153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemons JM, Aaron C. Effect of grip width on the myoelectric activity of the prime movers in bench press. J Strength and Cond Res. 1997;11:82&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Inc. Hillsdale; New Jersy: 1988. Statistical Power for the Behavioral Sciences.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D. Interpretation of the surface electromyogram in dynamic contractions. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2006;34(3):121&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16829739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass SC, Armstrong T. Electromyographical activity of the pectoralis muscle during incline and decline bench presses. J Strength and Cond Res. 1997;11:163&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golas A, Maszczyk A, Pietraszewski P, Stastny P, Tufano J, Zajac A. Effects of pre-exhaustion on the patterns of muscular activity in the flat bench press. J Strength and Cond Res. 2016 ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27984499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Komi PV, Alen M, Kauhanen H. EMG, muscle fibre and force production characteristics during a 1 year training period in elite weight-lifters. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1987;56:419&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3622485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10:361&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11018445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jobe W, Tibone E, Perry J, Moynes D. An EMG measurments during bicycle pedalling, in Biomechanics Symposium. Am J Sports Med. 1984;11:3&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:674&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Scheuermann BW. Influence of bench position on upper extremity muscular activation during bench press exercise. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16:309&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25799093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehman GJ. The influence of grip width and forearm pronation/supination on upper-body myoelectric activity during the flat bench press. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19:587&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16095407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen N, McLaughlin T. Kinematic factors influencing performance and injury risk in the bench press exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1984;16:376&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6493018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maszczyk A, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A, Czuba A, Kr&#xf3;l H, Wilk M, S&#x144;t&#x2019;astn&#xfd; P, Goodwin J, Kostrzewa M, Zaj&#x105;c A. EMG analysis and modelling of flat bench press using artificial neural networks. S Afric J Res Sport, Phys Edu Rec. 2016;38(1):91&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, Housh TJ, Kibler WB, Kraemer WJ, Triplett NT. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, van den Tillaar R, Fimland MS. A comparison of muscle activity and 1-RM strength of three chest-press exercises with different stability requirements. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:533&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21225489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stastny P, Golas A, Blazek D, Maszczyk A, Wilk M, Pietraszewski P, Petr M, Uhlir P, Zajac A. A systematic review of surface electromyography analyses of the bench press movement task. Plos One. 2017;12:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5295722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28170449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillaar R, Ettema G. A comparison of muscle activity in concentric and counter movement maximum bench press. Tillaar R, Saeterbakken AH, Ettema G. Is the occurrence of the sticking region the result of diminishing potentiation in bench press? J Hum Kinet. J Sports Sci. 2013;2012;3830:63&#x2013;71. 591&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3827767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24235985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trebs AA, Brandenburg JP, Pitney WA. An electromyography analysis of 3 muscles surrounding the shoulder joint during the performance of a chest press exercise at several positions. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:1925&#x2013;1930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20512064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Ettema G. A comparison of successful and unsuccessful attempts in maximal bench pressing. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:2056&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19812510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Ettema G. The &#x201c;sticking period&#x201d; in a maximum bench press. J Sports Sci. 2010;28:529&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20373201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Saeterbakken AH. Fatigue effects upon sticking region and electromyography in a six-repetition maximum bench press. J Sports Sci. 2013;31:1823&#x2013;1830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23879709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsch EA, Bird M, Mayhew JL. Electromyographic activity of the pectoralis major and anterior deltoid muscles during three upper-body lifts. J Strength and Cond Res. 2005;19:449&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter DA, Fuglevand AJ, Archer SE. Crosstalk in surface electromyography: Theoretical and practical estimates. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 1994;4:15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20870543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>