<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31628720</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2151-4658</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>72</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthritis care &amp; research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Muscle Strength Training on Muscle Mass Gain and Hypertrophy in Older Adults With Osteoarthritis: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1703</StartPage><EndPage>1718</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1703-1718</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/acr.24097</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the effect of muscle strength exercise training (MSET) on lean mass (LM) gain and muscle hypertrophy in older patients with lower extremity osteoarthritis (OA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A comprehensive search of online databases was performed on April 20, 2019. Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) that reported the effects of MSET on LM, muscle thickness, and cross-sectional area (CSA) in older patients with OA were identified. A risk of bias assessment and meta-analysis were performed for the included RCTs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We included 19 RCTs with a median Physiotherapy Evidence Database score of 6 of 10 (range 3-7). In total, data from 1,195 patients (65% women, 85% with knee OA) with a mean age of 62.1 years (range 40-86 years) were analyzed. MSET resulted in significantly higher LM gain (standardized mean difference [SMD] 0.49 [95% confidence interval (95% CI) 0.28, 0.71], P &lt; 0.00001) than did the nonexercise controls. Meta-analysis results revealed significantly positive effects of MSET on muscle thickness (SMD 0.82 [95% CI 0.20, 1.43], P = 0.009) and CSA (SMD 0.80 [95% CI 0.25, 1.35], P = 0.004) compared with nonexercise controls. No significant effects in favor of MSET were observed for any muscle outcome compared with exercise controls. Five RCTs reported nonsevere adverse events in response to MSET, whereas no RCTs reported severe events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">MSET is effective in increasing LM and muscle size in older adults with OA. Clinicians should incorporate MSET into their management of patients at risk of low muscle mass to maximize health status, particularly for older individuals with OA.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020, American College of Rheumatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Chun-De</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1930-4915</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Taiwan University and Shuang Ho Hospital, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hung-Chou</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shuang Ho Hospital and Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Chi</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Taipei University of Nursing and Health Sciences, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsauo</LastName><ForeName>Jau-Yih</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Wei</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1815-6938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shuang Ho Hospital and Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan, and National Taiwan Sport University, Taoyuan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liou</LastName><ForeName>Tsan-Hon</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shuang Ho Hospital and Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518086</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2151-464X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018908" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Weakness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010003" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoarthritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31628720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.24097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Loureiro A, Constantinou M, Diamond LE, Beck B, Barrett R. Individuals with mild-to-moderate hip osteoarthritis have lower limb muscle strength and volume deficits. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2018;19:303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wluka AE, Berry PA, Siew T, Teichtahl AJ, Urquhart DM, et al. Increase in vastus medialis cross-sectional area is associated with reduced pain, cartilage loss, and joint replacement risk in knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Rheum 2012;64:3917-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharias A, Green RA, Semciw A, English DJ, Kapakoulakis T, Pizzari T. Atrophy of hip abductor muscles is related to clinical severity in a hip osteoarthritis population. Clin Anat 2018;31:507-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HM, Kim HJ, Lee B, Kwon M, Jung SM, Lee SW, et al. Decreased muscle mass is independently associated with knee pain in female patients with radiographically mild osteoarthritis: a nationwide cross-sectional study (KNHANES 2010-2011). Clin Rheumatol 2018;37:1333-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Ro HJ, Chung SG, Kang SH, Seo KM, Kim DK. Low skeletal muscle mass in the lower limbs is independently associated to knee osteoarthritis. PLoS One 2016;11:e0166385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimaldi A, Richardson C, Stanton W, Durbridge G, Donnelly W, Hides J. The association between degenerative hip joint pathology and size of the gluteus medius, gluteus minimus and piriformis muscles. Man Ther 2009;14:605-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi M, Fukumoto Y, Kobayashi M, Kawasaki T, Maegawa S, Ibuki S, et al. Quantity and quality of the lower extremity muscles in women with knee osteoarthritis. Ultrasound Med Biol 2015;41:2567-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady AO, Straight CR. Muscle capacity and physical function in older women: what are the impacts of resistance training? J Sport Health Sci 2014;3:179-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nur H, Sertkaya BS, Tuncer T. Determinants of physical functioning in women with knee osteoarthritis. Aging Clin Exp Res 2018;30:299-306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Piasecki M, Atherton PJ. The age-related loss of skeletal muscle mass and function: measurement and physiology of muscle fibre atrophy and muscle fibre loss in humans. Ageing Res Rev 2018;47:123-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tieland M, Trouwborst I, Clark BC. Skeletal muscle performance and ageing. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2018;9:3-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culvenor AG, Ruhdorfer A, Juhl C, Eckstein F, &#xd8;iestad BE. Knee extensor strength and risk of structural, symptomatic, and functional decline in knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2017;69:649-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruhdorfer A, Wirth W, Eckstein F. Longitudinal change in thigh muscle strength prior to and concurrent with minimum clinically important worsening or improvement in knee function: data from the Osteoarthritis Initiative. Arthritis Rheumatol 2016;68:826-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruhdorfer A, Dannhauer T, Wirth W, Hitzl W, Kwoh CK, Guermazi A, et al. Thigh muscle cross-sectional areas and strength in advanced versus early painful osteoarthritis: an exploratory between-knee, within-person comparison in Osteoarthritis Initiative participants. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2013;65:1034-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson MK, Magnusson H, Coster M, Karlsson C, Rosengren BE. Patients with knee osteoarthritis have a phenotype with higher bone mass, higher fat mass, and lower lean body mass. Clin Orthop Relat Res 2015;473:258-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikberg S, S&#xf6;rl&#xe9;n N, Brand&#xe9;n L, Johansson J, Nordstr&#xf6;m A, Hult A, et al. Effects of resistance training on functional strength and muscle mass in 70-year-old individuals with pre-sarcopenia: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2019;20:28-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trethewey SP, Brown N, Gao F, Turner AM. Interventions for the management and prevention of sarcopenia in the critically ill: a systematic review. J Crit Care 2019;50:287-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharias A, Green RA, Semciw AI, Kingsley MI, Pizzari T. Efficacy of rehabilitation programs for improving muscle strength in people with hip or knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2014;22:1752-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen MJ, Viechtbauer W, Lenssen AF, Hendriks EJ, de Bie RA. Strength training alone, exercise therapy alone, and exercise therapy with passive manual mobilisation each reduce pain and disability in people with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review. J Physiother 2011;57:11-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartholdy C, Juhl C, Christensen R, Lund H, Zhang W, Henriksen M. The role of muscle strengthening in exercise therapy for knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-regression analysis of randomized trials. Semin Arthritis Rheum 2017;47:9-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Su Y, Chen S, Zhang Y, Zhang Z, Liu C, et al. The effects of resistance exercise in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil 2016;30:947-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agergaard J, Bulow J, Jensen JK, Reitelseder S, Drummond MJ, Schjerling P, et al. Light-load resistance exercise increases muscle protein synthesis and hypertrophy signaling in elderly men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 2017;312:E326-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ. Anabolic resistance: the effects of aging, sexual dimorphism, and immobilization on human muscle protein turnover. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 2009;34:377-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlietstra L, Hendrickx W, Waters DL. Exercise interventions in healthy older adults with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Australas J Ageing 2018;37:169-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Sen A, Gordon PM. Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2011;43:249-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips S, Vechin FC, Ugrinowitsch C. A review of resistance training-induced changes in skeletal muscle protein synthesis and their contribution to hypertrophy. Sports Med 2015;45:801-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zammit PS, Partridge TA, Yablonka-Reuveni Z. The skeletal muscle satellite cell: the stem cell that came in from the cold. J Histochem Cytochem 2006;54:1177-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marimuthu K, Murton AJ, Greenhaff PL. Mechanisms regulating muscle mass during disuse atrophy and rehabilitation in humans. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2011;110:555-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraz RB, Gualano B, Rodrigues R, Kurimori CO, Fuller R, Rodrigues Lima F, et al. Benefits of resistance training with blood flow restriction in knee osteoarthritis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2018;50:897-905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud WS, Elnaggar RK, Ahmed AS. Influence of isometric exercise training on quadriceps muscle architecture and strength in obese subjects with knee osteoarthritis. Int J Med Res Health Sci 2017;6:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valtonen A, P&#xf6;yh&#xf6;nen T, Sipil&#xe4; S, Heinonen A. Maintenance of aquatic training-induced benefits on mobility and lower-extremity muscles among persons with unilateral knee replacement. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2011;92:1944-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JY, Tchai E, Jang SN. Effectiveness of aquatic exercise for obese patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. PM R 2010;2:723-31; quiz 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar GC, Rocha SG, Rezende GA, Marcela R&#xea;go do Nascimento MR, Scalzo PL. Effects of resistance training in individuals with knee osteoarthritis. Fisioter Mov 2016;29:589-96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller B, Munukka M, Rantalainen T, Lammentausta E, Nieminen MT, Kiviranta I, et al. Effects of high intensity resistance aquatic training on body composition and walking speed in women with mild knee osteoarthritis: a 4-month RCT with 12-month follow-up. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 2017;25:1238-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos ML, Gomes WF, Pereira DS, Oliveira DM, Dias JM, Ferrioli E, et al. Muscle strength, muscle balance, physical function and plasma interleukin-6 (IL-6) levels in elderly women with knee osteoarthritis (OA). Arch Gerontol Geriatr 2011;52:322-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson D, Jackson T, Sapey E, Lord JM. Frailty and sarcopenia: the potential role of an aged immune system. Ageing Res Rev 2017;36:1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Massey GJ, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Morales-Artacho AJ, McKeown A, Appleby CL, et al. Changes in agonist neural drive, hypertrophy and pre-training strength all contribute to the individual strength gains after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 2017;117:631-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamseer L, Moher D, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: elaboration and explanation. BMJ 2015;349:g7647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen BB, Shih TT, Hsu CY, Yu CW, Wei SY, Chen CY, et al. Thigh muscle volume predicted by anthropometric measurements and correlated with physical function in the older adults. J Nutr Health Aging 2011;15:433-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Haas S, Bishop D, Dawson B, Goodman C, Edge J. Effects of rest interval during high-repetition resistance training on strength, aerobic fitness, and repeated-sprint ability. J Sports Sci 2007;25:619-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arazi H, Damirchi A, Asadi A. Age-related hormonal adaptations, muscle circumference and strength development with 8 weeks moderate intensity resistance training. Ann Endocrinol (Paris) 2013;74:30-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao CD, Tsauo JY, Wu YT, Cheng CP, Chen HC, Huang YC, et al. Effects of protein supplementation combined with resistance exercise on body composition and physical function in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr 2017;106:1078-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Special topics in statistics. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 5.1.0. The Cochrane Collaboration; 2011. URL: www.cochrane-handbook.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak NM, Res PT, de Groot LC, Saris WH, van Loon LJ. Protein supplementation augments the adaptive response of skeletal muscle to resistance-type exercise training: a meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr 2012;96:1454-64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi YL, Kim BK, Hwang YP, Moon OK, Choi WS. Effects of isometric exercise using biofeedback on maximum voluntary isometric contraction, pain, and muscle thickness in patients with knee osteoarthritis. J Phys Ther Sci 2015;27:149-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden J, Tierney JF, Copas AJ, Burdett S. Quantifying, displaying and accounting for heterogeneity in the meta-analysis of RCTs using standard and generalised Q statistics. BMC Med Res Methodol 2011;11:41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudreuil J, Coudreuse JM, Guyen CN, Deat P, Chabaud A, Pereira B, et al. An algorithm to improve knee orthosis prescription for osteoarthritis patients. Ann Phys Rehabil Med 2016;59 Suppl:e156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ 1997;315:629-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CH, Chen KT, Hou MT, Chang YF, Chang CS, Liu PY, et al. Prevalence and associated factors of sarcopenia and severe sarcopenia in older Taiwanese living in rural community: the Tianliao Old People study 04. Geriatr Gerontol Int 2014;14 Suppl 1:69-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briani RV, Ferreira AS, Pazzinatto MF, Pappas E, De Oliveira Silva D, Azevedo FM. What interventions can improve quality of life or psychosocial factors of individuals with knee osteoarthritis? A systematic review with meta-analysis of primary outcomes from randomised controlled trials. Br J Sports Med 2018;52:1031-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce-Brand RA, Walls RJ, Ong JC, Emerson BS, O&#x2019;Byrne JM, Moyna NM. Effects of home-based resistance training and neuromuscular electrical stimulation in knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2012;13:118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghroubi S, Elleuch H, Kaffel N, Echikh T, Abid M, Elleuch MH. Contribution of exercise and diet in the management of knee osteoarthritis in the obese. Ann Readapt Med Phys 2008;51:663-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;r H, Cakin N, Akova B, Okay E, K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;ko&#x11f;lu S. Concentric versus combined concentric-eccentric isokinetic training: effects on functional capacity and symptoms in patients with osteoarthrosis of the knee. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2002;83:308-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malas F&#xdc;, &#xd6;z&#xe7;akar L, Kaymak B, Ula&#x15f;l&#x131; A, G&#xfc;ner S, Kara M, et al. Effects of different strength training on muscle architecture: clinical and ultrasonographic evaluation in knee osteoarthritis. PM R 2013;5:655-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okoro T, Whitaker R, Gardner A, Maddison P, Andrew JG, Lemmey A. Does an early home-based progressive resistance training program improve function following total hip replacement? Results of a randomized controlled study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2016;17:173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetta C, Aagaard P, Rosted A, Jakobsen AK, Duus B, Kjaer M, et al. Training-induced changes in muscle CSA, muscle strength, EMG, and rate of force development in elderly subjects after long-term unilateral disuse. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2004;97:1954-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetta C, Andersen JL, Dalgas U, Berget J, Koskinen S, Aagaard P, et al. Resistance training induces qualitative changes in muscle morphology, muscle architecture, and muscle function in elderly postoperative patients. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2008;105:180-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsukagoshi R, Tateuchi H, Fukumoto Y, Ibuki S, Akiyama H, So K, et al. Functional performance of female patients more than 6 months after total hip arthroplasty shows greater improvement with weight-bearing exercise than with non-weight-bearing exercise: randomized controlled trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2014;50:665-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walls RJ, McHugh G, O&#x2019;Gorman DJ, Moyna NM, O&#x2019;Byrne JM. Effects of preoperative neuromuscular electrical stimulation on quadriceps strength and functional recovery in total knee arthroplasty: a pilot study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2010;11:119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keogh JW, Grigg J, Vertullo CJ. Is high-intensity interval cycling feasible and more beneficial than continuous cycling for knee osteoarthritic patients? Results of a randomised control feasibility trial. PeerJ 2018;6:e4738.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaStayo PC, Meier W, Marcus RL, Mizner R, Dibble L, Peters C. Reversing muscle and mobility deficits 1 to 4 years after TKA: a pilot study. Clin Orthop Relat Res 2009;467:1493-500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Mihalko SL, Legault C, Miller GD, Nicklas BJ, DeVita P, et al. Effects of intensive diet and exercise on knee joint loads, inflammation, and clinical outcomes among overweight and obese adults with knee osteoarthritis: the IDEA randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2013;310:1263-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheis C, Stoggl T. Strength and mobilization training within the first week following total hip arthroplasty. J Bodyw Mov Ther 2018;22:519-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Tu YK, Wang TG, Huang YT, Chien KL. Effects of resistance training, endurance training and whole-body vibration on lean body mass, muscle strength and physical performance in older people: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Age Ageing 2018;47:367-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart VH, Saunders DH, Greig CA. Responsiveness of muscle size and strength to physical training in very elderly people: a systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2014;24:e1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H, Chen C. Body mass index and risk of knee osteoarthritis: systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective studies. BMJ Open 2015;5:e007568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou ZY, Liu YK, Chen HL, Liu F. Body mass index and knee osteoarthritis risk: a dose-response meta-analysis. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2014;22:2180-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu SC, Yang RS, Yang RJ, Chang SF. Effects of resistance training on body composition and functional capacity among sarcopenic obese residents in long-term care facilities: a preliminary study. BMC Geriatr 2018;18:21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira Silva A, Dutra MT, de Moraes W, Schwerz Funghetto S, Lopes de Farias D, Fernandes dos Santos PH, et al. Resistance training-induced gains in muscle strength, body composition, and functional capacity are attenuated in elderly women with sarcopenic obesity. Clin Interv Aging 2018;13:411-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy J, Chevalier S, Gougeon R, Goulet ED, Morais JA. Effect of obesity and type 2 diabetes on protein anabolic response to insulin in elderly women. Exp Gerontol 2015;69:20-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morais JA, Jacob KW, Chevalier S. Effects of aging and insulin resistant states on protein anabolic responses in older adults. Exp Gerontol 2018;108:262-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart CA, Lee ML, South MA, Howell ME, Stone MH. Muscle hypertrophy in prediabetic men after 16 wk of resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2017;123:894-901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GI, Villareal DT, Sinacore DR, Shah K, Mittendorfer B. Muscle protein synthesis response to exercise training in obese, older men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2012;44:1259-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao CD, Tsauo JY, Huang SW, Ku JW, Hsiao DJ, Liou TH. Effects of elastic band exercise on lean mass and physical capacity in older women with sarcopenic obesity: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep 2018;8:2317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Damas F, Chacon-Mikahil MP, Cavaglieri CR, Ugrinowitsch C, Bottaro M, et al. Time course of resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy in the elderly. J Strength Cond Res 2016;30:159-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JE. The impact of duration on effectiveness of exercise, the implication for periodization of training and goal setting for individuals who are overfat, a meta-analysis. Biol Sport 2016;33:309-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller MS, Callahan DM, Tourville TW, Slauterbeck JR, Kaplan A, Fiske BR, et al. Moderate-intensity resistance exercise alters skeletal muscle molecular and cellular structure and function in inactive older adults with knee osteoarthritis. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2017;122:775-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petterson SC, Barrance P, Marmon AR, Handling T, Buchanan TS, Snyder-Mackler L. Time course of quad strength, area, and activation after knee arthroplasty and strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2011;43:225-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ondr&#xe9;sik M, Azevedo Maia FR, da Silva Morais A, Gertrudes AC, Dias Bacelar AH, Correia C, et al. Management of knee osteoarthritis: current status and future trends. Biotechnol Bioeng 2017;114:717-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks R. Osteoarthritis pain and muscle. SM J Orthop 2016;2:1037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu R, Gartlehner G, Grant M, Shamliyan T, Sedrakyan A, Wilt TJ, et al. Conducting quantitative synthesis when comparing medical interventions: AHRQ and the Effective Health Care Program. J Clin Epidemiol 2011;64:1187-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR. Notes on subgroup analyses and meta-regression. In: Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR, editors. Introduction to meta-analysis. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2009. p. 205-12.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>