<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23241341</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Protein timing and its effects on muscular hypertrophy and strength in individuals engaged in weight-training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>54</StartPage><MedlinePgn>54</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1550-2783-9-54</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this review was to determine whether past research provides conclusive evidence about the effects of type and timing of ingestion of specific sources of protein by those engaged in resistance weight training. Two essential, nutrition-related, tenets need to be followed by weightlifters to maximize muscle hypertrophy: the consumption of 1.2-2.0 g protein.kg -1 of body weight, and &#x2265;44-50 kcal.kg-1 of body weight. Researchers have tested the effects of timing of protein supplement ingestion on various physical changes in weightlifters. In general, protein supplementation pre- and post-workout increases physical performance, training session recovery, lean body mass, muscle hypertrophy, and strength. Specific gains, differ however based on protein type and amounts. Studies on timing of consumption of milk have indicated that fat-free milk post-workout was effective in promoting increases in lean body mass, strength, muscle hypertrophy and decreases in body fat. The leucine content of a protein source has an impact on protein synthesis, and affects muscle hypertrophy. Consumption of 3-4 g of leucine is needed to promote maximum protein synthesis. An ideal supplement following resistance exercise should contain whey protein that provides at least 3 g of leucine per serving. A combination of a fast-acting carbohydrate source such as maltodextrin or glucose should be consumed with the protein source, as leucine cannot modulate protein synthesis as effectively without the presence of insulin. Such a supplement post-workout would be most effective in increasing muscle protein synthesis, resulting in greater muscle hypertrophy and strength. In contrast, the consumption of essential amino acids and dextrose appears to be most effective at evoking protein synthesis prior to rather than following resistance exercise. To further enhance muscle hypertrophy and strength, a resistance weight- training program of at least 10-12 weeks with compound movements for both upper and lower body exercises should be followed.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stark</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Family, Consumer, and Nutrition Sciences, Northern Illinois University, DeKalb, IL, USA. jmlukaszuk@niu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lukaszuk</LastName><ForeName>Judith</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prawitz</LastName><ForeName>Aimee</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salacinski</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23241341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3529694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-9-54</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1550-2783-9-54</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lemon P. Effects of exercise on dietary protein requirements. Int J Sport Nutr. 1998;8:426&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9841962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon PW, Proctor DN. Protein intake and athletic performance. Sports Med. 1991;12:313&#x2013;325. doi: 10.2165/00007256-199112050-00004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-199112050-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1763249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider R. Effects of protein and amino acid supplementation on athletic performance. Sportscience. 1999;3(1)  http://sportsci.org/jour/9901/rbk.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Protein requirements and supplementation in strength sports. Nutrition. 2004;20:689&#x2013;695. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15212752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon PW. Beyond the zone: protein needs of active individuals. J Am Coll Nutr. 2000;19(Suppl):513S&#x2013;521S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11023001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemon PW. In: Sports Supplements. Antonio J, Stout J, editor. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott, Williams, &amp; Wilkins Publishing Co; 1996. Protein requirements of strength athletes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell B, Kreider R, Ziegenfuss T, Bounty P, Roberts M, Burke D, Landis J, Lopez H, Antonio J. International society of sports nutrition position stand: protein and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2007.  Available at:  http://www.jissn.com/content/4/1/8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gropper S, Smith J, Groff J. Advanced Nutrition and Human Metabolism. 5th. California: Wadsworth Cengage Learning; 2009. Protein; pp. 179&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Dietetic Association, Dietitians of Canada, &amp; American College of Sports Medicine. Position stand: nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:2130&#x2013;2145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11128862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimball SR, Jefferson LS. New functions for amino acids: effects on gene transcription and translation. Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;83:500S&#x2013;507S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16470021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony JC, Anthony TG, Kimball SR, Vary TC, Jefferson LS. Orally administered leucine stimulates protein synthesis in skeletal muscle of postabsorptive rats in association with increased eIF4F formation. J Nutr. 2000;130:139&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10720160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony JC, Yoshizawa F, Anthony TG, Vary TC, Jefferson LS, Kimball SR. Leucine stimulates translation initiation in skeletal muscle of postabsorptive rats via a rapamycin-sensitive pathway. J Nutr. 2000;130:2413&#x2013;2419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11015466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton L, Layman D, Garlick P. Isonitrogenous protein sources with different leucine contents differentially effect translation initiation and protein synthesis in skeletal muscle. FASEB J. 2008;22:869&#x2013;875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton L, Layman D, Bunpo P, Anthony T, Brana D, Garlick P. The Leucine content of complete meal directs peak activation but not duration of skeletal muscle protein synthesis and mammalian target of rapamycin signaling in rats. J Nutr. 2009;139(6):1103&#x2013;1109. doi: 10.3945/jn.108.103853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.108.103853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer H, Drummond, Pennings B, Fujita S, Glynn E, Chinkes D, Dhanani S, Volpi E, Rasmussen B. Leucine-enriched essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion following resistance exercise enhances mTOR signaling and protein synthesis in human muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;294:E392&#x2013;E400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2706121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18056791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stipanuk M. Leucine and protein synthesis: mTOR and beyond. Nutr Rev. 2007;65(3):122&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1111/j.1753-4887.2007.tb00289.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1753-4887.2007.tb00289.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17425063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton L, Layman D. Leucine regulates translation initiation of protein synthesis in skeletal muscle after exercise. J Nutr. 2006;136:533S&#x2013;537S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crozier S, Kimball S, Emmert S, Anthony J, Jefferson L. Oral leucine administration stimulates protein synthesis in rat skeletal muscle. J Nutr. 2005;135:376&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hara K, Maruki Y, Long X, Yoshino K-I, Oshiro N, Hidayat S, Tokunaga C, Avruch J, Yonezawa K. Raptor, a binding partner of target of rapamycin (mTOR), mediates TOR action. Cell. 2002;110:177&#x2013;189. doi: 10.1016/S0092-8674(02)00833-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0092-8674(02)00833-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12150926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Sarbassov D, Ali SM, King J, Latek R, Erdjument-Bromage H, Tempst P, Sabatini D. mTOR interacts with raptor to form a nutrient-sensitive complex that signals to the cell growth machinery. Cell. 2002;110:163&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1016/S0092-8674(02)00808-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0092-8674(02)00808-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12150925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton PJ, Babraj J, Smith K, Singh J, Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H. Selective activation of AMPK-PGC-1_ or PKB-TSC2-mTOR signaling can explain specific adaptive responses to endurance or resistance training like electrical muscle stimulation. FASEB J. 2005;19:786&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15716393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar K, Esser K. Phosphorylation of p70S6k correlates with increased skeletal muscle mass following resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 1999;276:C120&#x2013;C127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Wagenmakers A, Manders R, Zorenc A, Senden J, Gorselink M, Keizer H, Loon C. Combined ingestion of protein and free leucine with carbohydrate increases postexercise muscle protein synthesis in vivo in male subjects. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288:E645&#x2013;E653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15562251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulks RM, Li JB, Goldberg AL. Effects of insulin, glucose, and amino acids on protein turnover in rat diaphragm. J Biol Chem. 1975;250:290&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1141208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JB, Jefferson LS. Influence of amino acid availability on protein turnover in perfused skeletal muscle. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1978;544:351&#x2013;359. doi: 10.1016/0304-4165(78)90103-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-4165(78)90103-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">719005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buse MG, Reid SS. Leucine, a possible regulator of protein turnover in muscle. J Clin Invest. 1975;56:1250&#x2013;1261. doi: 10.1172/JCI108201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI108201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC301988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1237498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byfield MP, Murray JT, Backer JM. hVps34 is a nutrient-regulated lipid kinase required for activation of p70 S6 kinase. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:33076&#x2013;33082. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M507201200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M507201200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16049009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobukuni T, Joaquin M, Roccio M, Dann SG, Kim SY, Gulati P, Byfield MP, Backer JM, Natt F, Bos JL, Zwartkruis FJ, Thomas G. Amino acids mediate mTOR/raptor signaling through activation of class 3 phosphatidylinositol 3OH-kinase. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2005;102:14238&#x2013;14243. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0506925102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0506925102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1242323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16176982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D, Sheffield-Moore M, Zhang X, Volpi E, Wolf S, Aarsland A, Ferrando A, Wolfe R. Amino acid ingestion improves muscle protein synthesis in the young and elderly. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;286:E321&#x2013;E328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14583440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton K, Ferrando A, Phillips S, Doyle D, Wolfe R. Postexercise net protein synthesis in human muscle from orally administered amino acids. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E628&#x2013;E634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Tranchina C, Rashti S, Faigenbaum A. Effect of protein-supplement timing on strength, power, and body-composition changes in resistance-trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2009;19(2):172&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Ratamess N, Tranchina C, Rashti S, Kang J, Fiagenbaum A. Effects of a proprietary protein supplement on recovery indices following resistance exercise in strength/power athletes. Amino Acids. 2010;38:771&#x2013;778. doi: 10.1007/s00726-009-0283-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-009-0283-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19347247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb P, Hayes A. Effects of supplement timing and resistance exercise on skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(11):1918&#x2013;1925. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk L, Jonkers R, Gleeson B. Protein supplementation before and after exercise does not further augment skeletal muscle hypertrophy after resistance training in elderly men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89(2):608&#x2013;616. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.2008.26626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2008.26626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19106243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi J, Koyanen V, Selanne H, Kraemer W, Hakkinen K, Mero A. Acute and long-term effects of resistance exercise with or without protein ingestion on muscle hypertrophy and gene expression. Amino Acids. 2009;37:297&#x2013;308. doi: 10.1007/s00726-008-0150-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-008-0150-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18661258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen L, Tufekovic G, Zebis M, Crameri R, Verlaan G, Kjaer M, Suetta C, Magnusson P, Aagaard P. The effect of resistance training combined with timed ingestion of protein on muscle fiber size and muscle strength. Metabolism. 2005;54:151&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1016/j.metabol.2004.07.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2004.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15690307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliot T, Cree M, Sanford A, Wolfe R, Tipton K. Milk ingestion stimulates net muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(4):667&#x2013;674. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman J, Tang J, Wilkinson S, Tarnopolsky M, Lawrence R, Fullerton A, Phillips S. Consumption of fat-free fluid milk after resistance exercise promotes greater lean mass accretion than does consumption of soy or carbohydrate in young, novice, male weightlifters. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;86(2):373&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson S, Tarnopolsky M, MacDonald M, MacDonald J, Armstrong D, Phillips S. Consumption of fluid skim milk promotes greater muscle protein accretion after resistance exercise than does consumption of an isonitrogenous and isoenergetic soy-protein beverage. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;85(4):1031&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17413102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin J, Goldman L, Puglisi M, Nickols-Richardson S, Earthman C, Gwazdauskas F. Effect of post-exercise supplement consumption on adaptations to resistance training. J Am Coll Nutr. 2004;4(23):322&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15310736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse A, Tang J, Tarnopolsky M, Phillips S. Body composition and strength changes in women with milk and resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(6):1122&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19997019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J, Moore D, Kujbida G, Tarnopolsky M, Phillips S. Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(3):987&#x2013;992. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton L, Wilson G, Layman D, Moulton C, Garlick P. Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men. Nutr Metab. 2012;9:67. doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-9-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-9-67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman J, Falvo M. Protein&#x2014;which is best? J Sports Sci Med. 2004;3:118&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3905294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boirie Y, Dangin M, Gachon P, Vasson MP, Maubois JL, Beaufrere B. Slow and fast dietary proteins differently modulate postprandial accretion. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 1997;94:14930&#x2013;14935. doi: 10.1073/pnas.94.26.14930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.94.26.14930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC25140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9405716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton K, Elliot T, Cree M, Wolf S, Sanford A, Wolfe R. Ingestion of casein and whey proteins result in muscle anabolism after resistance exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2004;36:2073&#x2013;2081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15570142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Rasmussen BB, Miller SL, Wolf SE, Owens-Stovall SK, Petrini BE, Wolfe RR. Timing of amino acid-carbohydrate ingestion alters anabolic response of muscle to resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2001;281:E197&#x2013;E206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11440894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton K, Elliott T, Cree M, Aarsland A, Sanford A, Wolfe R. Stimulation of net muscle protein synthesis by whey protein ingestion before and after exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007;292:E71&#x2013;E76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16896166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>