<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32740287</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Blood Flow Restriction at High Resistance Loads Increases the Rate of Muscular Fatigue, but Does Not Increase Plasma Markers of Myotrauma or Inflammation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2419</StartPage><EndPage>2426</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2419-2426</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003742</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Winchester, LJ, Morris, CE, Badinger, J, Wiczynski, TL, and VanWye, WR. Blood flow restriction at high resistance loads increases the rate of muscular fatigue, but does not increase plasma markers of myotrauma or inflammation. J Strength Cond Res 34(9): 2419-2426, 2020-High-load resistance training and blood flow restriction (BFR) training at low loads both promote protein synthesis and growth through different cell signaling mechanisms. Therefore, co-activation of these pathways could result in a synergistic effect for additional growth enhancement. The purpose of this study was to evaluate how BFR effects performance and physiological responses after an acute bout of high-load barbell squat training. Twelve resistance-trained, college-aged men and women performed 5 sets of barbell squats at 75% of 1 repetition maximum until failure under traditional (TRAD; control) or intermittent BFR conditions. Perceived limb pain and number of repetitions performed were recorded after each set. Blood samples were collected at baseline and 1-hour postexercise after each trial for analysis of myoglobin and interleukin-6 (IL-6). An alpha level of p &lt; 0.05 was used to determine significance. Blood flow restriction trial performance significantly declined at set 3 and was lower than performance during control, whereas control performance did not decrease until set 5. Perceived limb pain was statistically increased with BFR use for the whole trial and was significantly higher with BFR during set 3 than observed during TRAD. Plasma myoglobin and IL-6 were significantly increased after both trials when compared with baseline, but were not significantly different between trials. Intermittent BFR use during high-load barbell squats increases the rate of muscular fatigue and perceived limb pain, but does not increase muscular damage or inflammatory response. Data obtained from this study can be used by fitness professionals as a means of potentially enhancing the rate of muscular hypertrophy.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Winchester</LastName><ForeName>Lee J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morris</LastName><ForeName>Cody E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Studies, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badinger</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Western Kentucky University, Bowling Green, Kentucky; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiczynski</LastName><ForeName>Teresa L</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Western Kentucky University, Bowling Green, Kentucky; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>VanWye</LastName><ForeName>William R</ForeName><Initials>WR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Program, Gannon University, Ruskin, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006439" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32740287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202009000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Sato Y. Muscle size and strength are increased following walk training with restricted venous blood flow from the leg muscle, Kaatsu-walk training. J Appl Physiol 100: 1460&#x2013;1466, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Yasuda T, Midorikawa T, et al. Skeletal muscle size and circulating IGF-1 are increased after two weeks of twice daily &#x201c;KAATSU&#x201d; resistance training. Int J KAATSU Train Res 1: 6&#x2013;12, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameln H, Gustafsson T, Sundberg CJ, et al. Physiological activation of hypoxia inducible factor-1 in human skeletal muscle. FASEB J 19: 1009&#x2013;1011, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balnave C, Thompson M. Effect of training on eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage. J Appl Physiol 75: 1545&#x2013;1551, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton ER, Morris L, Musaro A, Rosenthal N, Sweeney HL. Muscle-specific expression of insulin-like growth factor I counters muscle decline in mdx mice. J Cell Biol 157: 137&#x2013;148, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 50&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Gatta PA, Cameron-Smith D, Peake JM. Acute resistance exercise increases the expression of chemotactic factors within skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 2157&#x2013;2167, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitschen PJ, Kistler BM, Jeong JH, et al. Perceptual effects and efficacy of intermittent or continuous blood flow restriction resistance training. Clin Physiol Funct I 34: 356&#x2013;363, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flann KL, LaStayo PC, McClain DA, Hazel M, Lindstedt SL. Muscle damage and muscle remodeling: No pain, no gain? J Exp Biol 214: 674&#x2013;679, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frigeri A, Nicchia GP, Verbavatz JM, Valenti G, Svelto M. Expression of aquaporin-4 in fast-twitch fibers of mammalian skeletal muscle. J Clin Invest 102: 695&#x2013;703, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Appl Physiol 108: 1199&#x2013;1209, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol 103: 903&#x2013;910, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita T, Brechue WF, Kurita K, Sato Y, Abe T. Increased muscle volume and strength following six days of low-intensity resistance training with restricted muscle blood flow. Int J KAATSU Train Res 4: 1&#x2013;8, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill M, Goldspink G. Expression and splicing of the insulin-like growth factor gene in rodent muscle is associated with muscle satellite (stem) cell activation following local tissue damage. J Physiol 549: 409&#x2013;418, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiscock N, Chan MS, Bisucci T, Darby IA, Febbraio MA. Skeletal myocytes are a source of interleukin-6 mRNA expression and protein release during contraction: Evidence of fiber type specificity. FASEB J 18: 992&#x2013;994, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kefaloyianni E, Gaitanaki C, Beis I. ERK1/2 and p38-MAPK signalling pathways, through MSK1, are involved in NF-kappaB transactivation during oxidative stress in skeletal myoblasts. Cell Signal 18: 2238&#x2013;2251, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ikeda T, Homma T, Suzuki Y. Effects of low-intensity resistance exercise under acute systemic hypoxia on hormonal responses. J Strength Cond Res 26: 611&#x2013;617, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmidou I, Vassilakopoulos T, Xagorari A, et al. Production of interleukin-6 by skeletal myotubes: Role of reactive oxygen species. Am J Resp Cell Mol 26: 587&#x2013;593, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: Progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: 674&#x2013;688, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaStayo P, McDonagh P, Lipovic D, et al. Elderly patients and high force resistance exercise&#x2014;a descriptive report: Can an anabolic, muscle growth response occur without muscle damage or inflammation? J Geriatr Phys Ther 30: 128&#x2013;134, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Balapur A, Thrower AD, Barnes JT, Pujol TJ. The perceptual responses to occluded exercise. Int J Sports Med 32: 181&#x2013;184, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Abe T, Bemben MG. The anabolic benefits of venous blood flow restriction training may be induced by muscle cell swelling. Med Hypotheses 78: 151&#x2013;154, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Zourdos MC, Bemben MG. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: A meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1849&#x2013;1859, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medicine ACoS. Preparticipation health screening. In: ACSM's Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2013. pp. 26&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozcan A, Donat H, Gelecek N, Ozdirenc M, Karadibak D. The relationship between risk factors for falling and the quality of life in older adults. BMC Public Health 5: 90, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol 10: 533, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peake JM, Suzuki K, Wilson G, et al. Exercise-induced muscle damage, plasma cytokines, and markers of neutrophil activation. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 737&#x2013;745, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ, Hussain SR. A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med 45: 187&#x2013;200, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson RS, Wagner H, Mudaliar SR, et al. Human VEGF gene expression in skeletal muscle: Effect of acute normoxic and hypoxic exercise. Am J Physiol 277: H2247&#x2013;H2252, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Does exercise-induced muscle damage play a role in skeletal muscle hypertrophy?. J Strength Cond Res 26: 1441&#x2013;1453, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med 43: 179&#x2013;194, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano AL, Baeza-Raja B, Perdiguero E, Jard&#xed; M, Mu&#xf1;oz-C&#xe1;noves P. Interleukin-6 is an essential regulator of satellite cell-mediated skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell Metab 7: 33&#x2013;44, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard JM, Triplett NT, Haff GG, Triplett NT. Program design for resistance training. In: Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning (4th ed). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2015. pp. 453&#x2013;456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sjogaard G, Adams RP, Saltin B. Water and ion shifts in skeletal muscle of humans with intense dynamic knee extension. Am J Physiol 248: R190&#x2013;R196, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Morita N, et al. Intramuscular metabolism during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol 106: 1119&#x2013;1124, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, et al. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol 88: 61&#x2013;65, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidball JG. Mechanical signal transduction in skeletal muscle growth and adaptation. J Appl Physiol 98: 1900&#x2013;1908, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vierck J, O'Reilly B, Hossner K, et al. Satellite cell regulation following myotrauma caused by resistance exercise. Cell Biol Int 24: 263&#x2013;272, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Jarrebring R, Andreasson MA, Augustsson J. Acute effects of blood flow restriction on muscle activity and endurance during fatiguing dynamic knee extensions at low load. J Strength Cond Res 23: 2389&#x2013;2395, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, VanEnk C, Taylor L. Effects of concentric and eccentric contractions on exercise induced muscle injury, inflammation, and serum IL-6. J Exerc Physiol Online 6: 8&#x2013;15, 2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfson L, Judge J, Whipple R, King M. Strength is a major factor in balance, gait, and the occurrence of falls. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 50: 64&#x2013;67, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright HL, Cross AL, Edwards SW, Moots RJ. Effects of IL-6 and IL-6 blockade on neutrophil function in vitro and in vivo. Rheumatology 53: 1321&#x2013;1331, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Abe T, Sato Y, et al. Muscle fiber cross-sectional area is increased after two weeks of twice daily KAATSU-resistance training. Int J KAATSU Train Res 1: 65&#x2013;70, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou K, Meador BM, Johnson B, et al. The &#x3b1;7&#x3b2;1-integrin increases muscle hypertrophy following multiple bouts of eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol 111: 1134&#x2013;1141, 2011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>