<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32740889</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Resistance Training on Muscle Size and Strength in Very Elderly Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1983</StartPage><EndPage>1999</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1983-1999</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-020-01331-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Effects of resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy are well established in adults and younger elderly. However, less is currently known about these effects in the very elderly (i.e., 75&#xa0;years of age and older).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine the effects of resistance training on muscle size and strength in very elderly individuals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Randomized controlled studies that explored the effects of resistance training in very elderly on muscle strength, handgrip strength, whole-muscle hypertrophy, and/or muscle fiber hypertrophy were included in the review. Meta-analyses of effect sizes (ESs) were used to analyze the data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-two studies were included in the review. The meta-analysis found a significant effect of resistance training on muscle strength in the very elderly [difference in ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.97; 95% confidence interval (CI) 0.50, 1.44; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001]. In a subgroup analysis that included only the oldest-old participants (80&#x2009;+&#x2009;years of age), there was a significant effect of resistance training on muscle strength (difference in ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.28; 95% CI 0.28, 2.29; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.020). For handgrip strength, we found no significant difference between resistance training and control groups (difference in ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.26; 95% CI -&#xa0;0.02, 0.54; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.064). For whole-muscle hypertrophy, there was a significant effect of resistance training in the very elderly (difference in ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0 30; 95% CI 0.10, 0.50; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.013). We found no significant difference in muscle fiber hypertrophy between resistance training and control groups (difference in ES&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.33; 95% CI -&#xa0;0.67, 1.33; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.266). There were minimal reports of adverse events associated with the training programs in the included studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We found that very elderly can increase muscle strength and muscle size by participating in resistance training programs. Resistance training was found to be an effective way to improve muscle strength even among the oldest-old.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grgic</LastName><ForeName>Jozo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport (IHES), Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia. jozo.grgic@live.vu.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garofolini</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport (IHES), Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orazem</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Human Services and Nursing, Lehman College, Bronx, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabol</LastName><ForeName>Filip</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fitness Academy, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Lehman College, Bronx, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedisic</LastName><ForeName>Zeljko</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport (IHES), Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32740889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01331-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-020-01331-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM. What is dynapenia? Nutrition. 2012;28:495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22469110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3571692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M, Deeg DJ, Lips P, et al. Skeletal muscle mass and muscle strength in relation to lower-extremity performance in older men and women. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2000;48:381&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10798463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Kupelian V, Visser M, et al. Strength, but not muscle mass, is associated with mortality in the health, aging and body composition study cohort. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61:72&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">16456196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM. Functional consequences of sarcopenia and dynapenia in the elderly. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2010;13:271&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20154609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2895460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48:16&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faigenbaum AD, Kraemer WJ, Blimkie CJ, et al. Youth resistance training: updated position statement paper from the national strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:S60&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19620931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CJ, Latham NK. Progressive resistance strength training for improving physical function in older adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2009;3:002759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the National Strength and Conditioning Association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2019&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouchi Y, Rakugi H, Arai H, et al. Redefining the elderly as aged 75 years and older: proposal from the Joint Committee of Japan Gerontological Society and the Japan Geriatrics Society. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2017;17:1045&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28670849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart VH, Saunders DH, Greig CA. Responsiveness of muscle size and strength to physical training in very elderly people: a systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:e1&#x2013;.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24151875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. A brief review of critical processes in exercise-induced muscular hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2014;44:71&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4008813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Gorissen SH, van Loon LJ. Anabolic resistance of muscle protein synthesis with aging. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2013;41:169&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23558692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim JS, Mayhew DL, et al. Potent myofiber hypertrophy during resistance training in humans is associated with satellite cell-mediated myonuclear addition: a cluster analysis. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104:1736&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim JS, Cross JM, et al. Efficacy of myonuclear addition may explain differential myofiber growth among resistance-trained young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291:E937&#x2013;E946946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsen A, Bechsh&#xf8;ft RL, Malmgaard-Clausen NM, et al. Lack of muscle fibre hypertrophy, myonuclear addition, and satellite cell pool expansion with resistance training in 83&#x2013;94-year-old men and women. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2019;227:e13271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Gustafsson T. Fibre hypertrophy, satellite cell and myonuclear adaptations to resistance training: have very old individuals reached the ceiling for muscle fibre plasticity? Acta Physiol. 2019;227:e13287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ, Vandervoort AA, Brown WF. Effects of ageing on the motor unit: a brief review. Can J Appl Physiol. 1993;18:331&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8275048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ, Vandervoort AA, Taylor AW, et al. Effects of motor unit losses on strength in older men and women. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74:868&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8458808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiatarone MA, Marks EC, Ryan ND, et al. High-intensity strength training in nonagenarians. Effects on skeletal muscle. JAMA. 1990;263:3029&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2342214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruunsgaard H, Bjerregaard E, Schroll M, et al. Muscle strength after resistance training is inversely correlated with baseline levels of soluble tumor necrosis factor receptors in the oldest old. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004;52:237&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14728633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caserotti P, Aagaard P, Larsen JB, et al. Explosive heavy-resistance training in old and very old adults: changes in rapid muscle force, strength and power. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2008;18:773&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18248533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gin&#xe9;-Garriga M, Guerra M, Pag&#xe8;s E, et al. The effect of functional circuit training on physical frailty in frail older adults: a randomized controlled trial. J Aging Phys Act. 2010;18:401&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hruda KV, Hicks AL, McCartney N. Training for muscle power in older adults: effects on functional abilities. Can J Appl Physiol. 2003;28:178&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12825328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judge JO, Whipple RH, Wolfson LI. Effects of resistive and balance exercises on isokinetic strength in older persons. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1994;42:937&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8064101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalapotharakos VI, Diamantopoulos K, Tokmakidis SP. Effects of resistance training and detraining on muscle strength and functional performance of older adults aged 80 to 88 years. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2010;22:134&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20440099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HK, Suzuki T, Saito K, et al. Effects of exercise and amino acid supplementation on body composition and physical function in community-dwelling elderly Japanese sarcopenic women: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2012;60:16&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22142410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Rexach JA, Bustamante-Ara N, Hierro Villar&#xe1;n M, et al. Short-term, light- to moderate-intensity exercise training improves leg muscle strength in the oldest old: a randomized controlled trial. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2011;59:594&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21453381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelton DA, Young A, Greig CA, et al. Effects of resistance training on strength, power, and selected functional abilities of women aged 75 and older. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1995;43:1081&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7560695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechsh&#xf8;ft RL, Malmgaard-Clausen NM, Gliese B, et al. Improved skeletal muscle mass and strength after heavy strength training in very old individuals. Exp Gerontol. 2017;92:96&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benavent-Caballer V, Rosado-Calatayud P, Segura-Ort&#xed; E, et al. Effects of three different low-intensity exercise interventions on physical performance, muscle CSA and activities of daily living: a randomized controlled trial. Exp Gerontol. 2014;58:159&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25131453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Casas-Herrero A, Zambom-Ferraresi F, et al. Multicomponent exercises including muscle power training enhance muscle mass, power output, and functional outcomes in institutionalized frail nonagenarians. Age (Dordr). 2014;36:773&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Suzuki T, Kim M, et al. Effects of exercise and milk fat globule membrane (MFGM) supplementation on body composition, physical function, and hematological parameters in community-dwelling frail Japanese women: a randomized double blind, placebo-controlled, follow-up trial. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0116256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25659147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4319727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin UK, Kirdi N, Bozoglu E, et al. Effect of low-intensity versus high-intensity resistance training on the functioning of the institutionalized frail elderly. Int J Rehabil Res. 2018;41:211&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29620558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen K, Doblhammer G, Rau R, et al. Ageing populations: the challenges ahead. Lancet. 2009;374:1196&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2810516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2810516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Health Statistics. Survey description, national health interview survey, 2015. Hyattsville: National Center for Health Statistics; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151:264&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">19622511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA. The role of progressive resistance training and nutrition in the preservation of lean body mass in the elderly. J Am Coll Nutr. 1995;14:587&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8598419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guizelini PC, de Aguiar RA, Denadai BS, et al. Effect of resistance training on muscle strength and rate of force development in healthy older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Exp Gerontol. 2018;102:51&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29196141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberman K, Forti LN, Beyer I, et al. The effects of exercise on muscle strength, body composition, physical functioning and the inflammatory profile of older adults: a systematic review. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2017;20:30&#x2013;533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27755209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter MM. High-intensity strength training for the older adult&#x2014;a review. Top Geriatr Rehabil. 1995;10:61&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steib S, Schoene D, Pfeifer K. Dose-response relationship of resistance training in older adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:902&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straight CR, Lindheimer JB, Brady AO, et al. Effects of resistance training on lower-extremity muscle power in middle-aged and older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Med. 2016;46:353&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26545362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs SH, Black N. The feasibility of creating a checklist for the assessment of the methodological quality both of randomised and non-randomised studies of health care interventions. J Epidemiol Community Health. 1998;52:377&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9764259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1756728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, et al. Effect of resistance training frequency on gains in muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:1207&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, et al. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018;48:137&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris B. Estimating effect sizes from pretest&#x2013;posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods. 2008;11:364&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner-Smith EE, Tipton E, Polanin JR. Handling complex meta-analytic data structures using robust variance estimates: a tutorial in R. J Dev Life Course Criminol. 2016;2:85&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki H, Kasagi F, Yamada M, et al. Grip strength predicts cause-specific mortality in middle-aged and elderly persons. Am J Med. 2007;120:337&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17398228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher Z, Tipton E, Zhipeng H. robumeta: robust variance meta-regression. R package version 2.0. 2017. https://www.CRAN.R-project.org/package=robumeta . Accessed 1 Feb 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. J Stat Softw. 2010;36:1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiatarone MA, O'Neill EF, Ryan ND, et al. Exercise training and nutritional supplementation for physical frailty in very elderly people. N Engl J Med. 1994;330:1769&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8190152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiatarone Singh MA, Ding W, Manfredi TJ, et al. Insulin-like growth factor I in skeletal muscle after weight-lifting exercise in frail elders. Am J Physiol. 1999;277:E135&#x2013;E143143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipil&#xe4; S, Suominen H. Effects of strength and endurance training on thigh and leg muscle mass and composition in elderly women. J Appl Physiol. 1995;78:334&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7713834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipil&#xe4; S, Multanen J, Kallinen M, et al. Effects of strength and endurance training on isometric muscle strength and walking speed in elderly women. Acta Physiol Scand. 1996;156:457&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8732251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipil&#xe4; S, Elorinne M, Alen M, et al. Effects of strength and endurance training on muscle fibre characteristics in elderly women. Clin Physiol. 1997;17:459&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9347195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hvid LG, Strotmeyer ES, Skj&#xf8;dt M, et al. Voluntary muscle activation improves with power training and is associated with changes in gait speed in mobility-limited older adults&#x2014;a randomized controlled trial. Exp Gerontol. 2016;80:51&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27090485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Suzuki T, Saito K, et al. Effects of exercise and tea catechins on muscle mass, strength and walking ability in community-dwelling elderly Japanese sarcopenic women: a randomized controlled trial. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2013;13:458&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22935006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue QL, Beamer BA, Chaves PH, et al. Heterogeneity in rate of decline in grip, hip, and knee strength and the risk of all-cause mortality: the women&#x2019;s health and aging study II. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010;58:2076&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21054287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3058914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell WK, Williams J, Atherton P, et al. Sarcopenia, dynapenia, and the impact of advancing age on human skeletal muscle size and strength; a quantitative review. Front Physiol. 2012;3:260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22934016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3429036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Park SW, Harris TB, et al. The loss of skeletal muscle strength, mass, and quality in older adults: the health, aging and body composition study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61:1059&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17077199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico MJ, Harris TB, Visser M, et al. Longitudinal study of muscle strength, quality, and adipose tissue infiltration. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;90:1579&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2777469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreland JD, Richardson JA, Goldsmith CH, et al. Muscle weakness and falls in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004;52:1121&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15209650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin J, Lawton T, Harris N, et al. A brief review of handgrip strength and sport performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:3187&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28820854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saric J, Lisica D, Orlic I, et al. Resistance training frequencies of 3 and 6 times per week produce similar muscular adaptations in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:S122&#x2013;S129129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale D, MacDougall D. Specificity in strength training: a review for the coach and athlete. Can J Appl Sport Sci. 1981;6:87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7016357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tieland M, Verdijk LB, de Groot LC, et al. Handgrip strength does not represent an appropriate measure to evaluate changes in muscle strength during an exercise intervention program in frail older people. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2015;25:27&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24903908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Dankel SJ, Bell ZW, Abe T, Loenneke JP. The association of handgrip strength and mortality: what does it tell us and what can we do with it? Rejuvenation Res. 2019;22:230&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30200809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgartner RN, Koehler KM, Gallagher D, et al. Epidemiology of sarcopenia among the elderly in New Mexico. Am J Epidemiol. 1998;147:755&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9554417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson W, Breen L, Lord JM, et al. The challenges of muscle biopsy in a community based geriatric population. BMC Res Notes. 2018;11:830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30477571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6260758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton E, Farrier K, Lewin G, et al. Motivators and barriers for older people participating in resistance training: a systematic review. J Aging Phys Act. 2017;25:311&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27620535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Bottaro M. Effects of training attendance on muscle strength of young men after 11 weeks of resistance training. Asian J Sports Med. 2013;4:101&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3690729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, et al. Determining strength: a case for multiple methods of measurement. Sports Med. 2017;47:193&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, et al. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>