<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31108025</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-1716</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>228</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta physiologica (Oxford, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Physiol (Oxf)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Muscle fibre activation and fatigue with low-load blood flow restricted resistance exercise-An integrative physiology review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13302</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13302</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/apha.13302</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Blood flow-restricted resistance exercise (BFRRE) has been shown to induce increases in muscle size and strength, and continues to generate interest from both clinical and basic research points of view. The low loads employed, typically 20%-50% of the one repetition maximum, make BFRRE an attractive training modality for individuals who may not tolerate high musculoskeletal forces (eg, selected clinical patient groups such as frail old adults and patients recovering from sports injury) and/or for highly trained athletes who have reached a plateau in muscle mass and strength. It has been proposed that achieving a high degree of muscle fibre recruitment is important for inducing muscle hypertrophy with BFRRE, and the available evidence suggest that fatiguing low-load exercise during ischemic conditions can recruit both slow (type I) and fast (type II) muscle fibres. Nevertheless, closer scrutiny reveals that type II fibre activation in BFRRE has to date largely been inferred using indirect methods such as electromyography and magnetic resonance spectroscopy, while only rarely addressed using more direct methods such as measurements of glycogen stores and phosphocreatine levels in muscle fibres. Hence, considerable uncertainity exists about the specific pattern of muscle fibre activation during BFRRE. Therefore, the purpose of this narrative review was (1) to summarize the evidence on muscle fibre recruitment during BFRRE as revealed by various methods employed for determining muscle fibre usage during exercise, and (2) to discuss reported findings in light of the specific advantages and limitations associated with these methods.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Scandinavian Physiological Society. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wernbom</LastName><ForeName>Mathias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0411-3611</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health and Performance, Department of Food and Nutrition and Sport Science, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aagaard</LastName><ForeName>Per</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Sciences and Clinical Biomechanics, SDU Muscle Research Cluster (SMRC), University of Southern Denmark, Odense M, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Physiol (Oxf)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101262545</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-1708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood supply</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor units</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occlusion</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31108025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.13302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Tanaka Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:2097-2106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:406-412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellefsen S, Hammarstr&#xf6;m D, Strand TA, et al. Blood flow-restricted strength training displays high functional and biological efficacy in women: a within-subject comparison with high-load strength training. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2015;309:R767-R779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:361-378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Raastad T. Ischemic strength training: a low-load alternative to heavy resistance exercise? Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2008;18:401-416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1003-1011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Thiebaud RS, Bemben MG. Exercise intensity and muscle hypertrophy in blood flow-restricted limbs and non-restricted muscles: a brief review. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2012;32:247-252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, de Paoli F, Bjerg K, Riis S, Ringgard S, Vissing K. Blood flow restricted and traditional resistance training performed to fatigue produce equal muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25:754-763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Takada S, et al. Effect of multiple set on intramuscular metabolic stress during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:3915-3920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada S, Okita K, Suga T, et al. Low-intensity exercise can increase muscle mass and strength proportionally to enhanced metabolic stress under ischemic conditions. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:199-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Andersen JL, Dyhre-Poulsen P, et al. A mechanism for increased contractile strength of human pennate muscle in response to strength training: changes in muscle architecture. J Physiol. 2001;534:613-623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim J-S, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:531-544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetta C, Andersen JL, Dalgas U, et al. Resistance training induces qualitative changes in muscle morphology, muscle architecture, and muscle function in elderly postoperative patients. J Appl Physiol. 2008;105:180-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsen MD, Sundstrup E, Randers MB, et al. The effect of strength training, recreational soccer and running exercise on stretch-shortening cycle muscle performance during countermovement jumping. Hum Mov Sci. 2012;31:970-986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faulkner JA, Claflin DR, McCully KK. Power output of fast and slow fibers from human skeletal muscle. In: Jones NL, McCartney N, McComas AJ, eds. Human Muscle Power. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1986:81-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, et al. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Physiol. 2012;590:4351-4361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Sherman WM, Shibata M, Matsumoto T, Shinohara M. Oxygen availability and motor unit activity in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1992;64:552-556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:61-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, J&#xe4;rrebring R, Andreasson MA, Augustsson J. Acute effects of blood flow restriction on muscle activity and endurance during fatiguing dynamic knee extensions at low load. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:2389-2395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, S&#xf6;derlund K, Relu MU, Ferguson RA, Bangsbo J. Heterogeneous recruitment of quadriceps muscle portions and fibre types during moderate intensity knee-extensor exercise: effect of thigh occlusion. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2009;19:576-584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumming KT, Paulsen G, Wernbom M, et al. Acute response and subcellular movement of HSP27, &#x3b1;B-crystallin and HSP70 in human skeletal muscle after blood-flow-restricted low-load resistance exercise. Acta Physiol. 2014;211:634-646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsgaard JE, Christiansen M, Sieljacks P, et al. Impact of blood flow-restricted bodyweight exercise on skeletal muscle adaptations. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2018;38(6):965-975. https://doi.org/10.1111/cpf.12509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnsen T, Wernbom M, Kirketeig A, et al. Type 1 muscle fiber hypertrophy after blood flow-restricted training in powerlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:288-298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnsen T, Wernbom M, L&#xf8;vstad A, et al. Delayed myonuclear addition, myofiber hypertrophy and increases in strength with high-frequency low-load blood flow restricted training to volitional failure. J Appl Physiol. 2019;126:578-592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumide T, Sakuraba K, Sawaki K, Ohmura H, Tamura Y. Effect of resistance exercise training combined with relatively low vascular occlusion. J Sci Med Sport. 2009;12:107-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinohara M, Kouzaki M, Yoshihisa T, Fukunaga T. Efficacy of tourniquet ischemia for strength training with low resistance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1998;77:189-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T. Motor unit and motoneurone excitability during explosive movement. In: Komi P, ed. Strength and Power in Sport. 2nd ed. Oxford: Blackwell Science; 2003:27-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Semmler JG, Enoka RM. Training adaptations in the behavior of human motor units. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:1766-1775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalmers GR. Can fast-twitch muscle fibres be selectively recruited during lengthening contractions? Review and applications to sport movements. Sports Biomech. 2008;7:137-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heckman CJ, Enoka RM. Motor unit. Compr Physiol. 2012;2:2629-2682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE, Levine DN, Zajac FE 3rd, Tsairis P, Engel WK. Mammalian motor units: physiological-histochemical correlation in three types in cat gastrocnemius. Science. 1971;174(4010):709-712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE, Levine DN, Tsairis P, Zajac FE 3rd. Physiological types and histochemical profiles in motor units of the cat gastrocnemius. J Physiol. 1973;234:723-748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edstr&#xf6;m L, Grimby L. Effect of exercise on the motor unit. Muscle Nerve. 1986;9:104-126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh JC, Binder MD, Reinking RM, Stuart DG. Tetrapartite classification of motor units of cat tibialis posterior. J Neurophysiol. 1980;44:696-712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE. The structure and function of motor units. In: Karpati G, Hilton D, Griggs RC, eds. Disorders of Voluntary Muscle, 7th ed. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2001:3-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RE. Some unresolved issues in motor unit research. In: Gandevia S, Proske U, Stuart DG, eds. Sensorimotor Control of Movement and Posture. New York: Kluwer Academic/Plenum Press; 2002:171-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garnett RA, O'Donovan MJ, Stephens JA, Taylor A. Motor unit organization of human medial gastrocnemius. J Physiol. 1979;287:33-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchthal F, Schmalbruch H. Contraction times and fibre types in intact human muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1970;79:435-452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ennion S, Sant'Ana Pereira J, Sargeant AJ, Young A, Goldspink G. Characterization of human skeletal muscle fibres according to the myosin heavy chains they express. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 1995;16:35-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sant'Ana Pereira JA, Sargeant AJ, Rademaker AC, de Haan A, van Mechelen W. Myosin heavy chain isoform expression and high energy phosphate content in human muscle fibres at rest and post-exercise. J Physiol. 1996;496:583-588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron RS, Herman JR, Schuenke MD. Misclassification of hybrid fast fibers in resistance-trained human skeletal muscle using histochemical and immunohistochemical methods. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:2616-2622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Influence of exercise and training on motor unit activation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1987;15:95-151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntosh BR, Gardiner PF, McComas AJ. Skeletal Muscle: Form and Function. 2nd ed. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2006:195-207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron RS. Human skeletal muscle fiber types: delineation, development, and distribution. Can J Appl Physiol. 1997;22:307-327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen JL, Klitgaard H, Saltin B. Myosin heavy chain isoforms in single fibres from m. vastus lateralis of sprinters: influence of training. Acta Physiol Scand. 1994;151:135-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen JL, Aagaard P. Myosin heavy chain IIX overshoot in human skeletal muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23:1095-1104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klitgaard H, Zhou M, Richter EA. Myosin heavy chain composition of single fibres from m. biceps brachii of male body builders. Acta Physiol Scand. 1990;140:175-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sant'Ana Pereira JA, Wessels A, Nijtmans L, Moorman AFM, Sargeant AJ. New method for the accurate characterization of single human skeletal muscle fibres demonstrates a relation between mATPase and MyHC expression in pure and hybrid fibre types. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 1995;16:21-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karatzaferi C, de Haan A, Ferguson R, van Mechelen W, Sargeant A. Phosphocreatine and ATP content in human single muscle fibres before and after maximum dynamic exercise. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch. 2001;442:467-474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prats C, Gomez-Cabello A, Nordby P, et al. An optimized histochemical method to assess skeletal muscle glycogen and lipid stores reveals two metabolically distinct populations of type I muscle fibers. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(10):e77774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ess&#xe9;n B, Jansson E, Henriksson J, Taylor AW, Saltin B. Metabolic characteristics of fibre types in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1975;95:153-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, S&#xf6;derlund K, Ren JM, Hultman E. Energy metabolism in single human muscle fibres during intermittent contraction with occluded circulation. J Physiol. 1993;460:443-453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Nevill ME, Soderlund K, et al. The metabolic responses of human type I and II muscle fibres during maximal treadmill sprinting. J Physiol. 1994;478:149-155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E. Relation between size of neurons and their susceptibility to discharge. Science. 1957;126:1345-1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E, Somjen G, Carpenter DO. Functional significance of cell size in spinal motoneurons. J Neurophysiol. 1965;28:560-580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner-Brown HS, Stein RB, Yemm R. The orderly recruitment of human motor units during voluntary isometric contractions. J Physiol. 1973;230:359-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freund HJ, B&#xfc;dingen HJ, Dietz V. Activity of single motor units from human forearm muscles during voluntary isometric contractions. J Neurophysiol. 1975;38:933-946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monster AW, Chan H. Isometric force production by motor units of extensor digitorum communis muscle in man. J Neurophysiol. 1977;40:1432-1443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens JA, Usherwood TP. The mechanical properties of human motor units with special reference to their fatiguability and recruitment threshold. Brain Res. 1977;125:91-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desmedt JE, Godaux E. Ballistic contractions in man: characteristic recruitment pattern of single motor units of the tibialis anterior muscle. J Physiol. 1977;264:673-693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garnett R, Stephens JA. Changes in the recruitment threshold of motor units produced by cutaneous stimulation in man. J Physiol. 1981;311:463-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calancie B, Bawa P. Recruitment order of motor units during the stretch reflex in man. Brain Res. 1984;292:176-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bawa P, Lemon RN. Recruitment of motor units in response to transcranial magnetic stimulation in man. J Physiol. 1993;471:445-464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Fuglevand AJ. Motor unit physiology: some unresolved issues. Muscle Nerve. 2001;24:4-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannerz J. Discharge properties of motor units in relation to recruitment order in voluntary contraction. Acta Physiol Scand. 1974;91:374-385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukulka CG, Clamann HP. Comparison of the recruitment and discharge properties of motor units in human brachial biceps and adductor pollicis during isometric contractions. Brain Res. 1981;219:45-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie A, Greig Inglis J, Kamen G, Gabriel DA. Relationships between surface EMG variables and motor unit firing rates. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:177-185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oya T, Riek S, Cresswell AG. Recruitment and rate coding organisation for soleus motor units across entire range of voluntary isometric plantar flexions. J Physiol. 2009;587:4737-4748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, Hostage EC. Relationship between firing rate and recruitment threshold of motoneurons in voluntary isometric contractions. J Neurophysiol. 2010;104:1034-1046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bawa PN, Jones KE, Stein RB. Assessment of size ordered recruitment. Front Hum Neurosci. 2014;8:532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L, Hannerz J. Firing rate and recruitment order of toe extensor motor units in different modes of voluntary contraction. J Physiol. 1977;264:865-879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardone A, Roman&#xf2; C, Schieppati M. Selective recruitment of high-threshold human motor units during voluntary isotonic lengthening of active muscles. J Physiol. 1989;409:451-471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L. Single motor unit discharge during voluntary contraction and locomotion. In: Jones NL, McCartney N, McComas AJ, eds. Human Muscle Power. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1986:111-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges PW, Tucker K. Moving differently in pain: a new theory to explain the adaptation to pain. Pain. 2011;152(3 Suppl):S90-S98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanda K, Burke RE, Walmsley B. Differential control of fast and slow twitch motor units in the decerebrate cat. Exp Brain Res. 1977;29:57-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masakado Y, Kamen G, De Luca CJ. Effects of percutaneous stimulation on motor unit firing behavior in man. Exp Brain Res. 1991;86:426-432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binder MD, Heckman CJ, Powers RK. The physiological control of motoneuron activity. In: Rowell LB, Shepherd JT, eds. Handbook of Physiology. Exercise: Regulation and Integration of Multiple Systems. Vol. 12. New York: American Physiological Society; 1996:1-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cope TC, Clark BD. Are there important exceptions to the size principle of &#x3b1;-motoneurone recruitment? In: Taylor A, Gladden MH, Durban R, eds. Alpha and Gamma Motor Systems. Boston, MA: Springer; 1995:71-78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bawa P, Jones KE. Do lengthening contractions represent a case of reversal in recruitment order? Prog Brain Res. 1999;123:215-220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker K, Butler J, Graven-Nielsen T, Riek S, Hodges P. Motor unit recruitment strategies are altered during deep-tissue pain. J Neurosci. 2009;29:10820-10826.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker KJ, Hodges PW. Motoneurone recruitment is altered with pain induced in non-muscular tissue. Pain. 2009;141:151-155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards RH, Young A, Hosking GP, Jones DA. Human skeletal muscle function: description of tests and normal values. Clin Sci Mol Med. 1977;52:283-290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Sj&#xf6;holm H, J&#xe4;derholm-Ek I, Krynicki J. Evaluation of methods for electrical stimulation of human skeletal muscle in situ. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch. 1983;398:139-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory CM, Dixon W, Bickel CS. Impact of varying pulse frequency and duration on muscle torque production and fatigue. Muscle Nerve. 2007;35:504-509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberstein A, Goodgold J. Slow and fast twitch fibers in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol. 1968;215:535-541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulds RF, Young A, Jones DA, Edwards RH. A study of the contractility, biochemistry and morphology of an isolated preparation of human skeletal muscle. Clin Sci Mol Med. 1977;52:291-297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie B, Rice CL, Garland SJ, et al. Task-dependent factors in fatigue of human voluntary contractions. In: Gandevia SC, Enoka RM, McComas AJ, eds. Fatigue. Boston, MA: Springer; 1995:361-380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desmedt JE, Godaux E. Ballistic contractions in fast or slow human muscles: discharge patterns of single motor units. J Physiol. 1978;285:185-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cutsem M, Duchateau J, Hainaut K. Changes in single motor unit behaviour contribute to the increase in contraction speed after dynamic training in humans. J Physiol. 1998;513:295-305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbate F, Bruton JD, De Haan A, Westerblad H. Prolonged force increase following a high-frequency burst is not due to a sustained elevation of [Ca2+]i. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2002;283:C42-C47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng AJ, Place N, Bruton JD, et al. Doublet discharge stimulation increases sarcoplasmic reticulum Ca2+ release and improves performance during fatiguing contractions in mouse muscle fibres. J Physiol. 2013;591:3739-3748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamen G, Knight CA. Training-related adaptations in motor unit discharge rate in young and older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2004;59:1334-1338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie A, Kamen G. Short-term training adaptations in maximal motor unit firing rates and afterhyperpolarization duration. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:651-660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight CA, Kamen G. Relationships between voluntary activation and motor unit firing rate during maximal voluntary contractions in young and older adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;103:625-630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods JJ, Furbush F, Bigland-Ritchie B. Evidence for a fatigue-induced reflex inhibition of motoneuron firing rates. J Neurophysiol. 1987;58:125-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strojnik V. Muscle activation level during maximal voluntary effort. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1995;72:144-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Whittle J, Button D, Power K. Intermuscle differences in activation. Muscle Nerve. 2002;25:236-243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babault N, Pousson M, Michaut A, Ballay Y, Hoecke JV. EMG activity and voluntary activation during knee-extensor concentric torque generation. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;86:541-547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltman JG, Sargeant AJ, van Mechelen W, de Haan A. Voluntary activation level and muscle fiber recruitment of human quadriceps during lengthening contractions. J Appl Physiol. 2004;97:619-626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Place N, Casartelli N, Glatthorn JF, Maffiuletti NA. Comparison of quadriceps inactivation between nerve and muscle stimulation. Muscle Nerve. 2010;42:894-900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Leeuwen DM, De Ruiter CJ, De Haan A. Effect of stimulation intensity on assessment of voluntary activation. Muscle Nerve. 2012;45:841-848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pucci AR, Griffin L, Cafarelli E. Maximal motor unit firing rates during isometric resistance training in men. Exp Physiol. 2006;91:171-178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L, Hannerz J, Hedman B. Contraction time and voluntary discharge properties of individual short toe extensor motor units in man. J Physiol. 1979;289:191-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellemare F, Woods JJ, Johansson R, Bigland-Ritchie B. Motor-unit discharge rates in maximal voluntary contractions of three human muscles. J Neurophysiol. 1983;50:1380-1392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L, Hannerz J, Hedman B. The fatigue and voluntary discharge properties of single motor units in man. J Physiol. 1981;316:545-554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanosue K, Yoshida M, Akazawa K, Fujii K. The number of active motor units and their firing rates in voluntary contraction of human brachialis muscle. Jpn J Physiol. 1979;29:427-443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harwood B, Davidson AW, Rice CL. Motor unit discharge rates of the anconeus muscle during high-velocity elbow extensions. Exp Brain Res. 2011;208:103-113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannerz J, Grimby L. The afferent influence on the voluntary firing range of individual motor units in man. Muscle Nerve. 1979;2:414-422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gydikov A, Kosarov D. Some features of different motor units in human biceps brachii. Pflugers Arch. 1974;347:75-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, LeFever RS, McCue MP, Xenakis AP. Behaviour of human motor units in different muscles during linearly varying contractions. J Physiol. 1982;329:113-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, Erim Z. Common drive of motor units in regulation of muscle force. Trends Neurosci. 1994;17:299-305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erim Z, De Luca CJ, Mineo K, Aoki T. Rank-ordered regulation of motor units. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19:563-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, Contessa P. Hierarchical control of motor units in voluntary contractions. J Neurophysiol. 2012;107:178-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Person RS, Kudina LP. Discharge frequency and discharge pattern of human motor units during voluntary contraction of muscle. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1972;32:471-483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanji J, Kato M. Recruitment of motor units in voluntary contraction of a finger muscle in man. Exp Neurol. 1973;40:759-770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Rate coding and the control of muscle force. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2017;7(10):a029702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrkiewicz M, T&#xfc;rker K. Onion skin or common drive? Front Cell Neurosci. 2017;11:2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosarov D, Gydikov A. Dependence of the discharge frequency of motor units in different human muscles upon the level of the isometric muscle tension. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1976;16:293-306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz CT, Barry BK, Pascoe MA, Enoka RM. Discharge rate variability influences the variation in force fluctuations across the working range of a hand muscle. J Neurophysiol. 2005;93:2449-2459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry BK, Pascoe MA, Jesunathadas M, Enoka RM. Rate coding is compressed but variability is unaltered for motor units in a hand muscle of old adults. J Neurophysiol. 2007;97:3206-3218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L, Hannerz J. Recruitment order of motor units on voluntary contraction: changes induced by proprioceptive afferent activity. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1968;31:565-573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatev P, Ivanova T, Gantchev GN. Changes in the firing pattern of high-threshold motor units due to fatigue. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1986;26:83-93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warmolts JR, Engel WK. Open-biopsy electromyography. I. Correlation of motor unit behavior with histochemical muscle fiber type in human limb muscle. Arch Neurol. 1972;27:512-517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warmolts JR, Engel WK. Correlation of motor unit behavior with histochemical myofiber type in humans by open-biopsy electromyography. In: Desmedt JE, ed. New Concepts of the Motor Unit, Neuromuscular Disorders, Electromyographic Kinesiology. Basel: Karger Publishers; 1973:35-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L. Firing properties of single human motor units during locomotion. J Physiol. 1984;346:195-202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;gaard K, Christensen H, Fallentin N, Mizuno M, Quistorff B, Sj&#xf8;gaard G. Motor unit activation patterns during concentric wrist flexion in humans with different muscle fibre composition. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1998;78:411-416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L, Hannerz J, Borg J, Hedman B. Firing properties of single human motor units on maintained maximal voluntary effort. In: Porter R, Whelan J, eds. Human Muscle Fatigue: Physiological Mechanisms. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.; 1981:157-177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cutsem M, Duchateau J. Preceding muscle activity influences motor unit discharge and rate of torque development during ballistic contractions in humans. J Physiol. 2005;562:635-644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harwood B, Choi I, Rice CL. Reduced motor unit discharge rates of maximal velocity dynamic contractions in response to a submaximal dynamic fatigue protocol. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:1821-1830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawczuk A, Powers RK, Binder MD. Intrinsic properties of motoneurons. In: Gandevia SC, Enoka RM, McComas AJ, eds. Fatigue. Boston, MA: Springer; 1995:123-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kernell D, Eerbeek O, Verhey BA. Relation between isometric force and stimulus rate in cat's hindlimb motor units of different twitch contraction time. Exp Brain Res. 1983;50:220-227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zengel JE, Reid SA, Sypert GW, Munson JB. Membrane electrical properties and prediction of motor-unit type of medial gastrocnemius motoneurons in the cat. J Neurophysiol. 1985;53:1323-1344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardiner PF. Physiological properties of motoneurons innervating different muscle unit types in rat gastrocnemius. J Neurophysiol. 1993;69:1160-1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie BR, Dawson NJ, Johansson RS, Lippold OC. Reflex origin for the slowing of motoneurone firing rates in fatigue of human voluntary contractions. J Physiol. 1986;379:451-459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JL, Amann M, Duchateau J, Meeusen R, Rice CL. Neural contributions to muscle fatigue: from the brain to the muscle and back again. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:2294-2306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Sidhu SK, Weavil JC, Mangum TS, Venturelli M. Autonomic responses to exercise: group III/IV muscle afferents and fatigue. Auton Neurosci. 2015;188:19-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windhorst U, Kirmayer D, Soibelman F, Misri A, Rose R. Effects of neurochemically excited group III-IV muscle afferents on motoneuron afterhyperpolarization. Neuroscience. 1997;76:915-929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin PG, Weerakkody N, Gandevia SC, Taylor JL. Group III and IV muscle afferents differentially affect the motor cortex and motoneurones in humans. J Physiol. 2008;586:1277-1289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garland SJ, Griffin L, Ivanova T. Motor unit discharge rate is not associated with muscle relaxation time in sustained submaximal contractions in humans. Neurosci Lett. 1997;239:25-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonde-Petersen F, Mork AL, Nielsen E. Local muscle blood flow and sustained contractions of human arm and back muscles. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1975;34:43-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin L, Garland SJ, Ivanova T, Hughson RL. Blood flow in the triceps brachii muscle in humans during sustained submaximal isometric contractions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;84:432-437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freund PR, Hobbs SF, Rowell LB. Cardiovascular responses to muscle ischemia in man-dependency on muscle mass. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol. 1978;45:762-767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JH, Payne FC, Saltin B, Schibye B. The role of muscle mass in the cardiovascular response to static contractions. J Physiol. 1980;309:45-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seals DR. Influence of muscle mass on sympathetic neural activation during isometric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1989;67:1801-1806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seals DR. Influence of active muscle size on sympathetic nerve discharge during isometric contractions in humans. J Appl Physiol. 1993;75:1426-1431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matkowski B, Place N, Martin A, Lepers R. Neuromuscular fatigue differs following unilateral vs bilateral sustained submaximal contractions. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:268-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossman MJ, Venturelli M, McDaniel J, Amann M, Richardson RS. Muscle mass and peripheral fatigue: a potential role for afferent feedback? Acta Physiol. 2012;206:242-250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossman MJ, Garten RS, Venturelli M, Amann M, Richardson RS. The role of active muscle mass in determining the magnitude of peripheral fatigue during dynamic exercise. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2014;306:R934-R940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietz V. Analysis of the electrical muscle activity during maximal contraction and the influence of ischaemia. J Neurol Sci. 1978;37:187-197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho AJ, McKee NH. Active and passive forces during ischemia and reperfusion of rat fast and slow twitch skeletal muscles. Adv Exp Med Biol. 1992;311:365-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho AJ, McKee NH, Green HJ. Metabolic and contractile responses of fast- and slow-twitch rat skeletal muscles to ischemia. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 1996;74:1333-1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gossen ER, Ivanova TD, Garland SJ. Ischemia sensitivity and motoneuron afterhyperpolarization in human motor units. Muscle Nerve. 2004;30:195-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folkow B, Halicka H. A comparison between &#x201c;red&#x201d; and &#x201c;white&#x201d; muscle with respect to blood supply, capillary surface area and oxygen uptake during rest and exercise. Microvasc Res. 1968;1:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahlin K, Edstr&#xf6;m L, Sj&#xf6;holm H. Force, relaxation and energy metabolism of rat soleus muscle during anaerobic contraction. Acta Physiol Scand. 1987;129:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Karlsson J, Piehl K, Saltin B. Selective glycogen depletion in skeletal muscle fibres of man following sustained contractions. J Physiol. 1974;241:59-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murthy G, Hargens AR, Lehman S, Rempel DM. Ischemia causes muscle fatigue. J Orthop Res. 2001;19:436-440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bylund-Fellenius AC, Walker PM, Elander A, Holm S, Holm J, Scherst&#xe9;n T. Energy metabolism in relation to oxygen partial pressure in human skeletal muscle during exercise. Biochem J. 1981;200:247-255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DG, Lamb GD, Westerblad H. Skeletal muscle fatigue: cellular mechanisms. Physiol Rev. 2008;88:287-332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DG, Trajanovska S. The multiple roles of phosphate in muscle fatigue. Front Physiol. 2012;3:463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karatzaferi C, Franks-Skiba K, Cooke R. Inhibition of shortening velocity of skinned skeletal muscle fibers in conditions that mimic fatigue. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2008;294:R948-R955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson CR, Debold EP, Fitts RH. Phosphate and acidosis act synergistically to depress peak power in rat muscle fibers. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2014;307:C939-C950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debold EP. Decreased myofilament calcium sensitivity plays a significant role in muscle fatigue. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2016;44:144-149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Del Canale S, Sj&#xf6;holm H. Effect of induced metabolic acidosis on intracellular pH, buffer capacity and contraction force of human skeletal muscle. Clin Sci. 1985;69:505-510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Sj&#xf6;hom H, Sahlin K, Edstr&#xf6;m L. Glycolytic and oxidative energy metabolism and contraction characteristics of intact human muscle. In: Porter R, Whelan J, eds. Human Muscle Fatigue: Physiological Mechanisms. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.; 1981:19-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Sj&#xf6;holm H. Electromyogram, force and relaxation time during and after continuous electrical stimulation of human skeletal muscle in situ. J Physiol. 1983;339:33-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Sj&#xf6;holm H. Biochemical causes of fatigue. In: Jones NL, McCartney N, McComas AJ, eds. Human Muscle Power. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics Publishers; 1986:215-238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derlund K, Hultman E. ATP content in single fibres from human skeletal muscle after electrical stimulation and during recovery. Acta Physiol Scand. 1990;139:459-466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derlund K, Greenhaff PL, Hultman E. Energy metabolism in type I and type II human muscle fibres during short term electrical stimulation at different frequencies. Acta Physiol Scand. 1992;144:15-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;derlund K, Hultman E. ATP and phosphocreatine changes in single human muscle fibers after intense electrical stimulation. Am J Physiol. 1991;261:E737-E741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonkonogi M, Walsh B, Tiivel T, Saks V, Sahlin K. Mitochondrial function in human skeletal muscle is not impaired by high intensity exercise. Pflugers Arch. 1999;437:562-568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Thorsson A, Fujitsuka N. Creatine phosphate in fiber types of skeletal muscle before and after exhaustive exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1989;66:1756-1759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colliander EB, Dudley GA, Tesch PA. Skeletal muscle fiber type composition and performance during repeated bouts of maximal, concentric contractions. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1988;58:81-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA. Muscle fatigue in man. With special reference to lactate accumulation during short term intense exercise. Acta Physiol Scand Suppl. 1980;480:1-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q-A, Hess DT, Nogueira L, et al. Oxygen-coupled redox regulation of the skeletal muscle ryanodine receptor-Ca2+ release channel by NADPH oxidase 4. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:16098-16103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loureiro ACC, R&#xea;go-Monteiro ICD, Louzada RA, et al. Differential expression of NADPH oxidases depends on skeletal muscle fiber type in rats. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2016;2016:6738701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards RH, Toescu V, Gibson H, et al. Historical perspective: a framework for interpreting pathobiological ideas on human muscle fatigue. In: Gandevia SC, Enoka RM, McComas AJ, eds. Fatigue. Boston, MA: Springer; 1995:481-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saugen E, Vollestad NK, Gibson H, Martin PA, Edwards RH. Dissociation between metabolic and contractile responses during intermittent isometric exercise in man. Exp Physiol. 1997;82:213-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Hisdal J, Raastad T. Contractile function and sarcolemmal permeability after acute low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:2051-2063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieljacks P, Matzon A, Wernbom M, Ringgaard S, Vissing K, Overgaard K. Muscle damage and repeated bout effect following blood flow restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:513-525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Brechue WF, Fujita T, et al. Muscle activation during low-intensity muscle contractions with varying levels of external limb compression. J Sports Sci Med. 2008;7:467-474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Brechue WF, Fujita T, Shirakawa J, Sato Y, Abe T. Muscle activation during low-intensity muscle contractions with restricted blood flow. J Sports Sci. 2009;27:479-489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Muro M, Kijima A, Gaffney FA, Parsons D. Electromechanical changes during electrically induced and maximal voluntary contractions: surface and intramuscular EMG responses during sustained maximal voluntary contraction. Exp Neurol. 1985;88:484-499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadamoto T, Bonde-Petersen F, Suzuki Y. Skeletal muscle tension, flow, pressure, and EMG during sustained isometric contractions in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1983;51:395-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf8;gaard G, Savard G, Juel C. Muscle blood flow during isometric activity and its relation to muscle fatigue. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1988;57:327-335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cupido CM, Galea V, McComas AJ. Potentiation and depression of the M wave in human biceps brachii. J Physiol. 1996;491:541-550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galea V. Electrical characteristics of human ankle dorsi- and plantar-flexor muscles. Comparative responses during fatiguing stimulation and recovery. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;85:130-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonard CT, Kane J, Perdaems J, Frank C, Graetzer DG, Moritani T. Neural modulation of muscle contractile properties during fatigue: afferent feedback dependence. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1994;93:209-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks A, McComas AJ. Increased sodium pump activity following repetitive stimulation of rat soleus muscles. J Physiol. 1989;414:337-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Falces J, Place N. Determinants, analysis and interpretation of the muscle compound action potential (M wave) in humans: implications for the study of muscle fatigue. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118:501-521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie B. EMG and fatigue of human voluntary and stimulated contractions. In: Porter R, Whelan J, eds. Human Muscle Fatigue: Physiological Mechanisms. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.; 1981:130-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlb&#xe4;ck LO, Ekstedt J, St&#xe5;lberg E. Ischemic effects on impulse transmission to muscle fibers in man. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1970;29:579-591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieck GC, Prakash YS, et al. Fatigue at the neuromuscular junction. In: Gandevia SC, Enoka RM, McComas AJ, eds. Fatigue. Boston, MA: Springer; 1995:83-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandercock TG, Faulkner JA, Albers JW, Abbrecht PH. Single motor unit and fiber action potentials during fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 1985;58:1073-1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramson DI, Rickert BL, Alexis JT, Hlavova A, Schwab C, Tandoc J. Effect of repeated periods of ischemia on motor nerve conduction velocity in forearm. J Appl Physiol. 1971;30:636-642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal P, Shenoy S, Sandhu JS. Effect of different cuff widths on the motor nerve conduction of the median nerve: an experimental study. J Orthop Surg Res. 2008;3:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desaulniers P, Lavoie PA, Gardiner PF. Incomplete recovery of endplate potential amplitude while intermittently activating rat soleus neuromuscular junctions in situ. Muscle Nerve. 2002;26:810-816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen T, Overgaard K, Nielsen OB. Evidence that the Na+-K+ leak/pump ratio contributes to the difference in endurance between fast- and slow-twitch muscles. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;180:209-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson E, Dudley GA, Norman B, Tesch PA. Relationship of recovery from intensive exercise to the oxidative potential of skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1990;139:147-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf8;gaard G, Houston ME, Nygaard E, Saltin B. Subgrouping of fast twitch fibres in skeletal muscles of man. A critical appraisal. Histochemistry. 1978;58:79-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron RS, Hikida RS, Hagerman FC. Reevaluartion of human muscle fast-twitch subtypes: evidence for a continuum. Histochemistry. 1983;78:33-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron RS, Hikida RS, Hagerman FC, Dudley GA, Murray TF. Human skeletal muscle fiber type adaptability to various workloads. J Histochem Cytochem. 1984;32:146-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ess&#xe9;n-Gustavsson B, Henriksson J. Enzyme levels in pools of microdissected human muscle fibres of identified type. Adaptive response to exercise. Acta Physiol Scand. 1984;120:505-515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahlin K, Ren JM. Relationship of contraction capacity to metabolic changes during recovery from a fatiguing contraction. J Appl Physiol. 1989;67:648-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Edwards RHT, Hultman E, Nordesj&#x4e7; LO, Nylind B, Sahlin K. The time course of phosphorylcreatine resynthesis during recovery of the quadriceps muscle in man. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch. 1976;367:137-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umbel JD, Hoffman RL, Dearth DJ, Chleboun GS, Manini TM, Clark BC. Delayed-onset muscle soreness induced by low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(6):687-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edstr&#xf6;m L, Kugelberg E. Histochemical composition, distribution of fibres and fatiguability of single motor units. Anterior tibial muscle of the rat. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1968;424-433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Armstrong RB, Sembrowich WL, Shepherd RE, Saltin B. Glycogen depletion pattern in human skeletal muscle fibers after heavy exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1973;34:615-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Armstrong RB, Saubert CW, Sembrowich WL, Shepherd RE, Saltin B. Glycogen depletion patterns in human skeletal muscle fibers during prolonged work. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch. 1973;344:1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollnick PD, Piehl K, Saltin B. Selective glycogen depletion pattern in human muscle fibres after exercise of varying intensity and at varying pedalling rates. J Physiol. 1974;241:45-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xf8;llestad NK, Vaage O, Hermansen L. Muscle glycogen depletion patterns in type I and subgroups of type II fibres during prolonged severe exercise in man. Acta Physiol Scand. 1984;122:433-441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xf8;llestad NK, Blom PC. Effect of varying exercise intensity on glycogen depletion in human muscle fibres. Acta Physiol Scand. 1985;125:395-405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xf8;llestad NK, Tabata I, Medb&#xf8; JI. Glycogen breakdown in different human muscle fibre types during exhaustive exercise of short duration. Acta Physiol Scand. 1992;144:135-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen JL, Gruschy-Knudsen T. Rapid switch-off of the human myosin heavy chain IIX gene after heavy load muscle contractions is sustained for at least four days. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2018;28:371-380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robergs RA, Pearson DR, Costill DL, et al. Muscle glycogenolysis during differing intensities of weight-resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1991;70:1700-1706.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascoe DD, Gladden LB. Muscle glycogen resynthesis after short term, high intensity exercise and resistance exercise. Sports Med. 1996;21:98-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Ploutz-Snyder LL, Ystr&#xf6;m L, Castro MJ, Dudley GA. Skeletal muscle glycogen loss evoked by resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 1998;12:67-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz JPJ, Groenendaal W, Wessels B, et al. Combined in vivo and in silico investigations of activation of glycolysis in contracting skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2013;304:C180-C193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin ES, Sherry AD, Malloy CR. Evidence for reverse flux through pyruvate kinase in skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2009;296:E748-E757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin ES, Sherry AD, Malloy CR. Lactate contributes to glyceroneogenesis and glyconeogenesis in skeletal muscle by reversal of pyruvate kinase. J Biol Chem. 2015;290:30486-30497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund J, Aas V, Tingstad RH, Van Hees A, Nikoli&#x107; N. Utilization of lactic acid in human myotubes and interplay with glucose and fatty acid metabolism. Sci Rep. 2018;8:9814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLane JA, Holloszy JO. Glycogen synthesis from lactate in the three types of skeletal muscle. J Biol Chem. 1979;254:6548-6553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltman JGM, Sargeant AJ, Haan H, Mechelen W, Haan A. Changes in PCr/Cr ratio in single characterized muscle fibre fragments after only a few maximal voluntary contractions in humans. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;180:187-193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltman JGM, de Haan A, Haan H, Gerrits HL, van Mechelen W, Sargeant AJ. Metabolically assessed muscle fibre recruitment in brief isometric contractions at different intensities. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92:485-492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tupling AR, Bombardier E, Stewart RD, Vigna C, Aqui AE. Muscle fiber type-specific response of Hsp70 expression in human quadriceps following acute isometric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103:2105-2111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingemann-Hansen T, Halkjaer-Kristensen J, Halskov O. Skeletal muscle phosphagen and lactate concentrations in ischaemic dynamic exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1981;46:261-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch P, Karlsson J. Lactate in fast and slow twitch skeletal muscle fibres of man during isometric contraction. Acta Physiol Scand. 1977;99:230-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MA, Polgar J, Weightman D, Appleton D. Data on the distribution of fibre types in thirty-six human muscles. An autopsy study. J Neurol Sci. 1973;18:111-129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elder GC, Bradbury K, Roberts R. Variability of fiber type distributions within human muscles. J Appl Physiol. 1982;53:1473-1480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Henriksson-Lars&#xe9;n K, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M. Distribution of different fibre types in human skeletal muscles. 2. A study of cross-sections of whole m. vastus lateralis. Acta Physiol Scand. 1983;117:115-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Taylor CC. Variability in muscle fibre areas in whole human quadriceps muscle. How much and why? Acta Physiol Scand. 1989;136:561-568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Bergstr&#xf6;m J, Anderson NM. Breakdown and resynthesis of phosphorylcreatine and adenosine triphosphate in connection with muscular work in man. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1967;19:56-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson J, Saltin B. Lactate, ATP, and CP in working muscles during exhaustive exercise in man. J Appl Physiol. 1970;29:596-602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson J, Diamant B, Saltin B. Muscle metabolites during submaximal and maximal exercise in man. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1970;26:385-394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehunen S, N&#xe4;veri H, Kuoppasalmi K, H&#xe4;rk&#xf6;nen M. High-energy phosphate compounds during exercise in human slow-twitch and fast-twitch muscle fibres. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1982;42:499-506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madapallimattam AG, Cross A, Nishio ML, Jeejeebhoy KN. Stability of high-energy substrates in fast- and slow-twitch muscle: comparison of enzymatic assay of biopsy with in vivo 31P nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Anal Biochem. 1994;217:103-139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Holobar A, Merletti R, Enoka RM. Decoding the neural drive to muscles from the surface electromyogram. Clin Neurophysiol. 2010;121:1616-1623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Lehman GJ, Trajano GS, Vieira TM. Interpreting signal amplitudes in surface electromyography studies in sport and rehabilitation sciences. Front Physiol. 2018;8:985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Stegeman D, Merletti R. Basic physiology and biophysics of EMG signal generation. In: Merletti R, Parker P, eds. Electromyography: physiology, engineering and noninvasive applications. Hoboken, NJ: IEEE Press; Wiley-lnterscience; 2004:1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Enoka RM. Surface EMG decomposition requires an appropriate validation. J Neurophysiol. 2011;105:981-982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, Chang S-S, Roy SH, Kline JC, Nawab SH. Decomposition of surface EMG signals from cyclic dynamic contractions. J Neurophysiol. 2015;113:1941-1951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, Nawab H. Reply to Farina and Enoka: the reconstruct-and-test approach is the most appropriate validation for surface EMG signal decomposition to date. J Neurophysiol. 2011;105:983-984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG: an update. J Appl Physiol. 2014;117:1215-1230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. Reply to De Luca, Nawab, and Kline: The proposed method to validate surface EMG signal decomposition remains problematic. J Appl Physiol. 2015;118:1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca CJ, Nawab SH, Kline JC. Clarification of methods used to validate surface EMG decomposition algorithms as described by Farina et al. (2014). J Appl Physiol. 2015;118:1084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arabadzhiev TI, Dimitrov VG, Dimitrova NA, Dimitrov GV. Influence of motor unit synchronization on amplitude characteristics of surface and intramuscularly recorded EMG signals. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:227-237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arabadzhiev TI, Dimitrov VG, Dimitrov GV. The increase in surface EMG could be a misleading measure of neural adaptation during the early gains in strength. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:1645-1655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitrova NA, Dimitrov GV. Interpretation of EMG changes with fatigue: facts, pitfalls, and fallacies. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2003;13:13-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson J, Persson A. Changes in the action potential and contraction of isolated frog muscle after repetitive stimulation. Acta Physiol Scand. 1971;81:340-348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson J. The effects of repetitive stimulation on the action potential and the twitch of rat muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1974;90:387-400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson J. Effects of repetitive stimulation on membrane potentials and twitch in human and rat intercostal muscle fibres. Acta Physiol Scand. 1974;92:238-248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenan KG, Farina D, Maluf KS, Merletti R, Enoka RM. Influence of amplitude cancellation on the simulated surface electromyogram. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98:120-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dideriksen JL, Enoka RM, Farina D. Neuromuscular adjustments that constrain submaximal EMG amplitude at task failure of sustained isometric contractions. J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:485-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG. J Appl Physiol. 2004;96:1486-1495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neyroud D, Kayser B, Place N. The need to normalize surface EMG. J Appl Physiol. 2015;119:1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Valdes E, Negro F, Falla D, De Nunzio AM, Farina D. Surface electromyographic amplitude does not identify differences in neural drive to synergistic muscles. J Appl Physiol. 2018;124:1071-1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Muro M. Motor unit activity and surface electromyogram power spectrum during increasing force of contraction. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1987;56:260-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clamann HP. Activity of single motor units during isometric tension. Neurology. 1970;20:254-260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight CA, Kamen G. Superficial motor units are larger than deeper motor units in human vastus lateralis muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2005;31:475-480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgerton VR, Smith JL, Simpson DR. Muscle fibre type populations of human leg muscles. Histochem J. 1975;7:259-266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray CA, Dudley GA. Muscle use during dynamic knee extension: implication for perfusion and metabolism. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85:1194-1197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enocson AG, Berg HE, Vargas R, Jenner G, Tesch PA. Signal intensity of MR-images of thigh muscles following acute open- and closed chain kinetic knee extensor exercise-index of muscle use. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;94:357-363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalliokoski KK, Boushel R, Langberg H, et al. Differential glucose uptake in quadriceps and other leg muscles during one-legged dynamic submaximal knee-extension exercise. Front Physiol. 2011;2:75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson RS, Frank LR, Haseler LJ. Dynamic knee-extensor and cycle exercise: functional MRI of muscular activity. Int J Sports Med. 1998;19:182-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe K, Akima H. Normalized EMG to normalized torque relationship of vastus intermedius muscle during isometric knee extension. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:665-673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorstensson A, Karlsson J, Viitasalo JHT, Luhtanen P, Komi PV. Effect of strength training on EMG of human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1976;98:232-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Komi PV. Electromyographic changes during strength training and detraining. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1983;15:455-460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eloranta V. Patterning of muscle activity in static knee extension. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1989;29:369-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkner BA, Tesch PA, Berg HE. Quadriceps EMG/force relationship in knee extension and leg press. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:459-463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabita G, P&#xe9;rot C, Lensel-Corbeil G. Differential effect of knee extension isometric training on the different muscles of the quadriceps femoris in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2000;83:531-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiridis IG, Martin A, Morlon B, et al. Co-activation and tension-regulating phenomena during isokinetic knee extension in sedentary and highly skilled humans. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1996;73:149-156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komi PV, Linnamo V, Silventoinen P, Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; M. Force and EMG power spectrum during eccentric and concentric actions. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:1757-1762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrom RA, Osborn RW, Goehner HM, et al. Electromyographic normalization procedures for determining exercise intensity of closed chain exercises for strengthening the quadriceps femoris muscles. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:766-771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beutler AI, Cooper LW, Kirkendall DT, Garrett WE Jr. Electromyographic analysis of single-leg, closed chain exercises: implications for rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2002;37:13-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westing SH, Cresswell AG, Thorstensson A. Muscle activation during maximal voluntary eccentric and concentric knee extension. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1991;62:104-108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson SP, Halkjaer-Kristensen J, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Neural inhibition during maximal eccentric and concentric quadriceps contraction: effects of resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2000;89:2249-2257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Dudley GA, Duvoisin MR, Hather BM, Harris RT. Force and EMG signal patterns during repeated bouts of concentric or eccentric muscle actions. Acta Physiol Scand. 1990;138:263-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Enoka RM. Human motor unit recordings: origins and insight into the integrated motor system. Brain Res. 2011;1409:42-61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basmajian JV, De Luca CJ. Muscles Alive. Baltimore, MD: Williams &amp; Wilkins; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, Muro M, Nagata A. Intramuscular and surface electromyogram changes during muscle fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 1986;60:1179-1185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trontelj JV, Jabre J, Mihelin M. Needle and wire detection techniques. In: Merletti R, Parker P, eds. Electromyography: physiology, engineering and noninvasive applications. Hoboken, NJ: IEEE Press; Wiley-lnterscience; 2004:27-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent-Braun JA, Miller RG, Weiner MW. Human skeletal muscle metabolism in health and disease: utility of magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1995;23:305-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan MJ, Saltin B, Negro-Vilar R, Duscha BD, Charles HC. Skeletal muscle pH assessed by biochemical and 31P-MRS methods during exercise and recovery in men. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77:2194-3200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantin-Teodosiu D, Greenhaff PL, McIntyre DB, Round JM, Jones DA. Anaerobic energy production in human skeletal muscle in intense contraction: a comparison of 31P magnetic resonance spectroscopy and biochemical techniques. Exp Physiol. 1997;82:593-601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenborne K, McCully K, Kakihira H, et al. Metabolic heterogeneity in human calf muscle during maximal exercise. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1991;88:5714-5718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houtman CJ, Heerschap A, Zwarts MJ, Stegeman DF. pH heterogeneity in tibial anterior muscle during isometric activity studied by (31)P-NMR spectroscopy. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91:191-200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Ess&#xe9;n B, Hultman E. Glycogen phosphorylase activity in biopsy samples and single muscle fibres of musculus quadriceps femoris of man at rest. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1976;36:512-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Brown RL, Park CR, et al. Functional pools of oxidative and glycolytic fibers in human muscle observed by 31P magnetic resonance spectroscopy during exercise. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1987;84:8976-8980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achten E, Van Cauteren M, Willem R, et al. 31P-NMR spectroscopy and the metabolic properties of different muscle fibers. J Appl Physiol. 1990;68:644-659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno M, Secher NH, Quistorff B. 31P-NMR spectroscopy, rsEMG, and histochemical fiber types of human wrist flexor muscles. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76:531-538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahlin K, Harris RC, Hultman E. Creatine kinase equilibrium and lactate content compared with muscle pH in tissue samples obtained after isometric exercise. Biochem J. 1975;152:173-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer RA, Slade JM, Towse TF, Olive JL, Forbes SC. Phosphocreatine resynthesis during recovery after exercise with blood flow occlusion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(5):S349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor DJ, Bore PJ, Styles P, et al. Bioenergetics of intact human muscle. A 31P nuclear magnetic resonance study. Mol Biol Med. 1983;1:77-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeneson JA, Wesselink MW, de Boer RW,Amelink HG. Peak-splitting of inorganic phosphate during exercise: anatomy or physiology? A MRI-guided 31P MRS study of human forearm muscle. In: Proceedings, 8th Annual Meeting of the Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine. Amsterdam; 1989:1030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson R, Arnold D, Leger G. Splitting of the phosphate peak in exercising muscle is due to macroscopic not microscopic heterogeneity (Abstract). Magn Reson Med. 1990;Suppl. 2:866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenborne K, Walter G, Leigh JS, Goelman G. pH heterogeneity during exercise in localized spectra from single human muscles. Am J Physiol. 1993;265:C1332-C1339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno M, Justesen LO, Bedolla J, et al. Partial curarization abolishes splitting of the inorganic phosphate peak in 31P-NMR spectroscopy during intense forearm exercise in man. Acta Physiol Scand. 1990;139:611-612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno M, Horn A, Secher NH, Quistorff B. Exercise-induced 31P-NMR metabolic response of human wrist flexor muscles during partial neuromuscular blockade. Am J Physiol. 1994;267:R408-R414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanagisawa O, Niitsu M, Yoshioka H, Goto K, Itai Y. MRI determination of muscle recruitment variations in dynamic ankle plantar flexion exercise. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;10:760-765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segal RL, Song AW. Nonuniform activity of human calf muscles during an exercise task. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2005;86:2013-2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyerspeer M, Robinson S, Nabuurs CI, et al. Comparing localized and nonlocalized dynamic 31P magnetic resonance spectroscopy in exercising muscle at 7 T. Magn Reson Med. 2012;68:1713-1723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valkovi&#x10d; L, Chmel&#xed;k M, Just Kukurov&#xe1; I, et al. Depth-resolved surface coil MRS (DRESS)-localized dynamic (31) P-MRS of the exercising human gastrocnemius muscle at 7 T. NMR Biomed. 2014;27:1346-1352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossiter HB, Ward SA, Howe FA, et al. Dynamics of intramuscular 31P-MRS P(i) peak splitting and the slow components of PCr and O2 uptake during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:2059-2069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Karlsson J. Effects of exhaustive, isometric training on lactate accumulation in different muscle fiber types. Int J Sports Med. 1984;5:89-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houtman CJ, Heerschap A, Zwarts MJ, Stegeman DF. An additional phase in PCr use during sustained isometric exercise at 30% MVC in the tibialis anterior muscle. NMR Biomed. 2002;15:270-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Watari H. Exercise-induced splitting of the inorganic phosphate peak: investigation by time-resolved 31P-nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69:465-473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Kent-Braun JA, Sharma KR, Weiner MW. Mechanisms of human muscle fatigue. Quantitating the contribution of metabolic factors and activation impairment. In: Gandevia SC, Enoka RM, McComas AJ, eds. Fatigue. Boston, MA: Springer; 1995:195-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller RG, Giannini D, Milner-Brown HS, et al. Effects of fatiguing exercise on high-energy phosphates, force, and EMG: evidence for three phases of recovery. Muscle Nerve. 1987;10:810-821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vestergaard-Poulsen P, Thomsen C, Sinkjaer T, Stubgaard M, Rosenfalck A, Henriksen O. Simultaneous electromyography and 31P nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy-with application to muscle fatigue. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1992;85:402-411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vestergaard-Poulsen P, Thomsen C, Sinkjaer T, Henriksen O. Simultaneous 31P-NMR spectroscopy and EMG in exercising and recovering human skeletal muscle: a correlation study. J Appl Physiol. 1995;79:1469-1478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendahan D, Jammes Y, Salvan AM, et al. Combined electromyography-31P-magnetic resonance spectroscopy study of human muscle fatigue during static contraction. Muscle Nerve. 1996;19:715-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houtman CJ, Stegeman DF, Van Dijk JP, Zwarts MJ. Changes in muscle fiber conduction velocity indicate recruitment of distinct motor unit populations. J Appl Physiol. 2003;95:1045-1054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannesini B, Cozzone PJ, Bendahan D. Non-invasive investigations of muscular fatigue: metabolic and electromyographic components. Biochimie. 2003;85:873-883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crenshaw AG, Hargens AR, Gershuni DH, Rydevik B. Wide tourniquet cuffs more effective at lower inflation pressures. Acta Orthop Scand. 1988;59:447-451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. Effects of vascular occlusion on muscular endurance in dynamic knee extension exercise at different submaximal loads. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:372-377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke MH, Kaiser KK. Muscle fiber types: how many and what kind? Arch Neurol. 1970;23:369-739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billeter R, Heizmann CW, Howald H, Jenny E. Analysis of myosin light and heavy chain types in single human skeletal muscle fibers. Eur J Biochem. 1981;116:389-395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green H, Goreham C, Ouyang J, Ball-Burnett M, Ranney D. Regulation of fiber size, oxidative potential, and capillarization in human muscle by resistance exercise. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:R591-R596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke MH, Kaiser KK. Three &#x201c;myosin adenosine triphosphatase&#x201d; systems: the nature of their pH lability and sulfhydryl dependence. J Histochem Cytochem. 1970;18:670-672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubowitz V, Sewry CA, Oldfors A. Muscle biopsy: A Practical Approach. 4th ed. Philadelphia: Elsevier Health Sciences; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frid&#xe9;n J, Seger J, Ekblom B. Sublethal muscle fibre injuries after high-tension anaerobic exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1988;57:360-368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han YS, Proctor DN, Geiger PC, Sieck GC. Reserve capacity for ATP consumption during isometric contraction in human skeletal muscle fibers. J Appl Physiol. 2001;90:657-664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piehl K. Time course for refilling of glycogen stores in human muscle fibres following exercise-induced glycogen depletion. Acta Physiol Scand. 1974;90:297-302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairchild TJ, Armstrong AA, Rao A, Liu H, Lawrence S, Fournier PA. Glycogen synthesis in muscle fibers during active recovery from intense exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:595-602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Apro W, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Blomstrand E, Raastad T. Acute low-load resistance exercise with and without blood flow restriction increased protein signalling and number of satellite cells in human skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:2953-2965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zehnder M, Muelli M, Buchli R, Kuehne G, Boutellier U. Further glycogen decrease during early recovery after eccentric exercise despite a high carbohydrate intake. Eur J Nutr. 2004;43:148-159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen P, Saltin B. Maximal perfusion of skeletal muscle in man. J Physiol. 1985;366:233-249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Person RS, Golubovich K. Electromyographic study of fatigue in man in conditions of artificial ischemia in the working muscle. Fiziologicheskii zhurnal SSSR imeni IM Sechenova. 1960;46:1181-1187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arendt-Nielsen L, Mills KR. The relationship between mean power frequency of the EMG spectrum and muscle fibre conduction velocity. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1985;60:130-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers SJ, Sullivan WP. Effect of crculatory occlusion on time to muscular fatigue. J Appl Physiol. 1968;24:54-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan WP. Muscle Fatigue and Electromyographic Changes During Isometric Exercise in Presence of Vascular Occlusion [PhD thesis]. The Ohio State University; 1968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgerton VR, Roy RR, Apor P. Specific tension of human elbow flexor muscles. In: Saltin B, ed. Biochemistry of Exercise VI. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1986:487-500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signorile JF, Digel S, Moccia G, Applegate B, Perry A. Effects of partial occlusion of circulation on frequency and amplitude of surface electromyography. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 1991;1:124-129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Iida H, Nakajima T. Effect of low-load resistance exercise with and without blood flow restriction to volitional fatigue on muscle swelling. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115:919-926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, MacDougall JD, Sale DG. Contractile adaptations in the human triceps surae after isometric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1989;66:2725-2732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Sale DG, MacDougall JD. Twitch contractile adaptations are not dependent on the intensity of isometric exercise in the human triceps surae. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1990;60:346-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Burgomaster KA, Schofield LM, Gibala MJ, Sale DG, Phillips SM. Neuromuscular adaptations in human muscle following low intensity resistance training with vascular occlusion. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92:399-406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Borg's Perceived Exertion and Pain Scales. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooistra RD, de Ruiter CJ, de Haan A. Muscle activation and blood flow do not explain the muscle length-dependent variation in quadriceps isometric endurance. J Appl Physiol. 2005;98:810-816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Murphy BG, Labarbera KE. Neuromuscular function after a bout of low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:67-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M. Effects of an Acute Bout of Low-Load Resistance Training with Blood Flow Restriction-With Special Reference to Muscle Damage, Hypertrophic Signaling and Satellite Cells [doctoral dissertation]. Oslo, Norway: Norwegian School of Sport Sciences; 2011. Retrieved from Google Scholar.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Kim D, Fahs CA, et al. Effects of exercise with and without different degrees of blood flow restriction on torque and muscle activation. Muscle Nerve. 2015;713-721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatela P, Reis JF, Mendonca GV, et al. Acute neuromuscular adaptations in response to low-intensity blood-flow restricted exercise and high-intensity resistance exercise: are there any differences? J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32:902-910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magora A, Blank A, Gonen B. Effects of artificially induced ischemia (AII) on the electrophysiological pattern of muscular fatigue in healthy humans. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1980;20:125-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Watari H. Effect of circulatory occlusion on human muscle metabolism during exercise and recovery. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1997;75:200-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Morita N, et al. Intramuscular metabolism during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:1119-1124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga T, Okita K, Morita N, et al. Dose effect on intramuscular metabolic stress during low-intensity resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:1563-1567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trappe TA, Raue U, Tesch PA. Human soleus muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;182:189-196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravel D, Richards CL, Filion M. Angle dependency in strength measurements of the ankle plantar flexors. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1990;61:182-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters M, Svantesson U, Grimby G. Effect of prior isometric muscle action on concentric torque output during plantar flexion. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1995;71:272-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadeau S, Gravel D, Arsenault AB, Goyette M. Preloading and range of motion effect on plantarflexor muscle performance. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1996;77:1000-1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svantesson U, Grimby G, Thome&#xe9; R. Potentiation of concentric plantar flexion torque following eccentric and isometric muscle actions. Acta Physiol Scand. 1994;152:287-293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanagisawa O, Sanomura M. Effects of low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction on high-energy phosphate metabolism and oxygenation level in skeletal muscle. Interv Med Appl Sci. 2017;9:67-75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saltin B, Gollnick PD. Skeletal muscle adaptability: significance for metabolism and performance. Handbook of Physiology. Skeletal Muscle. 1983;10:555-631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Johansen L, Quistorff B, Saltin B. NMR and analytic biochemical evaluation of CrP and nucleotides in the human calf during muscle contraction. J Appl Physiol. 1993;74:2034-2039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenborne K, Walter G, Ploutz-Snyder L, et al. Energy-rich phosphates in slow and fast human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol. 1995;268:C869-C876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Sato Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with vascular occlusion on muscle function in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;86:308-314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawada S. What phenomena do occur in blood flow-restricted muscle? Int J Kaatsu Training Res. 2005;1:37-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimby L, Hannerz J. Disturbances in voluntary recruitment order of low and high frequency motor units on blockades of proprioceptive afferent activity. Acta Physiol Scand. 1976;96:207-216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchthal F, Pinell P, Rosenfalck P. Action potential parameters in normal human muscle and their physiological determinants. Acta Physiol Scand. 1954;32:219-229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg J, Sullivan SJ, Seaborne DE. The effect of two intensities of massage on H-reflex amplitude. Phys Ther. 1992;72:449-457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robichaud JA, Agostinucci J, Vander Linden DW. Effect of air-splint application on soleus muscle motoneuron reflex excitability in nondisabled subjects and subjects with cerebrovascular accidents. Phys Ther. 1992;72:176-183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostinucci J. Circumferential pressure's inhibitory effects on soleus H-reflex. Transl Neurosci. 2013;4:251-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostinucci J. The effects of circumferential pressure on the soleus muscle F-wave in healthy subjects. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2012;22:223-227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge W, Khalsa PS. Encoding of compressive stress during indentation by group III and IV muscle mechano-nociceptors in rat gracilis muscle. J Neurophysiol. 2003;89:785-792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;rtenblad N, Macdonald WA, Sahlin K. Glycolysis in contracting rat skeletal muscle is controlled by factors related to energy state. Biochem J. 2009;420:161-168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe DA, Alway SE. Animal models for inducing muscle hypertrophy: are they relevant for clinical applications in humans? J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2002;32:36-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Okuyama R, Sugiyama H, et al. Effects of heat stress and mechanical stretch on protein expression in cultured skeletal muscle cells. Pfl&#xfc;gers Arch. 2003;447:247-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Oda H, Kondo H, et al. Responses of muscle mass, strength and gene transcripts to long-term heat stress in healthy human subjects. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:17-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudo M, Ando S, Kano Y. Repeated blood flow restriction induces muscle fiber hypertrophy. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55:274-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natsume T, Ozaki H, Saito AI, Abe T, Naito H. Effects of electrostimulation with blood flow restriction on muscle size and strength. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47:2621-2627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgey AS, Timmons MK, Dolbow DR, et al. Electrical stimulation and blood flow restriction increase wrist extensor cross-sectional area and flow meditated dilatation following spinal cord injury. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:1231-1244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima T, Koide S, Yasuda T, et al. Muscle hypertrophy following blood flow-restricted, low-force isometric electrical stimulation in rat tibialis anterior: role for muscle hypoxia. J Appl Physiol. 2018;125:134-145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz JT, Burr JF. The effects of blood flow restricted electrostimulation on strength and hypertrophy. J Sport Rehabil. 2018;27:257-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Oda H, Morioka S, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy induced by low-intensity exercise with heat stress in healthy human subjects. Jpn J Aerosp Environ Med. 2007;44:13-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med. 2007;37:225-264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DWD, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113:71-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieljacks P, Degn R, Hollaender K, Wernbom M, Vissing K. Non-failure blood flow restricted exercise induces similar muscle adaptations and less discomfort than failure protocols. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29:336-347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Komuro T, Ishiguro N, et al. Effects of low-load resistance training with vascular occlusion on the mechanical properties of muscle and tendon. J Appl Biomech. 2006;22:112-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer-Poveda D, Romero-Arenas S, Vera-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez A, Vi&#xf1;uela-Garc&#xed;a M, M&#xe1;rquez G. Effects of 4 weeks of low-load unilateral resistance training, with and without blood flow restriction, on strength, thickness, V wave, and H reflex of the soleus muscle in men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:1339-1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Scott BR, Hayes KL, Murphy BG. Neuromuscular Adaptations to low-load blood flow restricted resistance training. J Sports Sci Med. 2018;17:66-73.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>