<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35622106</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Volume Load Rather Than Resting Interval Influences Muscle Hypertrophy During High-Intensity Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1554</StartPage><EndPage>1559</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1554-1559</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003668</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Longo, AR, Silva-Batista, C, Pedroso, K, de Salles Painelli, V, Lasevicius, T, Schoenfeld, BJ, Aihara, AY, de Almeida Peres, B, Tricoli, V, and Teixeira, EL. Volume load rather than resting interval influences muscle hypertrophy during high-intensity resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 36(6): 1554-1559, 2022-Interset rest interval has been proposed as an important variable for inducing muscle mass and strength increases during resistance training. However, its influence remains unclear, especially when protocols with differing intervals have equalized volume. We aimed to compare the effects of long (LI) vs. short rest interval (SI) on muscle strength (one repetition maximum [1RM]) and quadriceps cross-sectional area (QCSA), with or without equalized volume load (VL). Twenty-eight subjects trained twice a week for 10 weeks. Each subject's leg was allocated to 1 of 4 unilateral knee extension protocols: LI, SI, SI with VL -matched by LI (VLI-SI), and LI with VL-matched by SI (VSI-LI). A 3-minute rest interval was afforded in LI and VSI-LI protocols, while SI and VLI-SI employed a 1-minute interval. All subjects trained with a load corresponding to 80% 1RM. One repetition maximum and QCSA were measured before and after training. All protocols significantly increased 1RM values in post-training (p &lt; 0.0001; LI: 27.6%, effect size [ES] = 0.90; VLI-SI: 31.1%, ES = 1.00; SI: 26.5%, ES = 1.11; and VSI-LI: 31.2%, ES = 1.28), with no significant differences between protocols. Quadriceps cross-sectional area increased significantly for all protocols in post-training (p &lt; 0.0001). However, absolute changes in QCSA were significantly greater in LI and VLI-SI (13.1%, ES: 0.66 and 12.9%, ES: 0.63) than SI and VSI-LI (6.8%, ES: 0.38 and 6.6%, ES: 0.37) (both comparisons, p &lt; 0.05). These data suggest that maintenance of high loads is more important for strength increases, while a greater VL plays a primary role for hypertrophy, regardless of interset rest interval.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longo</LastName><ForeName>Ariel Roberth</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva-Batista</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Arts, Sciences and Humanities, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedroso</LastName><ForeName>Kelly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Salles Painelli</LastName><ForeName>Vitor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lasevicius</LastName><ForeName>Thiago</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad Jon</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, New York; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aihara</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9; Yui</ForeName><Initials>AY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>America's Diagnostics S/A, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Almeida Peres</LastName><ForeName>Bergson</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tricoli</LastName><ForeName>Valmor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>Emerson Luiz</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paulista University, UNIP, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202206000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Short vs. long rest period between the sets in hypertrophic resistance training: Influence on muscle strength, size, and hormonal adaptations in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 19: 572&#x2013;582, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. ASEP procedures recommendation I: Accurate assessment of muscular strength and power. J Exerc Physiol Online 4: 1&#x2013;21, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buresh R, Berg K, French J. The effect of resistive exercise rest interval on hormonal response, strength, and hypertrophy with training. J Strength Cond Res 23: 62&#x2013;71, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol 88: 50&#x2013;60, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Some issues in power analysis. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 531&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Salles BF, Polito MD, Goessler KF, et al. Effects of fixed vs. self-suggested rest between sets in upper and lower body exercises performance. Eur J Sport Sci 16: 927&#x2013;931, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink JE, Schoenfeld BJ, Kikuchi N, Nakazato K. Acute and long-term responses to different rest intervals in low-load resistance training. Int J Sports Med 38: 118&#x2013;124, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel DA, Kamen G, Frost G. Neural adaptations to resistive exercise. Sports Med 36: 133&#x2013;149, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 955&#x2013;963, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Krieger JW, Schoenfeld BJ. The effects of short versus long inter-set rest intervals in resistance training on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 983&#x2013;993, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henselmans M, Schoenfeld BJ. The effect of inter-set rest intervals on resistance exercise-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med 44: 1635&#x2013;1643, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill-Haas S, Bishop D, Dawson B, Goodman C, Edge J. Effects of rest interval during high-repetition resistance training on strength, aerobic fitness, and repeated-sprint ability. J Sports Sci 25: 619&#x2013;628, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: A meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1150&#x2013;1159, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 772&#x2013;780, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis MJ, McGlory C, Gibala MJ, Phillips SM. Investigating human skeletal muscle physiology with unilateral exercise models: When one limb is more powerful than two. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 42: 563&#x2013;570, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol 113: 71&#x2013;77, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Low-load bench press training to fatigue results in muscle hypertrophy similar to high-load bench press training. Int J Clin Med 4: 114, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piirainen JM, Tanskanen M, Nissil&#xe4; J, et al. Effects of a heart rate&#x2013;based recovery period on hormonal, neuromuscular, and aerobic performance responses during 7 weeks of strength training in men. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2265&#x2013;2273, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 20: S135&#x2013;S145, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low-vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2954&#x2013;2963, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, et al. Longer interset rest periods enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 30: 1805&#x2013;1812, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med 37: 225&#x2013;264, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM. A brief review: Factors affecting the length of the rest interval between resistance exercise sets. J Strength Cond Res 20: 978&#x2013;984, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. The effect of different rest intervals between sets on volume components and strength gains. J Strength Cond Res 22: 146&#x2013;152, 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>