<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34937968</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of resistance training on hypertrophy, strength and tensiomyography parameters of elbow flexors: role of eccentric phase duration.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>587</StartPage><EndPage>594</EndPage><MedlinePgn>587-594</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2021.99323</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of the study was to compare the effects of two different training protocols, which differ in the duration of the eccentric phase, on the one-repetition maximum (1RM), thickness and contractile properties of elbow flexors. Twenty untrained college students were randomly divided into two experimental groups, based on the training tempo: FEG (Faster Eccentric Group: 1/0/1/0) and SEG (Slower Eccentric Group: 4/0/1/0). Training intervention was a biceps bending exercise, conducted twice a week for 7 weeks. The intensity (60-70% RM), sets (3-4) and rest intervals (120 s) were held constant, while repetitions were performed until it was not possible to maintain a set duration. In the initial and final measurements, 1RM, muscle thickness and tensiomyography parameters - contraction time (Tc) and radial deformation (Dm) - were evaluated. An ANCOVA model (using baseline outcomes as covariates) was applied to determine between-group differences at post-test, while Pearson's product-moment correlation coefficient was used to investigate the relationship between absolute changes in muscle thickness and Dm. Muscle strength increase was greater for SEG than for FEG (6.0 &#xb1; 1.76 vs. 3.30 &#xb1; 2.26 kg, p &lt; 0.01). In both groups muscle thickness increased equally (FEG: 3.24 &#xb1; 2.01 vs. SEG: 3.57 &#xb1; 1.17 mm, p &lt; 0.01), while an overall reduction in Dm was observed (FEG: 1.99 &#xb1; 1.20 vs. SEG: 2.26 &#xb1; 1.03 mm, p &lt; 0.01). Values of Tc remained unchanged. A significant negative relationship was observed between changes in muscle thickness and Dm (r = -0.763, Adj.R&#xb2; = 0.560, p &lt; 0.01). These results indicate that the duration of the eccentric phase has no effect on muscle hypertrophy in untrained subjects, but that slower eccentric movement significantly increases 1RM.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Biology of Sport 2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koji&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Filip</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Teacher Education Faculty, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranisavljev</LastName><ForeName>Igor</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Physical Education, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x106;osi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Du&#x161;an</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Center Kovin, Department of Radiology, Kovin, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Popovi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Dejana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Centre of Serbia, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stojiljkovi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Stanimir</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Physical Education, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ili&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Physical Education, University of Belgrade, Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">1 RM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle stiffness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle thickness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tensiomyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training tempo</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors certify that there is no conflict of interest with any financial organization regarding the material discussed in the manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.99323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">99323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baechle TR, Earle RW. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. 3rd ed. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Andrews RJ, West DWD, et al. Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub-fractional synthetic responses in men. J Physiol. 2012;590:351&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22106173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calixto RD, Verenglia R, Crisp AH, et al. Acute effects of movement velocity on blood lactate and growth hormone responses after eccentric bench press exercise in resistance-trained men. Biol Sport. 2014;31:289&#x2013;294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4296844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25609886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cureton K, Collins M, Hill D, McElhannon F. Muscle hypertrophy in men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20:338&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3173042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Barcelos S, Nobrega SR, et al. Individual muscle hypertrophy and strength responses to high vs. low resistance training frequencies. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:897&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30289872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on dynamic muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47:1603&#x2013;1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias CP, Toscan R, de Camargo M, et al. Effects of eccentric-focused and convectional resistance training on strength and functional capacity of older adults. Age. 2015;37:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5005842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26374635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ema R, Akagi R, Wakahara T, Kawakami Y. Training induced changes in architecture of human skeletal muscles: Current evidence and unresolved issues. J Phys Fitness Sports Med. 2016;5:37&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. Morphological and neurological contribution to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37:145&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Manso JM, Garcia-Matoso D, Sarmiento S. Effects of high load and high volume resistance exercise on tensiomyographic twitch response of biceps brachii. J Electromyo Kines. 2012;22:612&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gumucio JP, Sugg KB, Mendias CL. TGF-&#xdf; superfamily signaling in muscle and tendon adaptations to resistance exercise. Exerc Sci Sport Rev. 2015;43:93&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4369187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25607281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Davies TB, Orr R, Kuang K, Halaki M. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on muscle specific hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18:473&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29431597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Osburn SC, et al. Muscle fiber hypertrophy in response to 6 weeks of high-volume resistance training in trained young men is largely attributed to sarcoplasmic hypertrophy. PloS one. 2019;14(6):1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31166954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howe LP, Read P, Waldron M. Muscle hypertrophy: A narrative review on training principles for increasing muscle mass. Strength Cond J. 2017;39:72&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter AM, Galloway SDR, Smith IJ, et al. Assessment of eccentric exercise induced muscle damage of the elbow flexor by tensiomyography. J Electromyo Kines. 2012;22:334&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22336641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulig K, Powers CM, Shellock FG, Terk M. The effects of eccentric velocity on activation of elbow flexors: evaluation by magnetic resonance imaging. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:196&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11224805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macgregor LJ, Hunter AM, Orizio C, Fairweather MM, Ditriolo M. Assessment of skeletal muscle contractile properties by radial displacement: The case for tensiomyography. Sports Med. 2018;48:1607&#x2013;1620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5999145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29605838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mike JN, Cole N, Herrera C, VanDusseldorp T, Kravitz L, Kersick CM. The effect of eccentric contraction duration on muscle strength, power, vertical jump and soreness. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:773&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27787464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Roi GS, Landoni L, Minetti CE, Cerreteli M. Changes in force, cross-sectional area and neural activation during strength training and detraining of human quadriceps. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1989;59:310&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2583179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogueira W, Gentil P, Mello SN, Oliveira RJ, Bezerra AJ, Bottaro M. Effects of power training on muscle thickness of older men. Int J Sports Med. 2016;30:200&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19199198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paula-Simola RA, Harms N, Raeder C, et al. Assessment of neuromuscular function after different strength training protocols using tensiomyography. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:1339&#x2013;1348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25474337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira PEA, Motoyama YL, Esteves GJ, et al. Resistance training with slow speed of movement is better for muscle hypertrophy and strength gains than fast speed of movement. Int J Appl Exerc Physiol. 2016;5:37&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi&#x161;ot R, Narici MV, &#x160;imuni&#x10d; B, et al. Whole muscle contractile parameters and thickness loss during 35-day bed rest. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;104:409&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18297302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryor RR, Sforzo GA, King DL. Optimizing power output by varying repetition tempo. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:3029&#x2013;3034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21881531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkisas S, Baudry S, Bauer J, et al. Application of ultrasound for muscle assessment in sarcopenia: towards standardized measurements. Eur Geriatric Med. 2018;9:739&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34674473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TA. Progession models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:918&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Krieger JW. Effect of repetition duration during resistance training on muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45:577&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low-vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:2954&#x2013;2963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanism of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24:2857&#x2013;2872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuenke MD, Herman JR, Gliders RM, et al. Early-phase muscular adaptations in response to slow-speed versus traditional resistance-training regimens. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:3585&#x2013;3595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikholeslami-Vatani D, Ahmadi D, Chehri B, Tadibi T. The effect of changes in concentric-eccentric contraction time ratio on hormonal response to resistance exercise in trained men. Sci Sports. 2016;33:164&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata T, Tarizawa K, Nosaka K, Mizuno M. Effects of prolonging eccentric phase duration in parallel back-squat training to momentary failure on muscle cross-sectional area, squat one repetition maximum and performance tests in university soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30325791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanimoto M, Sanada K, Yamamoto K, et al. Effects of whole-body low-intensity resistance training with slow-movement and tonic force generation on muscular size and strength in young men. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1926&#x2013;1938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tax AAM, van der Gom DJJ, Gielen CCAM, Kleyne M. Differences in central control of m. biceps brachii in movement task and force tasks. Exp Brain Res. 1990;79:138&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2311690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Than C, To&#x161;ovi&#x107; D, Seidl L, Brown JM. The effect of exercise hypertrophy and disuse atrophy on muscle contractile properties: a mechanomyographic analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:2115&#x2013;2165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27614880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usui S, Maeo S, Tayashiki K, Nakatani M, Kanehisa H. Low load slow movement squat training increases muscle size and strength but not power. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37:305&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Golas A, Krzystofik M, Nawrocka M, Zajec A. The effects of eccentric cadence on power and velocity of the bar during concentric phase of the bench press movement. J Sport Sci Med. 2019;18:191&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Golas A, Zmijewski P, et al. The effects of the movement tempo on the one-repetition maximum bench press results. J Human Kin. 2020;72:151&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32269656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Stastny P, Gola&#x161; A, et al. Physiological responses to different neuromuscular movement tasks during eccentric bench press. Neuroendocrin Lett. 2018;39:26&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29803204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk M, Tufano JJ, Zajac A. The influence of movement tempo on acute neuromuscular, hormonal and mechanical response to resistance exercise- A mini review. J Strength Cond Res. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zubac D, &#x160;imuni&#x10d; B. Skeletal muscle contraction time and tone decrease after 8 week of plyometric training. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:1610&#x2013;1619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>