<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40314751</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Task Specificity of Dynamic Resistance Training and Its Transferability to Non-trained Isometric Muscle Strength: A Systematic Review with Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1651</StartPage><EndPage>1676</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1651-1676</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02225-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Resistance training (RT) specificity has been confirmed for movement patterns (e.g., multi-joint or single joint), movement velocities, ranges of motion, and contraction types (e.g., dynamic vs isometric). However, a systematic analysis of the effects of dynamic mass-loaded (e.g., isoinertial) RT on dynamic versus isometric strength tests is lacking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">We aimed to examine the specific effects of dynamic RT on dynamic (isoinertial) versus isometric muscle strength, including possible moderating factors (e.g., training length, single joint and multi-joint, upper body and lower body, RT status) and mechanisms (e.g., hypertrophy, muscle activation).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A systematic literature search was conducted in MEDLINE (EBSCO), Web of Science, and Scopus up to March 2024. The included interventions contained at least ten training sessions, both dynamic and isometric muscle strength assessments before and after the training period, and healthy participants aged 16-60&#xa0;years (encompassing untrained and trained individuals). Advanced RT approaches, such as electrical stimulation, isokinetic training, velocity-based training, and blood flow restriction training, were excluded. Within-subject, weighted standardized mean differences (SMDs) of the pre-intervention to post-intervention tests were calculated for both dynamic and isometric muscle strength measures using a random-effects model. Univariate sub-group analyses of RT status, intervention length, complexity (i.e., single-joint or multi-joint exercises), and body segments (i.e., upper and lower body) were independently computed. Random-effects meta-regressions were computed to examine if dynamic RT effects on dynamic and isometric muscle strength are predicted by RT effects on muscle hypertrophy or muscle activity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Overall, 43 studies with 1660 participants across 72 different RT interventions were eligible for inclusion. The overall effect on dynamic strength was significant and moderate magnitude (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.98, 95% confidence interval 0.91-1.06, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), whereas the transfer to non-trained isometric strength measures was significant but small (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.42, 95% confidence interval 0.35-0.49, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Sub-analyses demonstrated moderate-to-large task-specific effects (range SMD; 95% confidence interval 0.75-1.30) of conducting dynamic RT and only small-to-medium effects (range SMD; 0.29-0.70) of the transferability of muscle strength to the non-trained isometric contraction form. Muscle hypertrophy and activity changes did not significantly predict dynamic RT effects on dynamic and isometric muscle strength (p&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.222).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings demonstrated task specificity of dynamic RT, as dynamic strength increased with a two-fold larger effect size than non-trained isometric muscle strength. Medium-to-large effects were observed for the dynamic strength improvements in the different sub-group analyses with small-to-medium effects in the isometric improvements. The limited transferability of dynamic (task-specific) strength to non-trained isometric contractions suggests that these two strength outcomes represent different neuromuscular domains.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeterbakken</LastName><ForeName>Atle H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Food and Natural Sciences, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stien</LastName><ForeName>Nicolay</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Food and Natural Sciences, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paulsen</LastName><ForeName>G&#xf8;ran</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Food and Natural Sciences, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behm</LastName><ForeName>David George</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Kinetics and Recreation, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. John's, NL, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andersen</LastName><ForeName>Vidar</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Food and Natural Sciences, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solstad</LastName><ForeName>Tom Erik Jorung</ForeName><Initials>TEJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Food and Natural Sciences, Western Norway University of Applied Sciences, Sogndal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prieske</LastName><ForeName>Olaf</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4475-4413</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Exercise and Movement, University of Applied Sciences for Sports and Management Potsdam, Olympischer Weg 7, Potsdam, 14471, Germany. prieske@fhsmp.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="Y">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Funding: No funding was received for the preparation of this article. Conflicts of Interest/Competing Interests: Atle Hole Saeterbakken, Nicolay Stien, G&#xf8;ran Paulsen, David George Behm, Vidar Andersen, Tom Erik Jorung Solstad, and Olaf Prieske have no conflicts of interest that are directly relevant to the content of this article. Ethics Approval: Not applicable. Consent to Participate: Not applicable. Consent for Publication: Not applicable. Availability of Data and Material: The datasets generated and/or analyzed during the current study will be publicly available in Open Science Framework. Code Availability: Not applicable. Authors&#x2019; Contributions: AHS conceived the original idea and wrote the first draft of the manuscript, conducted the search strategy, scored the included papers, and extracted the data from the included studies. NS screened potential papers, scored the included papers, and provided critical feedback and inputs. DGB and GP provided critical feedback and inputs. VA scored the included papers and provided critical feedback and inputs. TEJS scored the included papers and provided critical feedback and inputs. OP analyzed the data, created the figures, helped with supervision of the project, and provided critical feedback, comments, and inputs.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40314751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12296774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02225-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02225-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abernethy P, Wilson G, Logan P. Strength and power assessment: issues, controversies and challenges. Sports Med. 1995;19(6):401&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7676101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorstensson A, Hulten B, von Dobeln W, et al. Effect of strength training on enzyme activities and fibre characteristics in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 1976;96(3):392&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">179278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitz RW, Kataoka R, Dankel SJ, et al. Quantifying the generality of strength adaptation: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(3):637&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36396899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasch PJ, Morehouse LE. Effect of static and dynamic exercises on muscular strength and hypertrophy. J Appl Physiol. 1957;11(1):29&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13462914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford OM, Jones DA. The role of learning and coordination in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1986;55(1):100&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thepaut-Mathieu C, Van Hoecke J, Maton B. Myoelectrical and mechanical changes linked to length specificity during isometric training. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1988;64(4):1500&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3378984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitai TA, Sale DG. Specificity of joint angle in isometric training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1989;58(7):744&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2737195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Sale DG. Velocity specificity of resistance training. Sports Med. 1993;15(6):374&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8341872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moffroid MT, Whipple RH. Specificity of speed of exercise. Phys Ther. 1970;50(12):1692&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5481818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesmes GR, Costill DL, Coyle EF, et al. Muscle strength and power changes during maximal isokinetic training. Med Sci Sports. 1978;10(4):266&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">750845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanehisa H, Miyashita M. Specificity of velocity in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1983;52(1):104&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6686117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale D, MacDougall D. Specificity in strength training: a review for the coach and athlete. Can J Appl Sport Sci. 1981;6(2):87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7016357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrissey MC, Harman EA, Johnson MJ. Resistance training modes: specificity and effectiveness. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27(5):648&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7674868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Weakley J, Comfort P, et al. The relationship between isometric and dynamic strength following resistance training: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and level of agreement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;19(1):2&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37741636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Murphy AJ. The use of isometric tests of muscular function in athletic assessment. Sports Med. 1996;22(1):19&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8819238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, et al. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2012;113(1):71&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Fisher J, Steele J. A review of the acute effects and long-term adaptations of single- and multi-joint exercises during resistance training. Sports Med. 2017;47(5):843&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27677913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brearley S, Bishop C. Transfer of training: how specific should we be? Strength Cond J. 2019;41(3):97&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum D, Barbosa TM. Brief review: effects of isometric strength training on strength and dynamic performance. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40(6):363&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30943568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Wagner CM, Keiner M, et al. Maximal strength measurement: a critical evaluation of common methods-a narrative review. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:1105201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9981657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36873661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Test-retest reliability of the one-repetition maximum (1RM) strength assessment: a systematic review. Sports Med Open. 2020;6(1):31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med. 2016;46(10):1419&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks R. The effect of isometric quadriceps strength training in mid-range for osteoarthritis of the knee. Arthritis Care Res. 1993;6(1):52&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8443259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagberg M, Harms-Ringdahl K, Nisell R, et al. Rehabilitation of neck-shoulder pain in women industrial workers: a randomized trial comparing isometric shoulder endurance training with isometric shoulder strength training. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2000;81(8):1051&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10943754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullrich B, Kleinoder H, Bruggemann GP. Influence of length-restricted strength training on athlete&#x2019;s power-load curves of knee extensors and flexors. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(3):668&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20145573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Pain MT, Folland JP. Short-term unilateral resistance training affects the agonist-antagonist but not the force-agonist activation relationship. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43(3):375&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21319165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA, Rutherford OM. Human muscle strength training: the effects of three different regimens and the nature of the resultant changes. J Physiol. 1987;391:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1192197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3443943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beltman JG, van der Vliet MR, Sargeant AJ, et al. Metabolic cost of lengthening, isometric and shortening contractions in maximally stimulated rat skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 2004;182(2):179&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15450114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newham DJ, Jones DA, Turner DL, et al. The metabolic costs of different types of contractile activity of the human adductor pollicis muscle. J Physiol. 1995;488(Pt 3):815&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1156747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8576871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady CJ, Harrison AJ, Comyns TM. A review of the reliability of biomechanical variables produced during the isometric mid-thigh pull and isometric squat and the reporting of normative data. Sports Biomech. 2020;19(1):1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29781788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stien N, Riiser A, Shaw MP, et al. Effects of climbing- and resistance-training on climbing-specific performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Biol Sport. 2023;40(1):179&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9806751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36636194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoladz JA, Szkutnik Z, Majerczak J, et al. Isometric strength training lowers the O<sub>2</sub> cost of cycling during moderate-intensity exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(12):4151&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22526253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albracht K, Arampatzis A. Exercise-induced changes in triceps surae tendon stiffness and muscle strength affect running economy in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(6):1605&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23328797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Hawker K, Leach B, et al. Strength training: isometric training at a range of joint angles versus dynamic training. J Sports Sci. 2005;23(8):817&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott BC, Wilson GJ, Kerr GK. A biomechanical analysis of the sticking region in the bench press. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1989;21(4):450&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2779404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Ettema G. A comparison of successful and unsuccessful attempts in maximal bench pressing. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(11):2056&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19812510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Prieske O, Jorung Solstad TE, et al. Does relative strength influence bench press kinematics in resistance-trained men? J Sports Sci. 2022;40(20):2225&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36413441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum D, Haff GG, Barbosa TM. The relationship between isometric force-time characteristics and dynamic performance: a systematic review. Sports (Basel). 2020;8(5):63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7281606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32429176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Talpey SW, Young WB, et al. Strength classification and diagnosis: not all strength is created equal. Strength Cond J. 2023;45(3):333&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Katch FI, LaChance PF. Interrelationships among various measures of upper body strength assessed by different contraction modes: evidence for a general strength component. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1989;58(7):749&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2737196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banyard HG, Nosaka K, Haff GG. Reliability and validity of the load-velocity relationship to predict the 1RM back squat. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(7):1897&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27669192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Aagaard P, Monte A, et al. The role of pennation angle and architectural gearing to rate of force development in dynamic and isometric muscle contractions. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34(5): e14639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38686976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milner TE, Cloutier C. Compensation for mechanically unstable loading in voluntary wrist movement. Exp Brain Res. 1993;94(3):522&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8359266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darainy M, Ostry DJ. Muscle cocontraction following dynamics learning. Exp Brain Res. 2008;190(2):153&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18584164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haugen ME, Varvik FT, Larsen S, et al. Effect of free-weight vs. machine-based strength training on maximal strength, hypertrophy and jump performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15(1):103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10426227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37582807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25554246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LP, Weakley J, Comfort P, et al. The relationship between isometric and dynamic strength following resistance training: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and level of agreement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023;18(2):1427&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37741636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieske O, Chaabene H, Moran J, et al. Editorial: adaptations to advanced resistance training strategies in youth and adult athletes. Front Physiol. 2022;13: 888118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9009352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Applications of the dose-response for muscular strength development: a review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J Strength Cond Res. 2005;19(4):950&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Nigro F, Lanzoni IM, et al. A comparison between total body and split routine resistance training programs in trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(6):1520&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32168178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Wilson G, Carlyon B. Generality versus specificity: a comparison of dynamic and isometric measures of strength and speed-strength. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;68(4):350&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8055895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drevon D, Fursa SR, Malcolm AL. Intercoder reliability and validity of WebPlotDigitizer in extracting graphed data. Behav Modif. 2017;41(2):323&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27760807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brughelli M, Cronin J, Levin G, et al. Understanding change of direction ability in sport: a review of resistance training studies. Sports Med. 2008;38(12):1045&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, et al. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2003;83(8):713&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Bosch F, Meijer K. Can resistance training enhance the rapid force development in unloaded dynamic isoinertial multi-joint movements? A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(8):2324&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28737611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrel JA, Keith SW, Leiby BE. Meta-analysis: a brief introduction. Clin Transl Sci. 2009;2(5):374&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5350756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20443922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Statistical models for meta-analysis: a brief tutorial. World J Methodol. 2012;2(4):27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4145560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25237614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deo SV, Deo VS. Systematic review and meta-analysis: a brief introduction. Indian J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2022;38(3):342&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9023640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie JE, Salanti G, Lewis SC, et al. Meta-analysis and The Cochrane Collaboration: 20&#xa0;years of the Cochrane Statistical Methods Group. Syst Rev. 2013;2:80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4219183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24280020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Young JD, Whitten JHD, et al. Effectiveness of traditional strength vs. power training on muscle strength, power and speed with youth: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2017;8:423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5491841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28713281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: explanation and elaboration. J Clin Epidemiol. 2009;62(10):e1&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19631507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, et al. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, et al. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(1):3&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamson M, Macquaide N, Helgerud J, et al. Unilateral arm strength training improves contralateral peak force and rate of force development. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;103(5):553&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18443814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akagi R, Sato S, Hirata N, et al. Eight-week low-intensity squat training at slow speed simultaneously improves knee and hip flexion and extension strength. Front Physiol. 2020;11:893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alegre LM, Jimenez F, Gonzalo-Orden JM, et al. Effects of dynamic resistance training on fascicle length and isometric strength. J Sports Sci. 2006;24(5):501&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16608764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer KS, Fukuda DH, Boone CH, et al. Short-term unilateral resistance training results in cross education of strength without changes in muscle size, activation, or endocrine response. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(5):1213&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26466136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomquist K, Langberg H, Karlsen S, et al. Effect of range of motion in heavy load squatting on muscle and tendon adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(8):2133&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23604798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botton CE, Radaelli R, Wilhelm EN, et al. Neuromusclar adaptations to unilaterl vs. bilateral strength training in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(7):1924&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26348920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braith RW, Graves JE, Pollock ML, et al. Comparison of 2 vs 3&#xa0;days/week of variable resistance training during 10- and 18- week programs. Int J Sports Med. 1989;10(6):450&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2628366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaouachi A, Ben Othman A, Chaouachi M, et al. Comparison of cross-education and global training effects in adults and youth after unilateral strength training. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36(8):2121&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer-Poveda D, Romero-Arenas S, Farinas J, et al. Training load but not fatigue affects cross-education of maximal voluntary force. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31(2):313&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comfort P, Dos'Santos T, Thomas C, et al. An investigation into the effects of excluding the catch phase of the power clean on force-time characteristics during isometric and dynamic tasks: an intervention study. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(8):2116&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29889775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras B, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effects of a six-week hip thrust vs. front squat resistance training program on performance in adolescent males: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(4):999&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27253835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Scott BR, Hayes KL, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations to low-load blood flow restricted resistance training. J Sports Sci Med. 2018;17(1):66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5844210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McCaulley GO, McBride JM. Power versus strength-power jump squat training: influence on the load-power relationship. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(6):996&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17545891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diniz RCR, Tourino FD, de Lacerda LT, et al. Resistance training intervention performed with different muscle action durations influences the maximal dynamic strength without promoting joint-angle specific strength gains. J Sports Sci. 2021;39(21):2386&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34107836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MDM, Couto BP, Augusto IG, et al. Effects of 12&#xa0;weeks of dynamic strength training with local vibration. Eur J Sport Sci. 2014;4(7):695&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Fletcher G, Folland JP. The contribution of muscle hypertrophy to strength changes following resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(6):1239&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24610245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine RM, Jones DA, Williams AG, et al. Inter-individual variability in the adaptation of human muscle specific tension to progressive resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;110(6):1117&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20703498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faude O, Roth R, Di Giovine D, et al. Combined strength and power training in high-level amateur football during the competitive season: a randomised-controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(13):1460&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23768214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fimland MS, Helgerud J, Gruber M, et al. Functional maximal strength training induces neural transfer to single-joint tasks. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(1):21&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19504119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AC, Powell DR, Kraemer WJ. Validity of isokinetic and isometric testing modalities for assessing short-term resistance exercise strength gains. J Sport Rehabil. 1992;1(4):275&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves JE, Pollock ML, Leggett SH, et al. Effect of reduced training frequency on muscular strength. Int J Sports Med. 1988;9(5):316&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3246465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves JE, Webb DC, Pollock ML, et al. Pelvic stabilization during resistance training: its effect on the development of lumbar extension strength. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1994;75(2):210&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8311680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamas L, Ugrinowitsch C, Rodacki A, et al. Effects of strength and power training on neuromuscular adaptions and jumping movement pattern and performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(12):3335&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22222321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Yasuda T, Ishii N, et al. Comparison of muscle hypertrophy following 6-month of continuous and periodic strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(4):975&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter KB, Haff GG, Ramsey MW, et al. Strength gains: block versus daily undulating periodization weight training among track and field athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2012;7(2):161&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22173008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Olsen A, Behm DG, et al. The short- and long-term effects of resistance training with different stability requirements. PLoS One. 2019;14(4):e0214302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6443166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30934001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG, Martin JE, Moroz DE. Hypertrophy without increased isometric strength after weight training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1992;64(1):51&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1735412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stien N, Pedersen H, Ravnoy AH, et al. Training specificity performing single-joint vs. multi-joint resistance exercises among physically active females: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2020;15(5):e0233540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7259582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, McKeever SM, Comfort P. Training with weightlifting derivatives: the effects of force and velocity overload stimuli. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(7):1808&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toohey JC, Townsend JR, Johnson SB, et al. Effects of probiotic (<i>Bacillus subtilis</i>) supplementation during offseason resistance training in female Division I athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(11):3173&#x2013;81.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33105368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travis SK, Zwetsloot KA, Mujika I, et al. Skeletal muscle adaptations and performance outcomes following a step and exponential taper in strength athletes. Front Physiol. 2021;12: 735932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8582352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34777004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trzaskoma &#x141;, Tihanyi L, Trzaskoma Z. The effect of a short-term combined conditioning training for the development of leg strength and power. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(9):2498&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20802288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir LP, Housh DJ, Housh TJ, et al. The effect of unilatera eccentric weight training and detraining on joint angle specificity, cross-training, and the bilateral deficit. J Ortho Sports Phys Ther. 1995;22(5):207&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8580948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Newton RU, Murphy AJ, et al. The optimal training load for the development of dynamic athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1993;25(11):1279&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8289617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Keiner M, Hartmann H, et al. Effect of 8&#xa0;weeks of free-weight and machine-based strength training on strength and power performance. J Hum Kinet. 2016;53:201&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5260589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28149424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth K, Keiner M, Szilvas E, et al. Effects of eccentric strength training on different maximal strength and speed-strength parameters of the lower extremity. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(7):1837&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki M, et al. Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(10):2525&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Buckner SL, Jessee MB, et al. Practicing the test produces strength equivalent to higher volume training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(9):1945&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. A randomized trial to consider the effect of Romanian deadlift exercise on the development of lumbar extension strength. Phys Ther Sport. 2013;14(3):139&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23867152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins SA, Wiswell RA, Schroeder ET. The relationship between bone adaptations to resistance exercise and reproductive-hormone levels. J Aging Phys Act. 2002;10(1):64&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, et al. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2005;37(6):964&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Myklestad D, Raastad T. The influence of volume of exercise on early adaptations to strength training. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(1):115&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen V, Fimland MS, Kolnes MK, et al. Elastic bands in combination with free weights in strength training: neuromuscular effects. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2932&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25807031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PW, McEwen M, Robbins DW. Strength and neuromuscular adaptation following one, four, and eight sets of high intensity resistance exercise in trained males. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(12):3007&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21451937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadlec D, Sainani KL, Nimphius S. With great power comes great responsibility: common errors in meta-analyses and meta-regressions in strength &amp; conditioning research. Sports Med. 2023;53(2):313&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9877053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36208412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeterbakken AH, Andersen V, Behm DG, et al. Resistance-training exercises with different stability requirements: time course of task specificity. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(11&#x2013;12):2247&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27671996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Counts BR, Barnett BE, et al. Muscle adaptations following 21 consecutive days of strength test familiarization compared with traditional training. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(2):307&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27875635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake D, Kennedy R, Wallace E. Familiarization, validity and smallest detectable difference of the isometric squat test in evaluating maximal strength. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(18):2087&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishida A, Suarez DG, Travis SK, et al. Intrasession and intersession reliability of isometric squat, midthigh pull, and squat jump in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(1):18&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36515586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Burkett LN, et al. A meta-analysis to determine the dose response for strength development. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(3):456&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(1):94&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Calder AW, Sale DG, et al. A comparison of strength and muscle mass increases during resistance training in young women. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1998;77(1&#x2013;2):170&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9459538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Massey GJ, Maden-Wilkinson TM, et al. Changes in agonist neural drive, hypertrophy and pre-training strength all contribute to the individual strength gains after resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(4):631&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28239775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37(2):145&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber CB, Vigotsky A, Nuckols G, et al. Exercise-induced myofibrillar hypertrophy is a contributory cause of gains in muscle strength. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):993&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31016546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigotsky AD, Halperin I, Lehman GJ, et al. Interpreting signal amplitudes in surface electromyography studies in sport and rehabilitation sciences. Front Physiol. 2017;8:985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29354060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG. Neuromuscular implications and applications of resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 1995;9(4):264&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamori N, Rossi SJ, Justice BD, et al. Peak force and rate of force development during isometric and dynamic mid-thigh clean pulls performed at various intensities. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):483&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Requena B, Garcia I, Requena F, et al. Relationship between traditional and ballistic squat exercise with vertical jumping and maximal sprinting. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(8):2193&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21572354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindberg K, Solberg P, Bjornsen T, et al. Strength and power testing of athletes: associations of common assessments over time. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(8):1280&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35894923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Tillaar R, Ettema G. A comparison of muscle activity in concentric and counter movement maximum bench press. J Hum Kinet. 2013;38:63&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3827767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24235985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Murphy AJ, Pryor JF. Musculotendinous stiffness: its relationship to eccentric, isometric, and concentric performance. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1994;76(6):2714&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7928905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>