<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33044332</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-3008</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Exercise and sport sciences reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exerc Sport Sci Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strength Training: In Search of Optimal Strategies to Maximize Neuromuscular Performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2</StartPage><EndPage>14</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2-14</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/JES.0000000000000234</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Training with low-load exercise performed under blood flow restriction can augment muscle hypertrophy and maximal strength to a similar extent as the classical high-load strength training method. However, the blood flow restriction method elicits only minor neural adaptations. In an attempt to maximize training-related gains, we propose using other protocols that combine high voluntary activation, mechanical tension, and metabolic stress.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duchateau</LastName><ForeName>Jacques</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Applied Biology and Neurophysiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stragier</LastName><ForeName>S&#xe9;verine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baudry</LastName><ForeName>St&#xe9;phane</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Applied Biology and Neurophysiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carpentier</LastName><ForeName>Alain</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Biometry and Exercise Nutrition, Universit&#xe9; Libre de Bruxelles, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Exerc Sport Sci Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0375434</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0091-6331</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2022 Oct 1;50(4):173-174. doi: 10.1249/JES.0000000000000292.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36095072</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00003677-202101000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hellebrandt FA, Houtz SJ. Mechanisms of muscle training in man: experimental demonstration of the overload principle. Phys. Ther. Rev . 1956; 36(6):371&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2009; 41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2004; 36(4):674&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG, MacDougall JD, Alway SE, Sutton JR. Voluntary strength and muscle characteristics in untrained men and women and male bodybuilders. J. Appl. Physiol . 1987; 62(5):1786&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2017; 31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf8;nfeldt BM, Lindberg Nielsen J, Mieritz RM, Lund H, Aagaard P. Effect of blood-flow restricted vs heavy-load strength training on muscle strength: systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports . 2020; 30(5):837&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br. J. Sports Med . 2017; 51(13):1003&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2018; 48(2):361&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney KJ, Herbert RD, Balnave RJ. Fatigue contributes to the strength training stimulus. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 1994; 26(9):1160&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schott J, McCully K, Rutherford OM. The role of metabolites in strength training. II. Short versus long isometric contractions. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol . 1995; 71(4):337&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manini TM, Clark BC. Blood flow restricted exercise and skeletal muscle health. Exerc. Sport Sci. Rev . 2009; 37(2):78&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Schoenfeld BJ, Paulsen G, et al. Commentary: can blood flow restricted exercise cause muscle damage? Commentary on blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front. Physiol . 2020; 11:243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ, Hussain SR. A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med . 2015; 45(2):187&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, Nindl BC. Recovery responses of testosterone, growth hormone, and IGF-1 after resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol . 2017; 122(3):549&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcotte GR, West DW, Baar K. The molecular basis for load-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Calcif. Tissue Int . 2015; 96(3):196&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, Phillips SM. Exercise and the regulation of skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Prog. Mol. Biol. Transl. Sci . 2015; 135:153&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Pope ZK, Benik FM, et al. Longer interset rest periods enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2016; 30(7):1805&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J, Lundbye-Jensen J. Assessment of neuroplasticity with strength training. Exerc. Sport. Sci. Rev . 2020; 48(4):151&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Selvanayagam VS, Riek S, Semmler JG. Neural adaptations to strength training: moving beyond transcranial magnetic stimulation and reflex studies. Acta Physiol (Oxf) . 2011; 202(2):119&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Semmler JG, Enoka RM. Training adaptations in the behavior of human motor units. J. Appl. Physiol . 2006; 101(6):1766&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Baudry S. Training adaptation of the neuromuscular system. In: Komi PV, editor. Neuromuscular Aspects of Sport Performance , XVII. Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell; 2011. p. 216&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med . 2007; 37(2):145&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vierck J, O&#x2019;Reilly B, Hossner K, et al. Satellite cell regulation following myotrauma caused by resistance exercise. Cell Biol. Int . 2000; 24(5):263&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Andersen JL, Dyhre-Poulsen P, et al. A mechanism for increased contractile strength of human pennate muscle in response to strength training: changes in muscle architecture. J. Physiol . 2001; 534(Pt. 2):613&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami Y, Abe T, Kuno SY, Fukunaga T. Training-induced changes in muscle architecture and specific tension. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol . 1995; 72(1&#x2013;2):37&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Grumbt WH, Stray-Gundersen J, Gonyea WJ. Effects of resistance training on elbow flexors of highly competitive bodybuilders. J. Appl. Physiol . 1992; 72(4):1512&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Noble BJ, Clark MJ, Culver BW. Physiologic responses to heavy-resistance exercise with very short rest periods. Int. J. Sports Med . 1987; 8(4):247&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Ugrinowitsch C, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Effects of different intensities of resistance training with equated volume load on muscle strength and hypertrophy. Eur. J. Sport Sci . 2018; 18(6):772&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolstenhulme MT, Conlee RK, Drummond MJ, Stites AW, Parcell AC. Temporal response of desmin and dystrophin proteins to progressive resistance exercise in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol . 2006; 100(6):1876&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinohara M, Kouzaki M, Yoshihisa T, Fukunaga T. Efficacy of tourniquet ischemia for strength training with low resistance. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol . 1998; 77(1&#x2013;2):189&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Tanaka Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J. Appl. Physiol . 2000; 88(6):2097&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaijser L, Sundberg CJ, Eiken O, et al. Muscle oxidative capacity and work performance after training under local leg ischemia. J. Appl. Physiol . 1990; 69(2):785&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM, Hoffman RL, et al. Relative safety of 4 weeks of blood flow-restricted resistance exercise in young, healthy adults. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports . 2011; 21(5):653&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Abe T, Sato Y, Bemben MG. The effects of low-intensity resistance training with vascular restriction on leg muscle strength in older men. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2010; 108(1):147&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Komuro T, Ishiguro N, et al. Effects of low-load resistance training with vascular occlusion on the mechanical properties of muscle and tendon. J. Appl. Biomech . 2006; 22(2):112&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Hamlin MJ, Ross JJ, Taylor R, Manimmanakorn N. Effects of low-load resistance training combined with blood flow restriction or hypoxia on muscle function and performance in netball athletes. J. Sci. Med. Sport . 2013; 16(4):337&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Loenneke JP, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Blood flow restricted exercise for athletes: a review of available evidence. J. Sci. Med. Sport . 2016; 19:360&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnsen T, Wernbom M, Kirketeig A, et al. Type 1 muscle fiber hypertrophy after blood flow-restricted training in powerlifters. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2019; 51(2):288&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh MJ, Davies CT. Adaptive response of mammalian skeletal muscle to exercise with high loads. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol . 1984; 52(2):139&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamosh M, Lesch M, Baron J, Kaufman S. Enhanced protein synthesis in a cell-free system from hypertrophied skeletal muscle. Science . 1967; 157(3791):935&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg AL, Etlinger JD, Goldspink DF, Jablecki C. Mechanism of work-induced hypertrophy of skeletal muscle. Med. Sci. Sports . 1975; 7(3):185&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong TS, Booth FW. Protein metabolism in rat gastrocnemius muscle after stimulated chronic concentric exercise. J. Appl. Physiol . 1990; 69(5):1709&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen LA, Nicoll JX, Fry AC. The skeletal muscle fiber: a mechanically sensitive cell. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2019; 119(2):333&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, Phillips SM. Assessing the regulation of skeletal muscle plasticity in response to protein ingestion and resistance exercise: recent developments. Curr. Opin. Clin. Nutr. Metab. Care . 2014; 17(5):412&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velloso CP. Regulation of muscle mass by growth hormone and IGF-I. Br. J. Pharmacol . 2008; 154(3):557&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldspink G. Mechanical signals, IGF-I gene splicing, and muscle adaptation. Physiology (Bethesda) . 2005; 20:232&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spangenburg EE, Le Roith D, Ward CW, Bodine SC. A functional insulin-like growth factor receptor is not necessary for load-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J. Physiol . 2008; 586(1):283&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Charifi N, Denis C, et al. The behaviour of satellite cells in response to exercise: what have we learned from human studies? Pflugers Arch . 2005; 451(2):319&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relaix F, Zammit PS. Satellite cells are essential for skeletal muscle regeneration: the cell on the edge returns centre stage. Development . 2012; 139(16):2845&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luk HY, Levitt DE, Boyett JC, et al. Resistance exercise-induced hormonal response promotes satellite cell proliferation in untrained men but not in women. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab . 2019; 317(2):E421&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha-Hikim I, Cornford M, Gaytan H, Lee ML, Bhasin S. Effects of testosterone supplementation on skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy and satellite cells in community-dwelling older men. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab . 2006; 91(8):3024&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanssen KE, Kvamme NH, Nilsen TS, et al. The effect of strength training volume on satellite cells, myogenic regulatory factors, and growth factors. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports . 2013; 23(6):728&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg TR, Mart&#xed;nez-Aranda LM, Sanz G, et al. Early accentuated muscle hypertrophy is strongly associated with myonuclear accretion. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol . 2020; 319(1):R50&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, et al. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J. Physiol . 2012; 590(17):4351&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson L, Tesch PA. Motor unit fibre density in extremely hypertrophied skeletal muscles in man. Electrophysiological signs of muscle fibre hyperplasia. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol . 1986; 55(2):130&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Thornell LE. Concomitant increases in myonuclear and satellite cell content in female trapezius muscle following strength training. Histochem. Cell Biol . 2000; 113(2):99&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med . 2013; 43(3):179&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Loenneke JP. Do metabolites that are produced during resistance exercise enhance muscle hypertrophy? Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2017; 117(11):2125&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon S, Jenkins D. Factors affecting the rate of phosphocreatine resynthesis following intense exercise. Sports Med . 2002; 32(12):761&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto K, Ishii N, Kizuka T, Takamatsu K. The impact of metabolic stress on hormonal responses and muscular adaptations. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2005; 37(6):955&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalbandian M, Takeda M. Lactate as a signaling molecule that regulates exercise-induced adaptations. Biology . 2016; 5(4):38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Loenneke JP, Buckner SL, Abe T. Muscle growth across a variety of exercise modalities and intensities: contributions of mechanical and metabolic stimuli. Med. Hypotheses . 2016; 88:22&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J. Appl. Physiol . 2010; 108(5):1199&#x2013;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dentel JN, Blanchard SG, Ankrapp DP, McCabe LR, Wiseman RW. Inhibition of cross-bridge formation has no effect on contraction-associated phosphorylation of p38 MAPK in mouse skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Cell Physiol . 2005; 288(4):C824&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada S, Okita K, Suga T, et al. Low-intensity exercise can increase muscle mass and strength proportionally to enhanced metabolic stress under ischemic conditions. J. Appl. Physiol . 2012; 113(2):199&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ikeda T, Homma T, Suzuki Y. Effects of low-intensity resistance exercise under acute systemic hypoxia on hormonal responses. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2012; 26(3):611&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oishi Y, Tsukamoto H, Yokokawa T, et al. Mixed lactate and caffeine compound increases satellite cell activity and anabolic signals for muscle hypertrophy. J. Appl. Physiol . 2015; 118(6):742&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willkomm L, Schubert S, Jung R, et al. Lactate regulates myogenesis in C2C12 myoblasts in vitro. Stem Cell Res . 2014; 12(3):742&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsukamoto S, Shibasaki A, Naka A, Saito H, Iida K. Lactate promotes myoblast differentiation and myotube hypertrophy via a pathway involving MyoD in vitro and enhances muscle regeneration in vivo. Int. J. Mol. Sci . 2018; 19(11):3649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Acute hormonal and neuromuscular responses and recovery to forced vs maximum repetitions multiple resistance exercises. Int. J. Sports Med . 2003; 24(6):410&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Hormonal responses and adaptations to resistance exercise and training. Sports Med . 2005; 35(4):339&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingren JL, Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA, Anderson JM, Volek JS, Maresh CM. Testosterone physiology in resistance exercise and training: the up-stream regulatory elements. Sports Med . 2010; 40(12):1037&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Tang JE, et al. Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J. Appl. Physiol . 2010; 108(1):60&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buresh R, Berg K, French J. The effect of resistive exercise rest interval on hormonal response, strength, and hypertrophy with training. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2009; 23(1):62&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther B, Keogh J, Cronin J, Cook C. Possible stimuli for strength and power adaptation: acute hormonal responses. Sports Med . 2006; 36(3):215&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sculthorpe N, Solomon AM, Sinanan ACM, Bouloux PM, Grace F, Lewis MP. Androgens affect myogenesis in vitro and increase local IGF-1 expression. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2012; 44(4):610&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, Storer TW, Berman N, et al. The effects of supraphysiologic doses of testosterone on muscle size and strength in normal men. N. Engl. J. Med . 1996; 335(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvorning T, Andersen M, Brixen K, Schjerling P, Suetta C, Madsen K. Suppression of testosterone does not blunt mRNA expression of myoD, myogenin, IGF, myostatin or androgen receptor post strength training in humans. J. Physiol . 2007; 578(Pt. 2):579&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Pujol TJ, Bemben MG. Acute and chronic testosterone response to blood flow restricted exercise. Horm. Metab. Res . 2011; 43(10):669&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder ET, Villanueva M, West DDW, Phillips SM. Are acute post-resistance exercise increases in testosterone, growth hormone, and IGF-1 necessary to stimulate skeletal muscle anabolism and hypertrophy? Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2013; 45(11):2044&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKendry J, P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez A, McLeod M, et al. Short inter-set rest blunts resistance exercise-induced increases in myofibrillar protein synthesis and intracellular signalling in young males. Exp. Physiol . 2016; 101(7):866&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottaro M, Martins B, Gentil P, Wagner D. Effects of rest duration between sets of resistance training on acute hormonal responses in trained women. J. Sci. Med. Sport . 2009; 12(1):73&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doessing S, Heinemeier KM, Holm L, et al. Growth hormone stimulates the collagen synthesis in human tendon and skeletal muscle without affecting myofibrillar protein synthesis. J. Physiol . 2010; 588(Pt. 2):341&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce JR, Clark BC, Ploutz-Snyder LL, Kanaley JA. Growth hormone and muscle function responses to skeletal muscle ischemia. J. Appl. Physiol . 2006; 101(6):1588&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves GV, Kraemer RR, Hollander DB, et al. Comparison of hormone responses following light resistance exercise with partial vascular occlusion and moderately difficult resistance exercise without occlusion. J. Appl. Physiol . 2006; 101(6):1616&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J. Appl. Physiol . 2000; 88(1):61&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatela P, Mendonca GV, Veloso AP, Avela J, Mil-Homens P. Blood flow restriction alters motor unit behavior during resistance exercise. Int. J. Sports Med . 2019; 40(9):555&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpentier A, Duchateau J, Hainaut K. Motor unit behaviour and contractile changes during fatigue in the human first dorsal interosseus. J. Physiol . 2001; 534(Pt. 3):903&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Translating fatigue to human performance. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2016; 48(11):2228&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitts RH. The role of acidosis in fatigue: pro perspective. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2016; 48(11):2335&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Place N, Yamada T, Bruton JD, Westerblad H. Muscle fatigue: from observations in humans to underlying mechanisms studied in intact single muscle fibres. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2010; 110(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Hainaut K. Electrical and mechanical failures during sustained and intermittent contractions in humans. J. Appl. Physiol . 1985; 58(3):942&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchthal F, Schmalbruch H. Contraction times and fibre types in intact human muscle. Acta Physiol. Scand . 1970; 79:435&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Rotarius T, Scheuermann BW. The effect of eccentric exercise with blood flow restriction on neuromuscular activation, microvascular oxygenation, and the repeated bout effect. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2017; 117(5):1005&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Brechue WF, Fujita T, Shirakawa J, Sato Y, Abe T. Muscle activation during low-intensity muscle contractions with restricted blood flow. J. Sports Sci . 2009; 27(5):479&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, J&#xe4;rrebring R, Andreasson MA, Augustsson J. Acute effects of blood flow restriction on muscle activity and endurance during fatiguing dynamic knee extensions at low load. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2009; 23(8):2389&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booghs C, Baudry S, Enoka R, Duchateau J. Influence of neural adjustments and muscle oxygenation on task failure during sustained isometric contractions with elbow flexor muscles. Exp. Physiol . 2012; 97(8):918&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK, Enoka RM. Changes in muscle activation can prolong the endurance time of a submaximal isometric contraction in humans. J. Appl. Physiol . 2003; 94(1):108&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baudry S, Sarrazin S, Duchateau J. Effects of load magnitude on muscular activity and tissue oxygenation during repeated elbow flexions until failure. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2013; 113(7):1895&#x2013;904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG: an update. J. Appl. Physiol . 2014; 117(11):1215&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adreani CM, Kaufman MP. Effect of arterial occlusion on responses of group III and IV afferents to dynamic exercise. J. Appl. Physiol . 1998; 84(6):1827&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JL, Amann M, Duchateau J, Meeusen R, Rice CL. Neural contributions to muscle fatigue: from the brain to the muscle and back again. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2016; 48(11):2294&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC, Allen GM, Butler JE, Taylor JL. Supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue: evidence for suboptimal output from the motor cortex. J. Physiol . 1996; 490(Pt 2):529&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman MP, Rybicki KJ, Waldrop TG, Ordway GA. Effect of ischemia on responses of group III and IV afferents to contraction. J. Appl. Physiol . 1984; 57(3):644&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Farias Zuniga A, et al. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. J. Physiol . 2019; 597:4601&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Newton RU, Gordon SE, et al. Changes in muscle morphology, electromyographic activity, and force production characteristics during progressive strength training in young and older men. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci . 1998; 53(6):B415&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am. J. Phys. Med . 1979; 58(3):115&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Roi GS, Landoni L, Minetti AE, Cerretelli P. Changes in force, cross-sectional area and neural activation during strength training and detraining of the human quadriceps. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol . 1989; 59(4):310&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson SP, Halkjaer-Kristensen J, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Neural inhibition during maximal eccentric and concentric quadriceps contraction: effects of resistance training. J. Appl. Physiol . 2000; 89(6):2249&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiridis IG, Martin A, Morlon B, et al. Co-activation and tension-regulating phenomena during isokinetic knee extension in sedentary and highly skilled humans. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol . 1996; 73(1&#x2013;2):149&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight CA, Kamen G. Adaptations in muscular activation of the knee extensor muscles with strength training in young and older adults. J. Electromyogr. Kinesiol . 2001; 11(6):405&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Hainaut K. Training effects of sub-maximal electrostimulation in a human muscle. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 1988; 20(1):99&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamen G, Knight CA. Training-related adaptations in motor unit discharge rate in young and older adults. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci . 2004; 59(12):1334&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Enoka RM. Neural adaptations with chronic activity patterns in able-bodied humans. Am. J. Phys. Med. Rehabil . 2002; 81(Suppl. 11):S17&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Manimmanakorn N, Taylor R, et al. Effects of resistance training combined with vascular occlusion or hypoxia on neuromuscular function in athletes. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2013; 113(7):1767&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Burgomaster KA, Schofield LM, Gibala MJ, Sale DG, Phillips SM. Neuromuscular adaptations in human muscle following low intensity resistance training with vascular occlusion. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2004; 92(4&#x2013;5):399&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer-Poveda D, Romero-Arenas S, Vera-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez A, Vi&#xf1;uela-Garc&#xed;a M, M&#xe1;rquez G. Effects of 4 weeks of low-load unilateral resistance training, with and without blood flow restriction, on strength, thickness, V wave, and H reflex of the soleus muscle in men. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2017; 117(7):1339&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Sim&#xe3;o R, Miranda F, Novaes Jda S, Lemos A, Willardson JM. Rest interval between sets in strength training. Sports Med . 2009; 39(9):765&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert CP, Flynn MG. Fatigue during high-intensity intermittent exercise: application to bodybuilding. Sports Med . 2002; 32(8):511&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpinelli RN. A critical analysis of the claims for inter-set rest intervals, endogenous hormonal responses, sequence of exercise, and pre-exhaustion exercise for optimal strength gains in resistance training. Med. Sport . 2010; 14(3):126&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willardson JM, Burkett LN. A comparison of 3 different rest intervals on the exercise volume completed during a workout. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2005; 19(1):23&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Sim&#xe3;o R, Miranda H, Bottaro M, Fontana F, Willardson JM. Strength increases in upper and lower body are larger with longer inter-set rest intervals in trained men. J. Sci. Med. Sport . 2010; 13(4):429&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincivero DM, Lephart SM, Karunakara RG. Effects of rest interval on isokinetic strength and functional performance after short-term high intensity training. Br. J. Sports Med . 1997; 31(3):229&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JM, Stone MH, Johnson RL, Penland CM, Warren BJ, Lewis RD. Effects of different weight training exercise/rest intervals on strength, power, and high intensity exercise endurance. J. Strength Cond. Res . 1995; 9(4):216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Sonmez GT, Alvar BA. Effects of different volume-equated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2014; 28(10):2909&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villanueva MG, Lane CJ, Schroeder ET. Short rest interval lengths between sets optimally enhance body composition and performance with 8 weeks of strength resistance training in older men. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2015; 115(2):295&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Short vs. long rest period between the sets in hypertrophic resistance training: influence on muscle strength, size, and hormonal adaptations in trained men. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2005; 19(3):572&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza TP Jr., Fleck SJ, Sim&#xe3;o R, et al. Comparison between constant and decreasing rest intervals: influence on maximal strength and hypertrophy. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2010; 24(7):1843&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent C, Penzer F, Letroye B, Carpentier A, Baudry S, Duchateau J. Effect of a strength training method characterized by an incremental number of repetitions across sets and a very short rest interval. Sci Sports . 2016; 31(5):e115&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stragier S, Baudry S, Carpentier A, Duchateau J. Efficacy of a new strength training design: the 3/7 method. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2019; 119(5):1093&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keen DA, Yue GH, Enoka RM. Training-related enhancement in the control of motor output in elderly humans. J. Appl. Physiol . 1994; 77(6):2648&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenan KG, Farina D, Maluf KS, Merletti R, Enoka RM. Influence of amplitude cancellation on the simulated surface electromyogram. J. Appl. Physiol . 2005; 98(1):120&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penzer F, Cabrol A, Baudry S, Duchateau J. Comparison of muscle activity and tissue oxygenation during strength training protocols that differ by their organisation, rest interval between sets, and volume. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2016; 116(9):1795&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Gordon SE, Fleck SJ, et al. Endogenous anabolic hormonal and growth factor responses to heavy resistance exercise in males and females. Int. J. Sports Med . 1991; 12(2):228&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, Devries MC, Phillips SM. Skeletal muscle and resistance exercise training; the role of protein synthesis in recovery and remodeling. J. Appl. Physiol . 2017; 122(3):541&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Bellamy L, Parise G, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Muscular and systemic correlates of resistance training&#x2013;induced muscle hypertrophy. PLoS One . 2013; 8(10):e78636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Libardi CA. Is resistance training to muscular failure necessary? Front. Physiol . 2016; 7:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2015; 29(10):2954&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DWD, Staples AW, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS One . 2010; 5(8):e12033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink J, Kikuchi N, Nakazato K. Effects of rest intervals and training loads on metabolic stress and muscle hypertrophy. Clin. Physiol. Funct. Imaging . 2018; 38(2):261&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seynnes OR, Erskine RM, Maganaris CN, et al. Training-induced changes in structural and mechanical properties of the patellar tendon are related to muscle hypertrophy but not to strength gains. J. Appl. Physiol . 2009; 107(2):523&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klass M, Baudry S, Duchateau J. Voluntary activation during maximal contraction with advancing age: a brief review. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2007; 100(5):543&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobi JM, Rice CL. Voluntary muscle activation varies with age and muscle group. J. Appl. Physiol . 2002; 93(2):457&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC. Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiol. Rev . 2001; 81(4):1725&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Suetta C, Caserotti P, Magnusson SP, Kjaer M. Role of the nervous system in sarcopenia and muscle atrophy with aging: strength training as a countermeasure. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports . 2010; 20(1):49&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, Folland J, Tillin N, Duchateau J. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol . 2016; 116(6):1091&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger HP, K&#xf6;sters A, M&#xfc;ller E, Seynnes OR. Effects of increased loading on in vivo tendon properties: a systematic review. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2015; 47(9):1885&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J, Magnusson SP, Rasmussen LR, Kjaer M, Aagaard P. Muscle performance during maximal isometric and dynamic contractions is influenced by the stiffness of the tendinous structures. J. Appl. Physiol . 2005; 99(3):986&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclay J, Martin A, Duclay A, Cometti G, Pousson M. Behavior of fascicles and the myotendinous junction of human medial gastrocnemius following eccentric strength training. Muscle Nerve . 2009; 39(6):819&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Morimoto M, Komuro T, et al. Effects of plyometric and weight training on muscle-tendon complex and jump performance. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc . 2007; 39(10):1801&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Four&#xe9; A, Nordez A, Cornu C. Plyometric training effects on Achilles tendon stiffness and dissipative properties. J. Appl. Physiol . 2010; 109(3):849&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurent C, Baudry S, Duchateau J. Comparison of plyometric training with two different jumping techniques on Achilles tendon properties and jump performances. J. Strength Cond. Res . 2020; 34(6):1503&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Lauber B, Seynnes OR, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction training induces similar morphological and mechanical Achilles tendon adaptations compared with high-load resistance training. J. Appl. Physiol . 2019; 127(6):1660&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson GJ, Wilson JM. A mechanistic approach to blood flow occlusion. Int. J. Sports Med . 2010; 31(1):1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>