<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28966596</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Resistance Training on Skeletal Muscle Mitochondrial Biogenesis, Content, and Function.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>713</StartPage><MedlinePgn>713</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">713</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2017.00713</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Skeletal muscle metabolic and contractile properties are reliant on muscle mitochondrial and myofibrillar protein turnover. The turnover of these specific protein pools is compromised during disease, aging, and inactivity. Oppositely, exercise can accentuate muscle protein turnover, thereby counteracting decay in muscle function. According to a traditional consensus, endurance exercise is required to drive mitochondrial adaptations, while resistance exercise is required to drive myofibrillar adaptations. However, concurrent practice of traditional endurance exercise and resistance exercise regimens to achieve both types of muscle adaptations is time-consuming, motivationally demanding, and contended to entail practice at intensity levels, that may not comply with clinical settings. It is therefore of principle interest to identify effective, yet feasible, exercise strategies that may positively affect both mitochondrial and myofibrillar protein turnover. Recently, reports indicate that traditional high-load resistance exercise can stimulate muscle mitochondrial biogenesis and mitochondrial respiratory function. Moreover, fatiguing low-load resistance exercise has been shown capable of promoting muscle hypertrophy and expectedly entails greater metabolic stress to potentially enhance mitochondrial adaptations. Consequently, fatiguing low-load resistance exercise regimens may possess the ability to stimulate muscle mitochondrial adaptations without compromising muscle myofibrillar accretion. However, the exact ability of resistance exercise to drive mitochondrial adaptations is debatable, not least due to some methodological challenges. The current review therefore aims to address the evidence on the effects of resistance exercise on skeletal muscle mitochondrial biogenesis, content and function. In prolongation, a perspective is taken on the specific potential of low-load resistance exercise on promoting mitochondrial adaptations.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Groennebaek</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section for Sport Science, Department of Public Health, Aarhus UniversityAarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vissing</LastName><ForeName>Kristian</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section for Sport Science, Department of Public Health, Aarhus UniversityAarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioenergetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restricted exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondrial protein synthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondrial volume density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28966596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abadi A., Glover E. I., Isfort R. J., Raha S., Safdar A., Yasuda N., et al. (2009). Limb immobilization induces a coordinate down-regulation of mitochondrial and other metabolic pathways in men and women. PLoS ONE 4:e6518. 10.1371/journal.pone.0006518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0006518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2716517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19654872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM (2009). American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 41, 687&#x2013;708. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen J. P., Walker S., Silvennoinen M., Kyrolainen H., Nindl B. C., Hakkinen K., et al. (2015). Exercise type and volume alter signaling pathways regulating skeletal muscle glucose uptake and protein synthesis. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 115, 1835&#x2013;1845. 10.1007/s00421-015-3155-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3155-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25861013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balakrishnan V. S., Rao M., Menon V., Gordon P. L., Pilichowska M., Castaneda F., et al. (2010). Resistance training increases muscle mitochondrial biogenesis in patients with chronic kidney disease. Clin. J. Am. Soc. Nephrol. 5, 996&#x2013;1002. 10.2215/CJN.09141209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.09141209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2879307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20498251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell G. J., Syrotuik D., Martin T. P., Burnham R., Quinney H. A. (2000). Effect of concurrent strength and endurance training on skeletal muscle properties and hormone concentrations in humans. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 81, 418&#x2013;427. 10.1007/s004210050063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohe J., Low A., Wolfe R. R., Rennie M. J. (2003). Human muscle protein synthesis is modulated by extracellular, not intramuscular amino acid availability: a dose-response study. J. Physiol. 552(Pt. 1), 315&#x2013;324. 10.1113/jphysiol.2003.050674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2003.050674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12909668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd N. A., Andrews R. J., West D. W., Little J. P., Cochran A. J., Hector A. J., et al. (2012). Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub-fractional synthetic responses in men. J. Physiol. 590, 351&#x2013;362. 10.1113/jphysiol.2011.221200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2011.221200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22106173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd N. A., West D. W., Staples A. W., Atherton P. J., Baker J. M., Moore D. R., et al. (2010). Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS ONE 5:e12033. 10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch R., Kim Y. K., Neese R. A., Schade-Serin V., Collins M., Awada M., et al. (2006). Measurement of protein turnover rates by heavy water labeling of nonessential amino acids. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1760, 730&#x2013;744. 10.1016/j.bbagen.2005.12.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbagen.2005.12.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck P. D., Syrotuik D. G., Bell G. J. (1999). The effect of strength training on estimates of mitochondrial density and distribution throughout muscle fibres. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 80, 604&#x2013;609. 10.1007/s004210050641</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10541929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey V. G., Zhong Z., Shield A., Canny B. J., Chibalin A. V., Zierath J. R., et al. (2006). Early signaling responses to divergent exercise stimuli in skeletal muscle from well-trained humans. FASEB J. 20, 190&#x2013;192. 10.1096/fj.05-4809fje</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.05-4809fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16267123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes A., Dekerle J., Webborn N., Watt P., Bougault V., Daussin F. N. (2015). Exercise-induced metabolic fluctuations influence AMPK, p38-MAPK and CaMKII phosphorylation in human skeletal muscle. Physiol. Rep. 3:e12462. 10.14814/phy2.12462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4600372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Donato D. M., West D. W., Churchward-Venne T. A., Breen L., Baker S. K., Phillips S. M. (2014). Influence of aerobic exercise intensity on myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis in young men during early and late postexercise recovery. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 306, E1025&#x2013;E1032. 10.1152/ajpendo.00487.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00487.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4010655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24595306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donges C. E., Burd N. A., Duffield R., Smith G. C., West D. W., Short M. J., et al. (2012). Concurrent resistance and aerobic exercise stimulates both myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis in sedentary middle-aged men. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 112, 1992&#x2013;2001. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00166.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00166.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22492939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake J. C., Peelor F. F., III., Biela L. M., Watkins M. K., Miller R. A., Hamilton K. L., et al. (2013). Assessment of mitochondrial biogenesis and mTORC1 signaling during chronic rapamycin feeding in male and female mice. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 68, 1493&#x2013;1501. 10.1093/gerona/glt047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glt047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3814233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23657975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dufner D. A., Bederman I. R., Brunengraber D. Z., Rachdaoui N., Ismail-Beigi F., Siegfried B. A., et al. (2005). Using 2H2O to study the influence of feeding on protein synthesis: effect of isotope equilibration <i>in vivo</i> vs. in cell culture. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab.
288, E1277&#x2013;E1283. 10.1152/ajpendo.00580.2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00580.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15671077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J., de Paoli F., Bjerg K., Riis S., Ringgard S., Vissing K. (2015). Blood flow restricted and traditional resistance training performed to fatigue produce equal muscle hypertrophy. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 25, 754&#x2013;763. 10.1111/sms.12396</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25603897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga E. M., Navarro-Amezqueta I., Calbet J. A., Hellsten Y., Cusso R., Guerrero M., et al. (2012). Energy metabolism during repeated sets of leg press exercise leading to failure or not. PLoS ONE 7:e40621. 10.1371/journal.pone.0040621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0040621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3396634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22808209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gram M., Vigelso A., Yokota T., Hansen C. N., Helge J. W., Hey-Mogensen M., et al. (2014). Two weeks of one-leg immobilization decreases skeletal muscle respiratory capacity equally in young and elderly men. Exp. Gerontol. 58, 269&#x2013;278. 10.1016/j.exger.2014.08.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2014.08.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green H., Goreham C., Ouyang J., Ball-Burnett M., Ranney D. (1999). Regulation of fiber size, oxidative potential, and capillarization in human muscle by resistance exercise. Am. J. Physiol. 276(2 Pt. 2), R591&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9950941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greggio C., Jha P., Kulkarni S. S., Lagarrigue S., Broskey N. T., Boutant M., et al. (2017). Enhanced respiratory chain supercomplex formation in response to exercise in human skeletal muscle. Cell Metab. 25, 301&#x2013;311. 10.1016/j.cmet.2016.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2016.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27916530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller T., Ortner M., Gnaiger E. (1994). A respirometer for investigating oxidative cell metabolism: toward optimization of respiratory studies. Anal. Biochem. 218, 338&#x2013;342. 10.1006/abio.1994.1188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/abio.1994.1188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8074290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley S. A., Selbert M. A., Goldstein E. G., Edelman A. M., Carling D., Hardie D. G. (1995). 5'-AMP activates the AMP-activated protein kinase cascade, and Ca<sup>2+</sup>/calmodulin activates the calmodulin-dependent protein kinase I cascade, via three independent mechanisms. J. Biol. Chem.
270, 27186&#x2013;27191. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7592975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppeler H., Howald H., Conley K., Lindstedt S. L., Claassen H., Vock P., et al. (1985). Endurance training in humans: aerobic capacity and structure of skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 59, 320&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4030584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irving B. A., Lanza I. R., Henderson G. C., Rao R. R., Spiegelman B. M., Nair K. S. (2015). Combined training enhances skeletal muscle mitochondrial oxidative capacity independent of age. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 100, 1654&#x2013;1663. 10.1210/jc.2014-3081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2014-3081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4399307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25599385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs R. A., Lundby C. (2013). Mitochondria express enhanced quality as well as quantity in association with aerobic fitness across recreationally active individuals up to elite athletes. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 114, 344&#x2013;350. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01081.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01081.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23221957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahoor F., Zhang X. J., Baba H., Sakurai Y., Wolfe R. R. (1992). Comparison of constant infusion and flooding dose techniques to measure muscle protein synthesis rate in dogs. J. Nutr. 122, 878&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1552362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubrias S. A., Esselman P. C., Price L. B., Cress M. E., Conley K. E. (2001). Large energetic adaptations of elderly muscle to resistance and endurance training. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 90, 1663&#x2013;1670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11299253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M., Leal J. A., Jr., Garcia S. D., Cavazos C., Bemben M. (2014). Tissue oxygenation, strength and lactate response to different blood flow restrictive pressures. Clin. Physiol. Funct. Imaging 34, 263&#x2013;269. 10.1111/cpf.12090</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. Y., Hickner R. C., Cortright R. L., Dohm G. L., Houmard J. A. (2000). Lipid oxidation is reduced in obese human skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 279, E1039&#x2013;E1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11052958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkwood S. P., Munn E. A., Brooks G. A. (1986). Mitochondrial reticulum in limb skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. 251(3 Pt. 1), C395&#x2013;C402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3752235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M., Ohiwa N., Honda A., Matsubayashi T., Ikeda T., Akimoto T., et al. (2014). Effects of systemic hypoxia on human muscular adaptations to resistance exercise training. Physiol. Rep. 2:e12033. 10.14814/phy2.12033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24907297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuznetsov A. V., Veksler V., Gellerich F. N., Saks V., Margreiter R., Kunz W. S. (2008). Analysis of mitochondrial function <i>in situ</i> in permeabilized muscle fibers, tissues and cells. Nat. Protoc.
3, 965&#x2013;976. 10.1038/nprot.2008.61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nprot.2008.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18536644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen S., Nielsen J., Hansen C. N., Nielsen L. B., Wibrand F., Stride N., et al. (2012). Biomarkers of mitochondrial content in skeletal muscle of healthy young human subjects. J. Physiol. 590, 3349&#x2013;3360. 10.1113/jphysiol.2012.230185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.230185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3459047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22586215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver J. D., Cayot T. E., Rotarius T., Scheuermann B. W. (2017). The effect of eccentric exercise with blood flow restriction on neuromuscular activation, microvascular oxygenation, and the repeated bout effect. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 117, 1005&#x2013;1015. 10.1007/s00421-017-3589-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3589-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28324168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luthi J. M., Howald H., Claassen H., Rosler K., Vock P., Hoppeler H. (1986). Structural changes in skeletal muscle tissue with heavy-resistance exercise. Int. J. Sports Med. 7, 123&#x2013;127. 10.1055/s-2008-1025748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2008-1025748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2942497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDougall J. D., Sale D. G., Moroz J. R., Elder G. C., Sutton J. R., Howald H. (1979). Mitochondrial volume density in human skeletal muscle following heavy resistance training. Med. Sci. Sports 11, 164&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">158694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinild Lundby A. K., Jacobs R. A., Gehrig S., de Leur J., Hauser M., Bonne T. C., et al. (2017). Exercise training increases skeletal muscle mitochondrial volume density by enlargement of existing mitochondria and not de novo biogenesis. Acta Physiol. 10.1111/apha.12905. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.12905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28580772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melov S., Tarnopolsky M. A., Beckman K., Felkey K., Hubbard A. (2007). Resistance exercise reverses aging in human skeletal muscle. PLoS ONE 2:e465. 10.1371/journal.pone.0000465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0000465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1866181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17520024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B. F., Hamilton K. L. (2012). A perspective on the determination of mitochondrial biogenesis. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 302, E496&#x2013;E499. 10.1152/ajpendo.00578.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00578.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3311289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22205627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B. F., Konopka A. R., Hamilton K. L. (2016). The rigorous study of exercise adaptations: why mRNA might not be enough. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 121, 594&#x2013;596. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00137.2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00137.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27013604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B. F., Wolff C. A., Peelor F. F., III., Shipman P. D., Hamilton K. L. (2015). Modeling the contribution of individual proteins to mixed skeletal muscle protein synthetic rates over increasing periods of label incorporation. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 118, 655&#x2013;661. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00987.2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00987.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4360018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25593288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell C. J., Churchward-Venne T. A., West D. W., Burd N. A., Breen L., Baker S. K., et al. (2012). Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 113, 71&#x2013;77. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen J., Gejl K. D., Hey-Mogensen M., Holmberg H. C., Suetta C., Krustrup P., et al. (2016). Plasticity in mitochondrial cristae density allows metabolic capacity modulation in human skeletal muscle. J. Physiol. 595, 2839&#x2013;2847. 10.1113/JP273040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP273040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27696420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry C. G., Lally J., Holloway G. P., Heigenhauser G. J., Bonen A., Spriet L. L. (2010). Repeated transient mRNA bursts precede increases in transcriptional and mitochondrial proteins during training in human skeletal muscle. J. Physiol. 588(Pt/23), 4795&#x2013;4810. 10.1113/jphysiol.2010.199448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2010.199448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3010147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20921196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesta D., Hoppel F., Macek C., Messner H., Faulhaber M., Kobel C., et al. (2011). Similar qualitative and quantitative changes of mitochondrial respiration following strength and endurance training in normoxia and hypoxia in sedentary humans. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 301, R1078&#x2013;R1087. 10.1152/ajpregu.00285.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00285.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen K. F., Dufour S., Befroy D., Garcia R., Shulman G. I. (2004). Impaired mitochondrial activity in the insulin-resistant offspring of patients with type 2 diabetes. N. Engl. J. Med. 350, 664&#x2013;671. 10.1056/NEJMoa031314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa031314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14960743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philp A., Schenk S., Perez-Schindler J., Hamilton D. L., Breen L., Laverone E., et al. (2015). Rapamycin does not prevent increases in myofibrillar or mitochondrial protein synthesis following endurance exercise. J. Physiol. 593, 4275&#x2013;4284. 10.1113/JP271219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP271219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26227152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picard M., Taivassalo T., Ritchie D., Wright K. J., Thomas M. M., Romestaing C., et al. (2011). Mitochondrial structure and function are disrupted by standard isolation methods. PLoS ONE 6:e18317. 10.1371/journal.pone.0018317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0018317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21512578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ploutz L. L., Tesch P. A., Biro R. L., Dudley G. A. (1994). Effect of resistance training on muscle use during exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 76, 1675&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8045847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter C., Reidy P. T., Bhattarai N., Sidossis L. S., Rasmussen B. B. (2015). Resistance exercise training alters mitochondrial function in human skeletal muscle. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 47, 1922&#x2013;1931. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4478283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25539479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzuto R., Pinton P., Carrington W., Fay F. S., Fogarty K. E., Lifshitz L. M., et al. (1998). Close contacts with the endoplasmic reticulum as determinants of mitochondrial Ca<sup>2+</sup> responses. Science
280, 1763&#x2013;1766. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9624056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson M. M., Dasari S., Konopka A. R., Johnson M. L., Manjunatha S., Esponda R. R., et al. (2017). Enhanced protein translation underlies improved metabolic and physical adaptations to different exercise training modes in young and old humans. Cell Metab. 25, 581&#x2013;592. 10.1016/j.cmet.2017.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2017.02.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5423095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28273480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson M. M., Soop M., Sohn T. S., Morse D. M., Schimke J. M., Klaus K. A., et al. (2014). High insulin combined with essential amino acids stimulates skeletal muscle mitochondrial protein synthesis while decreasing insulin sensitivity in healthy humans. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab. 99, E2574&#x2013;E2583. 10.1210/jc.2014-2736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2014-2736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4255106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson M. M., Turner S. M., Hellerstein M. K., Hamilton K. L., Miller B. F. (2011). Long-term synthesis rates of skeletal muscle DNA and protein are higher during aerobic training in older humans than in sedentary young subjects but are not altered by protein supplementation. FASEB J. 25, 3240&#x2013;3249. 10.1096/fj.11-186437</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.11-186437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3157680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21613572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rontoyanni V. G., Nunez Lopez O., Fankhauser G. T., Cheema Z. F., Rasmussen B. B., Porter C. (2017). Mitochondrial bioenergetics in the metabolic myopathy accompanying peripheral artery disease. Front. Physiol. 8:141. 10.3389/fphys.2017.00141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2017.00141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5346567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooyackers O. E., Adey D. B., Ades P. A., Nair K. S. (1996a). Effect of age on <i>in vivo</i> rates of mitochondrial protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 93, 15364&#x2013;15369. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC26410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8986817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooyackers O. E., Kersten A. H., Wagenmakers A. J. (1996b). Mitochondrial protein content and <i>in vivo</i> synthesis rates in skeletal muscle from critically ill rats. Clin. Sci.
91, 475&#x2013;481. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8983873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvadego D., Domenis R., Lazzer S., Porcelli S., Rittweger J., Rizzo G., et al. (2013). Skeletal muscle oxidative function <i>in vivo</i> and <i>ex vivo</i> in athletes with marked hypertrophy from resistance training. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985)
114, 1527&#x2013;1535. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00883.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00883.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23519233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith K., Reynolds N., Downie S., Patel A., Rennie M. J. (1998). Effects of flooding amino acids on incorporation of labeled amino acids into human muscle protein. Am. J. Physiol. 275(1 Pt. 1), E73&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparks L. M., Johannsen N. M., Church T. S., Earnest C. P., Moonen-Kornips E., Moro C., et al. (2013). Nine months of combined training improves <i>ex vivo</i> skeletal muscle metabolism in individuals with type 2 diabetes. J. Clin. Endocrinol. Metab.
98, 1694&#x2013;1702. 10.1210/jc.2012-3874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2012-3874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3615199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23463651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J. E., Hartman J. W., Phillips S. M. (2006). Increased muscle oxidative potential following resistance training induced fibre hypertrophy in young men. Appl. Physiol. Nutr. Metab. 31, 495&#x2013;501. 10.1139/h06-026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h06-026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17111003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanimoto M., Ishii N. (2006). Effects of low-intensity resistance exercise with slow movement and tonic force generation on muscular function in young men. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 100, 1150&#x2013;1157. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00741.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00741.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch P. A., Thorsson A., Colliander E. B. (1990). Effects of eccentric and concentric resistance training on skeletal muscle substrates, enzyme activities and capillary supply. Acta Physiol. Scand. 140, 575&#x2013;580. 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1990.tb09035.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1990.tb09035.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2082717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K., Andersen J. L., Schjerling P. (2005). Are exercise-induced genes induced by exercise? FASEB J. 19, 94&#x2013;96. 10.1096/fj.04-2084fje</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.04-2084fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15516373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K., McGee S., Farup J., Kjolhede T., Vendelbo M., Jessen N. (2013). Differentiated mTOR but not AMPK signaling after strength vs endurance exercise in training-accustomed individuals. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 23, 355&#x2013;366. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01395.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01395.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N., Hikida R. S., Staron R. S., Simoneau J. A. (1993). Muscle fiber types of women after resistance training&#x2013;quantitative ultrastructure and enzyme activity. Pflugers Arch. 424, 494&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8255733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson S. B., Phillips S. M., Atherton P. J., Patel R., Yarasheski K. E., Tarnopolsky M. A., et al. (2008). Differential effects of resistance and endurance exercise in the fed state on signalling molecule phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human muscle. J. Physiol. 586, 3701&#x2013;3717. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.153916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.153916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2538832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18556367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright D. C., Geiger P. C., Han D. H., Jones T. E., Holloszy J. O. (2007). Calcium induces increases in peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma coactivator-1alpha and mitochondrial biogenesis by a pathway leading to p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase activation. J. Biol. Chem. 282, 18793&#x2013;18799. 10.1074/jbc.M611252200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M611252200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17488713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>