<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37506190</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Time Course of Proteolysis Biomarker Responses to Resistance, High-Intensity Interval, and Concurrent Exercise Bouts.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2326</StartPage><EndPage>2332</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2326-2332</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004550</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Godwin, JS, Telles, GD, Vechin, FC, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o, MS, Ugrinowitsch, C, Roberts, MD, and Libardi, CA. Time course of proteolysis biomarker responses to resistance, high-intensity interval, and concurrent exercise bouts. J Strength Cond Res 37(12): 2326-2332, 2023-Concurrent exercise (CE) combines resistance exercise (RE) and high-intensity interval exercise (HIIE) in the same training routine, eliciting hypertrophy, strength, and cardiovascular benefits over time. Some studies suggest that CE training may hamper muscle hypertrophy and strength adaptations compared with RE training alone. However, the underlying mechanisms related to protein breakdown are not well understood. The purpose of this study was to examine how a bout of RE, HIIE, or CE affected ubiquitin-proteasome and calpain activity and the expression of a few associated genes, markers of skeletal muscle proteolysis. Nine untrained male subjects completed 1 bout of RE (4 sets of 8-12 reps), HIIE (12 &#xd7; 1 minute sprints at V&#x307; o2 peak minimum velocity), and CE (RE followed by HIIE), in a crossover design, separated by 1-week washout periods. Muscle biopsies were obtained from the vastus lateralis before (Pre), immediately post, 4 hours (4 hours), and 8 hours (8 hours) after exercise. FBXO32 mRNA expression increased immediately after exercise (main time effect; p &lt; 0.05), and RE and CE presented significant overall values compared with HIIE ( p &lt; 0.05). There was a marginal time effect for calpain-2 mRNA expression ( p &lt; 0.05), with no differences between time points ( p &gt; 0.05). No significant changes occurred in TRIM63/MuRF-1 and FOXO3 mRNA expression, or 20S proteasome or calpain activities ( p &gt; 0.05). In conclusion, our findings suggest that 1 bout of CE does not promote greater changes in markers of skeletal muscle proteolysis compared with 1 bout of RE or HIIE.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Godwin</LastName><ForeName>Joshua S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Telles</LastName><ForeName>Guilherme D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Sao Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vechin</LastName><ForeName>Felipe C</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Sao Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Miguel S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Sao Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Sao Carlos, Sao Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ugrinowitsch</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education and Sport, University of Sao Paulo, Sao Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Michael D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MUSCULAB, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Sao Carlos, Sao Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.22.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002154">Calpain</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059748" MajorTopicYN="N">Proteolysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002154" MajorTopicYN="Y">Calpain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072696" MajorTopicYN="Y">High-Intensity Interval Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37506190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202312000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Apr&#xf3; W, Moberg M, Hamilton DL, et al. Resistance exercise-induced S6K1 kinase activity is not inhibited in human skeletal muscle despite prior activation of AMPK by high-intensity interval cycling. Am J Physiol-Endocrinol Metab 308: E470&#x2013;E481, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton PJ, Babraj J, Smith K, Singh J, Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H. Selective activation of AMPK-PGC-1alpha or PKB-TSC2-mTOR signaling can explain specific adaptive responses to endurance or resistance training-like electrical muscle stimulation. FASEB J 19: 786&#x2013;788, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balabinis CP, Psarakis CH, Moukas M, Vassiliou MP, Behrakis PK. Early phase changes by concurrent endurance and strength training. J Strength Cond Res 17: 393&#x2013;401, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belcastro AN, Shewchuk LD, Raj DA. Exercise-induced muscle injury: A calpain hypothesis. Mol Cell Biochem 179: 135&#x2013;145, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera DM, West DWD, Phillips SM, et al. Protein ingestion increases myofibrillar protein synthesis after concurrent exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 82&#x2013;91, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner T, Yano J, Kimura E, et al. Identification of muscle specific ring finger proteins as potential regulators of the titin kinase domain. J Mol Biol 306: 717&#x2013;726, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Hawley JA. Concurrent exercise training: Do opposites distract? J Physiol 595: 2883&#x2013;2896, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Jemiolo B, Edge J, Garnham AP, Trappe SW, Hawley JA. Effect of consecutive repeated sprint and resistance exercise bouts on acute adaptive responses in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 297: R1441&#x2013;R1451, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conceicao MS, Chacon-Mikahil MPT, Telles GD, et al. Attenuated PGC-1&#x3b1; isoforms following endurance exercise with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 1699&#x2013;1707, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C. The development of skeletal muscle hypertrophy through resistance training: The role of muscle damage and muscle protein synthesis. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 485&#x2013;500, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Ugrinowitsch C, Libardi CA, et al. Resistance training in young men induces muscle transcriptome-wide changes associated with muscle structure and metabolism refining the response to exercise-induced stress. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 2607&#x2013;2616, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donges CE, Burd NA, Duffield R, et al. Concurrent resistance and aerobic exercise stimulates both myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis in sedentary middle-aged men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 112: 1992&#x2013;2001, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feasson L, Stockholm D, Freyssenet D, et al. Molecular adaptations of neuromuscular disease-associated proteins in response to eccentric exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Physiol 543: 297&#x2013;306, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bishop DJ, Bartlett JD, et al. Enhanced skeletal muscle ribosome biogenesis, yet attenuated mTORC1 and ribosome biogenesis-related signaling, following short-term concurrent versus single-mode resistance training. Sci Rep 8: 560, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bishop DJ, Zacharewicz E, Russell AP, Stepto NK. Concurrent exercise incorporating high-intensity interval or continuous training modulates mTORC1 signaling and microRNA expression in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 310: R1297&#x2013;R1311, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, et al. Neuromuscular adaptations during concurrent strength and endurance training versus strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 42&#x2013;52, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickson RC. Interference of strength development by simultaneously training for strength and endurance. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 45: 255&#x2013;263, 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howley ET, Bassett DR Jr., Welch HG. Criteria for maximal oxygen uptake: Review and commentary. Med Sci Sports Exerc 27: 1292&#x2013;1301, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Forsberg NE. Role of calpain in skeletal-muscle protein degradation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 95: 12100&#x2013;12105, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyatt HW, Powers SK. The role of calpains in skeletal muscle remodeling with exercise and inactivity-induced atrophy. Int J Sports Med 41: 994&#x2013;1008, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones TW, Eddens L, Kupusarevic J, et al. Aerobic exercise intensity does not affect the anabolic signaling following resistance exercise in endurance athletes. Sci Rep 11: 10785, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis E, Raue U, Yang Y, Jemiolo B, Trappe S. Time course of proteolytic, cytokine, and myostatin gene expression after acute exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol (1985) 103: 1744&#x2013;1751, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy JP, Pozniak MA, Agre JC. Neuromuscular adaptations to concurrent strength and endurance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 34: 511&#x2013;519, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP. Recent advances in the understanding of the repeated bout effect: The protective effect against muscle damage from a single bout of eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports 13: 88&#x2013;97, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellgren RL, Miyake K, Kramerova I, et al. Calcium-dependent plasma membrane repair requires m- or mu-calpain, but not calpain-3, the proteasome, or caspases. Biochim Biophys Acta&#x2014;Mol Basis Dis 1793: 1886&#x2013;1893, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley CB, Haun CT, Roberson PA, et al. Biomarkers associated with low, moderate, and high vastus lateralis muscle hypertrophy following 12 weeks of resistance training. PLoS One 13: e0195203, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach KA, Bagley JR. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy with concurrent exercise training: Contrary evidence for an interference effect. Sports Med 46: 1029&#x2013;1039, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murton AJ, Constantin D, Greenhaff PL. The involvement of the ubiquitin proteasome system in human skeletal muscle remodelling and atrophy. Biochim Biophys Acta&#x2014;Mol Basis Dis, 1782: 730&#x2013;743, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parr EB, Camera DM, Areta JL, et al. Alcohol ingestion impairs maximal post-exercise rates of myofibrillar protein synthesis following a single bout of concurrent training. PLoS One 9: e88384, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Carbone JW. Assessment of skeletal muscle proteolysis and the regulatory response to nutrition and exercise. IUBMB Life 66: 478&#x2013;484, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillon NJ, Gabriel BM, Dollet L, et al. Transcriptomic profiling of skeletal muscle adaptations to exercise and inactivity. Nat Commun 11: 470, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh JK, Faulkner SH, Jackson AP, King JA, Nimmo MA. Acute molecular responses to concurrent resistance and high-intensity interval exercise in untrained skeletal muscle. Physiol Rep 3: e12364, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raastad T, Owe SG, Paulsen G, et al. Changes in calpain activity, muscle structure, and function after eccentric exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 42: 86&#x2013;95, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid MB. Response of the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway to changes in muscle activity. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 288: R1423&#x2013;R1431, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabag A, Najafi A, Michael S, Esgin T, Halaki M, Hackett D. The compatibility of concurrent high intensity interval training and resistance training for muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 36: 2472&#x2013;2483, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanetti RJ, Lamon S, Wallace M, Vendelbo MH, Russell AP, Vissing K. Regulation of ubiquitin proteasome pathway molecular markers in response to endurance and resistance exercise and training. Pfl&#xfc;gers Archiv&#x2014;Eur J Physiol 467: 1523&#x2013;1537, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telles GD, Libardi CA, Conceicao MS, et al. Time course of skeletal muscle miRNA expression after resistance, high-intensity interval, and concurrent exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 53: 1708&#x2013;1718, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Williams BD, Wolfe RR. Muscle protein metabolism in female swimmers after a combination of resistance and endurance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 81: 2034&#x2013;2038, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vechin FC, Conceicao MS, Telles GD, Libardi CA, Ugrinowitsch C. Interference phenomenon with concurrent strength and high-intensity interval training-based aerobic training: An updated model. Sports Med 51: 599&#x2013;605, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K, Overgaard K, Nedergaard A, Fredsted A, Schjerling P. Effects of concentric and repeated eccentric exercise on muscle damage and calpain-calpastatin gene expression in human skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol 103: 323&#x2013;332, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Jemiolo B, Trappe S. Proteolytic mRNA expression in response to acute resistance exercise in human single skeletal muscle fibers. J Appl Physiol (1985) 101: 1442&#x2013;1450, 2006.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>