<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30967915</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2008-7802</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of preventive medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Prev Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Skeletal Muscle Hypertrophy, Insulin-like Growth Factor 1, Myostatin and Follistatin in Healthy and Sarcopenic Elderly Men: The Effect of Whole-body Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>29</StartPage><MedlinePgn>29</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">29</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijpvm.IJPVM_310_17</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sarcopenia describes the inevitable deterioration in muscle mass and strength that accompanies biological aging. The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of resistance training (RT) on quadriceps hypertrophy and related biochemistry in sarcopenic and healthy elderly men.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 31 elderly men (55-70 years old) were classified as sarcopenic and nonsarcopenic and were divided into two groups. Both groups participated in a progressive RT program for 8 weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Data indicated that the strength in the sarcopenic group increased more than the healthy group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Quadriceps cross-sectional area also increased more in the healthy group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Myostatin concentration decreased in both groups after training (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Follistatin and testosterone increased in the healthy group; in contrast, only testosterone increased in the sarcopenic group after training (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings from this study suggest that RT improves muscle cross-sectional area and biomarker-related muscle loss in both healthy and sarcopenic elderly men. The findings also demonstrate that growth factor profiles at baseline and changes in testosterone levels play an important role in muscle hypertrophy observed in both groups.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Negaresh</LastName><ForeName>Raoof</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranjbar</LastName><ForeName>Rouholah</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baker</LastName><ForeName>Julien S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Science and Sport, University of the West of Scotland, Paisley, Scotland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Habibi</LastName><ForeName>Abdolhamid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mokhtarzade</LastName><ForeName>Motahare</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Physiology, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gharibvand</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Momen</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Jundishapur University of Medical Sciences, Ahvaz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fokin</LastName><ForeName>Andrej</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Sciences and Innovation, Lithuanian Sports University, Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Prev Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535380</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2008-7802</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">follistatin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myostatin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30967915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6425763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijpvm.IJPVM_310_17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJPVM-10-29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lauretani F, Bautmans I, De Vita F, Nardelli A, Ceda GP, Maggio M, et al. Identification and treatment of older persons with sarcopenia. Aging Male. 2014;17:199&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25207857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judge LW, Bellar DM, Hoover DL, Biggs D, Leitzelar BN, Craig BW, et al. Effects of acute androstenedione supplementation on testosterone levels in older men. Aging Male. 2016;19:161&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27558186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson DD. Aging and sarcopenia. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2007;7:344&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18094505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero AA, Hulmi JJ, Salmij&#xe4;rvi H, Katajavuori M, Haverinen M, Holviala J, et al. Resistance training induced increase in muscle fiber size in young and older men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:641&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22898716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbono O. Sarcopenia &#x2013; Age-Related Muscle Wasting and Weakness. Netherlands: Springer; 2011. Excitation-contraction coupling regulation in aging skeletal muscle; pp. 113&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamauchi J, Mishima C, Nakayama S, Ishii N. Force-velocity, force-power relationships of bilateral and unilateral leg multi-joint movements in young and elderly women. J Biomech. 2009;42:2151&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19647259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrini S, Laviola L, Carreira MC, Cignarelli A, Natalicchio A, Giorgino F, et al. The GH/IGF1 axis and signaling pathways in the muscle and bone: Mechanisms underlying age-related skeletal muscle wasting and osteoporosis. J Endocrinol. 2010;205:201&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20197302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratkevicius A, Joyson A, Selmer I, Dhanani T, Grierson C, Tommasi AM, et al. Serum concentrations of myostatin and myostatin-interacting proteins do not differ between young and sarcopenic elderly men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011;66:620&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21382886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherron AC, Lawler AM, Lee SJ. Regulation of skeletal muscle mass in mice by a new TGF-beta superfamily member. Nature. 1997;387:83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9139826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YS, Lehar A, Sebald S, Liu M, Swaggart KA, Talbot CC, Jr, et al. Muscle hypertrophy induced by myostatin inhibition accelerates degeneration in dysferlinopathy. Hum Mol Genet. 2015;24:5711&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4581601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26206886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari Kamrani AA, Zamani Sani SH, Fathire-Zaie Z, Bashiri M, Ahmadi E. The psychometric characteristics of the exercise benefits/barriers scale among Iranian elderly. Iran J Public Health. 2014;43:362&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4419175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25988097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltais ML, Ladouceur JP, Dionne IJ. The effect of resistance training and different sources of postexercise protein supplementation on muscle mass and physical capacity in sarcopenic elderly men. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:1680&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Selby A, Rankin D, Patel R, Atherton P, Hildebrandt W, et al. Age-related differences in the dose-response relationship of muscle protein synthesis to resistance exercise in young and old men. J Physiol. 2009;587:211&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2670034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Gleeson BG, Jonkers RA, Meijer K, Savelberg HH, Dendale P, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance training is accompanied by a fiber type-specific increase in satellite cell content in elderly men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2009;64:332&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim JS, Cross JM, Kosek DJ, Bamman MM. Efficacy of myonuclear addition may explain differential myofiber growth among resistance-trained young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291:E937&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Heymsfield SB, Ross R. Low relative skeletal muscle mass (sarcopenia) in older persons is associated with functional impairment and physical disability. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50:889&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee RC, Wang Z, Heo M, Ross R, Janssen I, Heymsfield SB, et al. Total-body skeletal muscle mass: Development and cross-validation of anthropometric prediction models. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72:796&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. A practical approach to strength training. Contemporary Books. 1995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Generalized equations for predicting body density of men. Br J Nutr. 1978;40:497&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">718832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. Body composition from fluid spaces and density: Analysis of methods. Tech Meas Body Compos. 1961;61:223&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8286893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2006;101:531&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkisas S, De Cock A, Verhoeven V, Vandewoude M. Physiological and architectural changes in the ageing muscle and their relation to strength and function in sarcopenia. Eur Geriatr Med. 2016;7:201&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Blanco CE, Sattler FR, Schroeder ET, Wiswell RA. Satellite cell numbers in young and older men 24 hours after eccentric exercise. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33:242&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16315322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent-Braun JA, Ng AV. Specific strength and voluntary muscle activation in young and elderly women and men. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1999;87:22&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10409554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch NA, Metter EJ, Lindle RS, Fozard JL, Tobin JD, Roy TA, et al. Muscle quality. I. Age-associated differences between arm and leg muscle groups. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1999;86:188&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9887130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang ZM, Messi ML, Delbono O. L-type ca(2+) channel charge movement and intracellular ca(2+) in skeletal muscle fibers from aging mice. Biophys J. 2000;78:1947&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1300787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10733973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe DA, Thomas DD, Thompson LV. Force generation, but not myosin ATPase activity, declines with age in rat muscle fibers. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2002;283:C187&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12055087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel CS, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Exercise dosing to retain resistance training adaptations in young and older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1177&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker S, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Similar increases in strength after short-term resistance training due to different neuromuscular adaptations in young and older men. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:3041&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25051001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Langley B, Berry C, Sharma M, Kirk S, Bass J, et al. Myostatin, a negative regulator of muscle growth, functions by inhibiting myoblast proliferation. J Biol Chem. 2000;275:40235&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10976104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szulc P, Schoppet M, Goettsch C, Rauner M, Dschietzig T, Chapurlat R, et al. Endocrine and clinical correlates of myostatin serum concentration in men &#x2013; The STRAMBO study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012;97:3700&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22802085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leiter JR, Peeler J, Anderson JE. Exercise-induced muscle growth is muscle-specific and age-dependent. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43:828&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21607967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Martel GF, Ferrell RE, Metter EJ, Hurley BF, Rogers MA, et al. Myostatin gene expression is reduced in humans with heavy-resistance strength training: A brief communication. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 2003;228:706&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12773702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS. Effects of heavy resistance training on myostatin mRNA and protein expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:574&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jespersen JG, Nedergaard A, Andersen LL, Schjerling P, Andersen JL. Myostatin expression during human muscle hypertrophy and subsequent atrophy: Increased myostatin with detraining. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:215&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19903317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Wilborn CD. Estradiol in females may negate skeletal muscle myostatin mRNA expression and serum myostatin propeptide levels after eccentric muscle contractions. J Sports Sci Med. 2006;5:672&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3861770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24357964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, Tenover JS. Age-associated sarcopenia &#x2013; Issues in the use of testosterone as an anabolic agent in older men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1997;82:1659&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9177358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga M, Bhasin S, Jasuja R, Pervin S, Singh R. Testosterone inhibits transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; signaling during myogenic differentiation and proliferation of mouse satellite cells: Potential role of follistatin in mediating testosterone action. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2012;350:39&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3264813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22138414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Ahtiainen JP, Kaasalainen T, P&#xf6;ll&#xe4;nen E, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, et al. Postexercise myostatin and activin IIb mRNA levels: Effects of strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:289&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen J, Brandt C, Nielsen AR, Hojman P, Whitham M, Febbraio MA, et al. Exercise induces a marked increase in plasma follistatin: Evidence that follistatin is a contraction-induced hepatokine. Endocrinology. 2011;152:164&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21068158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barb&#xe9; C, Kalista S, Loumaye A, Ritvos O, Lause P, Ferracin B, et al. Role of IGF-I in follistatin-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2015;309:E557&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4572457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26219865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>