<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41048240</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A professional assessment of training plans for muscle hypertrophy and maximal strength developed by generative artificial intelligence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>353</StartPage><EndPage>366</EndPage><MedlinePgn>353-366</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2026.152350</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this study was to evaluate the quality of resistance training plans for muscle hypertrophy and maximal strength generated by three large language models (LLMs): GPT-3.5 (via ChatGPT and Microsoft Copilot) and Google Gemini (GG). A total of 10 experienced coaches, each with at least a bachelor's degree in exercise science and at least 2 years of coaching experience, rated these plans on a 1-5 Likert scale based on 27 criteria essential for effective training plan design. The LLMs were accessed on April 30, 2024, with a prompt structure that included key training objectives and the training history of a fictional advanced trainee. Results showed that the overall quality of the LLM-generated training plans was moderate. GG outperformed GPT-3.5 (via ChatGPT and Microsoft Copilot) for hypertrophy-related plans on 2 out of 27 criteria (advanced exercise methods, recovery strategies; p &lt; 0.05), while GPT-3.5 (via Microsoft Copilot) outperformed GG for strength-related plans on 1 out of 27 criteria (testing procedure; p &lt; 0.05). Across all criteria, GG received ratings &gt; 3 more frequently than GPT-3.5 (via ChatGPT and Microsoft Copilot), particularly for general aspects, training principles, and training methods. Differences between hypertrophy- and strength-oriented plans within each LLM were minimal, although GPT-3.5 (via ChatGPT) showed the most inconsistency in ratings. Although LLM-generated plans can serve as an initial framework for hypertrophy and strength development, expert supervision remains crucial to refine these plans, as LLMs cannot account for individual responses to training, safety considerations, and the complex physiological adaptation processes observed by experienced coaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Institute of Sport &#x2013; National Research Instutite.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Havers</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fitness and Health, IST University of Applied Sciences, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Health Sciences, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jelonnek</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fitness and Health, IST University of Applied Sciences, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masur</LastName><ForeName>Lukas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Movement Pedagogy, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isenmann</LastName><ForeName>Eduard</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fitness and Health, IST University of Applied Sciences, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sperlich</LastName><ForeName>Billy</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Integrative and Experimental Exercise Science and Training, Institute of Sport Science, University of W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geisler</LastName><ForeName>Stephan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Fitness and Health, IST University of Applied Sciences, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#xfc;king</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Movement Pedagogy, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chat bots</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coaching evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Generative AI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Large language models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maximal strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training plan design</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>In this study, artificial intelligence (AI) was used at some instances for linguistic refinement. Commercial products, including ChatGPT, Google Gemini and Microsoft Copilot, were used in the research process. The authors declare that there are no conflicts of interest related to the use of these products, and no financial or personal relationships with the respective companies that could have influenced the results or interpretation of the study. The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41048240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12492345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2026.152350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012; 11(4):209&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1249/JSR.0b013e31825dabb8 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e31825dabb8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Guidelines on Physical Activity and Sedentary Behaviour . 1st ed. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2020. 104 p. eng.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33369898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Fisher J, Grgic J, Haun C, Helms E, Phillips S, Steele J, Vigotsky A. Resistance Training Recommendations to Maximize Muscle Hypertrophy in an Athletic Population: Position Stand of the IUSCA. Int J Strength Cond. 2021; 1(1). doi: 10.47206/ijsc.v1i1.81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47206/ijsc.v1i1.81</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camargo JBB de, Brigatto FA, Zaroni RS, Trindade TB, Germano MD, Junior ACT, Oliveira TP de, Marchetti PH, Prestes J, Lopes CR. Manipulating Resistance Training Variables to Induce Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy: A Brief Narrative Review. Int J Exerc Sci. 2022; 15(4):910&#x2013;33. Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9458289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Squatting kinematics and kinetics and their application to exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2010; 24(12):3497&#x2013;506. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181bac2d7 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181bac2d7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20182386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C, Nunes EA, Currier BS, McLeod JC, Thomas ACQ, Phillips SM. An Evidence-Based Narrative Review of Mechanisms of Resistance Exercise-Induced Human Skeletal Muscle Hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022; 54(9):1546&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002929 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9390238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35389932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2019; 126(1):30&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00685.2018 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00685.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30335577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Lin Y. The Benefits and Challenges of ChatGPT: An Overview. Front Comput Intell Syst. 2022; 2(2):81&#x2013;3. doi: 10.54097/fcis.v2i2.4465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54097/fcis.v2i2.4465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team G. Bard becomes Gemini: try Ultra 1.0 and a new mobile app today. Google, Inc. [Internet]. Available from: https://blog.google/products/gemini/bard-gemini-advanced-app/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhur A. Redefining Healthcare With Artificial Intelligence (AI): The Contributions of ChatGPT, Gemini, and Co-pilot. Cureus. 2024; 16(4):e57795. doi: 10.7759/cureus.57795 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.57795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11077095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38721180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Pagaduan J, James C, Dergaa I, Beaven CM. Artificial intelligence in sport: Exploring the potential of using ChatGPT in resistance training prescription. Biol Sport. 2024; 41(2):209&#x2013;20. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.132987 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.132987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10955742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OpenAI. Introducing ChatGPT [Internet]. 2023.  [cited 2024 Dec 30]. Available from: https://openai.com/index/chatgpt/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Farooq A, Krug I, Pyne DB, Verhagen E, Taylor L, Del Wong P, Mujika I, Cortis C, Haddad M, Ahmadian O, Al Jufaili M, Al-Horani RA, Al-Mohannadi AS, Aloui A, Ammar A, Arifi F, Aziz AR, Batuev M, Beaven CM, Beneke R, Bici A, Bishnoi P, Bogwasi L, Bok D, Boukhris O, Boullosa D, Bragazzi N, Brito J, Cartagena RPP, Chaouachi A, Cheung SS, Chtourou H, Cosma G, Debevec T, DeLang MD, Dellal A, D&#xf6;nmez G, Driss T, Pe&#xf1;a Duque JD, Eirale C, Elloumi M, Foster C, Franchini E, Fusco A, Galy O, Gastin PB, Gill N, Girard O, Gregov C, Halson S, Hammouda O, Hanzl&#xed;kov&#xe1; I, Hassanmirzaei B, Haugen T, H&#xe9;bert-Losier K, Mu&#xf1;oz Hel&#xfa; H, Herrera-Valenzuela T, Hettinga FJ, Holtzhausen L, Hue O, Dello Iacono A, Ihalainen JK, James C, van Janse Rensburg DC, Joseph S, Kamoun K, Khaled M, Khalladi K, Kim KJ, Kok L-Y, MacMillan L, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Matsunaga R, Memishi S, Millet GP, Moussa-Chamari I, Musa DI, Nguyen HMT, Nikolaidis PT, Owen A, Padulo J, Pagaduan JC, Perera NP, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Pillay L, Popa A, Pudasaini A, Rabbani A, Rahayu T, Romdhani M, Salamh P, Sarkar A-S, Schillinger A, Seiler S, Setyawati H, Shrestha N, Suraya F, Tabben M, Trabelsi K, Urhausen A, Valtonen M, Weber J, Whiteley R, Zrane A, Zerguini Y, Zmijewski P, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Ben Saad H, Chamari K. Training During the COVID-19 Lockdown: Knowledge, Beliefs, and Practices of 12,526 Athletes from 142 Countries and Six Continents. Sports Med. 2022; 52(4):933&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01573-z Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01573-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Saad HB, El Omri A, Glenn JM, Clark CCT, Washif JA, Guelmami N, Hammouda O, Al-Horani RA, Reynoso-S&#xe1;nchez LF, Romdhani M, Paineiras-Domingos LL, Vancini RL, Taheri M, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Trabelsi K, Chtourou H, Zghibi M, Eken &#xd6;, Swed S, Aissa MB, Shawki HH, El-Seedi HR, Mujika I, Seiler S, Zmijewski P, Pyne DB, Knechtle B, Asif IM, Drezner JA, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Chamari K. Using artificial intelligence for exercise prescription in personalised health promotion: A critical evaluation of OpenAI&#x2019;s GPT-4 model. Biol Sport. 2024; 41(2):221&#x2013;41. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.133661 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.133661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10955739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;king P, Sperlich B, Voigt L, van Hooren B, Zanini M, Zinner C. ChatGPT Generated Training Plans for Runners are not Rated Optimal by Coaching Experts, but Increase in Quality with Additional Input Information. J Sports Sci Med. 2024; 23(1):56&#x2013;72. doi: 10.52082/jssm.2024.56 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2024.56</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10915606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38455449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Liu Q, Pang J, Zeng C, Ma X, Li P, Ma L, Huang J, Xie H. Assessment of Personalized Exercise Prescriptions Issued by ChatGPT 4.0 and Intelligent Health Promotion Systems for Patients with Hypertension Comorbidities Based on the Transtheoretical Model: A Comparative Analysis. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2024; 175063&#x2013;78. doi: 10.2147/JMDH.S477452 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JMDH.S477452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11559245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39539514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Ben Saad H, Ghouili H, M Glenn J, El Omri A, Slim I, Hasni Y, Taheri M, Ben Aissa M, Guelmami N, Al-Horani R, Washif JA, Shoib S, Mohammed Alyasiri O, Jose Mataruna-Dos-Santos L, Ferreira Alves R, Ibrahim Ceylan H, Swed S, Z Alshahrani N, Chalghaf N, Dai H, Luigi Bragazzi N, Chamari K. Evaluating the Applicability and Appropriateness of ChatGPT as a Source for Tailored Nutrition Advice: A Multi-Scenario Study. N Asian J Med. 2024; 2(1):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.61838/kman.najm.2.1.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61838/kman.najm.2.1.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havers T, Masur L, Isenmann E, Geisler S, Zinner C, Sperlich B, D&#xfc;king P. Reproducibility and quality of hypertrophy-related training plans generated by GPT-4 and Google Gemini as evaluated by coaching experts. Biol Sport. 2025;42(2):289&#x2013;329. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2025.145911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2025.145911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11963122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40182716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha-Silva R, Lima BE de, Costa TG, Morais NS, Jos&#xe9; G, Cordeiro DF, Almeida AA de, Lopim GM, Viana RB, Sousa BS, Colugnati DB, Vancini RL, Andrade MS, Weiss K, Knechtle B, Arida RM, Lira CAB de. Can people with epilepsy trust AI chatbots for information on physical exercise? Epilepsy Behav. 2024; 163110193. doi: 10.1016/j.yebeh.2024.110193 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2024.110193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39637730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandbakk SB, Walther J, Solli GS, T&#xf8;nnessen E, Haugen T. Training Quality-What Is It and How Can We Improve It? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023; 18(5):557&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2022-0484 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2022-0484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36965489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD, Arena R, Riebe D, Pescatello LS. ACSM&#x2019;s new preparticipation health screening recommendations from ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription, ninth edition. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2013; 12(4):215&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1249/JSR.0b013e31829a68cf Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e31829a68cf</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff G, Triplett NT, editors. Essentials of strength training and conditioning. Champaign, IL, Windsor, ON, Leeds: Human Kinetics; 2016. 735 p. eng.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffries AC, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ, Wallace L, McCall A, Impellizzeri FM. Development of a Revised Conceptual Framework of Physical Training for Use in Research and Practice. Sports Med. 2022; 52(4):709&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01551-5 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01551-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone M, Plisk S, Collins D. Training principles: evaluation of modes and methods of resistance training--a coaching perspective. Sports Biomech. 2002; 1(1):79&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1080/14763140208522788 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763140208522788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14658137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bern&#xe1;rdez-V&#xe1;zquez R, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Castillo D, Beato M. Resistance Training Variables for Optimization of Muscle Hypertrophy: An Umbrella Review. Front Sports Act Living. 2022; 4949021. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2022.949021 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.949021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9302196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35873210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toigo M, Boutellier U. New fundamental resistance exercise determinants of molecular and cellular muscle adaptations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006; 97(6):643&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1007/s00421-006-0238-1 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-006-0238-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coratella G. Appropriate Reporting of Exercise Variables in Resistance Training Protocols: Much more than Load and Number of Repetitions. Sports Med. &#x2013; Open. 2022; 8(1):99. doi: 10.1186/s40798-022-00492-1 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00492-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9339067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35907047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Androulakis Korakakis P, Wolf M, Coleman M, Burke R, Pi&#xf1;ero A, Nippard J, Schoenfeld BJ. Optimizing Resistance Training Technique to Maximize Muscle Hypertrophy: A Narrative Review. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2023; 9(1). doi: 10.3390/jfmk9010009 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk9010009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10801605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38249086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Arent S, Schoenfeld BJ, Stout JR, Campbell B, Wilborn CD, Taylor L, Kalman D, Smith-Ryan AE, Kreider RB, Willoughby D, Arciero PJ, VanDusseldorp TA, Ormsbee MJ, Wildman R, Greenwood M, Ziegenfuss TN, Aragon AA, Antonio J. International society of sports nutrition position stand: nutrient timing. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017; 1433. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0189-4 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0189-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5596471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayers JW, Poliak A, Dredze M, Leas EC, Zhu Z, Kelley JB, Faix DJ, Goodman AM, Longhurst CA, Hogarth M, Smith DM. Comparing Physician and Artificial Intelligence Chatbot Responses to Patient Questions Posted to a Public Social Media Forum. JAMA Intern Med. 2023; 183(6):589&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.1838 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2023.1838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10148230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37115527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seth I, Cox A, Xie Y, Bulloch G, Hunter-Smith DJ, Rozen WM, Ross RJ. Evaluating Chatbot Efficacy for Answering Frequently Asked Questions in Plastic Surgery: A ChatGPT Case Study Focused on Breast Augmentation. Aesthet Surg J. 2023; 43(10):1126&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1093/asj/sjad140 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/asj/sjad140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37158147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukac S, Dayan D, Fink V, Leinert E, Hartkopf A, Veselinovic K, Janni W, Rack B, Pfister K, Heitmeir B, Ebner F. Evaluating ChatGPT as an adjunct for the multidisciplinary tumor board decisionmaking in primary breast cancer cases. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2023; 308(6):1831&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1007/s00404-023-07130-5 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00404-023-07130-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37458761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Beaven CM, Pagaduan J, Lim J, Raja Azidin, Raja Mohammed Firhad, Tan E, Lum D, James C. Current practices of warm-up during strength training and conditioning based on coaching experience. Sport Sci Health. 2025; 1&#x2013;13. En; en. doi: 10.1007/s11332-025-01341-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-025-01341-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleiss JL. Measuring nominal scale agreement among many raters. Psychological Bulletin. 1971; 76(5):378&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1037/h0031619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0031619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R: A language and environment for statistical computing : The R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puce L, Ceylan H&#x130;, Trompetto C, Cotellessa F, Schenone C, Marinelli L, Zmijewski P, Bragazzi NL, Mori L. Optimizing athletic performance through advanced nutrition strategies: can AI and digital platforms have a role in ultraendurance sports? Biol Sport. 2024; 41(4):305&#x2013;13. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.141063 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.141063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11475005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naz R, Akac&#x131; O, Erdo&#x11f;an H, A&#xe7;&#x131;kg&#xf6;z A. Can large language models provide accurate and quality information to parents regarding chronic kidney diseases? J Eval Clin Pract. 2024; 30(8):1556&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1111/jep.14084 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.14084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38959373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Fekih-Romdhane F, Hallit S, Loch AA, Glenn JM, Fessi MS, Ben Aissa M, Souissi N, Guelmami N, Swed S, El Omri A, Bragazzi NL, Ben Saad H. ChatGPT is not ready yet for use in providing mental health assessment and interventions. Front Psychiatry. 2023; 141277756. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1277756 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1277756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10794665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38239905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enes A, Alves RC, Schoenfeld BJ, Oneda G, Perin SC, Trindade TB, Prestes J, Souza-Junior TP. Rest-pause and drop-set training elicit similar strength and hypertrophy adaptations compared with traditional sets in resistance-trained males. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2021; 46(11):1417&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2021-0278 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2021-0278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34260860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Tran DL, Hogan CM, Haff GG, Latella C. Chronic Effects of Altering Resistance Training Set Configurations Using Cluster Sets: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2021; 51(4):707&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1007/s40279-020-01408-3 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01408-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33475986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Malleron T, Har-Nir I, Androulakis-Korakakis P, Wolf M, Fisher JP, Halperin I. Are Trainees Lifting Heavy Enough? Self-Selected Loads in Resistance Exercise: A Scoping Review and Exploratory Meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2022; 52(12):2909&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1007/s40279-022-01717-9 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01717-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35790622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson ZP, Pelland JC, Remmert JF, Refalo MC, Jukic I, Steele J, Zourdos MC. Exploring the Dose-Response Relationship Between Estimated Resistance Training Proximity to Failure, Strength Gain, and Muscle Hypertrophy: A Series of Meta-Regressions. Sports Med. 2024; 54(9):2209&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1007/s40279-024-02069-2 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02069-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38970765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinton PA, Schoenfeld BJ, Murphy A. Dose-Response Modelling of Resistance Exercise Across Outcome Domains in Strength and Conditioning: A Metaanalysis. Sports Med. 2024; 54(6):1579&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1007/s40279-024-02006-3 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02006-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11239729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38652410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and Hypertrophy Adaptations Between Low- vs. High-Load Resistance Training: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017; 31(12):3508&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamarsland H, Moen H, Skaar OJ, Jorang PW, R&#xf8;dahl HS, R&#xf8;nnestad BR. Equal-Volume Strength Training With Different Training Frequencies Induces Similar Muscle Hypertrophy and Strength Improvement in Trained Participants. Front physiol. 2021; 12789403. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.789403 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.789403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8766679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ratamess NA, Peterson MD, Contreras B, Sonmez GT, Alvar BA. Effects of different volumeequated resistance training loading strategies on muscular adaptations in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res. 2014; 28(10):2909&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000480 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24714538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Davies TB, Lazinica B, Krieger JW, Pedisic Z. Effect of Resistance Training Frequency on Gains in Muscular Strength: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2018; 48(5):1207&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0872-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29470825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The Effect of Weekly Set Volume on Strength Gain: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2017; 47(12):2585&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0762-7 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0762-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5684266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28755103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Riek S, Carson RG. Neural adaptations to resistance training: implications for movement control. Sports Med. 2001; 31(12):829&#x2013;40. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200131120-00001 Cited in: PubMed; PMID .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200131120-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11665911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>