<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33312275</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1640-5544</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>74</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of human kinetics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hum Kinet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Low-Load Vs. High-Load Resistance Training on Muscle Fiber Hypertrophy: A Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>51</StartPage><EndPage>58</EndPage><MedlinePgn>51-58</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/hukin-2020-0013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this meta-analysis was to explore the effects of low-load vs. high-load resistance training on type I and type II muscle fiber hypertrophy. Searches for studies were performed through ten databases. Studies were included if they: (a) compared the effects of low-load vs. high-load resistance training (performed to momentary muscular failure); and, (b) assessed muscle fiber hypertrophy. A random-effects meta-analysis was performed to analyze the data. Ten study groups were included in the analysis. In the meta-analysis for the effects of low-load vs. high-load resistance training on type I muscle fiber hypertrophy, there was no significant difference between the training conditions (standardized mean difference: 0.28; 95% confidence interval: -0.27, 0.82; p = 0.316; I<sup>2</sup> = 18%; 95% prediction interval: -0.71, 1.28). In the meta-analysis for the effects of low-load vs. high-load resistance training on type II muscle fiber hypertrophy, there was no significant difference between the training conditions (standardized mean difference: 0.30; 95% confidence interval: -0.05, 0.66; p = 0.089; I<sup>2</sup> = 0%; 95% prediction interval: -0.28, 0.88). In this meta-analysis, there were no significant differences between low-load and high-load resistance training on hypertrophy of type I or type II muscle fibers. The 95% confidence and prediction intervals were very wide, suggesting that the true effect in the population and the effect reported in a future study conducted on this topic could be in different directions and anywhere from trivial to very large. Therefore, there is a clear need for future research on this topic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Jozo Grgic, published by Sciendo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grgic</LastName><ForeName>Jozo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health and Sport (IHES), Victoria University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>J Hum Kinet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1640-5544</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CSA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-sectional area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intensity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">loading zones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">volume</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">hukin-2020-0013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. Introduction to Meta-Analysis. West Sussex: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 385;; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, Ragg KE, Ratamess NA, Kraemer WJ, Staron RS. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88(1-2):50&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on dynamic muscular strength: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(8):1603&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs SH, Black N. The feasibility of creating a checklist for the assessment of the methodological quality both of randomised and non-randomised studies of health care interventions. J Epidemiol Commun Health. 1998;52(6):377&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9764259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Semmler JG, Enoka RM. Training adaptations in the behavior of human motor units. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101(6):1766&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16794023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37(2):145&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Bottaro M. Effects of training attendance on muscle strength of young men after 11 weeks of resistance training. Asian J Sports Med. 2013;4(2):101&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Homolak J, Mikulic P, Botella J, Schoenfeld BJ. Inducing hypertrophic effects of type I skeletal muscle fibers: A hypothetical role of time under load in resistance training aimed at muscular hypertrophy. Med Hypotheses. 2018a;112:40&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29447936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Skrepnik M, Davies TB, Mikulic P. Effects of rest interval duration in resistance training on measures of muscular strength: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2018b;48(1):137&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ. Are the Hypertrophic Adaptations to High and Low-Load Resistance Training Muscle Fiber Type Specific? Front Physiol. 2018;9:402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5915697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Roberts MD. A Critical Evaluation of the Biological Construct Skeletal Muscle Hypertrophy: Size Matters but So Does the Measurement. Front Physiol. 2019;10:247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6423469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman E, Somjen G, Carpenter DO. Functional significance of cell size in spinal motoneurons. J Neurophysiol. 1965;28:560&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14328454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Equivalence Tests: A Practical Primer for t Tests, Correlations, and Meta-Analyses. Soc Psychol Personal Sci. 2017;8(4):355&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5502906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28736600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C, Kim HJ, Morton RW, Harris R, Phillips SM, Jeong TS, Kim CK. Resistance Exercise-induced Changes in Muscle Phenotype Are Load Dependent. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51(12):2578&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31306302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, West DW, Burd NA, Breen L, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2012;113(1):71&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, Mazara N, McGlory C, Quadrilatero J, Baechler BL, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. J Appl Physiol. 2016;121(1):129&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4967245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sonne MW, Farias Zuniga A, Mohammad IYZ, Jones A, McGlory C, Keir PJ, Potvin JR, Phillips SM. Muscle fibre activation is unaffected by load and repetition duration when resistance exercise is performed to task failure. J Physiol. 2019;597(17):4601&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogborn D, Schoenfeld BJ. The role of fiber types in muscle hypertrophy: implications for loading strategies. Strength Cond J. 2014;36(2):20&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Dos Santos ED, Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ. Acute Effects of Different Training Loads on Affective Responses in Resistance-trained Men. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40(13):850&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31499564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and Hypertrophy Adaptations Between Low- vs. High-Load Resistance Training: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Vigotsky AD, Grgic J, Haun C, Contreras B, Delcastillo K, Francis A, Cote G, Alto A. Do the anatomical and physiological properties of a muscle determine its adaptive response to different loading protocols? Physiol Rep. 2020;8(9):e14427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7186566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32342648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Wilson JM, Lowery RP, Krieger JW. Muscular adaptations in low- versus high-load resistance training: A meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25530577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuenke MD, Herman JR, Gliders RM, Hagerman FC, Hikida RS, Rana SR, Ragg KE, Staron RS. Early-phase muscular adaptations in response to slow-speed versus traditional resistance-training regimens. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(10):3585&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron RS, Hagerman FC, Hikida RS, Murray TF, Hostler DP, Crill MT, Ragg KE, Toma K. Fiber type composition of the vastus lateralis muscle of young men and women. J Histochem Cytochem. 2000;48(5):623&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10769046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>