<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">33443368</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Low-Load Resistance Training Performed to Muscle Failure or Near Muscle Failure Does Not Promote Additional Gains on Muscle Strength, Hypertrophy, and Functional Performance of Older Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1209</StartPage><EndPage>1215</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1209-1215</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003632</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bergamasco, JGA, Gomes da Silva, D, Bittencourt, DF, Martins de Oliveira, R, J&#xfa;nior, JCB, Caruso, FC, Godoi, D, Borghi-Silva, A, and Libardi, CA. Low-load resistance training performed to muscle failure or near muscle failure does not promote additional gains on muscle strength, hypertrophy, and functional performance of older adults. J Strength Cond Res 36(5): 1209-1215, 2022-The aim of the present study was to compare the effects of low-load resistance training (RT) protocols performed to failure (FAI), to voluntary interruption (VOL), and with a fixed low repetitions (FIX) on muscle strength, hypertrophy, and functional performance in older adults. Forty-one subjects (60-77 years) were randomized into one of the RT protocols (FAI, VOL, or FIX) and completed 12 weeks of RT at 40% of 1 repetition maximum (1RM), twice a week. The assessments included 1RM test, muscle cross-sectional area (CSA), rate of torque development (RTD), and functional performance (chair stand [CS], habitual gait speed [HGS], maximal gait speed [MGS], and timed up-and-go [TUG]). All protocols significantly increased 1RM values from Pre (FAI: 318.3 &#xb1; 116.3 kg; VOL: 342.9 &#xb1; 93.7 kg; FIX: 328.0 &#xb1; 107.2 kg) to Post (FAI: 393.0 &#xb1; 143.1 kg, 23.5%; VOL: 423.0 &#xb1; 114.5 kg, 23.3%; FIX: 397.8 &#xb1; 94.6 kg, 21.3%; p &lt; 0.0001 for all groups). Regarding CS, all protocols showed significant improvements from Pre (FAI: 11.5 &#xb1; 2.4 seconds; VOL: 12.1 &#xb1; 2.5 seconds; FIX: 11.3 &#xb1; 1.1 seconds) to Post (FAI: 10.5 &#xb1; 1.1 seconds, -8.5%, p = 0.001; VOL: 10.3 &#xb1; 1.5 seconds, -15.1%, p = 0.001; FIX: 11.0 &#xb1; 1.1, -3.2%, p = 0.001). Habitual gait speed values increased significantly from Pre (FAI: 1.3 &#xb1; 0.2 m&#xb7;s-1; VOL: 1.3 &#xb1; 0.1 m&#xb7;s-1; FIX: 1.3 &#xb1; 0.1 m&#xb7;s-1) to Post (FAI: 1.4 &#xb1; 0.2 m&#xb7;s-1, 2.5%, p = 0.03; VOL: 1.4 &#xb1; 0.2 m&#xb7;s-1, 5.2%, p = 0.036; FIX: 1.4 &#xb1; 0.1 m&#xb7;s-1, 5.7%, p = 0.03). No significant differences between protocols were found (p &gt; 0.05). In addition, there were no significant changes in CSA, RTD, MGS, and TUG for any protocols (p &gt; 0.05). In conclusion, low-load RT performed without muscle failure promotes significant improvements in muscle strength and some parameters of functional performance in older adults.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergamasco</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o Guilherme Almeida</ForeName><Initials>JGA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Silva</LastName><ForeName>Deivid Gomes</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bittencourt</LastName><ForeName>Diego Fernandes</ForeName><Initials>DF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Oliveira</LastName><ForeName>Ramon Martins</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J&#xfa;nior</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9; Carlos Bonjorno</ForeName><Initials>JCB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine Department, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caruso</LastName><ForeName>Fl&#xe1;via Rossi</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Department, Cardiopulmonary Physiotherapy Laboratory, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Godoi</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, DIN&#xc2;MICA-Motor Behavior Laboratory, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borghi-Silva</LastName><ForeName>Audrey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy Department, Cardiopulmonary Physiotherapy Laboratory, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Libardi</LastName><ForeName>Cleiton Augusto</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, MUSCULAB-Laboratory of Neuromuscular Adaptations to Resistance Training, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Carlos (UFSCar), S&#xe3;o Carlos, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076604" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Functional Performance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33443368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202205000-00006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 1510&#x2013;1530, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borde R, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U. Dose&#x2013;response relationships of resistance training in healthy old adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 45: 1693&#x2013;1720, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. ASEP procedures recommendation I: Accurate assessment of muscular strength and power. J Exerc Physiol Online 4: 1&#x2013;21, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell AJ, Borrie MJ, Spears GF. Risk factors for falls in a community-based prospective study of people 70 years and older. J Gerontol 44: M112&#x2013;M117, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chmelo EA, Crotts CI, Newman JC, et al. Heterogeneity of physical function responses to exercise training in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc 63: 462&#x2013;469, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Social Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ: Erllbaum Associates, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ. Invited review: Aging and sarcopenia. J Appl Physiol 95: 1717&#x2013;1727, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallentin N, Jorgensen K, Simonsen EB. Motor unit recruitment during prolonged isometric contractions. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 67: 335&#x2013;341, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, et al. Short-term recovery following resistance exercise leading or not to failure. Int J Sports Med 37: 295&#x2013;304, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins ND, Housh TJ, Bergstrom HC, et al. Muscle activation during three sets to failure at 80 vs. 30% 1RM resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 115: 2335&#x2013;2347, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang C, Ranganathan VK, Zhang J, Siemionow V, Yue GH. Motor effort training with low exercise intensity improves muscle strength and descending command in aging. Medicine 95: e3291, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, Souza T, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o M, et al. The number of sessions required to stabilize peak torque and rate of torque development in isometric contractions in young, middle-age and older individuals. Isok Exerc Sci 24: 165&#x2013;170, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, Catai AM, Miquelini M, et al. Hemodynamic responses to blood flow restriction and resistance exercise to muscular failure. Int J Sports Med 38: 134&#x2013;140, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Bottaro M, et al. Vastus lateralis muscle cross-sectional area ultrasonography validity for image fitting in humans. J Strength Cond Res 28: 3293&#x2013;3297, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus RL, Addison O, Dibble LE, et al. Intramuscular adipose tissue, sarcopenia, and mobility function in older individuals. J Aging Res 2012: 629&#x2013;637, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy EK, Horvat MA, Holtsberg PA, Wisenbaker JM. Repeated chair stands as a measure of lower limb strength in sexagenarian women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 59: 1207&#x2013;1212, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miotto JM, Chodzko-Zajko WJ, Reich JL, Supler MM. Reliability and validity of the fullerton functional fitness test: An independent replication study. J Aging Phys Activ 7: 339&#x2013;353, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki J, Murata S, Horie J, et al. Lumbar lordosis angle (LLA) and leg strength predict walking ability in elderly males. Arch Gerontol Geriatr 56: 141&#x2013;147, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobrega SR, Ugrinowitsch C, Pintanel L, Barcelos C, Libardi CA. Effect of resistance training to muscle failure vs. Volitional interruption at high- and low-intensities on muscle mass and strength. J Strength Cond Res 32: 162&#x2013;169, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pau M, Leban B, Collu G, Migliaccio GM. Effect of light and vigorous physical activity on balance and gait of older adults. Arch Gerontol Geriatr 59: 568&#x2013;573, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisciottano M, Pinto S, Szejnfeld V, de Moura Castro CH. The relationship between lean mass, muscle strength and physical ability in independent healthy elderly women from the community. J Nutr Health Aging 18: 554&#x2013;558, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Wilhelm EN, Botton CE, et al. Effects of single vs. multiple-set short-term strength training in elderly women. Age 36: 9720, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Castillo A, de la Fuente CI, et al. High-speed resistance training is more effective than low-speed resistance training to increase functional capacity and muscle performance in older women. Exp Gerontol 58: 51&#x2013;57, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Martin KI, Doros G, et al. Comparative effects of light or heavy resistance power training for improving lower extremity power and physical performance in mobility-limited older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 70: 374&#x2013;380, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Haun CT, Mobley CB, et al. Physiological differences between low versus high skeletal muscle hypertrophic responders to resistance exercise training: Current perspectives and future research directions. Front Physiol 9: 834, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers ME, Rogers NL, Takeshima N, Islam MM. Methods to assess and improve the physical parameters associated with fall risk in older adults. Prev Med 36: 255&#x2013;264, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low-vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2954&#x2013;2963, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Leenders M, de Groot L, van Loon LJ, Verdijk LB. Muscle mass and strength gains following 6 months of resistance type exercise training are only partly preserved within one year with autonomous exercise continuation in older adults. Exp Gerontol 121: 71&#x2013;78, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steffen TM, Hacker TA, Mollinger L. Age- and gender-related test performance in community-dwelling elderly people: Six-minute walk test, berg balance scale, timed up &amp; go test, and gait speeds. Phys Therapy 82: 128&#x2013;137, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Chandler TJ, Conley MS, Kramer JB, Stone ME. Training to muscular failure: Is it necessary? Strength Cond J 18: 44&#x2013;48, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan GM, Feinn R. Using effect size-or why the P value is not enough. J Graduate Medical Educ 4: 279&#x2013;282, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiggemann CL, Dias CP, Radaelli R, et al. Effect of traditional resistance and power training using rated perceived exertion for enhancement of muscle strength, power, and functional performance. Age 38: 42, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng BS, Marsh DR, Hamilton MT, Booth FW. Strength and aerobic training attenuate muscle wasting and improve resistance to the development of disability with aging. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 50: 113&#x2013;119, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Roie E, Delecluse C, Coudyzer W, Boonen S, Bautmans I. Strength training at high versus low external resistance in older adults: Effects on muscle volume, muscle strength, and force-velocity characteristics. Exp Gerontol 48: 1351&#x2013;1361, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallerstein LF, Tricoli V, Barroso R, et al. Effects of strength and power training on neuromuscular variables in older adults. J Aging Phys Activ 20: 171&#x2013;185, 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>