<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41093307</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2733-7545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical activity and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Act Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ladder-climbing resistance training stimulates upper limb flexor digitorum profundus muscle hypertrophy in rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23</StartPage><EndPage>32</EndPage><MedlinePgn>23-32</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20463/pan.2025.0022</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Skeletal muscles have notable features that enable muscle hypertrophy in response to resistance training (RET). Most animal studies on ladder climbing have focused on the lower limb muscles; however, the movement also involves the upper limb muscles. Moreover, little evidence exists regarding whether RET affects food intake. Therefore, this study aimed to investigate RET-induced muscle hypertrophy in both the upper and lower limb muscles and to examine changes in food intake.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty male Wistar Hannover rats (6 weeks old) were randomly assigned to sedentary control (SED, n = 10) or resistance training (RET, n = 10) groups during a 2-week acclimatization period. RET rats underwent the primary exercise training for 8 weeks, after 1 week of climbing adaptation, with a one-repetition maximum test. Body weight and food intake were monitored weekly. Twenty-four hours after the final training session, major muscles were dissected and weighed, and the flexor digitorum profundus (FDP) was analyzed using the cross-sectional area (CSA) of the myofibers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">RET group showed significantly decreased final body weight and food intake compared to the SED group (p &lt; 0.001). RET enhanced both muscle quantity (increased relative FDP muscle weight) and quality (improved muscle strength capacity and larger FDP myofibers).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Ladder-climbing RET induced hypertrophy in the upper limb FDP muscle rather than in other lower limb muscles despite decreases in body weight and food intake. Upper extremity strength training can provide benefits to healthy adults and individuals with limited lower extremity mobility.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Insu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity and Performance Institute (PAPI), Konkuk University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Konkuk University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Act Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2733-7545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body weight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-sectional area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">food intake</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle weight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myofiber</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41093307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12530985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2025.0022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pan.2025.0022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Qaisar R, Bhaskaran S, Van Remmen H. Muscle fiber type diversification during exercise and regeneration. Free radical biology &amp; medicine. 2016;98:56&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27032709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Roberts BM, Adams GR. Molecular regulation of exercise-induced muscle fiber hypertrophy. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2018;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh Q, Song T, Petrany MJ, Cramer AA, Sun C, Sadayappan S, Lee SJ, Millay DP. Myonuclear accretion is a determinant of exercise-induced remodeling in skeletal muscle. Elife. 2019;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6497442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31012848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:674&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarasheski KE, Lemon PW, Gilloteaux J. Effect of heavy-resistance exercise training on muscle fiber composition in young rats. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1990;69:434&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2146243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki T, Uchiyama S, Nakano S. A weight-lifting exercise model for inducing hypertrophy in the hindlimb muscles of rats. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;24:881&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1406173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Vechetti-J&#xfa;nior IJ, Alves de Souza RW, Castan EP, Milanezi-Aguiar RC, Padovani CR, Carvalho RF, Silva MD. Myogenin, MyoD and IGF-I regulate muscle mass but not fiber-type conversion during resistance training in rats. Int J Sports Med. 2013;34:293&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23059557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>das Neves W, de Oliveira LF, da Silva RP, Alves CRR, Lancha AH. Fasting: a major limitation for resistance exercise training effects in rodents. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2017;51:e5427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5685054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29185588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan ND, Williams DA, Lynch GS. Adaptations in rat skeletal muscle following long-term resistance exercise training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1998;77:372&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9562367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrar RP. Physiological hypertrophy of the FHL muscle following 8 weeks of progressive resistance exercise in the rat. Can J Appl Physiol. 2004;29:16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15001801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Barton ER, Sweeney HL, Farrar RP. Viral expression of insulin-like growth factor-I enhances muscle hypertrophy in resistance-trained rats. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2004;96:1097&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14766764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begue G, Douillard A, Galbes O, Rossano B, Vernus B, Candau R, Py G. Early activation of rat skeletal muscle IL-6/STAT1/STAT3 dependent gene expression in resistance exercise linked to hypertrophy. PloS one. 2013;8:e57141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3579782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23451164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L, Lu AM, Wang Y, Hong A, Chen Y, Hu J, Li X, Qin ZH. Chronic resistance training activates autophagy and reduces apoptosis of muscle cells by modulating IGF-1 and its receptors, Akt/mTOR and Akt/FOXO3a signaling in aged rats. Exp Gerontol. 2013;48:427&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23419688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung S, Ahn N, Kim S, Byun J, Joo Y, Kim S, Jung Y, Park S, Hwang I, Kim K. The effect of ladder-climbing exercise on atrophy/hypertrophy-related myokine expression in middle-aged male Wistar rats. J Physiol Sci. 2015;65:515&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10717129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26223833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilha CS, Cella PS, Ribeiro AS, Voltarelli FA, Testa MTJ, Marinello PC, Iarosz KC, Guirro PB, Deminice R. Moderate vs highload resistance training on muscular adaptations in rats. Life sciences. 2019;238:116964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31639398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippe AG, Lionne C, Sanchez AMJ, Pagano AF, Candau R. Increase in muscle power is associated with myofibrillar ATPase adaptations during resistance training. Exp Physiol. 2019;104:1274&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31168842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung YL, Sato A, Takino Y, Ishigami A, Machida S. Influence of oestrogen on satellite cells and myonuclear domain size in skeletal muscles following resistance exercise. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2022;13:2525&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9530499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35818664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Rosa Lima T, &#xc1;vila ETP, Fraga GA, de Souza Sena M, de Souza Dias AB, de Almeida PC, Dos Santos Trombeta JC, Junior RCV, Damazo AS, Navalta JW, Prestes J, Voltarelli FA. Effect of administration of high-protein diet in rats submitted to resistance training. Eur J Nutr. 2018;57:1083&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28236109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu WG, Hibbert JE, Lin KH, Steinert ND, Lemens JL, Jorgenson KW, Newman SM, Lamming DW, Hornberger TA. Weight Pulling: A Novel Mouse Model of Human Progressive Resistance Exercise. Cells. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8465477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34572107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trautman ME, Braucher LN, Elliehausen C, Zhu WG, Zelenovskiy E, Green M, Sonsalla MM, Yeh CY, Hornberger TA, Konopka AR, Lamming DW. Resistance exercise protects mice from protein-induced fat accretion. Elife. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10686620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38019262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippe M, Wegst D, M&#xfc;ller T, Raschner C, Burtscher M. Climbing-specific finger flexor performance and forearm muscle oxygenation in elite male and female sport climbers. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:2839&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22131087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meznaric M, &#x10c;arni A. Characterisation of flexor digitorum profundus, flexor digitorum superficialis and extensor digitorum communis by electrophoresis and immunohistochemical analysis of myosin heavy chain isoforms in older men. Ann Anat. 2020;227:151412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31408678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebal E, Cavalie H, Michaux O, Lac G. Effect of a moderate exercise on the regulatory hormones of food intake in rats. Appetite. 2007;49:521&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17462789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim CH, Gil JH, Quan H, Viet DH, Kim CK. Effect of 8-week leucine supplementation and resistance exercise training on muscle hypertrophy and satellite cell activation in rats. Physiological reports. 2018;6:e13725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6021278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29952091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon I, Go G-W, Lee Y, Kim J-H. Prolonged Endurance Exercise Adaptations Counteract Doxorubicin Chemotherapy-Induced Myotoxicity in Mice. Applied Sciences. 2022;12:3652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon I. Protective effects of endurance exercise on skeletal muscle remodeling against doxorubicin-induced myotoxicity in mice. Phys Act Nutr. 2020;24:11&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7451836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noto Y, Shiga K, Tsuji Y, Kondo M, Tokuda T, Mizuno T, Nakagawa M. Contrasting echogenicity in flexor digitorum profundus-flexor carpi ulnaris: a diagnostic ultrasound pattern in sporadic inclusion body myositis. Muscle Nerve. 2014;49:745&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24037920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki M, Yamazaki Y, Matsunami K. Relationship between force and electromyographic activity during rapid isometric contraction in power grip. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1994;93:218&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7515798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brorsson S, Nilsdotter A, Pedersen E, Bremander A, Thorstensson C. Relationship between finger flexion and extension force in healthy women and women with rheumatoid arthritis. J Rehabil Med. 2012;44:605&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22674244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon I, Jang Y, Cho JY, Jang YC, Lee Y. Long-term resistance exercise-induced muscular hypertrophy is associated with autophagy modulation in rats. J Physiol Sci. 2018;68:269&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10718009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28213823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>