<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">16051622</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-3751</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>568</Volume><Issue>Pt 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fasted-state skeletal muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise is altered with training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>283</StartPage><EndPage>290</EndPage><MedlinePgn>283-90</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of the present investigation was to determine how fasted-state protein synthesis was affected, acutely, by resistance training. Eight men (24.8+/-1.7 years, body mass index=23.2+/-1.0 kg m-2; means+/-s.e.m.) undertook an 8 week programme of unilateral resistance exercise training (3 sessions week-1, progression from two to four sets; intensity was 80% of the subjects' single repetition maximum (1RM): knee extension and leg press). Following training, subjects underwent two primed constant infusions of l-[ring-13C6]phenylalanine to determine mixed and myofibrillar muscle protein synthesis (MPS) at rest and 12 h after an acute bout of resistance exercise at the same exercise intensity--each leg 80% of 1RM. Biopsies (vastus lateralis) were taken to measure incorporation of labelled phenylalanine into mixed and myofibrillar skeletal muscle proteins and yield fractional MPS. Training resulted in significant dynamic strength gains that were greater (P&lt;0.001) in the trained leg. Hypertrophy of type IIa and IIx fibres (P&lt;0.05) was observed following training. After training, resting mixed MPS rate was elevated (+48%; P&lt;0.05). Acutely, resistance exercise stimulated mixed MPS only in the untrained leg (P&lt;0.05). Myofibrillar MPS was unchanged at rest following training (P=0.61). Myofibrillar MPS increased after resistance exercise (P&lt;0.05), but was not different between the trained and untrained legs (P=0.36). We observed divergent changes in resting mixed versus myofibrillar protein synthesis with training. In addition, resistance training modified the acute response of MPS to resistance exercise by dampening the increased synthesis of non-myofibrillar proteins while maintaining the synthesis of myofibrillar proteins.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Paul L</ForeName><Initials>PL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, IWC AB116, McMaster University, 1280 Main Street W., Hamilton, ON, Canada L8S 4K1.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staron</LastName><ForeName>Robert S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Stuart M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2005</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009124">Muscle Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>47E5O17Y3R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010649">Phenylalanine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049108" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Enlargement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005215" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fasting</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007866" MajorTopicYN="N">Leg</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009119" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018656" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fibers, Fast-Twitch</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009124" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="Y">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010649" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenylalanine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2006</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16051622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2005.093708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jphysiol.2005.093708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Balagopal P, Ljunovist Q, Nair KS. Skeletal muscle myosin heavy-chain synthesis rate in healthy humans. Am J Physiol. 1997a;272:E45&#x2013;E50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9038850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balagopal P, Rooyackers OE, Adey DB, Ades PA, Nair KS. Effects of aging on in vivo synthesis of skeletal muscle myosin heavy-chain and sarcoplasmic protein in humans. Am J Physiol. 1997b;273:E790&#x2013;E800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9357810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balagopal P, Schimke JC, Ades PA, Adey DB, Nair KS. Age effect on transcript levels and synthesis rate of muscle MHC and response to resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metabolism. 2001;280:E203&#x2013;E208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11158921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Maggi SP, Williams BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Increased rates of muscle protein turnover and amino acid transport after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1995;268(31):E514&#x2013;E520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Tipton KD, Klein S, Wolfe RR. An abundant supply of amino acids enhances the metabolic effect of exercise on muscle protein. Am J Physiol. 1997;273:E122&#x2013;E129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boh&#xe9; J, Low JF, Wolfe RR, Rennie MJ. Latency and duration of stimulation of human muscle protein synthesis during continuous infusion of amino acids. J Physiol. 2001;532:575&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11306673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsheim E, Tipton KD, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Essential amino acids and muscle protein recovery from resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2002;283:E648&#x2013;E657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12217881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caso G, Ford GC, Nair KS, Garlick PJ, McNurlan MA. Aminoacyl-tRNA enrichment after a flood of labeled phenylalanine: insulin effect on muscle protein synthesis. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2002;282:E1029&#x2013;E1038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11934667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson D, Smith K, Babraj J, Leese G, Waddell T, Atherton P, Wackerhage H, Taylor PM, Rennie MJ. Anabolic signaling deficits underlie amino acid resistance of wasting, aging muscle. FASEB J. 2005;19:422&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell PA, Fedele MJ, Hernandez J, Fluckey JD, Miller JL, III, Lang CH, Vary TC, Kimball SR, Jefferson LS. Hypertrophy of skeletal muscle in diabetic rats in response to chronic resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1999a;87:1075&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10484579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell PA, Fedele MJ, Vary TC, Kimball SR, Lang CH, Jefferson LS. Regulation of protein synthesis after acute resistance exercise in diabetic rats. Am J Physiol. 1999b;276:E721&#x2013;E727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell PA, Hernandez JM, Fedele MJ, Vary TC, Kimball SR, Jefferson LS. Eukaryotic initiation factors and protein synthesis after resistance exercise in rats. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:1036&#x2013;1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10710401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasten DL, Pak-Loduca J, Obert KA, Yarasheski KE. Resistance exercise acutely increases MHC and mixed muscle protein synthesis rates in 78&#x2013;84 and 23&#x2013;32 yr olds. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2000;278:E620&#x2013;E626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klitgaard H, Ausoni S, Damiani E. Sarcoplasmic reticulum of human skeletal muscle: age-related changes and effect of training. Acta Physiol Scand. 1989;137:23&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2529737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Jahn LA, Long W, Fryburg DA, Wei L, Barrett EJ. Branched chain amino acids activate messenger ribonucleic acid translation regulatory proteins in human skeletal muscle, and glucocorticoids blunt this action. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2001;86:2136&#x2013;2143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11344218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Jahn LA, Wei L, Long W, Barrett EJ. Amino acids stimulate translation initiation and protein synthesis through an Akt-independent pathway in human skeletal muscle. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2002;87:5553&#x2013;5558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12466352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Wu Y, Nicklas EW, Jahn LA, Price WJ, Barrett EJ. Unlike insulin, amino acids stimulate p70S6K but not GSK-3 or glycogen synthase in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2003;286:E523&#x2013;E528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14656717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis M, Poortmans JR, Francaux M, Berre J, Boisseau N, Brassine E, Cuthbertson DJ, Smith K, Babraj JA, Waddell T, Rennie MJ. No effect of creatine supplementation on human myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic protein synthesis after resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2003;285:E1089&#x2013;E1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12824083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Phillips SM, Babraj JA, Smith K, Rennie MJ. Myofibrillar and collagen protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle after maximal shortening and lengthening contractions. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288:E1153&#x2013;E1159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15572656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BW, Zhang XJ, Chen Y, Klein S, Wolfe RR. Measurement of very low stable isotope enrichments by gas chromatography/mass spectrometry: application to measurement of muscle protein synthesis. Metabolism. 1997;46:943&#x2013;948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9258279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson BW, Zhao G, Klein S. Improved accuracy and precision of gas chromatography/mass spectrometry measurements for metabolic tracers. Metabolism. 1998;47:706&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9627371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Parise G, Roy BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR, Tamopolsky MA. Resistance-training-induced adaptations in skeletal muscle protein turnover in the fed state. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2002;80:1045&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12489923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown following resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1997;273:E99&#x2013;E107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Wolfe RR. Resistance training reduces the acute exercise-induced increase in muscle protein turnover. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E118&#x2013;E124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H. Connecting the dots for mechanochemical transduction in muscle. J Physiol. 2003;553:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12963787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1992;20:S135&#x2013;S145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3057313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith K, Reynolds N, Downie S, Patel A, Rennie MJ. Effects of flooding amino acids on incorporation of labeled amino acids into human muscle protein. Am J Physiol. 1998;275:E73&#x2013;E78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart BG, Tarnopolsky MA, Hicks AL, McCartney N, Mahoney DJ, Staron RS, Phillips SM. Treadmill training-induced adaptations in muscle phenotype in persons with incomplete spinal cord injury. Muscle Nerve. 2003;30:61&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultan KR, Dittrich BT, Leisner E, Paul N, Pette D. Fiber type-specific expression of major proteolytic systems in fast- to slow-transforming rabbit muscle. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2001;280:C239&#x2013;C247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11208517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultan KR, Dittrich BT, Pette D. Calpain activity in fast, slow, transforming, and regenerating skeletal muscles of rat. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2000;279:C639&#x2013;C647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10942714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Phillips SM, Doyle DJ, Wolfe RR. Postexercise net protein synthesis in human muscle from orally administered amino acids. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E628&#x2013;E634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>