<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33927114</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Periodized Resistance Training With and Without Functional Training Improves Functional Capacity, Balance, and Strength in Parkinson's Disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1611</StartPage><EndPage>1619</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1611-1619</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004025</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Strand, KL, Cherup, NP, Totillo, MC, Castillo, DC, Gabor, NJ, and Signorile, JF. Periodized resistance training with and without functional training improves functional capacity, balance, and strength in Parkinson's disease. J Strength Cond Res 35(6): 1611-1619, 2021-Periodized progressive resistance training (PRT) is a common method used to improve strength in persons with Parkinson's disease (PD). Many researchers advocate the addition of functional training to optimize translation to activities of daily living; however, machine-based PRT, using both force and velocity training components, may elicit similar benefits. Thirty-five persons with PD (Hoehn and Yahr I-III) were randomized into a strength, power, and hypertrophy (SPH; n = 17) or strength, power, and functional (SP + Func; n = 18) group, training 3 times weekly for 12 weeks. Both groups performed machine-based strength and power training on days 1 and 2 each week, respectively; whereas, on day 3, SPH group performed machine-based hypertrophy training and SP + Func group performed functional training. Functional performance was tested using the timed up and go, 30-second sit-to-stand (30-s STS), gallon-jug shelf-transfer, and seated medicine ball throw (SMBT) tests. Balance (Mini-BESTest), strength, motor symptoms (UPDRS-III), quality of life, and freezing of gait (FOG) were also assessed. Repeated measures analysis of variance revealed a main effect for time (p &#x2264; 0.05) with significant improvements for the sample in the 30-s STS (p = 0.002), SMBT (p = 0.003), Mini-BESTest (p &lt; 0.001), upper-body strength (p = 0.002) and lower-body strength (p &lt; 0.001). A significant group &#xd7; time interaction was seen for FOG, with SP + Func alone showing improvement (p = 0.04). Furthermore, the SPH group produced a clinically important difference for the UPDRS-III (mean difference = 4.39, p = 0.18). We conclude that both exercise strategies can be equally effective at improving functional capacity, balance, and muscular strength in individuals with PD. In addition, FOG and motor symptoms may be targeted through SP + Func and SPH, respectively. The results provide options for individualized exercise prescriptions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strand</LastName><ForeName>Keri L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sports Sciences, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Research and Active Aging, University of Miami, Coral Gables, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cherup</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas P</ForeName><Initials>NP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sports Sciences, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Research and Active Aging, University of Miami, Coral Gables, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Totillo</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sports Sciences, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Research and Active Aging, University of Miami, Coral Gables, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo</LastName><ForeName>Diana C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sports Sciences, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Research and Active Aging, University of Miami, Coral Gables, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabor</LastName><ForeName>Noah J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sports Sciences, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Research and Active Aging, University of Miami, Coral Gables, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Signorile</LastName><ForeName>Joseph F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sports Sciences, Laboratory of Neuromuscular Research and Active Aging, University of Miami, Coral Gables, Florida; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Miller School of Medicine, Center on Aging, University of Miami, Miami, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT03867877</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000203" MajorTopicYN="N">Activities of Daily Living</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020233" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gait Disorders, Neurologic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33927114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202106000-00018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allen NE, Canning CG, Sherrington C, et al. The effects of an exercise program on fall risk factors in people with Parkinson's disease: A randomized controlled trial. Mov Disord 25: 1217&#x2013;1225, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balachandran AT, Gandia K, Jacobs KA, et al. Power training using pneumatic machines vs. plate-loaded machines to improve muscle power in older adults. Exp Gerontol 98: 134&#x2013;142, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzycki M. Strength testing&#x2014;Predicting a one-rep max from reps-to-fatigue. JOPERD 64: 88&#x2013;90, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behari M, Srivastava AK, Pandey RM. Quality of life in patients with Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 11: 221&#x2013;226, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bushnell DM, Martin ML. Quality of life and Parkinson's disease: Translation and validation of the US Parkinson's disease questionnaire (PDQ-39). Qual Life Res 8: 345&#x2013;350, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buskard A, Zalma B, Cherup N, et al. Effects of linear periodization versus daily undulating periodization on neuromuscular performance and activities of daily living in an elderly population. Exp Gerontol 113: 199&#x2013;208, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho A, Barbirato D, Araujo N, et al. Comparison of strength training, aerobic training, and additional physical therapy as supplementary treatments for Parkinson's disease: Pilot study. Clin Interv Aging 10: 183&#x2013;191, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherup NP, Buskard ANL, Strand KL, et al. Power vs strength training to improve muscular strength, power, balance and functional movement in individuals diagnosed with Parkinson's disease. Exp Gerontol 128: 110740, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences (2nd ed.). Hillsdale, NJ: L. Erlbaum Associates, 1988. pp. 368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcos DM, Robichaud JA, David FJ, et al. A two-year randomized controlled trial of progressive resistance exercise for Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord 28: 1230&#x2013;1240, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva-Grigolleto ME, Brito CJ, Heredia JR. Functional training: Functional for what and for whom?. Braz J Kinanthr Hum Perform 16: 714&#x2013;719, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibble LE, Hale TF, Marcus RL, Gerber JP, LaStayo PC. High intensity eccentric resistance training decreases bradykinesia and improves quality of life in persons with Parkinson's disease: A preliminary study. Parkinson Relat Disord 15: 752&#x2013;757, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giladi N, Hausdorff JM. The role of mental function in the pathogenesis of freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease. J Neurol Sci 248: 173&#x2013;176, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giladi N, Shabtai H, Simon ES, et al. Construction of freezing of gait questionnaire for patients with Parkinsonism. Parkinson Relat Disord 6: 165&#x2013;170, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glendinning DS, Enoka RM. Motor unit behavior in Parkinson's disease. Phys Ther 74: 61&#x2013;70, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagell P, Nilsson MH. The 39-item Parkinson's disease questionnaire (PDQ-39): Is it a unidimensional construct? Ther Adv Neurol Disord 2: 205&#x2013;214, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris C, Wattles AP, DeBeliso M, et al. The seated medicine ball throw as a test of upper body power in older adults. J Strength Cond Res 25: 2344&#x2013;2348, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hass CJ, Buckley TA, Pitsikoulis C, Barthelemy EJ. Progressive resistance training improves gait initiation in individuals with Parkinson's disease. Gait Posture 35: 669&#x2013;673, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazell T, Kenno K, Jakobi J. Functional benefit of power training for older adults. J Aging Phys Act 15: 349&#x2013;359, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch MA, Toole T, Maitland CG, Rider RA. The effects of balance training and high-intensity resistance training on persons with idiopathic Parkinson's disease. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 84: 1109&#x2013;1117, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horv&#xe1;th K, Aschermann Z, &#xc1;cs P, et al. Minimal clinically important difference on the motor examination part of MDS-UPDRS. Parkinson Relat Disord 21: 1421&#x2013;1426, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim A, Singh DKA, Shahar S. &#x201c;Timed up and go&#x201d; test: Age, gender and cognitive impairment stratified normative values of older adults. PLoS One 12: e018564, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Cadore EL. Muscle power training in the institutionalized frail: A new approach to counteracting functional declines and very late-life disability. Curr Med Res Opin 30: 1385&#x2013;1390, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankovic J. Parkinson's disease: Clinical features and diagnosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 79: 368&#x2013;376, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CJ, Rikli RE, Beam WC. A 30-s chair-stand test as a measure of lower body strength in community-residing older adults. Res Q Exerc Sport 70: 113&#x2013;119, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal LCP, Abrahin O, Rodrigues RP, et al. Low-volume resistance training improves functional capacity of older individuals with Parkinson's disease. Geriatr Gerontol Int 19: 635&#x2013;640, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy AL, Crowner BE, Earhart GM. Utility of the Mini-BESTest, BESTest, and BESTest sections for balance assessments in individuals with Parkinson disease. JNPT 35: 90&#x2013;97, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy EK, Horvat MA, Holtsberg PA, Wisenbaker JM. Repeated chair stands as a measure of lower limb strength in sexagenarian women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 59: 1207&#x2013;1212, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni M, Signorile JF, Mooney K, et al. Comparative effect of power training and high-speed yoga on motor function in older patients with Parkinson disease. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 97: 345&#x2013;354.e15, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nocera JR, Stegemoller EL, Malaty IA, et al. Using the Timed up &amp; Go test in a clinical setting to predict falling in Parkinson's disease. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 94: 1300&#x2013;1305, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nocera JR, Buckley T, Waddell D, Okun MS, Hass CJ. Knee extensor strength, dynamic stability, and functional ambulation: Are they related in Parkinson's disease? Arch Phys Med Rehabil 91: 589&#x2013;595, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul SS, Canning CG, Sherrington C, Fung VSC. Reduced muscle strength is the major determinant of reduced leg muscle power in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 18: 974&#x2013;977, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petzinger GM, Fisher BE, McEwen S, et al. Exercise-enhanced neuroplasticity targeting motor and cognitive circuitry in Parkinson's disease. Lancet Neurol 12: 716&#x2013;726, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsiadlo D, Richardson S. The timed up &amp; go: A test of basic functional mobility for frail elderly persons. J Am Geriatr Soc 39: 142&#x2013;148, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasitsiriphon O, Pothisiri W. Associations of grip strength and change in grip strength with all-cause and cardiovascular mortality in a European older population. Clin Med Insights Cardiol 12: 1179546818771894, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prodoehl J, Rafferty MR, David FJ, et al. Two-year exercise program improves physical function in Parkinson's disease: The PRET-PD randomized clinical trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair 29: 112&#x2013;122, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Castillo A, de la Fuente CI, et al. High-speed resistance training is more effective than low-speed resistance training to increase functional capacity and muscle performance in older women. Exp Gerontol 58: 51&#x2013;57, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothstein TL, Olanow CW. The neglected side of Parkinson's disease. Am Sci 96: 218&#x2013;226, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scandalis TA, Bosak A, Berliner JC, Helman LL, Wells MR. Resistance training and gait function in patients with Parkinson's disease. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 80: 38&#x2013;46, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shulman LM, Katzel LI, Ivey FM, et al. Randomized clinical trial of 3 types of physical exercise for patients with Parkinson disease. JAMA Neurol 70: 183&#x2013;190, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siderowf A, McDermott M, Kieburtz K, et al. Test&#x2013;retest reliability of the unified Parkinson's disease rating scale in patients with early Parkinson's disease: Results from a multicenter clinical trial. Mov Disord 17: 758&#x2013;763, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signorile JF, Sandler D, Ma F, et al. The gallon-jug shelf-transfer test: An instrument to evaluate deteriorating function in older adults. J Aging Phys Activ 15: 56&#x2013;74, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva NL, Oliveira RB, Fleck SJ, Leon AC, Farinatti P. Influence of strength training variables on strength gains in adults over 55 years-old: A meta-analysis of dose&#x2013;response relationships. J Sci Med Sport 17: 337&#x2013;344, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Batista C, Corcos DM, Roschel H, et al. Resistance training with instability for patients with Parkinson's disease. Med Sci Sports Exerc 48: 1678&#x2013;1687, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steffen T, Seney M. Test-retest reliability and minimal detectable change on balance and ambulation tests, the 36-item short-form health survey, and the unified Parkinson disease rating scale in people with Parkinsonism. Phys Ther 88: 733&#x2013;746, 2008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>