<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39439846</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2367-1890</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine international open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Int Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>One Year of Heavy Resistance Training Modifies Muscle Fiber Characteristics in the Elderly.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>a23388226</StartPage><MedlinePgn>a23388226</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">a23388226</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2338-8226</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Physical function declines with age, accelerating during the 6th decade of life, primarily due to loss in muscle mass and strength. The present study aimed to investigate the effect of one year of heavy resistance training in older adults (62-70 years) on muscle mass and strength. Further, we investigated muscle characteristics after the intervention by obtaining muscle biopsies from the vastus lateralis to compare muscle fiber characteristics between the heavy resistance training (HRT) (n=10) and the sedentary control group (CON) (n=10). We found that one year of resistance training increased isometric muscle strength (p&lt;0.0001, ES: 2.43 (Hedges' g)) and lean body mass (p&lt;0.05, ES: 0.96), whereas cross-sectional area of the vastus lateralis and lean leg mass were unaltered. At year 1, the percentage of type IIX muscle fibers was lower in HRT compared to CON (p&lt;0.05, ES: 0.99), whereas the muscle fiber size did not differ between groups for the major fiber types (I and II). In conclusion, one year of resistance training in elderly improved muscle strength and lean body mass but not cross-sectional area and lean leg mass. This indicates that the increase in muscle strength may be caused by neuromuscular adaptations rather than morphological muscle tissue changes per se.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). This is an open access article published by Thieme under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonDerivative-NonCommercial-License, permitting copying and reproduction so long as the original work is given appropriate credit. Contents may not be used for commercial purposes, or adapted, remixed, transformed or built upon. (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gates</LastName><ForeName>Anne Theil</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg and Frederiksberg Hospital, Bispebjerg Hospital Institute of Sports Medicine Copenhagen, 2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, University of Copenhagen Center for Healthy Aging, 2200 Copenhagen NV, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kjaer</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg and Frederiksberg Hospital, Bispebjerg Hospital Institute of Sports Medicine Copenhagen, 2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Copenhagen, University of Copenhagen Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, 2200 Copenhagen NV, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Andersen</LastName><ForeName>Jesper Loevind</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Copenhagen University Hospital, Bispebjerg and Frederiksberg Hospital, Bispebjerg Hospital Institute of Sports Medicine Copenhagen, 2400 Copenhagen NV, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Int Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101721695</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2367-1890</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39439846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11495243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2338-8226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">a23388226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft A J, Bahat G, Bauer J et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48:16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindle R S, Metter E J, Lynch N A et al. Age and gender comparisons of muscle strength in 654 women and men aged 20&#x2013;93 yr. J Appl Physiol. 1997;83:1581&#x2013;1587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9375323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skelton D A, Greig C A, Davies J M et al. Strength, power and related functional ability of healthy people aged 65&#x2013;89 years. Age Ageing. 1994;23:371&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7825481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Heymsfield S B, Wang Z et al. Skeletal muscle mass and distribution in 468 men and women aged 18&#x2013;88 yr. J Appl Physiol. 2000;89:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10904038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetta C, Haddock B, Alcazar J et al. The Copenhagen Sarcopenia Study: lean mass, strength, power, and physical function in a Danish cohort aged 20&#x2013;93 years. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2019;10:1316&#x2013;1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6903448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31419087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohl H W, Craig C L, Lambert E V et al. The pandemic of physical inactivity: global action for public health. Lancet. 2012;380:294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee I-M, Shiroma E J, Lobelo F et al. Effect of physical inactivity on major non-communicable diseases worldwide: an analysis of burden of disease and life expectancy. Lancet. 2012;380:219&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3645500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilwik R, Snijders T, Leenders M et al. The decline in skeletal muscle mass with aging is mainly attributed to a reduction in type II muscle fiber size. Exp Gerontol. 2013;48:492&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23425621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew D L, Kim J S, Cross J M et al. Translational signaling responses preceding resistance training-mediated myofiber hypertrophy in young and old humans. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:1655&#x2013;1662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel C S, Cross J C, Bamman M M. Exercise dosing to retain resistance training adaptations in young and older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1177&#x2013;1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unhjem R, Lundestad R, Fimland M S et al. Strength training-induced responses in older adults: attenuation of descending neural drive with age. Age (Omaha) 2015;37:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4418975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25940749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Suetta C, Caserotti P et al. Role of the nervous system in sarcopenia and muscle atrophy with aging: Strength training as a countermeasure. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20487503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell M J, McComas A J, Petito F. Physiological changes in ageing muscles. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1973;36:174&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1083551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4708452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moro T, Brightwell C R, Volpi E et al. Resistance exercise training promotes fiber type-specific myonuclear adaptations in older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2020;128:795&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7191507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32134710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertz K H, Reitelseder S, Bechshoeft R et al. The effect of daily protein supplementation, with or without resistance training for 1 year, on muscle size, strength, and function in healthy older adults: A randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2021;00:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33564844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leenders M, Verdijk L B, van der Hoeven L et al. Elderly men and women benefit equally from prolonged resistance-type exercise training. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2013;68:769&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23223011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gylling A T, Eriksen C S, Garde E et al. The influence of prolonged strength training upon muscle and fat in healthy and chronically diseased older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2020;136:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32277977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechsh&#xf8;ft R L, Malmgaard-Clausen N M, Gliese B et al. Improved skeletal muscle mass and strength after heavy strength training in very old individuals. Exp Gerontol. 2017;92:96&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne T A, Tieland M, Verdijk L B et al. There are no nonresponders to resistance-type exercise training in older men and women. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2015;16:400&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25717010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kryger A I, Andersen J L. Resistance training in the oldest old: consequences for muscle strength, fiber types, fiber size, and MHC isoforms. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2007;17:422&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17490465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek D J, Kim J S, Petrella J K et al. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:531&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang E, Nyberg S K, Hoff J et al. Impact of maximal strength training on work efficiency and muscle fiber type in the elderly: Implications for physical function and fall prevention. Exp Gerontol. 2017;91:64&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28232199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen J L, Aagaard P. Myosin heavy chain IIX overshoot in human skeletal muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2000;23:1095&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10883005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron R S, Karapondo D L, Kraemer W J et al. Skeletal muscle adaptations during early phase of heavy-resistance training in men and women. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76:1247&#x2013;1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8005869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen J L, Aagaard P. Effects of strength training on muscle fiber types and size; consequences for athletes training for high-intensity sport. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:32&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20840560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen C S, Garde E, Reislev N L et al. Physical activity as intervention for age-related loss of muscle mass and function: Protocol for a randomised controlled trial (the LISA study) BMJ Open. 2016;6:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5168596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27913559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstrom J. Percutaneous needle biopsy of skeletal muscle in physiological and clinical research. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1975;35:609&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1108172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke M H, Kaiser K K. Muscle fiber types: How many and what kind? Arch Neurol. 1970;23:369&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4248905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke M H, Kaiser K K. Three &#x201c;myosin adenosine triphosphatase&#x201d; systems: the nature of their pH lability and sulfhydryl dependence. J Histochem Cytochem. 1970;18:670&#x2013;672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4249441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Z, Andersen J L, Zhou S. Visualisation of capillaries in human skeletal muscle. Histochem Cell Biol. 1997;107:169&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9062802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heisterberg M F, Andersen J L, Schjerling P et al. Losartan has no additive effect on the response to heavy-resistance exercise in human elderly skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2018;125:1536&#x2013;1554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30091666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea M R. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18:918&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakov&#xe1; D, Holwerda A M, Betz M W et al. Muscle fiber type grouping does not change in response to prolonged resistance exercise training in healthy older men. Exp Gerontol. 2023;173:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36621699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegler A K, Jensen S M, Schjerling P et al. The effect of resistance exercise upon age-related systemic and local skeletal muscle inflammation. Exp Gerontol. 2019;121:19&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30905721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Taylor C C. Variability in muscle fibre areas in whole human quadriceps muscle: effects of increasing age. J Anat. 1991;174:239&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1256058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2032938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey A L, Esmarck B, Kadi F et al. Enhanced satellite cell proliferation with resistance training in elderly men and women. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2007;17:34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17305939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk L B, Gleeson B G, Jonkers RA M et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance training is accompanied by a fiber type-specific increase in satellite cell content in elderly men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2009;64A:332&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen L L, Andersen J L, Magnusson S P et al. Changes in the human muscle force-velocity relationship in response to resistance training and subsequent detraining. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99:87&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15731398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm L, Reitelseder S, Pedersen T G et al. Changes in muscle size and MHC composition in response to resistance exercise with heavy and light loading intensity. J Appl Physiol. 2008;105:1454&#x2013;1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18787090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk L B, Snijders T, Holloway T M et al. Resistance training increases skeletal muscle capillarization in healthy older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:2157&#x2013;2164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27327032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen E B, Andersen J L et al. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93:1318&#x2013;1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>