<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32067343</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1467-789X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obesity reviews : an official journal of the International Association for the Study of Obesity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obes Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beyond general resistance training. Hypertrophy versus muscular endurance training as therapeutic interventions in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13007</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13007</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/obr.13007</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Resistance training (RT) is a powerful first-line intervention for the management of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Nonetheless, the effects of the most frequent RT (hypertrophy training [HT] and muscular endurance training [MERT]) employed for the management of T2DM, and which type of RT might exert superior effects, remain elusive. Thus, this review aims to assess the effects of HT and MERT on glycaemic control, physical fitness, body composition, lipid profile, blood pressure, C-reactive protein, and quality of life in patients with T2DM; to analyse which particular RT is more effective; to assess the effects of general RT; and to identify RT components, characteristics of patients, and medications that could mediate the effects of RT. Randomized controlled trials (RCT) and non-RCT (RT&#x2265; 4 weeks) in adults with T2DM were selected. Both HT and MERT improved HbA1c, insulin levels and sensitivity, muscle strength, body mass index, waist circumference, and fat mass. Additionally, HT improved glucose, cardiorespiratory fitness, fat percentage, lean body mass, lipid profile, systolic blood pressure, and C-reactive protein, and MERT improved weight. Overall, HT and MERT exert beneficial effects well comparable with aerobic training. Both types of RT can be used as potent therapeutic interventions for the management of T2DM depending on patients' limitations/preferences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 World Obesity Federation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Acosta-Manzano</LastName><ForeName>Pedro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4494-2353</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PA-HELP "Physical Activity for Health Promotion, CTS-1018" Research Group, Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sports Science, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Health University Research Institute (IMUDS), University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodriguez-Ayllon</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Health University Research Institute (IMUDS), University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PROFITH "PROmoting FITness and Health Through Physical Activity" Research Group, Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sports Science, University of Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Acosta</LastName><ForeName>Francisco M</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4792-0969</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Health University Research Institute (IMUDS), University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PROFITH "PROmoting FITness and Health Through Physical Activity" Research Group, Department of Physical Education and Sports, Faculty of Sports Science, University of Granada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niederseer</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Heart Center Zurich, University Hospital Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niebauer</LastName><ForeName>Josef</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Institute of Sports Medicine, Prevention and Rehabilitation and Research Institute of Molecular Sports Medicine and Rehabilitation, Paracelsus Medical University, Salzburg, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Obes Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100897395</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1467-7881</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glycaemic control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32067343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Ley SH, Hu FB. Global aetiology and epidemiology of type 2 diabetes mellitus and its complications. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2018;14(2):88-98. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrendo.2017.151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lifestyle management: standards of medical care in Diabetes-2019. Diabetes Care. 2019;42(Supplement 1):S46-s60. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc19-S005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiuza-Luces C, Garatachea N, Berger NA, Lucia A. Exercise is the real polypill. Phys Ther. 2013;28(5):330-358. https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.00019.2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sixt S, Rastan A, Desch S, et al. Exercise training but not rosiglitazone improves endothelial function in prediabetic patients with coronary disease. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2008;15(4):473-478. https://doi.org/10.1097/HJR.0b013e3283002733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines, E. C. f. S., Corr&#xe0;, U., Piepoli, M. F. Carr&#xe9;, F., Heuschmann, P., Hoffmann, U., Verschuren, M., Halcox, J., Document Reviewers, Giannuzzi, P. and Saner, H. Secondary prevention through cardiac rehabilitation: physical activity counselling and exercise training: key components of the position paper from the cardiac rehabilitation section of the European Association of Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation. Eur Heart J 31, 1967-1974, doi:https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehq236 (2010), 16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhees L, Geladas N, Hansen D, et al. Importance of characteristics and modalities of physical activity and exercise in the management of cardiovascular health in individuals with cardiovascular risk factors: recommendations from the EACPR. Part II. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2012;19(5):1005-1033. https://doi.org/10.1177/1741826711430926</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher GF, Landolfo C, Niebauer J, Ozemek C, Arena R, Lavie CJ. Promoting physical activity and exercise: JACC Health Promotion Series. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72(14):1622-1639. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2018.08.2141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowler WC, Barrett-Connor E, Fowler SE, et al. Reduction in the incidence of type 2 diabetes with lifestyle intervention or metformin. N Engl J Med. 2002;346(6):393-403. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa012512</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan B, Zierath JR. Exercise metabolism and the molecular regulation of skeletal muscle adaptation. Cell Metab. 2013;17(2):162-184. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2012.12.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo LC, Dativo-Medeiros J, Menezes-Silva CE, Barbosa FT. Physical exercise on inflammatory markers in type 2 diabetes patients: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2017;2017:8523728-10. https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/8523728</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiguro H, Kodama S, Horikawa C, et al. In search of the ideal resistance training program to improve glycemic control and its indication for patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(1):67-77. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-015-0379-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGinley SK, Armstrong MJ, Boule NG, Sigal RJ. Effects of exercise training using resistance bands on glycaemic control and strength in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Acta Diabetol. 2015;52(2):221-230. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00592-014-0594-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Scott CA, Mao C, Tang J, Farmer AJ. Resistance exercise versus aerobic exercise for type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2014;44(4):487-499. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-013-0128-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Missbach B, Dias S, Konig J, Hoffmann G. Impact of different training modalities on glycaemic control and blood lipids in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Diabetologia. 2014;57(9):1789-1797. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-014-3303-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueira FR, Umpierre D, Cureau FV, et al. Association between physical activity advice only or structured exercise training with blood pressure levels in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2014;44(11):1557-1572. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-014-0226-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heijden MM, van Dooren FE, Pop VJ, Pouwer F. Effects of exercise training on quality of life, symptoms of depression, symptoms of anxiety and emotional well-being in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Diabetologia. 2013;56(6):1210-1225. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-013-2871-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umpierre D, Ribeiro PA, Schaan BD, Ribeiro JP. Volume of supervised exercise training impacts glycaemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review with meta-regression analysis. Diabetologia. 2013;56(2):242-251. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-012-2774-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukala WR, Page R, Cheema BS. Exercise training in high-risk ethnic populations with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review of clinical trials. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2012;97(2):206-216. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2012.02.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashino Y, Jackson JL, Fukumori N, Nakamura F, Fukuhara S. Effects of supervised exercise on lipid profiles and blood pressure control in people with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2012;98(3):349-360. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2012.10.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umpierre D, Ribeiro PA, Kramer CK, et al. Physical activity advice only or structured exercise training and association with HbA1c levels in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA. 2011;305(17):1790-1799. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2011.576</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chudyk A, Petrella RJ. Effects of exercise on cardiovascular risk factors in type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Care. 2011;34(5):1228-1237. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc10-1881</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irvine C, Taylor NF. Progressive resistance exercise improves glycaemic control in people with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Aust J Physiother. 2009;55(4):237-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snowling NJ, Hopkins WG. Effects of different modes of exercise training on glucose control and risk factors for complications in type 2 diabetic patients: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Care. 2006;29(11):2518-2527. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc06-1317</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boule NG, Kenny GP, Haddad E, Wells GA, Sigal RJ. Meta-analysis of the effect of structured exercise training on cardiorespiratory fitness in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetologia. 2003;46(8):1071-1081. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-003-1160-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boule NG, Haddad E, Kenny GP, Wells GA, Sigal RJ. Effects of exercise on glycemic control and body mass in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a meta-analysis of controlled clinical trials. JAMA. 2001;286(10):1218-1227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codella R, Ialacqua M, Terruzzi I, Luzi L. May the force be with you: why resistance training is essential for subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus without complications. Endocrine. 2018;62(1):14-25. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12020-018-1603-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanuso S, Sacchetti M, Sundberg CJ, Orlando G, Benvenuti P, Balducci S. Exercise in type 2 diabetes: genetic, metabolic and neuromuscular adaptations. A review of the evidence. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1533. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-096724</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Pesta D. Resistance training for diabetes prevention and therapy: experimental findings and molecular mechanisms. Biomed Res Int. 2013;2013:805217. https://doi.org/10.1155/2013/805217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tresierras MA, Balady GJ. Resistance training in the treatment of diabetes and obesity: mechanisms and outcomes. J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2009;29:67-75. https://doi.org/10.1097/HCR.0b013e318199ff69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuk JL, Kilpatrick K, Davidson LE, Hudson R, Ross R. Whole-body skeletal muscle mass is not related to glucose tolerance or insulin sensitivity in overweight and obese men and women. App phy, nutr, and me = Physiologie appliquee, nutrition et metabolisme. 2008;33:769-774. https://doi.org/10.1139/H08-060</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaspelkis BB 3rd, Singh MK, Trevino B, Krisan AD, Collins DE. Resistance training increases glucose uptake and transport in rat skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol Scand. 2002;175(4):315-323. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-201X.2002.00998.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen E, Landstad BJ, Gundersen KT, Torjesen PA, Svebak S. Insulin sensitivity after maximal and endurance resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(2):327-334. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0b013e318220e70f</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colberg SR, Sigal RJ, Fernhall B, et al. Exercise and type 2 diabetes: the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Diabetes Association: joint position statement. Diabetes Care. 2010;33(12):e147-e167. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc10-9990</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687-708. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamseer L, Moher D, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: elaboration and explanation. Br Med J. 2015;349(jan02 1). https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.g7647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger A, Niederseer D, Diem G, et al. Different types of resistance training in type 2 diabetes mellitus: effects on glycaemic control, muscle mass and strength. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2013;20(6):1051-1060. https://doi.org/10.1177/2047487312450132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687-708. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1334-1359. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213fefb</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boule NG, Kenny GP, Larose J, Khandwala F, Kuzik N, Sigal RJ. Does metformin modify the effect on glycaemic control of aerobic exercise, resistance exercise or both? Diabetologia. 2013;56(11):2378-2382. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-013-3026-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks N, Layne JE, Gordon PL, Roubenoff R, Nelson ME, Castaneda-Sceppa C. Strength training improves muscle quality and insulin sensitivity in Hispanic older adults with type 2 diabetes. Int J Med Sci. 2006;4(1):19-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda C, Layne JE, Munoz-Orians L, et al. A randomized controlled trial of resistance exercise training to improve glycemic control in older adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25(12):2335-2341. https://doi.org/10.2337/diacare.25.12.2335</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cauza E, Hanusch-Enserer U, Strasser B, et al. The relative benefits of endurance and strength training on the metabolic factors and muscle function of people with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2005;86(8):1527-1533. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2005.01.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church TS, Blair SN, Cocreham S, et al. Effects of aerobic and resistance training on hemoglobin A(1c) levels in patients with type 2 diabetes. A Randomized Controlled Trial Jama. 2010;304(20):2253-2262. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2010.1710</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira VN, Bessa A, Mendonca Pereira Jorge ML, et al. The effect of different training programs on antioxidant status, oxidative stress, and metabolic control in type 2 diabetes. App phy, nutr, and me = Physiologie appliquee, nutrition et metabolisme. 2012;37(2):334-344. https://doi.org/10.1139/h2012-004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Puddey IB, Beilin LJ, Burke V, Morton AR, Stanton KG. Effects of a short-term circuit weight training program on glycaemic control in NIDDM. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 1998;40(1):53-61. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0168-8227(98)00027-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavin C, Sigal RJ, Cousins M, et al. Resistance exercise but not aerobic exercise lowers remnant-like lipoprotein particle cholesterol in type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Atherosclerosis. 2010;213(2):552-557. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2010.08.071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorge M, de Oliveira VN, Resende NM, et al. The effects of aerobic, resistance, and combined exercise on metabolic control, inflammatory markers, adipocytokines, and muscle insulin signaling in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Metab Clin Exp. 2011;60(9):1244-1252. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.metabol.2011.01.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku YH, Han KA, Ahn H, et al. Resistance exercise did not alter intramuscular adipose tissue but reduced retinol-binding protein-4 concentration in individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Int Med Res. 2010;38(3):782-791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HR, Han KA, Ku YH, et al. The effects of resistance training on muscle and body fat mass and muscle strength in type 2 diabetic women. Korean Diabetes J. 2010;34(2):101-110. https://doi.org/10.4093/kdj.2010.34.2.101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HR, Min KW, Ahn HJ, et al. Effects of aerobic exercise vs. resistance training on endothelial function in women with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Metab J. 2011;35(4):364-373. https://doi.org/10.4093/dmj.2011.35.4.364</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larose J, Sigal RJ, Khandwala F, et al. Associations between physical fitness and HbA(1c) in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetologia. 2011;54(1):93-102. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-010-1941-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln AK, Shepherd A, Johnson PL, Castaneda-Sceppa C. The impact of resistance exercise training on the mental health of older Puerto Rican adults with type 2 diabetes. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2011;66:567-570. https://doi.org/10.1093/geronb/gbr034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers VH, McVay MA, Brashear MM, et al. Exercise training and quality of life in individuals with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Care. 2013;36(7):1884-1890. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc12-1153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng CLW, Goh S-Y, Malhotra R, Ostbye T, Tai ES. Minimal difference between aerobic and progressive resistance exercise on metabolic profile and fitness in older adults with diabetes mellitus: a randomised trial. J Physiother. 2010;56(3):163-170. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1836-9553(10)70021-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid RD, Tulloch HE, Sigal RJ, et al. Effects of aerobic exercise, resistance exercise or both, on patient-reported health status and well-being in type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomised trial. Diabetologia. 2010;53(4):632-640. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-009-1631-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, Boule NG, et al. Effects of aerobic training, resistance training, or both on glycemic control in type 2 diabetes-a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147(6):357-369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparks LM, Johannsen NM, Church TS, et al. Nine months of combined training improves ex vivo skeletal muscle metabolism in individuals with type 2 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;98(4):1694-1702. https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2012-3874</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, Johannsen NM, Earnest CP, Blair SN, Church TS. Effect of exercise training modality on C-reactive protein in type 2 diabetes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(6):1028-1034. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824526cc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cauza E, Hanusch-Enserer U, Strasser B, Kostner K, Dunky A, Haber P. Strength and endurance training lead to different post exercise glucose profiles in diabetic participants using a continuous subcutaneous glucose monitoring system. Eur J Clin Invest. 2005;35(12):745-751. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2362.2005.01573.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Johannsen NM, Swift DL, et al. Aerobic and strength training in concomitant metabolic syndrome and type 2 diabetes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(7):1293-1301. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000000242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen ND, Dunstan DW, Robinson C, Vulikh E, Zimmet PZ, Shaw JE. Improved endothelial function following a 14-month resistance exercise training program in adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2008;79(3):405-411. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2007.09.020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Vulikh E, Owen N, Jolley D, Shaw J, Zimmet P. Community center-based resistance training for the maintenance of glycemic control in adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2006;29(12):2586-2591. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc06-1310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavros Y, Kay S, Anderberg KA, et al. Changes in insulin resistance and HbA(1c) are related to exercise-mediated changes in body composition in older adults with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2013;36(8):2372-2379. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc12-2196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavros Y, Kay S, Simpson KA, et al. Reductions in C-reactive protein in older adults with type 2 diabetes are related to improvements in body composition following a randomized controlled trial of resistance training. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2014;5(2):111-120. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13539-014-0134-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda F, Layne JE, Castaneda C. Skeletal muscle sodium glucose co-transporters in older adults with type 2 diabetes undergoing resistance training. Int J Med Sci. 2006;3(3):84-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon PL, Vannier E, Hamada K, et al. Resistance training alters cytokine gene expression in skeletal muscle of adults with type 2 diabetes. Int J Immunopathol Pharmacol. 2006;19(4):739-749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings AE, Alberga A, Sigal RJ, Jay O, BoulE N, Kenny G. The effect of exercise training on resting metabolic rate in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(8):1558-1565. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e31819d6a6f</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannsen NM, Swift DL, Lavie CJ, Earnest CP, Blair SN, Church TS. Categorical analysis of the impact of aerobic and resistance exercise training, alone and in combination, on cardiorespiratory fitness levels in patients with type 2 diabetes results from the HART-D study. Diabetes Care. 2013;36(10):3305-3312. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc12-2194</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stegen S, Sigal RJ, Kenny GP, et al. Aerobic and resistance training do not influence plasma carnosinase content or activity in type 2 diabetes. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2015;309(7):E663-E669. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpendo.00142.2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao G, Lopez-Jimenez F, Boyd J, et al. Methodological standards for meta-analyses and qualitative systematic reviews of cardiac prevention and treatment studies: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2017;136(10):e172-e194. https://doi.org/10.1161/cir.0000000000000523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343(oct18 2):d5928. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.d5928</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Deeks JJ (editors). Chapter 7: selecting studies and collecting data. In: Higgins JPT, Green S (editors), Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from www.handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. A basic introduction to fixed-effect and random-effects models for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010;1:97-111. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrsm.12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Higgins JPT. Meta-analysis and subgroups. Prev Sci. 2013;14(2):134-143. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11121-013-0377-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batson S, Burton H. A systematic review of methods for handling missing variance data in meta-analyses of interventions in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Plos One. 2016;11:10. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0164827</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiebe N, Vandermeer B, Platt RW, Klassen TP, Moher D, Barrowman NJ. A systematic review identifies a lack of standardization in methods for handling missing variance data. J Clin Epidemiol. 2006;59(4):342-353. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2005.08.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follmann D, Elliott P, Suh I, Cutler J. Variance imputation for overviews of clinical trials with continuous response. J Clin Epidemiol. 1992;45:769-773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Sutton AJ, Ioannidis JPA, et al. Recommendations for examining and interpreting funnel plot asymmetry in meta-analyses of randomised controlled trials. Br Med J. 2011;343(jul22 1):8. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.d4002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Egger M, Smith GD. Systematic reviews in health care-investigating and dealing with publication and other biases in meta-analysis. Br Med J. 2001;323(7304):101-105. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.323.7304.101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker WL, White CM, Cappelleri JC, Kluger J, Coleman CI, Health Outcomes, Policy, and Economics (HOPE) Collaborative Group. Understanding heterogeneity in meta-analysis: the role of meta-regression. Int J Clin Pract. 2009;63(10):1426-1434. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1742-1241.2009.02168.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shreef FM, Al-Jiffri OH, Abd El-Kader SM. Bone metabolism and hand grip strength response to aerobic versus resistance exercise training in non-insulin dependent diabetic patients. Afr Health Sci. 2015;15(3):896-901. https://doi.org/10.4314/ahs.v15i3.25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldi JC, Snowling N. Resistance training improves glycaemic control in obese type 2 diabetic men. Int J Sports Med. 2003;24(6):419-423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moe B, Augestad LB, Asvold BO, Flanders WD. Effects of aerobic versus resistance training on glycaemic control in men with type 2 diabetes. Eur J Sports Exerc Sci. 2011;11:365-374. https://doi.org/10.1080/17461391.2010.523851</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuing Farias T, Santos-Lozano A, Solis Urra P, Cristi-Montero C. Effects of training and detraining on glycosylated haemoglobin, glycaemia, and lipid profile in type-II diabetics. Nutr Hosp. 2015;32(4):1729-1734. https://doi.org/10.3305/nh.2015.32.4.9341</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keihanian A, Arazi H, Kargarfard M. Effects of aerobic versus resistance training on serum fetuin-A, fetuin-B, and fibroblast growth factor-21 levels in male diabetic patients. Physiology Int. 2019;106(1):70-80. https://doi.org/10.1556/2060.106.2019.01</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S, Woo JH, Shin KO, et al. Circuit resistance exercise improves glycemic control and adipokines in females with type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Sports Sci Med. 2009;8:682-688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora E, Shenoy S, Sandhu JS. Effects of resistance training on metabolic profile of adults with type 2 diabetes. Indian J Med Res. 2009;129(5):515-519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi E, Negri C, Zanolin ME, et al. Metabolic effects of aerobic training and resistance training in type 2 diabetic subjects. A randomized controlled trial (the RAED2 study). Diabetes Care. 2012;35(4):676-682. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc11-1655</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum K, Votteler T, Schiab J. Efficiency of vibration exercise for glycemic control in type 2 diabetes patients. Int J Med Sci. 2007;4(3):159-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou NP, Fotiadis G, Athanasiadou Z, Vitta I, Lampropoulos S, Vrabas IS. The effects of resistance training on ApoB/ApoA-I ratio, Lp(a) and inflammatory markers in patients with type 2 diabetes. Endocrine. 2012;42(3):561-569. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12020-012-9650-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadoglou NP, Fotiadis G, Kapelouzou A, Kostakis A, Liapis CD, Vrabas IS. The differential anti-inflammatory effects of exercise modalities and their association with early carotid atherosclerosis progression in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabet Med: A J of the British Diabet Assoc. 2013;30(2):e41-e50. https://doi.org/10.1111/dme.12055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotnikoff RC, Eves N, Jung M, Sigal RJ, Padwal R, Karunamuni N. Multicomponent, home-based resistance training for obese adults with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes (Lond). 2010;34(12):1733-1741. https://doi.org/10.1038/ijo.2010.109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukala WR, Page R, Lonsdale C, et al. Exercise improves quality of life in indigenous Polynesian peoples with type 2 diabetes and visceral obesity. J Phys Act Health. 2013;10(5):699-707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukala WR, Page R, Rowlands DS, et al. South Pacific Islanders resist type 2 diabetes: comparison of aerobic and resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(1):317-325. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00421-011-1978-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavari A, Najafipoor F, Aliasgarzadeh A, Niafar M, Mobasseri M. Effect of aerobic exercise, resistance training or combined training on glycaemic control and cardiovascular risk factors in patients with type 2 diabetes. Biol Sport. 2012;29:135-143. https://doi.org/10.5604/20831862.990466</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh P-L, Tseng C-H, Tseng YJ, Yang W-S. Resistance training improves muscle function and cardiometabolic risks but not quality of life in older people with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized controlled trial. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2018;41(2):65-76. https://doi.org/10.1519/jpt.0000000000000107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celes R, Bottaro M, Cadore E, Dullius J, Schwartz F, Luzine F. Low-load high-velocity resistance exercises improve strength and functional capacity in diabetic patients. Eur J Transl Myol. 2017;27(2):121-129. https://doi.org/10.4081/ejtm.2017.6292</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung NW, Cinnadaio N, Russo M, Marek S. A pilot randomised controlled trial of resistance exercise bands in the management of sedentary subjects with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2009;83(3):e68-e71. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diabres.2008.12.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cindy Li Whye N, Tai ES, Goh S-Y, Wee H-L. Health status of older adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus after aerobic or resistance training: a randomised trial. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2011;9. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477-7525-9-59</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de lade CG, Bouzas Marins JC, Lima LM, et al. Effects of different exercise programs and minimal detectable changes in hemoglobin A1c in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2016;8(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s13098-016-0123-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed UA, Manzar D, Raza S, Shareef MY, Hussain ME. Resistance training leads to clinically meaningful improvements in control of glycemia and muscular strength in untrained middle-aged patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. N Am J Med Sci. 2012;4:336-343. https://doi.org/10.4103/1947-2714.99507</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos GM, Montrezol FT, Pauli LS, et al. Undulatory physical resistance training program increases maximal strength in elderly type 2 diabetics. Einstein. 2014;12(4):425-432. https://doi.org/10.1590/s1679-45082014ao3162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botton CE, Umpierre D, Rech A, et al. Effects of resistance training on neuromuscular parameters in elderly with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a randomized clinical trial. Exp Gerontol. 2018;113:141-149. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exger.2018.10.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: standards of medical care in Diabetes-2019. Diabetes Care. 2019;42:S13-S28. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc19-S002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Kim D, Kim C. Resistance training for glycemic control, muscular strength, and lean body mass in old type 2 diabetic patients: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Therapy: Research, Treatment and Education of Diabetes and Related Disorders. 2017;8(3):459-473. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13300-017-0258-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Impact of progressive resistance training on lipids and lipoproteins in adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Prev Med. 2009;48:9-19. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2008.10.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens NA, Sparks LM. Resistance to the beneficial effects of exercise in type 2 diabetes: are some individuals programmed to fail? J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2015;100(1):43-52. https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2014-2545</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Deeks JJ, Douglas GA. Chapter 16: special topics in statistics. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from www.handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S (editors). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 [updated March 2011]. The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from www.handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein, M., Hedges, L. V., Higgins, J. P. and Rothstein, H. R. . (2009).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>