<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37685476</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2227-9032</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Healthcare (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Healthcare (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effects of Combining Aerobic and Heavy Resistance Training on Body Composition, Muscle Hypertrophy, and Exercise Satisfaction in Physically Active Adults.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2443</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/healthcare11172443</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigated the effects of combined aerobic and heavy resistance training on the variables of body composition, muscle hypertrophy, and exercise satisfaction in physically active adults in comparison with heavy resistance training only (predominantly designed for hypertrophy). Twenty-two healthy male adults between the ages of 18 and 35, who had limited previous experience with muscle resistance training, participated in the intervention program while maintaining their physical activity level. The participants were randomly allocated into two groups: the resistance training group (control group) and the combined training group (experimental group), which involved both resistance training and aerobic training. Aerobic training consisted of 30 min aerobic interval training sessions three times a week with a total of 8 min work bouts in each at 60-70% of heart rate reserve (HRR). The intervention training program lasted for eight weeks. Resistance training consisted of a 3-day muscle group split (2-3 exercises per muscle group, 8 sets per muscle group, 6-12 repetition maximum (RM). Upon completion, body composition, muscle hypertrophy, and exercise satisfaction were analyzed using the mixed-design ANOVA. Variables selected for this study as markers of body composition responded differently to the different interventions and time; however, some trends were not statistically significant. Overall, it is not possible to state unequivocally that one training modality was superior to another in the body composition cluster, for significant improvements were observed within the groups from pre- to post-interventions, but no significant differences were observed between the resistance training and combined training groups, while, both interventions showed improvement with time in some variables of muscle hypertrophy. Compared to baseline, the exercise satisfaction post-intervention improved within the groups. From pre- to post-testing, both resistance and combined training groups improved exercise satisfaction (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05 in both groups). However, there was no significant difference in exercise satisfaction observed between the resistance training and combined training groups after the training intervention (<i>p</i> &gt; 0.05).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Jerrican</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fitness Innovations Malaysia Sendirian Berhad, Petaling Jaya 47820, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian 16150, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krasilshchikov</LastName><ForeName>Oleksandr</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7575-1026</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports Science and Recreation, Universiti Teknologi MARA, Shah Alam 40450, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuan</LastName><ForeName>Garry</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1103-3871</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian 16150, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hashim</LastName><ForeName>Hairul Anuar</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9137-0415</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian 16150, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aldhahi</LastName><ForeName>Monira I</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5255-4860</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, College of Health and Rehabilitation Sciences, Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University, P.O. Box 84428, Riyadh 11671, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Mhanna</LastName><ForeName>Sameer Badri</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9063-0185</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kubang Kerian 16150, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badicu</LastName><ForeName>Georgian</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4100-8765</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Special Motricity, Faculty of Physical Education and Mountain Sports, Transilvania University of Bra&#x15f;ov, 500068 Bra&#x15f;ov, Romania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PNURSP2023R 286</GrantID><Agency>Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Healthcare (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101666525</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2227-9032</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heavy resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physically active adults</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37685476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10487730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11172443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">healthcare11172443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Martel G.F., Roth S.M., Ivey F.M., Lemmer J.T., Tracy B.L., Hurlbut D.E., Hopkins W.G., Fyfe J.J., Phillips S.M., Bishop D.J., et al. Age and sex affect human muscle fibre adaptations to heavy-resistance strength training. Exp. Physiol. 2006;91:457&#x2013;464. doi: 10.1113/expphysiol.2005.032771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/expphysiol.2005.032771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16407471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia M., Stubbs R., Henry C. Differences in fat, carbohydrate, and protein metabolism between lean and obese subjects undergoing total starvation. Obes. Res. 1999;7:597&#x2013;604. doi: 10.1002/j.1550-8528.1999.tb00720.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.1550-8528.1999.tb00720.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10574520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly J.E., Lambourne K. Classroom-based physical activity, cognition, and academic achievement. Prev. Med. 2011;52:S36&#x2013;S42. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2011.01.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2011.01.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21281666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M., Burns S. Increasing Lean Mass and Strength: A Comparison of High Frequency Strength Training to Lower Frequency Strength Training. Int. J. Exerc. Sci. 2016;9:159&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4836564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27182422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber C.E., Blissmer B., Deschenes M.R., Franklin B.A., Lamonte M.J., Lee I.-M., Nieman D.C., Swain D.P. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334&#x2013;1359. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213fefb.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318213fefb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw B., Shaw I., Krasilshchikov O. Effects of aerobic and concurrent aerobic and resistance training on effort- or muscle-dependant spirometry parameters in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD): A meta-analysis. Asian J. Exerc. Sports Sci. 2008;5:63&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw I., Shaw B., Krasilshchikov O. Comparison of aerobic and combined aerobic and resistance training on low-density lipoprotein cholesterol concentrations in men. Cardiovasc. J. Afr. 2009;20:290&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19907801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann M., Feuerbacher J.F., S&#xfc;nkeler M., Freitag N., R&#xf8;nnestad B.R., Doma K., Lundberg T.R. Compatibility of Concurrent Aerobic and Strength Training for Skeletal Muscle Size and Function: An Updated Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2021;52:601&#x2013;612. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01587-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01587-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8891239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34757594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuan G., Wan Firdaus Krasilshchikov O. Effects of using complex training method on muscular power among competitive male weightlifters. Malays. J. Sport Sci. Recreat. (MJSSR) 2018;14:11&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargreaves M., Spriet L.L. Skeletal muscle energy metabolism during exercise. Nat. Metab. 2020;2:817&#x2013;828. doi: 10.1038/s42255-020-0251-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42255-020-0251-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32747792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton P.J., Babraj J.A., Smith K., Singh J., Rennie M.J., Wackerhage H. Selective activation of AMPK-PGC-1&#x3b1; or PKB-TSC2-mTOR signaling can explain specific adaptive responses to endurance or resistance training-like electrical muscle stimulation. FASEB J. 2005;19:1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15716393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey V.G., Hawley J.A. Concurrent exercise training: Do opposites distract? J. Physiol. 2017;595:2883&#x2013;2896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27506998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepto N.K., Benziane B., Wadley G.D., Chibalin A.V., Canny B.J., Eynon N., McConell G.K. Short-term intensified cycle training alters acute and chronic responses of PGC1&#x3b1; and Cytochrome C oxidase IV to exercise in human skeletal muscle. PLoS ONE. 2012;7:e53080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3532354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23285255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M.J.-C., Ballantyne J.K., Chagolla J., Hopkins W.G., Fyfe J.J., Phillips S.M., Bishop D.J., Bartlett J.D. Order of same-day concurrent training influences some indices of power development, but not strength, lean mass, or aerobic fitness in healthy, moderately-active men after 9 weeks of training. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:e0233134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7224562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32407361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmins R.G., Shamim B., Tofari P.J., Hickey J.T., Camera D.M. Differences in lower limb strength and structure after 12 weeks of resistance, endurance, and concurrent training. Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 2020;15:1223&#x2013;1230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J. The Effects of Upper Body Strength Training Versus Concurrent Strength + Endurance Training on Indices of Strength, Aerobic Power, and Muscle Cross-Sectional Area. J. Exerc. Physiol. Online. 2023;26:183&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullen S.P., Olson E.A., Phillips S.M., Szabo A.N., W&#xf3;jcicki T.R., Mailey E.L., Gothe N.P., Fanning J.T., Kramer A.F., McAuley E. Measuring enjoyment of physical activity in older adults: Invariance of the physical activity enjoyment scale (paces) across groups and time. Int. J. Behav. Nutr. Phys. Act. 2011;8:103. doi: 10.1186/1479-5868-8-103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5868-8-103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3206413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21951520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashim H.A., Grove J.R., Whipp P. Testing a model of physical education enjoyment and physical activity among high school students. ICHPER-SD J. Res. Health. 2008;3:95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneda K., Sato D., Wakabayashi H., Hanai A., Nomura T. A comparison of the effects of different water exercise programs on balance ability in elderly people. J. Aging Phys. Act. 2008;16:381&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19033600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan A.A. Resistance Training: Benefits on Health &amp; Fitness. Int. J. Fitness Health Phys. Educ. Iron Games. 2016;3:60&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xf6;chm&#xfc;ller M., Schwingshackl L., Colombani P.C., Hoffmann G. A systematic review and meta-analysis of carbohydrate benefits associated with randomized controlled competition-based performance trials. J. Int. Soc. Sports Nutr. 2016;13:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4940907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27408608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba&#xf1;ez J., Izquierdo M., ARGuelles I., Forga L., Larri&#xf3;n J.L., Garc&#xed;a-Unciti M., Idoate F., Gorostiaga E.M. Twice-weekly progressive resistance training decreases abdominal fat and improves insulin sensitivity in older men with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:662&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira M.L., Sherrington C., Smith K., Carswell P., Bell R., Bell M., Nascimento D.P., Pereira L.S.M., Vardon P. Physical activity improves strength, balance and endurance in adults aged 40&#x2013;65 years: A systematic review. J. Physiother. 2012;58:145&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22884181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jago R., Drews K.L., McMurray R.G., Thompson D., Volpe S.L., Moe E.L., Jakicic J.M., Pham T.H., Bruecker S., Blackshear T.B., et al. Fatness, fitness, and cardiometabolic risk factors among sixth-grade youth. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2010;42:1502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2921216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worthey C.D. The Effects of Two Different Resistance Training Protocols with Similar Volume on Muscular Strength, Muscle Thickness, and Fat-Free Mass. Illinois State University; Normal, IL, USA: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller S., Wolfe R.R. The danger of weight loss in the elderly. J. Nutr. Health Aging. 2008;12:487&#x2013;491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18615231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T., Mull S., Aragon A.A., Krieger J., Schoenfeld B.J. Resistance training combined with diet decreases body fat while preserving lean mass independent of resting metabolic rate: A randomized trial. Int. J. Sport. Nutr. Exerc. Metab. 2018;28:46&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28871849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voisin S., Alm&#xe9;n M.S., Zheleznyakova G.Y., Lundberg L., Zarei S., Castillo S., Eriksson F.E., Nilsson E.K., Bl&#xfc;her M., B&#xf6;ttcher Y., et al. Many obesity-associated SNPs strongly associate with DNA methylation changes at proximal promoters and enhancers. Genome Med. 2015;7:103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4599317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26449484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osawa K., Miyoshi T., Koyama Y., Sato S., Akagi N., Morimitsu Y., Kubo M., Sugiyama H., Nakamura K., Morita H. Differential association of visceral adipose tissue with coronary plaque characteristics in patients with and without diabetes mellitus. Cardiovasc. Diabetol. 2014;13:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3975136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24624968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb P.J., Williams A.D., Stathis C., Carey M.F., Hayes A. Effects of whey isolate, creatine and resistance training on muscle hypertrophy. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 2007;39:298&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFreitas J.M., Beck T.W., Stock M.S., Dillon M.A., Kasishke P.R. An examination of the time course of training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 2011;111:2785&#x2013;2790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21409401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Aziz Habib H. Effect of functional resistance drills with Elastic bands on some of physical and biomechanical variables and kicking accuracy in soccer. Assiut J. Sport. Sci. Arts. 2018;2018:312&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss T., Kreitinger J., Wilde H., Wiora C., Steege M., Dalleck L., Janot J. Effect of functional resistance training on muscular fitness outcomes in young adults. J. Exerc. Sci. Fit. 2010;8:113&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karavirta L., H&#xe4;kkinen A., Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E., Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez D., Kauhanen A., Haapasaari A., Alen M., Pakarinen A., Kraemer W.J., Izquierdo M. Effects of combined endurance and strength training on muscle strength, power and hypertrophy in 40&#x2013;67-year-old men. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports. 2011;21:402&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20030775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H., Sakamaki M., Yasuda T., Fujita S., Ogasawara R., Sugaya M., Nakajima T., Abe T. Increases in thigh muscle volume and strength by walk training with leg blood flow reduction in older participants. J. Gerontol. Ser. A Biomed. Sci. Med. Sci. 2011;66:257&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20974731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins K.A., Fos L.B., Ross L.M., Slentz C.A., Davis P.G., Willis L.H., Piner L.W., Bateman L.A., Houmard J.A., Kraus W.E. Aerobic, resistance, and combination training on health-related quality of life: The STRRIDE-AT/RT randomized trial. Front. Sports Act. Living. 2021;2:620300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33644749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srismith D., Dierkes K., Zipfel S., Thiel A., Sudeck G., Giel K.E., Behrens S.C. Physical activity improves body image of sedentary adults. Exploring the roles of interoception and affective response. Curr. Psychol. 2022 doi: 10.1007/s12144-022-03641-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-022-03641-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>