<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39679645</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Velocity-Specific Adaptations to Three Widely Used Strength Training Methods.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2258</StartPage><EndPage>2268</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2258-2268</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003630</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We examined bench press adaptations to three widely used strength training methods: maximal strength training (MST), hypertrophy training (HT), and explosive strength training (EST). To reflect how these methods are typically applied by practitioners, MST and EST were volume matched, whereas HT was performed at higher volume.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Sixty-three moderately trained subjects (32 males, 31 females) were assigned into 8 wk of MST, HT, EST, or control (CON), three sessions per week. MST performed 4 &#xd7; 4 repetitions bench press at &#x2265;85% of one-repetition maximum (1RM). HT performed 3 &#xd7; 8-12 repetitions at &#x223c;70%-80% of 1RM. EST performed 4 &#xd7; 6-7 repetitions bench press throws at 40% of 1RM. Maximal, explosive, and endurance strength characteristics were assessed, as well as muscle hypertrophy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">1RM increased more after MST (+21.5%) and HT (+17.9%) compared with EST (+5.9%) and CON (all P &#x2264; 0.001). Rate of force development (RFD) at 50% of 1RM increased more after MST (+58.4%) and HT (+38.9%) compared with CON ( P &#x2264; 0.001 and P &#x2264; 0.05, respectively). Mean propulsive velocity (MPV) increased more after MST and HT compared with CON across all loads (20%-80% of 1RM), and more than EST at 80% and 60% (all P &#x2264; 0.05-0.001). MST increased MPV more than EST at 40% of 1RM ( P &#x2264; 0.05). &#x394;1RM correlated with &#x394;MPV at all loads of the load-velocity (L-v) profile ( r = 0.40-0.56, P &#x2264; 0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">MST and HT were more effective than EST for improving maximal strength and concentric velocity against moderate and high loads. At low loads, EST was not more effective than MST and HT, despite high degree of velocity specificity. Changes in muscle strength appear to be more important than velocity specificity to increase performance across the L-v profile.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trane</LastName><ForeName>Glenn</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education and Arts, Nord University, Bod&#xf8;, NORWAY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pedersen</LastName><ForeName>Stine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education and Arts, Nord University, Bod&#xf8;, NORWAY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehus</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe5;kon Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education and Arts, Nord University, Bod&#xf8;, NORWAY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helgerud</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Unhjem</LastName><ForeName>Runar Jakobsen</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education and Arts, Nord University, Bod&#xf8;, NORWAY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BENCH PRESS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BENCH PRESS THROW</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EXPLOSIVE STRENGTH TRAINING (EST)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HYPERTROPHY TRAINING (HT)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LOAD&#x2013;VELOCITY (L&#x2013;V) PROFILE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MAXIMAL STRENGTH TRAINING (MST)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RATE OF FORCE DEVELOPMENT (RFD)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39679645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-00685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alm&#xe5;sbakk B, Hoff J. Coordination, the determinant of velocity specificity? J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1996;81(5):2046&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson T, Kearney JT. Effects of three resistance training programs on muscular strength and absolute and relative endurance. Res Q Exerc Sport . 1982;53(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshaw TG, Massey GJ, Maden-Wilkinson TM, Tillin NA, Folland JP. Training-specific functional, neural, and hypertrophic adaptations to explosive- vs. sustained-contraction strength training. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2016;120(11):1364&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GE, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2002;88(1&#x2013;2):50&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McCaulley GO, McBride JM. Power versus strength-power jump squat training: influence on the load&#x2013;power relationship. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2007;39(6):996&#x2013;1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Adaptations in athletic performance after ballistic power versus strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2010;42(8):1582&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris GR, Stone MH, O'Bryant HS, Proulx CM, Johnson RL. Short term performance effects of high power, high force, or combined weight-training methods. J Strength Cond Res . 2000;14(1):14&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris NK, Cronin JB, Hopkins WG, Hansen KT. Squat jump training at maximal power loads vs. heavy loads: effect on sprint ability. J Strength Cond Res . 2008;22(6):1742&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heggelund J, Fimland MS, Helgerud J, Hoff J. Maximal strength training improves work economy, rate of force development and maximal strength more than conventional strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2013;113(6):1565&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones K, Bishop P, Hunter G, Fleisig G. The effects of varying resistance-training loads on intermediate- and high-velocity&#x2013;specific adaptations. J Strength Cond Res . 2001;15(3):349&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride JM, Triplett-McBride T, Davie A, Newton RU. The effect of heavy- vs. light-load jump squats on the development of strength, power, and speed. J Strength Cond Res . 2002;16(1):75&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res . 2015;29(10):2954&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Vigotsky AD, Peterson M. Differential effects of heavy versus moderate loads on measures of strength and hypertrophy in resistance-trained men. J Sports Sci Med . 2016;15(4):715&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res . 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone WJ, Coulter SP. Strength/endurance effects from three resistance training protocols with women. J Strength Cond Res . 1994;8(4):231&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA, Folland JP. Maximal and explosive strength training elicit distinct neuromuscular adaptations, specific to the training stimulus. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2014;114(2):365&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K, Brink M, L&#xf8;nbro S, et al. Muscle adaptations to plyometric vs. resistance training in untrained young men. J Strength Cond Res . 2008;22(6):1799&#x2013;810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson GJ, Newton RU, Murphy AJ, Humphries BJ. The optimal training load for the development of dynamic athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1993;25(11):1279&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2004;36(4):674&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Developing maximal neuromuscular power: part 2&#x2014;training considerations for improving maximal power production. Sports Med . 2011;41(2):125&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Nimphius S. Training principles for power. Strength Cond J . 2012;34(6):2&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TE, et al. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Sale DG. Intended rather than actual movement velocity determines velocity-specific training response. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1993;74(1):359&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Sale DG. Velocity specificity of resistance training. Sports Med . 1993;15(6):374&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Fisher J, Grgic J, et al. Resistance training recommendations to maximize muscle hypertrophy in an athletic population: position stand of the IUSCA. IJSC . 2021;1(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamori N, Haff GG. The optimal training load for the development of muscular power. J Strength Cond Res . 2004;18(3):675&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Newton RU. Training for muscular power. Phys Med Rehabil Clin N Am . 2000;11(2):341&#x2013;vii.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevan HR, Bunce PJ, Owen NJ, et al. Optimal loading for the development of peak power output in professional rugby players. J Strength Cond Res . 2010;24(1):43&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Humphries BJ, Murphy AJ. Kinematics, kinetics, and muscle activation during explosive upper body movements. J Appl Biomech . 1996;12(1):31&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, Folland J, Tillin N, Duchateau J. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2016;116(6):1091&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zatsiorsky V. Biomechanics of strength and strength training. In: Komi PV, editor. Strength and Power in Sport . Oxford (UK): Blackwell science; 2003. p. 440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneko M, Fuchimoto T, Toji H, Suei K. Training effect of different load on the force&#x2013;velocity relationship and mechanical power output in human muscle. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 1983;5(2):50&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss BM, Refsnes PE, Abildgaard A, Nicolaysen K, Jensen J. Effects of maximal effort strength training with different loads on dynamic strength, cross-sectional area, load&#x2013;power and load&#x2013;velocity relationships. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1997;75(3):193&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Effects of ballistic training on preseason preparation of elite volleyball players. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1999;31(2):323&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haglo H, Berg OK, Hoff J, Helgerud J, Wang E. Maximal strength training in patients with inflammatory rheumatic disease: implications for physical function and quality of life. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2022;122(7):1671&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff J, Gran A, Helgerud J. Maximal strength training improves aerobic endurance performance. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2002;12(5):288&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff J, Tj&#xf8;nna AE, Steinshamn S, H&#xf8;ydal M, Richardson RS, Helgerud J. Maximal strength training of the legs in COPD: a therapy for mechanical inefficiency. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2007;39(2):220&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kittilsen HT, Goleva-Fjellet S, Freberg BI, et al. Responses to maximal strength training in different age and gender groups. Front Physiol . 2021;12:636972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;ren &#xd8;, Helgerud J, St&#xf8;a EM, Hoff J. Maximal strength training improves running economy in distance runners. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2008;40(6):1087&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf8;ien T, Pedersen Haglo H, Unhjem R, Hoff J, Wang E. Maximal strength training: the impact of eccentric overload. J Neurophysiol . 2018;120(6):2868&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unhjem R, Lundestad R, Fimland MS, Mosti MP, Wang E. Strength training-induced responses in older adults: attenuation of descending neural drive with age. Age (Dordr) . 2015;37(3):9784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Van Every DW, Plotkin DL. Loading recommendations for muscle strength, hypertrophy, and local endurance: a re-examination of the repetition continuum. Sports (Basel) . 2021;9(2):32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2002;93(4):1318&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LL, Aagaard P. Influence of maximal muscle strength and intrinsic muscle contractile properties on contractile rate of force development. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2006;96(1):46&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;ster&#xe5;s H, Helgerud J, Hoff J. Maximal strength-training effects on force&#x2013;velocity and force&#x2013;power relationships explain increases in aerobic performance in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2002;88(3):255&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;ren &#xd8;, Helgerud J, S&#xe6;b&#xf8; M, et al. The effect of age on the V&#x307;O 2max response to high-intensity interval training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2017;49(1):78&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA . 2013;310(20):2191&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzocchi A, Ponti F, Albisinni U, Battista G, Guglielmi G. DXA: technical aspects and application. Eur J Radiol . 2016;85(8):1481&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hind K, Oldroyd B, Truscott JG. In vivo precision of the GE Lunar iDXA densitometer for the measurement of total body composition and fat distribution in adults. Eur J Clin Nutr . 2011;65(1):140&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. Accurate assessment of muscular strength and power. J Exerc Physiol . 2001;4(3):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L. Movement velocity as a measure of loading intensity in resistance training. Int J Sports Med . 2010;31(5):347&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Schoenfeld BJ, Pedisic Z. Test&#x2013;retest reliability of the one-repetition maximum (1RM) strength assessment: a systematic review. Sports Med Open . 2020;6(1):31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Cronin J, Storey A, Zourdos MC. Application of the repetitions in reserve&#x2013;based rating of perceived exertion scale for resistance training. Strength Cond J . 2016;38(4):42&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleck SJ, Kraemer W. Designing Resistance Training Programs . Champaign (IL): Human Kinetics; 2014. p. 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res . 2010;24(10):2857&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JD, Lippman JD, Trevino MA, Herda TJ. Neural drive is greater for a high-intensity contraction than for moderate-intensity contractions performed to fatigue. J Strength Cond Res . 2020;34(11):3013&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll KM, Bazyler CD, Bernards JR, et al. Skeletal muscle fiber adaptations following resistance training using repetition maximums or relative intensity. Sports (Basel) . 2019;7(7):169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Roberts BM, Vigotsky AD, Schoenfeld BJ, Roberts MD. A critical evaluation of the biological construct skeletal muscle hypertrophy: size matters but so does the measurement. Front Physiol . 2019;10:247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Konrad A, Nakamura M, et al. A narrative review of velocity-based training best practice: the importance of contraction intent versus movement speed. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2025;50:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength in athletic performance. Sports Med . 2016;46(10):1419&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Influence of strength on magnitude and mechanisms of adaptation to power training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2010;42(8):1566&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetmore AB, Moquin PA, Carroll KM, Fry AC, Hornsby WG, Stone MH. The effect of training status on adaptations to 11 weeks of block periodization training. Sports (Basel) . 2020;8(11):145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll KM, Bernards JR, Bazyler CD, et al. Divergent performance outcomes following resistance training using repetition maximums or relative intensity. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2019;14(1):46&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva-Batista C, et al. Muscle failure promotes greater muscle hypertrophy in low-load but not in high-load resistance training. J Strength Cond Res . 2022;36(2):346&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>