<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37796222</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Different Weekly Set Progressions on Muscular Adaptations in Trained Males: Is There a Dose-Response Effect?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>553</StartPage><EndPage>563</EndPage><MedlinePgn>553-563</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003317</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study investigated the effect of progressively adding sets for the lower limb every 2 wk versus performing a constant set volume in resistance-trained males.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty-one resistance-trained males (age = 24.4 &#xb1; 2.9 yr, height = 175.5 &#xb1; 6.5 cm, body mass = 80.1 &#xb1; 9.4 kg, body fat = 14.4% &#xb1; 3.1%, resistance training [RT] experience = 5.1 &#xb1; 2.2 yr; one-repetition maximum [1RM] barbell back squat: body mass ratio = 1.7 &#xb1; 0.1 a.u.) were randomly allocated into a constant group (CG, n = 10), a four-set progression group (4SG, n = 10) or a six-set progression group (6SG, n = 11). After a 2-wk washout period and another 2-wk familiarization period, participants performed a lower-limb training program twice a week for 12 wk. Maximum dynamic strength (1RM) in the barbell back squat, vastus lateralis cross-sectional area, and the sum of lateral thigh muscle thickness at 30%, 50%, and 70% of the femur length were assessed at baseline and after the 12-wk training program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Regarding 1RM, multiple comparisons revealed that 6SG elicited higher muscle strength gains than 4SG ( P = 0.002) and CG ( P &lt; 0.0001), and 4SG had greater improvements than CG ( P = 0.023). Cross-sectional area and sum of lateral thigh muscle thickness showed no between-group differences ( P = 0.067 and P = 0.076, respectively). However, an inspection of 95% confidence intervals suggests a potential dose-response relationship, with results appearing to plateau in the higher volume conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results suggest that progressively adding four or six sets per week every 2 wk elicited greater lower-limb strength in resistance-trained individuals over a 12-wk training period. Although our findings indicate a possible small benefit for higher volume conditions regarding hypertrophic adaptations in this population, the limited certainty of our findings warrants caution.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Enes</LastName><ForeName>Alysson</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Strength Training Research Group-Federal University of Paran&#xe1; (UFPR), Curitiba, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DE Souza</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo O</ForeName><Initials>EO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, The University of Tampa, Tampa, FL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souza-Junior</LastName><ForeName>T&#xe1;cito P</ForeName><Initials>TP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Metabolism, Nutrition and Strength Training Research Group-Federal University of Paran&#xe1; (UFPR), Curitiba, PR, BRAZIL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013848" MajorTopicYN="N">Thigh</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37796222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202403000-00018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abou Sawan S, Nunes EA, Lim C, McKendry J, Phillips SM. The health benefits of resistance exercise: beyond hypertrophy and big weights. Exerc Sport Mov . 2023;1(1):e00001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Fisher J, Grgic J, et al. Resistance training recommendations to maximize muscle hypertrophy in an athletic population: position stand of the IUSCA. Int J Strength Cond . 2021;1(1):ijsc.v1i1.81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aube D, Wadhi T, Rauch J, et al. Progressive resistance training volume: effects on muscle thickness, mass, and strength adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res . 2022;36(3):600&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2019;51(1):94&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpelli MC, N&#xf3;brega SR, Santanielo N, et al. Muscle hypertrophy response is affected by previous resistance training volume in trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res . 2022;36(4):1153&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Lima LEM, Germano MD, Aoki MS, Braz TV, Lopes CR. High resistance-training volume enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res . 2022;36(1):22&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Balsalobre-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Alix-Fages C, Santos-Concejero J. A systematic review of the effects of different resistance training volumes on muscle hypertrophy. J Hum Kinet . 2022;81(1):199&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski KJ, Wilson GJ, Weatherby R, Murphy PW, Lyttle AD. The effect of weight training volume on hormonal output and muscular size and function. J Strength Cond Res . 1997;11(3):148&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PWM, McEwen M, Robbins DW. Strength and neuromuscular adaptation following one, four, and eight sets of high intensity resistance exercise in trained males. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2011;111(12):3007&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaselgrave SR, Blacker J, Smeuninx B, McKendry J, Breen L. Dose-response relationship of weekly resistance-training volume and frequency on muscular adaptations in trained men. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2019;14(3):360&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf3;brega SR, Scarpelli MC, Barcelos C, Chaves TS, Libardi CA. Muscle hypertrophy is affected by volume load progression models. J Strength Cond Res . 2023;37(1):62&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israetel M, Feather J, Faleiro TV, Juneau C-E. Mesocycle progression in hypertrophy: volume versus intensity. Strength Cond J . 2020;42(5):2&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Grgic J. Evidence-based guidelines for resistance training volume to maximize muscle hypertrophy. Strength Cond J . 2018;40(4):107&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haun CT, Vann CG, Mobley CB, et al. Effects of graded whey supplementation during extreme-volume resistance training. Front Nutr . 2018;5:84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G* Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods . 2007;39(2):175&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos Junior ERT, de Salles BF, Dias I, Ribeiro AS, Sim&#xe3;o R, Willardson JM. Classification and determination model of resistance training status. Strength Cond J . 2021;43(5):77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Weir JP. ASEP procedures recommendation I: accurate assessment of muscular strength and power. J Exerc Physiol Online . 2001;4(3):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2000;81(3):174&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Bottaro M, et al. Vastus lateralis muscle cross-sectional area ultrasonography validity for image fitting in humans. J Strength Cond Res . 2014;28(11):3293&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves ND, Maganaris CN, Narici MV. Ultrasonographic assessment of human skeletal muscle size. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2004;91(1):116&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res . 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir JP. Quantifying test-retest reliability using the intraclass correlation coefficient and the SEM. J Strength Cond Res . 2005;19(1):231&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull . 1992;112(1):155&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Some issues in power analysis. In: Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences . New York: Routledge; 1988. pp. 531&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley KS, Flippin KJ, Blom LC, Bolin JE, Hoover DL, Judge LW. Practices, perceived benefits, and barriers to resistance training among women enrolled in college. Int J Exerc Sci . 2018;11(5):226&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertz W, Tsui JC, Judd JT, et al. What are people really eating? The relation between energy intake derived from estimated diet records and intake determined to maintain body weight. Am J Clin Nutr . 1991;54(2):291&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fell J, Williams AD. The effect of aging on skeletal-muscle recovery from exercise: possible implications for aging athletes. J Aging Phys Act . 2008;16(1):97&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>