<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35403756</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of specific collagen peptide supplementation combined with resistance training on Achilles tendon properties.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1131</StartPage><EndPage>1141</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1131-1141</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.14164</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of specific collagen peptides (SCP) combined with resistance training (RT) on changes in tendinous and muscular properties. In a randomized, placebo-controlled study, 40 healthy male volunteers (age: 26.3&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;4.0&#xa0;years) completed a 14&#xa0;weeks high-load resistance training program. One group received a daily dosage of 5g SCP while the other group received 5g of a placebo (PLA) supplement. Changes in Achilles tendon cross-sectional area (CSA), tendon stiffness, muscular strength, and thickness of the plantar flexors were measured. The SCP supplementation led to a significantly (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.002) greater increase in tendon CSA (+11.0%) compared with the PLA group (+4.7%). Moreover, the statistical analysis revealed a significantly (p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.014) greater increase in muscle thickness in the SCP group (+7.3%) compared with the PLA group (+2.7%). Finally, tendon stiffness and muscle strength increased in both groups, with no statistical difference between the groups. In conclusion, the current study shows that the supplementation of specific collagen peptides combined with RT is associated with a greater hypertrophy in tendinous and muscular structures than RT alone in young physically active men. These effects might play a role in reducing tendon stress (i.e., deposition of collagen in load-bearing structures) during daily activities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science In Sports published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jerger</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2697-7568</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Centner</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6839-4438</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Praxisklinik Rennbahn, Muttenz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lauber</LastName><ForeName>Benedikt</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9684-3675</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences and Movement Sciences, University of Fribourg, Fribourg, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seynnes</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Performance, Norwegian School of Sport Sciences, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sohnius</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jendricke</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oesser</LastName><ForeName>Steffen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CRI, Collagen Research Institute GmbH, Kiel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gollhofer</LastName><ForeName>Albert</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Sport Science, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K&#xf6;nig</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Nutrition, Exercise and Health, Centre of Sports Science, University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Nutrition, Exercise and Health, Faculty of Life Sciences, University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Gelita AG, Eberbach, Germany</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010455">Peptides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011091">Polyesters</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-34-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003094">Collagen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000125" MajorTopicYN="Y">Achilles Tendon</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003094" MajorTopicYN="N">Collagen</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010455" MajorTopicYN="N">Peptides</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011091" MajorTopicYN="N">Polyesters</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-sectional area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein supplementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stiffness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tendon</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35403756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kjaer M, J&#xf8;rgensen NR, Heinemeier K, Magnusson SP. Exercise and regulation of bone and collagen tissue biology. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci. 2015;135:259-291. doi:10.1016/bs.pmbts.2015.07.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger HP, Kosters A, Muller E, Seynnes OR. Effects of increased loading on in vivo tendon properties: a systematic review. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(9):1885-1895. doi:10.1249/MSS.0000000000000603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arampatzis A, Karamanidis K, Albracht K. Adaptational responses of the human Achilles tendon by modulation of the applied cyclic strain magnitude. J Exp Biol. 2007;210(Pt 15):2743-2753. doi:10.1242/jeb.003814</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeier KM, Kjaer M. In vivo investigation of tendon responses to mechanical loading. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2011;11(2):115-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Ikebukuro T, Maki A, Yata H, Tsunoda N. Time course of changes in the human Achilles tendon properties and metabolism during training and detraining in vivo. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(7):2679-2691. doi:10.1007/s00421-011-2248-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schunck M, Oesser S. Specific collagen peptides benefit the biosynthesis of matrix molecules of tendons and ligaments. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10(Suppl. 1):P23. doi:10.1186/1550-2783-10-S1-P23</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng M, Betti M. Transepithelial transport efficiency of bovine collagen hydrolysates in a human Caco-2 cell line model. Food Chem. 2017;224:242-250. doi:10.1016/j.foodchem.2016.12.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taga Y, Kusubata M, Ogawa-Goto K, Hattori S. Efficient absorption of X-hydroxyproline (Hyp)-gly after oral administration of a novel gelatin hydrolysate prepared using ginger protease. J Agric Food Chem. 2016;64(14):2962-2970. doi:10.1021/acs.jafc.6b00609</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Wang Q, Liang Q, et al. Determination of bioavailability and identification of collagen peptide in blood after oral ingestion of gelatin. J Sci Food Agric. 2015;95(13):2712-2717. doi:10.1002/jsfa.7008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar K. Stress relaxation and targeted nutrition to treat patellar tendinopathy. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019;29(4):453-457. doi:10.1123/ijsnem.2018-0231</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praet SFE, Purdam CR, Welvaert M, et al. Oral supplementation of specific collagen peptides combined with calf-strengthening exercises enhances function and reduces pain in achilles tendinopathy patients. Nutrients. 2019;11(1):76. doi:10.3390/nu11010076</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dressler P, Gehring D, Zdzieblik D, Oesser S, Gollhofer A, Konig D. Improvement of functional ankle properties following supplementation with specific collagen peptides in athletes with chronic ankle instability. J Sports Sci Med. 2018;17(2):298-304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdzieblik D, Oesser S, Baumstark MW, Gollhofer A, Konig D. Collagen peptide supplementation in combination with resistance training improves body composition and increases muscle strength in elderly sarcopenic men: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Nutr. 2015;114(8):1237-1245. doi:10.1017/S0007114515002810</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jendricke P, Centner C, Zdzieblik D, Gollhofer A, K&#xf6;nig D. Specific collagen peptides in combination with resistance training improve body composition and regional muscle strength in premenopausal women: a randomized controlled trial. Nutrients. 2019;11(4):892. doi:10.3390/nu11040892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oertzen-Hagemann V, Kirmse M, Eggers B, et al. Effects of 12 weeks of hypertrophy resistance exercise training combined with collagen peptide supplementation on the skeletal muscle proteome in recreationally active men. Nutrients. 2019;11(5):1072. doi:10.3390/nu11051072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitakaze T, Sakamoto T, Kitano T, et al. The collagen derived dipeptide hydroxyprolyl-glycine promotes C2C12 myoblast differentiation and myotube hypertrophy. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2016;478(3):1292-1297. doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2016.08.114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacinto JL, Nunes JP, Gorissen SHM, et al. Whey protein supplementation is superior to leucine-matched collagen peptides to increase muscle thickness during a 10-week resistance training program in untrained young adults. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2022;1-11. doi:10.1123/ijsnem.2021-0265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arampatzis A, Stafilidis S, DeMonte G, Karamanidis K, Morey-Klapsing G, Br&#xfc;ggemann GP. Strain and elongation of the human gastrocnemius tendon and aponeurosis during maximal plantarflexion effort. J Biomech. 2005;38(4):833-841. doi:10.1016/j.jbiomech.2004.04.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maganaris CN. Tendon conditioning: artefact or property?Proc Biol Sci. 2003;270(Suppl_1):S39-S42. doi:10.1098/rsbl.2003.0004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Lauber B, Seynnes OR, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction training induces similar morphological and mechanical Achilles tendon adaptations compared to high-load resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2019;127(6):1660-1667. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00602.2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook MS, Wilkinson DJ, Mitchell WK, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy adaptations predominate in the early stages of resistance exercise training, matching deuterium oxide-derived measures of muscle protein synthesis and mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 signaling. FASEB J. 2015;29(11):4485-4496. doi:10.1096/fj.15-273755</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey I, Berg A, Grathwohl D, Keul J. [Freiburg questionnaire of physical activity--development, evaluation and application]. Soz Praventivmed. 1999;44(2):55-64. doi:10.1007/bf01667127. Freiburger Fragebogen zur k&#xf6;rperlichen Aktivit&#xe4;t--Entwicklung, Pr&#xfc;fung und Anwendung.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Ferguson RA. Enhancing strength and postocclusive calf blood flow in older people with training with blood-flow restriction. J Aging Phys Act. 2011;19(3):201-213. doi:10.1123/japa.19.3.201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grubbs FE. Sample criteria for testing outlying observations. Ann Math Statist. 1950;21(1):27-58. doi:10.1214/aoms/1177729885</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm S, Mersmann F, Arampatzis A. Human tendon adaptation in response to mechanical loading: a systematic review and meta-analysis of exercise intervention studies on healthy adults. Sports Med Open. 2015;1(1):7. doi:10.1186/s40798-015-0009-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, Rahbek SK, Vendelbo MH, et al. Whey protein hydrolysate augments tendon and muscle hypertrophy independent of resistance exercise contraction mode. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(5):788-798. doi:10.1111/sms.12083</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeier KM, Schjerling P, Heinemeier J, Magnusson SP, Kjaer M. Lack of tissue renewal in human adult Achilles tendon is revealed by nuclear bomb (14)C. FASEB J. 2013;27(5):2074-2079. doi:10.1096/fj.12-225599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen CS, Svensson RB, Gylling AT, Coupp&#xe9; C, Magnusson SP, Kjaer M. Load magnitude affects patellar tendon mechanical properties but not collagen or collagen cross-linking after long-term strength training in older adults. BMC Geriatr. 2019;19(1):30. doi:10.1186/s12877-019-1043-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Coupp&#xe9; C, Scheijen J, et al. Regional collagen turnover and composition of the human patellar tendon. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2020;128(4):884-891. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00030.2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw G, Lee-Barthel A, Ross ML, Wang B, Baar K. Vitamin C-enriched gelatin supplementation before intermittent activity augments collagen synthesis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2017;105(1):136-143. doi:10.3945/ajcn.116.138594</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minaguchi J, Koyama Y, Meguri N, et al. Effects of ingestion of collagen peptide on collagen fibrils and glycosaminoglycans in Achilles tendon. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo). 2005;51(3):169-174. doi:10.3177/jnsv.51.169</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll CC, Dickinson JM, LeMoine JK, et al. Influence of acetaminophen and ibuprofen on in vivo patellar tendon adaptations to knee extensor resistance exercise in older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2011;111(2):508-515. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.01348.2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger HP, Rieder F, K&#xf6;sters A, M&#xfc;ller E, Seynnes OR. Sport-specific capacity to use elastic energy in the patellar and achilles tendons of elite athletes. Front Physiol. 2017;8:132. doi:10.3389/fphys.2017.00132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvist M. Achilles tendon injuries in athletes. Sports Med. 1994;18(3):173-201. doi:10.2165/00007256-199418030-00004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mersmann F, Bohm S, Arampatzis A. Imbalances in the development of muscle and tendon as risk factor for tendinopathies in youth athletes: a review of current evidence and concepts of prevention. Front Physiol. 2017;8:987. doi:10.3389/fphys.2017.00987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Kirby TJ, Kosmac K, McCarthy JJ, Peterson CA. Myogenic progenitor cells control extracellular matrix production by fibroblasts during skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell Stem Cell. 2017;20(1):56-69. doi:10.1016/j.stem.2016.09.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdzieblik D, Jendricke P, Oesser S, Gollhofer A, K&#xf6;nig D. The influence of specific bioactive collagen peptides on body composition and muscle strength in middle-aged, untrained men: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(9):4837. doi:10.3390/ijerph18094837</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirmse M, Oertzen-Hagemann V, deMar&#xe9;es M, Bloch W, Platen P. Prolonged collagen peptide supplementation and resistance exercise training affects body composition in recreationally active men. Nutrients. 2019;11(5):1154. doi:10.3390/nu11051154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG, Martin JE, Moroz DE. Hypertrophy without increased isometric strength after weight training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1992;64(1):51-55. doi:10.1007/BF00376440</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training : morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37(2):145-168. doi:10.2165/00007256-200737020-00004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Wilson G, Carlyon B. Generality versus specificity: a comparison of dynamic and isometric measures of strength and speed-strength. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;68(4):350-355. doi:10.1007/bf00571456</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schadow S, Simons VS, Lochnit G, et al. Metabolic response of human osteoarthritic cartilage to biochemically characterized collagen hydrolysates. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18(1):207. doi:10.3390/ijms18010207</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brush&#xf8;j C, Henriksen BM, Albrecht-Beste E, H&#xf6;lmich P, Larsen K, Bachmann NM. Reproducibility of ultrasound and magnetic resonance imaging measurements of tendon size. Acta Radiol. 2006;47(9):954-959. doi:10.1080/02841850600854936</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mc Auliffe S, Mc Creesh K, Purtill H, O'Sullivan K. A systematic review of the reliability of diagnostic ultrasound imaging in measuring tendon size: Is the error clinically acceptable?Phys Ther Sport. 2017;26:52-63. doi:10.1016/j.ptsp.2016.12.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruse A, Stafilidis S, Tilp M. Ultrasound and magnetic resonance imaging are not interchangeable to assess the Achilles tendon cross-sectional-area. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(1):73-82. doi:10.1007/s00421-016-3500-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Teshima T, Hirose N, Tsunoda N. A cross-sectional study of the plantar flexor muscle and tendon during growth. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35(10):828-834. doi:10.1055/s-0034-1367011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson SP, Aagaard P, Dyhre-Poulsen P, Kjaer M. Load-displacement properties of the human triceps surae aponeurosis in vivo. J Physiol. 2001;531(Pt 1):277-288. doi:10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0277j.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira LF, Peixinho CC, Silva GA, Menegaldo LL. In vivo passive mechanical properties estimation of Achilles tendon using ultrasound. J Biomech. 2016;49(4):507-513. doi:10.1016/j.jbiomech.2015.10.033</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>