<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24149888</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1303-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sports science &amp; medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sports Sci Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ACTN3 R577X Polymorphism and Neuromuscular Response to Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>393</StartPage><EndPage>399</EndPage><MedlinePgn>393-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The R577X polymorphism at the ACTN3 gene has been associated with muscle strength, hypertrophy and athletic status. The X allele, which is associated with the absence of ACTN3 protein is supposed to impair performance of high force/velocity muscle contractions. The purpose of the present study was to investigate the association of the R577X polymorphism with the muscle response to resistance training in young men. One hundred forty one men performed two resistance training sessions per week for 11 weeks. Participants were tested for 1RM bench press, knee extensors peak torque, and knee extensors muscle thickness at baseline and after the training period. Genotyping was conducted using de DdeI restriction enzyme. Genotype distribution was 34.4% for RR, 47% for RX and 18.6% for the XX genotype. According to the results, the R577X polymorphism at the ACTN3 gene is not associated with baseline muscle strength or with the muscle strength response to resistance training. However, only carriers of the R allele showed increases in muscle thickness in response to training. Key pointsACTN3 Genotype distribution in the present study was similar to others populations (34.4% for RR, 47% for RX, and 18.6% for the XX).The R577X polymorphism at the ACTN3 gene is not associated with baseline muscle strength or with the muscle strength response to resistance training.It appears that the R allele carriers respond better to muscle thickness gains in response to training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gentil</LastName><ForeName>Paulo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, University of Brasilia , Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pereira</LastName><ForeName>Rinaldo W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leite</LastName><ForeName>Tailce K M</ForeName><Initials>TK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bottaro</LastName><ForeName>Martim</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>J Sports Sci Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101174629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1303-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alpha-actinin 3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genotype</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee extensor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peak torque</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T., DeHoyos D.V., Pollock M.L., Garzarella L. (2000) Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. European Journal of Applied Physiology 81, 174-180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10638374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM (2009) American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 41, 687-708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arden N.K., Spector T.D. (1997) Genetic influences on muscle strength, lean body mass, and bone mineral density: a twin study. Journal of Bone and Mineral Research 12, 2076-2081</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9421240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beggs A.H., Byers T.J., Knoll J.H., Boyce F.M., Bruns G.A., Kunkel L.M. (1992) Cloning and characterization of two human skeletal muscle alpha-actinin genes located on chromosomes 1 and 11. Journal of Biological Chemistry 267, 9281-9288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1339456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beunen G., Thomis M. (2004) Gene powered?. Where to go from heritability (h2) in muscle strength and power? Exercise and Sport Science Reviews 32, 148-154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15604933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray M.S., Hagberg J.M., Perusse L., Rankinen T., Roth S.M., Wolfarth B., Bouchard C. (2009) The human gene map for performance and health-related fitness phenotypes: the 2006-2007 update. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 41, 35-73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19123262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brutsaert T.D., Parra E.J. (2006) What makes a champion? Explaining variation in human athletic performance. Respiratory Physiology &amp; Neurobiology 151, 109-123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan S., Seto J.T., MacArthur D.G., Yang N., North K.N., Head S.I. (2008) A gene for speed: contractile properties of isolated whole EDL muscle from an alpha-actinin-3 knockout mouse. American Journal of Physiology:Cell Physiology 295, C897-904</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanock S.J., Manolio T., Boehnke M., Boerwinkle E., Hunter D.J., Thomas G., Hirschhorn J.N., Abecasis G., Altshuler D., Bailey-Wilson J.E., Brooks L.D., Cardon L.R., Daly M., Donnelly P., Fraumeni J.F., Jr, Freimer N.B., Gerhard D.S., Gunter C., Guttmacher A.E., et al. (2007) Replicating genotype-phenotype associations. Nature 447, 655-660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17554299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck P.D., Stride D., Farthing J.P., Burke D.G. (2004) Effect of creatine ingestion after exercise on muscle thickness in males and females. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 36, 1781-1788</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15595301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson P.M., Devaney J.M., Gordish-Dressman H., Thompson P.D., Hubal M.J., Urso M., Price T.B., Angelopoulos T.J., Gordon P.M., Moyna N.M., Pescatello L.S., Visich P.S., Zoeller R.F., Seip R.L., Hoffman E.P. (2005) ACTN3 genotype is associated with increases in muscle strength in response to resistance training in women. Journal of Applied Physiology 999, 154-163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson P.M., Newham D.J. (1995) Associations between muscle soreness, damage, and fatigue. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology 384, 457-469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8585472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico M.J., Kostek M.C., Doldo N.A., Hand B.D., Walsh S., Conway J.M., Carignan C.R., Roth S.M., Hurley B.F. (2007) Alpha-actinin-3 (ACTN3) R577X polymorphism influences knee extensor peak power response to strength training in older men and women. Journal of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences 62, 206-212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmonico M.J., Zmuda J.M., Taylor B.C., Cauley J.A., Harris T.B., Manini T.M., Schwartz A., Li R., Roth S.M., Hurley B.F., Bauer D.C., Ferrell R.E., Newman A.B. (2008) Association of the ACTN3 genotype and physical functioning with age in older adults. Journal of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences 63, 1227-1234</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19038838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Druzhevskaya A.M., Ahmetov I.I., Astratenkova I.V., Rogozkin V.A. (2008) Association of the ACTN3 R577X polymorphism with power athlete status in Russians. Journal of Applied Physiology European Journal of Applied Physiology 103, 631-634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18470530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eynon N., Duarte J.A., Oliveira J., Sagiv M., Yamin C., Meckel Y., Goldhammer E. (2009) ACTN3 R577X polymorphism and Israeli top-level athletes. International Journal of Sports Medicine 30, 695-698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19544227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey N., Olson E.N. (2002) Calsarcin-3, a novel skeletal muscle-specific member of the calsarcin family, interacts with multiple Z-disc proteins. Journal of Biological Chemistry 277, 13998-14004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11842093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey N., Richardson J.A., Olson E.N. (2000) Calsarcins, a novel family of sarcomeric calcineurin-binding proteins. The Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 997, 14632-14637</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC18970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11114196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry A.C. (2004) The role of resistance exercise intensity on muscle fibre adaptations. Sports Medicine 34, 663-679</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15335243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P., Bottaro M. (2010) Influence of Supervision Ratio on Muscle Adaptations to Resistance Training in Nontrained Subjects. Journal of Strength Conditioning Research. 24, 639-643</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harriss D.J., Atkinson G. (2009) International Journal of Sports Medicine - ethical standards in sport and exercise science research. International Journal of Sports Medicine 30, 701-702</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19809942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hather B.M., Tesch P.A., Buchanan P., Dudley G.A. (1991) Influence of eccentric actions on skeletal muscle adaptations to resistance training. Acta Physiologica Scandinavica 143, 177-185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1835816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung A.P. (2003). The impact of resistance training on distance running performance. Sports Medicine 33, 539-552</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12762828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer W.J., Fry A.C. (1995) Strength testing: development and evaluation of methodology. In: Physiological assessment of human fitness. : Maud P., Foster C.Human Kinetics, Champaingn, IL: 115-138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacArthur D.G., North K.N. (2004) A gene for speed?. The evolution and function of alpha-actinin-3. Bioessays 26, 786-795</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacArthur D.G., North K.N. (2007) ACTN3: A genetic influence on muscle function and athletic performance. Exercise and Sport Science Review 35, 30-34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacArthur D.G., Seto J.T., Chan S., Quinlan K.G., Raftery J.M., Turner N., Nicholson M.D., Kee A.J., Hardeman E.C., Gunning P.W., Cooney G.J., Head S.I., Yang N., North K.N. (2008) An Actn3 knockout mouse provides mechanistic insights into the association between alpha-actinin-3 deficiency and human athletic performance. Human Molecular Genetics 17, 1076-1086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18178581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCauley T., Mastana S.S., Hossack J., Macdonald M., Folland J.P. (2009) Human angiotensin-converting enzyme I/D and alpha-actinin 3 R577X genotypes and muscle functional and contractile properties. Experimental Physiology 994, 81-89</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18676575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran C.N., Yang N., Bailey M.E., Tsiokanos A., Jamurtas A., MacArthur D.G., North K., Pitsiladis Y.P., Wilson R.H. (2007) Association analysis of the ACTN3 R577X polymorphism and complex quantitative body composition and performance phenotypes in adolescent Greeks. European Journal of Human Genetics 115, 88-93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17033684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman A.B., Kupelian V., Visser M., Simonsick E.M., Goodpaster B.H., Kritchevsky S.B., Tylavsky F.A., Rubin S.M., Harris T.B. (2006) Strength, but not muscle mass, is associated with mortality in the health, aging and body composition study cohort. Journal of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences 61, 72-77</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemi A.K., Majamaa K. (2005). Mitochondrial DNA and ACTN3 genotypes in Finnish elite endurance and sprint athletes. European Journal of Human Genetics 113, 965-969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15886711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman B., Esbjornsson M., Rundqvist H., Osterlund T., von Walden F., Tesch P.A. (2009). Strength, power, fiber types, and mRNA expression in trained men and women with different ACTN3 R577X genotypes. Journal of Applied Physiology 106, 959-965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19150855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>North K.N., Beggs A.H. (1996) Deficiency of a skeletal muscle isoform of alpha-actinin (alpha-actinin-3) in merosin-positive congenital muscular dystrophy. Neuromuscular Disorders 66, 229-235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8887951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>North K.N., Yang N., Wattanasirichaigoon D., Mills M., Easteal S., Beggs A.H. (1999) A common nonsense mutation results in alpha-actinin-3 deficiency in the general population. Nature Genetics 21, 353-354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10192379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadimitriou I.D., Papadopoulos C., Kouvatsi A., Triantaphyllidis C. (2008) The ACTN3 gene in elite Greek track and field athletes. International Journal of Sports Medicine 29, 352-355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17879893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paparini A., Ripani M., Giordano G.D., Santoni D., Pigozzi F., Romano-Spica V. (2007) ACTN3 genotyping by real-time PCR in the Italian population and athletes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 39, 810-815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17468578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior S.J., Roth S.M., Wang X., Kammerer C., Miljkovic-Gacic I., Bunker C.H., Wheeler V.W., Patrick A.L., Zmuda J.M.. (2007) Genetic and environmental influences on skeletal muscle phenotypes as a function of age and sex in large, multigenerational families of African heritage. Journal of Applied Physiology 103, 1121-1127</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17656630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth S.M., Walsh S., Liu D., Metter E.J., Ferrucci L., Hurley B.F. (2008) The ACTN3 R577X nonsense allele is under-represented in elite-level strength athletes. European Journal of Human Genetics 116, 391-394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2668151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18043716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakuma K., Yamaguchi A. (2010) The functional role of calcineurin in hypertrophy, regeneration, and disorders of skeletal muscle. Journal of Biomedicine and Biotechnology 2010, 721219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2850156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20379369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>San Juan A.F., Gomez-Gallego F., Canete S., Santiago C., Perez M., Lucia A. (2006) Does complete deficiency of muscle alpha actinin 3 alter functional capacity in elderly women?. A preliminary report. British Journal of Sports Medicine 440, e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2491941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16371478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanada K., Kearns C.F., Midorikawa T., Abe T. (2006) Prediction and validation of total and regional skeletal muscle mass by ultrasound in Japanese adults. European Journal of Applied Physiology 996, 24-31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16235068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart C.E., Rittweger J. (2006) Adaptive processes in skeletal muscle: molecular regulators and genetic influences. Journal of Musculoskeletal and Neuronal Interactions 66, 73-86</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16675891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch P.A., Karlsson J. (1985) Muscle fiber types and size in trained and untrained muscles of elite athletes. Journal of Applied Physiology 559, 1716-1720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4077779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomis M., Beunen G., Maes H., Blimkie C., Van Leemputte M., Claessens A., Marchal G., Willems E., Vlietinck R. (1998) Strength training: importance of genetic factors. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 30, 724-731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9588615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomis M., Huygens W., Heuninckx S., Chagnon M., Maes H., Claessens A., Vlietinck R., Bouchard C., Beunen G. (2004) Exploration of myostatin polymorphisms and the angiotensin-converting enzyme insertion/deletion genotype in responses of human muscle to strength training. European Journal of Applied Physiology 992, 267-274</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15083369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomis M.A., Van Leemputte M., Maes H.H., Blimkie C.J., Claessens A.L., Marchal G., Willems E., Vlietinck R.F., Beunen G.P. (1997). Multivariate genetic analysis of maximal isometric muscle force at different elbow angles. Journal of Applied Physiology 882, 959-967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9074988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiainen K., Sipila S., Kauppinen M., Kaprio J., Rantanen T. (2009) Genetic and environmental effects on isometric muscle strength and leg extensor power followed up for three years among older female twins. Journal of Applied Physiology 106, 1604-1610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent B., De Bock K., Ramaekers M., Van den Eede E., Van Leemputte M., Hespel P., Thomis M.A. (2007) ACTN3 (R577X) genotype is associated with fiber type distribution. Physiol Genomics 32, 58-63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17848603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M., Goodpaster B.H., Kritchevsky S.B., Newman A.B., Nevitt M., Rubin S.M., Simonsick E.M., Harris T.B. (2005) Muscle mass, muscle strength, and muscle fat infiltration as predictors of incident mobility limitations in well-functioning older persons. Journal of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences 60, 324-333</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh S., Liu D., Metter E.J., Ferrucci L., Roth S.M. (2008) ACTN3 genotype is associated with muscle phenotypes in women across the adult age span. Journal of Applied Physiology 105, 1486-1491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2584847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18756004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfarth B., Bray M.S., Hagberg J.M., Perusse L., Rauramaa R., Rivera M.A., Roth S.M., Rankinen T., Bouchard C. (2005) The human gene map for performance and health-related fitness phenotypes: the 2004 update. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 37, 881-903</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N., MacArthur D.G., Gulbin J.P., Hahn A.G., Beggs A.H., Easteal S., North K. (2003) ACTN3 genotype is associated with human elite athletic performance. American Journal of Human Genetics 73, 627-631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1180686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12879365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N., MacArthur D.G., Wolde B., Onywera V.O., Boit M.K., Lau S.Y., Wilson R.H., Scott R.A., Pitsiladis Y.P., North K. (2007) The ACTN3 R577X polymorphism in East and West African athletes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 39, 1985-1988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17986906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>