<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40481272</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Implications and Applications of Stretch-Mediated Hypertrophy in Therapy, Rehabilitation and Athletic Training-An Outlook to Future Potential Applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1815</StartPage><EndPage>1825</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1815-1825</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02237-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Muscle strength and hypertrophy are of high importance for almost every sport, but also for more general prevention and therapeutical approaches. While the most common way to enhance functional and structural muscle capacities is resistance training, there are scenarios in which a resistance training routine may not be feasible or may even be contraindicated. Recently published works showed the potential of high-volume static stretching programs when it comes to promoting muscle strength and hypertrophy, albeit with comparatively long stretching durations per bout in comparison with resistance training. Therefore, there is limited practical applicability of this training approach for healthy participants with access to dynamic training facilities and supervised training. However, there are potential settings in which stretch-mediated hypertrophy could be useful and should be investigated. This current opinion paper explores such potential settings, including in immobilization-induced atrophy, in patients with type 2 diabetes, and as a supplement to common resistance training routines to increase the accumulated volume of mechanical overload of the muscle in healthy or athletic populations. Static stretching might also be used to counteract atrophy in spaceflight because other forms of training that may induce sufficient levels of mechanical strain seem infeasible or impractical. Thus, we explore the potential applications of static stretching routines while considering the feasibility and opportunity for their practical implementation. Consequently, this current opinion paper provides a demand for further investigations of static stretch-mediated adaptations as a potential passive alternative with a focus on therapy and prevention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warneke</LastName><ForeName>Konstantin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4964-2867</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Human Movement Science, Sport and Health, University of Graz, 8010, Graz, Austria. Konstantin.Warneke@uni-jena.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Motion Science and Exercise Physiology, Friedrich Schiller University, 07749, Jena, Germany. Konstantin.Warneke@uni-jena.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Afonso</LastName><ForeName>Jos&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Research, Education, Innovation and Intervention in Sport (CIFI2D), Faculty of Sport, University of Porto, Porto, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Ewan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise Sciences Research Unit, Department of Psychology, Educational Science and Human Movement, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rittweger</LastName><ForeName>J&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Aerospace Medicine, German Aerospace Center (DLR), Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Adolescence Medicine, University Hospital Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Konrad</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Human Movement Science, Sport and Health, University of Graz, 8010, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moser</LastName><ForeName>Othmar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Exercise Physiology and Metabolism, Department of Sport Science, University of Bayreuth, 95440, Bayreuth, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Metabolic Medicine, Division of Endocrinology and Diabetology, Department of Internal Medicine, Medical University of Graz, 8036, Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lohmann</LastName><ForeName>Lars H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Motion Science and Exercise Physiology, Friedrich Schiller University, 07749, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zech</LastName><ForeName>Astrid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Motion Science and Exercise Physiology, Friedrich Schiller University, 07749, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Motion Science and Exercise Physiology, University of Hamburg, 20148, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science and Recreation, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behm</LastName><ForeName>David G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Kinetics and Recreation, Memorial University of Newfoundland, St. Johns, NL, A1C 5S7, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Stretching Exercises</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009133" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscular Atrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: None of the included authors have a conflict of interest to declare. Data availability statement: N/A. Author contribution: Each of the listed authors was responsible for at least one of the included sections. K.W. developed the idea for the review, provided the first structure, drafted the introduction and worked with J.A. on the section about counteracting immobilization-induced atrophy and the one about athletes with D.G.B. and B.J.S. J.A. worked on the section about counteracting immobilization-induced atrophy, the introduction and conclusion. E.T. provided the graphical illustration and co-authored the section about diabetes with O.M. L.H.L. and A.Z. were responsible for the section about fall prevention and declining motor function, while L.H.L. contributed to the revisions and reworking of the individual sections. J.R. wrote the section about space flight, and D.G.B. was responsible for the conclusion. All authors revised the whole manuscript and agreed to the final version. Funding: No funding was received for the preparation or publication of this article. Consent to Participate: N/A. Consent for Publication: N/A. Code Availability: N/A. Ethics Approval: N/A.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40481272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12460394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02237-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02237-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Andrade R, Rocha-Rodrigues S, Nakamura FY, Sarmento H, Freitas SR, et al. What we do not know about stretching in healthy athletes: a scoping review with evidence gap map from 300 trials. Sports Med. 2024;54:1517&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02002-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11239752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38457105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Behm DG, Wirth K, Keiner M, Schiemann S, et al. Effects of chronic static stretching on maximal strength and muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2024;10:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00706-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11026323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38637473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arntz F, Markov A, Behm DG, Behrens M, Negra Y, Nakamura M, et al. Chronic effects of static stretching exercises on muscle strength and power in healthy individuals across the lifespan: a systematic review with multi-level meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53:723&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01806-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Schoenfeld BJ, Hamilton DL, Lehti M, Hulmi JJ. Stimuli and sensors that initiate muscle hypertrophy following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2019;126:30&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00685.2018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30335577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerhage H, Woods NM. Exercise-induced signal transduction and gene regulation in skeletal muscle. J Sports Sci Med. 2002;1:103&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3979001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24748841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K, McGee SL, Farup J, Kj&#xf8;lhede T, Vendelbo MH, Jessen N. Differentiated mTOR but not AMPK signaling after strength vs endurance exercise in training-accustomed individuals. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23:355&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01395.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farnfield MM, Breen L, Carey KA, Garnham A, Cameron-Smith D. Activation of mTOR signalling in young and old human skeletal muscle in response to combined resistance exercise and whey protein ingestion. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2012;37:21&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h11-132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22148961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldspink G, Harridge S. Cellular and molecular aspects of adaptation in skeletal muscle. In: Komi PV, editor. Strength and power in sport. 2nd ed. 2003. p. 231&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Freund PA, Schiemann S. Long-lasting stretching induces muscle hypertrophy: a meta-analysis of animal studies. Journal of Science in Sport and Exercise. Springer, Berlin, 2023. p. 289&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley G. Mechanical overload and skeletal muscle fiber hyperplasia: a meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:1584&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1996.81.4.1584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8904572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE. Force and contractile characteristics after stretch overload in quail anterior latissimus dorsi muscle. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77:135&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1994.77.1.135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7961225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankeny JR, Holly GR, Ashmore CR. Effects of graded duration of stretch on normal and dystrophic skeletal muscle. Muscle Nerve. 1983;6:269&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.880060405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6866007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates GP. The relationship between duration of stimulus per day and the extend of hypertrophy of slow-tonic skeletal muscle in the fowl Gallus gallus. Comp Biochem Physiol. 1993;106A:755&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0300-9629(93)90393-I</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7906634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panidi I, Bogdanis GC, Terzis G, Donti A, Konrad A, Gaspari V, et al. Muscle architectural and functional adaptations following 12-weeks of stretching in adolescent female athletes. Front Physiol. 2021;12: 701338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.701338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8322691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34335307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahata K, Konrad A, Sato S, Kiyono R, Yoshida R, Fukaya T, et al. Effects of a high-volume static stretching programme on plantar-flexor muscle strength and architecture. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:1159&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04608-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33502614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Brinkmann A, Hillebrecht M, Schiemann S. Influence of long-lasting static stretching on maximal strength, muscle thickness and flexibility. Front Physiol. 2022;13: 878955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.878955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35694390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Keiner M, Hillebrecht M, Schiemann S. Influence of one hour versus two hours of daily static stretching for six weeks using a calf-muscle-stretching orthosis on maximal strength. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:11621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191811621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36141890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiner M, Gabriel A, Sommer D, Bernsteiner D, Tilp M, Konrad A. Effects of a high-volume 7-week pectoralis muscle stretching training on muscle function and muscle stiffness. Sports Med Open. 2023;9:40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00582-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10235143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37261567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlann T, Warneke K, Kalder V, Behm DG, Schmidt T, Schiemann S. Influence of 8-weeks of supervised static stretching or resistance training of pectoral major muscles on maximal strength, muscle thickness and range of motion. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:1885&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05413-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11129965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38240811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Hillebrecht M, Claassen-Helmers E, Wohlann T, Keiner M, Behm DG. Effects of a home-based stretching program on bench press maximum strength and shoulder flexibility. J Sports Sci Med. 2023;8:597&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2023.597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10690509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38045741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlann T, Warneke K, Hillebrecht M, Petersmann A, Ferrauti A, Schiemann S. Effects of daily static stretch training over 6 weeks on maximal strength, muscle thickness, contraction properties, and flexibility. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2023.1139065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10149921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37139297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Lima CD, Hollander K, Konrad A, Zech A, et al. Physiology of stretch-mediated hypertrophy and strength increases: a narrative review. Sports Med. 2023;53:2055&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01898-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37556026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Behm DG, Alizadeh S, Hillebrecht M, Konrad A, Wirth K. Discussing conflicting explanatory approaches in flexibility training under consideration of physiology&#x2014;a narrative review. Sports Med. 2024;54:1785&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-024-02043-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11258068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38819597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Wirth K, Keiner M, Lohmann LH, Hillebrecht M, Brinkmann A, et al. Comparison of the effects of long-lasting static stretching and hypertrophy training on maximal strength, muscle thickness and flexibility in the plantar flexors. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123:1773&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05184-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10363083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso J, Ramirez-Campillo R, Mosc&#xe3;o J, Rocha T, Zacca R, Martins A, et al. Strength training versus stretching for improving range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Healthcare. 2021;9:427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare9040427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh S, Daneshjoo A, Zahiri A, Anvar SH, Goudini R, Hicks JP, et al. Resistance training induces improvements in range of motion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53:707&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01804-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9935664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36622555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Wackerhage H, De Souza E. Inter-set stretch: a potential time-efficient strategy for enhancing skeletal muscle adaptations. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:1035190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.1035190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9706104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36457663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arntz F, Markov A, Schoenfeld BJ, Behrens M, Behm DG, Prieske O, et al. Chronic effects of static stretching exercises on skeletal muscle hypertrophy in healthy individuals: a systematic review and multilevel meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2024;10:106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00772-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11438763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39340744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sola OM, Christensen DL, Martin AW. Hypertrophy and hyperplasia of adult chicken anterior latissimus dorsi muscles following stretch with and without denervation. Exp Neurol. 1973;41:76&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0014-4886(73)90182-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4270324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE. Attenuation of Ca 21-activated ATPase and shortening velocity in hypertrophied fast twitch skeletal muscle from aged Japanese quail. Exp Gerontol. 2002;37:665&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0531-5565(02)00003-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11909684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Gonyea WJ. Progressive stretch overload of skeletal muscle results in hypertrophy before hyperplasia. J Appl Physiol. 1993;75:1263&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.75.3.1263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Nakamura M, Ribeiro AS, Cunha PM, Cyrino ES. Does stretch training induce muscle hypertrophy in humans? A review of the literature. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2020;40:148&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31984621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Keiner M, Wohlann T, Lohmann LH, Schmitt T, Hillebrecht M, et al. Influence of long-lasting static stretching interventions on functional and morphological parameters in the plantar flexors: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37:1993&#x2013;2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37318350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlann T, Warneke K, Behm DG, Schiemann S. Comparison of supervised stretching with a stretching device vs. self-administered home based stretching on maximal- and explosive strength. Sports. 2024;12:109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports12040109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11054409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38668577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, McCarthy JJ, Hornberger TA, Phillips SM, Mackey AL, Nader GA, et al. Mechanisms of mechanical overload-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: current understanding and future directions. Physiol Rev. 2023;103:2679&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00039.2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37382939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Granacher U, Warneke K, Arag&#xe3;o-Santos JC, Da Silva-Grigoletto ME, Konrad A. Minimalist training: is lower dosage or intensity resistance training effective to improve physical fitness? A narrative review. Sports Med. 2023;54:289&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01949-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37924459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Morales C, L&#xf3;pez-L&#xf3;pez D, Almaz&#xe1;n-Polo J, Mogedano-Cruz S, Sosa-Reina MD, Garc&#xed;a-P&#xe9;rez-de-Sevilla G, et al. Prevalence, diagnosis and management of musculoskeletal disorders in elite athletes: a mini-review. Dis Mon. 2024;70: 101629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.disamonth.2023.101629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37716840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Alizadeh S, Anvar SH, Drury B, Granacher U, Moran J. Non-local acute passive stretching effects on range of motion in healthy adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021;51:945&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01422-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33459990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelet DCS, Orsatti FL. Effects of resistance training at different intensities of load on cross-education of muscle strength. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2021;46:1279&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2021-0088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley LK, Davi SM, Burland JP, Lepley AS. Muscle atrophy after ACL injury: implications for clinical practice. Sports Health. 2020;12:579&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120944256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7785904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32866081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders TL, Maradit Kremers H, Bryan AJ, Larson DR, Dahm DL, Levy BA, et al. Incidence of anterior cruciate ligament tears and reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:1502&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516629944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia L, De Oliveira SD, Whalan M, McKay MJ, Sullivan J, Fuller CW, et al. Non-contact anterior cruciate ligament injury epidemiology in team-ball sports: a systematic review with meta-analysis by sex, age, sport, participation level, and exposure type. Sports Med. 2022;52:2447&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01697-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9136558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydberg EM, Wennergren D, Stigevall C, Ekelund J, M&#xf6;ller M. Epidemiology of more than 50,000 ankle fractures in the Swedish Fracture Register during a period of 10 years. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18:79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-023-03558-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9887758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36721256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens JE, Walter GA, Okereke E, Scarborough MT, Esterhai JL, George SZ, et al. Muscle adaptations with immobilization and rehabilitation after ankle fracture. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:1695&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000142407.25188.05</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15595289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa H, Nakajima T, Shibasaki I, Nasuno T, Kaneda H, Katayanagi S, et al. Low-intensity resistance training with moderate blood flow restriction appears safe and increases skeletal muscle strength and size in cardiovascular surgery patients: a pilot study. J Clin Med. 2021;10:547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm10030547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7867301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33540756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suetta C, Magnusson SP, Rosted A, Aagaard P, Jakobsen AK, Larsen LH, et al. Resistance training in the early postoperative phase reduces hospitalization and leads to muscle hypertrophy in elderly hip surgery patients&#x2014;a controlled, randomized study. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2004;52:2016&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2004.52557.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15571536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotta K, Behnke BJ, Arjmandi B, Ghosh P, Chen B, Brooks R, et al. Daily muscle stretching enhances blood flow, endothelial function, capillarity, vascular volume and connectivity in aged skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2018;596:1903&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP275459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5978284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29623692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morie M, Reid KF, Miciek R, Lajevardi N, Choong K, Krasnoff JB, et al. Habitual physical activity levels are associated with performance in measures of physical function and mobility in older men. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010;58:1727&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03012.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2945416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20738436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst C, Dismore L, Granic A, Tullo E, Noble JM, Hillman SJ, et al. Attitudes and barriers to resistance exercise training for older adults living with multiple long-term conditions, frailty, and a recent deterioration in health: qualitative findings from the Lifestyle in Later Life &#x2013; Older People&#x2019;s Medicine (LiLL-OPM) study. BMC Geriatr. 2023;23:772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-023-04461-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10675908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38001414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokes KA, Jones B, Bennett M, Close GL, Gill N, Hull JH, et al. returning to play after prolonged training restrictions in professional collision sports. Int J Sports Med. 2020;41:895&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1180-3692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7799169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32483768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekenros L, Frid&#xe9;n C, von Rosen P. Experiences of rehabilitation in young elite athletes: an interview study. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9: e001716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2023-001716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10626772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37937307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambegaonkar JP, Jordan M, Wiese KR, Caswell SV. Kinesiophobia in injured athletes: a systematic review. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2024;9:78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk9020078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11036235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38651436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu C-J, Meierbachtol A, George SZ, Chmielewski TL. Fear of reinjury in athletes. Sports Health. 2017;9:162&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738116666813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27590793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WJ. Skeletal muscle loss: cachexia, sarcopenia, and inactivity. Am J Clin Nutr. 2010;91:1123S-1127S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2010.28608A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20164314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths RD, Palmer TE, Helliwelli T, MacLennan P, MacMillan RR. Effect of passive stretching on the wasting of muscle in the critically ill. Nutrition. 1995;11:428&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8748193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasa T, Sairyo K, Yoshida N, Fukunaga M, Koga K, Ishikawa M, et al. Continuous muscle stretch prevents disuse muscle atrophy and deterioration of its oxidative capacity in rat tail&#x2013;suspension models. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;83:851&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.PHM.0000140803.48932.90</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15502738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanziano DC, Roos BA, Perry AC, Lai S, Signorile JF. The effects of an active-assisted stretching program on functional performance in elderly persons: a pilot study. Clin Interv Aging. 2009;4:115&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2685233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19503774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim G, Kim H, Kim WK, Kim J. Effect of stretching-based rehabilitation on pain, flexibility and muscle strength in dancers with hamstring injury: a single-blind, prospective, randomized clinical trial. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2018;58:1287&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.17.07554-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29072027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Lohmann LH, Keiner M, Wagner C, Schmidt T, Wirth K, et al. Using long-duration static stretch training to counteract strength and flexibility deficits in moderately trained participants. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:13254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192013254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9603712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36293831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelan EA, Ritchey K. Fall prevention in community-dwelling older adults. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/AITC201812040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30508457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruschke C, Butcher HK. Evidence-based practice guideline: fall prevention for older adults. J Gerontol Nurs. 2017;43:15&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/00989134-20171016-01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29065212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick R, McCloskey DI. Proprioceptive, visual and vestibular thresholds for the perception of sway during standing in humans. J Physiol. 1994;478(Pt 1):173&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1994.sp020240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1155655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7965833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muehlbauer T, Gollhofer A, Granacher U. Associations between measures of balance and lower-extremity muscle strength/power in healthy individuals across the lifespan: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45:1671&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0390-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26412212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suwa M, Imoto T, Kida A, Yokochi T. Early reduction in toe flexor strength is associated with physical activity in elderly men. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28:1472&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.28.1472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4905892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27313353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cattagni T, Scaglioni G, Laroche D, Van Hoecke J, Gremeaux V, Martin A. Ankle muscle strength discriminates fallers from non-fallers. Front Aging Neurosci. 2014;6:336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2014.00336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4271599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25566068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Geriatrics Society, American Academy of Orthopedic Surgeons Panel on Fall Prevention. Guideline for the prevention of falls in older persons. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2001;49:664&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11380764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Muehlbauer T, Kibele A, Granacher U. Effects of strength training using unstable surfaces on strength, power and balance performance across the lifespan: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45:1645&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0384-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero-Odasso M, van der Velde N, Martin FC, Petrovic M, Tan MP, Ryg J, et al. World guidelines for falls prevention and management for older adults: a global initiative. Age Ageing. 2022;51:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afac205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36178003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacroix A, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Beurskens R, Granacher U. Effects of supervised vs unsupervised training programs on balance and muscle strength in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47:2341&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0747-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28573401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Justine M, Azizan A, Hassan V, Salleh Z, Manaf H. Barriers to participation in physical activity and exercise among middle-aged and elderly individuals. Singapore Med J. 2013;54:581&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11622/smedj.2013203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24154584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epro G, McCrum C, Mierau A, Leyendecker M, Br&#xfc;ggemann G-P, Karamanidis K. Effects of triceps surae muscle strength and tendon stiffness on the reactive dynamic stability and adaptability of older female adults during perturbed walking. J Appl Physiol. 2018;124:1541&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00545.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29494289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim N, Park J, Shin H, Bae Y. Gastrocnemius medial head stiffness is associated with potential fall risk in community-dwelling older adults. Healthcare. 2022;10:785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10050785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9141566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35627922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohmann LH, Zech A, Pl&#xf6;schberger G, Ora&#x17e;e M, Jochum D, Warneke K. Acute and chronic effects of stretching on balance: a systematic review with multilevel meta-analysis. Front Med (Lausanne). 2024;11:1451180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2024.1451180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11427387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39346940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou B, Rayner AW, Gregg EW, Sheffer KE, Carrillo-Larco RM, Bennett JE, et al. Worldwide trends in diabetes prevalence and treatment from 1990 to 2022: a pooled analysis of 1108 population-representative studies with 141 million participants. The Lancet. 2024;404:2077&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)02317-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7616842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39549716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramtahal R, Khan C, Maharaj-Khan K, Nallamothu S, Hinds A, Dhanoo A, et al. Prevalence of self-reported sleep duration and sleep habits in type 2 diabetes patients in South Trinidad. J Epidemiol Glob Health. 2015;5:S35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jegh.2015.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26073574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies MJ, Aroda VR, Collins BS, Gabbay RA, Green J, Maruthur NM, et al. A consensus report by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and the European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD). Diabetologia. 2022;2022(65):1925&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-022-05787-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9510507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36151309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Pedrosa JM, Camprubi-Robles M, Guzman-Rolo G, Lopez-Gonzalez A, Garcia-Almeida JM, Sanz-Paris A, et al. The vicious cycle of type 2 diabetes mellitus and skeletal muscle atrophy: clinical, biochemical, and nutritional bases. Nutrients. 2024;16:172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16010172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10780454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38202001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans PL, McMillin SL, Weyrauch LA, Witczak CA. Regulation of skeletal muscle glucose transport and glucose metabolism by exercise training. Nutrients. 2019;11:2432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11102432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31614762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Missbach B, Dias S, K&#xf6;nig J, Hoffmann G. Impact of different training modalities on glycaemic control and blood lipids in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Diabetologia. 2014;57:1789&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-014-3303-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24996616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ozairi E, Alsaeed D, Alroudhan D, Voase N, Hasan A, Gill JMR, et al. Skeletal muscle and metabolic health: how do we increase muscle mass and function in people with type 2 diabetes? J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106:309&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/clinem/dgaa835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33336682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doupis J, Karras K, Avramidis K. The role of individualized exercise prescription in type 2 diabetes mellitus management. touchREVIEWS in Endocrinology. 2021;17:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8320009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35118440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas E, Ficarra S, Nakamura M, Drid P, Trivic T, Bianco A. The effects of stretching exercise on levels of blood glucose: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2024;10:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00661-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10858005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38334888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser O, Eckstein ML, West DJ, Goswami N, Sourij H, Hofmann P. Type 1 diabetes and physical exercise: moving (forward) as an adjuvant therapy. Curr Pharm Des. 2020;26:946&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1381612826666200108113002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31912769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartee GD. Roles of TBC1D1 and TBC1D4 in insulin- and exercise-stimulated glucose transport of skeletal muscle. Diabetologia. 2015;58:19&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-014-3395-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4258142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25280670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh J, Roberts R, Heinemann L. Confusion regarding duration of insulin action. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2014;8:170&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1932296813514319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4454113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24876553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuura S, Nagata S, Shibazaki K, Uchida R, Imai Y, Shibata S, et al. Increased skeletal muscle mass index was involved in glycemic efficacy following diabetes treatment, and changes in fat mass index correlated with the changes in the lipid ratio in type 2 diabetes. J Diabetes Compl. 2024;38: 108717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2024.108717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38422562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannavo A, Carandina A, Corbi G, Tobaldini E, Montano N, Arosio B. Are skeletal muscle changes during prolonged space flights similar to those experienced by frail and sarcopenic older adults? Life. 2022;12:2139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life12122139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9781047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36556504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavanagh PR, Genc KO, Gopalakrishnan R, Kuklis MM, Maender CC, Rice AJ. Foot forces during typical days on the international space station. J Biomech. 2010;43:2182&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2010.03.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20462584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genc KO, Gopalakrishnan R, Kuklis MM, Maender CC, Rice AJ, Bowersox KD, et al. Foot forces during exercise on the International Space Station. J Biomech. 2010;43:3020&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2010.06.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20728086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalakrishnan R, Genc KO, Rice AJ, Lee SMC, Evans HJ, Maender CC, et al. Muscle volume, strength, endurance, and exercise loads during 6-month missions in space. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2010;81:91&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3357/ASEM.2583.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20131648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto A, Shigematsu T, Fukunaga T, Kawakami K, Mukai C, Sekiguchi C. medical baseline data collection on bone and muscle change with space flight. Bone. 1998;22:79S-82S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S8756-3282(98)00020-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9600758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavy-Le Traon A, Heer M, Narici MV, Rittweger J, Vernikos J. From space to Earth: advances in human physiology from 20 years of bed rest studies (1986&#x2013;2006). Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101:143&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0474-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17661073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene KA, Tooze JA, Lenchik L, Weaver AA. Change in lumbar muscle size and composition on MRI with long-duration spaceflight. Ann Biomed Eng. 2022;50:816&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10439-022-02968-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9167780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35459964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Witt JK, Ploutz-Snyder LL. Ground reaction forces during treadmill running in microgravity. J Biomech. 2014;47:2339&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2014.04.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24835563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaisar R, Karim A, Elmoselhi AB. Muscle unloading: a comparison between spaceflight and ground-based models. Acta Physiol. 2020;228:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.13431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31840423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittweger J, Albracht K, Fl&#xfc;ck M, Ruoss S, Brocca L, Longa E, et al. Sarcolab pilot study into skeletal muscle&#x2019;s adaptation to long-term spaceflight. NPJ Micrograv. 2018;4:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41526-018-0052-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6141586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30246141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitts RH, Trappe SW, Costill DL, Gallagher PM, Creer AC, Colloton PA, et al. Prolonged space flight-induced alterations in the structure and function of human skeletal muscle fibres. J Physiol. 2010;588:3567&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2010.188508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2988519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20660569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita-Goto K, Okuyama R, Honda M, Kawasaki K, Fujita K, Yamada T, et al. Maximal and submaximal forces of slow fibers in human soleus after bed rest. J Appl Physiol. 2001;91:417&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2001.91.1.417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11408459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homer KA, Helms ER, Spence A. The effect of a combined long-duration static stretching and resistance training regimen on a competitive bodybuilder: a case study. Physiol Rep. 2025;13:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.70156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11824903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39825474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Konrad A, Keiner M, Zech A, Nakamura M, Hillebrecht M, et al. Using daily stretching to counteract performance decreases as a result of reduced physical activity&#x2014;a controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:15571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192315571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9741422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36497646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrier I. Does stretching improve performance? A systematic and critical review of the literature. Clin J Sports Med. 2004;14:267&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00042752-200409000-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15377965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros DM, Lima CS. Influence of chronic stretching on muscle performance: systematic review. Hum Mov Sci. 2017;54:220&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2017.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warneke K, Freundorfer P, Pl&#xf6;schberger G, Konrad A, Behm DG, Schmidt T. Effects of chronic static stretching interventions on jumping and sprinting performance&#x2014;a systematic review with multilevel meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2024;1372:689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11002243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38595642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rindom E, Kristensen AM, Overgaard K, Vissing K, de Paoli FV. Estimation of p70S6K Thr389 and 4E-BP1 Thr 37/46 phosphorylation support dependency of tension per se in a dose-response relationship for downstream mTORC1 signalling. Acta Physiol. 2020;22:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31804016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larouche M-C, Camir&#xe9; Bernier S, Racine R, Collin O, Desmons M, Mailloux C, et al. Stretch-induced hypoalgesia: a pilot study. Scand J Pain. 2020;20:837&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/sjpain-2020-0018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatano G, Matsuo S, Asai Y, Suzuki S, Iwata M. Effects of high-intensity stretch with moderate pain and maximal intensity stretch without pain on flexibility. J Sports Sci Med. 2022;8:171&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2022.171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9157514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35719229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;ve MP, Hirata RP, Palsson TS. Regional and widespread pain sensitivity decreases following stretching in both men and women&#x2014;indications of stretch-induced hypoalgesia. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2024;39:32&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2024.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38876646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>